i
i heard you there speak there michael
i'm just seeing if i could pipe youtube
out
uh back through so i could play some
elevator music
in that case it's okay that it didn't
work it's okay that it didn't work yeah
but you know girl from epinephrine
is apparently the canonical elevator
music
i'm not sure i'm glad to know that but
okay yeah
apparently it's it's in all the movies
whenever they're standing in an elevator
they
that's what they play all right
so militia is your audio up and running
um uh can you hear me can you confirm
that you
can hear me i can hear you that sounds
good thank you
okay perfect all right we'll give it um
the traditional extra minute or two
i don't know that we have two hours
worth of discussion this morning or this
afternoon or this evening wherever you
are
so we'll start at uh two going on for
three past the hour
now it does work for me i hit reload by
mistake
okay i guess it's three minutes past so
assuming we're all ready to rock and
roll we should start
so again good morning good afternoon
good evening wherever you are um
welcome to the itf 109 lake working
group meeting
my name is stephen farrell i'm one of
your chairs and
militia
is muted but is it another one of your
chairs
this is hello everyone
great uh so
we have the let me just go over here
so you can see the working group
character link to the main list
jabber room if you're in jabber
otherwise
then in mid echo you take a link and the
ether pad for where meeting notes can be
collaboratively taken and michael has
michael richardson has volunteered to
take notes in the pad michael is that
correct
pat yes excellent thank you
with that all right we have the note
well
it's i guess the first time this week
you'll be seeing this
for some of you at least um it's a
reminder that
atf policies apply this this slide
itself is not those policies you should
go read those
but by participating you agree to these
policies
here's our agenda and we're at
point zero we'll be talking john we'll
be talking about
uh ad hoc and the
issues we have with that and then
francesca has a slot afterwards
and then we have one aob item
uh which i think was also john was this
militia sorry i don't recall right now
i'll go ahead sorry um so we have one
arb item at the end
uh which is to discuss relationship with
kosei and so on
so with that does anybody want to bash
the agenda some
now it's time if you want to add
something or
tell us something about the agenda
so let's just add in the minute that for
a year in the iob
slot we will discuss the late related
work at the iitf
109 and this will be led by euron
great thank you
yeah uh so
assuming that means that we have nothing
else in the agenda
um i did have one piece of administrator
to check and we'll com
we'll go to the list with this as well
um i just wanted to note that there's
been a bunch of discussion in
the github repo issues um
which is a fine thing and something
that's entirely okay for a working group
to do
but it you know for some people it suits
them well to work that way for other
people
less well so i just wanted to check uh
if anybody has a problem with that or if
everybody's okay with it and again we'll
confirm this on the list that
we there's a kind of process for saying
that discussion in
on github issues is a fine thing to do
it does mean of course that anything
substantive gets brought to the mining
list but
if that's a thing somebody has a comment
on or wants to talk about now is a good
time
um i just wanted to request the chairs
to there's a config you can do that will
send a summary
like a weekly summary to the list i
don't know how to do it
but it's possible and it's in the github
rfc somewhere
sure uh we can try to i've seen those in
other working groups and i find them
useless myself but
if people wanted sure we can do that i i
find that it's useful for the simple
reason that
it goes in the archives it links back to
the issues which are now closed and so
when you go back to the archives to find
out what happened you see that message
and you're like oh the discussion was
over there and that's why you didn't
find it in the archive
fair point okay so we'll take an action
for one of the chairs to
tweak that button and github somehow
and again we will bring this up on the
list with a pointer to the right
reference for uh in the the guest
working group that they have a document
about this so we'll bring that to the
list
shortly okay so with that i think that's
our administrivia
and i believe
this is the correct next slide
please correct me from wrong yeah so
this is the
slide set for the next two points one
and two
great and with that i shall mute and let
you run away john
thank you uh by
by the way do we have should do people
raise hands or they just
talk or
when they want to say something people
can raise their hands
inside of uh meet echo
but i guess if you if you give people a
chance and say you know that's a good
time to ask questions
as you go through the new slides that
would be fine too yeah
good we can go to the next slide
[Music]
so this is point one on the agenda
changes and there has been two versions
since
the last itef meeting 108.
the changes from zero zero to zero one
was
removal of the psk method because it was
agreed that the asymmetric method was
fast enough and there was basically
no difference in message size then
there's
removal of examples with certificate
by value and some editorial changes
and then changes from zero one to zero
two which was
submitted two weeks ago also not so many
changes
uh those requested to have a use of ad
hoc
section in the beginning to better
describe the use cases
this came from the people doing formal
verification
then there's a new sub section added
and more text inline to
clarify the encoding of the bitstring
identifiers
there was comments on people looking at
the test vectors
and so on questioning if it was
correct so now a lot more clarification
has been added
and then there's text added on what
an identity these and what a small set
of
identities can be in practice
there's new text on
and also that was requested by the
people doing formal verification
then add the text on key confirmation
and there's a now as a recommendation
that
the responder had have received explicit
key confirmation
of the key prk 4 3m
before storing the long key material
long
term can still send
messages but should probably have key
confirmation before
storing it and these identities and give
confirmation will
we will come back to in the issues then
there is
test vectors for static dv hellmann
previous version only had test vectors
for signatures
and i think francesca will talk more
about test vectors
in her presentation about interrupt and
then there is editorial changes
so any comments on that
um you're on here can you hear me
yes yeah i just wanted to add that we'd
start
uh this uh new subsection on bitstring
identifiers there was still some
some confusion around that so steven uh
uh risdysoff has provided feedback and
we're
trying to make it even more clear what
what's the purpose of this
and maybe you should say a few words
about that
okay yeah i have not seen that
discussion yeah that's good um
just point out that bit string the
encoding of b string
identifier is absolutely needed it's
like saves
four bytes which is essential to get it
to fit in
lorawan and five hop
sixties
unless there any more comments i guess
we
go to the next part on agenda
so the the rest of your presentation are
is open issues
and most of them
are quite old
but there was now with the latest
mails it has increased the discussion on
github which is
great it has also spawned some
new issues
um so my plan is to go through them
one by one and
allow all the discussion we need to have
on them and
if we don't have time with all of them i
would
suggest that we have an interim meeting
somewhere after this meeting
i don't know if somebody wants some
other order
we can fix this but otherwise i plan to
go
through them according to this order and
there's one or several slides per
per issue or issue group so some of
these
consist of several issues and some of
the research are also
related so
otherwise unless there is any comments
i think we move on to agreement and
negotiation
so agreement the negotiation of
parameters
this is issue 11 and 23
and this is more uh
check that to so that
this has been properly discussed and
agreed otherwise
this is not part of some this is more
just how things happen to be as the
protocol was built so you could consider
other
options here but basically ad hoc has
several options and parameters the
documents state that some of them must
be
agreed beforehand like the method
the transport and correlation and the
use
and format of the auxiliary data
the cypher suits they are negotiated or
verified and then
there are some cozy parameters
namely the how to identify the
credentials and
how to structure the identifier that are
on the fly chosen by the
participants
and all of these have different
trade-offs
agreeing beforehand of course reduces
flexibility we of course
make sure that it's a very easy solution
negotiation might increase message sizes
and round trips
letting the parties choose things inside
the protocols
may allow an own path attacker to
to deduce things from the messen site
and block things
and also you might run into problem
where
something is not supported
and the discussion on github so far is
a comment that people
that person was happy with the current
configuration
okay let's see see
tls there yeah good
any comments on agreement negotiation
maybe one comment from for me you're on
but
i mean when when it's stated here that
the parameters agreed beforehand it's
basically understood that the initiator
decides and and the responder
uh so declines if it if it can't support
so it's basically it's a very crude
negotiation but it's still
it's the principal possible that
initiator and responders suppose
support different methods
and the initiator decides with message
one which method is going to be
oh she has a clarification oh michael is
in the cube
my suggestion is that maybe we should
add a
appendix with an example such that
someone who is invoking ad hoc in their
protocol
will be informed that the following
parameters must be agreed on beforehand
in other words you better put them in
your document that uses ad hoc
uh as as to what you intend to do
for those and
so that people don't forget something as
a kind of a
proto applicability statement block
maybe
also as we add things or subtract things
or to change our mind then at least
we'll know what what we've we're
supposed to say
i i don't think we're going to change
our mind a lot but it could be
yeah that sounds like a good idea i
think
i think every it is mentioned but it's
probably a little bit spread out in the
document so
having uh easy to find
list is probably a very good idea
um unless there any more
comments i assume we have the working
assumption that
this stays as is but keep
the github issue open for some more time
yeah that sounds like a good plan let's
start with an action point
that essentially we add a subsection on
or clarifying what these uh negotiated
parameters
negotiated than the great parameters
from before so add this in the draft
then i guess we can go to the next slide
so re-keying us of
all oscar aad this might
suggest basically that this is
not ad hoc but this has been discussed
in it this was brought up in a lake
working group
and there's a choice to do this
in ad hoc or or score so
see if audi is currently working on a
document specifying equations to
calculate
aad limits you might have seen the
document or
the previous discussion on lake when
this was brought up
or the discussion in tls or quick
and basically the questions that you
put limits on the number of encryption
operations
and the number of four jury attempts
that you allow so these are the
different parties
it's the client and the server
have two different limits and tls dtls
and quick has
adopted very strict limits based on
these equations
uh and but these
the limits themselves are not following
from the equations there's a lot of
assumptions you one assumption is what
target probability you want um
for either to an attacker distinguishing
the ciphertext from a random string or
achieving
a single forgery
the equations does not handle multiple
forgeries
that's much more complicated to
calculate
another factor is packet length so plain
text plus
additional data for integrity only plain
text for
the confidentiality
and here you get you can have higher
limits if you
have smaller messages and you accept a
lower
probability um having strictly necessary
is
not a problem at all if re-keying is
easy
if requiring is not easy it might cause
problems
so this is not these aad limits is
not at all a problem for ad hoc it
docused each key
only once it might be a problem for os
score
and re-keying for os score can be done
either in
or erdog or oscor
as an example dtl is at the limit for
ccm
with a 16 byte tag
to 2 to the power of 23 and 2 to the
power
23.8
and q is the confidentiality limit and v
is the forgery limit
dtls also state that given the
probability target for tls
which was decided for tls 103 i think
you cannot get ccm 8
to work and dtls103 states that
ccm8 must not be used unless you take
additional safeguards so i think
my feelings here is that the iot
community should
discuss more what reasonable
limits for q and v are for ccm8
ccm8 is very very well used in the iot
community
and it's not
clear that the tls limits or
is the ones that should apply to all
other protocols
and also my suggestion and water scene
is that this is better done in
oscor and the core working group
than in edoc
comments opinions
and this is on the agenda for the core
working group on friday
so you have michael in the queue and
then me in the queue good
so i i guess i can't understand
um this is not specific to ccm8 it's
just we use it a lot there's lots of
other algorithms that have
limits where you must re-key it um going
back to 3ds
does that um so i don't understand
and everything else in detail in tls and
ipsec and all this stuff we've always
just
had run the re the keying the keying
protocol again to re-key it
we've never done this at the so-called
transport layer
um so i don't know why this would be
different in
uh os core and ad hoc um
there and and and i don't know
if you're if it's really specific for
ccm or that's just we have some advice
right now about that
uh i think the reason why you might
start want to
want want to do things on the
record layer or the oscar layer is that
if if you set this
um re-keying a
period so short that it starts to get a
problem to rerun the handshake
at least for very constrained iot
devices
um and i think basically
the the equations here are not specific
for ccm8
it's i think they're quite generic for
any
algorithm with the 64 bit
tag and if you then put
forgery probability uh
as what is it
low as tls has
done then then basically you cannot use
64 byte
tags basically or it you get very very
frequent re-keying
at least with the packet sizes that tls
dtls has calculated with
which is two to a power of 14 bytes
that wasn't i i understood all that but
that didn't tell me why we should do it
in os core
rather than uh i didn't understand why
i mean either way right it's gonna
involve the same crypto operations
unless i don't understand
so i don't unders i guess i don't don't
know what would be the
advantage of doing an os core ah yeah
no no it might not at all involve the
same crypto operation
i think in on the ad hoc level
everything
is already done you can just if you want
you can rerun ad hoc and that would
solve the problem what you can do on the
record layer is that you can
do things without asymmetric crypto so
one option is that you you have a master
key and
periodically you derive like you have
the oscar master key and periodically
you derive
send new sender key from that key
you can also hash the sender key
periodically
which also gives you forward secrecy or
you can exchange new keys
in the au score
level with psk protection so
all of this you could do much much much
more cheaper than
rerunning ad hoc
so i i i'm assuming michael's questions
finished with they've not jumped back in
michael uh so i had a
just a comment last question uh
is it documented somewhere in a way that
would be friendly for
a developer of a let's say a small
device that is going to be deployed for
a long time
um well i i don't think that should be
an ad hoc probably but
is there text somewhere that such a
developer could read and know what to do
not right now right now they would have
to read the
uh see if rga aad limits
documents and there's no reference
to that from os core
but that would
presumably be the outcome of the core
discussions
okay so as a suggestion i think it would
be good
if somewhere there was a developer
friendly
reference here because a lot of people
won't understand all these details
and will either never change keys or
change them all the time
um so if somebody was happy to write
some text like that that would be great
and i'm sure if a home for it could be
found somewhere
could probably fit in some some text in
ad hoc also this is quite this is quite
related to other
other reasons to do rikki and like
getting forward or
backward secrecy so
probably a dog should also have some
section of recommendations for
how often you should
how long you should use your session
keys or or how
often you should redo ad hoc
okay thanks and then i have been in the
queue
roughly getting back to michael's point
uh in terms of
you know is this something specific to
ccm8
is this something specific to oscar or
ad hoc
um and like yes this is a fairly
generic topic i think the specific
formulas and specific limits
are specific to ccm8 and i think that
from a practical point of view part of
why we're going to be stuck doing it
in oscore or maybe ad hoc
as opposed to somewhere else is that
gtls and the tls working group
essentially feels like they can get away
with saying
don't use ccm8 but i don't think that
that would really fly if
if oscar said don't use ccm8 because
people are using it already
and you know telling them to not do that
is not really going to be effective
so the the way that this analysis would
sort of take form would presumably be to
say
well yes maybe we can accept the lower
security
your attack success probability in some
of these cases
and maybe it depends on how strongly we
care about the particular data in
question
um but i think that probably
oscor is going to have to you know look
at the formulas and
figure out what is actually appropriate
for the iot environments
in order to save that we could use this
um
and i think michael was sort of talking
and typing into the chat
about how yes we shouldn't be rerunning
ad hoc every time
and i agree that's the right way to go i
think john had also mentioned that
so my my sense here is that probably
oscor
or maybe ad hoc is going to be stuck
talking about ccm8
safety and when it's appropriate to use
it
and how
[Music]
and i guess michael jumped back in the
queue so presumably he wants to respond
uh okay so ben so if i understand what
you're telling me is that
because the limits of ccm8 are quite low
um that tls is saying we will solve this
problem by just not using that algorithm
and that's simply not an
option here um right should i get that
correct okay so that's very interesting
to
to understand um so um
so i don't know what that would mean if
i
if i do dtls to set up an os
core oscore uh context um
and then there was no way to well i
guess you'd have to run
the re-key algorithm there so all i'm
really saying though
is that it just seems it seems bizarre
to me to put a re-key whether
john suggested no we can do master keys
and all sorts of other stuff
well it seems to me if we're going to do
that it should be an ad hoc not an os
core that's what i'm trying to say
really okay
i don't care how you do it well maybe i
do care but but
it just seems to me that we should we
should write that down in the key
agreement process not in the other part
um unless there's some strong reason to
do it another way i don't understand
why that would be uh okay
i mean i think it comes up in dts
because dtls is both the key exchange
and the record protection algorithm
and i guess i had been seeing it as
saying if when you're using the record
protection algorithm
you need to do the key update mechanism
which is a
in protocol message for dtls
after however many records and
for ad hoc and oscar we of course have
the
key agreement and the record protection
in separate documents and so it actually
becomes more important
to think about which one it's attached
to in the documentation
i don't have a super strong opinion off
the top of my head so it's
something to think about at least
i think maybe keep it
open and see where the discussions in
core on friday is going and
probably this should be some
information in both ad hoc and
if needed if there will be some update
document to
oscore which of course be there as well
yeah that certainly sounds reasonable
yeah you're around here i just want to
remind you that we also need for oscor
itself
assuming you're keying oscar with
symmetric keys you also need
for that case to have instructions about
how frequently you need to re-key and
how to do it
so if we do it in off court and we solve
it both for for the case when you key it
with asymmetric keys and with symmetric
keys
but i agree with with what's been stated
here that
we should have text in both documents
explaining the problem
but i think the mechanism to solve it
should be enough score
good um any more comment on this or
should we move to the next
issue
it's a comment from jonathan in the
chat
yeah yeah that's
good now we only talked about the second
um where to do i think the
my i guess jonathan's comment here
discuss
about the yeah
i i agree that lake would be a better
place to have discussion about
um this the crypto and security
parts of these equations and what they
mean and
um this is not only
oscar i guess ccm8 is used
in most constrained iot
so it would be good to have a more
general discussion about that
okay so i guess we should keep this one
open and continue the discussion on
github before closing
yeah definitely i think
it should be this will probably not be
closed in a while
if this is going to be discussed in core
so you'd like the next slide john yep
yes please so
next point is future proofing ad hoc
and this is two different slides and two
different
issues so let's start with issue number
is shall we replace hkdf with a more
general extract and expand to
allow kmac
so basically hmac is
was designed and is needed to mitigate
length
extension weaknesses in md5 sha-1 shot 2
and shot 3 and shake does not have this
weakness
and therefore nist has standardized the
more simple and efficient
kmac mode
currently the addock document says that
you shall use
hmac in hkdf
but as has been also been suggested and
discussed for the hpke
document in cfrd
the suggestion is to specify ad hoc
in terms of extract and expand
instead of hkdf extractance band
and then you use hmac
when the hash function is short two and
use kmac
when the hash function is shake
and i already
sent the mail to cfrg
yesterday and quickly got the response
there from hillary
who suggested the following
adaptation to kmac for extract and
expand
and could be discussed whether
it should include a context obviously
the hkdf
use does not use a context as specified
but hillary pointed out that kmac
could use the constant context
that's the kdf extraction and expansion
and the comments on gpa
github was is positive that this is
something we should
probably do i myself feel that there is
we should do this to be open to
not only kmac but also any future
kdfs that are specified
um and there is
a question from sean how well why the
implement the kmac is
i don't really know shake is
i feel is having quite
quite some implementation and growing
kmac is basically if you have shake you
have
kmac but the kmx specification is quite
new so i i don't
think there's probably not many apis but
you can if you have shake you can very
very very easily do it yourself
yes the discussion in hpk was
definitely the same thing i think what
they decided was that they did not
mention
kmac but the document
they made the document or the document
the boss
general in terms of extract and expand
the auto set
any comments on this
let's do in comment yep i think it was
one comment from
from tim in the in the
issue tracker which was basically
supportive
well yeah i think that was basically
both from from peter and timothy there
was
yeah that was good support and and also
with respect to implementation
so so yes you're in the queue or
militia i see you on thecube yes can you
hear me
yeah i'm having some little issues with
uh with i'm using my mic
sorry about that so uh essentially what
i wanted to say i want to judge john
uh that based on the understanding of
this issue
adding kmac would mean adding another
element in the cypher suit with which we
would be
increasing the complexity right so uh i
have a question
i have a question whether it's possible
to do uh
hkdf with shake and what are the
disadvantages of this
yes you you can use um
hmac with shake it requires
you need to run shake double the amount
of time basically
the plan was not to include this in
register any shake kmac cipher suits
as currently specified you can use ad
hoc with all the
[Music]
cosi algoriths
if you use a private cypher suit
the plan was to
instead of having hkdf expand to use
expand and extract and then
have a line saying that if you have
short 2 then you use h
hmac hkdf and if you have
shake then you use kmac
and give give formulas
like the ones here how you do that that
will not be something people
need to need to implement
okay i see so essentially you're saying
if the if the hash
if the hash function is shaped that by
default we would be using
kmac and therefore not be adding it to
the
district okay i see
so we have uh stephen and timothy in the
queue
yes is there any reason why the answer
here should be different for
ad hoc and hpke
no
so i guess my suggestion in that case is
if there's no reason for them to differ
we should probably have them the same
or then find a reason otherwise i
i think i think
one difference is that hpk was very far
i actually commented on this a long time
ago but then the authors
did not do anything then there was a
comment now when they are very late in
the process and they did not want to
add any new formulas but they said it
was
general so i think the change is that
the difference is that ad hoc is a lot
earlier in the standardization process
so it
i would suggest to add like formulas
like this into the draw to explain how
how one would use kmac
okay yeah i mean i i guess
generally i'm i'm adding adding more
options for people to implement
is not something that is that friendly
towards implementers but
if that's the right thing to do i guess
but
tim
did you want to say something
so there is an army button in the uh
in this in in the upper left
corner that you should hit can you hear
me now
yes okay sorry uh yeah i was only
wondering
uh if there was a substantial difference
between
a shake software implementation and uh
the sha software implementation um
[Music]
i don't know if anybody knows this
i guess not i can look it up maybe
later
comment on michael's commentary so so
both
shot two and shake are currently
uh possible to use in hedok
as they are registered cozy algoriths
okay seems to be posted to
to to make the change from
to extract and the span similar to hpk
e and that's otherwise i think let's
discuss more on github maybe
and just understanding christian's
comment here when he says i understood
it already be a choice of
charter with hkdf shake with kmac
and so on so that i mean
the so the the difference would be
that if you decide to implement shake
then or if the cypher suite says shake
then
you need to have kmac and yeah so yeah
and that's well it's a good question
is that is that too complex
thing to have uh is it obvious is it
better that we
stick to hkdf
i i think the the the idea is to
decrease the complexity for somebody
that in the future only wants to support
shake
and not short to then you don't need to
implement
hmac
yep good point let's let's take it to
the issue so
shake plus hmac shake would not be a
thing is what you're saying
yes okay and i think we're all on
agreement with that i think everyone's
in agreement with that
and maybe a surprise that that was even
a consideration
okay good then we
i guess the the plan is to
move ahead with this um then
uh but let's discuss let's keep the
issue open on the
github let's move to the next slide
maybe
unless there's any more uh so
this is a different issue under the
future proofing ad hoc
so
ad hoc currently uses elliptic
curve dv hellmann both for key exchange
and for authentication in one of the
methods
and all the new peak you see
algos for from a nist is expected to be
be specified as key encapsulation
methods
uh therefore it might be a good idea to
specify ad hoc
in terms of key encapsulation
methods so it's prepared to be used with
future chem algorithms uh
for divi hellman i think this would be a
purely specification change
depending yeah depending a bit
on exactly what you do there was would
definitely not be a change to message
size
uh cfrdhpe
is the has done a great job of defining
exact interfaces for both un
authenticated and unauthenticated
chem if
you would use implement ad hoc
variants of these interfaces there would
be no
change to the implementations if you
want to follow the seder code in
hpke then there would be
implementation changes but no changes to
message sizes
so the interfaces defined by hpke
is generatekeeper that's easy to
understand you generate the
private and public key then you have
on the left side you have the methods
that will be needed for the signature
method so it's only
key exchange so ncap takes a public key
and generates a shared secret and
encryption
and in the dv helmand case the ch secret
is
e to the power of x y and encryption is
the the the other the new public key
basically
g to the power of y and then you have
the
d cap where you take encryption which in
different minus c to power
y and you take your own secret key which
is x
and you get the same shared secret in
the
hellmann case you would need the
authenticated ncap functions
where you in addition to the ephemeral
public key
pkr you also input your own
secret staticky in erdoc
the secret staticky is called
r on the respondent side and i on the
initiator's
side
and uh reading up about this after the
issue was created it seems
very likely that future camps will
adhere to the general keeper and captain
d
cab but maybe not as clear that they
would
adhere to the cfrt hpk
authm cap auth dcap interfaces
uh seems to be an open research
question at this time um
but i'm not sure
a problem is that while
the ephemeral key is only used one time
in this auth end cap
inside what end cap function it
basically needs to be done used twice
for
encapsulation which does not necessarily
work with all the pqc
algoriths comments on github was
generally
positive but
i think if we are sure that
if this will lead to that we can just
plug in pqc algorithms
and i think this is a good thing to do
if we are unsure that that will work
then i think this is just
making the document
it might make the document harder to
understand for
people that are used to elliptic curtis
helmand and not to key encapsulation
methods um
i think maybe a way forward would be to
ask cfrdy for
advice
any comments on this
i don't think it's worth doing only for
the key exchange if we cannot do it for
the
authenticated
gaps
so so just just one comment that we in
the requirements document
for lake we actually said that uh public
that post quantum is out of scope so
it doesn't mean that we don't have to
take
take it into account in this way but we
are not obliged to
to support that in in this version of
the
of the document yeah i think the
plan is not to try to standardize any
pqc algorith
this time it's just to if this is the
future way authenticated
public key encryption and key exchange
interfaces
will look like it might be a very good
idea to
adopt to that already today
and the algorithms themselves will not
necessarily
need to specify these interfaces
themselves but they
it would be necessary that they can be
made to work with the old authenticated
cap
interfaces
[Music]
if there's not any more comments
i suggest that i formulate the
message to cfrg and
let's see what see if all this says
about this
could also formulate the mail to the
nist
pqc standardization list
and then we could see based on that we
can
discuss this more so
just a clarification question ignoring
post quantum is the proposal to
make ad hoc apis look more like hpke
yes okay uh i i think that sounds like a
quite a good idea because
it seems that people seem to like the
the interface in hpk so
i think the interface so what you're
saying is that it might be a good idea
even if we don't
are not sure that the future pqc
algorithms will
be a plug and play here
yes the idea of adopting to hpke is good
certainly i mean yeah the the api the
apis that
that it includes people seem to like so
that seems like a reasonable idea
[Music]
that's a good point
would you then suggest just using the
same api or using the seder code also
that
um hpka
are uh providing for
authencap and old decap i think that
would
be very possible to do but it would
definitely change the test vectors
i i guess i'm neutral um so but i i
the more like these things are i guess
that would that would help people
implementing to some extent
but again i'm neutral so yeah but i
think that might be
that might be a
then you might be able to reuse hpke
implementation for the associates would
have
might have benefits
there's a comment by tara here which i
didn't understand terry would you like
to
take this this comment about the ad
interface and how that
applies here
can you hear me now yeah yes yeah so
so i i mean ip second secret cell and
so on we had this issue with aid
algorithms
because early early days we have a
separate you know authentication and
separate
encryption algorithm i did cause some
problems
later when we every now everything is
aad algorithms
for example last ever sorry secret cell
there was lots of issues
because the interfaces don't really
support
the aad algorithms that are used now
don't really support the way that the
security is doing things so if you move
things to use
you know something that is
going to be used by future algorithms it
knows also it also makes so that we
don't actually use any features that are
not
allowed by that
sorry could you i my phone just rang
could you repeat what you you said
you heard you just began talking about
the ada
and that it was good to adopt to that
early was that their understanding it
would have been easier if you had
adopted that in earlier in about yeah
good
because we didn't do that we ended up
problems but we then started you know
start to form things in this way and
then we realized that oh
we are doing some things that we can't
actually do there with that
framework and for example the secure
cell was having did that they actually
encrypted the length which means that
before they can actually
record the pocket they have to you know
decrypt the first uh first block
before they can actually verify the hash
and aad algorithms doesn't allow that to
be done very easily
and that kind of we ended up in some
issues there
good um
christian had a a question
here on the chat how this would affect
cozy apis
with this use then hpk apis rather than
encodes the apis that's
that's a good question which i
don't have an answer to right now i
[Music]
think
so generally i think the people are
positively inclined to doing this change
yes does anyone object
i hear none so i guess we should be
doing this john
yeah let's have the working assumption
that we will
do this i think it requires a more
investigation how it will affect
different things
and which will probably result in more
discussion but
let's move ahead with
with analyzing and trying to specify
this
sounds good okay
next slide
so more ways to identify certificates
c5u and c5t
[Music]
so these are two quite different
two different issues so currently
the assumption in the addock document
is that you use x5t or x5zu
to identify a certificate x509
certificates
and if you're using a raw public key
that is
identified with a kit which the entities
shows themselves it's just a variable
length
byte string
cosy working group is planning to work
on seaboard certificate
it's in the draft charter and that would
very likely result in new identifiers
for
seabor certificates
but yeah maybe stick into so basically
the current x5t
identifier as given an example here in
the middle of the slide
is at least 14 bytes
when it's simple encoded
on the other hand a kid identifier
can be as small as one byte
when it's encoded in that hook so
there's a quite
large different and this might limit the
use of
certificates when compared to rpk and
very constrained devices
but if a raw public key in ad hoc can be
identified by a kid
as said the certificate should as well
there is no
real differences so the suggestion is to
specify
uh how that certificates
can be identified with a kid
which would lead to certificates
by reference could be as small as rpk
making them 15 51 by laura bond and five
hope
sixties uh the
the other thing with cosy certificates
would
have to wait until and if
because the working group has adopted
work on seaboard certificates
i hope not everybody is having audio
problem
like steven so
i i i agree that
you know you can construct a situation
where
you could somehow identify your less
than 256 or maybe it's even less
than that of seaboard when seabourn
coded of
um raw public keys with one byte
um but of course all the clients need to
know which byte to send
because it's arbitrary because you need
to pack them there
um at which point
um i think you've done so much work that
you would
have no use for using certificates
anyway you have such a small
number of devices and you've touched
them all
to tell them what key id to use that
there's not really a lot of
point in trying to do this with
certificate as well
i think the point of is when you're
using a certificate is because
you either have more devices or you just
don't want to have to touch them to
initialize that kid so i just don't
think it's a realistic
kind of thing to say there
and i'm sure you know the uh off
the ace off of common you're on how's it
pronounced again
that the document that we've been
working on uh which does
reference certificates out of band um
so i i don't think this is a terribly
useful optimization
in practice um that's my
instinct
so michael uh that's the ace ache
authorization you were referring to and
i think i think that it actually can be
useful in
in the sense that you are not
actually transporting the certificates
so
it still still means that you need to
understand what this
byte or a few bytes mean
but not all devices will will need to
have an encoding for all certificates
so it could still make sense to have
just a few bytes identifiers
instead of well 14 or
whatever so
i agree that it's true that not all
devices will need to understand
all certificates but i think michael's
point is that
in order to use these very short
identifiers
you need to tell the device
which byte refers to which certificate
and it's going to be different for each
device
because as you said not all devices will
need to know about all of the
certificates
and by the point that you are already
giving
a customized configuration to each
device
it seems like the the benefit from using
a certificate
as compared to if i understand correctly
just a raw public key
is very minimal because you still
have to manually give custom
configuration to each device
and the general point for using
certificates is that you don't have to
give custom configuration you can
have the pki sort of relay the necessary
information down
[Music]
would there be a benefit if devices does
not need
to support raw public key
uh raw public key and the self science
setting
is basically the same so if you want to
use
you might maybe some implementation want
to support
pki certificates and self-signed
certificates
and would not have to support a special
specific encoding for raw public keys
so so um on the device and on the sender
side
the device has to have access to its uh
private key to sign things
and it really has really has doesn't
have any clue or care
how the whether it's actually using a
raw public key or a self-signed
certificate or certificate
device just signs with its private key
right so there's not actually any code
except for whether i initialize the nx5t
with some blob
or a kid with some other blob in either
case
that blob is doesn't have to be
interpreted or created it doesn't have
to speak
asn 1 to do that it's the other end it's
the responder that has to do that and if
that other guy has got internet
and it's not constrained that it's less
of an issue so
so i don't see a difference between the
two of them for the the constrained side
of the set of the in
that device um it's again
like how do i put the right thing in it
if i've provisioned a certificate into
the device
somehow at the factory then yeah the
device could actually you know figure
out what to put into the x5 t on its own
perhaps compressing it etc so maybe it
does need some code but again that can
be actually calculated ahead of time and
put in the right place so i i don't
i don't see the advantage and we've gone
through raw public key
believing this is a panacea for iot and
i don't
i don't really see it i've never seen
why it was a
a big deal
michael going in the other direction
when
the device is going to authenticate to a
non-constrained
network node it would be a good thing if
it
doesn't have to send i mean it actually
doesn't have to send anything
right it could basically just
point to repo that would be
and i mean provide an identifier and
point to a repo
so in that case from the point of view
direction to the
to the yes to the responder yes and we
described that
in exactly so sending from that point of
view sending 14 bytes of hash doesn't
add anything
right no no and i think that the
representation we got was better and
and had better privacy implications too
um although the fact that you have to
point to the repo probably costs you
around 14 bytes anyway i mean it could
be
seven or something if you really push it
right right but then you don't need the
additional
um hash of the of the certificate so
so having a identifier in that situation
it would be useful actually
um sure it depends on how you construct
the key identifier
right because it's got to be
you have the pointer to the repo and you
have the key identifier then
you either have to someone has to decide
what that what that value is
and um that's okay but but my
point is that it's not going to be one
bite i think that was the point i was
trying to get at
is that that i don't think i don't think
it's meaningful to to be able to say i
can reduce it to one bite
in this raw public key environment and
wouldn't it be good to get certificates
that small because i don't actually
believe that one byte is a realistic uh
usable deployable situation
i think one byte is a lower
limit but hopefully the key id could be
smaller than 14 bytes
again yes i agree provided that you walk
up to every device
before you turn it on plug in a cable or
something
and tell it which three byte key id
identifier to use
right i some way you've got to tell it
that thing right
at which point you could just as well
pull the certificate out
uh and have it use a raw public key and
put that in your database because you've
got to have a database to identify to
map
the two things together right so all i'm
saying is that all the cases where a
certificate could be used with a
very small identifier that's not derived
from the certificate
then you could probably do raw public
key anyway
yeah this is basically a alternative
representation of a raw public key
instead of a koseki
yeah but again michael from the point of
view
from the point of view of the the device
proving to the network
then it is a then the network would
rather have a certificate
than a public key so in that case it's
an advantage for this point of view
more scalable to do that and
um so if you can i i it's probably more
scalable
but but most of the advantages of the
the certificate which is like that you
could change the public key or something
like that
or you can resign it or you can you can
put a
crl out saying that the thing is died
right
um all of that
you know yeah that might be useful but
again as i'm trying to say
still got to go touch the device and
give it it's it's kid
to use there sure
i i think this has works as an at least
as an option it does it's sort of
i don't see what it complicates to allow
this
and if there are not so many use cases
or if they are
these sort of the one touch type of
scenarios
well why not still have the option
yeah maybe continue this discussion on
github
so comment from
stephen that you're on slide eight
of 22.
so and that we should
prioritize what to discuss next
is there any other somebody that
might suggest them would be that we just
take
the slides in order and then we and
allow
discussion on each as much as we need
and then we move
everything else to the to in dream
uh is there anybody that wants to
discuss any
particular of the remaining issues then
we could
prioritize that issue
so we have discussed the first four
bullets
there are nine bullets remaining
i think verification of intended peer is
good and
we should probably get into the cipher
suite
sha 512 um
and the forward backwards secrecy so the
last three ones is
i think we should discuss and and
verification of intent appear that's
uh and perhaps uh the key confirmation
delivery of receipt
uh i don't think we have time at all to
discuss these
in the same amount that we have
discussed the first
bullets would you then suggest that we
take
each of them very high level five
minutes which is
not at all enough to discuss for example
forward secrecy i think
or the algorithms
okay perhaps perhaps your proposal was
best let's let's let's go through the
issues in order and schedule another
meeting if necessary
that would definitely be necessary
any more comments otherwise we move on
to verification of
intended peer then resumption then maybe
error
that is probably the only thing we will
have time to
good verification of intended peer
so this is something that was
we made some updates to the document in
the last revision based on
comments from the people doing formal
verification uh to
better illustrate what's what an
identity was
or a small set of identities
are and
and
is also let's see but
there was one comment was that maybe we
should skip the identity concept
uh totally um i
identity is in the sigma protocol which
this is very tied to
pki and a person
which might or might not be applicable
applicable directly to iot setting where
you have
devices and not persons and
also it's not clear that these
devices or services inside devices
have identities in the same way as
humans have names
sometimes you might see the public key
itself
as an identity
ad hoc have
when raw public keys are used in ad hoc
eric allows the parties to agree on an
optional
subject name similar to the subject
field in a certificate
and this subject name is included in the
mac
signature it's not sent on the buyer
and this protects against attacks
as mentioned in the sigma paper where an
attacker
successfully registered a pub
succeeds in register a public key with a
different
subject name
and then fools you when you talk to the
real owner of the public key then you
would have a wrong
subject name if you add the subject name
that you think that you know
in the mac then the connection would
fail in such a situation
so the questions here is first is
uh i think the feedback has been that
this
is from the formal verification is that
this is a very good idea
the question is will there always be a
subject name
available for example the ui 64
should we recommend
to use the subject name with the raw
public key to
even mandate using a subject name
but that depends if the subject name is
always available advice i think
should not mandate that
the document would authors would also
want
more feedback on from
people operationally doing
constrainability
how they see identities it's the
is do they see the rope the public key
itself
as the identity is there identities
available
like eui-64 and so on and also
other questions should we should we use
the word identity or should we
only talk about raw public keys and
subject names
can you talk with eui 64 are you talking
about binding it to the
actual layer 2 or layer 3 address or
it's just something that they have
that's a good question which i realized
pretty
recently and we'll bring up for
discussion in
cosi after this i
my understanding now is that it's it's
the the binding to a mac address is
deprecated
by ieee and so that's not something you
should do in the future
and that the eui-64 and then is then
identity disconnected from the network
layers
but you probably know this better than i
do
so comment from michael that is
seems like a needless complexity seems
to
and not want to definitely not want the
manatees
so discussions in the
chat section
maybe somebody maybe somebody want to
say something
instead i think there's several people
in this group that has
a lot of knowledge about the euis force
but
the question here is that they need to
think about this topic a bit more
so this direction can you hear me yeah
all right so
i think the 15-4 doesn't have any plans
of doing any kind of
you know privacy addresses yet so so the
l2
addresses are going to be same
in most of the environments what they
are doing for there is actually it
doesn't matter for some
uh cases they actually they already do
have the 16-bit you know
this local address or short addresses
which they can use for
for example if you have a already formed
network
for example a personal area network that
could use the you know
short addresses but it doesn't help that
if somebody is there when you actually
register or join the network
then they can see the l2 address is the
full 64-bit addresses
and i have no idea i have no knowledge
that
anybody would be actually thinking about
doing any work on that
chasing those
comment from dawn indicating
support of using public key as identity
from there was previously a lot of
comments about identities in
ad hoc from several
tls people the authors
would like to have subject name in law
public is at least
optional otherwise
you don't protect against these attacks
that sigma
try to protect against
then if whether they are realistic in
iot scenario or not can be discussed
and using the identity as seeing the
public key as
identity is definitely possible
in the current specification
any other
so i guess we should leave this open for
discussion on the github and
more i think so
so next is resumption
and that's also a
synergy check so previously
the protocol had resumption
then it was decided to remove the psk
method which also removed the resumption
but i
my understanding is that there was no
real discussion
whether to remove resumption or not they
just followed from removing the psk
so this issue brings this up just to
take a decision that we don't need
resumption or that we need resumption
uh so is there any need for resumption
uh resumption allows you to minimize
state
if you don't know if you will ever see
the other party again
you also get forward secrecy and
and freshness but these you can probably
get
in a cheaper way and
iot connections are long-lived so
typically
having a resumption mechanism probably
and
doing a new handshake probably cost more
than not doing this
so my suggestion
and i think the comment on
github is that resump we don't need a
resumption
method
any other
opinions regarding resumption
or can we
confirm that the adult does not need
a specific resumption method
this summary assumption could
potentially follow from
if we want to do some forward things for
forward or backward secrets or something
but we don't define any resumption just
because of
resumption
should i take the silence as a
confirmation that we
don't need to assumption can you hear me
john yes
uh hi this is mohit so i guess
if you're getting rid of the psk then
maybe getting rid of assumption is a
natural consequence
because at least in dls the resumption
is based on psk and since
uh doc has chosen not to support psk's
then i don't see like
i i i don't have strong opinion it's a
little bit sad if you're going to lose
resumption but
uh i think this is natural consequence
of then not supporting psk
mode so
yes and no i think the decision was to
not
support psk as the initial
authentication method but
as the resumption was using that like in
tls103 it disappeared
also but you you say it's
sad but is there any
any re use case
like i don't know where and like uh
where all edoc will be used hopefully in
many places and if later we find out
that there is some people who
do more frequent handshakes and don't
want to
do the full uh full handshake every time
but maybe in in this case the full
handshake is not
such a big uh performance
degradation that performing a full
handshake every time is
not such a big issue so yeah i
uh yeah i i think it's it's fine uh
to get rid of it in most situations and
if someone comes up later then we will
see it but
i can't think of some specific use case
where we would need
frequent assumptions
good then i guess the assumption is that
we
we don't need
i resumption we should um we should
consider what is coming out of the
australian session of discussions about
how we how we re-key and whether we can
re-key inside our score
if that is turning out that if it's if
the decision there
is that we can re-key easily on the
quote a record layer um then
um we don't they then we don't get a
requirement for assumption there
but if oscar says that yep please hire
layer pl
do something for us then resumption
should still be an option so
i don't think we'll have to discuss much
about this now but we should keep
the option open until we have a
re-keying mechanism for oscore
yeah i agree
so should we move on to the next slide
or
is maybe the time is running out so we
should instead
move to francesca and joran or what does
the cheerson
says say let's go for
until uh 45 past uh okay then we can
the slides of francesca and euron and
move on all the other on the all the
pending issues to the inter meeting
yep okay then next slide
i think you could go even to ten two uh
francesca asked for one minute
and and i i can i can easily do with
five minutes
good so next issue
is distinguish error message
and this was raised by a implementer i
maybe your unreme i don't remember
exactly who
but the question was how do you
distinguish that you get the error
message
and not a message
two or three or maybe even a new message
one and this is not really
discussed in the draft
looking at here on the
cdl for the two first
elements you can notice that the error
message
has a text string as the first
or second zebra item
in the sequence so
that can definitely be used to
distinguish it
from the other messages
question is is this good enough
for distinguishing or should we add
something else the well
message 2 is for example full we should
not add a single
byte to that but error message adding
some bytes would
not matter uh
irrespective of that i think the draft
should definitely add some
text on how to distinguish the error
message from the other messages
and i think it's only guidance on error
message that is missing all the other
messages
you distinguish by the connection
identifiers or by underlying
properties of the underlying network
layers
and i see there's a lot of discussion
about
identities in rpk that's great
let's summarize this
in the github it would be very thankful
it
would be great if the people writing
this could also write something in the
github
i guess otherwise maybe someone else can
summarize it
any comments about distinguishing error
message
um yeah
my take on this would be that since we
don't have any constraints and size in
the error message we
might want to add an explicit identifier
of the error message
so
that sounds good maybe we can
bounce it back to
[Music]
the peop the person implementing this
what they
how they how would they like this to
[Music]
look like if they have any preferences
and whatever we decide i think we should
have add
guidance in the draft how you
can do this
and any more comments
about adding explicit identify or
relying on text string uh
can you hear me yes yes um
i was just wondering about what militia
said do you mean
an identifier for each like for like
common types of errors
or like just an identifier saying this
is an error message and then like
the the actual error message can be
described inside the text string
i meant uh i meant the letter the letter
so essentially it's a
message yeah okay right yeah yeah i
agree with that
okay so if there are no other comments i
propose that we move on and take this
one
to github yes that sounds good
so this issue is about the encryption
in message two and this
is the encryption of the
id cred r identifier
for the credentials of r
and as discussed in sig the sigma
paper the responder sends its
identity to anybody who asks
so an attacker active attacker
can get ours identity
there is therefore no need to have in
cca encryption
i.e encryption with integrity
of this identity it's enough to only
have encryption
in cpa encryption encryption without
integrity
in this case and just as a note
everything in the message is integrity
protected by the
inner mac which is also an aad without
it's an a80 without plain text
and a problem is that cosi
only has aad algoriths so they all
have a tag and
having a tag here makes this too big to
fit the laura bond
51 byte or five hop
sixties so that was the reason
that i think ad hoc two or three
um versions ago removed
the integrity tag in message
2 on the outer
encryption because it
had no purpose and
the specific ad hoc specification today
the solution is that it
generates a long encryption key and then
form a sore cipher it source the long
key
with the plain text
and this has the benefit that it is
independent of the encryption algorithm
uh but it led to
comments both from the people doing
formal verification which has why are
you using
source cipher and they also said that
they got
comments from the reviewers of their
paper
saying why is this using source iphone
which brings to this issue uh so
how should we do this encryption without
integrity
so option one is to do like today option
two would be to
do an aad and then remove the tag
from the aad i think this works for
the current cosal grids but it in
general it does not work
for an aad that does not have a
well-defined
tag there are some such algorithms but
none of them defined for cosi
third option would to basically make a
table
where for each coca the algorithm you
assigned uh encryption algorithm without
integrity so for ccm and gcm
you would use asc's tr and for cha cha
poly
1305 you use cha-cha
and these have then the disadvantage
that you need to specify something
for if course is specified a new ada
algorithm
um and my feeling is that
to fit in laura 1 and 60s we need to we
cannot introduce the integrity
tag again it fills new purpose
and these are the three different
solutions that
i could come up with they all have the
benefits and disadvantages
i think we have to choose one of these
hmm
i think christian comment here about
difference between
two and three um might
be i'm
it might be some i don't know if you
you have different nonsense that depend
maybe on ccm and gcm so
maybe the encryption would not look
exactly
the same if you just remove the tag
as if you would specify a ctr but
um we will need to look
into that more in detail
comment from pen is to basically
dtl is doing something similar to tree
and i guess ben's suggestion would be to
do
number three
and i think we can not use
we cannot use ecb because it has
two short block lengths we would need to
use
ctr
anybody wants to say something
[Music]
about encryption or about babies
it sounds like everyone says we should
just do number three
i don't know why there's a downside of
that
no they i think that's
the the only downside is that you
basically need them a mapping so if
cosi specify a new algorithm
it might not follow
directly at least theoretically it
doesn't follow directly what you should
use but maybe in practice it follows
anyway
it seems to be a preference here for
tree i don't have any strong opinions
myself um
do we have an implementation input here
on
xor versus
counter mode
i suppose counter mode is should be fine
yeah having implemented not really
implemented the protocol but
test vectors i think they are quite
both of them would be very easy to
implement i think
okay so i propose that we continue
discussing this on the on the github
page
uh and we stop here because it's already
uh
nine till the hour yes sounds good and
people are starting discussing babies
instead so
it's a good breaking point yes so i
invite everyone to
to comment on the github issues uh
with the comments you might have in chat
and with that
uh i would uh we should move on to the
next agenda
item which is the interrupt planning so
front uh stephen can you present the
slides or
yes hello can you hear me yes
yes we hear you from jessica
i'm also gonna share my
i will see you okay
so this is just a quick
i just want to quickly talk about
implementation interrupt
and test vector status right now so
next slide please
so in version zero two zero two
of the draft we have added one more
test vector to to the draft because we
had a positive feedback about it
and so i think i don't see the slides
updating
i don't know if we're looking at
slide two
but the test vector in the document
keys and using the
x5t hash value to identify the
certificate
and then method three which is adopt
authenticated with static difficult keys
and
raw public keys encoded as kosike with a
key id used to identify the credential
and we also have a way more extensive
set of test vectors
on github at this link and
yeah implementers should be aware that
these exist
and that you can check them out and
the one in the document in appendix b of
the draft are actually
should give you more guidance about how
things are built and
and constructed but then the vectors in
the
in the github as well are
yeah should be used to to test your
implementation
and we also have test vector for our
message uh in progress
so next slide
we are starting to think about interop
so we've uh
talked about
we have contacted several people
that showed interest and that showed
that they had
maybe some implementation available and
um we are looking for more people to
participate so if you are
planning to implement or you have an
implementation and you're interested
please uh let us know right in the
mailing list contact us
and hopefully we can have something
going for december
depending on availability of
implementers as well
and we are also starting to
think about the uh the test suite which
will be based on the test vectors
um so yeah we will keep everybody
aware of this effort in the lake mailing
list but if you want to
participate it's also good if you come
to us
or write in the mailing list and that's
all i wanted to say okay thanks
francesca
so uh we should follow up on this on the
mail english definitely this is an
interesting topic
uh but since we are very close to the
end of the meeting i propose
we move on with the slides that euron
uh had prepared uh on
related work stephen could you present
that
[Laughter]
okay
yes here they are uh
yep can you hear me yes yes
okay so yeah this is just uh just
information
um lake meeting is almost over
but there are more topics related to
lake
at this meeting so
the cozy meeting falling right after the
break will speak about
seaborne coding of x519 certificates and
identification as we mentioned
we discussed this previously it's not
decided whether it's relevant or not but
if you're interested that's uh that's
the
that's the slot for for that topic uh
on tuesday uh there is a slot descri
in the core working group looking at the
draft
for combining auto ad hoc and escort
head how can we score in one message and
also in core
on friday is the discussion about
re-keying
as was mentioned there's also the ace
working group on
wednesday the two drafts are related to
how to use ad hoc for authorization
uh to add authorization to ad hoc and
also to add
certificate enrollment and there is a
charter discussion
where one of the topics for potential
new work items
is around authorized access to raw
public keys
using the authorization framework so
that would be a way of
of kickstarting ad hoc next slide please
thanks so just just for illustration
since i like colors i put together this
example
using the drafts of the of the previous
slide and how how they could be combined
this is just one example they are not
really they don't need to combine them
this way
but so just quickly on the colors here
you can do ad hoc which is the blue oh
this is an example about the device
joining
network assisted by a third party
authorization
server and also doing certificate
enrollment
uh request and and response
so this is uh with this this is what i
think a little bit what
michael was mentioning referring to um
we have the authentication in blue here
that's the ad hoc messages123
there are the black messages which is
the oscar request response
and they contain the est payloads
uh which are uh in this case
uh it's a significant this is a simple
enrollment
method so it's the sen and
it's the request is a cbor encoded
certificate signing request
and you get back a c board certificate
or a reference there too
as described in this green green
reference
and the combination of oscore and ad hoc
is that's the yellow box
and the third-party optional third-party
assisted authorization is the red
red blob so i don't go through this in
detail but if you're interested
then go to the corresponding working
group and
and have yeah raise your raise your
opinion
so that was it for me thank you okay
thank you
so just uh before wrapping up uh
we are on top of the hour but i would
just like to discuss the next steps
and since we did not cover all the
issues in the today's meeting
uh i propose that we have an interim
meeting so now the question is whether
we would like to have the meeting
before or after the holidays
so i welcome any comments
so joran uh would like committing before
the holidays marco agreed to that
do we have any other opinions
michael agrees with that as well so it
seems we
okay and john okay so it seems we have
consensus that
we should have an interim meeting before
the holidays
after the u.s thank giving as michael
proposes so essentially beginning
mid-december uh from what i can gather
uh so let's make it uh
let's make an action point for chairs to
to schedule this
meeting uh soonish and with that
i would like to thank you for attending
the today's meeting
i also thank michael for note-taking
and so maybe put it just at the end of
planned interrupt
so okay we still don't have a date on
interrupt michael so
i wouldn't tie it to that but i will try
to coordinate with francesca and maybe
link the two together
uh so thank you everyone thank you for
attending see you
on the uh for the rest of the week and
talk to you on the mailing list and
github pages
bye
you