those slides are good to people
just verifying the share works
hey folks just getting ready to go
the jabber room is not working and i
just sent a chat to
uh here at medeco and nothing showed up
i believe the uh ietf jabra server is
down right now
yeah that might explain it
seems like we should use mls instead no
well mls doesn't create any chat
functionality it just
creates another opportunity for the chat
not to work
more failure points lots of failure
points in mls
no infinite regress john what
still figuring it out yes i really want
to share my screen what do i want to do
the uh mp3 audio stream is not working
either
not sure if that goes over the same
portion of the infrastructure
in the meantime we need a note taker
just looking through the participant
lists jonathan lennox jonathan hoyland
maybe
my alertness at local 4am is not
fabulous but i could
give it a try
is there anything to do if the jumper is
down
well not taking is still i have to do
something
they say they're working on the jabber
and they'll let us know when it's up
yeah the kodi md is still up so in terms
of
recording group decisions
uh and taking notes
uh about conversations the note taker is
still useful
so jonathan lennox if you want to open
it up
and uh record the decisions that would
be
fantastic
yeah i've got it open
okay i think i've pressed enough buttons
to make this work
there's this is this going to go into
the right thing are you guys seeing the
slides
yeah okay yeah
all right i think we're here let's do
this
um welcome to mls meeting um it's
thursday hopefully you guys have seen
all this stuff
um turn your video off
uh meet your microphone unless you're
speaking obviously you made it here at
meat echo
i don't know if the audio is gonna work
uh if it's only but
uh and the jabber i think is down as
well so i think we're just gonna plow
ahead and we'll deal with it later
uh here's the no well obviously we're
recording the session
um jabber is back up sean oh great cool
um there's the address there mls at
jabra.iotf.org
um i believe that the um chat
in meet echo actually we're lazy to
jabber so if anybody is in jabber land
and does
like do a mic colon um please feel free
to jump in and um
uh you know relay that for me
and nick as well um again here's the
notewell uh basically
you know uh put rules and policies to
play along with the itf
um we're recording it be polite you know
uh you know of any apr you're supposed
to disclose it um
again it's thursday so hopefully you've
seen this this is us
i'm sean turner nick is here as well
um our agenda is pretty straightforward
we're going to go through some minus
trivia
we're going to have an architecture
update um and then the rest of the time
we're going to do with the protocol
um richard uh lets me know the chances
of us going to full two hours is
somewhat minimal
so that might be good so everyone can
get back in bed so we're just basically
just gonna jump over
he's got some slides i've uploaded them
um and bedroom and also gave me some
slides in the architecture
so we're gonna go through uh
status actually i should jump back i
fell off
is there a minute taker
yes i'm in the cody md and if anybody
wants to join me
awesomely thank you thank you very much
jonathan um so the status basically the
architecture draft we're going to talk
about that we're basically waiting for a
new version
um the mls protocol draft i guess
technically is no longer in working
group last call it ended yesterday
um and the uh federation draft we had
has expired
but i'm hoping that we'll we'll we'll
get back to that after we get the
protocol document kind of up the
out of the way so for those of you not
everyone in this working group is like
immersed in the iatf uh you know know
about the process and what's going on
but i wanted to kind of outline the
timeline for what's going on now
um we just completed working group last
call since that little bubble there
about uh we are here
um the plan is is that we are going to
publish a draft 11
which addresses all known comments and
then we're going to have a feature
freeze where we're going to let the
security researchers
kind of beat on things for a little bit
we haven't quite decided how long that's
going to be but i think it's going to be
long enough that we can get multiple
multiple sets of researchers to actually
provide us some input
so they can get a kind of a warm and
fuzzy that um
we are offering the properties that we
say we are given the right choices
i suspect they will find something so
there will be another draft though
there's
a draft 12 of the question mark um i'm
betting that we'll find something
um then we'll make some tweaks um if we
make tweaks that are substantial enough
we need to run another working group
last call
um uh and then after that there's
probably some
i'm sure there's some editorial thing
that'll pop out so we'll have a draft
13.
um now the nice thing about where we get
to it if we get to a draft 13
if we've had this analysis it makes
things a lot easier for the ad and later
for us when we have to deal with
comments
because the the document will be
reviewed by
more than just the people in the working
group it's actually going to be other
people
security researchers will make sure it's
clear that the the document's doing what
it says it's going to do
but our a.d ben is going to do a review
and then whatever he tells us to make
changes to
we will discuss with him we'll make some
changes and we'll have a draft 14
and then after that it goes into what's
called the ietf last call it'll be two
weeks
um and then you know
i suspect there will probably be some
other uh
procedural things that we maybe miss you
never know maybe we'll get lucky and we
don't need a draft 15 but a lot of times
this is where you get cross area review
so there's directors that will kick off
like jen aren't they'll tell us we did
our iana considerations wrong or
something and
we'll fix it um and then after that it
goes to
um isg review
all of the area directors from the itf
will take a review
they will uh find even more things and
we'll probably do another draft 16 to
try to get
get through them um once we're there
basically it gets approved
and gets dumped into the rfc editor
queue then there's a process at the very
end of that called off
48 which is where basically it's copy
editing but sometimes they find other
things so there will be there will be
other changes that come out of the draft
um come out of the process sorry they
end up resulting in a draft and at the
end we're gonna have an rc
um the process after we get from area
director review to an rfc
um it's probably three months so i think
we're looking at
you know six to nine months away before
we could
we could realistically get an rfc number
out and be done
are there any questions on that
hey uh this has been paid up to 80 i
think the three months from 80 to review
from 80 review to rfc might be a little
optimistic the
rfp production center is like still
dealing with this giant
cluster of webrtc stuff no it's still
doing 238
yeah i mean most of it is in off 48 but
there's
there's still some uh knockoff effects
basic
knock-on effects basically all right
well fair enough i mean i think it's
it's good because basically it still
gives people additional time to review
things
and i mean i think the nice thing is
that we're we're basically following the
tls
um kind of pattern and i think it's good
because
when we get after the feature freeze and
analysis and we actually get review
chances are we'll we'll we'll find most
of the big things there's a chance that
we can find
other things that are worthwhile to
change later but at that point the bar
is pretty high and then other people
that we have to convince that we're
changing and not breaking everything
is also higher um so i think it's it's
basically good
and all right that's it so now i guess
i'm going to hand over
to richard
oh sorry to benjamin so where did
thought i thought we were doing
architecture first
yeah or maybe whatever you play
fractured it's fine
now go ahead benjamin because the the
protocol stuff i think can expand to
fill time
sure okay let me try to
screen can you see that
can you see my screen right now not
quite yet i think uh
the chairs have to allow you
oh yes i think i'm doing that
it's good i did upload these slides as
well yep
it's a stupid ios thing
where you you have to actually like you
know log in and stuff like this so sorry
about that
do you have actually my slide showing
maybe it's easier there is only one
slide anyway
i contact you
can you hear me now
yeah i still can't hear you uh we can
hear you
okay okay i can hear you know sorry um
technical things yeah so okay let me
jump in now
thank you uh so the the idea was that
a few months back we sent an email to
the main english saying that we are
gonna
do an editorial pass collectively on the
architecture documents
and uh the timeline shifted obviously
because of
multiple things covered and the delay in
the protocol document as well
the idea was like basically we could
sort of go back to the architecture
documents once the the protocol document
was stable
but i think we are pretty in pretty good
shape to actually
look at it now so the chairs ask the
editors to actually take a pass on the
architecture
document which will which i'm doing
right now
and ask for the other editors to review
the idea is that basically i want to
have something stable by december 7th so
that people can sort of
input from that point so um
i don't think there are many many uh
actual things to discuss
we are gonna pretty aggressively as sean
mentioned in in the
mailing list we are pretty aggressively
gonna close
issues and uh try to solve them of
course
but uh like
allow people uh and encourage people to
to do a pass on the architectural
document after december 7.
so the idea is basically we expect uh
i mean i expect depending on what the
chairs think is good idea but i
i would expect that between beginning of
december and under january we have
something
like uh everybody feeling issues and
reviewing
uh producing pr's for the documents
and that we can recurse on that multiple
times until we we have something that's
uh
that's good but i expect that the
changes to the architecture document are
pretty limited
it's more uh typically um
what we're interested in here is the the
fact that we are missing some things
like with
the dms protocol is quite big right it's
complicated so we
we definitely miss important information
or insights
on the protocol
and especially in the arctic
architecture document sorry
and we want to describe very clearly uh
the security the security guarantees
that we expect
uh with much more precision than we have
right now so right now we have something
very generic which is like oh yeah by
the way this protocol
wishes to provide uh forward secrecy
across epochs
forward secrecy for application messages
uh post compromise security across
epochs
uh things like this but it actually
depends on many things right it actually
depends on people updating regularly
on people sharing or not sharing their
identity keys things like this are
actually left to the application
for the protocol document so the
architecture
at least should mention what are the
pros and cons of
doing such things like using signature
keys not using them
updating frequently or not updating
frequently
the idea still is that we
want this document not to have normative
language as much as possible so i
suspect we will be able to do it
like only based on recommendations
because
uh the protocol the core protocol
document contains every requirement
that's needed for for to provide the
security guarantees that we
would like to have but uh you know like
people have looked at it we have done
security analysis
of the protocol and we know that
depending on what you do exactly there
are some slight differences in terms of
security guarantees so we want to
actually
make make those guarantees and
expectations very precise in the
architectural documents
without without mandating anything in
some sense it's going to be an
information of
what's the what the protocol should give
and there is missing discussion on
application
metadata and server assist so server
assist i believe we've discussed
previously
a potential document that rafael and i
would write
on server assist because for those dude
that were at
new york for the interim engineering uh
we
i a few colleagues of mine rafael and i
also looked at um the general
architecture of a
messaging infrastructure like this and
we could notice that there are many many
different
aspects in terms of privacy that that
are affected by the actual
infrastructure
um so
we don't want like this document will
not be able to moderate anything
right in terms of infrastructure but
it's
it will be it will be able to provide
guidance the services documents on
maybe this solution is one possible
solution to actually provide some
reasonable privacy guarantees in your
infrastructure
and i believe that we should do that
after the architecture document is done
so that
i mean at least it's stable so that
we can focus on federation and serve
their assists after
uh like in q1
q probably in q1 and of q1 something
like this
um so yeah that's it for me i think i
think
after december 7 and end of january
sounds good i don't know what you think
uh
sean and and uh nick but um
[Music]
it feels like pretty reasonable so that
people don't have to work in the
like at christmas and use new year's eve
things like this we can have the full
january months
there is no urgency for that document
anyway but i think it's
completely fair to get back to it right
now
so yeah expect uh i guess expect an
email from us
around january 7th something like this
i think that works um yeah i mean if you
drop it
like mid december no one's gonna look at
this until the beginning of the
of the new year so i think i think take
your time
and uh you know get it as close as
possible and then we'll let the
death by a thousand paper cuts happen
via github
it is what it is the only thing i would
add to your summary is that uh
in terms of getting to getting through
the process the only way that like the
follow-on process
like to get through the isg is going to
be able is going to happen when we
actually get
the architecture and protocol document
together and get them moving forward so
they'll probably go forward as a package
so i think it kind of it makes sense so
all right thank you very much
i thank you i'm just
i believe i have granted richard the
screen
interesting i do not see that permission
myself
let me stop sharing my screen let's see
if i can now grant you there we go there
we go there we go
all right is that visible
it's all of its bright pinkness i
figured i'd use a little bit of a
you know visual energy to keep people
awake uh across time zones
so this is going to be an update on the
latest stuff on the protocol it's going
to be blend of me
and uh raphael and joelle all of whom
from looking at different aspects here
um we're going to go through kind of
what we've gotten done recently for
folks who might not have been
tracking along in detail we got a couple
of kind of major issues that joelle
and rafael are going to present um
fortunately though they're
significant and have some security
implications we have
solutions that are pretty
straightforward so hopefully we can get
those agreed here
then if we have time there's a couple of
other minor stuff we might pull up on
github
i'll probably let sean drive that part
so just diving into
the highlights of recent stuff
one major change here um is we've kind
of improved
how we do authentication on mls
plaintext this is a symmetric
authentication of membership in the
group
uh and a confirmation that it commits uh
produced
the right output so the confirmation
that the recipient of a commit got the
same output at that sender did
um we had had this confirmation tag
hanging around for a while we called it
a tag now
moved it to the end so that it covers
the signature as well
this is due to some work i think that uh
joelle did with uh
athena yost and martin lunarchik
um finding some some issues with not
covering that signature with the
confirmation tag
so that simplifies the structure a
little bit simplifies that little select
statement and
gets some better security moving the
confirmation tag down
that same group also noticed some issues
that um
if you get an mls plain text uh you know
you get a signature on it on the left
hand side
but you don't get any authentication the
signer is actually in the group
until you um uh
accepts to the degree that you you look
at the verification key
in your group tree so immediately you
don't get any
authentication that the sender knows the
group secret so if someone you know
compromised the signing key but not
the group secrets then they could send
these mls plaintexts into the group
so this membership tag is just a mac
over everything
uh proceeding that uh
authenticates that's the center of the
most plain text is a member of the group
so you can verify that before you do
anything else
with a message and folks folks by the
way should feel free to stop uh
step uh jump in if there's uh questions
or comments here
um second thing to highlight um
pre-shared keys is really good
oh yeah uh sorry so it's so
the the the problem you mentioned is
actually only in the case where you
don't encrypt the the preparation
messages right
because in that way if you include them
you you you have this authentication
guaranteed like it's a weak one but it's
you you have it
yeah so when you're when you're
encrypted when you're sending mls
ciphertext on the wire you get the
authentication from the aead tag
um so this is only for the case where
mls plaintext is what you're sending on
the wire
so do you so i remember that the
phrasing is
relatively relaxed right now in the
document where we say we
could i think send plain text and not
encrypt them
why you still it's still reasonable
yeah no i think i think we are going to
have use cases where we don't want to
encrypt the
uh handshake message of the mls messages
um and so i think it is important to
continue to support that
um and it's that means we do have to
kind of have a switch
in the code um because you're not going
to have one of these uh membership tags
for an mls plaintext you've decrypted
from this mla ciphertext
but i think that that's tolerable it's
not a huge amount of complexity
okay thank you sure thanks
um second cool thing uh thanks to some
good work from rita hale
and conrad cobrook um we have a new
nice psk framework um it works more or
less like you'd expect
um people someone who wants to add a psk
at an epoch
um sends out a proposal um you can get
multiple those proposals so we have a
scheme for
combining multiple psks and then they
get injected into the key schedule
as you're transitioning from one uh the
last xbox in its secret to the current
epochs
epoch secret um
really the novelty here is this proposal
mechanism um
and there's a corresponding signaling
welcome um i think this is kind of nice
because it
incorporates you know it's kind of
inspired by the tls13 design where you
have psk ids and
kpsks and incorporates some learnings
from
recent tls and follow on work213
so we have i think one thing that has
been done more recently and tls is
folks trying to introduce structured
labels so you can have specific
labels that have internal structure for
specific use cases um we're building
that in from the start here
um and uh i think
jonathan hoyland has done some work on
looking at um and also
stability and the post quantum folks
looking at how you incorporate multiple
psks or multiple entry sources
into the key schedule so we're trying to
capture all that good advice good
experience here
and incorporate it in round one of mls
so that's pre-shared keys um the only
thing i would add there is that um that
was a
an exercise in patience on uh britain
conrad's part that they
they um thrust and parried and finally
got the stuff done so it was good to see
the working group uh
finally got that that this uh this stuff
incorporated
yeah i i and i owe them a massive mia
culpa i
uh i imposed a lot of delay and made
them uh explain a bunch of stuff to me
over and over again
um but i think we ended up in a finally
in a really good place
i appreciate their work here um
one thing that came up is kind of a this
is a kind of a bit of a performance
improvement
um you know before the center of a
proposal could send out a bunch of
i'm sorry the center of a commit could
send alongside that a bunch of proposals
um and those proposals would each be
individually signed in their own
envelopes plain text
this change with this change
those proposals can just go directly in
the commit um
and so you save a lot of signature
overhead a lot of bandwidth overhead
and just send the proposals in line
now syntactically with that you know we
wanted to preserve this property that we
have a single proposals array so it's
clear
what order the proposals are applied in
um
and so what we did is just change that
array of proposals from being a
list of references to proposals by hash
to a list of proposal or references so
you can get the proposal by value
or by reference so we maintain that
ordering
but we can indicate things by value or
by reference
um so this lets the committer just send
along a bunch of stuff
to apply um as part of that commit um
so you can imagine that if the committee
wanted to say sentence um
add a psk as part of the commit you just
add the
that proposal to the end of the
proposals vector
this simplifies in particular some of
the external commit stuff which
raphael will talk about in a moment
and another this is kind of consistent
with another idea
that we discussed earlier that
um the kind of design principle that
the way you extend the commit message is
with new proposal types as opposed to
having extensions
uh in the commit message itself so
you know being able to put proposals
directly in the commit message
kind of makes clear that that's is
consistent with that design principle
so it's it's basically mostly an
optimization list of securities and
these other things
but i kind of nice
from an implementation point of view
um some more uh focused things um
didn't pull these out onto one's um
major slides um
one implication of the psk work that was
done
is that we can kind of we can do
subgroups and read in it
so when you generate a subgroup
much like with i think there's a nice
analogy to to tls and resumption here
that the key schedule produces
resumption secrets and
you can use those secrets to connect one
group state to other group states so
branching
is one instance of that where you want
to instantiate a subgroup or
a related group you can pull that
resumption psk
out of the prior group and then and
insert it into the uh
subgroup or the branch group likewise if
you're going to reinitialize the group
to say upgrade the cipher suite or
upgrade to a new protocol version
then you can tie the new group to the
old group again using this resumption
psk
so that's kind of a nice application of
the psk work that was done
um more optimization work on the third
bullet here um
the ratchet tree for these cases where
the the delivery service might cache
some of the tree information
um based on say plain text uh
handshake messages if the server is
following along
then it can provide the tree and it
doesn't need to be provided end to end
in the welcome
so the welcome just provides a
commitment to the tree not the tree
itself it can optionally include the
tree in an extension
just a performance optimization there um
more work from uh alberta and conrad
this authentication secret derived from
the key schedule this provides kind of a
um yeah in a lot of apps today you have
these security codes that are
that people can compare uh to verify
that they have the same crypto state
um so here we can just um since we have
this framework for deriving stuff with
the
off the key schedule we can just derive
another value off the key schedule that
can be used for that purpose so you can
compare this and
you know you're in the you know if
everyone in the group has the
um same authentication secret then they
know that they have
exactly the same crypto state for that
state of the group
and finally there's been some concerns
off and on about deniability
um sophia chile
did some review on this and proposed one
one change to improve compatibility with
deniability going forward which is to
have a little bit of decoupling between
the signing keys that are
in the in the mls transcript and the
signing keys that are used for
for verifying messages that landed after
draft 10 but it's it's
in master right now
uh finally a couple of uh you know
efficiency improvements
we had had this constant time ad
i can't remember if that yeah i think
that was before before we
made the switch to proposal commit um we
had constant time add
where you could um you know you didn't
have to change anything about the tree
besides the leaf
um we
re-added that in um
in draft 10 um forgetting the details of
how that was done
um but you know now ads can be kind of
gonna be done in constant time you don't
have to um
all right this is this is uh where we
made the the the update path in the
commit
the thing that takes you log to linear
time to generate log linear number of dh
operations or
h chem operations um
you can omit that path you can not
um
[Music]
have a new entropy to the group if the
only thing you are doing is adding
because everyone can just hash forward
so yeah that gets us back to this um
uh notion of constant time ad um
another optimization is that this this
update path in the commits
um used to encrypt new entropy to the
entire group for the new epoch including
the people you just added even to those
people
uh were getting the information from the
welcome not the commit so the update
path
had useless encrypted secrets and so um
we're omitting that now because they're
just not necessary
um and finally we consolidated the key
schedule a little bit we used to have
separate uh
key derivation schemes for uh encrypting
application messages versus encrypting
handshake messages
and now we use the same secret tree for
both of those so um
you can delete a bunch of code that was
managing that second
key derivation scheme so that's the
review
of what we have done recently
um i think i'd like to pass it over to
joelle here to talk about
um some issues that that he and his team
uh discovered with
uh the current uh hashing scheme we have
for authenticating the tree
to drill intake over here
all right uh just before we do that so
this is one of the issues that got
called out during working group last
call that we hadn't
um uh uh come to conclusion on
were there was there anything else that
you saw that came up that needs to be
addressed
um i have not done
i i should do one more review of the
mailing list but i don't think i saw
anything come up
that was that needed to be addressed in
in the next draft
okay excellent thank you sorry joel
joelle are you awake see you in the
participant list
you can click the microphone button to
send audio
while i have two seconds before join
um there is one section that was
mentioned multiple times but we didn't
really address
and we should definitely decide whether
we are going to address it or not
is the application message location
thing
so right now and an attacker can
actually like i
would hardly remove messages at the end
of the application messages hello is
everybody actually knowing
gerard we do hear you we do here
and uh yeah that's something we should
discuss
at some point that's it because this is
a remaining issue as well
yeah that's a good point we um
i think we did have issues for that and
i'm not sure why
i may have erroneously closed them um
but i think we should make a clear
decision about that maybe we should have
a call
i think we can see if we have time on on
in this session but if not we should um
schedule a call in the next couple weeks
to close out on that
so joelle one more time we were hearing
you before um
but i think you turned your mic back off
okay um i hear you i hear you now
all right good i guess some reason i
can't hear anybody else when i talk
but i guess sean gave me a thumbs up
which means i guess you can hear me
uh okay well i'll keep talking
but uh if if there's a question then
sean just wave and i'll
turn and turn off the sound so that i
can actually hear other people okay
um thanks
uh richard do you think i think you're
still screen sharing so do you think you
could just go to the next slide
um
you know yeah on further thought that
was it
all right okay so
uh yeah so this is basically what
this this concerns um a feature called
parent hash
which um was originally introduced
um by uh karthik and
benjamin um when they pointed out that
we need to be able to authenticate this
tree in particular to give guarantees to
people joining the group
right um and so what we did is or what
they did at the time is they introduced
this notion of a parent hash
that hashes uh a part of the tree
and you end up with actually a sequence
of parent hashes each node has its own
parent hash to find and then you put the
the last one down the leaf every time
you're doing an update path and then you
sign your entire leaf and that includes
the parent hash and so in so doing
you're kind of authenticating certain
stuff in the tree
but then there was some amount of debate
um
around how exactly to define this parent
hash
and um at the time there were
then kind of two candidates and we um
went with
one um which hatched in less um because
we were hoping it would maybe give us
then a bit more deniability because at
the end of the day you do sign this
parent hash so the more that it binds
the more you're sort of committing to
aspects properties of the group
and um so we really revisited this we
being
um daniel jost and um martin mullarczyk
in our security review of mls and
we found actually that there's um
there's a
this opens a class of attacks on mls
the way that parent hash was defined in
this minimal way
so um we then proposed a pr
that addresses this attack so this is
basically what i'm going to tell you
about now
you can go to the next slide please
okay so first i'll tell you a little bit
about what the attack is
because that's really going to motivate
them the changes as well
um so first the the way that the
the whole the parent hash has been
defined up till now this sort of more
minimal way of doing
we've defined it in the past it's
basically when you do an update path so
you're doing a commit
you're inserting a bunch of keys on your
direct path
and you pretty much just hash back down
to your leaf again
only those hpk public keys right so
um here on the top left we've got a
picture of a small group with alice bob
and charlie alice just did
the most recent commit that's why her
direct pass is mark blue
and so in particular she would then hash
first the root hpk public key that she
put in
and then she'd hash in um the parent
node between alice and bob and then she
would at the end hashing her own
uh no actually i think she wouldn't even
do that she'd just you know just
just take that hash from uh the parent
that includes hpk
key it's apparent to the root and then
she put that under leaf and she'd sign
the whole thing
so the issue with this kind of in a
nutshell is that it really doesn't tell
you anything about
who was told these
secret keys that correspond to these hpk
public keys in other words
it makes it easy to or possible to
um create ratchet trees that violate the
two
invariant which leads to other bad
things things
like removes not really working as if
you think you removed somebody but in
reality you didn't really remove them
from the group so here's an example of
this like a
sort of pretty minimal example of how
this attack would work
um bob is our attacker so this is about
insiders all right this attack would be
mounted by an insider somebody who's
actually a participant in a legitimate
group
and the legitimate group is at the top
left it contains alice bob and charlie
right now let's did the most recent
commit as we said so here's what bob
does bob constructs a fake ratchet tree
like an artificial one
and um so it's it's a fake group
and it's the top right ratchet tree and
then
he invites dave who's the victim of this
attack to this ratchet period okay
so in other words we now um
one of the main thing to notice is that
the way he constructed this tree is he
took this direct path from alice which
is a legit
direct path but then instead of putting
himself where he was in
the actual group he switched out and put
charlie there
right and then he put himself
in charlie's spot then creates this
proposal to add dave
and commits to it so you end up with
this other this this other ratchet tree
over here
which looks legit because all the parent
hashes still
work out right um in particular you'll
see
you know alice's direct path has been
maintained
so hope her the signature at her leaf
is gonna verify for dave same thing for
charlie bob can sign whatever he wants
at his leave
um and so dave is going to accept this
welcome message and he's going to join
this group
but of course the attack where things
have started to go wrong here is that
bob
actually knows the hpk secret of alice's
parent because in the real group that's
also on his direct path
but in this fake group it looks like
it's not he doesn't know it it's not on
his direct path
so the next thing he does is he now you
know gets tells dave hey look i want to
leave this group
and gets dave to commit to removing bob
so in the removal process how does that
work well we blank bob's
you know dave announces this uh this
commitment and then
everybody will everybody being only dave
because alice and charlie
you know aren't even aware of this group
will blank bob's
leaf key and then
which means it'll leave that node
alice's parent node intact it'll leave
the same hpke key there
which bob actually knows the secret to
and in particular it even encrypts the
rude secret to that
so bob can actually still decrypt this
new rude secret this this
commit secret and so he can compute the
new key schedule for this new epoch
despite the fact that
dave thinks he's removed bob from the
tree in other words
this turned into an attack where a
removal did not actually have the effect
we would expect and the real problem
here is that bob was able to create a
tree that violated
the tree invariant that was really the
cause of this attack
so this whole class of attacks you can
do a couple different things with this
but this is the core and the problem is
that the signature at alice's leaf which
includes this parent hash
doesn't authenticate enough it doesn't
bind in who alice
told each one of these new hpk secrets
to
so this is what we address with this pr
um
next slide
so what's the intuition to fix here i've
been trying to sort of
you know lead the thought pattern here
with what i've been saying but
the idea is basically we want to extend
what goes into the parent hash
so that it at least indirectly includes
for each node that's included in the
parent hash which other
secrets uh which other people received
the secret key
right we we actually figured out that
you can do this a little more indirectly
maybe for reasons of deniability or just
simplicity
really and it's enough to just include
into the parent hash
every time you want to include an hpk
public key of a node covered by a parent
hash
you also include the resolution of
the sibling on the co-path right so
that's exactly that correspond so
actually the hpk keys of this resolution
that corresponds exactly to
the keys to which the hpk
secret is being sent right so the set of
public keys
to which the parent's private key was
encrypted too so we augment the
definition of parent hash with this
um and otherwise we still keep the same
things in which is basically just all
the new public keys that are being put
into the tree on the direct
path itself next slide please
so here's a here's a pictorial
depiction you know we have a
small tree um with three three leaves
and this shows how you would compute
parent hash if leaf two does a commit
all right so that means leaf two has
inserted new keys at node one
and node 3 on node 2 as well and so now
it comes time to compute the parent hash
and the way it works is
these red arrows indicate which values
you're putting into the hash
when you compute the parent hash at a
node right so you look at node one it's
got this parent hash
well just as before you include the
public key of its parent i.e
the root and the parent hash value at
the root which is simply defined to be
zero by the way for the root as a
special case
um but now in addition that's how things
were up till now
but now in addition you also include the
resolution
at node four all right and that sort of
binds
into this parent hash value not just the
fact that oh
this is the key uh at node three but
also
where did you send the secret key
corresponding to that key where did
where did
the person at least two send it they
sent it to the resolution of node four
right so that's the parent hash at node
one and then the parent hash at node two
you do the same thing recursively right
so you include the public key and parent
hash of node 1
and the resolution of like who did who
was that sent to well it was sent to the
resolution of zero which in particular
is just the public key of zero itself
so um that's kind of the intuition of
how it works
um but of course there's a little bit of
a caveat here which is
um if you see the name of the
[Music]
field in the data structure um we called
it original
sibling resolution and that's because
the following
thing this makes this is all clean and
simple at the time of a commit but of
course
the whole point of these parent hashes
is that five epochs later when somebody
joins the group
gets a welcome message they want to
verify these parent hashes
which means they should be recomputing
the parent hashes
right so you got to make sure that when
you recompute the parent hash for a
given node say node 1
that you'll end up with the same value
as the person
as as did the person at the time who who
put it into the tree namely
the person at least two and in the
meantime
in these intermittent father blocks
things can change in the tree
right there's constantly the tree's
constantly changing in every epoch
so we have to make sure that the way we
define these parent hatch is invariant
to any change to the tree which will
preserve the public key at node one
because the moment the moment the the
public key at node one changes
we don't care about recomputing the same
parrot hash anymore
so it only has to be this definition of
parenthesis only has to be invariant to
changes of the tree that don't affect
the public key at node one how can it be
affected well either node one can be
blanked
yep questions so
oh yeah sorry joel um just a quick
clarification
uh here i think this is i haven't quite
verified this
to convince myself totally but i think
we're kind of okay here
because the parrot hashes are all sort
of downward looking they only
um incorporate stuff incorporate the
parent stuff but they only
are kind of visible lower in the tree so
here for example
if um four updated and overwrote nodes
four and three then
uh the hashem note and node one would no
longer verify node three but
that's already kind of accounted for in
the validation algorithm
you would still be able to validate that
um you know the signature over the
parenthesis node two
uh verified the parenthesis node one
which then would
verify the both the public key in node
one
and the uh resolution in node zero so
you still
kind of have that invariant so i
actually think that this that we're
pretty safe
on this consistency count
over yeah i mean i agree i think we are
safe
in the sense that it works out i think
the one case
so the most changes you make to the tree
are either going to end up
you know um uh blanking
or or re-ending up with the re-key in
which case we don't care about
preserving the parent hash computation
the only case i think that's interesting
if you add unmerged leaves right
so say we were now we we compute the
parent hash at one
because two just committed right and now
the next thing that happens is
a new guy is added to the new person's
added to the group as leaf5
right technically that means now that
the resolution of node 4 has changed
because there's a new unmerged leaf that
gets included in the resolution
right but it turns out that the same
unmerged leaf is also going to be added
as an unmerged leaf at three
so the more general no definition we
have a parent hash
which collapses to the same thing and
the commit moment but later on
may be important this generalization is
what you actually take is the resolution
of the co-path node
but then you take out the nodes which
are unmerged at the parent
so when you're computing parent hash is
one you take
the resolution of four and you remove
anything that's unmerged at three
so now if you were to add
a fifth leaf yes it gets added to the
resolution of four but it would get
removed again because it's also an
unmerged leaf of three so you end up
with the same with the original
resolution of four that you had at the
time before five was added
so that's the only sort of tricky tricky
bit and that's that's the way that it's
actually defined and that's why
the field is called original sibling
resolution
um yeah
so yeah that's basically the definition
i don't know is there another slide i
forgot
no okay good well then i think if
there's no questions and i guess that's
that
so i think what i'd like to get here is
uh any
concerns people have with this general
approach because
if folks are okay with this general
scheme
um you know don't have any of the
concerns that we had back in
in january then joel and i can work out
the details
in the pr just want to make sure the
group is okay with this
general approach um you know kind of in
concept
see raphael and benjamin yeah so
pretty much anyway i mean the current
status of the draft is that it's
insecure right
and what joel is bringing us is
immediately stronger anyway
so i'm completely in favor of
taking that right now and anyway we have
the security analysis period so that we
can validate that
that's a good fix and things like this
so
i don't see any reason to not take it in
some sense
rafael did you ever come in here you
just uh queued up no i was just getting
ready for the
next slide the the only comment i have
is i think that i'm channeling
um brendan macmillan here is that um we
didn't make this change or really
consider this earlier because there
wasn't an attack and so since
joel found it and we got a fix i don't
see a reason why we wouldn't include
this so basically just
echoing what benjamin said so let's
let's make it so
okay cool so i will work with joel to
to figure out the the nuances but we'll
it'll be pretty much the solution
all right so next uh i want to pass over
to raphael to talk about
the external commit mechanism that we
added in draft 10
and um one issue that we were resolving
during last call
so raphael yeah yeah thanks
richard for uh driving the slides um
yeah so this is something that um
had been there for a while as a problem
um so i can talk a little bit about the
motivation here
we covered that extensively in the
interim meetings but i think it's good
to repeat it here
so essentially in the architecture
document we say that at no point in time
two devices of the same group ever have
to be
online at the same time and technically
that's true
that sensor protocol is asynchronous but
when somebody wants to join
um the the problem was that
one of the existing members had to send
a welcome message
to the new member in order for the new
member to be able to join the group
and intuitively that seems correct
because you want the
existing members to guard who gets
access to the group
um but it turns out that
you don't have to rely on this welcome
mechanism necessarily
in order to keep the same logic
so there are cases where it would be
very beneficial
if members can just join without having
to
wait for an existing member to come
online
and issue a welcome message for example
when you run mls in a multi-device
context where
you have a concept of users that can
each have several devices
and a user wants to add a device
and in that scenario up until now though
you would have to rely on one of the
devices of that user or
other users to be online in order to
grant access to the group to the new
device
but realistically is not how a lot of
messaging apps work for example um
and so maybe just a quick overview the
the way
we decide on who gets to be in a group
is um
actually decided by the authentication
service
in the sense that um it's this
abstract layer there's other scope for
the the protocol
and group members have to
agree on a policy on who can join and
who cannot but if they all agree
all we need is a mechanism for the new
joiner to actually be able to
get into the group as quickly as
possible and in this particular example
that i mentioned where
in a motor device context you just want
to add another device if on the
authentication layer
you can clearly prove that that device
belongs to the user and it's a
legitimate device and there's actually
no reason
why that device couldn't join right away
so we never had a good solution for that
and then a while back
we looked at how commits worked
up until now and there was a chance to
actually
modify it a little bit in the sense that
um this could be used by external dramas
as well
so the the way the the policy is being
applied is still the same
so before external commits existing
members could always reject
an ad proposal or ads that
they think were actually not legitimate
and this remains true for external
commits and we're going to look at the
details in a bit
i think you can go to the next slide
richard
so how how does it work in practice
what we need in order to issue an
external commit is
that the new joiner needs
some information on the current group
state and all of that is general
generally speaking public information
there are no secrets needed
whether this should be available or not
is for the the specific application to
decide
but we have the structure down on the
left
code public group states where we have
some of the parameters like the cipher
suite
it's being used for the group obviously
the group id and the epoch we're in
we have a tree hash over the public tree
and there we can reuse the same
mechanism we have for welcome messages
now where we can use an extension if we
want to
have the whole tree in there and there's
the interim transcript hash
the extensions itself for our group
so all of that is very similar
to what you have in the group info that
is part of the welcome message
there's almost no difference
and then one thing we added was an hpk
public key
that is essentially derived
from the current key schedule so this is
a public key whose secret
key is known to existing group members
and new journalist can use
that to come something to that key so
in the first iteration we didn't have
that mechanism and
um there essentially an external member
would just send
a commit secret like in a regular commit
to all existing members
um so that essentially
they could handle the shared secret
there um now
in the second iteration uh i think
richard proposed that
we have this external public key
um and then the the new joiner can also
um send an init secret to that key so
this is strictly more secure in the
sense that
before an attacker would only
have to have one secret key
in one of the intermediate nodes of the
tree
one of the leaf nodes now the attacker
also needs to know the actual group
secret
in order to break in so this simply
raises the bar on the security side here
so effectively what happens normally um
there is this in its secret that is the
last output of the key schedule in every
epoch and that gets reused in the next
epoch
as a starting point for the key schedule
and so this init secret obviously is not
known to the new joiner
so instead the new joiner generates an
image secret and
cans it to this external
public key and that way existing members
will receive it and can use it to
calculate the
secrets in the next epoch and in that
sense
um aside from this mechanism where
this external init secret is shared
between the new genre and existing
members
the rest of the logic is pretty similar
to how we currently do commits
and obviously here we reuse hpk like
we do everywhere else
um yeah we can go to the next slide
so there's one weakness that we quickly
discovered there
with that external public key so this
initially was not authenticated at all
which is not great because that means
that the delivery service can actually
pick that key
it's not entirely clear what an attacker
can do in that situation
but at the very least the new genre
would be tricked to can something
you know to a party that is actually not
an existing member
so this is not good so
if you go to the next slide
there is also an obvious solution to
that um
which is not on master currently
we're still debating on some of the
details but it looks pretty
straightforward at this point
um so all we need here is to have a
signature over the whole
public group state that includes the
external public key
there was a bit of a debate on whether
we should sign
all of the fields in there some of them
we don't have a good reason to sign them
but also only be cautious here so
currently what we have in the pr i think
is that all the fews are being signed
and that means that the delivery service
cannot just simply swap out the external
public key here
and so we we have a signature here and
at the same time we also
have the um the parent hash
which is signed what i just explained
earlier
and these two signatures should be from
the same member so the the last member
to commit
will calculate the parent hash will
update its own key package
include the parent hash as an extension
sign the whole thing
and then in addition to that also
produce this public group state and sign
that
so the the new member has to verify that
both have been signed
by the same member and that way this
public group state can be tied
to the last commit
if you can go to the next slide please
so there are a few other security
considerations um
so what changes here is that as i
mentioned earlier
uh the key schedule as such is
discontinued
because we don't carry over the init
secret um
from one epic to another instead we take
an inning secret that comes from
uh the new member so we we invert the
logic here
in the sense that previously we would
send
a secret to new members as part of the
welcome message
inviting them to the group in that sense
and here's a new member actually
who's sending the unit secret to the
group so one obvious downside of that
is that the accumulated entropy in the
group is lost at that point so
obviously we want random number
generators to be as good as possible
but in addition to that we since we keep
on rehashing things between apex
we also accumulate some more entropy
which is a good thing so this
uh takes a hit in that particular
instance
so we we didn't see any uh obvious
attacks so far with that
but it's also pretty clear that we have
slightly different security guarantees
benjamin did you have a comment on that
yeah i was wondering what's happening
with the transcript dash in destiny in
that scenario is it isn't isn't it
actually ashton
somewhere in your design
um i think the transcript hash is uh
hashed in but it's public yeah
the transcript hash is handled in
exactly the same way as a normal commit
so i actually i'm not sure i agree with
the
first two points here with the
hpk ebay scheme the
keys the information in the key schedule
and the entropy from the
prior group carries forward via the
external key pair right since those are
derived off the
epoch secret which has all of the
entropy that the group has
has accumulated so far um the only
um difference is that the that entropy
you know the the new in its secret
that's derived by hpke
is also accessible to uh someone who
holds
the um you know the new joiners uh
asymmetry key pair um so there is
i guess some dilution that way but um
you're still carrying forward
um the information that was in the group
already
so i i may be a little less worried
about these first two bullets than you
are
okay yeah i um maybe i'm being too
pessimistic here
but uh yeah this is certainly something
for the analysis analysis
okay
i mean the status quo is that this does
not validate any of the
security guarantees we want to have in
general like you still have authenticity
confidentiality
fs and pcs obviously so it's going to be
a matter of details hopefully
and so yeah since this requires you know
certain information to be public like
the whole public group state needs to be
published
uh with every epic change this mechanism
is also entirely optional
so members can just not publish that
and therefore external commits become
impossible because you don't have that
public information
and even if they do publish it existing
members can also simply reject these
external commits
which is something so again this is
governed by the authentication service
so
whether a member is allowed to enter a
group via an external commit
is for existing members to decide if
they
according to their policy they come to
the conclusion that the new member
should not
enter the group they simply completely
reject that external commits
and merely continue as before
so we haven't changed the the access
control as such
so i think that concludes that part
are there any questions
so this is richard um i i am totally on
board with this i think
you know so the the change proposal here
is to add the signing i think that
makes sense we already merged the uh
external commit stuff which i think is
also a good idea
um so i think the signing is a good idea
i think rafael you mentioned one thing
that i
don't think i quite agree with um you
mentioned that the
signer of the public group state should
be the same as the last committer
well i agree that's the obvious
implementation strategy like
you know if you're implementing this in
a whole system you should probably just
have
the you know whenever someone sends a
commit they also send an updated public
group state
um but i don't think that necessarily
needs to be the case you could i think
you could
allow for other any any group member to
sign
even if they're not the latest committer
yeah possibly yes the question is how
would that work in practice because as
you say
the committer is the one being active
when you change epochs
so this would require another group
member to be active at the same time
because obviously these things
need to be synced um at the very least
you know the epoch number is in the
public group state so
um this gets stale immediately after you
change effects
um i i don't know i'd have to think
about it i don't have any
obvious arguments against it other than
i think it's
not something that would be realistic in
a number of cases but
if we can relax the uh
what we want to achieve here then i'm
sure why not
jonathan i see you're making some
comments in the in the chat did you
want to bring anything forward here
jonathan horland i i was just uh
trying to understand what the scheme
means what it's supposed to be doing
so you you're asking if the the new
genre can evict people from the group
before anyone processes the external
commit
so the external commit works exactly
like current commits so
it can reference
actually any proposal that's out there
or it can create new proposals
um it could also have the the proposals
by value
as uh richard explained before so uh a
new joiner
could actually evict people
as part of that commit
um however we would have to see
because the evicted members at the very
least they know
the the secret
to the the public key the group public
key
um so this is not something you can take
back because this is calculated ahead of
time
we would have to see if the eviction is
as good
as it should be it's an interesting
question
but yeah i think that's something that
might not be immediately obvious to
folks about this external commit
um it is actually a fairly powerful
mechanism
and that you can include the you know
the person that's adding cannot just
you know they need to add themselves
that's
required for the commit to be valid but
in addition to adding themselves they
can do any other group operations so
they can
add other people they can remove people
from the group
they can add psks they can request the
groupie
reinitialized it even
so there's a full power commit
now personally i think that's a feature
and not a bug i think there's some cool
stuff you could do with this
on the one i put in the chat is that you
could you know
one of the concerns that had been raised
like what if someone loses their
loses their state need to resync well
this gives you a resync operation based
on the public group state because
you can now make an external commit that
adds your new version of you as you
re-adds you to the group
and removes uh your old appearance at
the same time
um so you get a resync operation for
free
by virtue of adding this external thing
um
so i personally i think this is a
feature not a bug but if other people
had concerns about the
the power of this uh feature i think
that
yeah there may be some things looking
there that i'm not thinking of
i think the uh it's it's great to be
powerful but this
just uh just means we're gonna have more
security review of it to see what
what the whether it's the power for good
or the power for bad
so i think that it's good that we've got
a security review time built in
so i mean it sounds like we should go
ahead and merge we should go ahead and
merge this stuff and then
basically see what happens
and now that i had a minute to think
about uh jonathan's question so i think
viking people still works because um
you change a tree so if you have a
remove proposal
you change the tree first and then the
new member would not send the commit
secret
to um people who have been evicted
so essentially the eviction would work
and i think there was also a previous
question whether the new genre can send
messages or not so
the whole idea behind this mechanism is
that the as long as this public group
state is available to the new joiner the
new joiner
can uh you know get started
immediately with that by issuing the
external commit
and and coming the external limit secure
to the group
um and then just you know apply this
commit
to its own state and and then the new
member can immediately start sending
messages
so it's immediately part of the group in
that sense
uh the only question is if other members
will agree with that external commit
but this is something we we have to
assume
that we do otherwise there was no point
in doing it in the first place
so if they will agree that external
commit then the
new genre is immediately a regular group
member
after having issued and applied the
external commit
there's no difference anymore between
the new joiner and other members
and as richard pointed out that you know
the motivation side i think this
uh simply might make mls
way more accessible in scenarios where
uh you don't want to have you don't want
to have this constraint that two devices
have to be online one after each other
and have a dramatic effect on
or impact on where mls is going to be
used
okay um i think the next slide is to
move to the github issues richard
well so same question here as for the
last one
um in terms of the pr so this is
kind of last call for folks to express
concerns about
the uh signing of the public group state
so
unless folks object here i think we'll
go ahead and get that that one merged
all right here hearing nothing
i think at this point all i had left was
um
there's a couple of other more minor
pr's on github
um if the chairs wanted to go through
those we could um
but other than that it's um further down
the uh the timeline that sean elaborated
all right let me know um where do you
want me to go issues or pull requests
uh when we go to pull requests
so we've discussed uh
let's see we discussed already number
uh four three three
and four three five and four three six
kind of go together that those the ones
that we discussed at joelle um we just
just look at 438 if people if you want
to um that's
mainly just removing some open issues
that have been flagged earlier
um that i think are no longer really
open
oh i see raphael commented on one thing
right
okay yeah so raphael is saying here that
we should continue to document the fact
that you could have a
now formed uh update path that
um encrypts one secret to some people
and another secret to other people
um this for folks you might not have
been tracking
is something we've known for a long time
and is not
really solvable with the um the tools we
have
that exist today um so yeah raphael i
think that's a good point we should um
add that to the security considerations
i'll update the pr to do that
yeah yeah that sounds good it doesn't
have to be an up initiative
okay so that's it
uh no there's one more at the top there
i could blow past
it sorry
sorry not here you meant here oh sorry
yeah yeah i think it should be okay yeah
so here i think we might have some some
disagreement among folks so the
i think the premise here is that is to
require that
each member in the group have a distinct
identity in their credential
yeah so
i don't know two things um
in the sense that there are some
inconsistencies in the
in the language of the uh the protocol
there and this is why this was started
and then it opened up some questions of
what we really want here
um
yeah i think we should this might need a
little bit more discussion in the pr to
get to what the
issue is because like i'm a little
concerned here that there
are cases where you want to have
multiple appearances of the same
identity
for example for multiple devices um
[Music]
and you might have multiple credentials
of the same identity and so i'm
worried when i see things like the
requirement here that um
and multiple ads for the same identity
would get ignored
or some of them would get ignored um
yeah maybe we should discuss it a little
more um maybe we can add that to
the the other subject we wanted to
discuss was it the tree signing
yeah the other one was a transcript
truncation
yes exactly sorry so maybe yeah maybe we
can combine that
um and uh and discuss that i recall
all right so sean it sounds like um our
chairs it sounds like maybe we should um
have a call
in in a couple weeks to close out these
last two issues
and then um and obviously we can have
some discussion in the pr in the
meantime
and then i will issue draft 11 and
uh start our feature freeze and analysis
period
i mean just just to be clear right
you're going to drop 11 before that
happens and then we'll
then we'll do the first right yes so
just to be clear um i think the the
timeline i had in mind was
have a call to discuss these last issues
then
once we've resolved them then drop 11
then start the future freeze
so we'll probably drop so that won't be
the analysis target
yeah so i think what we're saying is
that we're looking to have another
interim
uh possibly the first week of december i
haven't looked at my calendar i know
what's going on and we'll
we'll do a poll to try to make sure that
we can get uh
participation from all those interested
the the week after
thanksgiving in us terms
all right raphael i don't know
that sounds good
um i guess the other thing we could talk
about is um
implementation and in or out planning
but i don't know that we've got all the
right folks on here
right well i mean i think what we should
do is i would like to make sure that we
set up a wiki
in the github repo for implementations
and so that we can
set up an interoperability matrix and
then basically try to
try to blow through things and it would
be good if you and uh
say raphael benjamin and maybe brita you
know can figure out like if there's some
way to
like figure out the right the right
order of things to test to make sure
that the end you end up with an
implementation that works
i don't know if that's necessary but i
just have this vision that like
if you're trying to aid people that are
coming into stuff cold then it might be
good to have
a guide yeah and actually
it um if someone
in the group in the on on the uh in the
meeting wanted to
was more new to this and wanted to uh
get familiar with stuff that might be a
way to contribute is to help think
through what some of those cases are
uh that you'd want to test out um
based on your reading of the spec
so help would be welcome there
yes a second plant um and then we
we need to figure out a way how to
really test interrupt
um because i think right now the status
quo is that initially richard
started an implementation in c plus
which
is quite advanced by now and also saw
other people contributing
the same is true on my side and there is
one in rust
which is close to draft 10 now still a
few things to catch up
and then we we need to see how we can
actually
interrupt between at least these two
implementations
we already briefly discussed the
possibility of having a server there
this is something we're gonna continue
to work on uh richard so
it'll also be in the open so we can uh
let's see if we can reduce that
yeah i think we tried to do a more test
vector based approach
a little while ago um i think that's
having
played with that a bit i think it might
be a little challenging to to get that
exactly right um i think we are going to
need
we might be able to do some degree of
testing that way just to verify basic
functions like the
the crypto primitives and some of the
message serialization
but to really get the the behavioral
interop
i think we're going to need to do some
live testing um
via a server so we'll probably define
some little
you know json json over http and web
sockets
uh protocol to shut things back and
forth
yeah exactly i mean just for context
test factors are complicated because of
all the entropy that is
being injected all the time so in order
to
get that out of the way you have to make
a lot of modification to actual
implementation i think we should get
there at least on
on our side with openmls where
we're going to try and get there at some
point because i think els also has done
that in the past it's a good thing to
have
but it's not exactly a low-hanging fruit
um so the test factors we had in the
past was for
some of the tree math and like you said
some of the
serialization um well they're completely
inaccurate now because i think that
we're referencing something between
draft
one and four um we can try and get that
back of course but
i fully agree that we should try and
interrupt see how that
goes and then do full test requires as a
second step
why can't you actually replace your
random calls to
your random function you have z to
return zeros all the time
yeah that's one of those of course um
you could do that in principle but i
really do not like adding that's
production code
code that might end them from production
okay
i see it's something you want to do
behind a future flag or something
um it's it's not that straightforward in
practical terms
um okay
i mean so i hope that as we declare
uh an analysis draft that that will
encourage more people to show up with
implementations
because they'll have a warmer fuzzier
sense that the draft is not going to
change so much
um but we'll see
so yeah i think that's the that's the
main point at least for me on karthik
because we are doing the implementation
and the code are the same thing for us
right so we are proving something on the
code
uh so we don't want to
we do proofs like gazillions of times um
but yeah i'm pretty sure we'll have to
we
will we'll have something reasonable in
the next few months
during the analysis part but
that also depends on kartik not only on
me so
um all right well if anybody has
anything else
i mean at some point to be honest right
we're going to have to go back and
lean on a mod to do the finish the
federation draft or abandon it
and we're gonna need to do the server
assist draft um
and get working on that but i think the
the key point is getting the protocol
done get the analysis started do the
architecture draft
and then look to pick up the other
pieces should we
submit the first version of the
server assist draft just so that it's
actually public and under the
absolutely go ahead and submit it as an
individual submission
um whatever you know draft dash whatever
name last name we're going to use and
just go ahead and
put it up as soon as possible and we can
get people to start reviewing it
and if we have time and then there's
people that have reviewed it we can
adopt it whenever
there could be an actual a good place to
do uh
an informative proposal api for the
server part
if people want to interrupt we should
determine that somewhere i i'm wondering
if it's not worth
like doing um
like an exemplary api like a proposal
api in there
not sure i'll
put it in the chat right now there's
it's a stub right now and we haven't
looked at it in a while
um but that's what we can get started
with
yeah i mean the the nice thing here is
that uh don't
don't feel like you gotta hold back if
you got a good idea feel free to submit
uh um a draft
and or if you think it not really draft
material and you want to put it up on
the
github repo we can figure out a way to
get that done too
um speaking of drafts there's one a bit
farther afield i just posted a link in
the chat
um folks are already talking about how
to use
uh mls to key s frame which is another
working group for encrypting media
um so that might be interest folks
all right i think that's going once
going twice
sold thank you for participating today
or whatever hour it was in your local
locale
thank you again for taking notes
sorry nick i didn't want to jump on you
there
thanking folks for uh taking notes and
um
participating so far i think we've um
made a lot of progress and looking
forward to the new draft
great all right ciao folks
bye take everyone thanks bye everyone