good morning good evening good afternoon
this is the netconf working group
and um let me
pull up
the slides
hi my house this is captain can you hear
me
i can hear you can you hear me i can
hear you
all right
all right so i am
see your flight do you see this light
looking good
all right um good morning good afternoon
good evening our
very late night for some folks in north
america
uh this is the netcom working group
meeting for 109. um
i it's this is a note well
by participating in this you agree to
follow all the itf procedures and
policies
um if you are aware of any idea of
contributions
that are covered by patents or patent
applications
that are under control you must disclose
that fact
um of course you agree to
um to abide by any itf
rules regulations as that
pertain to an attendee
more information can be found in any of
these links
that you find on this page
just a quick recap on the administrative
trivia
uh kent and i will be trying to monitor
the meet
echo uh chat window or comments
but if you want uh um to present or
have one of us speak into the mic for
you make sure you preface the comment
with mike
in the front so we know that it one of
us needs to take it to the mic
uh the hum window
which is the one we you'll use for
polling will be
is right next to the chat tab on the
left side
uh no need to do any virtual blue sheet
signing meet echo will record your
presence
um when you need to queue up to ask any
questions
uh make sure you raise uh click on the
raise hand icon and
um we will then
call you and put you on the cue to speak
make sure
you unmute yourself by clicking on the
microphone icon
with the play symbol right
jabber uh we'll talk about it on the
next slide
we do encourage minute takers
as many as we can to take the minutes
uh you will find the link for the
kodi minute taker tab on the top side of
your screen
right and for jabber i have this link
to use if you want to set up jabber
and don't ask me too many details
uh the whatever information is there
probably is what does
i use to set up jabber but
also note that meet echo chat window
will cross
post or um they will cross post to each
other so
if you are on jabber we will see it on
the meet echo chat window
logs of course for the meeting will be
available after the meeting
all right status of
the chartered workgroup items
young push notifications um
when passed second uh
last call this has been called the
second time
uh we are still waiting for a pending
author's update
we hope uh we can get the authors to
come back
and finish the document
the crypto types trust anchor and key
store
uh documents are in working group last
call
um i guess ken will give an update
um something about sector review and
author responses
and let him speak to it when he gets the
status update
the client server suite of drafts uh
will go
into working class called once the
um security drafts listed above
clear last call we don't want to
inundate
the working group with more documents
till we have cleared what's on the deck
uh https notification is nearing working
group last call we'll talk about it
when i present that draft
young push notification messages again
uh is waiting on https draft
will resurrect it once we are ready to
send
https notification to last call
um the remaining documents are
all um work in progress
so and we'll hear about them in this
meeting
so here's the agenda i'm sorry
before moving on i'd see our id is in
the queue so
all right i'm sorry i just removed i'm
sorry
robert can i just remove you from the
queue can you go back in that's fine
it's my audio coming through
yes uh so just a quick question on the
meeting notes i went to cody md but it
gives me a
blank new page it looks like the fact
that i've created it
um so i can add some meeting notes to
that but doesn't have the normal
structure
that you would expect maybe that'll need
some
sorting out afterwards unless you know
so that actually may be the case i did
not initialize it with any content
did you mash no i don't maybe rob
i can after i when can start speaking
i can cut and paste the agenda into the
okay then i'll i'll wait for my keynotes
until you do that
well okay okay i just pasted this a bit
okay okay that sounds that's great
thanks
right um
so here's the agenda for the meeting uh
kent will walk through
the status and issues with all the
client server suite of drafts
including also the security set of
drafts
and in order to minimize uh exchanging
too many
screens again we'll continue with the
csr bootstrapping
sctp draft and then um
i'll take over followed by pair and
thomas
the non-chartered items uh we have
penguin
penglio and chen coming back with the
drafts they had presented before
and then we have one new draft from yan
lindman followed by kent and chin
talking about
a list pagination mechanism there is no
draft currently posted
i guess they will give us an update on
that
right any questions uh any agenda
bashing
anything else we want to see
all right with that i'll stop sharing
and bring up
the next swedish
sure
uh yeah
okay thank you
okay so this is the update i don't know
i'm getting echo
this is the update to the client server
suite of drafts
um since itf 108 uh just a
few small high-level updates and crypto
types we added the
password grouping to define a union
between a clear text password
and an encrypted password and um and
then you'll see
uh that grouping is now being used in i
think three of the other drafts
and we also added feature statements for
the
encrypted formats specifically
um password encryption symmetric key
encryption and private
key encryption those are all now um
those are the names of the features
i'm sorry my house she just dropped out
of full screen i'm not sure if you
didn't have this
it's okay
um those are the names of the features
and of course they're controlling
whether or not the server supports
the encrypting of passwords symmetric
keys and private keys
respectively and also
a a certificate expiration
notification we added a feature for that
for for controlling whether or not the
server supports
sending notifications when certificates
are expiring
in trust anchors um and actually really
for
the remaining uh the well
you'll see what the primary thing was is
that there was a sector review
by sandy murphy
on the key store draft but that review
had comments that were applicable to all
the drafts
i guess you might even say to some
degree they were editorial
and so you know the changing and
improving the way the content was being
presented uh was reflected in all the
drafts
so that's essentially the change that
was made in trust anchors
and in all the others as well um also in
the keystore draft
um their section four which is
entitled encrypting keys for
configuration
was pretty much entirely rewritten
uh to
present things in a more in a manner
that was more acceptable
to sector okay next slide please
um moving on we have
a tcp client server uh so here was the
case in the socks
gsa api we modified it uh there was a
field for a password
so we modified it to use the password
grouping and
now it's the case that the password may
be in clear text or
encrypted there in that in that
configuration data model
we also added there was missing
mandatory true uh
in that particular node when you
selected whether or not it was going to
be
us a kind of socks a password-based
socks
it didn't have it that the username and
password were actually mandatory
leaves so that got um added
i forget now who mentioned it but there
was a missing registration
for the tcp common
module so we added that in the iana
consideration section
similarly in the ssh client server draft
there's the modification to
the in the any client the ssh client
when you're configuring for
password-based authentication that
password was previously only it could
previously only be
clear text and now it's using the
password grouping so either clear text
or
encrypted password can be configured
in uh tls client server uh
the in the both the client
authentication and server authentication
for psks um
it's got converted from being a presence
container
to a leaf of type empty
there was a number of fixed needs that
got cleaned up
and that was the main update okay in the
http client server
draft there was also a uh some fixed
means that got removed
in the http client you know when you're
using basic authentication there's a
password it was previously just
clear text now it's using the password
grouping so it can be encrypted
and strangely oh okay i see it now
um hovering over the screen it it
blocks the text of what's being
presented
in the uh both the net conf incline and
client server drafts
the the same sector review comments were
reflected there
next slide please
um so i don't normally spend a lot of
time on
the changes that were made since the
last ietf meeting
because there's usually a lot more to
talk about but in this
case there isn't there was
just the sector review from sandy
and then um jav
near uh submitted a sector review for
the trust tour draft which i've yet to
work through
um though the changes um the comments
that were made there were fairly high
level
and didn't appear that they would have
any
uh significant impact to the drafts
uh in general um we've been waiting
and we i just putting on my chair hat
for a soaked moment adam
and i have been waiting for these
first three drafts to stabilize from a
sector
perspective and also from a yang doctor
perspective i think there's
a rein doctor review outstanding for
these drafts
so we're hoping to get that
those updates sort of completed for
these first
three core drafts and then
whatever cascading changes would occur
such as the ones you saw already the
sandy sector review had cascading impact
to all the other drafts
so any other cascading impacts would be
completed at which time
all the remaining drafts would be ready
for last call actually in my view
they're already ready for last call
sam's any potential
cascading changes that would need to be
made to them
as per the outstanding sector and yang
doctor reviews
and that might be it next slide i think
this is it
yeah that is it are there any questions
so
right if they're none can we move to the
next one
absolutely
all right so kent up what i'm finding is
that my windows gets taken over
completely
if i go into full screen
um
i don't think you need to go to full
screen um
okay let me try to see if i can share it
without going full screen
and see if it
so that's what it looks like
right and that doesn't not look good it
was better before windows
okay see do you have an ability to do
play in window
as opposed to full screen play in full
screen versus playing window
play no i don't
okay i think the full screen then is
better
can you do you want to go full screen
yeah i see it it looks good thank you
this presentation regards an update um
of course we just adopted this draft in
uh well actually it was one of the
remember we did
uh the chairs the metconf chairs did a
uh
adoption suitability um a number of
uh email threads one you know i think
for
nine drafts that were potentially queued
up for adoption
and this was one of the one of the
drafts that went through that
and uh it was adopted and
so immediately i posted the zero zero
which was identical to the zero one um
from before
the the k watts watson the id um
and that's really up until
monday just a couple days ago that was
the officially published version
um but then i was i did a
i did a grep for the word fix me and dvd
and i noticed that i had actually left
an editorial note
sorry next slide please um i noticed an
editorial note
and uh found myself needing to
make a quick fix to that and that's why
i posted a zero
one um in that there's in the security
considerations section
so you the update that you saw posted on
monday was just to for that zero one
update
uh sorry for that for that edit to fix
that mall that editorial comment that i
left in the
securities considerations section next
slide please
um okay so
when when this draft was presented last
time
we had said that the authors had made
every effort to
for the zero uh for the draft to
basically be ready for last call it was
already ready for last call we
had taken the time and effort to to do
everything
including security considerations and
considerations and everything
we thought we were done and ready but
then
um one of the authors had an exchange
with
another itf contributor from
a different company and not not someone
who's
commonly in the netcomfort group
regarding crmf
which is a a microsoft format
stands for certificate request message
format it's not actually it's not
technically
a microsoft format anymore it's an itf
format but it was originally
supported by microsoft and they wanted
to ensure
that crmf was being supported
and so we thought that we were going to
need to do an update for that
but to the second bullet point it turns
out that the draft already supports
supporting csrs um with the
crmfs and in particular this the draft
supports
csrs in three formats uh the first being
your standard uh p10 format
uh pkcs number 10 format
and then also cmp and cmc
and both cmp and cmc
themselves support
both p10 and crmf
and hence already the draft supports
crms
vis-a-vis its support for cnp and cmc
so with that resolved
um in in in essence there was no update
to the draft
it it turns out uh other than that
editorial emit that i mentioned in the
previous slide
um the draft was in fact
complete and done and ready for last
call
previously however to bullet point
number three
the same comment from that offer author
sorry itf contributor in a different
working group spun off a number of some
other drafts so you'll notice
in the lamps working group a couple
drafts by russ housley
on updating crmf
algorithms and yet another one for
updating
aes gmac algorithm so these
uh other drafts that are not
netcomp specific um sort of complete
the the response that was being
made by the other itf contributor
and uh so it's out of scope to this
draft
next slide please
and so beyond that there is in fact no
um remaining update to be made if uh
if there's any comments or questions or
concerns regarding this work
um please mention now
uh if not then i believe this this draft
is ready although i should say the
authors believe the straps is ready for
working group classical
i see a comment in the chat window from
rich congratulating for
the update thank you
i think we're done then and so
i think here mahesh is where i'm going
to take over being
slide presenter
this
that's
okay
all right so i will talk about updates
to the https
based transport for subscribe
notifications draft
um there were two updates uh one
just a quick um editorial not an extra
but a quick update
which i'll talk about um in
oh six that i'll talk about on the
slides next slide please
all right so um updates since o4
really there are only two main changes
um
the last update uh to zero six
uh really updated the security
considerations section
to uh bring it into compliance with
rx8407 and the second
change is regarding examples for
receiving of
event notifications um next slide please
so i think there were comments received
in the last itf
meaning that maybe the draft could do
well with
an example of for receiving of event
notifications
it was an example for json
um we did uh add
another example for xml the
corresponding example actually for xml
um in the drum so uh with those two
examples
and the fact that we have uh
completed the security considerations
section
uh let's go to actually i don't have
this end of the slide
yeah uh so with those two changes we
believe
uh that this document is also ready for
working group
last call but rather than us
teacher is calling for it we'll both
step down and
um see if
rob might take over at this point and
see if
he wants to do a pull or not
uh yes hopefully my audio is coming
through so i think the first question
is is anyone um
do they don't have any comments or
questions on this before i do a poll to
see if people are happy for me to
check for work in glasgow
so otherwise then i don't see any
comments in the queue
can one of you do kentucky do a poll
run a poll just to check so the question
is do other people happy for this to go
to working group last call
all right so please
so so just so people where they know
there's tabs on the left
um it's just under the hand icon looks
like three little
bars and you can either click to raise
your hand or do not raise your hand
or or choose to do nothing
i think i started the poll but i have a
typo so
is it started yes yep okay
it says wtls instead of wg
lsc sorry but
anyway so we've got 10 people that say
they're happy if this goes to working
with last call there's no one who's
chosen not to raise their hand out of 34
participants so it's 11. i think
i think that's fine so i think we can
yeah it's going up slightly so i think
we can take this to
first to do to kick off the working last
call i will
um work with kent mahesh to work out
exactly how
what the process should be in this
particular case
thank you thanks
uh rob
go
so kent are you going with the next deck
how did
yes i was just saying if pierre could
um come to the queue to
bring up i'll bring up their
presentation right now
it does take a little bit of effort to
switch presentations so that's why
there's
a delay you have to load it and then
ask to share the application window so
here um yeah i guess you don't
need to share your screen so i'm going
to cancel but
um
okay and now
i have it loaded i'm just about to share
the application window
[Music]
okay should look good
yep thanks so i'm pierre from
insalium and i'm going to present an
update on the udp native draft
joint work with guanine and tian ran
from huawei
thomas from swisscom and parlo from ntt
and a bunch of developers who worked on
this
notably last week during the cartoon so
next slide please smash
so i'll make a quick reminder of the
goal of the draft
then i'll show the main difference
with the 0-0
trying to cover the most important
comments that we received on the mailing
list since then
then the main point is to shut the my
mic and let you guys discuss
and take notes on this so next slide
please
so the
main use case presented on this draft is
to allow for
routers with distributed architectures
to publish
massive amounts of networking data
mostly traffic volume information
the point is to have line cars directly
send out the data towards the collector
and for this we had a requirement to
have a
low performance impact hence the use of
of a lightweight udp based protocol
this draft is to be used with thomas
with the draft that thomas is going to
give an update on later which is the
subscription to distributed
notifications
uh next slide please manage so
our first set of changes based on the
comments we received
in the last month we renamed
for obvious reason the fragmentation
option into segmentation option because
that's basically what we do
in order to be consistent with
the netconf distributed notif draft
i changed the generator id term into
observation domain id
then we reworked the applicability
section part of the draft to align with
the
rfc85 on udp usage guidelines
mostly what we covered is congestion
control or lag thereof
dealing with mtu and lack of reliability
of the draft basically what we did is to
show
that the context in which this protocol
would be deployed
is aligned with the recommendations that
are proposed that are
defined in the rfc uh so
i did not list all the strict
recommendations and guidelines of the
rfc but i
i've been sticking to the actual
guidelines for the context
of application of this protocol next
slide please
then we proposed some changes to
the notification message header so what
you can see first is that we stole a bit
from the
version field to
introduce what we called an encoding
space
flag when it is unset
it means that the encoding type field
is standard meaning that what you the
value that is in there
is defining an encoding that is standard
and when this flag is set it means that
we are falling into
private encoding tab space what we mean
by private is for example gpb
that is not a standard and what would go
there is any encoding type that a vendor
would support
that that is not a standard and that is
the vendor would designed on its own
which encoding type
it would decide to use uh i agree that
relying on the vendor documentation to
figure out what your favorite vendor is
sending to you would
feel a bit archaic so we have been
having discussion on whether we would
need uh
netconf to be able to retrieve a
description on what
uh the vendor is using as an encoding
type this is open for discussion
me personally i don't care too much
about non-standard encoding types so
i'm really really open to that
discussion
another comment that i received on the
header was
some people were challenging the need to
put the observation domain id and the
message id
in the header itself by making the
actually correct command that those
fields
could be found in the payload the main
one
critical reason to do that is that i
would like to
not have the big data people that are
further downstream
uh the communication channel to have to
deal with segmentation
so i would like to be able to
reassemble messages that have been
segmented
before passing them further down the
line towards big data
and so in order to do that as the
segmentation
option is defined within the scope of a
given message
received by a given generator i need
those two fields in order to
do a consistent job there so that's the
main reason
other reason another reason is quality
of life when i
have those fields up there i can
easily do load balancing based on by
preserving consistency on the generator
that is being done so i can do load
balancing based on the on the generator
and that easiest distributed uses of the
of the collector i received
another comment on the fact that
we currently use version 0
and that we should use version one so
that we make sure that the vendor is
actually the producer of those messages
is actually setting that field i'm fine
with that
i thought it does not change much to be
honest
uh if you don't mind i would like to
keep it to zero
until uh the header is uh
has converged to a stable state so i
would suggest that we do that
on the version of the draft just before
working group last call
if you have strong opinion on that i'm
okay to change it
no problem uh there was quite a bit of
discussion
on how to deal with this private space
so i already
said that we can either rely on vendor
documentation
or write a netconf draft to
retrieve that information uh i i would
like you to discuss this and and
honestly
we'll follow we'll follow the decision
on the working group i will not fight
against any decision that you guys would
make on this
um sure can't
if you want to go ahead
discount as a contributor regarding the
version
being zero um i do recommend it
i'd recommend that in fact there is a
separate rfc
i don't know the number of hand but
there is a ietf recommendation that any
enumerated field
both the zero and the max bit
values are reserved values um
and so yes both zero as well as
uh i guess seven the value seven should
be reserved fields
uh values for us if possible okay so
okay so what i will do i will put it to
one right away or if i'm not complying
and so and uh for testing repurposes etc
i will use zero internally but
i will put it to one uh in the draft
okay
that's does that work for you
and let's see my hash is in the queue go
ahead
right so um thank actually came to ask
one of the questions i was going to ask
uh
just what he suggested um
the question on the private space is um
obviously with the discussion around how
you're going to learn of the encoding
that is being
is there a negotiation mechanism that
you would have
then to find out what encoding is being
supported
even if it is a vendor specific no
what i was trying to to say is that
if you want we can define one okay i'm
okay to
to provide a draft a companion draft to
do that
okay personally i i don't
care really about non-standard encoding
but
if if that's needed if we consider here
as a working group that
uh basic
archaic vendor documentation would not
work then we'll do the work of providing
this mechanism
okay so
if you want to pull the working group on
how they want to deal with that i'm fine
with that
currently the uh people i'm interacting
with
care about the standard ones mostly
right and so
this was the reason why we made this
change was to deal with the fact that
gpb is not uh
will be supported by vendors and is not
standard
and so it was feeling weird to have it
be listed in the draft
and given a code point in the standard
encoding field
and so that was our way of dealing with
that if you want to change this i'm
also open to this we had also for
example a suggestion to uh
to have to not use a space flag but to
reserve the last values of the encoding
type field
and and let vendors use the research
space i wanted to make things more
clear you know you see and so and not
have to use reserved non-documented
bits and so i i it was i did that for
clarity reasons if you want me to
roll this back i'm fine with this i just
would like to know
yeah all right
promise you next
can you hear me yes okay perfect
i just want to raise that this is a
general problem
uh do we need to care about uh
private space or not if yes then uh
both transport protocols http s notif
and udp know this
should support it otherwise if the
working group thinks that
this needs not to be supported then i
think it can be removed on this draft
all right um andy
uh hi i would prefer to
take that s bit out and and put
a gp b back back
in the standard enumeration
i don't i don't know i think that's the
easier problem to solve
than than all the complexity being added
to descrip
discover proprietary encodings and
everything
i agree with you completely if
in three months no one tells me that gpb
is not standard and so it should not be
there
you see my point because the auras were
going to start working in circle
you see where i am there but i agree
with you on d i completely agree with
you
i'm just scared about what's gonna
happen in three months
well i don't know uh what you know ad
reviews and other
later reviews are gonna produce
as as objections but um
i don't know if there's a problem with
with how it's be
uh referenced or or something like that
if it's a documentation
or not so
and then hopefully uh you just put the
enumeration back
and it'll be important for
people to work with it my original
action was just the
the the there was no really reference
uh given document
not that it shouldn't be there yeah but
if i give a reference it will have to be
an informative one
and so the prop i will give one if we
put it back there
but it's gonna be informative and so
it's going to be the same comments
further than the
standardization line i'm afraid okay
well i still think the aspect should be
taken out
i don't mind i really don't mind
actually you might be right that if we
take it out and
and and use the approach where we
reserve some values
uh that would be used for private use
there would not be any reference to
non-standard encoding
but then i'm afraid that the question
the question will once again be raised
how how does an operator realize in a
multi-vendor context and multi-uh
release context uh which box is sending
what i mean right this is the main
problem with non-standard stuff so right
and and also following the lines of
thomas commands
i i hope we will be consistent with
other transport mechanisms that are
being used for
and that which face the same problem as
well
okay i would really have to
like to have robert's opinion on this
actually as a needy
um i i wasn't necessarily going to give
an opinion as an
ad on this um i think potentially some
further discussion
i i had a question really as an
individual that is
is he's just saying could be sufficient
enough
in terms of knowing what that encoding
actually would be because
i assumed that with yang there's there's
a couple of different ways that you can
code this data in
yang you can either have a generic gpb
encoding of gang data
or in some cases i thought some people
use specific
generated gpp
models generated from the gang data so
is there
an issue there that gpp is is not the
issue about whether the encoding is
known or not but actually what will that
data look like
um and maybe that could be solved by
being more specific about exactly what
the encoding is but i
i do worry about having something that
says it's done in this way but it's
unspecified
yeah the i completely agree with you the
good thing is that
for this draft it does not matter
because i would like to answer
with not my problem answer because to me
i'm packing messages that i i'm
reassembling messages when they are
split
at the transport layer with this draft
and then i'm passing it down towards the
big data people
which know when they register when they
use a distributed
uh subscription uh to go to connect to
the
box which deal at that on that side on
how they are going to do that
so thomas you may want to
to agree with me or not on this point
yeah what i just wanted to
to mention here and of course i agree
here uh is
maybe another option could be to have in
the standard space
uh have a fourth option where we just
say otter
that might solve the problem as well or
then
yeah the question is and we need i think
feedback from ad
here is if you can have like uh
in this area like where we just do gpb
or any we can list any
non-standard encoding there and in the
end it's
up to the network operator to figure out
how to to decode those messages
all right okay as a contributor
as uh there was a comment made about the
uh https notif
draft uh it it would also need to
support
private um encoding if this were
necessary and i just wanted to state
that i believe that's already the case
speak in two ways
first if uh if if uh
there's using http media types
and it does you know define
us or i should say use the standard
media types for
json coded young data and xml encoded
yang data
and but of course they could you know
private media types could be
generated and created and used and then
secondly
for those for when subscribe
notifications are being used and they're
being configured
for configured subscribe notifications
there's a yang
identity called uh encoding
i think and uh currently there's
sub identities for json and xml but of
course um
private or other standard identities sub
identities could be defined as well
so i think i think it's already
supported there uh if uh
to encode private
encodings for http for notifications for
https native
all right i think it
we may want to have a not me probably
offline another random discussion on
this
yeah if you don't mind so here why don't
you finish your presentation
you have two minutes sure go ahead
next slide please
okay i thought so i saw robin keep for a
second and my hush we do
we're running ahead of schedule i think
so yeah
okay last last update uh
we shrunk the segment number space to 16
bits because we were not needing 32
and then uh i tried to bring more
clarity on
boxes that would rely on ip
fragmentation instead of
supporting the segmentation option uh i
would like to i will further
i will uh simplify this even more and
basically do
like eip fix and say we should not do
fragmentation
i was just wanting to try and not allow
this
so say you can do this but not by
default uh
based on what we discovered last week
during the hackathon etc
i would like to change this and simply
say you should not do fragmentation
then i received a bunch of comments on
the relationship between the
last bit flag of this option and the
sequence number
mostly by andy i agree with all of them
and the request for clarification will
be done so
you had you were asking for details and
i agree with you it it wasn't clear on
some parts
and and the changes you were asking i
agree with all of them so
it will you will find them in the show
too next slide please
next
you can go to next slide
okay so the current uh implementation
status is
so during the academy we were working in
an environment where
within swisscom lab we had a huawei
implementation of this version
so we were following dash01 based on the
feedback that i will receive i will
update to the comment and
on the collector slide aside
we have a go long version of the
connector and a c version of the
collector
uh the c version is being validated and
integrated within a pmh gt right now
for our next steps we will probably
provide a ddls support for this
it's not our top priority because in all
the deployment scenarios we
we won't need it and then i will
apply the changes that you guys
recommend based on the
on the discussions on the mailing list
that we will have based on this meeting
thanks
all right any questions
i don't see anyone in the queue
and anyway
rob was in the queue before and while
i'm doing slide transitions maybe
he can come back and if he still has
something to say
okay go ahead joe uh yes uh it's
actually on the previous issue
if we still have time i'm i'm not sure
whether we need to discuss it further
now i think it needs
further discussion on the list and
potential get resolved during working
with last call i think the question was
really about
whether the icg would accept a protocol
where this is unspecified and the answer
is i don't know i think it will just
depend on the ad reviews at the time
um or the icg reviews when that happens
from my point of view i don't think it
makes sense to make this overly
complicated that as long as we can
communicate the intent
sufficiently enough that's that's
probably good enough but i need to look
at these a bit more closely again to
actually give a definitive answer
does that so yes that helps a lot so
what i would suggest is i remove those
bit
and i reserve the last few values of on
them so that i don't need
any reference to anything and i and i
and we proceed this way
and so that i don't and i follow in this
comment that
this stuff is too complicated for no
reason do i do that in the show too
so just to understand are you saying
that you wouldn't then have a gpb
encoding that you would i would not but
i would reserve
values and i would not create a private
space but i would just reserve values
and if we and so that the the header
will no longer change
and if based on the review we can leave
a reference to a value being gpb then we
just leave it there and that will
just be a value being uh fixed okay
and if there's a gpb won't work because
it's not standard
then i leave it in the reserved space
that is the usual blur response that
that we define at the atf for this
reason so i don't over complicate
stuff with this s bit i leave
room for gpb in the standard space if we
get review
further down the iesg review
that says but gpb is not a standard you
can put you cannot put it there
then i will leave gpb being used in the
reserved space that i will uh that i
would define
so i don't think it matters whether gpb
is a standard i don't think that unless
it'll be a problem
um from that perspective i think it's
just a matter of whether
it the the specification is clear or not
into what's used
and it it may be that effectively if
these are reserved you can have some
area in a space that actually defines
what these fields are for the ones that
aren't done in the document and hence
that can be extended with future
documents that specify this behavior if
required
excellent okay cool so we will we will
do that i like this
okay so the next presentation is
actually draft ietf.com
distributed note of not unite it's a
adopted draft
exactly exactly i'm sorry for that so
next slide please
so in uh compared to uh
zero zero uh these are the changes we
made in
the draft mainly in two areas in the
terminologies and uh
motivation part in the
terminologies uh we are basically
borrowing
uh the terms from rfc 7011 so
ipfix export in section
2 and 3.1 uh basically using the terms
observation domain and observation
domain id
and consequently replacing the term
generator id
with observation domain id in the drafts
distributed notif udp notif and
notification messages
in um in the motive motivation section
as requested from the the working group
mailing list
we were specifying uh the reasoning
for observation domain id
mainly on on the
on the data integrate decide to preserve
it
across multiple publisher
export processes the same also for
being able to recognize
lost and corrupt young notification
messages across
multiple export publisher processes
next slide please
so uh the questions from the
mailing list which has not been resolved
yet are listed here mainly from
andy and thank you very much so
one uh question uh was in
regards whether we should map
observation domain id
uh exactly down to
do to the position the processor
publisher export process
uh by mapping to uh itf hardware
yana hardware uh yang models
by looking up iona hardware young models
the closest match i saw was cpu
but it's unclear what cpu actually means
if
it's actually also matching the term
network processors as well and here
i like to get more feedback from the
working group and also from the authors
of itf hardware
yana hardware whatever this is really
the right
place to to augment to tool
because uh if we want to
map to the export process or just to the
to the to the the network processor to
the cpu
only so that's one question the the
second one
is in regards to the observation domain
id
uh if it's needed in the
the udp notif header and i think pierre
already
uh answered that question in his
previous
presentation and i just want to
emphasize
here that basically on the data
collection side
if the observation domain id would not
be within the udp notifier
uh basically we in order to
to enable data integrity we would need
to
look into the notification message
itself
and i think that would be a cross-layer
violation
which we would like to avoid
uh yeah looking forward for feedback
from
the group that's all
any questions
so this is a comment as an individual
and i have to say i've not read
the specifics here um but i would
i would i think i would probably regard
cpu and npu's generally being
different um in most cases often
sometimes they could be the same but it
might be useful to have a
separate turn to differentiate them
the only other question i have and again
i might be completely off
mark here is if it's the observation
domain ids are tied to what that is
obviously some line cards may have
multiple separate npus
so i don't know if that's something that
needs to be considered or not
or whether that is not an issue
exactly so as you nicely pointed out
it's not only about
the naming it's then also about being
able to
to model it down to uh chassis
line cards and pews and down that hold
yeah
absolutely
all right i'll put myself in the wrong
mask
if i understand i think andy's question
was how would you identify
and i don't want to speak for him he can
certainly speak uh also
but how do you identify a line card that
has either
been unplugged and put back in
however it's been replaced by
another line card with exactly the same
type
how would you be able to distinguish
between
those two line cards
right that's only possible if you
start to to to model observation domain
id
in a in a yang model
and for and currently i am
neither itf hardware nor ariana hardware
is supporting this
that's why i'm asking for uh feedback
from the working group and
the authors how you intend or what you
think is the best way to model this
because once uh we we have a feedback on
on this we can help here to to
extend augment the yang model and then
basically merge the observation domain
id there
the moment it's not existing
so would you say then that you have a
problem today
irrespective of whether atf hardware is
the right young model that
you need a way to uniquely identify a
line card
exactly if if that is the intent if that
is what we are
uh aiming for then absolutely
uh for instance uh in in ipfix
they did not resolve that problem
uh so there the the ids were
generated and you could not map it down
to the
to the line card to the the network
processors
and it was already sufficient uh to
to ensure data integrity so for the data
collection
it's not needed to to map down to
the specific network processor
but it uh in order to troubleshoot
further
it certainly helps and i'm not against
it i'm fully supporting that idea
okay
any other questions
if not we can ready we are ready to move
to
i guess the non-chartered items
and ping are you there can you queue up
all right
you're good to go you okay okay
and hello this is paulie from china
mobile and it's about
the telemetry data export capability
so next slides please
okay let's have a recap first and the
motivation is that the notification
mode divide in that curve notification
capabilities
allows a client to discover a set of
and such as transport independent
session level
and support by the server and but some
transport specific parameters are lacked
and just like the transport protocol
encoding format
and encryption so the goals
of the work is to augment system
capabilities
model and provides additional data
export
attributes for transport in independent
capability negotiation yeah so next
stars please
um okay this draft was first
presented in the
the last item meeting and it was just to
set up design team to process this work
and the latest update of the draft is
version two
and the change um three
points first is we removes the uh
max node per sensor group and max sensor
group
per update in uh yam model because um
um there are maybe some vendors don't
have donate to have
these characters and we also remove the
subscription
mode um and because because we
think that we can add some specific
and functions of parameters and we don't
use this
um subscription mode and it can be
more simplified and and simple yeah
and the third one is we can add
adaptive interval support and remove
sampling interval
list definition and to support the
adaptive
interval collection which will be
introduced
later yes okay next slice please
appearing you're a little bit quiet on
the microphone if you're able to
improve that to be good
okay
um okay this is overview of
the data export capability model and
the server it shows that server notifies
the telemetry data export capability
to the data collector and which could be
the network management system
it notifies transport protocol encoding
format
and secure
security and protocol yeah and then the
ms can
subscript the young notification
according to its demand
and for example it needs the odp
protocol
binary encoding format and js
security protocol then the server will
send the notification over
udp and also satisfied others
parameters or functions it just
shows the products are needed in fact
the server will notify all the
capability to the um network management
system
yeah and here are two pictures shows uh
um
version okay maybe i guess it's
not so it is very uh no problem yeah
um next page please
okay here are some issues uh which are
discussed
in the mailing list i think and
both of the three questions are solved
and the first question is the
server can provide hints based on the
exact request
from the client so we just to reply that
the answer is one of the principles set
by rfc
um young push is to
minimize the number of subscription
iterations between
subscriber and the publisher and
discourage random guessing of different
parameters by
a subscriber and our
idea is to try to prevent the problem at
the stage of
the negotiation of subsequent
subscription
in order to minimize the number of
um integrations yeah so we want to just
maybe it can improve the efficiency and
increase the loss rate yeah
and the second question is about the
static pronoun
monitoring data can be quite large
so we just discussed about it and we
think the subscriber
applications need a way to identify
capabilities for some datastore node
object
and in fact we can't assume that all
data objects defined in the
model support threshold handling and
maybe just some
of them support this functions and
so it won't generate so many um
date yeah and the um
third question is sensor group um
seems a very vendor specificability so
we remove the two parameters
and one is max node per sensor group and
max sensor group uh per object
and and we
have taken them out in the latest
version
yeah and these three questions are
three main questions discussed in the
mailing list
so i think um all of them are solved now
yeah
okay next slide please
so it's about the
data export capability and can we call
adoption of it as a work item
and any comments
it says this is ken that's co-chair um
this is one of the documents that
was we did the adoption suitability poll
for
before yeah and um
and there was an objection that was
raised i think by andy i just want to be
uh was that covered how did that
objection get resolved
okay so sorry i just missed some of the
voice
sorry i didn't understand the response
can you say that again
okay and i asked the question on kent's
behalf what he's asking is
did we resolve the objection that was
raised
during the adoption poll of the draft
um okay i
[Music]
you think answer this question
chen why don't you go next
shin do you want to step up to the mic
to answer the question
[Music]
okay
hello yeah jim oh
okay this is ching actually yeah as uh
pangu actually clarified we discussed
the
issue we listed in a lot of slides
actually all the issue has already
resolved in the latest version yeah
so we so all the changes we made
actually
has has already incorporated in the
version zero two
okay so quiet
my comments from something else i'll let
andy go first on this actually
i've got a comment about the structure
the draft
what content the draft all right go
ahead andy
well i just don't think this all this
extra complexity is needed and
that the rpcs already have
extensive mechanisms to provide these
hints
and ignoring that and doing something
else
isn't isn't that high priority
yeah andy actually will clarify
your issue actually in the first bullet
actually i i think
um uh we we did a center updated slides
actually you know you we did could use
our pc and
use the error option to show uh what was
what's uh what's
wrong actually but the if we define this
capability
advertisement actually we can avoid the
you know
uh unnecessary uh negotiation you know
so so that's the way you know we we
reference
some of the texts in uh young push
actually you know
it also you know uh highlight that you
know
we should avoid you know uh unnecessary
subscription exchange iteration
yeah this is how we how we address your
comments
[Music]
i don't see where that's happening
because either i send one request and i
get back the hints
or i send the request your way
and i get back the capabilities either
way
it's one request one response i don't
see all the extra
work iterations that you're talking
about
yeah well our idea is in the first step
we
you know to just advertise
the capability to to the server so
server can
to choose for example choose what
transport protocol
it will use in in a young push
substitution message
so you don't need to you know uh to
to uh have research
there too yeah yeah get me suggest that
you take this discussion we're
running a little behind and we still
have rob in the queue
so can you take the discussion of
iterations and
rpcs to the queue please let me
know okay we can take it to the list
yeah sure
bro uh so just one one quick comment on
that is i think what this draft is
providing is to allow the capabilities
to be expressed
up front as it may be in an instance
data document so
um a client could be coded to design
time
to know what the capabilities of the
servers like to be so that's one comment
to that
but the other question i had was in
terms of the structure of the yang
it looked like you could just define for
example one transport that supported or
one encoding whereas i'd have thought
that
servers have different capabilities that
they support
and hence um it may be that the
structure the model needs to be more
flexible or otherwise
i don't i don't understand in the yang
why it's only expressing one of those
rather than this is the set of different
transports or encodings that are
supported
yeah i think that we can allow the
server to
advertise the capability for example
support different transport protocols
better
we can make a client to make a choice
which transport program are encoding
they can support
okay we really need to move on to the
next presentation
i think chin you're up next
yeah can you open slides
yeah we're coming up
a few seconds
there's like five confirmation windows
you have to click through in order to
get to them
so go ahead okay uh so this is the chain
i'm here to discuss adaptive
subscription to young notification drop
update and next
so uh kernel status this job has been
presented
in previously 2itm meeting and
actually we tried in a previous item and
it was suggested to align with essay
model
and also we actually introduced a new uh
subsequent mode besides the periodic
subscription and
uh unchanged substitution and so we need
to better
characterize this separation
subscription
uh so in uh last night meeting we also
you know
discusses and uh uh we got
actually a lot of support and uh so in
latest version actually uh we
uh tried to you know uh remove the
dependency to the esa model we will
remove the past target definition
and we also you know clarify the xpath
external
evaluation node in the young model and
and rewrite the usage example to align
with these young model
parameter changes next
so for people who don't know what the
adaptive subscription is actually
it is the extension to the subscript
notification
for young push subscription they support
two uh different mode one is
period subscription which allow you to
publish
the data periodically and another is
unchanging substitution
which allow you to publish data when
data gets changed or protocol operation
on data get changed
but in some cases uh uh maybe uh for
server and client over they may support
multiple you know
uh period intervals so the server may
need to switch a different interval
according to the network condition
or research usage the typical example is
what is performance monitoring
the wireless signal stress can be weak
can be strong
so because of the air interface
resources is very is very expensive so
we can when the wireless signal strength
is very strong we actually can collect
the data at a
lower rate but when the signal strength
is very uh weak actually we can collect
more data since
we need to have sufficient enough data
to do the job shooting so this can uh
greatly reduce the data to export to the
client
so he uh so we introduce this
subscription
uh adaptive subscription and uh enable
this uh subscription to
the publishing event and so they can
adjust the wrong the telemetry traffic
next
so this is a what the model structure
look like actually we augment the
subscribe notification
uh we propose a set of parameters for
example periodic
angle time and this will specify
new duration for push-up data and this
period will be triggered when
conditions get changed and the anchor
time will specify
the starting point for each uh updated
interval at the same time updated
interval
and also we introduced uh
what water marker and uh
and expanse external evaluation this
actually
can provide the evaluation uh creation
and the water market uh actually is
part of this uh evaluation expression
and that can
uh use to uh to ex to to express the
condition
uh to be satisfied and and trigger
the interval switching so here we we
just
give an example so when uh
such condition uh excess expressed by
the express
external evaluation uh
actually get changed actually
the condition i'll get actually
satisfied actually it will send the
adaptive
preridic updated notification
immediately and so the
client can adjust the uh
the the telemetry uh
connection rate accordingly
next
uh here is the issue we actually uh
uh respect the nd on the list and about
the filter it's
this filter and trigger maybe not a in
good design
so we make a
some change actually accordingly for
example we take out the data path
target and things that we we don't think
this is
something needed because this actually
will
impact or influence the event recorder
output actually so in this model
we also changed the naming for then we
changed the condition expression
to the x-path's external expression this
expanse x naught expression will keep
track of
data objects change but this
expression will not you know affect the
event record output and the only
uh can used to trigger the interval uh
switching
in the server
that that's the main change we made
actually try to simplify
this model and recover from the
easy model since we think these
different use cases
doesn't need to be tied with easy use
cases
and next
the main change and also it was the one
that
um the reason why the adoption poll did
not succeed
um i don't recall it being discussed in
the list but
maybe andy since it was your objection
if you've had a chance to take a look at
this can you can you speak to it as if
as to whether or not it resolves your
issue
go ahead andy
i haven't read the latest draft and uh
don't really have any objections uh you
know that's
uh not really our focus right now with
yang push we've actually spent a lot of
work
implementing gang push and and decided
that the periodic stuff isn't
isn't that great so on change is is what
you want to use
and and and it's just much more
efficient
than trying to uh you know
adjust the period on the fly
it's more work to do on change but it's
better so
yeah thanks to andy so as a contributor
um andy i'm kind of curious about that
comment that you just made because i
think the
the reason for the periodic was because
um there's some values that just don't
change very often at all
maybe once a day or even less often
but because they're periodically pushed
in case this
subscriber comes in later um
they get it um you know the value but i
guess
there's also a sync up that occurs right
so when they first subscriber first
there's a sync up so they get all the
values up front
and then um and then i guess it's just
changed from that point forward okay so
okay maybe i do understand answer my
only question
yeah and you can you can request to
resync on the fly
too but if you if you missed that you
know
or lost it okay thank you uh robert
you're in the queue
uh so just a confidence individual so i
just again wonder whether this is quite
a complex solution
and to the problem and whether a simpler
solution might just be
to mark some subscriptions as being
effectively
higher priority data and others as lower
priority
and then uh to to have one setting to
say
allow this to be adaptive in some way
and then just leave it to the device to
try and
reduce the rate that it's sending this
information out if necessary
without specifying specific periods or
paths or that sort of thing so
to have it as a more course level
type of qs rather than having to specify
specific conditions and things like that
so you put more intelligence into the
device
you're relying on it to do some things
rather give you very specific
instructions
as to how to manage this data
but this is an individual comment
uh robert i'm i'm not sure you know
for your purpose it seems you need to
satisfy actually to lose some of data
since your
priorities some of the data but for our
cases that we
whether you use the high data clinician
rate or lower than
data connection rate you will not lose
any data
i just wanted to follow up on robert's
comment
uh i was thinking the same so
i think ideally if uh for a periodical
subscription
we could have a range say from from one
to ten
and then basically the the
the publisher decides depending on on
the state
which which value it's choosing for the
the export interval
yeah the assumption we made is you can
support multiple
updated interval but a server they may
have
the capability to to switch this
interval to
you know reduce uh you know the
volume of the data to be exported to to
the client or too
so you can you know address this
performance uh bottlenecker
so uh yeah that's what we proposed there
okay i think we are running behind so
maybe
um take it to the mailing list again
right
so chin i would suggest that uh you know
take the discussion to the mailing list
including the question of adoption
let's try to resolve on the mailing list
please
okay thank you
right next we have yen
we can very good so
next slide please
and next
so uh now that we have net conf being
spread around
and managers are actually starting to
use this a lot
one of the use cases i see very often is
that the manager wants to
keep in sync with the configuration
changes on a
large set of devices so you often see
that
okay it's doing a git config initially
to see what the configuration on that
device is and get to reply
and then after some time longer or
shorter it's interested to make a change
and before it makes a change
it likes to see is this configuration
still the same
it's issues now they get config and
eventually gets reply and sees that
oh yeah it's the same but this mechanism
is is quite wasteful because it's
getting this get config reply which is
oftentimes exactly the same as the git
config reply earlier and it is pretty
large in many cases
so if there was a shorter
easier way to get to know if this
configuration is the same or not
that would be very convenient
i have seen actually several vendors
have implemented their own proprietary
mechanisms
for providing a shorter way to convey
this information
like a time stamp of last change or
some checksum of the config or something
that you can read
in order to see if anything has changed
at all in the device
but those mechanisms we are using them
and
they are kind of nice they are better
than nothing but
they are not quite good enough because
in many cases there have been
small changes somewhere but maybe not in
the area where
this particular client is interested to
see oh has changed
so it will be reported as changed but it
hasn't changed in anything
in any area that this client is caring
about so we are back to
r1 essentially
if you go to the next slide this
mechanism also has the problem that
uh it also often gives or sometimes
gives false
false alarms or you miss it false
you say that you notice that oh i issue
you get config
and you get to get a complete reply you
spend a lot of cpu time to
compute is this the same as last time
yeah and
it is but in the meantime there's a
window of opportunity
for another client to come in and make a
change so we think it is still the same
but
actually it has changed since
somebody got in in the middle so then we
get into the case where we are updating
the server in an unsynchronized manner
even though we will check so
i'm proposing a mechanism to get away
from both of these problems make it more
efficient
and make it more reliable next please
contributor i think with netcall it's
traditional for
uh lock followed by get config followed
by
uh edit config so you're ensured that
you're only editing the data that you
had gotten
inside the lock you speak to that
that would take a long time then because
getting the config
and computing if there's change uh can
take several minutes
so then you would have to lock for a
long time and i think
that's not what we see happening in real
networks
okay thanks
okay so i'm proposing a solution uh
where we say
that we have a concept of a transaction
id attribute
that you that the server may report
for every container and list elements we
don't want to have this on every leaf
and everywhere
but on containers and list elements
and we make sure that whenever there's
an edit config
the server will update the transaction
the id value
for every container and list element
that have been touched by this
transaction
so that the client can rely on this
id being something new if it has changed
if something inside it has changed
and the client may optionally specify a
transaction id
value that they would like the server to
use
so anything that is touched by this
client also it can
in an edit configure clients can specify
this transaction id
and then the server will apply that
transaction id value to everything that
has been touched
but also the client during a get config
can specify transaction ids or what it
expects
to say oh i believe the contents of this
container or this list element
has this transaction id and if it
matches
there's no need for the server to send
the content of that
and on the next slide please uh i have
an example of what that looks like
so here we have an initial sync where
the client is issuing a get config
and with a filter for interfaces in
nacom
and on the interfaces it says hey can i
have
the transaction ids for this please by
issuing this in tag
equals question mark next please
and this is what a reply might look like
so
here the server has uh decorated
the reply with these transaction and tag
values and you can see this def
something that's something on various
containers on the
well you have on the top level here data
which is for the entire data store
saying that the global transaction id
for the data store is stiff
whereas for interfaces the whole set of
interfaces container is
and for a particular interface here
gigabit decent zero zero
it's def eight eight but uh another
interface gigabit ethernet zero one
has an older end tag called abc123
so this is how the server would decorate
the replies with
these tags for the areas of the response
where it was requested by the client
earlier
in the filter next please
and then later uh the client can say
okay i do get convict here on the
interfaces
with this and tag value abc123 which is
what i expect to be here
and next please this is how a server
would replied and it would say
yeah it has actually been some changes
in interfaces
so the the global transaction id is now
dev88
interface is also the date this give it
ethernet zero zero has also changed it's
definitely
and here's
the one which had
i think that was all my slides basically
go let's take the next one
yeah okay right uh so in a edit config
we could uh the client could also say
hey i expect
the transaction id of this interface
to be ghi5555
uh so if it is
go ahead and run this transaction and
delete this interface in this case
but if it isn't if one of these
transaction ids
have a mismatch then abort the whole
transaction and report it
things are not the way that you expected
since things have moved since you last
synchronized so then the transaction is
supported so that's a safe way of
performing this edit i think there was
one more slide with
just some see thank you
do you have a question or comment
go ahead
i have a question um and it's really
maybe uh can you address the issue of
the the race condition where uh you know
you set a transaction id
of foo and uh by the time you come back
with the git config
uh elements that you have changed is
have been changed uh
either by the system or or or through
other some other
client is that is that the intention how
do you handle the fact that your
data set of what you thought you changed
got changed between
between the time you changed it and you
got and you issued the kit
yeah this is exactly the mechanism to
handle that
problem so by the client
uh proposing a transaction id when it's
making another config
or by this and certainly by the server
guaranteeing that whatever
something changes a new transaction id
has to come on to this to the touched
containers and list elements that's how
a client can be sure that only
it can read updates only by using
getconfig with these transaction ids
and it can edit config safely by adding
this transaction id
for what it expects and only if all the
tags that is mentioned in the edit
config
are matching only then will the
transaction go through
so that's a safety lock there yeah but i
as a client won't know
i don't have any assurance that what i
have
changed under this transaction id
is indeed what is still changed when i
do like to get config right after i i
make my changes
or or i wait three seconds or
three minutes right i mean is that is
that
expected or is that a a hole in the uh
the concept right um
because you don't have any uh um with
lock everything's atomic
right you know everything's there and
it's and it's atomic with this
this is kind of it's not it's not as
it's
it's not safe in terms of the uh
uh the the transactional set right you
know that you know that this is what's
changed
uh uh what has changed which which
elements which
leafs have changed right it is
absolutely atomic if any
tags do not match now the transaction is
aborted entirely
right not giving up on transactionality
oh you're saying like on the delete
in in the i was talking about just the
original change with the get
i'm sorry i was back on the previous
slide when i when i entered the q
so i come in i do an edit config right
i'm not doing a delete operation yet
right i'm just trying to figure out what
changed
right so i do an edit config i say tag
foo right
and then i say okay git config you know
and i want to get the
now i want to understand which nodes
were changed to foo right
based upon foo but in between then some
other client can come in and make a
change
right and so it loses that tag
and so i never really understand there's
there's opportunity or there's chances
there that i will never really
understand
uh what actually changed right
particularly if it's a
quick changing set of nodes
or frequently changing set of nodes
i i just is that accurate i'm just
trying to make sure i understand
if that's a problem right i may not
understand
your intent exactly here so i mean if
you're interested in
knowing uh the exact state of the device
you're welcome to either do a get config
of everything and
or to do a subscription of some sort you
can do that to info
in order to follow everything but what
this is about is
to ensure that when when a client has a
view of
the states of the server it should be
able to
verify that view quickly by saying okay
i know this about
the configuration and these are the tags
i'm aware
and just report the differences versus
what i know
so that's the mechanism i'm looking for
here okay that's
so now i kind of understand it you're
just saying hey look i i made this
modification
and then i want to go back and do some
editing but only if i'm the last one
that changed it right okay
all right now yes yes yes and the
also the case that okay there may be
changes and if there are let me know
what those changes are versus what i
know
so don't report everything everywhere if
if things are as i expect them to be
then don't report them okay
sorry guys uh i know i'm in the queue
and the last is after me but
uh we are really out of time on this so
sorry bilas can you take your question
to the mailing list um actually my hash
i i'll give
some time to below it's okay
maybe my presentation with that for this
one for for other people who are
wondering
where that's coming from go ahead what's
your question uh
my point is that we have something very
similar
in rest golf and it would be good to
understand that
is this the same mechanism actually or
are we
if we have a data store that is
visible both on rest conf and net
confidence do we have to supply
uh support to similar but not the same
manners
so describe somehow the relationship
with
rest config tags yes this was definitely
greatly inspired by the e-tags and my
intention is that
the server implementation should be able
to be joined here
but things are still early in this draft
and
we will see where it takes it i don't
want to
guarantee that it will be exactly the
same or very much compatible with
e-tags but yes it is the same mechanism
that we have in e-tax already that i'm
trying to describe here
all right i know i i'm on the cue so
if it's okay can i take one more minute
i'll take that as a yes uh so
um again i i understand the optimization
in terms of trying to tag
at least at the container and the list
known but
couldn't this be a little more cold
strained for
um you just say for a given config
or a transaction you have a tag
and if you're trying to edit it and if
the tag doesn't match
you request that you do it now you
request the client make another
get config request before moving to
to try to make any edit changes meaning
you don't have to necessarily carry tag
at every container and list level you
could carry it at the transaction level
yes it's up to the client to decide
where what parts of the transaction it
really cares about things being the same
it can say for this part of the tree
i'll just go ahead as
traditional config but for the
interfaces list i'm really interested to
make sure that all the interviews that i
touch
are untouched or that no interfaces have
been passed or a particular aspect of
the details of one interface are
important
it's up to the client to decide where
the tags have to match
so uh so as chair um
can you go ahead and bring up my my last
presentation
um but as a contributor to yan
um i would recommend trying to align
this work exactly with resconf
uh if possible because i know that
some you know servers that present both
restaurant and netconf actually build
one of those interfaces on top of the
other
um and i think typically rest conf is
built on top of netconf but
um anyway if it i guess the question is
why wouldn't why couldn't it be the line
or aligned why wouldn't it be
aligned it was the reasoning for not
being aligned i think
uh i'm taking it to the list but please
um
try to address that comment later
certainly
all right my hush can you go full screen
please
okay so this is the last presentation um
as everyone probably saw on the list
there was some interest
in introducing support for list
pagination in both the netconf and the
rest comp protocols
i sent out a
call for participation and
did get some respondents responses
thank you jin olaf and way
there are actually also other
respondents but
um they haven't yet contributed
and so they're not yet listed here but
hopefully that will
improve next next presentation next
slide please
the motivation for this work is to first
inform us to better support user-facing
client interfaces
interacting with data from potentially
large
lists examples of potentially large
lists
include traffic logs or really any time
series data which might include audit
log but in general
um those uh time is kind of like config
false
op state type data but also within
configuration there are some
very large lists sometimes interfaces
or firewall rule bases can grow to be in
the thousands
and of course it's all very manageable
today with existing
and you know netconf i mean already
the client gets the entirety of the
large configured
list and then handles it itself in its
own memory
but if we are already solving the
problem for
the extremely large potentially
upstate list also you know
transferring that to the config true
lists would be of some benefit
and then lastly server-side processing
in general reduces latency
and bandwidth and client resources
so that's motivation behind this work
next slide please
the solution okay the i'm just looking
the graphics uh
no it's not like the bottom line is all
crossed out it's supposed to be filter
goes to sword sword goes a direction etc
you can see the little arrows but it's
uh it's not looking quite right anyway
i'll let me go back up to the top
of the slide the solution proposal is to
introduce
uh to both netconf and russkoff an api
for list pagination there's five control
points that have been discussed and this
was
on the list so i'm a bit repeating but
since this is the first
presentation introducing the work i
wanted to make sure
there's a slide for it um there's the
ability to limit the number of results
that are returned in the response
there's the ability to control the point
at which the result set begins you know
maybe you don't want to start always
start at the very beginning of the list
you might want to
begin somewhere in the middle uh there's
the
direction that the results are returned
are they returned in the forward or
reverse direction and
potentially there's the ability to sort
the results
maybe um on a particular node or in
in sql terms on a column you know sort
on a particular column and then
and then the results would be in that
order
or if it's an order by user list
by default the order is the order
the configured order as it were by the
order by user list
and then lastly there's potentially the
ability to filter
the items maybe the client is only
interested in
zooming in to a particular subset of the
data
now these control points are actually
ordered in processing there's a
processing order
uh it is in fact the reverse order so
first
the results are filtered filters in
general are very
fast they're almost always well
hopefully the
node or the leaf that you're filtering
on has been
indexed by your backend database so it's
a
fairly it's a pretty fast operation
to do the filter uh and then if there is
a need to do source that would happen
after the filter
so you're only sorting the subset of the
data that has
uh gotten through the filter uh if there
were
was a filter then lastly the direction
and and then um and then you can
choose whether or not you're going to
skip or do an offset into that result
set and then and then lastly figure out
what subset of the data or
how many re number of the results that
you're going to return
so that is the processing order and um
for those that are familiar with sql
that is exactly what sql does
and i imagine it is the same for
most backend databases but that is in
fact uh
what this uh author list is
is doing so there's a number of
authors that are or you know some
authors are more implementation oriented
and so we have a representation of
different backend databases
and we're doing prototypes to of this
of all this to ensure that it's mappable
to the various backend databases next
slide please
okay so this is mostly discussion so i
have
questions to the group they're first
there's
some protocol independent questions and
the first three are actually related so
i'm going to
speak to i'm going to say them all but
then sort of go back and ask
for comments on each one at a time so
first
how important is it to iterate over
stable result sets
i think it was jan who had
posted a comment about this to the list
but essentially should something like
cursors or snapshots be supported
and just sort of thinking out loud i'm
i'm you know for configured for
configure
for configuration um
with rest conf at least and and in the
last presentation the
the uh the equivalent of an e-tag or
timestamps uh
you know that is that good enough uh in
the sense that
um you know if you're doing like a get
on you know data and and you're saying
okay i know the e tag is supposed to
this where i know the time is supposed
to be this
and um you know if and you're you're
indexing or you're paging into the
data set but now the data set's been
changed under
under under the hood um you know
wouldn't it be good enough to
just for the client to get back an error
uh saying hey the data set's changed you
need to
restart your pet your pagination um
or is that not good enough and you we
actually need to create
uh something like a cursor um or
snapchat
uh so that's for my thinking out loud
for configuration and then
thinking out for upstate for again i'm
assuming
we're talking about read only time
series data like
audit log or traffic logs and
i'm you know i'm guessing it's stable
enough it's it's read-only
i i mean sure logs can expire you know
given how much um resources memory or
you know storage the the server has on
board
but you know you can imagine logs
sticking around for you know at least a
few hours or days or whatever
and um i mean they made the client may
not get the
the most recent set of logs but you
could imagine the
pagination logic always having in it
a a filter criteria saying that the
timestamp has to be
or i'm sorry cannot be greater than
whenever the pagination
began so all the uh logs that came in
after the pagination began would be
excluded and
hence effectively the remaining logs are
it is a stable data set
um again uh not including purging
okay so for number two and three and
again i'm gonna
mention these quickly and then go back
to one uh for two
i'm wondering if offset or skip
um i mean those are we're trying to
figure out what what
what the term what the name should be is
it offset or skip
um then that's actually the comment for
number three but it is the offset
skip uh parameter should it be an
integral
amount like an integer value which would
be consistent with
um sql's limit sorry as equals offset
parameter or should it be a key based
lookup
so you you begin your pagination and
and then somehow the the last
uh entry of the results that you got
back you know it contains a
keyed value and then your your
subsequent request
for the next page of data is actually by
page or i'm sorry by key
you're asking for the next set of data
beginning with a key as opposed to the
next set of data
indexed by an integer and then for
number three uh
and then it's really the question as a
naming question
should it be um called uh
skip or or should be called uh count
um i think in least sequels count
and or in and then and likewise should
be called offset or or limit
i'm sorry i think i have this backwards
it's skipper offset counter limit
i'm sorry i i don't have a but anyway
the question is how aligned to sql
um names should we be of course if going
to number two
if we're doing the key lookup ie we're
not going towards sql or we're moving
away from that approach
then the whole notion of whether or not
we're aligned with sql doesn't matter
so that's why or how it's three is
related to two and of course two is
connected to one so going back to one
and to the group please if anyone has
any comments
uh how important is it to iterate over a
stable set of results
we only have five minutes so if there's
any urgent urge urgent comment please
raise your hand
okay i don't see anything coming
[Music]
i'll take that to the list um for number
four
um question is should sub sorts be
supported
and currently the design as just present
on the
screen was very much uh just a single
sort
which is you know by and large 95 of
what clients want
just a single sort you about your email
client right you can only use
or do a single filter um at a time it
it's that's very common but
it is noted that sql supports sub sorts
so for instance you can do an order by
foo ascending
and then by bar descending for instance
um so there's this question as to
whether or not sub sorts
should be supported i do see belage in
the
queue please blush go ahead
early in yank design we avoided
sorting because for some data types
that's quite complex
just as an idea that the o with the two
dots
that letter is in some alphabets behind
the
oh the simple o somehow alphabet is
behind the
zed character are you going to
address these complexities of sorting or
what do you want to do with them
uh that's an interesting comment um
i will take that to the list martin had
strong opinions of that on that i don't
know a few years ago
okay so i think martin has been involved
of some
with this comment uh with the the
discussion on the list previously
and i mean in general the thinking is
that
we should be using xpath query language
for this and so whatever um
that it supports would be by and large
what would be doing um but i'll take
this to the list
do you have another question or comment
um thanks that's yes okay yeah you're
still in the game don't expect a full
answer just now
okay good thank you all right so next
slide please
alright so uh again with the protocol
independent or continuing with that
how many drafts should there be so this
one i'm really hoping to get a response
from right now
should there be one draft um i.e that
contains
three parts uh the general definition
netconf specifics and then restaurant
specifics
so the pros of this is that it's a nice
package brings it all together
the cons is that it's not a great rfc
target for future work
or there could be two drafts uh ones for
each
uh netconfin and rescoff pros is that we
then decoupled and now that
they make better rfc targets for future
work
um of course you can imagine you know if
a third protocol were to come along it
could
then be a tone draft and so that's very
nice but the cons is that there's some
redundancies between the two
so for instance the uh those five
control points that we talked about
before
they would have to be defined
individually each in those drafts
and likewise the examples you can
imagine an example module an example
data set
an example data results that you would
expect
i mean of course we wanted we do want to
illustrate the query language
in you know each of the protocol
specific drafts but we don't necessarily
need to
redefine um the authoritative
you know results set examples uh in each
um and then um or or three
option three is to have three drafts
which you know again
would be uh a general one draft should
be general definition
and then another for a net comp and a
third for rescoff
the pros this is completely decoupled
much like the nmda work
in fact if we were to do this we might
consider moving that general definition
draft to the net mod working group
uh the cons there's there's more drafts
so
any comments on this in the very few
minutes that we have remaining
blood i see you're still in the queue do
you mean to be or did you just not exit
the queue
to exit it's the hand icon in the upper
left corner
okay i don't see any comments so my hash
there is just one more slide and now
i know we're out of time but i just
quickly can we do that next slide
um so i have uh so those are the
protocol independent questions i'll take
that
them all to the list uh for rest count
specific
i do and then there's another slide for
neck off but there are no i don't have
any netcon specific questions so there's
this is truly the last slide
if you will um the question is what
should the scope of the
leaf uh and the leaf lift list
targets be um and in particular
are we just doing the get method which
would be the
minimally invasive type thing because
after all we're talking about list
pagination so it's just
get that we're talking about or should
we
define leaf i'm sorry i said leaf i
meant list
list and leaf list those two
nodes as being
targets for all http methods so not just
get but
post put delete patch etc
all of them so you know the of course
the considerations
are you know for increasing the scope
would be it's it's more complete
slash pure but you know i question
there's actually little value i mean
putting or posting or patching to the
container is
equally good you never do you need to
actually target
the um the list itself of course that's
uh known or is shown but illustrated by
the fact that we don't do it today
um i think delete actually has a benefit
you could delete the entire list at one
go
as opposed to you know in case it hasn't
been wrapped inside of a dedicated
container
uh you know instead of having to delete
the entire container you could
delete the entire list that way so this
delete has some benefit
um but it is like i mentioned it's kind
of out of scope but the focus of this
work is to introduce list pagination
which would only be the get method
but you know while we're here should we
expand extend to support other methods
any comments on that or should i take it
to the list
i don't see any comments on that i will
take it to the list
and uh yeah like mentioned there there
are no there was another slide for rest
comp but there was nothing there i was
just asking if anyone had any comments
and then there was just a thank you
slide at the very end
that concludes everything for this
meeting um
so switching my house taking off my
contributor hat putting on my
chair hat um thank you everyone for
joining
and um do you have any comments closing
comments
i don't thank you i know it's late for
some folks
yes okay very good
thank you everyone and we'll uh
virtually see you next time or on the
list before then
okay bye
it's kind of funny i'm looking for a way
to end the meeting but i don't think
the options there it's just
we just exit we just leave the room