yep
yep we see you flipping slides yeah
yes i'm sharing the full screen i
shared the application before it seems
doesn't work
you
okay i guess we should get going
i got uh well 1201 my time
um chat
just typing i think uh hank i think
you're also unmuted i think the typing
we hear
might have been you that i might have
been no i'm
okay i never mute
uh tinder you want to kick us off
uh yes sir i can do this um
okay let's start
hello everyone welcome to the opposite
wg and
ops aerial meeting this is an online
virtual meeting for
itf 109 as usual
we start from the note well please make
sure you understand the note well
and those important legal issues
basically
all the contributions including your
write-up the
presentation the audio video need to
follow the item rules
firstly we come to the opposite wg
it's chaired by tianyang joe and hank
we would like to welcome hank as our
co-chair
hank would you like to say something
thanks tyrone this is hank
i'm joining ranks with joe and tyrin
apparently
and yeah i'm too going to support um
chair duties um i have a
tiny iot background people might have
seen me in the itf
and yeah i'm happy to help
good we're happy to have you here thanks
hank
and the is automatically
recorded
is there any volunteer for a minute and
the job
well i'll volunteer for minutes i've
already got kodi md up and if you're
going to flip the slides 10 randall
i'll try to keep up with the minutes
here in ether pad
and the jabber
i'll i'll look at jabber if i need to no
problem
rob also just texted chatted with me
that he can help with minutes so we've
got rob wilton and i
um minutes and i'll keep an eye on the
chat
jabber tab too
okay good
here is the working group status and
during the past
three months rfc aka 86
and rfc 8907
are published for from this working
group
congratulations to the authors and
thanks to the contributors
the young model automation framework
draft is now in the rfcq we do not have
much thing to do the tech cn data model
is sent to the asg
the network telemetry framework draft
finished the working group last call we
are reaching for the shop at the right
half
we nearly adopted three drafts the vpn
common yen
model mod tls profiles
funding and using geofeed data
and two existing drafts the l2 and m
and l3 nm are going well all of them are
very readable
i encourage more people to read and
comment and joe and hank do you have
anything to add
i i think the um i think alex clem
is acting a shepherd on ntf
as i recall or maybe it's yeah i think
it was ntf
um and we will be hearing from the l3
sm nm l2nm and the
common model um here uh we just adopted
geofeeds um
i i think randy commented that um the
submission queue had just closed uh but
but now that it reopened it's it's been
rebranded as a
an ops awg document
everything is up all of these slides
that you'll be seeing are up in data
tracker
there there is a ops area section at the
end of this
uh rob was telling me that they were a
little late in getting the slide so i
imagine if they have anything we'll
we'll get that up in data tracker as
well for you to look at
um yeah i think it's all i had to uh
to add here great
any more questions
here is the agenda we got
eight topics any agenda fashion
um if no let's start the presentation
and the first one the
mod tos profiles
okay
anybody to present uh tutors here
uh can you join um what you call it the
queue
will
i cannot control the panel because i'm
showing the screen
i'm looking at the panel
but i can't seem to ah here he is
hey hello can you hear me yes we can
hear you now
hey hey thanks uh uh this is thiru here
i'll be presenting updates to our mart
taylor's
professor iot devices draft next slide
please
[Music]
uh the draft was recently adapted by the
working group after
several comments from both this working
group and dls working group
uh so in the last couple of revisions
we've been updating the draft to address
these comments so uh i'll be going over
these
uh major updates and uh taking any
further questions and comments next like
please
[Music]
one of the major comments that we got
from the tls working group was to not
include any uh tls
values which we were including in the
prior versions uh the main reason was
that
grease values are supposed to be used
for test purposes to test the
extensibility failures
uh in case if the peers are not able to
understand
the new parameters and start failing so
ah that's
that was one of the major comments that
for future extensibility we should not
be including uh grease parameters and we
have updated the
our tls gtls profiles parameters not to
include any more grease values
and this also allows to have uh random
values to be incorporated in future
tls parameters uh with this change uh
the the way that the network security
service would start enforcing policies
is basically
only if the network security service is
aware of known tls parameters it would
enforce
policies otherwise it would just simply
ignore those parameters which are
unknown to it
next slide
uh i have listed few examples just to
demonstrate how uh
this extendability is introduced and how
uh misbehavior from an iot device
because of a malware or an authorized
software would be detected
uh for example if a details parameter is
not specified in the
uh mud tls profile but it is recognized
by firewall then in that case it would
recognize that as
an unrecognized software or on
authorized software and can take
remediation action
uh for example in this case if if the
chacha 20
uh cipher stream is uh not specified in
the mud tls profile
but the parameter is already known to
firewall then the firewall can take
various actions either it could be
blocking the flow or quarantining the
iot device and remediating the device
next slide please
uh the other one which is which is the
major one for
uh to handle cases where
you have grease values or any other
unknown values
in those cases the firewall would not
take any action for example in case
where the
charger 20 history cipher stream is not
specified in the tls profile
and it is unknown then the firewall
would ignore it so this is very similar
to
grease values being ignored by a
firewall as those values will never be
specified in the
mart tls profile next slide please
uh this is this is a this is the problem
probably uh with the race conditions
that uh whether the iot device gets
updated with the new tls extensions or
tls versions versus
the firewall getting updated before that
so for example if
the iot devices get updated to support
new extensions or new ciphers and the
firewall is not ready
uh then what would happen is the mud tls
profile would get updated
uh the new cipher stream for example the
charger 20 would be specified in the
multils profile but the firewall would
see that
this parameter is unknown to it and
immediately an alert would be triggered
to the
id administrator or the iot device owner
and as well as the firewall vendor who
is giving the network security service
the same applies to any other tls
extension or even
new tls versions for example if there is
a new tls version for example
is 1.3 and it's specified in the mud
tailless profile but the firewall is not
aware of it then
it would be triggered so this basically
ensures that
both the administrator of the iot device
and the network security provider
are aware of the firewall not
recognizing new parameters and if
the firewall is not readily updatable
its protection efficacy is going to
decrease with
time uh next slide please
[Music]
uh we have also updated the young module
to address several comments that we
received from med and others
uh especially to uh make sure that we
have an inr dtls
young profile to include the dtls
versions and dtls parameters
and those values are being used in the
acl which in turn is used in the
mud tls profile
next slide please
uh we also updated the mud uh mud uh
young module to say that whether the
device is indeed supporting that uh
tls gtls profile or not so a boolean
value is introduced so that uh
it would signal to the network uh
security device whether uh
the manufacturer is already supporting
this extension or not and that would
enable
uh the network security service to know
realize that it's not supporting and it
has to upgrade its
software to parse and understand these
new
tls profiles next slide please
uh the all the parameters that we have
in the inr tls profile
are are indeed picked from tls and dtl
assigner registries
uh excluding uh tls version dtls version
spk pin set and certificate authority
uh spk insight is basically pinning a
specific
public key or a certificate like
self-send certificate
and certificate authorities are specific
to each iot device we have seen
iot device based on manufacture make and
model
use certificate specific certificate
authorities which vary from device type
to
device type and those values have to be
defined has to be maintained and defined
by the manufacturer itself
inr dtls profi uh tls and dtls profits
does not maintain
any registries for dtls versions uh
because uh uh the way uh
the versions are maintained today is
because of extensibility
uh in tls 1.3 a new extension has been
introduced in which the version is
defined so that's the reason they are
not maintaining any registry for that so
those are the parameters which are uh
not present in the
tls and dtl as inr registries and those
are the ones that are being defined in
this
specification and whenever uh it's
pretty
easy to update the young modules because
we have new registries
uh whenever the dtls versions or details
parameter registry is added with
a new version or a parameter then the
young module would be
automatically updated by ayana
next slide please
that's it and uh any any further
comments and suggestions are welcome on
the draft
thank you
any comments questions
i don't see anyone coming in the queue
uh rob wilton is in the queue
uh rob so it's just a quick question
really i'm i'm not i missed the
very very beginning of this slide deck i
tried to check whether
the section folks had a chance to have
an early review of this just to check
the tls side of that or maybe they're
already hooked in
so that was only a question this this
draft was posted before adaption to both
tls
and ob security working group so we had
received
several of these updates were done to
address the comments that we had
received from the dns working group
brilliant thanks everyone's instead yeah
if there's no more comments so we will
go to the next
this one a second
matt
[Music]
matt yeah thank you uh
everyone yeah um yeah so this
this will be a i would say and a quick
update of the uh what we have done on
the
vpn common draft so you can just move to
the next line
this this yeah since the the drought was
adopted
last september we um we went to uh into
three vision of the draft and
the um the draft was already i would say
worked out
in the background with the um the team
working on the uh the various space vpn
paper there
so that's why we we have already i would
say a fair stable version when we
we presented the document to the working
group so the um
the first version um that we uh that we
released
um addresses mainly the comment that we
received during the
the working of last call said there are
some i would say
minor editorial ones from from the rule
to
better articulate how the um the camera
vpn model will i would say
um can be reused by future revisions of
the
the um the current l3 uh service model
and and il2 uh we think that we have now
i would say
better text so that people will
understand that this vpn camera model
can can be reused when there is any
future revision of this of this document
um
there's also one um i would say
important good comment from from italy
about the uh discovering of the um
of the weapon camera model and as you
remember during the last
meeting we have presented this scope to
be uh restricted only to um
to types and warping that that will be
reused by
all the four models and um but it i
don't think that's we
need to relax that a little bit so if at
least there are two models that are that
are
reusing some of the type we need to uh
to define them into the
the common model in the beginning i
personally don't want to uh to get that
path because otherwise we
there is a risk that that we will we
would like to be i would say
more exhaustive there and that
can i would say delay the publication of
the l3
l training um but after all after
discussion with the
with the theme and also with the
implementers i think that's as
as as we are just defining some kind of
library
it's just fine to uh to relax this
conference that you can put there what
we think that are really
um available and reusable from the uh
the current model so
we updated the uh the document to
include them i would say
specific items that are that are not
reused for example in the uh
l3 nm um draft but are
will be reused in the uh
[Music]
uh there was also a comment from italy
about the um
the the overall scope of the draft he
proposed that we um
not respect the the kind of types and
the group technology
to the vpn but to define it as a service
generic model
and that one we i think yeah
for me that's we are going too far there
so
we discarded that that command and we
think that yeah
so that there are models are currently
worked in the uh c camp working in
france
that can reuse this this model but it's
it's up to them to to decide to justify
why do you want to reuse it but we
cannot claim on our side that we will
cover every service so
we want something that will be really
aligned and focused
and respected to what your working group
is doing that is that
vpn uh vietnamese services
we included a note in the in the drive
to uh to make that sure
and the the last the last modification
we have made is about yeah and it's more
i would say to include more description
more um i would say
missing references closer than as tom
patch has proposed in the
working of last call so i think that we
um we have we have done i would say most
exercise there there are always uh
thanks to be to be completed but i think
that we
we have made some fair progress on that
part
uh and as you can see in the next slide
um
we also released the
second version there um actually when we
started to um
to seriously work on the uh nm uh we
have found that there are some i would
say some group in there that
that can be um move to the common one
and
and then that are also um can be reused
also in the uh
in iltran m so we simplified also again
the uh
deltoid m and moved the many of the
the groupings and types into the the
common model and we uh we have uh
updated the um all the three model that
is the l2nm
l train and and the vpn camera model
um so so right now we um
i would say the uh the current pin
depending on which action from on our
side as you can see in the next slide is
that um as far as we
will progress on the l2 nm and given
that we uh we think that you are already
have a stable version on the l3m
we will keep monitoring the how tanks
are
are moving uh so that we can um update
if a
um if required uh the the camera model
to uh to
make remove some of the component that
we will found in the
indeed two m into uh to the common one
uh
next slide please so this is what what i
i
um i was mentioning this second bullet
here about the synchronization between
the
the other streams we have
joe has already sent a request to the um
to the young doctors to have an earlier
review of the document that we think
that's
we we start to have something which is
um i would say
in in good shape um modulo this um i
would say this happened in
action uh on the uh m uh so we hope to
have i would say um
feedback from them and we will address
that as soon as we receive them
so the plan here is to um to it to uh to
have a working platform for the full set
of the
vpn documents meaning the l2 nm iltranim
and the
vpn camera model and as usual
we need the fresh eyes on the document
as we it's
more than year rounds that we are
working on these documents and it's
uh it's always good to have outsider to
to look into the document and to
to give us their reviews and comments so
that we can react on them as soon as
possible and this has been a
presentation
so if there are any question or comment
please uh not to date
uh yeah a a clarifying question med um
back a few slides can run if you if you
could
um one could keep going back
uh that one um when you said working
group last call
you you meant comments raised during the
adoption call
ah yeah yeah that's that's that's only
uh yeah it's the adoption called yeah
yeah okay cool i wanted to make sure
um so you you commented on the thing
yeah uh
these will be um they'll go through last
call
altogether and and we just put in a
working uh
yang doctor early review um i've read
the
the latest common model um
document um no major thoughts
on my part as a contributor
but one thing i noticed is there there
are a few comments in there
early on like this might be applicable
to
l2 xm's or something along that
and i thought i like that i like that
you were at least at least initially
starting to group things um or or have
com
elements that that one might use in this
type of
model either at a certain layer or a
certain type of yang module
but it seemed to get lost towards the
end meaning
at least the way i read it i things seem
to be mixed between
sms and l3 and l2 and i
i guess my suggestion is more of a knit
really is
is i like that organization to be able
to where possible
keep things um side by side where they
make sense so that if i'm looking for
things that are i don't know what the
best kind of
organization is but if i'm looking for
things that are more
maybe l2 versus l3 and then within that
you have nm versus sm
i i just thought that would have been
easier to read through some of the yang
module semantics and kind of understand
uh where i might find things that i
could i could extract
that makes sense yeah that's that's a
fair comment that you will think
and yeah how to make this a bit area
thanks other questions or comments from
the working group
i don't see anyone coming up to the q
med so i think you're good thank you
thanks
okay next one oscar will present
hi good morning guys so now that med has
presented you the common module
now we are going to go through the two
modules the
l3 and the l2 modules that
use this one so here also you have the g
tripos where we keep
all the issues so in the l3 and then
preco we keep
all the issues for three names in the
20m1 the similar form too
uh however we decided to keep all the
junk
together in the l3 nm prepo
for better checking so we do continuous
checks
on the on the junks all the of the three
modules together okay so if you want to
go for the latest uh
code it is the l3 name repo that holds
all of them the common uh l2 r3 okay so
next is like this
okay so first i'm going to tell you
a couple of slides about what are the
latest in the
changes since the last idf
so we were waiting to
have the common module to address all
the young
all the young doctors of your comments
so now finally
in the latest published version we have
addressed all the all the comments
so there were some minor editorial
issues like the nba compliance days
some just minor editorial
we also had some clarifications of the
use of appendix a so we
we included this list of available
implementations
so we just follow the guidelines for rfc
6982 about the implementation status
section so we put all the clarifications
also we did a lot of cleanup
of the of the groupings so you know that
the first version of m3nm had a lot of
a lot of groupings so now all the
groupings are in the common
module so here we are reusing all of
them so
in the latest version available in
indeed i think we have
only one grouping left in l3 n1 is a
just a pure l3 specific
grouping that is not nm grouping that is
not reusable for
for other parts okay
[Music]
so this new young module uses all the
all the vpn
common that has been explained so also
we added some
text in the draft explaining the
rationale and which are the relation
with this coming
home module also we added some
section on the sample uses of the other
3m
model so to explain so for example how
to use it to
for enterprise layer 3dps services for
multi-domain cases
and we plan to add some
some more here just the explanation okay
also we added some completed
explanations of the
of the different sections of the draft
so for example we explain
the the role of the vpn profiles and
some
some examples uh there was also some
change to add the vpn type to
include the kind of a service signaling
type here
also we added some text to explaining
that from next slide please
er also we added some text to to explain
uh the underlay the underly transport
you know that the underlying transport
here is
in in the vpn uh what are you using to
er between the pes so for example if you
are using traffic engineering if you are
using ldp
segment route etc okay
then these complements too there is some
work
done in the tias working group where
they are doing the extensions
okay so if you choose to have a t as
under the transport all the extensions
that tell you which is the mapping is
that
of the mapping of the tunnels
to the to the service itself
that is done in tia's working group
extending
the a l3 nm
okay also we had an issue pending i
think it was like the
last two three itfs we had a lot of
discussions on the
are the assignment route assignment and
we had a
lot a lot a lot of discussions
in the in the list and implementation
feedback so we finally got
hey joe i'm not like seeing anything
under the show
show your hands too so just count me as
a plus one
sorry
all right there was a comment
now we show them the the earlier
assignment we have a choice now
with the four options with a directly
assigned with a pull a full out assign
and no rb so this is the the selected
choice so
please go on next slide
so we have just in this version we
solved the
all the open issues a indeed house so we
have just a few open
a few open issues since the last one so
you see that
uh i have number here that is in indeed
half so
so you see we are in the 180 something
just open because all the previous ones
were
were close so there are just some minor
territorial things
to to finalize so
to double check all the all the trees in
the document
and review the readability of the draft
of the
different sections review all the bgp
descriptions
we have some suggestions also for
example for the
for the if we want to incorporate to the
to the young model uh service visibility
flag
okay so instead of we are just using we
are using the model to request a till
the creation of a new series
so we wanted to double check if we can
use it for also for
service visibility not only creation
we need to do some cleanup on the
service type and the signaling option
type
so to avoid this over some overlapping i
think that the term might still have
some overlapping so we need to check
double check on that
we need to review the pc security
section
there are some manual things to add on
the on the static routes
also we have from the original
l3sm and we have the access to the
content service
to the cloud service provider so we need
to double check whether this still
applies also to the
network model and we also need to
use the commentation of ipv4 addresses
in the and ipv6 in the in the examples
okay so with just minor comments here so
let's go to the next
last slide so
so with this we think that all the
issues that we have uh
within the qualification of the last
draft were were solved so just minor
issues has
left us as explained er
we are using all the the common the
common module
so we think this is in this version is
stable it's
not gonna suffer major changes so it's
almost
ready for the working group class call
[Music]
so as in the other
as also said in the common module
the more is into the document the better
so please check because i think this is
the document that is
more stable so there are questions for
for this draft if not we can
jump to the next one
okay so for the l2nm uh
as in the previous case we updated the
the young module to use
the vpn command module groupings also
in the text we have started to do some
editorial work
to explain the common relation with the
draft and
add the different explanations of the of
the groupings that are
that are used and some
editorial improvements so we explain the
vpn profiles the signal and options the
vpn networks
connections etc i think there is still
some some work to
to do in the tutorial but we started
moving that
so we also have a big change as the the
full tree was too long
we cutted it and dissected into soup
trees
in different sections so then
i think it's much readable so
next slide please so
here uh as we mentioned that the l3 name
was very stable
and this l2 name is much stable but
there is only one
there is one major thing but we need to
finalize to to consider the
the draft let's say stable iran is the
complete avpr support okay so
i think among all the different layer
two types
all of the others were pretty much
covered but the vpn still had a
had some some gaps so in order to
support the vpn creation
for the service type we need to cover
the different
flavors of pva vpn vs land uspn the
classical vpn we need to add the
internet segment identifier
and there are some specific service
parameters like the english regulation
they are biproxy suppression anti-proxy
etc so there are particular vpn
parts and also we need to cover the
particular pvp
service parameter so for the pvp case
also we need
the pvb vpn flavor also we need to cover
the rtrds
that we are releasing all that from the
vpn code module we need to address value
also we will use that for the vpn common
we need to add the bridge domain
the mod type and also we need to add all
the i
am backbone identifier components
uh to include them here next slide
please
so also related to the
to the vpn uh people studying
is contributing with a lot of issues
so here i just put a sample even
after creating these slides there were
more comments reason
or more issues reason in the jit
regarding evpn so
you see that still we have uh
quite quite a few work on the vpn okay
and then we also have some
common l2 things so for example they
haven't shown how the present type is
different from the access priority
when we were requested also to add
examples
uh of the l two and m okay so similar
that we did in the l three
and here to add some some examples
and there is also an issue
there is a limit on the elements from
point to point on a
services okay so we need to solve this
issue so go to the slide please
so well the next steps in this draft is
so mainly is complete abp and support
solve all the open issues that we have
in github
and of course here please send us
senders reviews for this document
and because we think from all the three
tasks this is the
the one that still has some some more
work and some more work to do
and so we hope that the next version we
can solve all these
all these issues and then we complete
the pack for the next call
or the last call so
[Music]
questions
we have rob uh in the queue
uh just as a participant um so just a
quick question
i i think you're splitting up of the um
tree output in the documents is useful i
did wonder whether or not
it might also be useful to include the
full tree out put in the appendix
um so i i'm not sure i feel that
strongly about
it but it's just something to consider
maybe it might make it too long
it may be a bit repetitive but it's
certainly something that's worth
considering is
is whether that would be useful to
readers of this document or whether it
just adds an extra
10 or 15 pages that isn't useful i don't
know but maybe it's worth considering
okay the the thing with the with the
full tree also it was it was
so long not only in lines but also
the length it went very deep inside so
this is also why we decided to
to cut in in some trees so
yeah but then
well that sounds reasonable then that
sounds like reasonable answer if it ends
up being
so far uh indented due to the depth of
it then and it's not useful
uh then that makes sense and it's always
possible that people could generate this
from tooling fairly easy anyway
so that's not too much of a concern okay
i would say to uh to to the comments
from moscow that this this will be i
would say it will
it will be split over tens of pages and
it's really hardly readable and
personable by bed readers there's also i
would say
one more uh logistic issue there is that
the the current tools when generating i
would say the um
the the young tree tables um
we will end with the i would say we want
to represent the
the limit on the on the on the length on
the i would say
on the uh on the lines and the um
currently what we have done in the um
even with the
the the extract and the subtree that we
are pushing into the um
the core document we are modifying
manually the trees that you can
you can you can you can pass the net
check so
it would be a really a nightmare for us
if we include that one because we won't
have that
possibility to modify manually the trees
and so on so
i would personally avoid having that the
default tree there we can put it on the
github and we already have a copy of
that in the github and we can add a
pointer
if the work working group won't decide
that but i i wouldn't
put again the default tree because it's
really a nightmare
and um another question i have for the
uh for the for for
for the working group and also the chair
is that as you have seen the uh
in the presentation from from horse cars
that we we have i would say
a lot of issues currently in the in in
to a m so
and there is a risk that we it depends
on the activity and the energy that we
will put on this one but
um if we delay this um
the the vpn work and also the d3
iltranm document until we have i would
say a frozen version on the
into a name we will do our best to
to to to have that but there is a risk
that um
that the work may last longer so um
would be fair if we i would say at the
um if
we fix a medicine or did not to say that
yet if by
the middle of next year we don't have a
stable version
or we still see comments on the
ill-2 nm it would be i would say
feasible that we
we just run the working of last call on
the uh
3m and the the common model or we we
have to hope to get started on the
a2nm so this this this is a risk that
i'm seeing on on the set
um rob were you still in queued um
before i
was gonna yeah but if you have something
i'll just quickly reply to um let's
first comment
uh yes i think it's not to include the
tree out but
one other possibility would be just to
have um
maybe appendix instructions of how to
generate that or a point to how it could
be generated
but that might be one alternative way of
not completing the saying
using this tooling you could generate
the output right i don't think that's
useful or not
but i agree not including this it's just
going to be
useless information
so i on your second comment med i was
going to
try this fancy um uh show of hands tool
and i'm uh um
showing uh asking a question how many
people have read the current versions of
these
l 2 l 3 nm
drafts as well as the common module
raise your hand please
i'd like to get an idea of how
how many working group eyes have been on
this um just so we can get an idea
towards your question of if if there
if there's been a number of people
who've read this
um and and from an implementers and a
an operator's standpoint um that feel
the l three and m
is is ready and the common module
importantly
is um uh common enough
so to speak then maybe to your point if
if there really is
a struggle in in l2 and m that that
there might be a need to
to call a working group last call
ideally as i told
a number of you and the authors
i think it would be good to do it all
together that said i think there's
definitely interest i don't think
leaving l2m off would
would cause it to never progress
um but i i think there's there's value
in making sure everything
is is is properly um sewed up on all of
them
that's one chair's opinion but it looks
like
so far uh i don't know if we're gonna
get many more 10 people have raised
their hand that they have read it
six have not raised their hand
indicating that they have not read the
latest versions
um i haven't read i've read the latest
version of vpn common and
l3 i haven't gotten through l2
personally
so let me ask i'll end this session
should we do
a working group last call of l3 nm
independently if
issues still exist after
110 on l2 nm and by 110
i mean ietf110 um
next spring spring 2021
so it seems that there is lots of hands
going up quickly i mean we had 10 total
hands raised on the last one
we have seven hands raised no hands not
rays eight hands
uh raised
more hands going up so i i think it's
worth uh considering i i think
chances are if we put this out on the
working group um
alias that that chances are that that
would be the case
i would uh speaking as co-chair
uh um encourage the
the inter the the the people in the
working group working on
this uh to to work through those issues
let's see if we can get
uh some some more reviews like a and we
talked about a yang doctor's early
review of the l2 and m
let's see if we can get some of those
issues resolved but it sounds like
there's
certainly interest in in getting the l3
nm
out there um assuming that we make sure
that the common module
is sufficiently common um so hopefully
that addresses your comments their med
or question i should say
thank you thank you and one last um i
would say um
information is that um we have many
implementers that are involved in this
work and we have um
an appendix in which we we we provide a
pointer to uh to all
to each of these implementations and all
this information is available on the
github so yeah so this is a
joint work which is currently done with
the involvement of mini paper
and and i would also encourage you
speaking of github
come back if if there are more eyes that
you need on specific
um issues you you didn't ask a lot of
pointed questions here in this
presentation and by
you i mean oscar presented but in
general the authors
if there are things that you want more
broader eyes of the working group to get
consensus on please don't hesitate to
ask those questions and let's get uh
let's get that discussion going or those
discussions going
on on the list so we can get through
some of those issues
so here for this particular draft the i
think
the the biggest thing that we need in
there to name is
more experts on only vpn
okay so i think it's the what caused
some
or some more delay in advance it was
getting
getting people with knowledge from evp
and now we are getting it okay so we are
getting people that is implementing it
and so on but we need if we can have
more maybe some
we could promote also the work maybe in
base and in other
routine working groups to uh to have the
the rice into into it
okay um that
certainly is is doable we could we could
uh request some eyes over there um i can
reach out to the the chairs as well over
there and see if there's anyone we could
get to
get some reviewers looking at l2 and m
to help out
with some of those issues um sorry
didn't mean to monopolize time
you asked a chair question any other
comments from co-chairs or from the
other working group members
don't see anyone coming in the queue so
i
thank you med and oscar for presenting
and for con
leading and continuing the work with the
working group um
thanks
so we go to the next one
mic check yeah
good randy yep check check you are
you're loud and clear
okay this draft was revised
during adoption
so take it home
feed it and be nice to it and it should
be good to you
um the
suspects i don't know why massimo wanted
to start this
i did most the drafting work uh warren
and
eric klein who's too modest to be here
on
from google brought in the google work
which you'll see and russ did the
security stuff
next slide please ipg
location is to deal with country
regulations and localization etc
i.e you know there's a special version
of game of thrones playing in washington
dc now
um and you're not supposed to see it
anywhere else next slide please
who does
geolocation here are the organizations
providing the service
of if you have an ip address they will
give you a good guess as to where it is
the quality of the guesses vary
considerably um there are even
researchers who
compared them so next slide please
if you go to watch that next slide
please
if you go to watch that version of game
of thrones and you can't
i.e if your data for your ip address are
incorrect
you have to contact all of those people
and they take weeks to turn things
around
and you see people putting out pleas on
anag every week saying
i'm in bialystok and i can't watch
whatever
next slide please the basic problem is
that this is uncoordinated
and all those different providers of
information
are kind of almost doing research
so there's no real data
repository there is no ground truth
okay next slide please
so how do they come up with their
guesses
heavily used dns stated who is data
dns in the sense that lots of
routers have location in their names etc
etc
tons of strange magic but
to the rescue a gang of pretty much
googlers who have this problem big time
of course
came up with rfc 8805 which is a
definition
of a csv file which can
for prefix ranges
have country and
state or whatever font city
and that's the granularity because finer
they're worried about in some places if
you get
down to the postal code
it reveals personal information too much
so this is about the limit of the game
but rfc 8805
describes geofeeds files
next the four form
next thank you the format
is the rfc you publish only what
you want to publish it's flexible you
can geolocate single ips
entire prefixes instead of as prefix
match of course
and whatever you level you wanted
to for instance you could publish only
the country
or all the way down to the city level it
has been adopted by google and
a whole bunch of those providers are
listed
on slide three next slide please
to discuss the geofeed format you can go
to the geofeeds working
group there isn't one but let's not
discuss it here
next slide please but how do you
find geofeed profiles that's the problem
okay or at least that's the problem this
draft tries to address
next slide please
we use the irr who
is and these are the inec num objects
that are the external visible allocation
records
of the r rir
that says for this range
this is the authoritative
record since we cannot modify this
easily and you'll
see that we have a proposal for doing so
it has a remarks field and in that
remarks field
the person the organization which
controls the identity which
is the admin and tech contacts
who have that address space put this
url of where you can find
a file with the geofeed information
for that address range in the idea
next slide please
remarks that's disgusting next slide
please
the next gen in the irr
records will instead have a geo feed
attribute but of course
that's all in the rpsl working group
except there isn't one so the
rirs are talking and conspiring
and maybe this will come out in the
meantime
you learn to eat both and
deprecate one with the remarks field
but it's later there's a cute trick
about using this hui's data
next slide please that when you query it
for a particular address
the who is server returns the closest
covering range
so this works much better than a hack
like
dns where you would have to have an
exact
record for that address
okay so this is just god knows
why this happens in who is
but that's what the rirs do it's really
kind of nice
next slide please
now remember an eye net number points to
a geofeed file
but multiple ionic numbers could point
to the same geofeed file
and when you go to fetch following a
particular identity
you close your eyes to all the ones not
covered by that item
okay so use the longest match
and only what is covered
next slide please
and of course there's a nice knit six
num
multiple of them can point to the same
file
please feed them over https
and now we get into why russ is here
which is an optional authenticator may
be appended
because there's a problem the
authenticity of an eye net noun
in the who is um
let's say that the quality of
update controls varies across who is
systems across our irs
so is the geofeed data
really authorized
the eye net numb provides you some
assurance
so what we propose is
to have a digest of the main body of the
file of
piece you've been looking at is digested
and then
signed by the private key of the
relevant
rpki certificate for the covering prefix
this is optional
by the way of course aaron being a
unicorn
doesn't use highneck numbers they use
knit range but it's the same act
next slide please here's an example of
the strong signature
okay it's now
because it is signed by
the key of
the rpki record for that
range that signature cannot be good
for some other geofeed pointer
into this file so when there's a
signature
it can only represent one address space
next slide please you can
parse bulk who is data the rirs all
provide bulk data
over ftp et cetera et cetera aaron is
a unicorn of course you can ask and the
geoproviders get it use the data
and you can get the net range from bulk
and
comments from who is an ardex
next slide please and of course
there's an app for that it's on github
there's the url
you get a linux
binary and or sources and all the other
usual things
you run the darn thing it goes to all
the rirs it fetches
all the hue to his data and it produces
a results csv file to cover everything
for you if you're doing
lookups
and that's the story
and we really appreciate more reviews
reviews by the way people have been very
helpful
um and we don't want to threaten wglc
just to get more review but we would
really appreciate it
and of course massimo would love people
to run his code
and this is in use
questions
questions let me check the chat
there um there are a few comments in the
chat
from george michaelson and tom hill
randy
it looks like in general support for
this work
george has said people don't understand
that almost all economy assertions and
who is for numbers are about the entity
head office location
and not the network of use unless the
records are more specific than the
delegation record
and randy's on the money with this draft
it is a huge problem
so tom just plus one that so
i think there's in general support on
this
ntt is in tokyo right
i'm at the end of an ntt circuit here in
california now
somebody popped in the queue for a
moment
i was off that screen any other comments
for randy questions
answers
it's been fun thank you thanks randy
so we go to the next slide
uh can you hear me yes
hello uh uh my name is edna and
i'll be presenting uh ipfx
information element extension for
forwarding exceptions
uh this is the first time we are
presenting this in the atf and
uh i'll be presenting this zombie on
behalf of my co-authors
um next slide please
so just to give you some background on
what the draft is
uh so when you think of a network uh
traffic drops are generally generally
generally normal and they often go
unnoticed
unless unless there is a there is an end
service that is impacted
so detecting and identifying
and repairing the traffic drop in in
huge networks uh
can be uh mechanical and and very very
tedious
uh so in order to eliminate this this
tedious workflow
uh in uh in identifying and repairing
the networks
we can focus on simply localizing the
problem and
building correlation to some to some
entities
which which are responsible for dropping
the packets
if you the drop packets can can undergo
some deep inspection uh and
uh the some metadata can be can be
fetched from these drop packets can be
sent to the host
or the software queue along with the
type of exception
that that that has invoked this drop
and some metadata in this case like
in and out interface and some other
metadata
which i'll be covering in the in the
next slides uh next slide please
so um yeah as i just mentioned so the
exception information
may be exported in any format that is
desired the
uh some of uh some of you we can also
use
young or uh ipf expo so this this
proposal uh
specifically focuses on ipfix for
exporting uh the drop packet
uh information um so some of the
uh information elements uh that that
that can be used to export metadata are
already exist
this draft defines a new information
elements along with the corresponding
formats for these new new information
elements
needed for the metadata next slide
please
uh so uh the forwarding exceptions that
that we'll be focusing on are that that
generally uh uh responsible for
for the traffic for the traffic drop um
so the information elements that
that that we report as part of as part
of this mechanism
uh may change based on based on the type
of forwarding exception that has
occurred
on on a particular network um the
this subset of information may be uh
really
key in order to identify where the
traffic drop is
in in a huge network so if
when the packet drop happens or when a
traffic drop happens
uh what is the reason for the traffic
drop which flow has encountered this
drop
which includes the packet content which
which gives us the source
source for source port and destination
board source ip destination ib
and a few other details and some
additional metadata including what what
the flow direction is
uh what the next app index is uh input
and output interfaces
and and a few other details uh if if
needed
next slide please
so focusing uh on this on this draft we
have
we have proposed a new information
element called forwarding exception
called
uh which is a unique identifier
describing
the the reason for the for the traffic
drop
some irregularity or some traffic drop
uh
so we have uh this this particular
forwarding exception code can
can have different uh data records uh uh
indicating what forwarding error has
caused the traffic drop
so this can be we have identified a few
common ones uh an implementation may
choose to encode
its own internal device internal device
exception codes
in such scenarios enterprise bit may be
set to one
or else uh if if if if an implementation
may choose to use
the ident common identified exception
codes they may they may set the
enterprise bit to zero
next slide please
uh in addition to the forwarding
exception code we have
we also had the need to uh export
what the next stop id is a next stop id
is something that
that identifies the destination
inside a particular device um
typically represented in a forwarding
path as an index so
this this is very very useful in order
to
fetch more details on on what the what
the next stop in the next hub looks like
uh and the next stop that the packet
would take uh
so in order to do some deep inspection
uh so this
this next stop id would could include
some information about uh the outgoing
interface and the forwarding features
configured on the packet path
uh etc uh so there's a unique identifier
uh on any on every
on on every device so
this this is something that will be
really useful in identifying
uh the next the next stop details on on
every packet
next slide please
uh so this this this uh
basically captures uh what uh
a dropped uh exception packet would look
like uh in ipfx
uh it includes it includes some of the
some of the fields that
uh that are key now in order to identify
uh the which which devices
is dropping the packets and and which
flow is actually encountering this crop
so it can be represented in in any
format any which format uh we see two
different formats here
and it any any number of fields any
any number of other metadata fields can
be added to this template
uh so this is just a representation of
uh what uh how how we
uh capture different uh information
elements uh
from every device uh in order to uh
specifically
point out uh which entity has undergone
some traffic drop
and what is the reason for it uh next
slide please
so uh yes uh since this is the first uh
this is the first time we are
presenting this uh we are we're looking
for some feedback
uh and uh if yeah if you have any any
questions
uh suggestions uh there they're
absolutely welcome
questions
so i i had one as a contributor on the
next top id i
i wasn't really clear on what
that would be um or or i imagine this
would be something that's very vendor
specific
and there would be some way of decoding
that 64-bit value um
because you you don't really give a very
prescriptive you said it could be
egress interface it could be other
forwarding characteristics but there's
nothing
that i saw in the draft that was
like here's an example or anything
prescriptive
of of what that could be and i know in
one template you have egress interface
there so i imagine there's other
richness
that that would give you but i wasn't
clear on exactly how i would
if i was implementing this how i would
populate that
uh yes so uh next up uh we will add the
we'll add an example for the next stop
id uh in the in the next revision um
okay thanks
um we have two in the queue uh
jin ben
question
and ben can we can't hear you if you're
asking if you're speaking
okay uh yeah i i i think this is
uh hello yeah we can hear you
hello i'm saying that this is okay yeah
uh i i log in from hobby but i think
this is a truly a useful use case yeah
because we know that
in the ip there's always something the
forwarding errors
so i think the detailed information act
of course will to help the
troubleshooting i think this is a useful
use case piece
yeah okay
uh and we have shivam in the queue
i guess can you hear me we can
yeah hey i'm one of the co-op for this
so i think there was a question related
to
um what does the next stop uh actually
mean uh right
so i i just wanted to add uh so imagine
uh let's say
uh in a normal forwarding path uh a
packet arrives you do a lookup in the
forwarding table right
typically the result of the lookup is a
next stop the tech top is nothing but it
represents recording path that the
packet will eventually take
and it is supposed to uh translate into
packet going out of a
specific interface so obviously packet
is able to successfully
uh go out of that interface then you
will also have the ingress interface
material time permission set
as is displayed in the template right
but let's say the drop happens somewhere
in between
right you need to know um which path the
packet was taking so
next stop id in that case can be that id
with internal your system represents
that forwarding path
and let's say a bunch of uh
show commands on your node or or
metadata that you have
would wear on the controller can be used
to correlate saying that
this next hop id actually represented
this outgoing interface and therefore
the packet
uh during this process
that is pretty much this command okay
yeah
i i think seeing an example or
understand that
could could certainly help because it
feels kind of nebulous the way it's
written right now
but but thanks for that sure sure we'll
we'll cover that
other questions
uh rudiger i see you in the queue as
well
we can't hear you okay
yeah oh we can hear you more
fine um i
would suggest to
uh look at
the question of how to form it
and how to define and how to define the
schema for the data
afresh
i highly suggest when
to look at cddl
schema and seabor encoding
and removing essentially
the need for interpreting large ascii
art
uh sure ready could you yeah
that's that's uh uh interesting comment
so uh uh
we will we'll look in there could could
you also uh respond uh
uh uh on the on on the mailing list uh
we will follow up that
i'll try thank you
and uh i'd encourage to everyone to
review this
and any any comments or suggestions
would be really great
thank you folks thanks
okay let's go to the next presentation
i'm a new camera and i'm very happy to
join such a big family
okay today my topic is network
monitoring or idp
next slide please
um first i introduced the previous work
uh
last year a draft a draft about the
network wide
protocol the monitoring at the summit
some use needs are identified in aid
the or already originally now the
modification motivations
are as follows first is the quickly
reporting
especially the adp protocols containers
need to be reported
reported quickly and the second
is the high performance means processing
maybe the binary encoding it has the
more better the
performance than other encoding and the
study is
we want to get a protocol that is the
easier to standardize
and analyze though by the monitoring
scope
at first we want to support the includes
the adp
ldp and svt and river and so on
in fact the the the idea about
the monitoring the adp and
first of all first the president either
the 135 with the atf meeting
okay next slide please
let me talk about the recent changes
with the input from the customer
discussion and the new standard process
under the demo verification result we
identified some idp use case
and also the performance we find the is
similar
between the telemetry based and the bmp
live
and the last last changes the scope
and we find that in fact the for rib we
find the young module
for the river has been defined in rfc
and about the svt and ldp
with the rapid development of the
rooting technologies the rsvt and rdp
is replaced so next so
so the current drought we focus on the
idp
only okay next slide please
uh here are at least two adp use case
the first one is isis rupert piping
and the locating of the
flipping source and the identifying of
the root causes haven't been
easy work due to various reasons the
cause may be
systematic reflux or acid snapship
driving or driving and so on
and another use case is sdb and
secondation
failure during the isis flooding
however sometimes the lsp the
synchronization feeling happens
the cost maybe has a lot maybe the first
day the
identity is not creative advice is the
white history
or transmission error or is received but
now the current process oh this is the
tool you feel for
access okay on that side please
okay
okay so we're recording the
accordion that we introduce the case
under
the original the motivations so we
we stress in the two solution options
the operation one
is bmp-like we can also define the new
bmp message types
and the game from work our new protocol
and open tool is a telemetry based we
can define the young module for s
for assist the message so
that's all okay any
thanks looks like robin's back at the
mic
robin
hello yep we can hear you
okay uh robin from javi uh i added some
uh add some of the points uh
besides the presentation uh in fact that
we truly
have this work uh two years ago
but we later we we explained
we found that there's a lot of a lot of
things that happens in the routine area
so that
these are the points that we truly
identify the possible use cases
that that's necessary to export
the uh idp protocol data
i mean the the uh rsa
packet or the our
rsp pdu package for the
troubleshooting or other usage but
from our point of view maybe is a little
difficult
to defend the young model for such a
work so that we want uh
to limited the scope of this work
and try to unify the igp and the bdp
to export the protocol related
data with the similar mechanism
that's the the the work so
i wanted to collect the feedback from
this
the working group and also this is the
ops
area yeah that's uh at this point for
the clarification
um thanks i i i would suggest
i haven't seen this round any discussion
on the ops
awg list i would suggest raising what
you
the points you want to get clarity on
there um
and and the previous uh time the related
work was presented
i think people from um i want to say
grow
as i recall um commented um so it might
be good to
get just to get their uh
take on this as well um from the routing
area it sounds like maybe you've already
done some of that
but bringing that into the the working
group would be
would be useful to trigger or catalyze
some of those conversations on the list
okay okay i this uh okay we will try to
do this work and also use it to engage
the
grow area and also the routine area
people okay thanks and ram you're in
queue
uh yes i've i've not read this draft i'm
just looking at the slides here
i think the the big question for me is
still as to
why we'd want a new protocol here um
rather than like use what's already
there and
specifically on the first slide there's
a comment saying that it'd be easier to
define a new protocol
than to try and define uh the data that
needs to be exported in yang and i
um i'm struggling to understand why that
is
uh and even in the case that you um
may not want to expand the news out into
the yang
you could still carry them in the in a
yang data model
encoded um as binary pdus of binary data
so
i think for me the key thing here is to
try and
understand the data you're trying to
export
off and to understand um clearly
what what doesn't work with the existing
protocols
have they been tried and before we
go down the path of trying to invent a
new protocol here because that would
seem to be
significantly more work naively
i understand your point in fact in this
draft this in order to propose this is
the new protocol
here is also mentioned because in this
draft we propose that
the reusing the pmp for this
for this requirement user just to extend
several the message type only used for
the
for the idp so this is the
this is the proposal in this draft
and also you mentioned that's the
possible this is the young model
uh yeah because we also use the learned
uh
discuss with some of the young model uh
experts
and also because of
a little concern is that to export
the uh the protocol the
protocol the package through the model
i we are not experiencing enough in this
one
so we would like to collect the more
feedback
yes through this the main list well
thanks very
much for your comments
just just to add one more comment to
that then i again it goes back to i
think
focus on on clearly what the data is
that you want to export
and then that might help guide you with
what the right answer is
is there may be that actually that you
want to try and do it both ways i
have bmp extensions if that's possible
i don't know bmp very well and also
define it in yang
um one other comment was about the
encoding performance of using xml json
and a different path there is to use um
either cbor
as a binary encoding i know that netcomp
doesn't support that today but that is
something there's been some interest in
or to use gpb if you use going through
that stack
okay okay okay thanks
other questions actually i think we
probably want to move on to give ops
area some time
so yes please take your questions to the
list
uh robin um
thanks
[Music]
oh i think you're up okay thank you
can hear me we can yes
and this is paul uh i'm
going to present this uh vpn performance
monitor young model
on behalf of all the other
authors next please
oh it seems not
complete with the figure but actually
this figure is
from rp 41
76 it's about the framework
for layer 3 uh vpn operational
and management and this figure is about
the customer view of the different vpn
manager function
and you can see uh on the bottom of this
figure there's a vpn assurance function
there
so it means that uh the the customer
doesn't uh uh aside from the
the older uh implementation then
they also want some performance
monitoring to provide it to evaluate
whether the product is in good
condition then next
and then uh i mean the previous one
it seems yeah
and different also from the the same
dropped
and the last page is from the customer
view
and from the network review the provider
management system
must monitor the devices those devices
that
to implement the service uh the way
uh the the goal is to evaluate
the program uh whether they match the
service fls so
i i will so that's the intention here
then next slide please
given the working group
has already worked on the
modeling based framework
for automation of service and network
management
we can see that the figure
is from the automation draft
and uh and there three
nm and layers three uh two nm uh
have have been developed to fit for the
service delivery automation process
but the performance monitoring and
notification is still missing there
so this draft is trying to fill this gap
so this is the our function of this
draft
so next please next slide please
uh our um modeling uh cons
approach is to augment
uh rc 83 45
because uh it has defined the
physical network topology so
uh our thinking is we all we can augment
that dropped
with a more uh vpn performance monitor
data to extend it
on it so we can see a whole picture of
the vpn services on the performance
monitor part
so you can see in this figure uh
the the position of this model is the
similar
position as their service network models
so next slide please
then uh in this slide uh
we i give some example
on the the relationship
with the vpn performance monitor model
and uh
the 83 45 the basic
network topology model uh we
our consideration our proposal is to
extend the nodes and sometimes
links or uh termination points
with the corresponding vpn
data on it so in that way we can
not only associate the vpn
services via the underlay network
topology
but also we can see on on
that on top of that uh what the current
european statistics is like uh what kind
of uh
topology and uh what's the current uh
european
uh routine pair on each uh site
uh the usage uh later on that
and on the bottom uh i give some
example on the how this model
being uh created like uh after the
weapon service configuration has uh
completed then
uh the existing om mechanism can be
used to collect the the different uh
data of vpn services
so in the third step
we can collect the telemetry data of
between
ins interfaces uh tunnel
nodes and to calculate
the aggregate appears with data
then and also we can have the abstract
topology all right
the next
so here uh i don't we'll go to the
detail of the
model uh the basic idea here is just to
uh with augment node link
and also termination point to extend uh
more
vpn related data on it
and also we can use uh reuse current
uh netconf uh
uh young push or subscription model to
to subscribe uh those data
uh from the devices so
uh that's that this is a model so
next please
this draft has been discussed
in last ietf meeting and also
we also give some
uh also proposed to be discussed uh
in one of the layer three uh
and them uh working uh core meeting
so we uh have some
comments from there so we updated the
draft
to satisfy those uh comments
so we think uh this draft
is try to fill the missing pieces
of the whole closed-loop yarn-based
system so
so we propose this draft to be included
to vaping document sets
and also we think uh this draft is quite
stable
to for the working group adoption so
that's all for this presentation thank
you
any we'd like to hear more comments
on this chat thank you
questions
um don't see anyone coming up bo thanks
for presenting the um
on the question of last call so i i i
went and looked because i remembered you
presenting this before but i don't
recall ever seeing
discussion on the list about it and i
couldn't find any i did find it
mentioned in
like you said in some of the other vpn
related conversations
um it sounds like it's great that the
core team working on this is
is discussed this and i i i i don't
doubt that
that iterations have happened there but
to bring that back
to the list um would be very useful to
get more eyes on it more of the
discussion
so it doesn't feel like it's coming out
of nowhere if we do a last call
so if if you could even
bring it and announce it talk about some
of the issues
that you've um
[Music]
address some of the conversation that's
happened on those core calls that would
be very useful
to get some uh recorded uh
conversation recorded uh discussion
about this so then we can
we we can get to um calling for a
working group
consensus on adoption
okay sure thank you thanks
is there any more questions and comments
no let's go ahead
so elliot how fast can you be
very there's you know this is a very
quick update how about five minutes
okay then then we'll give it over to you
rob and warren
okay so this is just a very uh
simple update on a a previous draft
um the next slide please
um this is all about software bills of
material which i presented on the last
time
um and uh the the big
the the use of software bills of
material is to determine
um amongst other things uh what sort of
vulnerabilities a system has
and what sort of exposure a network
might have to particular vulnerabilities
one of the challenges we now know how to
write these things but we don't
necessarily
know how to retrieve them in a
standardized way
and so this draft is working on how to
retrieve them
and it solves it in several ways one is
via a well-known prefix and the other is
via mud extension
we've explored other ways but these are
the ways that we're moving with
thus far next slide please
now this is an update of a previous
draft the
this draft focuses far less on mud and
far more on s-bombs and how to share
the introduction has been rewritten to
make that clear but largely speaking the
content
uh in terms of the the model for mud is
the same
and we have the definition of the with a
well-known
uh suffix uh defined um the security
considerations have been added to
um we there's one or two more mechanisms
we want to add
in terms of um being able to
advertise different sorts of uh
retrieval mechanisms there are a couple
of other protocols that
that that we would add but that's a very
small change
and um we need to add a little bit of
non-normative text
to describe those mechanisms but that's
really
about it um next slide please
so um a couple of points just to mention
michael has raised one or two other
issues
uh around uh this draft they're not
nothing that are show stoppers we we
talked about possibly adopting it
last time and maybe it's worth starting
the call for adoption
if you guys are up for it or we should
do that um
say real soon now even if we do
adopt it i would expect it to take a
little while to get through the process
uh simply because we want to sync with a
couple of the other uh protocol
developers that that are doing this and
some of them are inside and outside the
iutf
and that's it how was that that was
quick
questions
hank yeah as an individual hi elliot um
you were talking in the last slide about
um retrieval
and some hints maybe um i am
aware that uh stephen bangert
and dave waltermeyer from nist were
introducing the rolly
uh mechanism to retrieve software
inventory related information maybe
that's that's something to look at here
yeah i mean so the the purpose of um
this work is to point at the different
types of mechanisms
um there's not going to be a single one
but i think it's probably you're right
we should make sure that we're
coordinating with them
this draft by the way is co-authored by
scott rose also from nist
so i'll make sure that he's talking to
his colleagues
sounds good thanks
but that also bears on the next
discussion one of the next discussions
right which is coordinating all this
and i i have seen the discussion on this
i think we
can we can bring
adoption to the list we seem to have
enough
interest at least and see how how well
it would be supported for adoption
and there was at least a little bit of
running code it's not perfect but there
is some
great thanks elliot
thank you so that's uh
that's opposite awg um i hand it over to
you uh rob and warren i think we got
your slides
up they're now in data tracker um
do one much uh they want me to share the
screen or yeah rob
yourself kiara and if you're willing to
share that would be great i think that's
that's more likely to work than us
trying to play i haven't done a screen
share through
me so i'll save the time
i i was able to load the slides 10 run
if you want me to try and share them
or if you've got them up that's fine too
i stopped the showing okay let's see if
i can do this
uh selects
that's gonna look weird how about this
oh good uh
yes you might want a little bit bigger
if that's possible
can you still see it uh
you're sharing a lot
okay let me try this
i think we learned from uh
select oh maybe i
oh screen one
now i bet you can see it
that's good yeah okay all you thank you
so um so so welcome to the ops
area part of the meeting and um from
warren i
and i think the main thing we would like
to um to discuss here is
i have some discussion on the itops
russian group charter that we're trying
to charge at the moment
i would also like to mention that warren
and i having
an ops ops area ads
meeting after this um so that's on the
agenda if anyone is interested in
talking to warren and i
there's an opportunity i'll try and
remember to put a link into that at the
end of this as well so
if anyone wants to any further
discussion issues with warren and i
there's an opportunity after this
meeting
uh during the break so um
so to give some background here uh go to
the next slide please
so um there's been discussion about
having
some some sort of ops or iot based
working group and for quite a long time
in the sg long lot longer than before i
joined
and um in the last uh
four months or so warren and i have been
trying a lot harder to try and get that
that charted and set up and i think we
are almost over the hill
now um but it's um but worth discussing
the aim of this is to really have um a
focal point for discussion
of issues related to iot uh uh
operational issues and also trying to
act as almost like a coordination point
where
lots of different work is happening in
the ietf
and protocols related to iot but
sometimes it's hard to
coordinate all of those or know what's
going on and the idea here
for iot ops is to have a working group
where
where that can also be coordinated in
some way and discussed and things so
people know what's going on
and gives an opportunity for people
outside of iit
outside of ietf to be able to bring
new iot related work into the iatf if
they don't quite know where it should go
so at the moment there's a perception
that it's sort of quite hard
if you're external to itf um and
i've got work related to iot to know
where to bring it there's no sort of
focal point and the aim of this working
group is to try and do that
it's a bit different from a regular
working group in the sense that
it's expected to be a bit more
discussion focused
and and
related rather than just working on
producing documents
so it has a bit more of a mops feel if
anyone
and if you're aware of mops uh but the
expectation is it can do some work
so it's okay for it to be um
discussing uh informational documents or
bcps
and to be discussing potential new work
but the aim is that if if new work is
identified
that although there need to be further
discussion about where that work
happens so it might be that that goes to
one of the existing working groups or
another area
it might be that we need to spin up a
new working group to do that work
or there is a possibility that it might
even be possible to do that
um in iot ops but there would need to be
further discussion
with the isg the isg and to decide if
that was if that was feasible for small
bits of work
so um at the moment the the aim is for
that to be outside the charter that
you can't do protocol work but if that
does come up
we can um have another look to see um
what the best way of doing that is
uh next slide please
so some discussion points it's worth
saying that there's actually been some
further discussion this week on this and
i think we sort of resolved
um some of this i believe the general
agreement between the discussion we've
had is that
um is that still should not do um
protocol work directly
and instead it says here perform a
dispatch function i think again the word
dispatch isn't necessarily the best
choice and we might
take that out of the charter the idea is
really that
like any working group if there is
discussion about particular work that
needs to happen
and it's not the right place then the
this working it would help to redirect
that work to other places or work out
where the place best place for that work
to occur is
but it doesn't need to follow a very
strict and dispatch
model where the conversation is focused
purely
only on how you dispatch the documents
and not on the content at all
we would see there to be a bit more
flexibility
to discuss some of the content of the
work
first and before deciding how best to
proceed with that work in the itf if
that was appropriate to do so
um it as it says here it can work on
architectural requirements that's fine i
think it was happy
and as i said before if there's a need
to do
protocol work then one possibility is
that it might be chartered to do small
bits of protocol work
um if that's appropriate but we would
look at that on a case-by-case basis and
we'd have discussions with the isg first
to see if that's okay so um the next
couple of
slides have the charter text on there
i'm not sure whether we need to bring
that
up um but but
really the question is now is does
anyone have any comments
um or points they'd like to raise so i'd
like to open this up really for
discussion now it might be worth asking
if warren wants to add any more
color to what i'm saying
that well thank you
tell us hi yeah thanks for this
so uh this this has been uh wait a lot
more than the nine months something like
this should i take the most so
um um so i i do think the
the one area that you know on on quick
look i didn't see
quite was that you know the aspect of
toi
from you know iot application solutions
to you know people uh doing the network
layer part or the protocol stuff
and vice versa i think that would be a
really cool thing if
we could get more of that right so um
in in in terms of that i would love to
see you know
uh get getting more outreach to
to to people from the industry
presenting on their stuff even if you
know the only outcome is this
this would be a presentation for tui uh
during
such such a meeting and the second
high level comment i think is that um
the the one thing i'm worried about is
to unnecessarily constrain
things to be called um iot
when they're not and i don't want to
have you know
a stupid discussion about what the heck
is iot and what is not iot to stand in
the way but
for uh in in terms of simply using the
group
for for for the discussion um but then
you know as appropriate also point out
that
you know something may not be uh limited
to iot and i think the best example to
me is that
the you know phil i think was uh
having a good definition of iot which
was kind of
not the typical devices with with a real
user interface
uh during this enrollment discussions we
had um
and i think that equally applies to you
know routers and switches and all the
other networking gear
we had so far um but i don't think we
have
traditionally called routers and
switches iot
um you know big service provider core
router also but i think a lot of
the you know life cycle management
problems we have for that equipment
um is very equal to you know what we
would more likely call iot so
um i'm not quite sure how to bring that
property into the charter but just
functionally that would be something i'd
become
concerned about okay
to to answer both those two points on
the first one
um yes it's definitely a desire for
people to bring
like tois and information from other
places here
so so that is one of the desires that
this is a forum where people can make
those presentations
and that's that's actually one of the
reasons why we wanted it to be a working
group rather than just a mailing list
is to have that timely agenda such that
that those presentations
could occur so so that's that's
definitely a
goal here i don't know whether it's
helpful to have anything in the chat
related to that or not
um so that so that's a question to have
or whether it's sufficient
uh just to be able to understand what's
there in terms of the
second question in terms of defining
what iot is
i think we want to try really hard not
to do that
and i i guess i've given some
partial definition of what it means in
this in this case
and i think we could be fairly flexible
with its scope i think mostly
people will um will know it when they
see it
and we don't need to worry too much
about it and um
and give the chairs the working group
some flexibility
in terms of what they define iot and if
it looks like
it's becoming going out of scope then we
can
rein it in again but i think for the
moment
it'd be better just to have a loose
definition
see how it progresses and if we need to
tweak anything after
after six months or a year then we can
do so but um
i hope that we can get it set up and
assume that the best intentions first
warren would you like anything to add
anything to
so then that to largely agree i think
that you know we've been trying to get
something like this done for a very long
time
we keep running into the perfect being
the enemy of the good for getting it set
up
and so getting something started so we
can at least
begin discussions um and then you know
recharge i want to prove
that we're not completely crazy i think
would be a
safer way to go um for obvious reasons
you know there's a number of concerns
about
stroke creep or just trying to take over
what is
being done in other areas and i think
that's where some of the
sensitivity is coming from
yeah as i said i didn't mean to i was i
i was explicitly saying let's not
take my comment as something to to make
life harder
but rather be you know more inclusive so
as to not partition
the discussion unnecessarily along the
definition
yes it sounds fine
okay before elliot gets this
lining queue there was a question from
eric on the
chat basically asking if this
iot ops working group would render the
iot directorate
kind of obsolete or basically how they
consequences their interactions are
so my answers i would assume not i
would assume that the iot directorate um
still serves very useful purpose
for um doing reviews of documents that
iot related i'd rather those go to an
iot directorate rather than coming to
this working group
so i'd see that continuing i i don't
know
exactly everything that goes on in the
iot directory i've only joined it
relatively recently
i know some of the sort of discussion
and coordination is happening there
it may end up that that this is a better
forum for that
if that answers your questionnaire
so so no i don't think it should be
obsoleted i do think we should just see
how it
um how it progresses
once this so this is warren yeah i mean
i think it's more sort of complementary
and kind of like what
um mcr said in the chat um you know
maybe the coordination calls become more
sag like
um
um so we have only four minutes left so
elliot
i'll just be brief and say that i i
think this is perfectly fine
idea i think it's actually way overdue
and i i think uh warren and and rob
and all of those preceding area
directors
have taken a swing at this um
the uh the text to me is is good
um the only thing i will just add is
that
this i i do view the iot ops
stuff more as you know to make sure that
the
the left two aspects right it's a locus
for
new work so that you know people want to
come into the ietf they can
at least hear about what's going on in
iot and then maybe bring some work along
there
on their own the second is to keep us
from tripping over ourselves
um and and to that end uh there's uh
just approving the working group will
get us there
we will need it's necessary but not
sufficient
it will need to be the case that the
iesg and everybody have to sort of
do some outreach to make sure that
anything that you know really is iot
like
at least gets you know discussed brought
in for discussion
you know not not so much that the work
gets done in iot ops but just that
people are aware
of how it all fits together and people
need to to
come together and be in that room for
that purpose and that will require a
little bit of work and it's it's a
little counter cultural
so i think that sounds fine and it
i think that all makes sense
sorry
tell us
okay let's consider the mic closed
so i think um i think that sounds
everything thank you for the feedback
and and hopefully we'll be able to get
this up and running soon
so i'll just try and find the link for
the ops area
upset the office hours
so in case anyone wants to join warren i
will be here for the next
half an hour so i'll just put that into
the chat but otherwise i think we can
call the ops area part of the meeting
also closed thank you everyone fitter
you