hear me now
yeah i can hear you
okay somehow my pieces
but this plugin mic works
i try to talk louder
so i think we can start at nine o'clock
so
high rift it's great to see
to be here and uh
it's atf-109 another virtual one
hopefully one before lost
uh we plan just to be reasonably short
meeting
everything is in motion and in process
uh we are going to go through not well
it's a reminder of itf policies by
participating in the atf you agree to
follow it f process policies
if anything is unclear the documents
that describe
how your contribution to atf is process
and policy is applicable
please go and read them if there's you
don't know
so agenda for today we'll be talking
about working group status and we'll
have updates on applicability draft
after that tony is going to talk about
what's going on in general without
slides
so working group status we have
submitted base back
to isd it's been
hanging around for quite some time
alvaro is planning to review asap
so we are looking forward to that
applicability statement draft is ready
for working group plus calls so we are
going to start one after atf
and young isn't going to work i believe
all comments have been
addressed and there's more work on
multicast on segment routing
we didn't really do anything and i
believe we will
start soon so bear with us
with that we are going to switch to the
applicabilities making draft and hear
what's new what's going on
i don't see the presenter ah here
are you your presenting right so please
um
yeah now yeah great
hello okay i can hear you now let me
share
the slides just a
[Music]
second
let's go ahead okay
uh hello cheers hello everyone
i have a very short introduction of the
latest status of rift applicability
draft
version 3 on behalf of all
the authors next page please
this is the agenda
i will talk about the updates since
ietf108
and the next steps um
[Music]
the total draft has 29 pages now and
the the main part of the draft chapter
2 chapter 3 and chapter 4.
chapter 2 is the problem statement of
routing in modern
ip fabric factory
chapter three analyzes applicability of
rift to cross ip fabrics
five use cases are included in chapter
three
and chapter 4 analyzes
14 aspects of rift deployment
in 14 sections
so the con
contents are quite stable now
next page please
the updates from version
0 1 to version 0 0 3 are tables
and abbreviation consistency
check uh thank mil melchio
for for his comments
i think i have reflected most of
corrections
to the mailing list
next slide please
so um comments are always
welcome of course and i would like to
request
the working group for last four
thank you thank you
tony the monk is here's
here i am so sorry i didn't make up any
powerpoint
uh just i'm pressing and just a couple
of um
loose things that are going on so people
are hooked up so you know what community
is doing
um so we had another interrupt
with bruno very little
drama basically synced up newest version
he actually with the test he found
a bug i introduced which um
was cute i was basically disaggregating
in a situation where this aggregation
was not needed and my test didn't catch
it and he's tested
but there was another one-liner fix that
was pretty much the whole drama um
the italian university of roma is
actually building
now a very large scale simulation well
simulation actually you know
cloud deployment of containers of rift
i don't know how big they will go it
kind of depends how much resources they
can grab
so that's going on they had the paper i
the paper was
uh contested because the scale wasn't
big enough
so we'll see how far they stretch it so
there's active work there
if you're interested you know there have
a lot of
container tools and all kind of images
and they throw all kind of routing stuff
into complex topologies
um i will bring next time
and if somebody has cycles they want
something to
uh you know for to be rich and famous
quickly
we need a key value draft uh and i will
be bringing that stuff next time
to the itf and the reason is that
we are actually working and drinking
through some stuff that
i hope will present next time where we
can do something
pretty interesting ztp over rift and
to make that stuff interoperable we will
need a key value pair
store on which we kind of agree how stub
is in codec to an extent
so if you're interested in a key value
draft please see me
we'll talk about it the last thing on my
plate that was going on and it was very
active
is um a day one book
is about to be published um
uh mel here is synchronizing that if you
don't know mel here
he is probably on the call yeah melcher
is on the call
and it evolved into quite an extensive
list of authors
and quite a fat volume it was supposed
to be something small
i think melchior will be still glad if
he got some reviewers
and uh you know we we supposed to you
know publish it minus two months ago or
something like that so i'm pretty
confident next time here we have the
stuff
if you're not familiar with the day one
this is something you know a juniper
press thing like a cisco press
it has also extensive section written by
bruno
uh in terms of the open source
implementation so that deals really with
deployment
and all kind of consideration on real
products and open source and so on
that's kind of my that's from my site if
any of that stuff you know resonate with
any participants you want to
know more or you want to engage and get
some work done um
for the day one book smell here
otherwise whatever you heard
engage me and if you're interested in
the
work that done in roma university roma i
can also provide you details there's
two people working on the phds there
that's about it thanks
thanks tony so is there any comments
please
do speak up
the ultraviolets are set everything is
in progress
so we expect more interesting stuff
coming
up next ats so tony working some stuff
we need to progress seven charging
multicast
and um we are looking forward to seeing
you
next atf and uh we're about to give you
some time back so you can do something
beautiful with it
thanks everyone and we will see you next
atf thanks
shout and sweet later
you