i'm hearing different background noise
no brian i'm not sure if you are you
hearing any background noise
i heard this noise that i had heard
before where we thought it was just
brian spann
but your your audio actually sounded
broken up there when you was speaking
paul
not noise just broken audio your audio
is breaking up
oh i've had trouble i've had trouble
with some conferencing systems in these
headphones so
i may try to turn the headphones off and
see yeah
yeah that's worse but i can try it
uh
it's a minute past our start time so
we can try
paul i see your headphones are off or
your no your audio isn't coming through
i can't hear you
nope can you hear me now
yep there you go is that better
yes okay i don't know what it is
okay we can get started
yeah um just a second i gotta share
here are your chair slides yeah
okay can you see the slides yep
okay
um i think most everybody here
has been been to a meeting an ietf
meeting before
if you haven't ever read the note well
you better read it it has to do with how
you participate
in all kind of legal crap uh
we won't go into any more than that
yeah welcome to where where are we brian
singapore
yeah now we're in bangkok oh bangkok
okay
hope you're enjoying the weather here
that's why we're at this uh ungodly hour
um
and at least for the people who live in
that area
it's it's a good time for them
i don't think we have any of them but
so uh welcome to rum
we haven't done much for quite a while
um
a little bit of mail discussion um
we're hoping to get things going and
hopefully finished before too long uh
we've only got one thing on the agenda
really and just to
talk about the open issues on uh
you know draft ietf from roof um
and uh other than that we'll
you know that's all we got to do today
uh if anybody else has something else
they want to add to the agenda and it's
a good time to speak up and
say what it is
go ahead eugene
one of the things that's the open issue
is obviously what we've been talking
about
in the email thread right the securing
of
files okay thank you
um
okay i think there's nothing else we can
turn it over to
uh brian you gotta push your own slides
you want me to push your slides
i know i can push the slides uh note
well
yeah i mentioned it already
i i didn't hear that but that's okay um
it's a itf meeting and subject to the
notewell
rules all right
i i didn't see that okay okay
all right so uh so i'm going to
publish the screen yes
uh application chrome tab
documentation share
um let's see
there okay
so uh these are the two open issues that
i believe we have
um one is the provider control of the
authorized apps
and the other is the cr uh the um
configuration file or how cred
credentials for registration are
kept especially when there's a white one
i'm not seeing i'm not seeing what
you're talking
about on the screen
you don't have a slide that says two
known open issues let me look at what's
going on
i see a slide that says latest results
okay uh
weird invitation you've shared the
medico documentation
yeah this this should be
well all right let's try it it should be
[Music]
here all right let's try
hang on one second um
go back to this
stop sharing publish screen yes
chrome tab
um there
share how's that
that's better okay wrong button
okay um so
the two issues the first one is the
provider controller over unauthorized
applications
and the other is the configuration file
which is how credentials for
registration are kept
especially when the provider when the
user has more than one provider that he
sees
he has two telephone numbers from two
different providers or
more than one so
um starting with the first one um
providers wanted to control over what
apps get access to their infrastructure
reasonable requests request in in closed
systems
the example is the easy example is ios
the way they do that is they sign
code and the system that loads programs
only
allows sign code to load so you
they have very tight control over what
apps can run you you can only run apps
that come from the
ios store um
we don't have a closed system um you
could have one on ios
if you had an ios app but that that's
roughly it
other than that it's pretty pretty open
and there's very little control that we
have over
what code can be loaded so we can't use
that mechanism that's all
my only point is that that mechanism
won't work
the the alternative that most people use
for this kind of thing is what we've
been calling an api key
um and an api key is a is a
as a string it's it's a secret
and it's given to the app provider after
the code is tested
and the string is sent encrypted as part
of initializing the app
and only that apps that haven't that
have been approved will have a valid key
um because it's sent encrypted
you can't steal a key from another
program
um and uh it it
it can be provided per provider right so
each provider could have their own key
and the
app could put the right key in um
typically you send this as a header or a
json object
in an https transaction that's typically
how it's used
we could do that um or we could send it
in a sip header
maybe a call info header in the register
operation
so both of those are possible and the
the the
the question on the floor is is this is
an acceptable mechanism
if it is i'm happy to write the text for
it um and we can
you know can make sure that that that
that says what we want and all that
other stuff but i'm i'm very happy to
um create the text that that defines how
an api key is used um i
will i would like to have a discussion
on do you want it on the register or
just do it with an https transaction
um and and um we can
we can work out how all the details work
so
i'd i'd like to have some discussion now
um
about that um and you know
is this what what what providers want is
is is doing it in https enough or do you
want it to be done in
in the sip register happy to do it
either way whatever whatever works
um is fine um and and
are there any other questions or
suggestions or
or whatever so the the floor is open
um for people um we have a small number
of people who are here if you want to
use the cue by all means do that that's
our normal process is put yourself in
the queue and
and we'll recognize you um or
um you can just unmute and talk and
it'll be all right there's a small
number of us
once you go first eugene
i personally feel that
using it outside of sip
would be a good option
um as an https transaction
um you know when when we actually do the
register
and those types of things of course
we're in sip but
um if it's pre-sip
connection maybe just using the https
transaction would be
a good option i'm certainly not expert
in the
security of of things so maybe i don't
understand
why putting it in the sip header would
be a better way to go i'm not sure
it just avoids having to do that https
transaction that's that's really
the only thing i i actually like i
prefer to do it with https only because
um uh it it's kind of the normal way
you know you're kind of you're you're
you're you're falling down a hole that's
been
been well smoothed out
um and and and so if if you ask me what
i think we want to do i think
let's just do it with an https
transaction that happens before the
register
it's an authorization step that you have
to do
your register will be rejected if you
don't do it um
uh and and and um
uh i i think that's a perfectly
reasonable thing to do
that would be my preference i'd rather
not go mess with sip
but i'm happy to do that if if if if
that's
what what we want i mean
yeah yeah that that
is another place to put it i mean if we
might i mean
otherwise go ahead
yes the second open issue is the
configuration file and then there's at
least some versions of doing that that
it
involves downloading things from from a
provider and
if that happens then that's the
transaction we'll use
to authorize yeah that that kind of
makes sense to me
one thing i was wondering about about
this is
has to do with the uh the mechanism
by which these things get
author you'll get certified or you know
verified or whatever you know
is there a separate i mean does every
implementation
need to test separately with every
provider
and get a separate key from each
or i i think that that's that we can
make that out of scope for our spec
and the providers can decide among
themselves how they want to do it
we can make the mechanism work both ways
and and you you can have the same key
for all providers
you can have independent keys um i
i i given that the itef is international
i don't want to
bias this towards you know the the the
u.s
providers and let them decide um and
make that stick
um for everybody um
so i i unless
they all think that the right thing to
do is once
somebody tests and then everybody
accepts that is acceptable
um i i think allowing it to be provider
is probably the way to to
to to write this back
it seems to me at least we need we need
to know the cardinality if the if the
roo has to keep one
per provider right you know if it's part
of the part
effectively if it's part of the
configuration information
um i think it's simpler than that
the there's already the remember there
there's already the configuration file
which is common which is the list of
available providers
right so if you have the list of
available providers then you can have a
list of
keys associated with each provider and
substitute the right one when you when
you go in
so it's pretty easy to make it work per
provider
but i it it's also
complex if if indeed
app vendor has to get approved by every
provider separately
i think it's just a matter of
what what the you know somebody who's
building a route
uh what what what
do they have to build in you know do
they have to build a separate mechanism
for u.s providers a different mechanism
for
if they go somewhere else no i think
again i think that
the way the spec could be written is
that that it can be per provider or it
can be
one um and and and
it basically if it's
if it if you're in an environment where
there's only one then there'll only be
one and if you're an environment where
there's more than
one you know there's one per provider
then you'll have you'll have to have a
configuration
of one one per provider but i think
that's
it even could be mixed right you know
provider a and b can use a common one
and provider c
can have have its own i mean that as
long as you allow per provider
and and have have the notion of common
then
it's just how it's how it's set up
in fact it's built into the code right
or it could be built into code for a
particular region anyways
can can we hear from other people what
they prefer to see is
what do you think this ought to be one
one per provider or you know a keeper
provider
or or do you think that it actually
might work out to be
one for a region
anybody wanna offer an opinion
i am eugene here yeah
so jim here uh so everybody else is
being quiet today
um having listened to the providers for
for a number of years on this topic
um it's not at all clear to me that uh
provider a
is going to be satisfied with provider b
is testing that this
is uh not impactful to their service so
you again it's a regulatory issue right
do we have a
an individual certifying entity that
does the testing and says this works for
all providers
or does each provider have to do that
brian your earlier point i think that
that could be
locale specific right just because the
us decides to do it one particular way
doesn't mean that another country would
do the same thing
so suspect in the us we would be looking
at a per-provider
certification it doesn't seem like the
spec ought to
lock you into that particular
thought process right
yeah i i i i think i have some ideas i
want to noodle them in my head and i'll
write some text down to
make it possible to be you know region
specific where
where it could be in one region it's one
way in another region it's another way
that that's fine and do recall that if
we
realize maybe not recall but realize
that if it's implemented per provider
and two providers decide oh look we'll
we'll
trust each other's keys then
then that that's what happens right you
you you you just
use providers a key with provider b
and it'll work
uh any other comments i i thought i
heard someone else try and get in when
jim started is there someone else
now have we looked at the possibility to
use
existing methods like oauth or saml or
anything else
for this it seems like we're reinventing
different problems created
this is not a this is not a authorize a
user
issue this is a authorize a piece of
code issue
yeah but the piece of code gets a key
as well in those but yeah we can to the
extent that an api
an api key is a key yeah i mean that's
true but i don't i've never heard of
someone trying to use oauth to do that
you're they would that would involve
infrastructure that would be hard to
come up with in some regions right
you're talking about
putting up could be
you know um
i mean identity provider also gets gets
keys
in order i mean you you you
right apply for a key with facebook to
use facebook
right yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah i
mean so
so patients actually get some sort of
key there
right right so so for those of you who
are not following this there's the
notion of using something like oauth
which
is a single sign-on mechanism right so
the there's there would be some sort of
identity provider and again you could
have one per region or you could have
one per
per provider and and and then
um well i guess it'd have to be one per
region in order for that to work right
so then
you get a key um
uh that that you can use
with the identity provider to prove to
another provider that you're good
um i'm not sure how would you
how would you make that work for this
app who who would who who do you think
would run the
identity provider and when how would how
would anybody get a key from that
identity provider
well i mean what one thing is identity
to provide the other is
how you register the services but i
guess it depends
uh i mean sweden you get kind of public
funding you get authorized to use a
service then you go pick a service
on the market obviously there's not many
market players here
and right public provided players as
well right
right so i mean
maybe you could use your facebook
account to log in
but the providers has to get in i don't
know uh
you can also look at something like saml
or eduroam
where you have a account in one
university can log into all universities
that provide services
well so yeah it could be another way but
i
i get that but i i i
i'm still not exactly clear how it would
work if you could
sort of maybe send an email to the list
describing how you think it would
actually
work i'm i'm having trouble i mean i
kind of understand the concept but i'm
i'm having trouble understanding the
mechanics and maybe i'm being biased by
what jim said which is in in north
america
it would be hard to have a single
anything
it's likely to be you know the per
provider kind of
world and
providers don't necessarily trust each
other in some circumstances anyways
sometimes they do sometimes they don't
regulations require that they trust them
in certain circumstances and
in other circumstances they they do
voluntarily and others they don't
um so i'm not sure
exactly how it would work i kind of see
the idea but i don't see the
it's not clear to me how that how how it
would actually
work so if you could kind of send an
email describing how it would work
all right all right it's an interesting
alternative
it's an interesting alternative and
there's not a whole lot of difference
between using saml and using
oauth right i mean it would still
fundamentally they would work the same
way it's just the mechanics that would
be different
saml has a federated trust that i find
very very interesting yeah but where you
have a set of authorized
identity providers yeah so
okay that could be the state or a couple
of states or something
so send send and send a message to the
list
so we can think about it but right at
the moment
let's we'll pursue the api key as being
something that's acceptable
and maybe we can have a better idea uh
another
question about the api key is whether or
not it's
just a random string or if it's actually
a token that contains some data
like we use in open id connect or
something
is this assigned something by something
that we can use to transport some sort
of data
just an open question in many cases
uh the keys in used in authentication
systems
actually contain some data
so yeah i mean typically an api key
doesn't
um although they're
actually what i'm no
in some environments it it it it does
but it's in
totally invisible nobody actually knows
that there's data in there but the
provider the the the the guy who
generates the key
actually is keeping data in it
i i yeah i don't think the spec would
say that
no but we can keep an open mind
see if that's useful in any in any way
shape or form
sure sure i mean i i've
built a system that effectively
put the identity of the of the
of the provider in the key just because
it was easier to do it there than keep a
separate database
it worked i mean i mean you can have
time limits in the api keys
yeah yeah yeah sure sure yep yeah
yeah sure you put the time you issued
the key and all kinds of other great
stuff in it it's just the string so
you know put some data in it digest it
and you're done
yep um
okay anyone else with um
with thoughts on that i mean
it seems like the api key is acceptable
um ali is talking about a possible
alternative
so we'll let them see if you can write
down how it would work and look at it as
an
alternative but
i i'm hearing that api key will be okay
is that is that true is there
anyone who who doesn't think that it
would be acceptable
to use an api key is the solution to
this problem
jim wants to talk go ahead jim
jim here very quickly ali you mentioned
uh perhaps using your facebook id
as as a uh as a common uh
mechanism for this because then you
already have the centralized
infrastructure
but the facebook id is attached to the
user not to the device
um something to keep in mind as you as
you write something up here is that it
really does need to be tied to the
device
so i just wanted to point that out i um
either i'm missing something or
or that doesn't okay quite work
yeah no i i i guess i i i miss that but
the device
you you want to authenticate the
implementation of that
actual hardware correct well software
but yes
it may be a device or it may just be a
software
app on a standard device correct yeah
but we're not looking for the mac
address we're looking for
a certain release of a certain software
correct that's exactly it it's a
it's a certain release of a certain
software
that's that's correct yep
all right uh anyone else's
go ahead james
hi sorry can you hear me yeah
um i just had a um an rfc
that sprung to mind i i don't
know the oauth is um
the way we would want to go i just uh i
noticed there's a
best practice roc8252 on oauth for
native apps
um i just hadn't seen those mentioned
and i just wonder it might help us
clear up the nomenclature around
different types of keys and
and that kind of thing sure sure
i think go ahead is it
is a potential candidate for
the the the basic authentication for the
user
i don't know so much for the device
well i mean that ollie wants to propose
it for the device so we'll we'll figure
out if you can
come up with a mechanism that'll work
any any other thoughts
okay so we're going to summary
summarizing here
i just just a reminder of itf
process right we don't make decisions at
meetings we make tentative decisions and
we confirm them on the list
so um even if we decided
full start that we're gonna do the api
key we would still have to go back to
the list and
ask people their thoughts on it so that
that's just our process
um but
i'm what i'm hearing at the moment is an
api key is acceptable
as is an acceptable answer
and we might have an alternative answer
using something like oh after saml ollie
is going to go and write up how he
thinks that might work and we'll
consider it
we'll do that on the list i'll start
writing
uh text for api key once we make the
decision on the list on if ellie's idea
has
merit i'll i'll uh
you know if we decide that then then
he may probably i will cooperate on
creating some text for that idea
um and otherwise they'll be uh the next
version will have either the api key or
or or if this oauth saml id works out
we'll
we'll have that so that's what i'm
hearing i'm going to do
as author um and and so
that and it's good from my point of view
this is good we have at least a solution
and we might have two
okay so i'm i'm going to go on to the
next item
so this is the configuration file issue
the the the way the current text works
it's a local file with sections for each
provider single file
sections for each provider it currently
is described as
having account user id and password and
clear text in that file
and that was deemed unacceptable um
i i note that almost every voip device
you
you have has such a file and it does in
most of the
way are in clear text which is not a
good idea but it's there
it has a local storage of username and
password
and and most um store
the the um
more than one provider you know a
multi-line phone right so you can have
all the configuration information
for each of your lines on your on your
voip phone
um in that local storage and that's
what we're replicating that that you
know what a voip phone does
you you can configure each line with you
know
where the proxy server is and what your
username and password is and what your
telephone number is and all the other
good things that are provisionable in
that configuration file
um your turn servers all of those are in
that
that piece of configuration it might be
a little piece of flash as opposed to a
a disk drive but it's it that that's
that is what i'm
what this mechanism is supposed to
replicate um so we've had lots of ideas
that have been tossed around on the list
including using open id or saml
as a way of authenticating users
and then getting configuration out of
that
or we've talked about having a local
login so the
app would have a username and password
that the user would put in that would
unlock the configuration file
and so a lot of these ideas have been
thrown around
um and i'm hoping that we can have a
good discussion now
on what we want to do and
and hopefully we'll come up with at
least a tentative answer or more than
you know one
at least one answer that we can start
writing text on
so again the floor is open on on ideas
for
how we handle this configuration file
can we start with agreeing that the
implementations that we have in sip
when had for over 10 years is
embarrassing in the year of 2020
and we shouldn't use them as a starting
point
at all the user id passwords
in clear text md5 authentication and
stuff we
have to leave behind
i think using a setup where we have some
sort of certificate enrollment
where the run device create a key parry
gets a certificate
somehow and then use that
then we can bootstrap configurations by
having encrypted configurations that
encrypted with the public key of the
device and we can use the certificate
for authentication and sip which is a
really good thing
i think we just have to escape the
the stuff you have in the middle of your
slide is
that how we have done it is embarrassing
and shouldn't be the base on how we
create new citizens
well i personally am with you ali
a lot of people have a lot of code that
uses all that stuff
and they're sometimes reluctant to uh to
to replace it with something more modern
but
if it were up to me i would do that
um do does everybody understand what
what ollie is talking about here we
we added the ability to use
um uh open id
um you know with with real certificates
um uh instead of username password
instead of
you know digest um
and and he's advocating using that
well open id is one part of the puzzle
but
somehow setting up a device
certificate and the renewal of that
regular renewal of that certificate
i think is an important part of the
puzzle
uh how you get that certificate is
an interesting prospect but since we
have an https transaction in the
beginning
we can do a lot of things assuming we
have a
user interface that well
okay but in a standards-based
environment
let's say that we did that that we we
had an http transaction
so we've got a certificate we've done
some
local authentication using that
certificate to create the https
transaction we've created a tls session
using that certificate you know mutual
off
so now what now what
it's a shaking and egg problem because
the certificate needs to be trusted by
a set of providers and how do we
establish
a trust in a third party by all these
providers for
the client search right
yeah but again i'm i'm looking for
standards right
i know how to do that with open id
because there's an rfc that does that
if i were trying to use a certificate
and i wasn't trying to use open id what
would i
what rfc would i be referencing the
thing is
there's a lot of ways to set up server
certificates you have acme
you have a lot of protocols for doing
that for the client certificates
we have an old c party that is
well it's beautiful uh
con considering those times but it
doesn't work anymore
um you need to have first an agreement
on
a device id right
and is that the same the the login on
the device is that the same as the user
login it's the user login we want here
right
right well it's registered right right
what are we using to protect the
register and there are a lot of i mean
you you can take oauth and
start with an oauth or sample
login that ends up in a certificate i
did that
15 years ago in the university
environment
so we had a saml login where you say oh
i'm from this university
and i got my
certificate after that
and used the client certificate to get
the provisioning
for my special version of bria software
and then use the client search to
bootstrap the tool
i understand what you're proposing i i
think that that's a lot of mechanism
that would be
unique to this environment
and i'm wrong i can use a microsoft
active directory to
use an oauth to login to get a client
search
no i i if we do it with oauth i
understand what i'm doing i'm not
arguing
off i'm arguing some other mechanism
using assert
we need them we need an authentication
mechanism
and maybe um we're not at the
authorization level and we need an
authentication mechanism that ends up in
a client
search and the client cert we want to be
using in the zip layer
and you would propose to use it for what
client authentication and zip instead of
having
passwords and you can also use the key
pair
and the on the search the public key
for encrypting the configuration file
so you can transport that yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah
through proxies all right can let let's
stop
between you and me and get other people
to opine about
whether or not they think this is a
fruitful direction
i i think that uh we're
we're missing some context here it seems
to me we need
i don't know if it's use cases or
something we need
some discussion of the life cycle here
starting from we have
we have a user he has a relationship
with a provider
he's got a virgin device or app
you know what
he and maybe he has a relationship to
multiple providers he
yeah how do you bootstrap up to
having that device
know how to use you know
yeah bootstrap up until it's registered
to
you to all the providers that that he
wants it to and then
how does it stay that way over the long
term
including cases where the provider where
there's some sort of
compromise of keys and things need
need to be revoked and reset and there's
an issue there
because if somebody's using this as a
lifeline
and you know the key is revoked in the
middle of the night you don't want it so
that
incoming calls can't happen right
i i we would have to work all of that
out in order
to to do this i think that there are
reasonable solutions for all of that
but i i agree that we would have to
there be a bunch of text
to deal with this and yeah and and ollie
has
made this problem bigger right we that
this this
slide talks about the configuration file
and he's talking about
more than just the configuration file
he's talking about
basic authentication for sip
right i should not use the word basic
i started with what's in the middle of
the slide with the username
password in clear text and i said
let's remove that and suggested
alternatives to that
right that's the content of the file and
you you went saying let's not have a
username and password in the file
let's use search instead of username and
password for registration
but we still need a configuration file
right i i
i indeed and and and
we can we can if we've got a cert
then we can maintain assert and do the
startup that
that um paul is talking about and handle
revocation and all the other things that
go along with certs
then the cert can be used for mutual off
with tls
the cert can be used for mutual off with
sip
i mean you could do that uh yeah but you
you have to consider
short term search not long term where
you have a lot
yeah yeah acme is here to save you um
so you know yeah three months not not
year
or maybe one month you know or session
length could be a few days but
still or session days oh wow you really
want to make them short sounds good to
me
um sure um
that's what we're discussing in iot for
device
because we can't handle revocation we
have jonathan waving
right sorry oh hi so i mean so when you
say
i mean i'm not sure what certs gain you
over open id
with open id has the advantage that the
spec is done right
88.99 that's what i keep that's what i
was
saying no no i want to to use the cert
in in the sip layer i want the result of
the authentication
to result in something i can use in sip
well that's what 8898 does 88 has open
id and sip
and so i'm not sure what the advantage
of assert is over night over
an open id token yeah we
we we have that document but it's well
needs to be discussed uh because that
i put in a requirement of an encrypted
token and there's not many
implementations of that
and that's why i'm hesitant to yeah i
mean i feel like you know the
you know the advantage in this context
of
you know specs that are done and
might actually be implemented by
somebody in a context that in a non-rom
context
is a great advantage
yeah my client search gets insip is
something
we had for a long time at least in
camellia that i'm using quite a lot
the open id stuff is still waiting for a
lot of
implementation okay
so the there's there's this proposal to
widen this whole thing out
and use search for everything that's a
change to how
registration would work it's a change to
um how i mean
the whole sip authentication process
works
is that something that that that we can
consider
is that is is that is that reasonable
to think about putting into this spec
this is like eugene and james and
jim and and and those kind of guys that
are in this world
is you do it are are you
are you saying hell no or or are you
saying impossible
um well they're thinking about it um the
one thing about
like using the client cert is that
i think it only makes it as far as the
the the the front-end proxy for the for
the server it doesn't necessarily
make it all the way to the registrar
well this is kind of what jonathan was
getting to and and
and not only is saying yeah but we've
been doing this for years
um so i mean i i i
i it's doable but as jonathan says
there's not a lot of rfc coverage for it
so i'm i'm still trying to figure out
whether i should
say that's great ollie but nobody else
wants to do it or not
i think we can start with agreeing that
the the traditional username password
digest authentication is safe is
something we don't want
and now we have two alternatives we have
the token based
sip authentication which is very new and
lacks implementations
and i kind of agree with eugene that if
you have an
ingress proxy you have to transport
the client search somewhere else in http
you do that
frequently in a header you take the
client search from the first
level and you transport it in the header
we have no such documents in sip
and i acknowledge that that is a problem
if you have
multiple proxies in the path
still looking for more feedback of the
is this is this
yes you agree or no you don't agree with
with what ollie is proposing
i think we we have to take this in step
brian can we first
discuss whether or not username password
and the yes to authentication is
something we want to have in 2020
and then look at the smoker's board of
options if we don't
okay to have digestive authentication
all right we
we can do that um heck we can use
our little raised hand tool how's that
um i i would actually like to see some
doc some
discussion before we go there um
this is ollie is asking if sort of a
fundamental question right
the traditional way you handle
authentication for sip is
basic or digest right and
use a username or password and he's
saying
this they don't allow basically i just
sorry don't lie sorry sorry i said the
wrong thing
digest so he's saying don't do that
do something involving certs or or
oauth tokens so that's the he wants to
make that the first question
is that a reasonable thing to do
as he says in 2020 we're writing a spec
in 2020
is it reasonable to say no no no we're
not going to use
digest we're going to use something
based on certs or
or or oauth tokens
for sip this is a sip question not a
configuration file
question
well let me understand the implication
then would be
that when you got your in your
configuration brian you keep asking that
question i'm trying to keep my mouth
shut and let the uh the providers
uh weigh in here because they're the
ones who are in the most
most impact i i will shut up as soon as
the provider
so um when you phrase it the way you
just phrased
it it seems like the uh the change
you're looking for would require
some significant logic changes to
the the platforms that the providers
already have that would impact
their existing clients that are not
required to be
uh compliant or or a parallel
development so they could handle
both what they do today and what we're
proposing here
um well i understand ali what you're
saying and where
um this is indeed the right direction to
be going i'm wondering if we should be
leading that or if we should be
following sip in general
when it gets there
well sip is going there that's what the
oauth thing did
we watched your audio brian
i mean we we tr we are trying to leave
md5 behind by implementing
sha 256 and 512 authentication it's
still
not a good solution to have username and
secrets in clear text
and configuration files clear text has
never been a good option
and we have severe security problems
with those solutions because
of the possibility of downgrade attacks
we have no document yet
on how to migrate from md5 in existing
installations to a stronger one
and if you still have to do a migration
it's better to
take the leap into 2020
and do another kind of authentication
and there's a lot of things happen in
this token based
authentication area there's a new
working group in itf
that kind of works with i think it's
gnapp
um that works on the successor or
an alternative to oauth 2.
so token-based authentication i think is
the way to go
or client search
if we want to look at something existed
we have eight minutes left in this
meeting um
i i would really like to hear from
providers what they think about this
no one's willing to say anything
we got eugene we got james
we can take it to the list um we're
running out of time to do anything else
anyways
um so what if what if the configuration
file supported
both user id password and
you know oauth tokens
we could do that
that's all that's all possible
a slightly different topic i was still
confused here i mean you described this
as a single configuration files you're
imagining this is something that the end
user populates
um that's traditionally how it's
done it would be cool if it wasn't that
hard
and right when you when you configure a
boy phone
but my impression is that we can't
ex expect these users
to populate a configuration file my
impression
from way back when was the assumption
here was that
when you do that initial configuration
step
you know you go to your provider
and download the configuration file from
the provider
and it was presumably set up by them
by the user having set up his account
online with the provider from a web
interface
that that that could be how it the the
the file is
populated that and that's fine but that
means
that you can't expect that to have
information for more than one provider
you're going to have to get it
separately from each provider
so suppose you had a local file that had
everything you want
pretty much along the lines of what the
current text says
and there was a mechanism that
downloaded the content
of each of the provider sections
from the provider at that point it's
just
it's it's it's just uh encoding whether
you talk about that as one
file or multiple files it's well it's
the difference between whatever you're
there well it's do you download it every
time you
turn your machine on or do you download
it once
i think you download it every time you
turn your machine on
the provider may want to change it
you know like change some of the urls or
or password or the authentication okay i
mean i think that i mean
i think either idea is viable
it could be easy to you know push the
button that says download it again
um but uh
yeah all of that
as i've been reading through it i kind
of have envisioned
that this would be downloaded once
but because it's it because it's
downloading data that's
relevant to the specific provider
it's only going to contain the data for
that provider and therefore he gets it
from that provider's website
yeah i i was thinking
okay and and why not let the device
store that data
if it needs to be updated you know there
would
it would need to have a a
another mechanism for updating that kind
of data but perhaps that's through
talking with the
provider thereafter right well it could
no i mean you're you're the the thing
that says
once could get triggered by some manual
action
right so the user interface that says do
it again
yeah reset yeah
yeah i mean i think we we need some
automation here
we could possibly just define a
well-known url like
dot well-known slash roo where you get
the basic
information from each provider based on
their domain name so we have a list of
domain names
that we update regularly uh which means
we have that automatically
and then we discover through the
well-known url the specific
configuration data for that provider
having the user press a button to
download configuration
files seems very old-fashioned
yeah i mean we can we we can automate
that
more i i i think the
once there there there is something of
of uh you know once a day
one once once once a month once a day
and once
every time you log in
it seems to me that that the simple way
is
that a revocation and
and reconfig is triggered by
the attempt to register with the
registrar
failing with a bad password
or something uh i mean i we're we're in
the weeds we we can
work out how this works but it's
automated then you fetch a new
configuration and try again
yeah okay i i think we can get there i
think that won't
i think that's not there there are many
ways to solve that problem
i i i think that people who are saying
look this should not take manual action
computers can figure this out i think
you're probably right
well what we can figure it out i'm i i
is the the only question that remains
depending on on where we go with ollie's
idea of using samls or
tokens or or certs is
what you do with credentials um
and and how those are unlocked right you
know
how is it securely stored
so that you don't have to re-enter per
provider credentials every time you
log in that
that that's the part that i want to make
sure that we do
right clear text won't work right that's
the
clear text problem right we can't do it
that way we have to do
we have to either use tokens or
something like that or we have to have a
a local id and you unlock it with that
local id
or something like that
and what does it even mean to log in i
mean the device
wants to stay connected when there's no
person around
off you know often it does
yeah but that's that i want to stay up
after a power cycle too
so it's not we're not talking about i
mean
it may have it has to be able to bring
itself up without a human there
there's i i i understand and you know
just what's the limit there
i mean there are there are mechanisms
that we can use to do that
it's uh i think that that's a solvable
problem i understand but i understand
your point
it's it you can't think of it as being
a kind of regular app where if you as
you say
power boot if it you know power failed
and it came back up again
incoming calls have to work you can't
wait for the user to show up
log in for incoming calls to work
you're correct that that that would not
be acceptable
brian so much of the so much of the
current implementations of the existing
vrs
providers is very much tied to
and based on a login
features call lists
contact lists so many of those things
are based on
the notion of somebody having logged in
sure but but we're we're all agreeing
that that's going to happen it's a
question whether
you do it with username and password or
you do it with a saml token
or you do it with an oauth token or you
do it with a cert
all of those would unlock all of that
or are we discussing multiple states at
the same time we have a
configuration provisioning state where
we set up a device we
authorize ourselves to use an account
and all that
and that's one thing and then we
bootstrap kind of a running state
where we have to answer incoming calls
and that's another thing i think we have
to separate these
in order to clear the running state
involves sip
and answering calls and we have java
persistent authentication
for that okay and we have to have
considered situations where we
have to accept expired certificates or
stuff
for handling emergency calls and other
things
but let's discuss two different things
because we
we have definitely have a login state
where
we provision accounts and so and we can
discuss how often you do that
or reasons to go back and do it when you
add
new additional services and stuff okay
we're we're over time now um so we're
going to have to close it out and
go back to the list um i i wish
yes i i very much appreciate everybody's
participation in the session
um it was it was very helpful um
let's see how far we can get on the list
on these issues if we need an interim
meeting or something else to
work out one or more of these things we
can we can schedule that
which could be scheduled at a different
time scale um
uh but thank you all very very much for
for uh showing up to you uh and
um so look look for a list traffic and
and and please respond
thanks now you can all go back to bed
yeah for those of you in those time
zones
yes yes
bye stay safe bye now
thanks bye bye