hello
uh welcome to the tease workbook
on our virtual or online ietf
109. we have
uh i'm blue burger pavon burum's online
i think we have
matt i'm not sure if matt is here but
he's always
very helpful and as our working group
secretary uh as usual the material
is online you can also if you click on
the chat button you should be able to
see the links
to that excuse me um
and you'll also see the link to code emd
which is our um
collaborative minute taking uh please do
go
join us there there's only a few people
there right now uh please join us there
and if you hear comments uh said during
the session
please help by capturing those
particularly if you also
say comments
see if i can turn flip slides there we
go
this is a formal ietf meeting which our
note
means our notewell applies and
everything we say and do here is
governed by our process
and become part of our permanent record
obviously we're using meat echo for this
meeting if you're
joining us today live you know
that's how you joined um we also are
uh uh reporting and
as usual um minutes uh audio
and video will be published and
so again everything you say here is part
of that record
and again please help with the minute
taking
as always seems to happen we end up with
a very packed agenda
uh no matter how much time we request we
always seem to fill it
uh which is great that's nice to have an
active working group
um this the only thing that's changed
since originally published as we
reordered things a little bit
um so if you happen to look at the
the first version of the agenda you
may find yourself moved around in
time and in order we
there was a minor tweaking on time just
to fit all the requests
we do give preference of course to
working group drafts and other
chartered activities
we will continue to be working this way
for a while as everyone has seen itf 109
is um sorry this is
updated a bunch of different slides
ietf110
um is going to be online
so our next one is online uh we're
online now
we'll continue working this way for a
while
please use the list and we have the
online webex available
for both informal meetings and uh
formal interims all it takes is
to get one of those is to make a request
to the chairs and we will set you up
with it for interims um you can also
request an interim although we
we will initiate those as um
we think necessary as you saw sometimes
we initiate and they
they don't quite work out um as happened
with our last interim
but we we want to use these online
meetings between idf's to keep our
process going so that
even though we're not meeting in person
we keep the momentum going
our formal ipr process which we do polls
both that accept working group
acceptance
and as part of our last call
um hasn't changed um
and but i think and i think everyone is
familiar with it but it's always good to
show this to remind newcomers
we're going to work through walk through
the um
uh active drafts in a moment uh pavon
will do that
um in terms of where we are from
the publication process we have one uh
new uh rfc this is actually
quite the bit of work um that was done
to get us here
and it's a um it's a
a significant foundational document in
in our yang work and this is about
um this allows us to represent te
topologies
in yang it's it took quite a while to
get
there and we really appreciate all who
contributed to it and their hard work
we have um we have one document
that is with the iesg there was
uh actually fun i i think you were gonna
talk about this on the in
the next slide deck so i'll leave it for
there and
um we also have had one new adoption
since the last meeting
we haven't received any liaisons we have
jointly sent
one liaison and it shows um
what our recent drafts and rfcs as well
as
working group changes um it's available
um
if you're looking online um you can
click on that link
and with that we're going to jump into
uh more detailed status
on drops and
okay hello everyone
my name is pawan bhiram i'm your other
co-chair
working group document status as you can
see on the slide is next on the agenda
we do have a very packed agenda so i'll
try and keep this
as as i can can you go to the next slide
please
so we currently have 21 working group
documents
they're all listed here five of those
the ones that are marked in blue or on
the agenda today
uh there is one draft the pc native ip
draft that
lou was referring to earlier is
currently under isg processing
it's actually currently with our ad
there was a new revision published for
this over the weekend uh
addressing uh deborah's comments um
there will be uh further guidance on the
proposed status of this document
that would be provided in a few days
time so
the guidance would be to change the
proposed status to a
informational so keep an eye out for
that email so that leaves us with 15
other documents the status of each of
them is covered in this deck
uh the modeling drafts for t um
let's let's stay on the let's see on the
yeah the modeling drafts for t and rsvp
and l3 and sr topology augments
are all nearing completion they've all
had a young doctor review done
we also have tom petch diligently
reviewing each of these
thanks to him the authors have been
making sure that each of his comments
do get addressed uh there's also this
new expectation rather recommendation
from the young doctors
to add a json instance of the young
model
in the appendix uh of the draft in which
the model is proposed
so the plan for most of these documents
uh is to address the last set of
comments from tom
add the json instance to the appendix
and then request working with last call
so in the meantime it would be great if
you could get some more reviews and
feedback and on the usability of these
modules
there are a couple of young documents
that are listed here as
ready for young doctor review those are
the act and vn yang
and the path computation young documents
we initiated the review process for both
of these documents over the weekend
we also have three documents marked in
red here which are currently in expired
state
the authors have promised to revive
those uh this week
um so before we move on to the next
slide deck there are a couple of
uh topics that i would like to double
click on so let's jump to slide six
yeah so this is the smp raft uh there
are a couple of open items for which the
others are seeking some inputs
they did start a couple of threads for
this on the list adrian did chime in on
one of them
i would encourage others to participate
in those threats and
help the others close them
let's go to slide seven
this is the document that discusses pce
cc use cases
a few meetings back there was some
debate on whether
they should just remain as a living
document and not go through the
publication process
we decided then to revisit the status of
this document at a later point in time
we believe it is that time now the
authors have just requested to change
the state of this document to
adopt it for working group info only
we would like to get some opinions in on
this before we make the change we
understand there's been
a fair bit of work uh put in to get this
document to the stage
and uh don't uh really want to
discourage folks from making similar
contributions going forward
so if the authors or anybody who wants
to chime in with their thoughts
yeah it would be great
drew or any of the authors would you
like to say something
so i think based on the past comments we
we thought that because the isg itself
was not preferring too many use cases
documents basically when
the extension work was almost ready and
these documents have done their job of
like you know convincing the working
group and the itf that this
work is needed so that was the
understanding we were in but we would
respect whatever opinion that the chairs
and the ads suggest
and if there is a push to uh publish we
would of course
be more happy to publish it because we
have done the work but
we are following the guidance that has
given to us so we are completely open to
what
you throw our way okay
fair enough anybody else would like to
chime in
so lou and i would uh discuss this with
ada
and make a call on it we will share the
outcome of that discussion on the list
uh i will stop here with respect to this
tech i'll let you go through the rest of
the slides and also the reports that are
sent to the list in leisure
please do send out an email on the list
if you find anything missing
so any quick questions on the status of
any working route
any working group document before we
invite drew to present the star
the next presentation
i guess not through europe
i will be presenting an update to three
working group documents
they are all yang model related to ac tn
and vn
next slide
so we have uh nine uh yang models here
we have a vn yang model uh augmenting of
te
and vn for kpi telemetry and
a bunch of service mapping model where a
generic types model
and then augmentation of various service
models
and network model so let's go over an
update of
each of them uh next slide
and maybe one more you can
yes so this is a introduction to what vn
yang
is this is the young model for vn
operations
it is from the customer point of view we
uh use heavily the abstract topology and
uh and the connectivity matrix to
uh to represent the vn model and
it is it is a higher abstraction it is
from the customer's point of view
and this has been uh sort of like
getting ready for a while we are
as power earlier mentioned that we think
that we are young doctor review ready
but i will quickly go over
what are the recent set of changes that
we have made next slide
so if you guys uh remember uh in the
last
meeting we presented an uh and
suggestion
from kenichi ogaki from kddi where he
would want
wanted to make a change to the vm
compute we discussed that during the
last meeting
and that change has been incorporated in
the draft so the basically the change
allows the vn compute rpc to be a single
rpc that can be used
uh to make a single call to get the
result
or the vn result in one call as i
mentioned earlier since we were
dependent on t topology earlier this was
a two call so that they wanted to
simplify and the way to simplify was
pretty straightforward we optionally
included two
groupings in the vm compute these are
the te types grouping
for generic path constraints and t types
grouping for generic path optimization
by reusing these two groupings in vn
compute we are able to now
get the results and pass all the
information needed for vn computation
in one rpc call this has been done
at the vl level as well as at the vn
member level
so this is the main change that we have
done but uh
continuing there were some more comments
that's uh in the next slide
so those are our current uh pending work
uh so the pending work is uh there was a
request
from kenichi that if we can describe
this in
a buy a figure so that has been us so we
have
a figure pending that we will add for vm
compute
uh there are some editorial comments
that are still pending from tom petch i
kind of missed them when i was updating
i i realized it later so when i was
making these slides
so i will uh update on that and as i
said earlier that i think we are ready
for uh yang doctor
review so this uh finishes the vn
compute if you have any questions i
think you can jump to the queue i can
answer
right now or at the end of all the three
presentations either way it's good with
me
but i'll continue to save some time so
the next update is the kpi telemetry
yank
we have two yang models here which
augments the t
model and the vn model it adds the
various
pm telemetry uh characteristics as well
as the scaling intent mechanism
into these two model this allows the
customer to subscribe to
whether at the vl level or at the t
tunnel level
uh various uh pm characteristics as well
as
uh we have a concept called automatic uh
uh
autonomic scaling intent which has been
been there from the start so the update
in this document
next slide is uh
it's pretty basic we had a change added
some
editorial cleanup of the yang model
there were some references that were
incorrect so that got fixed we had a
comment that we should describe
uh how the vl level performance metric
is
calculated so we have added that detail
in the description
uh of how at the vl level these metrics
are computed which is usually the max of
the vn members
so that's the minimal change in this
document the next what we have
uh next slide so next we have the te
service mapping gang
uh as i said this there are a bunch of
augmentation in this model i will just
quickly describe what this model is in
the next slide
so the role of this tea service mapping
model is to create
a mapping relationship between various
service models that we have
in itf l3 sm l2 sm layer 1
csm as well as uh we also allow the same
grouping to be used for the network
models
as well and we map these uh service and
network model to
our these yang models at various levels
at the topology level at the tunnel
level
or at the vn level so the main reason
why we do this so that we could have a
very seamless service operation
that when the customer is thinking in
terms of l3 sm
and underlying there are te tunnels
involved
we have a a mapping between how those
services are being delivered
uh uh using the un underlay te resources
this allows us to do various monitoring
diagnostic
and various other things uh to maintain
this
mapping next slide so
uh what what has been updated as you
know l3 and m and l2 nm
uh were added in the last update which
we discussed in the working group we
added a thing called tea mapping
template
there was a support for sr policy that
was added so these were all
the changes that we made uh last time
and they were a comment
on the mailing list again from kenichi
and we are very thankful for
or to him to come to come up with new
use cases
as he's implementing this model so one
requirement
that they had was they wanted to map one
l3 sm to
actually multiple vm models and they
said
that they have a use case that that is
use
that is needed for this and we discussed
on the list uh
it doesn't harm us uh to have a mapping
i think the most
usual case would be one is to one case
but if an operator wants to
further break it down into multiple vms
and maintain them separately for some
reason
it doesn't harm from the yang modeling
point of view so that's why
this change has been made and this was
discussed on the list
in the past as well apart from that the
changes were there were some errors in
our ex parts
that were pointed out to us which we
have fixed
after posting this update there was some
more discussion which is on the next
slide
where kenichi asked us to also handle
kios
profile which uh i will uh describe so
the what you see
are the two further augments that we
discussed on the mailing list that
uh that needs to be added which is
at the l3 vpn site level they have
a keyos profile and they allow you to
create
a custom qos profile and give
constraints
etc right there at the site level so
there
they wanted to maintain a mapping
between uh
these custom qos profile and the vnap
that is created
by our uh to to service this
uh this custom qos profile so that one
is to one mapping we are maintaining
maintaining it here so we wanted to get
more feedback
uh from people especially who have
implemented l3sm and have
uh feedback on this whether this augment
makes sense
and if
needs to change we will we will make
that change in the next slide
and that covers all the changes that we
have made in the last
uh these three yang models uh
any comments
see oscar is
oscar quite
there is a unmute button on the top the
mic button
ah now can you hear me now okay
that one so my question is in
in the latest uh i changed
that you that was proposed it was
announced on
l3sm to map the qs so would that also
apply
12 12 3 nm
yeah i think that's a very good uh
question uh
i i feel like you know that custom keyos
class if it is
existing in the l3 nm then of course it
would i have to check whether that's the
case or not and i think you can answer
it
right away you would know whether you
have something like custom qs profile
in l3 and m as well we have all the
profiles
because they apply also to the they
apply to both
a service model and a network model the
profiles applied to both
yeah so then i would definitely augment
both
this is just an example for l3sm i'll
make sure that that's applicable
for every other place where it's needed
okay thank you
is
okay guess not
we can proceed thank you
next up is dan
hi chairs um i was actually going to
present my screen remotely if possible
i've just requested
the screen okay
can you hear me clearly we can yeah i'm
trying to grant it
maybe i have to stop her
uh yeah yes okay let's see if this works
i'll be a guinea pig
i actually appreciate that better for us
oh you're very welcome
okay uh hi guys it's uh it's morning
here uh in the uk
i'll be talking about the applicability
of ac
tn to poi packet optical integration
there is um two documents actually that
uh attempted to show the applicability
of actn to
poi and actually the document uh that
you see
currently is the merger of these
efforts that's why we we do have quite
an
exhaustive list of sort of authors and
contributors you know good percentage
actually of the tease working group
um so what is the intention of the work
it's really to show uh almost a cookbook
of how you would take
the functional architecture of actn
the various functional components the
specific interfaces
and what procedures and protocols
specifically data models you would use
in order to
set up and operate packet over
optical services so this is um
really important i think work because it
it highlights all of the the discussions
that we're having with sort of the
separate
um protocols and data models and how we
will
use those in order to sort of deploy
these
services and from an operator
perspective as well as a vendor
perspective it's important to know if
these procedures and models are actually
suitable and
and fit for purpose we spend all this
time actually developing
uh yang models but you know how
efficient
are they and you know what are the gaps
uh
tends to be sort of uh after we've
deployed them in the field if there
isn't sufficient
um interrupt or implementation early on
in the
development of the document itself and
so we we know actually that
um the focus of the work is going to be
on the southbound interfaces
so it's predominantly between the
multi-domain service coordinator
and the underlying uh controllers
or managers you say the the physical the
packet physical
and the optical physical uh network
controller and ideally um
when we finish the work we will have a
fairly good
uh understanding of uh
what are the available models some are
optional you know how are they used
uh were there specific implementation
or technology gaps uh are there
operational management security issues
that that were not
identified uh during the development of
of some of these procedures
and protocols so
how about a reference architecture well
it's fairly
um formulaic essentially it's sort of
four domains
um so we have a hierarchy of
our packet layer that sits on top of the
optical layer and then
sort of uh sort of horizontally we've
got domain one
uh and domain two um and
these these interfaces in black uh are
between the
uh mdse and then the packet and the
optical uh pncs
uh respectively and then we've got a
further set of interfaces between
um the pnc and the optical uh pnc
to the actual layer the technology
domain
where the the actual sort of nodes uh
sit
and you already um there are a number of
generic and technology-specific models
that we can use
and we're seeing a number of kind of
not necessarily issues but some sort of
clarifications that that may be needed
there and i'll cover that a little bit
later
um what isn't in scope
uh of course is above the mdse but
it it turns out actually that some of
the operators who are involved in the
work are
uh very interested in sort of having
that discussion but
for the time being it's it's kind of out
of scope
so if you were to read the document in
its current form
uh we've we've managed to do sort of the
first
uh pass of merging the sort of prior
prior two documents that i highlighted
earlier so we currently have
uh two phases that we're working on
phases or scenarios i suppose uh you
might call these but it's it's how we
generate the um the view of the network
so
our sort of physical network topology
discovery
and then existing service
topology discovery uh how that
information is carried between the
various pncs
uh to the mdsc there are some sort of
procedures some aspects sort of
operationally that
that are kind of interesting to consider
and
and this includes things like the link
discoveries and the attachments
um discovery so some
operators might see this discovery
mechanism as being a
a sort of security risk you know other
operators may see it as
something that would be nice to have so
whether it's static
whether there's some sort of automated
uh process that that's kind of
some of the discussion that we're having
in the document currently
so i mentioned already that uh we've
identified
the common young models you know so the
tea
[Music]
service and the topology young models
and then we've got our
sort of technology specific extensions
or augmentations
that we're using as well and and this is
essentially the the ingredients that
we're using as part of our
our cookbook there are of course um some
uh service models um that that we
are considering as well uh for
some of the the packet aspects um sorry
not
serve service model network model so our
l2 nm
and our l3 and m uh models there
and another aspect to consider here is
the
um the the ongoing discussion whether
to use the the the uni topo versus
client topo so essentially um your what
augments
uh rfc 8345 with the service attach
attachment point abstraction discussion
we know that
that what we're sort of highlighting in
our document
is occurring as a parallel discussion
in things like the ops area and actually
sort of in in other
documents here in teas and also ccamp so
there are some discussion points around
um around the implementation of of uh
htm and poi that that are still ongoing
so
clearly um the work that we're doing is
just kind of feeding into some of that
parallel
discussion uh good
um so i think i just highlighted
actually some of the chapters
or sections uh in our in our document
so if if have read the document
you may have noticed there's actually
quite a lot of text and
and of clearly you know i'm sure the
chairs and certainly the isg would
appreciate brevity
or succinctness uh with with this type
of document
but i just want to kind of highlight
actually that because there are
sort of so many options and and various
permutations it's really important i
think
to document some of our assumptions
and maybe going forward we can actually
uh
prune you know or distill um some of
this discussion text
to make it uh sort of a little less
bloaty in the document but at least for
the time being we've just kind of
captured
all of the discussion and probably sort
of spent too much
effort uh working on our assumptions and
documenting those assumptions so maybe
going forward we will definitely try to
prune that text down
but some of the meat of the document
here are is contained within section
four
because this is you know how we actually
um solve some of these
scenarios so as i mentioned already you
know how we populate the topology
uh and current connectivity and then how
we establish uh
our sort of optical and then packet
services on top of that
so what are we currently uh working on
well there are at numerous open
issues uh these are sort of tracked here
sort of the
the current uh trend seems to be to use
uh github and
we will be mindful of course not to do
all of our work
by github uh what we will uh
sort of attempt to continue and i hope
we've achieved this
so far is to address some of the
uh sort of the issues uh the open
uh discussion points for instance there
may be you know how we discover
and populate uh inventory um in the mdsc
from the pncs
um what are the service attachment
points that we're using versus
some of the discussion around um uni and
client and what's actually being exposed
you these these are discussions that can
occur ideally on
the t's working list um
mailing list but we will also be
sort of discussing these during our
almost
weekly call that we actually have for
this particular piece of work and then
reporting some of the findings some of
the conclusions that we reach on these
separate calls
on the mailing list itself some of them
the other sort of hot topics at the
moment are around isolation we know that
sort of
um you know network slicing uh
and and isolation so sort of
providing circuits providing
a bandwidth to your particular
customers or particular um topologies
that are then represented in the mds
kind of a
a hot topic and whether that's uh uh
soft or hard
isolation continues to be an ongoing
discussion
uh what what we haven't addressed in the
document that that will be
uh in the next version are some of the
some of the additional operational
issues and drew just kind of highlighted
that
with some of the telemetry discussion on
the previous talk so
not only of course are we providing
network connectivity for sort of packing
over optical services but
we almost certainly will want to monitor
that
connectivity and in the event of some
kind of degrade
in service uh and certainly lots of
connectivity it needs to be reported
um adequately um and uh
appropriate action needs to be changed
or appropriate
action needs to be taken and potential
network changes
uh will incur what what isn't as
sort of discussed in the document
currently is is things like sort of um
pre-computed path um protection
for either type of service that seems to
be just a a step too far at this point
thank you i think those are um all the
slides i have
okay we have joel in the queue uh joel
go ahead
i wasn't going to raise this but since
you made a point of mentioning
isolation may i suggest you don't
talk in terms of isolation did you talk
in terms of
observable service parameters confidence
of delivering
observable service parameters and at
least until
there is actual working group agreement
on what the heck isolation means and how
it's supposed to be related to anything
else
just stay away from it
point taken clearly understood
thanks joel that's a that's a great
point
okay anybody else
uh thanks dan uh adrian you're up next
great
just wait for that slide to show up uh
so this
is uh rsc
320 bis so 3272
is the um overview
and discussion document for traffic
engineering in the internet
and way back we decided
uh that it would be helpful to update
this
old document so we did um
a couple of revisions and then it got
adopted
in july um uh
and it has been silent since then and in
my opinion
silence is not particularly helpful it
is not indicative of work in progress
it's uh really indicative of
nobody having the energy so
since i
had volunteered in inverted commerce to
be the editor of the work
i updated uh in uh
early july just to capture a couple of
points
that were raised during the adoption
poll
uh in particular um
whether the uh components of traffic
engineering
all needed to be present for a system to
be
truly traffic engineering and this is
phrased in terms now of
te versus partial t e
uh since then uh i've embarked on
editorial polish so going through
the the text which was
i think somewhat in uh daniel leduc's
uh tone of voice and
uh been polishing it a little bit um
the o2 came out start of the month where
i'd reached
uh 2.4.1 i've just posted
03 today where i have reached
section 5.3 which is almost exactly
halfway through the document
so i'll keep working on that um
and from here on the choice of how we
proceed
is either uh
we get some input from the working group
anyone or everyone and that's
edits or text suggestions or comments or
complaints
there are seven sections
needing technical overview material
they're all marked tbds they're very
easy to find in the document
and they cover quick igpte
alto network slicing
deterministic networking sdn and
intent based networking and if anybody
wants to
supply text for any of those sections
that would be most welcome
you might drop a note to the list just
to say you're doing it
so that nobody else works on the same
section at the same time so failing
anybody else doing anything my plan
would be to complete the document
by christmas myself either
um by um
carefully polishing or hitting it with a
hammer depending on
how short of time i am and then uh
asking the chairs
to get on and last call it uh in the new
year
as early as possible uh because
one way or the other it's i think it's
clear that the working group will have
finished
whatever it thinks needs doing and we
need to get that review and
and be finished that's it
any comments
so i see someone typing in comey md a
comment
it would be good if they uh made the
jeff good
hello yeah jeff go ahead oh
oh you can help me i'll do the intel
based networking part
lovely thank you i'll do it on daily
basis
which day
every day that's you
that's your intent yep i have great
intentions
we have drew and boris next through
good
working group i think when we started
out this work our main intention was
that we can point
to this document when somebody outside
the working group may be brte comes to
mind
and sr policy and srte discussion that
we had
so should we also evangelize this work
and say like look we have now a good
reference
being ready and see if outside the
working group people
can start using it and that could also
give us some inputs whether
we have succeeded in our mission in
clarifying what is te
in 2020 i think uh
i'm picking that from the bottom yes if
if
um if people are able to use it it will
give us a good
idea that we've done a good job um
but um before pushing it out
for other people um with us saying this
is
the reference i would like to hear more
than just me
saying this is um this document
captures our opinion
and i'm not hearing that at the moment
okay boris
okay so just as
jeff mentioned i also would like to
volunteer and help you
with those additional text pieces
that would be perfect so please have a
have a look at the document
um grab a section and write some text
i'm only looking for each of these
sections i'm only looking for sort of
three paragraphs
otherwise the document becomes
unbalanced
so it shouldn't be big work
okay got it
okay thanks adrian thanks for driving
this forward uh
there is still a fair bit of work to be
done so if anyone is interested in
contributing uh please do reach out to
adrian and
see how you can help
we are now moving to that segment of the
session for which
most of you have been waiting for and
are up but not are
75 minutes of network slicing topics
coming up
so after the last ietf we did
an adoption poll for a couple of
documents that were
produced by the design team the calls
failed but it did generate a lot of
great discussion uh it sort of resulted
in a bit of a research
uh resetting with respect to the
terminology the authors have been
focusing on addressing uh the comments
that were raised during the adoption
poll and
we will hear from them about it in a
little bit
uh the discussion on the list uh seems
to suggest that we are converging on
some
controversial items so uh like everyone
else i'm also eager to see how this
session progresses
so before we bring yari in to give a
brief update on
the design team um do you have anything
else to add
we'll see how it goes today and figure
out what the right next step is
so thanks for the intro and over to yari
okay do you hear me okay you can
yeah so if you can just move to the next
slide so my intent
was not to speak at length just sort of
give a very high level
status report and you know way forward
and
you know where are we and where where
are we not um
so as vishnu mentioned we attempted to
do a working adoption in august or in
the summer
which didn't succeed but i think there's
reason to
think that we can succeed and we are
close uh the issues during the summer
were primarily around terminology
names in particular and isolation a few
other
topics and since then a lot of work has
happened a lot of discussion has
happened
revisions have been made i believe on
the name issue of
or calling these terms a particular
thing
is that that's a solved issue
but uh one would observe that once you
move
past some issue like this like you don't
like the name of a thing
it's only then that some people actually
get to
think more about the actual content or
substance of things so i think some of
the
discussions that we've seen recently is
in that category that okay now we sort
of put that thing past us but let's
now look at what the thing actually says
and so
adrienne's drive for more accurate
definitions is in this category some of
the discussion isolation
some discussion on scope and so forth
screens
changing okay now it's back
i think my advice at least for this is
that we should find
what we have what is the commonly
acceptable minimal set of things and
move on
the reason for that is really that uh i
mean there's a lot of things that we
could do
let's let's agree on the on the simple
things
and uh the the concepts discussed here
are actually important for other work
and maybe not in terms of like actual
reference to
you know document dependency as such but
there's a lot of work that sort of
you know enters the space one way or the
other
and um if we actually had some agreement
about the terms what are we even talking
about
and i think that would be beneficial to
keep the keep the thing together
um and uh so for instance anything
that's discussed
in in in this section of the agenda like
it's
highly dependent on this so um and the
final comment is that
uh you know the we had a design team uh
the design team produced some results
that were
discussed by the working group and we've
intentionally
wanted to move the discussion to the
working group like it's not that the
design team has much
that much discussions it's mostly
practical if
if anything so
everything is really in the hands of the
working group and so
you know we we design team have no
particular status
the authors can propose stuff and they
they have and they revise documents
thank you for that but i think the
agreement needs to be found
in the working group amongst all of us
so so i think that's the
setup for kiran and others to start
talking about the actual details
and substance so i think i'm done here
unless people have
high level comments at this point where
i think we can move on
any comments
i'll be back
for providing the overview and
let's get into the details of what we
have been doing
specifically from the definitions draft
perspective
and as you notice the name of the draft
has changed
and i'll just provide an update on
behalf of all the authors
next slide please
um so an overview of the changes so
things you look at the
left column they have been pretty stable
even if we have gone through um
different discussions in between two
itfs
108 and 109 and interim meeting
our core definition hasn't changed the
way we describe the characteristics of
structure and stakeholders different
sections they haven't changed a whole
lot in terms of the content
what we did bring change was related to
the naming of course
and then we improved some of the text
related to sli and slos because they are
also the core part of the concept that
we are bringing in with network slices
and there was an action item to bring in
some
text for isolation we also got a
feedback that
security consideration should not be
left empty so
some text was provided there and um
we also got some feedback to remove
a lot of descriptive text from the
document and
probably make it a candidate for
framework um
draft later on next slide please
so in interim meeting it was um
mentioned that
transport slice is as the name is not
acceptable it was non-starter
so we pulled the mailing list came up
with 14 suggestions
and it seems that idf network slice was
the
name which was majorly selected
and if you want to see the pluses and
minuses
of all the names mentioned here i have
attached two slides
at the bottom so you can look at it
later on
next slide please
and once we change the name how things
how rest of the content changed into the
document
um now we don't have transport slices we
specific
we very clearly defined that we are
talking about ietf scoped
network in our document we qualify term
ietf because there was
a great amount of discussion that there
are other
parts in the network where you would use
network slicing so ietf
network slices not an end-to-end
solution so
having some kind of a prefix or a
qualifying term for ietf technologies
was necessary and the definition remains
the same
whatever we had as transport controller
is now called idf network slice
controller and accordingly we have
changed
nses and nsres as well
next slide please
and in terms of improvement i got
um a lot of review comments mainly from
adrian where we kind of restructured the
document
changed the nesting in the sense some
sections were pulled out at the top
level
and that we also deleted lot of stuff to
make document
more readable and i mentioned earlier
that
now we have a better text for
slo sli and it's easy to read also
it blends in with rest of the sections
much better
and the there was a general
feedback that you should not be talking
about too many details about
realization of the slices in this
definitions draft so we took lot of
section
related to that and some of the use case
description we had from the document
we also had um quite a
lot of discussion on what vertical or
horizontal slices
mean and we have taken that out for now
and hopefully framework document will
find some
space for that kind of explanation but
right now we just described the concepts
that how you would extend the slices
using
um hierarchical or sequential mechanisms
it's very brief right now next slide
and so one of the major discussion was
on isolation text
and the the way we brought in the text
is by explaining what we mean by
isolation
and the key point here we want to
highlight is that
from a consumer perspective there should
be no negative
impact on that customer slice
whenever there are changes in other
parts of the network
and then we have added text to describe
it in certain ways
and another thing we want to highlight
here is that customers should be able to
ask
for isolation explicitly yes it is
possible that in some cases
there are certain slos that will uh
satisfy isolation requirement but in
other cases the
customer may have explicit requirement
because
they feel the need that okay i i feel
that
this thing will not negatively impact me
so i would explicitly ask for that
so we decided to keep that text there
and i just described why it should be
slo
or not so we are not going to get into
that debate
and uh there was a discussion that we
should just keep a play
a placeholder and not provide any text
before
work grouping option but we felt that
providing some text that we can refine
going forward is much better than just
leaving it blank
next nextly
and we still have a couple of review
comments one is related to
improve the security section further to
describe it in a
slightly better manner and we are
working on it
there was one comment from med on the
mailing list that
from his perspective the document still
looks like
connectivity-centric and he needs to
provide us some more comments where he
thinks
that something is missing and what is
that
thing that he would like to get added
into the document
next slide so this is where we
are i personally think
that we could go ahead with give a group
adoption adoption
mainly the reason is that a lot of
people have contributed here
and yes we are still discussing couple
of items but
by and large document has remained
stable from last six months
of course readability has improved a lot
as we kept refining things and so the
open issues are
um rather incremental and
hopefully we can converge on them so
that was my last slide
thank you
i really wish you hadn't put in text on
the isolation
because i would really like to be able
to adopt the document
but the text you have put in doesn't
work it isn't a definition
it instead introduces ambiguity that
maybe there's something here maybe there
isn't
we had agreed to leave placeholder in i
was comfortable with having
a section that said this is a topic
that's under discussion
and we could do it later but the text
you put in doesn't work for me and if we
if there's an adoption call
with the text as it is given how
misleading it is
i would have to object to the adoption
so that is
um so what is the criteria for
workgroup adoption we can still continue
to
improve the document after that i mean
we need some starting tech
text don't we no we don't need we don't
need starting text on isolation the
agreement was not
that you were going to provide starting
text the agreement was we're going to
leave a placeholder in
yes this is not done
allow me to finish katan the working
group can improve the document
but at the same token though i am not as
a work group member obliged to adopt
text that i think is actually wrong
and in this case i think the text you
have put in is wrong
and that's an obstacle tie to adoption
places where it needs refinement i of
course there's places that need
refinement that doesn't bother me
but when it's wrong and misleading and
actively misleading as far as i'm
concerned
there's a problem
okay so i have seen your replies on the
mailing list also i understand where
you're saying things are wrong
but i haven't seen your definition of
isolation how would you like to express
it
because i don't think a definition of
isolation i don't believe the term is
needed
i'm willing to leave a placeholder so
that people can propose text
for discussion but i do not believe
there is any need for the term therefore
i am not going to propose a definition
okay
i wonder if anyone thinks they're
talking because it's quite quiet
that's what i was thinking i was
wondering if my internet was working
stuart is it your internet wow that
explains a lot
same situations
apparently things work now
i can see no i cannot see anything
all of you i'll come back again
uh seems like everybody got disconnected
uh
so can you guys hear me
can someone acknowledge i can hear you
yes bro okay
give me one minute
yeah i had some issue can you hear me
yeah i think the the whole session
dropped
i mean it dropped for them oh okay
okay okay i thought it's only me
no no we can hear you reza okay
okay the joy appears to be that there
was a
meat echo vm reboot
okay
so uh i think
we were in the middle of a discussion
with between joel
and kiron
yes see if we give people a minute i
think we're about at the same head count
we were before
lou is it possible that you could
unshare your screen
there's just a black screen there
the share space
i don't see an issue
now all i see is the black screen i'm
republishing
yes so we have both the black screen and
the new screen
elegant beat echo i don't know
i would say click reload but i'm a
little worried that you might not get
back in
yeah and in particular right now i don't
need to see the screen for the
conversation we were having
or right so uh let me kick it off with a
question
to you all uh yes uh
what i think i heard you say is that
no definition of isolation would be
acceptable to you
that's not no i think that's what i
heard you really say
i don't well i do not believe there is a
definition of isolation that is useful
but i am perfectly willing to allow for
discussion and proposal
but the definition that has been
proposed is not useful and i don't know
of a useful definition
so i can't very well propose one i mean
tom said so joel why haven't you
proposed a definition and the answer is
because i don't think it's a useful
concept to the task
okay um i i think we can note that
and um move to the
person unless you have another point my
problem with the text as it is
is i consider it seriously misleading
on the topic that's why i was perfectly
willing to to the agreement you
that you two chairs said we'll just put
in a placeholder and we'll
discuss separately what the definition
might be
okay uh have you
expressed how you think it's flawed
i believe so okay do you think
is kieran back
i didn't see her we have to wait
come on
okay here we go yes
welcome back yeah sorry i didn't realize
i was on mute
so yes we have started some discussion
and uh what we got was initially
scratched text from
people who are already in the queue to
once answer that
one feedback is we are going to strip
down
lot of information which is related to
realization
and have a minimal text so that
there is a way to express isolation from
a customer perspective
that's what i'm looking for right now
and we can have further discussions on
the email list and that is why this text
just here
is there in the draft so that we can
iteratively revise it so that everybody
agrees to it
and one thing we are clearly saying that
we are not making taking a stance that
isolation is always related to slo
and it can be met by all the slos
you could have additional parameters
that or some additional characteristic
which could come from
a regulatory perspective or it could
come from security side of things or the
perception of
the customer who wants to deploy that
slice
so we just want to provide a mechanism
to express that characteristic
i think it'd be really good to take this
discussion more
and follow it up on the list by joel if
it's okay
we have a bunch of people in the queue
and we got a little delayed because of
the meat echo
i think it'd be good to give them an
opportunity to speak as well if that's
okay
there okay thanks uh stuart
europe um well i
i will start with making a fundamental
objection to the position
that uh joel was taking it is not his
working group
it is not his right to object on behalf
of the working group
it is the working group to take a
decision and he may or may not be in the
rough
and i think that's a position that the
chairs should take
um as to uh isolation i find it a useful
concept
and found it a useful concept in the uh
days when we were working on vpn plus
because it it to my mind it does
describe um the concept of
two services operating in different
universes
now we can work on text but
i i don't i'm not sure why this why one
objection
by one person to one section should stop
a draft progressing
i think that's correct of chairs i have
not uh heard it stopping for questing
i've heard
an individual's objection and uh
you know it's duly noted and will
continue to be discussed on the list but
it's
as you say it's just one individual's
objection
uh i think
yeah um this is a difficult topic and
you know this is the reason why i i said
that it's important
for us to agree on the pits that we we
do agree and move on
and uh actually um we had a really good
process on this
name issue like we had people propose
alternatives you know you have an issue
with what we had
here's some alternatives that you know
and pros and cons and let's discuss that
and and
make a decision we didn't quite follow
the same process
in in this other discussion um
so it's more of like you know this is
the this text and you know let's edit it
if it needed or take away or not take
away
and so so we didn't really do this you
know top-down thing that
hey we could do a b or c or d
here and i i think that was a mistake
the discussion would have been easier if
we had done that and
maybe there's still time to do that
perhaps but um
yeah um so it should be noted that
like lots of people do have differing
opinions on this
um aspect i i do too by
the way i i think the
current text is somewhat misleading
there's been some discussion on the list
actually if
you follow those uh like adrian posted a
suggestion
of a fairly drastic cut down of the text
joel has said that he doesn't like to
mention it at all
and and so on i actually agreed
personally with
adrian's proposal
for me
not not not like nailing down the things
that we need to we need to do i think
for me what's important here is that we
do mention these concepts because
it is talked about um in the industry
um but we need to relate it to our
concepts
and and it we can't have the situation
where we have like this
concepts like you know you have reserved
bandwidth and then wink wink you don't
actually have a certain bandwidth but if
you have this other property then you
have
reserved bandwidth but wink wink it
doesn't actually work if you
you know a note goes down and then you
must have the third concept of false
tolerance of some sort
so you know there are some issues there
and i
i think we would do the industrial
service if we actually sort of tried to
relate
the industry terms to what we are
speaking about
and i think that would be totally fine
because we still are talking about
isolation then in the document
and uh we're not overselling it we're
not confusing anything
we are relating that you know this this
aspect can be represented by those
things
that we have elsewhere in the document
and and then we move on
and the final comment is that like i
think part of the objective that joel
had was that you know whose default goes
into the document
like we have several opinions about this
stuff obviously the working group
decides
all of us together um but uh
but i understand his position that he
doesn't want to start
from you know somebody else's definition
if he would like to have his definition
perhaps or start from a
blank sheet of paper where everybody is
on the same
position kind of so
i you know if it was me i would either
start with empty section placeholder
or adrian's definition i'd be happy with
adrian
that's all i had thank you
okay so uh jeff you're up and i'd like
to
cut the line if possible because we are
well over on the slot
sure so since i you just because
i brought this term number of times to
discuss with joel i actually stopped
doing this because my impression is
no definition will do anything i as long
as it's mtmrk
you put something that i'm unhappy so i
mean it shouldn't be
like this the definition i propose
they come from my experience personal
experience while
it's not observable it's definitely
something
and customers should be able to request
i've seen this in my life it's
definitely business and working
agreement so
i believe it should be there whether
it's under definition
or whatever we already have in the draft
we can find the text as long as we want
to come with the text and some
definitions
not to oppose to anything so that's my
position
okay
g
jimmy i just want to can you hear me
yeah good okay i just want to
say that um actually because network
lies
the network slicing is not only defining
itf
and for the whole industry isolation is
described in
almost all the number slicing related
documents
and also in itf's history it has been
mentioned
in the vpn related requirements
frameworks and solutions
so my opinion is clarifying the meaning
of isolation in the itf's context
and its relationship with the other
network slicing related activity would
be
really useful and we have been
working hard to separate the requirement
from the implementation
of the isolation and i think
many people give very good comments and
suggestions
and i hope we could work together to
polish it rather than just say no we
don't need
it yeah that's my opinion
thank you greg
and uh the current document reflects uh
their agreement of the design
team or of their
those who are listed as authors on this
document
sure what question you're really asking
in the end
we have to agree um as a working group
what the term is
so it's sort of you know whoever
contributed to it doesn't have special
standing
um we have to reach consensus as a
workforce
so it's you know that's that's a
starting point
but because to my understanding is
that there is no agreement
within the design team whether isolation
is something that
observable or not
so i i think that
there is that's um
since there is no agreement then why to
have
something which is questionable present
to the working group for adoption
um it's more logical is
take it out work it on
and when it's ready then
working group can edit to the document
because the working group when working
group adopts a document
is working group document and the
working group decides
uh their changes to the document
so if there is no clear understanding
of what isolation for the net network
slice
is then
just work on it as a separate work item
thank you that dave
thanks after dave
okay um yeah my comments are more along
the lines of what greg just stated
um i i think there there are differences
of opinion i don't think it was asserted
that it was just joel that had this
opinion i don't think that's correct
um it seems like something this
controversial to the group
we can put in and then ask for working
group adoption is a little premature
it would be better to leave the
placeholder in the document have a
reasonable discussion about the
definition
and then if there's agreement add text
i at this point with the text in there i
would be against working group adoption
i mean we have to start with what we
agree with not with what we don't agree
with
thank you
all right uh thank you very much um
clearly there's more work to be done
on this before we move to adoption uh
uh kieran and the authors have said that
they will
continue to discuss it on on the list i
think that's a
a good next step um
uh i'll pavon and i will talk
between ourselves as well as with yari
of whether or not it makes sense to have
um uh informal or a formal interim
on just this this piece uh clearly
um it's really important that we have
agreement on what it is we're doing and
fundamentally that's what we're doing
with
definitions and we do need to reach
working group consensus on what it is
we're doing it's not
uh one one one person or one set of
people don't
dictate to the rest of the working group
it's consensus and
clearly we don't have it yet on at least
the isolation term
uh and it sounds like there's some good
energy to
help move us forward and we'd like to
see where that leads us
and again we'll um we'll talk
with yari about what the next step is on
an informal or formal meeting uh
pavan anything you want to add that's
one quick thing
yes good yeah so that's one option but
but you did have
another option that you would go forward
with you know let's agree that we
disagree and have a placeholder and have
that discussion after adoption
i think the document might actually be
adoptable if you did that
well given that there's an active
discussion going on
it might be good to see if we can reach
any yeah conclusions with that active
discussion and um
i was trying to leave room for that
clearly if in a few weeks we don't have
any good
resolutions we can talk about where to
go next
and i agree that just putting in a
placeholder is a viable option
no i agree with that i mean we are at a
stage where we need to make a call
um so i think given that the discussion
is happening and a
few proposals have been made uh let's uh
yeah let's discuss that i mean i
i'm not taking the place holders thing
totally out of the equation yet but yeah
i mean let's
uh discuss it uh over the next week or
so and see if there's a need for another
interrupt
okay i think we are about 25 minutes
late running late by 24 minutes
we can if there isn't anything else on
this topic we can
jump to reza's presentation
let's wait for the slides
the topic of this uh presentation
is application of uh ietf network
slicing
in 5g on behalf of my quarters i'm going
to present this one
next slightly
let's try it in five minutes that's okay
the first the draft of this presenter
this was presented at
itf 105
[Music]
now the main changes that happen to the
draft is to be aligned with the
definition of the ietf network slice
exactly how it fits in 5g all the
terminology
everything that has been done in nsdt is
reflected here
and the content of this draft is
it's shown here how itf network slice
related to 5g
how they are related and
everything related to that northbound
interface and details of the
ietf network slicing is there well
described
in the in the draft next slide
as you've seen here and it is is
basically taking that
from the definition drop network slicing
as a concept
is related not only to 5g but other use
cases
in this trap specifically we are going
to talk about
5g network slicing how is relates and
we try to address everything that
happened
on the nfct the how it relates to
5g if you go to the next slide it's
trying to then next to us like trying to
just give a context visually how that
relates that to
5g the for the end-to-end network slice
as a whole
as you see here from the left to the
right
we have started from the ue user
equipment all the way to the rand domain
to transport domain and the core domain
how
various uh area alright this domain
related to end-to-end network is clearly
shown here
that end-to-end network slides as a
whole
has component in the ram
transport or core the portion which is
related to our work
is the yellow one that is related to itf
network slice
this is important to note that this
picture
and it's applicable to other use cases
as well that
that network is life is not end-to-end
network slide
you know this is important to understand
that why we call it ietf network slides
related
to the end-to-end context it's important
to
consider this picture when we go through
the rest that when we talk about iotm
network slice
is not the end-to-end context and it is
very important and the pictures clearly
show that
this is only one component of end-to-end
context
next slide
to see the same problem from the
different angle
as you seen here starting from bottom
up of this picture i have different
networks
i have run network i have various
transport networks
and i have a core network whatever
transport network provides
is providing the connectivity between
various components and in a specific in
5g
i try to show the component that needed
to be connected because the whole idea
of ietf
network as like definition starts from
the
connection with a specific sla slash slo
in the 5g in a specific the connectivity
that we do
we do connectivity inside the run
network we are doing the connectivity
between run network and core network and
potentially in the core network
these are various transfer slices or
sorry
ietf network slices which well described
in the document
why we need that depends under your rand
deployment there are various changes
your values item
network slice will be introduced and
it's uh
i also refer to the definition graph and
picture
that we use
in the context of 5g next slide please
i have two more slides the
so the definition draft
in this case there's a summary of the
work we will
define the itf network a slice
use case in the 5g and in a specific
the nbi that we need uh we discussed
that
there are potential some augmentation
needed to be done
in the nbi the draft there is some
informational model we are still working
on that one
but this is the main topic of uh this
draft
and last slide we are seeking for uh
feedback comments we
continuously aligned this drive with
nstt work and everything
that uh is happening uh in the in a
specific in the area of the
nbi that we need and uh
the proposed uh the draft
and enhancement will be presented in the
next idea there are two questions
uh then please go ahead
document and about the section three
for 5g n2n splicing i think
uh if the work is related to ietf
it is primarily the splitting maybe
slicing requirements and the mapping
uh mapping transport slice
to other slices from
different domains so i think maybe this
part of work could
consider to combine with
the existing work in this working group
i think maybe you have also read our
document about the factory
end-to-end network slice in my opinion i
think it can be combined
and what do you think
uh i will take a look let's have that
one on the mailing issue
if there are some synergy between those
documents for sure we can do that
please send that reference on the list
and yeah and rezak and and discuss it
with reza
i think we should move on to the next
comment jimmy okay
jimmy g
yes can you hear me now uh i would have
to cut the line after g
sorry g g go ahead you go ahead
can you hear me now get scrapped yeah
good
yeah yeah i see this draft mentioned
several topics
like the use cases in 5g nanoslides
and the relationship between the itf
slice and the 5g entrance device
also it measures some dead models like
for the not bound interface so i'm
asking which topic will be the most
important for this draft and some of
this
other part may be relatively overlapped
with some work in the design team and
also the northbound interface model and
as
she should mention uh to enter a slice
mapping
i draft maybe my suggestion will be
maybe this one can focus on the use
cases
and for the other part can coordinate
with other documents
in the working group if i understand
your question
correctly so this document for the first
two items that you mentioned
that are not overlapping but rather try
to
extend the abstract definition that we
have for ietf network applies in the 5g
so northbound included definition on
that
and for the last item as i mentioned if
there is synergy we can combine
so i know that we don't have time to go
through more detail but
if there are other comments please uh
put it in the main links and we can
cover accordingly
okay thank you thank you um lewis
can you hear me there we go
perfect okay um hello one if you can
keep it to five minutes that would be
great close
so next slide please
okay so the the motivation of this work
of this document is
basically um to consider the
or i'm not sure if this is proper sorry
this is for the use cases right not for
the uh
okay
look can you shift to the other
presentation or if you can do it in a
different order
the detail was wrong i think but i think
this is the proper presentation so
this is one the one about use cases yeah
so the um
yeah essentially here is that
we we don't have yet a clear view of
what could be the potential use cases in
that the consuming let's say the itf
network slices so
the indication of this document was
essentially go through the different
potential use cases and start and
try to get from them different
attributes
different procedures in order to
understand what could be the behavior of
the
and expected the behavior of the no
bound interface
so next slide
so we will go quickly through the
different use cases already identified
in this document the first one will be
about 5g services is
related with what the result was
presented before
so the objective will be essentially to
support and to end network slices as
defined for 5g systems
essentially in 3gpp and
regarding any node interface attributes
we could consider as
low such downlink uplink throughput or
slice qos parameters for instance
and plus a additional characteristics
such a
group communication support support of
non-ip traffic
etc regarding procedures we could
consider here where the procedure is
defined in 3dbp for a slice flight cycle
for instance inside instance allocation
slices as a location the allocation
modification status
et cetera et cetera the guardian
applicability of the
network slice in this context
essentially would be for the m3 and 9
and 6
interfaces in order to support the
different slice
types defined in 3dpp it has mobile
problem
ultra large variable low literacy and so
on so far
taking as references the dsma
is generic slice template and the 3gpp
spec on controlling management of slices
next slide please an additional use case
would be
the nsb based services so the yeti here
will be the support of connectivity
between virtual network functions that
are
instantiated in remote nfbi points of
presence
regarding any mbi attributes that could
be identified would be
slos such incoming and going bank with
qos metric etc
and additional characteristics such as
directionality
sorry directionality protection scheme
and so on so far
regarding mbi procedures will be all
related to lifecycle capacity fault and
perform
performance management of these
multi-site connectivity services as
defined by
hcnb the applicability clearly will be
the
the communication between these remote
and api pops
in order to support the different slos
that could be requested by
this connectivity the reference here are
the a couple of
specs from hcnb the iphone 32 and the
soul 17
which specify the the respective
behavior for these
communications next slide please
the last documented use case would be
the one of run sharing here the
objective would be the provision and
connectivity between cell sites
and interconnection points between
operators for um
essentially for delivering the traffic
from the this share
uh radio sales sites regarding
mbi attributes that could be expected to
be for sure as a low such a maximum and
guaranteed rate bounded latency packet
loss rate etc
and additional characteristics such as
secure connection ip addressing and so
respect to the mpi procedures that could
be expected for the use case with the
provision of connectivity services
collection of performance and fault data
etc
applicability of the itf network lies in
this context would be the multi-tenancy
of mobile
front-hall mid-hall and backhaul and the
reference is this is not
not normative but is the descriptive is
the metric internet form what paper and
from whole background shedding
next slide please
so this is the final one the next steps
would be to complete the draft with new
use cases we have
in mind to describe evolution of
wholesale services and cloud
computing-based services
regarding the document after that the
idea would be to elicit common slos
attributes and procedures for all the
cases in such a way that we could
document in an additional
chapter within the draft and
with respect to the group so the idea
here would be the other presentation to
collect feedback and comments from the
working group
to check if this work could be a
progress
as part of the work in the neighborhood
licensing design team
and for sure to prepare a new version
for for next meeting
and this is all from my side
okay any comments
we don't we don't have anybody on the
queue so
yeah you can go to your next
presentation okay thank you
so this presentation is about
the idea of how is the structure in the
itf network slice controller
and also how to to place the different
models uh
regarding to this structure so next
slide please
so regarding the problem to to be
addressed uh
that the impacts on how they destruct
the potential structure in terms of
components of the neglect less
controller
is to understand that there will be two
essential procedures to be performed by
the
uh networks less controller essentially
the mapping of the
itf negotiator requests as coming from
the from the customer
and then the realization of those those
slices
regarding the data models we could
consider two different views the
customer view which is a
focus on the individual itf network
slice request the customer
and the provider view that essentially
consider all the devices being
provisioned being realized in the
network so
these two different views are
complementary and necessary for
making it work so the goal of the
document is essentially to
identify the major networks like
controller components and how the
associated data models apply to
to these components or to the interface
interfaces between components
next slide please
so uh zooming in into the
a high level structure of uh that is
reflected in the neighborhood slice
definition document
we could take this itf network slice
controller entity
and trying to to say
divide in in some your components sorry
so regarding the structure we identified
these two major components the mapper
that would be the
the component um in charge of processing
the customer request
and putting it in into the constant
context of the overall itf network
slices in the network
and the realizer that would be
essentially the one that processed the
complete view of all the slices and
decides the proper technologies for
realizing the itm network slides
below in the itf technologies used for
that
and regarding the models you can see in
the in the picture in the middle three
different
interfaces that are labeled as a b and c
so um the first try of
mapping the models to the these
interfaces we
understand we would see that the
customer view is covered by the
w the t's itf network slice and bijan
model
the the interface label as b will be the
provider review that
could be accomplished by the leo this
transport network slice junk model
and the models in c would be essentially
the ones that
are used for going against
all the enabled controllers below and
would be out of the scope of this
document
next slide please so the next
step would be to solve some open points
that our signal has to do
items in the into the document uh we
have identified two so far so
one would be the breakdown of ns mapper
and ns realizer as
these major components that we do for c
the second one to this
would be to discuss the complementarity
of the formation models
for satisfying type one and type two
services as per act
rfc so the point here is that we need to
discuss uh to understand
the model label as b
could also accomplish on customer
request as customer slice request
then to collect feedback and comments
from the working group for sure to
propose a draft as a grid
sorry as a great outcome of the ts
uh neighbors like design team uh
by the way the all the co-authors of
this document are co-authors of the two
proposed models so there is
a concept on that and then to prepare a
new version for next meeting
and that's all from my side we have
adrian in the queue uh adrian yeah
thanks uh thanks luis
for this document i think it's useful to
pull
um things together the way you've done
uh can i ask you beg you to go and look
at
rsc 8309 which is the
ops area working group um
view um of how
young models are composed to provide a
top to bottom uh delivery of a
service and maybe map to that or use
some of that terminology
to be consistent uh with what the ietf
has already done
for sure i i we will proceed on that way
thank you
thanks i'll drop that to the list thank
you
okay uh boris can you keep it short
yeah okay so i will try lewis very short
question
could you mention what network
controller could be
optional because in some cases network
nsc
will be more than enough uh to provision
it so
network controller could be like
optional in
in several cases in my opinion
so uh do you refer to the the ones at
the bottom
right totally the bottom we are selling
two years
the high-level architecture that was in
definitions
maybe this is something that we could
also address so maybe we can add a
discussion topic i think
okay thank you thank you okay bo
you're up next yeah okay okay can you
hear me
yeah uh i'm here to present uh
for the iep network slice
uh northbound interface yeah model
uh next slide please
uh luis just mentioned that
uh there could be multiple
net itf network slice related model
uh to be like implemented in
in four different uh for different
networks like controller and this draft
is the goal of this draft is to define
a northbound interface young model and
since the
the terminology has been changed for the
for for the network slides so this draft
has been changed
so you can notice the name has changed
uh because uh
we have been this proposed for
discussion in
in the working group and also a network
slice design team for several times
so and this young model is quite
consistent
with the ietf network slice definition
drop
so this is the reason why we changed the
name
and and we also uh
received some comment about uh how
our uh how this mbi model to work with
the relationship with other
young model so here's we give the
uh some explanation about things
itf has a classified ser
young modules into different categories
and
like there could be service model and
network model
and also the device model so the mbi
the this ietf network slice and bi model
falls into the category of service model
uh also lewis mentioned this is from the
consumer view
and this model maybe will work together
with other
layers model to integ to be integrated
together to fulfillment uh the ietf
network slice
service and network management
coordination
so next slide please
uh chair
yes okay
based on the the discussion of ietf
network slice definition
mbi young model should fill the
the requirements that this model should
work not only for the configuration but
also for the monetary so
when modeling this model we think uh
uh the young model should fail uh these
requirements and uh
this young model like uh borrow uh
the definition from itf network slice
definition draft
uh like the ietf uh
the left-hand side is the view from the
slice definition draft it's a view from
a much higher level and there could be
a one itf network slice
they will be related
to different nse that's natural slice
endpoints
so in our modeling we also
use this terminology
and we expand to two more details
so i just gave some uh
high level design uh consideration about
uh the network slice connection group
because uh some of our authors think
there could be
use cases that in one ietf network
slides could be
multiple different uh slo requirements
for different
network slice members members means that
a
a pair of network slice endpoints
connections so
we created this new uh concept in in the
modeling
and also we think we need to create
a network slice member
concept to to for the for the monetary
uh modeling so here
that's a the modeling thinking
and can we skip to the next steps i'm
sorry we're really tired yeah yes
yeah yeah okay uh then we finished this
part
and uh our consideration
is we would like to uh seek more
comments from the working group and and
more input
for the designing uh modeling designing
so
that's all for these slides thank you
thank you
run
you're you're muted
run good
there is a unmute button at the top
the mic symbol
and can you hear us
uh ran if you would mind just typing in
jabber when you think you have it
working
and we will go to tariq and tariq just
because of the time if you can do
your first one in five minutes
can you hear me yes yeah yep great
thank you uh hi and my name is tariq
i'm one of the authors and the topic is
uh
realizing network slices slices in ipm
plus networks
uh next slide please
next slide
can you hear me oh okay
so a quick overview of the agenda uh
i'll cruise over the introduction with
whatever time i can
crunch in uh i want to talk about the
slice per hop definition
and how it facilitates the creation of
the slice
and um see if i can
go over the multiple approaches to
network slicing
that we have in the draft and then that
close off with the next steps
next slide please
so the solution we adopt is uh based on
the diffserv principles for network
slicing
the network resources the shared network
resources
and to ensure the proper placement of
the of the path
and getting the traffic treatment for uh
for sliced traffic uh when it's
traversing the
shared network resources um
the solution we're proposing is agnostic
to the path control technique
used to set up the path in the slice
domain
be it sr rsvp or others
it it it takes into account that
slices will have to be created
dynamically
and changed managed dynamically
and on demand and
yeah we we we have consideration for uh
different types of traffic
carried over the same slice and for that
we rely on the
diffserv class selector field in the
different data plane
technologies next slide please
so there are three approaches to the
solution that
to realize network slicing one is
a control clean only uh slicing of the
network resources the second is a data
plane only slicing of the network
resources
and the third is the combination of
control plane and data plane slicing of
the resources
um in in in our solution we
as i mentioned we we introduced this
slice per hop definition this definition
encompasses a data plane size selector
a uh a set of parameters for the
data plane resources uh a qs profile
the perhaps behaviors of
related to the slice as well it
encompasses a set of control cleaning
resources associated with the slice
with respect to reservable bandwidth
priorities
of reservation and the control plane and
any
shared resource groups that
you know this slice is willing to share
resources with
and the last piece of information that
the slice per hub definition
will contain is a reference to a
topology that
defines the links and nodes that this
slice
that belongs to this slice there are
multiple ways that to disseminate this
slice per hop definition that we looked
into one of them is
is a suitable netcom for grpc
interface once we have laid down the
the data model the other approach is
disseminating this or exchanging this in
a routing protocol
like igp or bgp and the last uh
is the manual configuration of the of
the definition
next slide please
we are on slide four
i'm sorry i can't hear you uh can you
wrap up
so we have some time for indeed
okay all right so the the hub definition
i mentioned that contains the slice
data plane slice selector it's it's a
field that is carried in the packets
there are multiple variations for this
uh i'll leave you to
go over the multiple options and where
uh one
is more suitable for different uh use
cases or deployments
we mentioned that there is a qs profile
associated with a slice can we
move on to the next slide please
and as well the control plane resource
management
the different parameters associated with
it
lastly the topology uh that defines the
links and nodes
associated with the slice so these are
the
pieces there are three slides and
subsequent slides here that define
different approaches to network slicing
the first one is
the data plane only slicing um
in in that one there's no network state
maintained in the control plane
the second one is the control plane only
slicing
of the network resources and in here we
have
the resources in the control thing being
sliced
without consideration um or without the
data plane being uh
knowledgeable about slices uh and the
last one
um the last one is the combination of
the two of the
of the previous two we think that the
last one will give us the
strict guarantees that we're looking for
uh at least we're trying to standardize
in ietf um unfortunately i don't i
didn't i don't have much time but okay
so for
in terms of next steps we are going to
coordinate with a number of drafts that
are already
out there with respect to prodigal
extensions
for slice aware traffic engineering
we do request the working group to
review the document
and give us feedback and we appreciate
that
um i don't know how much time do i have
i have another set of slides that
describe the
slideshow
are you available uh you were going to
try a different account
ran are you out there hi
hello yes i'm sorry yes hi
five minutes please
amazon from zte okay i will quickly
i will do the prioritizing with the
packing network selecting using segments
next place
yeah a unified administrative instance
identifier ai is used to distinguish
different virtual network resources for
both interdomain and into domain network
slices
scenario now let's look at the ai from
the following six items
the first is identifier of the dedicated
virtual network for the slides
the second is it supports end-to-end
slicing
and the third is advised unified lsi
across
multi-domain of transport network the
forces area is one of the constant
criteria of the color template and the
color template
template with ai provides a more
flexible
control the fifth is the uniform
color template for all overlaid uh
service mapping
to analyze results the sixth is uh its
ai meets the link
uh required requirements from 3gpp
it is independent of the exerting
uh domain partitions of the network
and it is also the independent of the
exiting and the lay frame and all
voting technologies there is no
modification
to the forwarding tables except close uh
policy process next please
there there is an example of our
solutions in fact there are two tablets
uh red and blue the red bullets include
node h one two three four e
and link between one one two one three
one four three four and the fourier the
blue topology include node eight one two
three four e
and link between x three three four
three one one two
uh three two four two and two e let's
see the
process of creating the uh slice
the first select the ai to the slice and
the second
allocates resources to the ai the third
is ai information is advertised
uh draw control place the control at the
controller connect
the resource information with ai through
bdpr is
then the controller can build the
corresponding
and they can calculate different paths
according to the color with ai
information in its
virtual network next place
next next please
yes uh here as a set of tn's last
resources identifiers
our solutions to both soft and hard
isolations
for l3 interface less obsolescence
in igp domain is numbered or unnumbered
l3
link could be configured with ai
information
under synchronized among idp numbers
the idp link state page database will
contain out three links with ai
information to support a t-pass
computations
uh ticker account take account of ai
criterias
each out three link could be configured
to belong to a single ai
or multiple ais for l2 interface slice
isolation
each l2 member link of our three
parent links destined to be config to
belong to
a single ai at different l2 members link
will have different
single ai configuration with different
agency sets
how to number could be any type
interface
such as internet we like interface
flexi channels t-pass computations based
on link state
database okay need
sorry next next place next slide
yes this is a multiple domain deployment
it is easy to provide into in
which network including the inter domain
is some deployment
adopt pplu for setup set up the bdpr usp
and only service will directly over the
bpr usp if the only service have the
requirement
of the te which defined as the color
the bdplu will also support the color
the pplu labels will
allocated pro color the below is option
b
in the domain it can also provide
end-to-end
visual network including the inter
domain link
the intro domain link can also choose
the link based on the color with ai
next place uh
it's the an end-to-end srt with sdn the
pdprs will
be used to inform the topology
information's contained
the ai to the control controller the
controller can calculate the sr path
based on the information for the enter
domain link
btpis can advertise the direct protocol
type or firstly put in the domain
interconnections to idp instance
then always important import the data
date
from idp protocol source next please
yes this is combined with sr flex
algorithm
uh there are two scenarios
for inter-domain case sdn controller
concrete we n for air
is ais based on ai and
we aim for fa ais based on
respectively sdn controller computers
end to end segment relates to its
contains multiple es and based on
different topologies
however for distinguished uh
model mode and border
border node iai with
indulgence igp magic
yes next please
[Music]
yes this draft also will resist
retest some standard ar values to
represent different types of ai like
normal urlc and
t next please
and for the indulgence of us
let's type e-m-b-b i'm iot we 2x will be
uh to be defined and will be defined in
future
yes next please comments welcome
thanks
okay
loose uh yeah can you uh introduce your
draft in a minute or two and
yes can you go directly to slice three i
i will do
on top of that slide number here
scenario so yeah um basically in the
in this route what we are trying to
address is the situation that uh now
operators are
starting to deploy computing facilities
there is a wide deployment of
different sizes a different number of
resources so the idea would be to to
have
a joint topological view of both the
working and computing resources
such a way that we could take better
decisions
immediate decisions taking into account
also the
the compute domain not only the network
domain but the compute domain
so somehow this is similar approach that
as the one following the
drive uh itfts service on our topology
model
so it is even is a an original piece of
work of that draft that
has taken its proper life
so in the pictures scenario essentially
you can see
there are the different data center pops
with different
resources and the idea would be to
incorporate the description of those
resources into
into a model augmenting the the te model
uh these resources could be raw
resources cpu memory storage
or being described in terms of quotas or
or bundles
uh and we drop either an example like in
the cmtt
so essentially what we expect is to
adapt the model to different ways of
exposing data center capabilities
working on the young modules combining
such model and
i'm for sure to receive any feedback or
comment that could come from the working
group
on this and that's all from my side
thanks lewis
thank you very much for do the quick
summary
um apologize about the interruption in
the middle which
squeezed that already tight meeting uh
closer
please stay tuned to the list
participate in the list discussion
and look uh there's we have uh look for
uh both the formal and informal meetings
that happen regularly we remind everyone
that the informal meetings are open to
all
uh and your contribution is most welcome
thank you all so much in participating
in this active
meeting and we look forward to um
resolving some of the open discussions
and moving forward with
uh adoption with uh
the design team uh documents once we
seem to have
some better agreement on the terminology
uh again thank you all
and really appreciate the contribution
and hard work
thanks everyone yeah we'll see you soon
okay
uh