for those of you who are following this
remotely which is
everybody and the chairs are just
gathering people and
we'll soon be starting the tsvwg meeting
this will be the second of the two
meetings so the
agenda's the second set of
information in the
in the documents area
sure
[Music]
okay can i compare with people whether
we have a note taker
and somebody's watching chap
do we have a note taker
do we have a volunteer for a note ticker
jake is in the queue that might be a
volunteer
you're i was raising my hand to
volunteer i i can do it
um i'd be happy to have assistance i see
andrew offering in the chat
uh so yeah please uh
great and thanks brian also i just
pasted
the agenda into the notepad
so for those that you are following the
notepad can you
make can you look to the end of the
notepad because the
the session are going to be taken after
the
current items um
okay they're now being entered so that's
great so we have a note taker and a few
backups that's great
clarification there uh the the link that
i saw
uh on uh
on the note taking tool from inside the
meat echo here
is pointing me to something that uh that
is new for this session
uh right so that's notes ietf 109 tsv2
uh which i'll put the link here just to
clarify in the chat
and uh um so it's interesting
because i think i i won't follow off the
agenda page
if i want to get the wrong one no
my mistake perhaps okay i think that
there's opportunity to get this wrong in
the in the agenda so i might get it
wrong
as well right so there there are
separate um strings for the meet echo
uh session because it's like two
sessions is two sessions but the agenda
page actually links back to the same
for the two sessions things that's
actually probably something we should
talk to me to
echo about for the second time but let's
use the link that i posted
so they're all in the same place just to
keep keep you all from having to merge
things
okay i will do that uh
thank you just to like put a link to the
second one and the one you're not using
so people can fall back to it
if they get the wrong one i will do that
um
oh very helpful
okay bob i've just uploaded your slides
so i think we have all the meeting
materials posted now
where where are the notes for the first
meeting
so i can just quickly look at them
they're on the same page
as we're taking the notes and second
being to scroll upward
no they're not they there's nothing in
the current
meeting page in the proceedings
um follow the following
brian pasted
it's all there
it's like
okay
yes
[Music]
all right should we get started here
i think we can get started
yeah so i think we uh i've already spent
time wrestling with uh tools here so
i think we probably should just jump
into the agenda so i think uh
today we have uh greg on the operational
guidance then bob
on the uh other l4s drafts
and if there's any time left there's
some
l4s and 5g work that uh
ingomar will discuss so
if there's nothing else or any agenda
bashing people want to do
i think we'll go straight to greg
it looks good to me i have bob's side so
i'll put those in the notes as well
okay are you able to hear me
test one two test one two
yes yeah all right thank you i'm trying
to pull your
charts up
okay so this first topic is to discuss
this work in progress draft
title operational guidance for
deployment of l4s in the internet
this is an individual draft that
i agreed to put together as
an editor and
in collaboration with several others
from the working group
folding in suggestions that had been
made via email
on the mailing list over the past
several months
um let me go on the next line
so although the title of the draft may
make it sound like it's covering more
territory than it is
i want to make clear here that the scope
actually the draft is specific to
a single issue and that is the issue of
single queue rfc 3168 bottleneck links
and some issues that need to be dealt
with
in that case and in particular it
provides guidance for
operators of hosts that would like to
utilize l4s and guidance to
operators and networks in particular
networks that have
deployed single queue rfc 3160
bottleneck links
and then recommendations to researchers
as well and how to
um or things that they could look at
and try to try to understand the scope
of the issue and any
any severity metrics that could be
derived from that
so all the general requirements for
l4s definition of the l4s experiment
itself
and other operational guidance for l4s
hosts
and networks can all be found in the l4s
drafts
themselves so the architecture draft
dual queue coupled aqm draft
and the ecnl for sid craft
there's a comment recently on the
mailing list from jake and
pete heist that perhaps this
draft should also um mention
uh fq uh bottleneck links that implement
rfc3168
um i think the next slide talks a little
bit about welcome back that gets to that
point on the next slide
move on so just to summarize
um situations where
coexistence of l4s and classic crappit
have been
discussed in the mailing list
we group the different network
bottleneck types in these six
categories based on the active q
management
technology that exists in the bottleneck
and the scheduler
that exists at that bottleneck so the
aqm could be an l4s
ecm
[Music]
aqm it could be a classic ecn aqm
could be just an aqm that does packet
drop so no no ecn at all
or could even be no aqm at all and just
tail drop and the scheduling could be
dual queue or fq or a single queue fifo
in all these cases um l4s traffic and
classic traffic coexist
uh well um except for
the one um in red where there's
a problem that's been identified where
classic flows
uh will receive less throughput than l4s
flows
when they are coexisting in a bottleneck
that is a single queue and
classification
and just the focus of the draft there is
an asterisk on the
fq classic ecn case getting back to
jake and pete's comment that there are
scenarios in an fq
classic ecm bottleneck where we don't
see
fairness being enforced by fq
one of those is a case where you've got
mixed traffic in tunnels
that are going through the fq fq is
known to
not provide fairness for the flows that
are inside tunnels
and um in this case if you have a
tunnel that has a mix of classic and l4s
traffic
there's a further unfairness between the
flows
that are within the tunnel also there's
a potential
in some fq implementations for hash
collisions to result in
multiple flows sharing a single queue
and so in those
relatively rare cases where you'd have
multiple long-running flows that are
hashed into the same queue and those
multiple long running flows are
mixed well for us in classic then you
can see some unfairness there as well
i think most of the bottleneck links
that
implement fq today run a more
advanced version of fq that eliminates a
lot of
that issue around hash collisions
okay next slide
we have a comment from sebastian
um something
can i do you hear me yes please go ahead
okay so um this looks fine and very
systematic
except that the first draw in this table
is pretty much under discussion
so it says duracu coupled akm provides
reasonable fairness across a range of
conditions which
is true i admit that the problem is
whether the
range of tested conditions actually is
sufficiently broad
to allow extrapolation onto the wider
internet
and i do not believe that this is
currently true that's just
the point i wanted to make
okay thanks
um so a little bit more detail on
um on this specific issue of um
the classic ecm bottleneck um
so rfc 3168 is the definition of classic
ecn
where an aqm ce marks are applied to ect
0 and ect1 packets instead of
drop and l4s which uses ect1
responds differently to those ce marks
compared to classic
senders which use ect 0.
[Music]
and specifically the l4s flows
effectively aim for a higher ce marking
rate than classic flows do
and so when you've got a mix of the two
flow types
sharing a single queue rfc 3168
bottleneck
the l4s flows will outperform the
classic flows
and so this really um affects uh
when you have multiple long-running
capacity seeking flows
um where this phenomenon occurs
um appears to be worse in situations
with moderate
bdp um levels so
on the order of 100 150 packets give or
take seems to be
where the problem is most pronounced um
so less
less so in low bdp connections
uh or in high bdp connections um
so low data rate um connections not as
big of an issue
and appears that potentially it's
for the high bdp bdp case um
uh potentially when cubic is operating
in its cubic mode
um maybe that's the the reason why it's
less impacted to hide bdb okay
but um in the cases where um
the impact is at its worst um it's been
shown
to to result in more than ten to one
uh flow rate ratio and there's an
example
um of some of the data that's been shown
on that there's
a number of experiments have been done
over the past uh year or more
um on that but um you can see figure one
in the in that link
uh for an example okay next
apply i see
you i don't know if there's something
more you want to share if you're still
in there from the last
chart
okay
next slide yeah so the the draft has um
again these sections on
uh guidance for the different um
[Music]
different audiences the operator from
l4s host
breaks down the host into two categories
um so one that would be deployed
in a constrained whether there's a
constrained set of networks or clients
that it's serving
where there are opportunities for
coordination
um and um and pre-launch testing
um across that constrained set of
networks of clients
um uh and so the graph talks about
what some of those options are um and
you know as as i mentioned this is a
work in progress draft
so there are some to do's left um in
this section
um so we would invite input
from the working group on
more details that can be added in in
these sections
as well as others um
so in particular um one thing that seems
to be
uh potentially useful in
in the case of the cdn or isp servers
is to do some pre-launch testing
to assess the presence or absence of
these bottlenecks
and there be nice to have some specific
tests uh coupled out or specific
requirements around
those tests um in the draft to give
guidance for
those who might be interested in
deploying hosts um
the second kind of sub bullet under
section 3.1
is in-band detection monitoring so the
l4s id draft has some
mandatory features that hosts need to
support to facilitate this uh
to attempt to detect uh rfc 3168
in in the bottleneck
and then the server could fall back in
real time
so when it detects the potential
presence of rc3168
it immediately
[Music]
discontinues the l4s congestion response
and
utilizes the classic congestion response
an alternative would be to flag
that path of that host
client as being potentially
behind a 3168 bottleneck and then
discontinue using l4s
for future connections to that host
and the second subsection in section
three is other hosts that are
serving a much wider uh set of networks
or clients
where that pre-launch testing may be
not feasible still the in-band
methods apply
[Music]
in either a real-time or non-real-time
response for those
real time might be a little bit more
feasible there
also could be some per destination path
testing
that could take place in addition to the
in-band detection monitoring
and draft has a placeholder for specific
tests there again
feedback or input would be helpful to
flesh out
that as well as the other components of
this section
yeah greg um where do you expect
the code that implements those
tests to reside is that residing in
the protocol being used
by the servers involved
or and other hosts or do you and or do
you expect
uh set um uh separate uh
test functionality um
well i think it it depends um so the
um pre-launch testing seems to me to be
separate testing code that would be
provided on a l4s host
that could be used to detect whether
rc3168 exists or not
certainly the in-band detection
monitoring
is utilizing features that are
already required in l4s hosts by the l4s
id
draft the response mechanism whether
it's
a fallback a real-time response
certainly would have to be a feature
supported by
the uh um by the l4s implementation
in the sender non-real-time response
would presumably be somewhat different
code but uh
um more operational management code that
could uh
control whether or not l4s is enabled on
a per
host basis uh so i think it's a mix um
but the draft certainly um adds some
some detail on that okay just please
please make sure that that answer is
reflected in the draft okay
so there's someone in the andrews in the
queue
so i was wondering as a follow-up to
um david's question on what kind of
granularity you expect
this to be done as in per
what destination prefix per host or
or what
um that's a good question um
so it probably depends a bit on the
network so one scenario that
has been highlighted
on the mailing list is a
residential isp where
the individual customer so a single ip
address
may have an implementation of
a single qr 6138 bottleneck
in their network and so
results of this testing could be
different on an ip address by
ip address basis
[Music]
that may not be true in all scenarios
but certainly could be that granularity
okay um the other comments
that
all right uh next slide then um the next
section the draft talks about
recommendations for an operator who has
deployed single queue rfc 3168
bottlenecks
um it provides currently a
a list of potential options um
for configuring uh that bottleneck
to or those bottlenecks to work better
with l4s traffic
and i won't go through all these in
detail on the call but the first one
there's a question on the mailing list
whether
routers are able to uh to actually
support that
um i think certainly it's um well known
that
uh software routers can can do that but
uh the question would be um in
hardware routers or other restrictions
that would
prevent the differential treatment
between
ect 0 and ect1 so that in that case here
it's
effectively treating ec2-1 as not ect
and
and only doing congestion experience
marking on ect 0 packets
for all of these i think that's an open
question to network gear vendors
operators as to
[Music]
how feasible are all of these are there
any
downsides to any any one of these uh
are there other options that have not
been identified so far that could be
added to this section
um and further um the details i guess on
on configuration of of these different
approaches would be helpful
okay um
corey
okay i just wondered if anybody who was
joining the meeting had um any eyes
which might help us from the
understanding of particular operated
routers that they're using or maybe
they're a vendor
does anybody come from the vendor
community who wants to kind of
comment quickly on that list that we
just had
um routers exist that can
do 4.1 treat um
ect1 as not ect jonathan pointed out in
the chat that it's um
formally contrary to rfc 3168 um
i don't think the feature is
particularly common
or the ability is particularly common
but it does exist in some routers
thank you that was andrew mcgregor yeah
what yes
well anybody else from the operating
community
can i just pick up andrew's point about
formally being countries to 3168 i don't
i don't think it is because it's not
saying um you don't change east tijuana
or tct you just um
treat it as not ect so you're you're
effectively being
a non-ecn router for the ect1 code point
bob while you're on the line um wasn't
um there's something in pcn
anyway so we we have that specs that
have chip played with ect one in the
ietf
in a different context that is true yeah
and and on the standard track effect oh
yeah i shouldn't say playing yeah a
standard striker
okay i wasn't mean to hold up the talk i
was just hoping to start this discussion
with people who
had inside knowledge about what products
might actually
i'll offer i'll leave um
i think it's also been suggested that um
you know the
working group could consider um formally
deprecating
um treating ect1 identically to ect 0
i think as a good point out it's not
required to be treated the same but
it could be formally deprecated and that
might
nudge things along towards implementing
borderline
okay next slide nope couple of uh
people in the queue um bob
oh sorry i'm not in the key okay jake
let's say i thought 8311 did that
um and placed some requirements on it
is that not correct
uh that has deprecated the treatment of
these t1 as
uh necessary and easy to zero i thought
that's already like
released as standard strike
um is it opens the door
to alternative treatments um as long as
they are
uh documented in an experimental rfc
um but doesn't um
oh i see this thing you're saying
reading them out you're saying
this is this is subtly different i think
goes back to 3168 which in particular
uh 3168 um allows
uh allows drop of uh
ect marked uh to mark mark traffic and
uh uh end points uh that that
uh apply to 3168 have to be prepared to
deal with drops because some
somebody got backed up and uh couldn't
mark had to drop
and so if you configure this you're
still compatible with 3168 as far as i
can tell
all right um you know i'm short on time
here um so
section five in the draft rule for
researchers um
pretty lightweight um uh text in this
section so far so certainly would
appreciate input from researchers on
um things we could add
[Music]
point out as well that um it would be
nice to have some specific
test requirements uh in this section and
not just
the fairly high level statements here
but we do have at least the high level
statements of
a couple of of items that researchers
could look at
obviously detecting 3168 through
measurement campaigns would be
an interesting step there's been some
attempt at that
in the past um but more useful
um also um uh out-of-band measurement
of l4s versus classic performance might
be
um uh
um something that be done as well
and then um not in the graph yet but
something is pointed out
off list to me um uh
research looking at how often
do you have multiple long-running flows
coinciding within
a bottleneck link and how often does it
happen and
help i can assess the scope of the
issue looks like your mic
is still on bob i don't know if you're
aware of that
next slide so there's some additional
meaningless comments recently last few
days
um sebastian had a comment to uh
reword the phrase more precise flow
balance in reference to dual cue
jonathan morton pointed out that
if the working group had gone a
different path
then we wouldn't have to write this
draft and then jake had a couple of
other comments
around adding some references that
uh help illustrate the unfairness issue
and then raise the question
the draft is currently listed as an
informational draft
raise a question of whether that's the
appropriate categorization or should it
be
listed as experimental and so that can
open for discussion so next slide
so uh last slide um i think this is
uh time for the work group working group
to consider whether this is
something we adopt um and i think
you know as i said i've been the editor
and folding in comments from
and text provided from others there have
been several who have contributed texts
but
i would hope that with adoption we'll
bring the commitment from
the working group to uh to flesh this
out and
provide a full list of what we're aware
of in terms of
uh guidance for for making l4s
work well with the presence of 3168
bottlenecks
so
i'll hand it back to the chairs
yeah i think uh starting an adoption
call on the mailing list is probably a
good idea but i think we'd like to
open the floor to hear some other
people's thoughts but i think
because this is something that came
about as a mitigation to
some of the comments and concerns people
had
when we decided to make the ect one
decision at the interim meeting
i think this is probably a good thing to
adopt myself i think jonathan's in the
queue so please go ahead jonathan
so i'd just like to clarify
a very brief summary of what this draft
is
trying to do
which is basically ensure that any
network that carries l4s
traffic is specially prepared for it
and the delphos traffic does not escape
such a network
is that correct
um i i think that's overstating it um
as i indicate in the first few slides
there are um they're known to exist
these 3168 single cube bottleneck um
implementations what's not known is
the prevalence of them um believed to be
rare um at least
you know studies so far have not shown
them to be widely
deployed in bottleneck locations
and again as as i discussed earlier
the impact of them existing
um it is not catastrophic it's not a
um not a major issue in a lot of cases
but
uh it's only in the case of long-running
flows
uh sharing those bottlenecks with a
moderate bdp
levels where um result is
something that we want to track and
and avoid it so i wouldn't say it has
anything to do with
um um uh
making networks in general prepared for
l4s it's really just this specific
scenario
so when it comes to these long-running
flows sharing a single queue
uh does that take into account the
possibility of
tunnels encountering um
an aqm even if that aqm
it will treat the tunnel as a single a
single flow
put it into a single cube apply a single
aqm instance to it
yeah as as i mentioned earlier um
that you know the asterisk on the
regular slide um
so so flow queue flow queueing
bottlenecks group tunnel traffic into a
single
queue and so they don't provide fairness
for tunnel traffic or flows are within a
tunnel
yeah that's a known issue with uh with
fq
systems and on top of that
if the mix of flows within that tunnel
contains both l4s and classic uh
then the entire tunnel is clearly only
seeing a
single uh ce marking
[Music]
well at least existing at q
implementations that total traffic would
see a single
um ce marking probability
and you see further unfairness within uh
flows inside the tunnel
that's true um it's been um
discussed that it's fairly uh
straightforward for
fq uh implementations to support
uh the all4s um
marking thresholds so it's not a problem
with fq in general
but but yes in the case of tunnel
traffic over an fq
uh uh bottleneck
then there is a second half in there as
uh as quickly as we can
yeah i just like to mention that in risk
analysis we need to need
to consider both the prevalence and the
severity
so we should also have a discussion
about the severity at some point
yeah i touched on that in the earlier
slides but
certainly something to be studied
further thanks
stuart
hi yeah i just wanted to comment on the
previous point
as i think many people know we enabled
ecn in apple clients
several years back so they would
negotiate end-to-end ecn
with the majority of linux servers out
there
i wish we had the problem today of
deployed legacy ecn routers that were
doing
smart queuing instead of tail drop
the sad reality is that from the data
we've collected from a billion iphones
around the world
the prevalence of ecn marking routers is
zero percent too many decimal places so
it would be nice if we had that legacy
problem to deal with
but the fact is we don't
you know thank you stuart that's uh
that's
definitely good feedback um help
understand the
scope of this uh issue and or maybe lack
thereof
all right uh jenna
hi um i love stuart i love the
zero percent to many decimal places by
the way i'd love to know
uh yeah the the thing i wanted to say
about this draft is that i think it's
the general uh it makes a lot of sense
to have an operational guidance
draft in the working group for for
for this i think the the questions that
are being
raised and addressed in this draft are
very useful
uh and i i think this ought to be
adopted
um i've taken a look at the draft i'll
admit to not having read it carefully
um it seems very thin but i suspect that
can be resolved
as we get into the as it gets into the
working room i would definitely
encourage adoption of this
uh the one thing i would i would also
suggest is maybe to articulate a little
bit more
of articulate the the
the the the goal
as not to promote fairness but to avoid
unfairness i think there is a difference
between the two
but again that isn't it i don't want to
spend too much time on it here
okay thank you good feedback
jake
yeah so i i did a presentation at
um uh map rg the
interim uh map rg
uh i think it was just after last ietf
and it was uh interim with
um with that at the conference right
yeah
and they uh
so we did not see uh
zero percent there were several networks
in which we saw
non-zero uh percentage deployment of ecn
uh when we looked according to asn so i
i would be very interested stuart if you
get a chance to
i don't know if you're planning on
publishing the data that you see
but um i
you know not only did we see non-zero
percent in a number of networks but we
saw a
growth in adoption over the last year um
so i just wanted to mention that i
although i agree the deployment is
relatively low when you look in the
aggregate
um it was uh it was only zero percent
down to
uh down to two decimal places for us
overall
um and i think we're we are getting
probably a different data set than the
then
you know what iphone would see in
general but um
uh we we did have some uh you know
zero percent to many decimal places was
not our observation so it might be good
to
sort of see if we can link those up a
little better
and maybe even get an ongoing
you know refresh of that perhaps
thanks i just wanted to point that out
in case
anybody hadn't seen it thank you
yeah thanks for that jake if you have
newer data
then then the data we collected a year
or two ago
that would be interesting the one
suggestion i would have is when we first
collected data
we were seeing uh some plausible amount
of ecn marking
in argentina notably and in france
and it led us to a false sense of
optimism at the start
and when we dug into a little bit deeper
it turned out to be
bogus it wasn't actual working
smart queuing with ecm uh
it was as far as we could tell it was
just bugs
so yeah if you have some actual working
ecm
that's that's very interesting because
thank you we we did note that when we
started our
project and we were looking for it also
and and uh did fail to replicate that i
think i reported that in the in the
presentation i did
um and uh but
nonetheless there were other networks
where they're there
and uh by country it was hard to find
anything with
uh that remotely approached some of the
numbers you reported in the initial
stuff and i understand that was
found to be bugs i think that's also
been reported and maybe mentioned during
that talk
uh but uh they're they're looking at
individual networks there are some that
do appear to be doing
uh real ecn traffic yeah
uh thanks
bob yeah i just um
just to make sure everyone's caught up
on this as well um you know
jake's data was important um but then
there's also the question of
was that single queue or fq um
because obviously in the last few years
um
fq coddle has been deployed with ecn
support and so
um i would have expected to see some of
that and i i'm assuming that's what jake
was finding but we
obviously now don't know without even
more difficult tests
to distinguish between um an fq
producing ce and a um single queue
because the fq
obviously does the scheduling itself and
isn't isn't going to allow
um this um domination of one flow by
another
okay thanks bob
i see no one else in the queue so i
because i hand it back to the chairs
yeah and i think uh this has been useful
discussion i think we're going to plan
to take
a adoption call to the mailing list
one quick reflective discussion for the
chat we're going to run in
we're going to run over one hour into
the break
uh sebastian suggested that we take no
more than 25 minutes to break which
seems like a reasonable suggestion
can i ask was that that we also check um
how many people have read the adoption
draft that this or the previous version
and therefore
get some view of um there are people
being exposed to this
sure do we know how to press these
buttons i don't
uh i think i just posted a question
operator guidance strap and we read it
that looks like a decent threshold of
people have read it
so click on the bar chart and um tick
raise your hand if you
have read it or do not raise your hand
if you have not read it
and we'll collect that as we go into the
next talk so that we can
run this adoption call later on the list
back to you and bob are you planning to
project your charts
um i'd would rather you do to be honest
but i well
i suppose i could whatever no you do it
okay is that okay it'll take a minute
okay
i only say that because i've not done it
before so it will take me a minute as
well to work out how to do it
i guess i could just start by saying
that um
the next door what the next talk is
going to be before we get the title side
it's um a status update on
um l4s and the the three
main alfres drafts other than the one
greg has just been talking about
um that's the architecture draft
the um alphas id
and the um dual queue couple day qm
right um that's fairly small on my
screen
um um i jump in just one second
yep while you're getting screen sorted
and i want to summarize the results of
the poll that we just ran
yeah there were 15 people said that
they'd read one of the operational
drafts
one of the two revisions and there were
19 people who
said that they hadn't presumably
intended to so a reasonable number of
people have read this
and that's useful input to our
processor's chairs
thanks ever so much that polls closed
back to you bob
okay yeah actually i um i don't know was
that
meant to be a precursor to a working
group working group adoption or
what's going to happen with that
yes that's a precursor to what adoption
will handle that in the list
okay good yeah right
okay so um there are the three drafts
with their
vision numbers and um next slide please
uh one slide recap of what l4s is and
why uh
how it's motivated it's motivated
as um a desire for
ultra low queueing delay for all
internet applications
um so so that um you don't have the
problem of
um the management problem of having some
favored over others
[Music]
and the key idea
is getting smaller saw teeth to respond
to congestion
so that you don't have the compromise
between low queueing delay
and poor utilization so you can keep
your
get your aqm right tight and you and you
also get them scalable throughput which
is the s
part of the l4s which um
otherwise um that has has been known
since
um early work in the 1990s which sally
floyd published as an rfc 3649 i think
um you you get longer and longer time
between each sawtooth as
as you try and get faster um and
um you get less tight control
next
i'll try and speed up the um
just just a bit of news on various
implementation things been going on
since the last time we gave a status
update which was
april i believe maybe july i can't
remember um
the uh low latency docsis
um working group has been continuing
doing interop testing
um currently three independent
implementations two cable modems one
cmts
and two implementations now completely
pass all the functional tests
there was a uh i know before i left
cleveland there was a
large set of um conformance tests
uh and functional tests that that were
defined against the spec
next one um this work hasn't started yet
but
the only new news is that it it's got a
date for when it's planned to start and
that's the
data plane development kit that's the
open source
libraries for um virtualization
um for a variety of cpu architectures
and
that's planned for dual queue coupled
aqm
implementation um in q1 next year
and then there's a lot of um
publications coming out of
ns3 sorry by publication i mean
published source
out of the ns3 efforts um
there's the simulation model of of low
latency docsis
itself which was used by um
the low latency docsis working group to
test everything
and that's in the ns3 app store and that
link
takes you to it off the slides
and it includes not only the dual queue
capital dqm but also low latency
doctor's cue protection
um which i think will be useful news to
some people who've been wanting a form
of q protection to test things against
and there's also a link to cable lab's
press release about that so you can
get a quick feel for what what's in that
that was released in september then
um it also um
tom henderson pointed out tom was
largely pulling all that
um stuff above together then he's also
pointed out that
alfred support has been added to um
coddle and
fq coddle models in ns3
and it's about to be released
it's been added and about to be released
in fq pi and fq cobalt
in their models in ns3 um
and it's already in the linux fq cuddle
um and that adds um
as as well that they add to the
the itf dual cue coupled acre meaning
the one that's in the itf draft the
sort of reference pseudocode um the
the code for that um is also
modeled in ns3 and has been for some
time
right um next
right um just want a quick heads up we
have a um
iccrg session on friday 500 utc
um 1400 in bangkok time
and um i think that's right
no no midday 1200 bangkok time
and um the
the i'll give a quick outline of what's
going to happen
um we have a congestion control that
gives really low latency
over a range of conditions um as in that
paper
you know reasonable um rtts and
um link rates
but you know pieces of it are still
missing you know that's
um absolutely obvious um so it's easy to
think up conditions where it doesn't
work well
and show that and we admit progress has
been slow
um covering up all those holes
and and fixing it all so
um you know as we've said many times
we being the um core team the design
team working on
um l4s we we're
primarily for network companies and and
being network operators or
vendors for for networks um
and you know we've got a bit of a
background in congestion control over
the years
but we're not the guys that will produce
this so you know we're having to do it
in
spare time because it's not funded by
our companies and so on
um so we want to generate interest
in the problem and the potential again
um and we thought if we explain the
interesting
things that we've done had to do in dc
tcp to get it um
to get it to meet all these prague
requirements and work over the internet
and talk about what we've learned um we
might
generate some interest and um get a bit
of a buzz around this
but at the end of the talk we want to
have start a conversation about
um what what is needed to get that buzz
going again because after the initial
buzz
we um imagined that
this was a good um
enough potential that people would want
to work on this
um we imagined a different way of
building congestion control if you like
whereas
mostly what a congestion control has
been given as a blob to the community by
researchers
and we were thinking it'd be great to
have something where
different components um
were were brought in by different
different groups
as more of open source project and that
didn't happen and that's probably our
fault nearly certainly our fault
as the core team just you know we didn't
um do it right
didn't make it open enough at the start
um but now with something worse has
happened we've sort of got a
toxic code point war that's um
you know it's it's good to have a red
team you know to be
um picking holes in in everything but
it's it's now getting to the point where
it's
i i think being a bit more destructive
in that it's you know there are problems
that
aren't really anything to do with l4s
congestion controls in particular that
you could you could pick up in
in other congestion controls that are
being pulled out for that and so
i think it overshadows the potential of
any
congestion control using high facility
fidelity signaling
where we're risking losing the losing
sight of the
potential of this so
we want a conversation about what a
relaunch would need to look like for you
to want to get involved and
you know we're looking for constructive
views but i'm not asking for that now
i'm just giving a heads up um
bob so yeah there's um
there was some confusion about the the
deadline for this meeting
and and that's not your fault however uh
i and many other people are not going to
be able to stretch this until
55 past um is there any way you can
bring forward like the key takeaways
and then for people who are interested
they'd be welcome to stick around for
okay your full presentation i'm i'm
sorry for that i know this is
unfortunate yeah it's actually the next
slide i think i i
i was going to say if if you want to
hear the whole talk in the next slide
then you can and go if you want um
so um
all three drafts that you know the rest
of the rest of the talk is about is
about the alfres drafts
because we've been putting a lot of work
into them to get them get them finished
and ready for
working group last call in our humble
opinion that stands for
um or it's an anagram of ohio
um and um
there the only bit left really is is
what the status of this alpha s ops
draft is it's an individual draft so we
didn't um refer to it yet so it
um we need to
put in a reference to that but otherwise
we're done and
and describe it a bit in the l4s id
but otherwise the three drafts there's
the offress architecture
had two revs since um the last
um status update and i guess the main
change i mean there's been some very
significant change in that um
and i will go through them but top level
really it's it's put fq up there
with dual queue as um sort of
alternatives in the architecture it's no
longer
the dual queue is no longer the
architecture it's um
fq as well and um
the other l4sid draft
there's been a lot of changes in that
one um
mainly uh you know i mean a lot of
um clarity changes but there's also been
a number of
um normative text changes
um based on conversations on the list um
where we've been tweaking the wording if
you like
and and some new stuff about smoothing
um smoothing signals um pacing
um to to make them um
requirements because that draft is
primarily a draft
about how to write a congestion control
draft or how to write a um
a draft about network equipment and it's
giving the requirements as to what has
to be in that draft so there's some
shits and musts on what on what has to
be in those things about pacing and
stuff
and um finally the dual queue coupled
aqm that's
very stable um wasn't i couldn't find
anything to change in that
um just some modern editorial stuff so
that's the top level for
martin if you want to go now um
well bob i think that might be a good
point just to pause for a moment to see
people have questions
because you'll have time to present the
rest
later but it'd be more important to take
questions if people have observations or
questions on this from the room
would anyone like to join our queue go
ahead
queue should i should i start
go okay thank you uh well at a high
level i
bob i i don't know that we need to go
over all the l4s drafts again
uh but i want to ask what is the intent
here ultimately are we
are we asking whether we should go to
last call are we are there any major
issues pending but the extent that i've
seen my understanding is that the
biggest issue
the biggest issue i've see i've seen and
and
forgive me if i've not seen all the
issues is the competition with classic
eqn at uh fifo queues
and uh is that the biggest issue that's
spending because i'd like to speak to
that if that is the biggest issue that's
pending
i guess god against that and and the
point i've just made about um
our congestion control is is not
up to speed with the with um the
aspirations in this draft but but one of
the questions at the end is
is the intent that that is part of the
experiment um rather than
right so so that's that's so so so
maybe i'll just take a minute to speak
to to to both of those points because i
think
my my point will ought to cover them
both
at a high level i feel i i'm i i feel
like this is ready for an experiment
uh i absolutely think that we should
outline
precisely what the outcomes of the
experiment ought to be
meaning that what are we measuring what
are we looking to see
um but uh era it absolutely seems like
we are ready to launch this experiment
um something that stewart said earlier
um
is is is very uh i think uh
uh it's an important point to note here
if if the concern about a competition
with classic issue
a classic ecn is a concern
uh i might argue that that only becomes
a real concern or a reality
if l4s becomes very successful
i would like that to happen i would like
for us to become successful and i would
like it to become a problem
for the non-existent classic ecn
so if the world we are talking about is
is potentially that we could we could
make this
uh get us out the door try and deploy
uh l4s then let's do it
i don't know that we need to wait for
much else at this point
so colin perkins in java says plus one
and
is there are there more comments apart
from jonas
i was going to add to john's comment
that i think john is going to suggest
that a path to
um successful working with glasgow on
the main lforest drafts
runs through uh solidification of the
lfrs operations traffic that
that's where the 3168 issue could sell
are you taking that as a um
are you taking that as a comment that
we're not ready
david
i i'm not sure i think as part of ruger
glass quality
group has to judge whether um there is
a reasonable approach to dealing with
yeah i can care with that and i think
that's that is i mean just
so to clarify for anybody who's watching
this
or listening remotely and the working
group last call doesn't confirm the
document the working group last call
gives people a last
call for comments on it where we have to
in detail
check that things are right and the
document could be frozen after that or
the document could be
published or the document could be could
we have certain pieces of work
identified that need to be done
so or indeed it could be dropped the
working group last call is a call
for comments
we're seeing several things in the java
um
does anybody want to speak we can take
notes from the jabber
i see two people saying that's right
go ahead i've taken some notes from the
jabber recorded several
plus ones and two i i believe
the jonas statement and also
some several
notes saying not ready
um they'll be there in the notes as best
i can capture them
yeah uh something's different from john
morton
he was he he said i'll read it exactly
i think working group last call at least
has to wait for l4s
ops to be completed so that's a personal
statement that the
ops draft should be completed does
anybody want to speak to that one
to that for no particular reason but uh
because i'm here in the queue uh i i
don't think that we need to wait for the
ops drafts i mean i think the obstacles
are useful it's it's
it's a brand new one and i think that
putting that
on the critical path rushes the draft i
think it's worth
spending some time getting that uh
ironed out
uh just in terms of getting the text
right and everything else but
uh i still don't understand why that
needs to be on the critical path
for getting these two experimental
status if people know how to deploy this
stuff
then they can do it
[Music]
any more thoughts
so i'm in the queue after jonah but i
see colin and john are still ahead of me
or
should i just speak i guess um
yes i will uh so the uh
you know the tests that jonathan and
pete have published lately
uh do show some some bad problems i
guess the
you know the claim is that this is as i
understand it is
essentially sufficient to uh
to call the l4s experiment likely to
fail
um so i'm not sure if the intent is to
sort of just
fix that after seeing the experiments
and i'm not sure why that wouldn't
happen in lab before
moving it forward but i guess the
sentiment here seems to be
let's get this rolled out so that people
can try it or something
i think there's already an
implementation people can try so i'm a
little confused what the
what the hold up is on running an
experiment just in terms of gathering
data i'm not sure
how that relates exactly to the last
call or not
like to me so far what's been
demonstrated kind of just
looks like probably a bad idea but it
there might be fixes for it that could
be in the works and i guess the idea is
to generate interest enough to get them
actually fixed um
you know that's that's just my sort of
take on on the experiments i've seen so
far but uh
yeah in terms of i guess the the goal
here is to get
wider operational experiment and that's
waiting on a draft i'm a little just
confused
on a on an rfc rather than than on a
draft and i'm a little confused on
how that even relates exactly so
i don't know who wants to speak to that
but
um so i'm not sure who's running with q
but i guess i may be next
um i i don't think we need to wait for
the abstract here uh
i'm confused as to why we're not just
proceeding with this already
the the problems we've seen identified
seem very minor
and unlikely to be a practical issue so
i don't i don't quite understand why
we're not proceeding with the
the experiment so yes i i would
encourage us to to move forward with
this
okay so i guess it's my turn and and i
will echo what some people said on this
like that um
just like on the chat that a little
active queue management telling us who
is next would be helpful from the chairs
um so i'm sort of struggling to know
what the experiment the experiment
uh actually is right so there's a bunch
of specs that talk about you know
queueing scheme all that that's great
but what's the experiment and i
think i try to say this in email so at
least in my mind
this tcp variant that would do something
clever with
whatever we put into the network is sort
of an intrinsic part of the experiment
because how else are you going to
evaluate something
and and that part i don't really see
described right so
i'm i'm probably convinced that what we
have in the draft is sort of
described well enough that you can
implement the queueing scheme like this
but i don't quite know unders i don't
know what what we're going to experiment
with
what's the outcome and what the date
what data do we want out of the
experiment to know whether we succeeded
or not
that that's the part i'm struggling with
um yes so i think the experiment is so i
think problems that have been detected
about dual queue actually make certain
assumptions about deployments
so part of the experiment is actually to
figure out if these deployments are
do exist in our problem because we
assume that it's not the case
so um you know that's something we can
figure out from a larger scale
experimentation
um and the and to also like hit on last
point
i think part of the experiment is also
um to give
these new kind of congestion control
rooms to evolve
and therefore we need some deployment of
the queuing scheme in the network
um so i think we're ready for that part
respond directly to that before we go to
cone
so did i understand this correctly that
the experiment is we're going to
throw this in the network and and see
what happens because that's kind of what
it sounded like
maybe cohn can speak to that yeah maybe
the thing i want to say is the
the experiment is is mainly for people
to
to start working on the congestion
controls uh to get the real experience
of of
what is going on and to get engagement
because a lot of
uh application developers i guess are
interested in using this and want to see
deployment
and also get convinced that deployment
will happen before they really engage
and
and solve all the problems and what the
problems we see today
are mainly well the main problem is of
course classic ecn
fallback and the longer we wait the more
classic ecn will be an alternative
because nobody starts to believe in
whether alphas will actually really
happen
that's that's the main danger and
i i don't think a lot of people are
convinced that the problems in in the
current
implementation cannot be solved it's a
huge opportunity to
to to experiment and to again gain
better
experience in the beginning we thought
okay data center tcp would
would be the reference and we didn't
need to work
on on the congestion control but in the
meantime
this this prague has become a kind of
reference implementation
uh status and and now even
asked to be to prove everything that uh
that it can gain i i think it's a wrong
expectation
especially from the people working on
that um
uh if if people are really concerned
that there is no
improvement possible then then okay
we we should stop here or wait until
this is really the case but i don't have
the the impression that people are are
thinking in that way
people are waiting for deployment and
really to to
to get things running and see this also
what's important is we get a lot of
traction in implementations if you're
going to wait
i i think the the confidence in
in this whole experiment and this whole
topic will will slowly disappear which
is a bigger
danger to get progress than than
whatever concerns there are now
which are i agree minor and or mainly
performance
improvement or performance issues with
uh
the the congestion control itself uh
so i'm i'm saying we should not wait
definitely not and the experiment is
still an experiment we should
we should engage and and more people
will will automatically
work on it
okay and then uh janna
um to to last this question of uh what
is the experiment i think
i think he is right in that we should
articulate precisely what the experiment
here is and i think
answer uh some of the questions
i'll emphasize just two points in there
one of them is that
our history history has shown that
uh just getting this deployed itself can
be a simple experiment what i mean by
that is
even though it does yes you write large
that you know are we just
going to throw this out there and see
what happens uh getting this
getting getting something like for us
the the
the ecn marking itself deployed is a
pretty big experiment if you succeed in
that
then i i'd be very happy um but yes uh
the encouraging endpoints to
experiment with different congestion
controllers is also an additional
piece there but for them to do that we
need the bit out there in the network
so i would say that we we launched the
experiment to see if we can actually
deploy this into the network and once we
do that we know that we can build
controllers
and we already have some example
controllers that even though they are
not
perfect they'll do something with it
something pretty good with it
i would also ask a a slightly different
question
which is do we think that by keeping it
in committee so to speak or keeping it
as a draft in the working group we
gain anything if we don't gain anything
by making it an experiment out there
my question would be what do we gain by
keeping it in the working group
i noticed that we lost sebastian from
the queue if you want to
jump back in i think you were in the
front uh at this point
thanks so um the concern i have at the
moment is that the operational safety
of all of the lfrs design and
implementation over the wider internet
has not been proven sufficiently at the
current time speaking about deploying
what we have
seems rather premature without
data showing that it really is safe over
the long haul and not just over the
short rtt low hop count
links between end user and cdns
seems rather uncautious
i think l4s simply isn't there
that we should talk about the lost last
call now
the data is missing i'm it's sad that
after seven years the data is still on
there but
that's how it is i'm pretty sure that
this data can be produced relatively
quickly and presented and if it's safe
no matter whether i like it or not then
make it an experiment but if it's not
safe
let's just drop them but let's make this
based on
data and not just how we feel about this
i have a feeling in this discussion that
many people have not actually looked
in the detailed measurements that were
presented
and hence we are discussing very much in
the abstract why we should be actually
talking about real data and numbers
thanks i see
cone jumped back in uh maybe you want to
address that comment before we go to
greg
yes maybe the the the main problem that
is open now like if i see it sebastian
is the
the the big round trip time uh
alpha s competing with alfres itself um
this this is not it's a concern of
course
and it's a performance concerns for
alfres users themselves um
it's a range where the the
congestion control that we have now is
not optimal yet
for the users themselves a very simple
fallback is just okay if your run trip
time is bigger than a certain amount
we fall back to cubic and and the
problem
in itself for our reference uh
uh um congestion control is solved
and it could be used as a as a as a
reference
for for experiments and of course it's
better to
to work on improving for longer round
trip times also the performance for
alphas
but on the other hand what's the value
of that because if you have a
run trip time of 160 already you you're
better off
uh or that extra one millisecond or 15
milliseconds
is not going to make a big difference so
we should also see what is the relevance
of
the problems that we see today uh in in
practice they
i i think they are zero um it's just a
matter if there is interest for people
with a very
long round trip time to have a buffer of
one millisecond instead of 15
milliseconds
it will be worked on otherwise the the
congestion controls will automatically
fall back
but all these things that's experience
that we need people working on it and
and
the right people with the right
incentives working on that and improving
it
uh if if you're if everybody looks at us
and and and expects that we are going to
make this this uh
uh ultimate super uh
perfect congestion control then then
that is the wrong
way of progressing we will probably
uh starve at the end from from
exhausting uh
i mean let's engage let's other people
get the opportunity to work on uh i see
only one main problem
which is not that big it's the the
classic ecn detection
so and the longer we wait the more
classic ecn will be the alternative
so i don't see any gain in waiting let's
go forward the question is is the
network part okay
then we should go ahead if the
congestion control is
okay i think now it's not perfect uh but
it can be improved so
what's why stopping i would say go ahead
make sure we can as fast as possible go
to work group lost call
and and the rest will follow
okay thanks i have uh greg then gory
lars and sebastian and we have to be
quick there's only a couple minutes left
yeah i just want to point out that the
original definition of ecn
is uh is 20 years old and so far
sounds like the deployment of that in
networks is
zero percent to some number of decimal
points
[Music]
whereas here we have
networks that are very interested in
deploying l4s
ecn signaling
and it would be a shame if the ietf
didn't take that opportunity to
to move this forward into an experiment
and and get all the benefits that uh
we're expecting to see from all for us
okay corey
am i at the end
i i'll i'll wait to the end
okay uh lars
i didn't want to sound oh my audio is
really garbled um
i didn't want to sound like i was going
to require like the perfect congestion
controller for for this experiment right
but but um you know asking for a fabric
upgrade is a pretty tall ask
and not being able to motivate it
to application developers that you also
talked about kind of
that you know no application can use
this without there being a
congestion controller that delivers some
sort of benefits to that application
right so you can throw this in the
network but if you can't be exploited by
the app
it's it's not going to be a very great
deployment story right so
um we can argue whether what we
currently have as a congestion
controller is good enough
but i think this is an integral part of
of this experiment if you
think back right we've done a few
classes of this before so
either we've done queueing improvements
that
intended to improve existing tcp traffic
without tcp
changes right we know how to do that
we've also done tcp changes to try to
you know work better with whatever cues
they found in the network and we know
how to do that and then we've done
ecn right we changed both changed the
network and changed gcp and it was a
pretty integrated design
right it was pretty minimal but it was
it was integrated and in my mind this
this needs to be a similarly integrated
activity it's not enough to just to
upgrade one part
without at least some heavy thinking
about how
you know that that q change is gonna
manifest itself
in application level improvements
otherwise what's the incentive
okay so so i i agree it's it's
it's very important to have both and
looking at the past
in the past we had the congestion
control for acn which was very simple
just do the same
as before instead of drop
and afterwards we didn't see any or
hardly any deployment
in the network now is the opposite we
have a network
with a lot of interest with a lot of uh
plans to deploy uh with standards
already defined
uh people working on products and now
we're saying
uh let's let's uh
wait until the end host which are
usually the easiest one to change things
uh are are at par i i think we are
blocking this at the moment we we have
uh
good uh engagement in networks
and and plans to deploy let's let's
release this
um i don't see any and unless
i would like to ask other people uh as
well i i don't see anything
that cannot be solved in the host at the
moment
um we're gonna need to we're gonna need
to wrap wrap this up the next minute or
two because the
plenary is about to start
so so but anyway the short thing is we
have
something which is good which can be
used at the moment already
um within a specific range
with some corner cases not but
if if that's the pro or the the the
question
we have that already we can do the the
experiment applications can
use it already within certain
constraints
defined in the operational guidelines
okay i think the chairs
need to take what's been said here under
advisement we'll
uh and we will consult with the ad about
a.d about the path forward here corey
did you want
anything to add
uh
all right any last words from anybody
else
i think bob uh may want to wrap up his
well um i don't necessarily want to wrap
up the talk but
i i just want to sort of state a fact
that
um i believe that
the people who are doing these network
implementations
would not deploy it unless there was an
rfc out there and
you know the process of going from
working group call to that
it's still going to be a you know a few
months away because that's how how long
the ietf takes
and these guys are ready but they're not
they're not going to deploy if there's
not a
you're not you're not going to you know
start dealing with a
change to ip without the itf approving
it
i think we're basically at time gord did
did you want to have a last word
i think it would be worthwhile um taking
a
sense of those people left in the room
we know people have already left the
meeting so this can only be imprecise
but
um if you think that it would be
a good idea to have a working group last
call
in the next period
can we get some indication about who
would be against
that and who would be for it
i think we've lost something
a bit more clearly yeah yeah
how many people would commit to review
this document
and contribute to a working group last
call
if we were to start one before the next
idea
how many people would review
okay so we're collecting that by the
tool and
it will again help the chairs to
gradually make forward progress we will
be talking to our ad we'll be talking to
the document editors
and when does this
pull clue conclude when you when when
you click on in session
there we go at that point here and 18
people said that they would
review this if it was uh presented for a
working group last call
that's a good number so that that makes
me happy that we will have reviewers
when we come to that decision
right we we meet echo says we can have a
little more
time if it's necessary is there anything
necessary now i think we need to declare
victory
i'm happy with that uh bob's got
additional slides that will be in the
proceedings
yeah i mean they're basically saying
what's in the draft i can also post on
the mailing list
um which well i've already done that um
for the last set of deltas but i can
say what the main changes are um that
haven't been discussed on the main list
okay thank you
and i'm done from my side thank you ever
so much for
a very productive meeting the other
chairs can say something more finished
i think we're done i'm going to tell
miracle i think we're done
going once
okay i think we're done thank you very
much everybody
so
oh
you