okay i think we'll get started this is
the ietf 109
meeting of the web transport working
group
a few meeting tips morning afternoon all
the time everyone
actually bernard if you want to enable
the video as we're going through the
chair slides so people can see how
personable we're
nice we are or how sleepy
um let me
let me see here i'll enable
uh video
okay and go back to slides
uh so the session is being recorded
and if you're here you're automatically
in the blue sheets
um please join the session jabber room
and use headphones although i'm not
doing that i'm using an echo cancelling
speakerphone
and state your full name before speaking
so we can get you into the minutes
david do you want to give a few tips
so the medical tool makes sense but it's
not necessarily very
intuitive so um
you need to do separate things like if
you want to speak you need to first
enter the queue
and then like the chairs will call on
you
at some point um you'll have to manually
leave the queue yourself when you're
done speaking
but also once we call on you we'll just
say something we don't have a button to
press to let you in like last time
so you need to yourself enable your
audio by unmuting so that's the button
here
and then when you're done you like kind
of stop by saying you're done and then
you mute
and we'll move on to the next person we
encourage folks to use their camera if
they're comfortable it's a lot easier to
understand
each other especially across like
different accents and everything when
you can kind of
see the person you're talking to but
that's not a requirement by any means
uh yeah also you need to leave the queue
yourself if you don't actually press the
tool to leave it you'll stay in it
okay the note well uh just a reminder of
itf policies you've probably heard this
several times
already if you've been attending other
meetings uh
and by participating you agree to follow
itf
proceed processes and policies and
definitive information
is in the document listed below and
other bcps
if you want more info please talk to the
working group
chairs or the ids
so at this meeting the agenda is posted
and it's up to date
we will want a volunteer for notetaker i
believe we have a volunteer for jabber
scribe
but we will want somebody to take notes
we have the kodi md
at this link so it's easy to do
but we do need a volunteer so we can
keep notes for what is about to
transpire
do we have a volunteer
until we have someone who can help take
notes it's really not that much work
and there's really no pressure we're not
expecting the notes to be perfect
um right like it's just
i'm assuming that maybe everyone is
clamoring to volunteer for note-taking
but they haven't figured out how to use
the audio tool
for the link so that we can verify we
can actually get into the notes this
time
yes so from me deco there if you click
in the top right there's a link to the
note meeting tool and you can either
have it in line or
you can open another tab
yeah uh if it's working the way we think
it is you should see the agenda
in the tool when you open it
at least that's what i think i put there
okay i can do that thank you so much
mike we really appreciate it
we really do okay so here is the agenda
um we had i have the preliminaries which
you've just talked about we should
probably uh do the agenda bash as well
david will handle a cue
and then we're going to have will law
from the w3c web transport working group
give us a little update luke will
give us some developer feedback from the
web transport origin trial
then we'll have victor do the overview
and requirements
eric will do http 2 and then
victor will do the quick and http 3
drafts and then we'll have the wrap up
and hopefully a bunch of time
for discussion during this session
uh is there anybody who'd like to bash
the agenda or have
another suggestion
okay so we'd like to turn over the floor
to will
law are you there will
well you need to uh if you're there
you need to press the audio tool to
unmute yourself
not seeing him in the currently present
participant list
okay well i can i can give his slide
probably well enough
uh for now uh so i will i will do it
um the w3c web transport working group
has been
established and the charter has been
published
and the working group has been created
and all that they did hold meetings
during
the w3c tpac held two two-hour meetings
and now they have set up bi-weekly
meetings at an alternating time slot of
7 a.m or 4 p.m pacific
and it's all on the w3c web transport
wiki
so you can go and find out all about it
we have some
draft editors and
there's been a call for consensus to
adopt the existing web transport api
spec
and so the it's now in the w3c web
transport github
so you can look for it there there are
lots of issues that have been filed by
various people including folks
that are part of this meeting and
so work is underway and if you're
interested please
please participate
all right so um now we're going to have
some developer feedback
um luke will tell us a little bit about
what is experienced i have also have a
few uh
observations to make so luke i'd like to
hand the floor to you
hello everyone um so i'm luke
uh i am a software engineer at twitch
um and also amazon
we were purchased a while ago and always
forget about that
um but uh yeah we've been messing around
with web transport
um quite a bit and uh have
some things i want to just talk about um
yeah so just to be clear for everybody
uh luke's gonna be giving feedback on
the web transport origin trial here's
some basic info about it
uh basically if you've got chromer edge
up to m88 like the canary
you can play with it um you should
probably i guess
do uh um for the latest api if you're
just working from the
api draft i guess m87 or later is
is a good thing um and there's some
various
uh info on the web uh to get more
experience with the api but
go ahead luke yeah so um
to that extent as well the uh there's a
few hurdles to get the api going
um but the stream part of the api quick
transport
works somewhat well i'll go into some of
the specific bugs
uh and the datagram um component works
uh
as well uh and you have to do stuff with
self-signed certs
uh so but there's there's guides out
there uh which is great
um so yeah um just some
some some heads up why we're trying to
use quick transport
um so uh the first problem we're trying
to deal with
is head of line blocking um surprise
surprise
it's kind of why quick was designed
to power hv3 because as we've noticed
when you deliver a lot of media it's
usually sequential
um you know like we're streaming this
video call
or you'd be streaming watching uh a
video download
and anytime you have congestion it just
causes the queue to backup
either when you're uh contributing to a
website
um like you're creating a new uh a
stream
uh we use rtmp at twitch and
congestion causes back pressure which
increases latency
um and then in my half i work on the uh
distribution team like the cdn
uh team we run our own uh uh
low latency live video cdn and again if
any time your network sputters just a
little bit
it causes a roadblock um increases
latency so we really want to
use quick more than anything to
investigate
um how to solve this and this is some
interesting
like ramifications with uh
um uh yeah how to do it
um so next slide
um the crux of our
idea and how to do uh low latency video
is that we really want to break video
into components
such that if there is um congestion
they're independent of each other
um so we want multiplex multiplexing we
want to have multiple requests in flight
uh and i think more critically we want
to prior to prioritize such that if
there is congestion we make sure the
important data gets there first
um so we're using quick transport um i
went through and run my own quick
implementation because we're uh
we're a go shop and the existing uh
quick wasn't there
uh and yeah we're we're right now
running experiments
uh for employees using um the origin
trial
uh and we wanna try to hit some
production traffic
uh next uh early next year to try and
see how it works
uh next slide um
one thing we've had a large debate over
is why not
uh htv3 um it's really because low
latency is hard to do
um especially over such
long stateful connections um
you have to go into the area of like
http push
and you have to start mapping well i'm
gonna have to make the client do these
requests in this order
this frequency um and it also gets
difficult when you wanna
have the same api for contributing and
distributing video uh you have to you
have to deal with firewalls so if
the client is pushing video it's a
different api than the clients
downloading video
um so it's really nice to have
like a quick based api where it's just
arbitrary streams it doesn't matter who
initiates
doesn't matter who's receiving uh the
api is symmetric in that regard
um and quick transport is so simple we
don't
we don't need uh
connection pooling like hp3 transport
there's almost no point having fallback
hv2
transport support um
because we just don't want to work with
tcp um
we want to use quick uh and also it's
nice that datagram's a potential
fallback
so this is if we do run into issues
with let's just say the quick
implementation it's always nice
knowing that you have this like uh swiss
army knife of being able to do it
yourself
um so next slide
um i've gone through and filed quite a
few bugs
with the chrome implementation um which
is great
um more or less the
state machine um just needed
some to be able to handle few uh
a few cases better a lot of stuff where
um
really the only case that worked out of
the box was if uh
was remote initiated unidirectional
streams were
great otherwise there's always like
little subtle issues with
every other configuration um
so here's just a few tickets if you want
to go through i think most of them are
being worked on some of them are fixed
um i know the using the entire cpu core
is fixed
um that was just a busy loop in the
kind of like the wake up logic um but
we've run into a few things like
uh half closed streams for example
should the
uh would transport api require
half closed or it should just be vague
or does it defer to quick
just a few things that needed like um
uh the draft to mention it explicitly so
that
implementations don't miss it
um let's see and then final slide
um so quick transport's working great
for us for
distribution uh purposes um
we're thinking about using it for
contribution but there's a few things we
would need of the streams api
um so this is a little like a feature
bucket list at the very end
um but prioritization we're really
concerned about congestion control
and i know it's very hard to do like a
way to pick things out
um and some issues with datagrams
like if you try and send a high rate of
datagrams you run into
fighting with the underlying congestion
control mechanism
uh that you also don't have control over
um
but yeah that's it uh i i think i've
given
more fine detailed uh uh
feedback by posting issues uh at least
on github
uh and yeah if anybody has any specific
questions as well
about what the uh the origin trials are
uh like but it's been great so far
um just being able to run quick
transport in the browser
it's been a lifesaver even before h3
support is uh you know ready
okay thank you luke um i just wanted to
give a little bit of
feedback um this
is the requirements and use cases that
the w3c
is developing i'm not going to talk
about any all of these but
just make your observation about a few
of these use cases
in particular i wanted to talk a little
bit about low latency streaming use
cases
uh such as game streaming and remote
desktop and then
a few what i would call large scale
events use cases these are for a lot of
participants like at least ten thousand
um things like company meetings or
concerts political gatherings sporting
events stuff like this
the distinction between these two is the
large-scale events generally don't have
the same
tight latency requirements so for many
of these things like a second delay is
okay
uh whereas the low latency it's uh needs
uh
as low latency as possible because
you're talking about uh things that
could be disrupted by
by uh additional latency so um
a little bit on the low latency
streaming use cases
uh and the primary ones i i work with a
lot of developers
in the gaming and remote desktop cases
they are almost always focused on quick
transport that's the thing that they ask
me about and they want to learn more
about so they were using a bunch of them
we're looking at the origin trial
one thing i think it's important to
understand and this is true of any use
case is to understand whether it's a
green field use case
whether people have something they're
already doing
doing it with and then if they do you
have to understand what the bar is to
get them to move from whatever they're
doing now to to what you want them to
move to
so in this particular case for these
things we see the
developers are using today webrtc
the data channel with rtp audio video
so in the case of the remote desktop
typically the audio video
they'll use whoever to see screen
sharing and then the data channel for
the keyboard and mouse events and
control
um for gaming there's we see
client server game streaming which is
done
exclusively with the data channel
so they send the audio video and the
control trap of the keyboard mouse stuff
over the data channel
we've also seen gaming
done with rtp audio and video as well
um with the data channel being used
uh for the for the keyboard and mouse uh
as well
um and i would mention that there's
a number of developers who use
both client server and peer-to-peer use
cases so for example
um you could stream a game from the
cloud but you could also stream it from
your game console to a mobile device
or the remote desktop could be a remote
desktop in the cloud
or you could be just doing a remote
desktop with your desktop
your own desktop for example as well
so a bunch of these developers they're
supporting both client server and
peer-to-peer
and they like to have a single code base
they don't want to have to write a
completely different
uh implementation for peer-to-peer
versus client server
and that's one of the reasons they like
webrtc is because it kind of gives them
both
and yes for the client server case they
need ice
um but it's more important to them in
general to have
the ability to write one code base than
it is to get rid of ice
so i know we pitched one of the things
about web transport is we get rid of ice
and
the answer from a bunch of these
developers is i'll keep the ice if i can
keep
do the peer-to-peer so a lot of these
folks have a strong interest
in the in the peer-to-peer extension to
great transport as well
um a few other things um these some of
these applications are pretty high
performance like the game streaming
uh and what i mean by this is that the
streams themselves may not be huge in
terms of bandwidth
but often the the things that you're
streaming to are not very high
performance so it can be for example an
older game console or something that's
not very powerful
um so some of these folks were having
issues with the data channel because uh
the the way the javascript uh back
pressure is implemented in data channel
so offering them potentially a better
back pressure was it was a very
attractive aspect of web transport
um but as luke just mentioned
it's not for de for uh for web transport
for reliable web transport it does
solve a lot of the back pressure
problems kind of nicely so you
uh you don't have to have basically what
we saw with the data channels they were
doing a lot of application layer
acknowledgement
but for datagrams you still need the app
layer acknowledgement so
in some ways if for developers who are
using datagrams
uh in this scenario they're not seeing a
lower
level of complexity with web transport
and they were kind of hoping that web
transport would
allow them to get rid of the application
layer acting that they were doing to
make the data channel function
uh but they're not they're not seeing
that advantage they still have to do
their application layer acting
um the other thing is that they're
asking about
just some basic devops issues like for
example
say they bring down a gaming server is
there a way to migrate these
uh web transport connections
uh to another to another server um
so there's just some practical aspects
of the clustering and draining that they
they wanted to understand how to do
better
um i've also heard the uh bandwidth
allocation it's a little bit different
maybe than luke's prioritization
um but they wanted to be able to
allocate uh
bandwidth between the datagram flows and
the streams and the reason is that the
datagram
is used for control traffic so they
don't want to be choked off
um and they don't want like the audio
video to take
to take so much of the bandwidth that
the control traffic for example
experiences delays
um so that's the kind of thing they
weren't i don't think they cared about
uh priority in the sense of dscp or
anything like that but just
making sure that their um their control
traffic had a certain minimum balance
okay a little bit on the event streaming
this use case
um there was more interest in http 3
transport as i mentioned the other one
was quick transport
and the folks i've talked to here the
existing solution is
hls so that's what they consider to be
the incumbent
you would hear a lot because hls is a
pretty mature technology
you can a lot of great support in cloud
infrastructure and cdns
stuff like this so here they they had a
concern about whether they could get the
same level of ecosystem support
uh for http 3 transport they could get
with hls
so a couple of things is is they wanted
to know whether we supported on mobile
platforms like
you know will i be able to get this on
all of my mobile operating systems
also would it be widely supported in
browsers of course some of these
questions i can't really answer right
now but um they were a little bit
concerned about the complexity of the
protocol and pooling issues with http 3
um and whether it would inter-operate
and i'll talk a little bit more about
that but quick transport didn't worry
them at all because they
uh for the other cases because it's so
simple it's like
yeah we think this will enter very
likely to inter-operate and
be the kind of thing people could
implement wildly but hp3 they weren't so
sure
um and then they went looking uh talking
to their server vendors and they got
some disturbing feedback which is that
um
most of the http 3 server vendors were
not planning to implement http 3
transport
so that kind of meant if they were using
a stock kind of a server
they would have to implement their own
server combination of http 3 and
http transport probably within a
framework and then
for the folks who were using node they
discovered oops i don't have a
there's no quick module that's going to
be available in any reasonable amount of
time
due to i guess some blocking issues with
openssl
and so they're kind of stuck with python
and aio quick
and for the people who are comfortable
with python that wasn't a really big
deal but if they weren't it was
um and then they would ask questions
like will http 3 transport be supported
widely by cdns you know hard to answer
that
um and then there was a few folks doing
this event streaming for like company
events who are interested in enterprise
and this got interesting
because a lot of these enterprises they
think of http
2 http is the thing they use as a
transport of last
resort so you know a lot of enterprises
they block udp
traffic they don't even necessarily
allow tcp on all ports
uh and the problem is in these kind of
an enterprise it's it's likely that
quick wouldn't work
um and so we talked a little bit and
said well we can do this http 2
failover and the problem there was if
you're an enterprise that doesn't allow
that's that tightly controlled you
probably don't support http 2 either
so it wasn't clear that http 2 transport
would really help them much
that this would this would help them
with this enterprise problem
things are very different from the folks
who are more uh on the consumer side
because they don't encounter a lot of
these crazy firewalls
but this was just something out there so
a bunch of questions among the
um customer base about http 3 transport
and how
um how much how much take-up it would
get in the in the ecosystem
um and also interoperability due to
complexity
okay are there any questions about this
feedback before we jump
to the next uh session let's drain the
queue
uh so i have a speaking notice well as
chair i'll say one of our main goals for
this session
today oh sorry i forgot to enable the
camera
there we go one of our main goals for
the session today is kind of
getting out of the transport zoo um as
we've been calling it
uh making some decisions in terms of of
all the possible transports we have
which ones we want to actually
like focus on and which ones we want to
like work on
um so but with all my chair hat on i
have some clarification questions for
luke
um so uh yeah
perfect cool um so the first one you
mentioned
that um you weren't interested in an h2
fallback so just out of curiosity
if on a network that blocks udp and
quick
what would you use instead or would you
just say
my feature doesn't work and that's also
a reasonable option i'm just curious
yeah so we we uh use hls for
distribution
um and we would fall back to hls as well
for third party cdn support if
our first party cdn is overwhelmed um
so we're mostly looking for quick as
kind of a uh
extra functionality and if it doesn't
work we'll just fall back to the
you know the backup um that being said
like we could
technically do our approach with tcp but
you just have fighting tcp flows um
and requests so it's just easier to
require quick
well but i guess just the my question is
you know if quick isn't there you need
something you can't require quick
because some users don't have access to
it and so then it's either
you have a fallback inside you know
underneath the javascript layer
like that could be h2 transport or you
manually at your layer fall back to
something else like hls i think they're
both reasonable options i'm just
oh so uh if we did h2 transport
i think the performance would actually
be worse than falling back to a
different protocol
um uh based on based on the the way
we're prioritizing data
because we expect the prioritization to
take effect but if under the hood we're
using tcp
um and they're you know the kernel
doesn't prioritize we're just gonna have
more buffering it's a little hard to
explain but
yeah i heard that same uh approach david
which is that they would just fall back
to hls
yeah no i think for especially for use
cases that are already on the market
or in production today uh with something
it's natural to
fall back to what they already have
built today that makes sense
cortex and then i had a second question
for you luke which was
you mentioned uh quick transport and
preferring that to h3 transport
you know one of the main questions we're
trying to answer today is
do we do we want to build one of them do
we want to build
both of them do we want to build neither
i'm guessing it's not going to be the
neither but
in your case it sounds like you prefer
quick transport if the working group
were to decide to reach consensus that
we only wanted to
build h3 transport what would be your
main objection
i think you're still muted oh go ahead i
saw it on the mailing list i've left
some feedback but
um it's really just h3 transport is more
complicated to implement
for in our case no benefit because our
web server doesn't
handle h3 requests it would only create
this
um web transport connection so it kind
of seems redundant to also have h3
support
uh my my implementation doesn't even
support h3
um so it's more like do you is the
complexity worth it and for us it's like
no okay so from your perspective if i'm
understanding correctly you're building
your
own stack from scratch and in that
scenario
having to also build h3 is more work for
limited benefit if you're not
the main value add would be pooling and
if you're not using it you're having
more complexity with less
with no benefit cool thanks that makes
sense
and yeah also david for the
um for the low latency streaming cases
they liked the quick transfer because
they could conceivably get the
peer-to-peer
without building an http 3 server into
their browser or their backend so
that's why they like the quick transport
for those
anyone else in the queue
okay i think uh victor you're up
um okay
uh so i have
uh my main question i guess is
the so do i understand correctly that
you serve
uh directly video from
there is no reverse proxy or any other
intermediation
in your use case because one of the
reasons people
are interested in http free transport
uh is the
for things like priorities uh you can
not prioritize on your socket
but if you have priorities that need to
cross a reverse proxy
you would have to communicate that and
http provides that way
so if you're using you if you do not
have any form of reverse proxy in from
your video server uh uh i guess you're
not interested that's why i'm asking
so we would we would use any form of h3
prioritization
as an alternative um but yeah we we
right now have a
uh we assign users to a host directly
um if you go to twitch and look at the
network tab you'll you'll see when you
start a video session
you're uh you're signed with a specific
host name
um and that host is then able to
prioritize traffic
um okay from two hosts then we couldn't
do it
oh okay and there is no direct
is there it's a direct connection to the
quick server in question
yep yeah we don't have any uh load
balancers we push
a little too much data to have load
balancers
um we have an application load balancing
tier kind of like out of band
hey everyone the chairs completely
messed up the q management here so uh
hold on
bernard let me handle the queue and uh
so we have five more people in it
uh well actually four ian sweat you're
next
cool um thank you david um
so uh just fyi um i think that
it's very likely that bbr2 would become
the default congestion control and quick
and q at the end of q1 uh 2021
um is very close to done after a lot of
work
so i think i am fairly optimistic about
that i do think that is in much better
congestion controller than
either bbr1 or cubic for
um yes sorry victory clarified uh yes in
the google quick slash chromium
implementation i cannot guarantee it for
anyone else obviously
um but you know if you wanted to you can
just like
yank whatever we have at the end of q1
um
i highly support the direction of making
a decision on these transports because i
think moving forward is important
on the fallback issue based on my
discussions with youtube they also do
not need a fallback
to tcp because if they were to have a
fallback
they would actually prefer to use http
1.1 and their current solution
um and although that being said
as long as they can say i only want to
use quick transport if i actually get
quick transport
i think they would be happy to use quick
transport so it's not that they're
um because they're importing our stack
anyway the cost of
the implementation cost is low but the
they would definitely not want to fall
back to
h2 transport they would only want to
fall back to
each one so as long as that
functionality is preserved then i think
we're all good
thanks
lucas
hello can you hear me yes
great uh thanks for the presentation
luke uh it was good to see
uh some more detail on on some of the
stuff you've been working on
i've been following some of the issues
um some of those i experienced myself
so i was playing with web transport um i
basically borrowed heavily from google's
example client
code um but then wrote my own web
transport server on top of
ish and that was really an experiment to
see
for an existing stack how much wicked
that obviously leverages datagram and so
as when i started this work some of that
was
changes to the library to support
datagram and i kind of expected web
transport might
take some changes to the library too but
in the end
it didn't i was able to just modify our
example
client and server to um
speak quick transport let's say that way
that was quite low impact uh i i suspect
for me
like adding hp3 transport to that
toy server would have been quite simple
too because all the existing http
3 heavy lifting would have been there
but then
like the fact i didn't do that is maybe
telling that
it's kind of a bit superfluous again i
didn't need connection pooling in this
this toy example um all i was doing was
echoing something back it's not as
complicated as
video streaming or anything but you can
see how
somebody who's coming kind of new into
quick would want to do the easiest
thing in maybe in some respect
um so yeah i think some of the questions
i had
have been answered in terms of luke the
the kind of
what work did it take on the server side
for you to to implement this stuff
um but it seems that you're quite
targeted towards this use case so i
i think i already got the answer there
um so
yeah just cheers for sharing and i i do
agree that it would be good
for us to come to some answer on what
people
want from either quick transport or http
3 transport and
and how the the fallbacks all relate
and you absolutely need to tell me where
i can buy that hat
uh eric kinnear
really nice to have uh some more
concrete uses of you know here's what
i'm actually doing and how i need to
send it and what that means
um a couple of questions i had i think
datagrams
do have congestion control and you kind
of spoke to that
in contrast to the to the slides um and
it seemed as though
the not having control over that uh i
don't want to say that's a feature
not a bug but i thought one of the one
of the benefits that we
people had been talking about previously
and it'd be really interesting to see if
this holds up in practice or if it
actually turns out that it's more
annoying
than it is helpful is being able to
share that congestion control context
with the other data that you're
potentially sending to that same
endpoint
under the idea that much of that data is
almost certainly taking
the same if not a very similar route and
therefore
a congestion controller that can
appropriately manage the amount of data
that you're shoving through that pipe
is going to be happier than many
instances of congestion controllers that
are trying to achieve an equilibrium
um so it'd be really interesting to see
if we can find any data about that or or
if it's just
you know hey i've got a congestion
controller built into my thing
right now and so it's it's annoying to
have this mode where it's not there um
the only other thought that kind of
comes with that is about the application
layer acts i think folks were mentioning
in the chat
that it's uh in theory if you had an api
uh the datagrams are act and so if you
had an api that exposed that to you
you wouldn't need application layer x
anymore
and from that perspective if you're
doing your own quick implementation
that seems a lot harder to me than
either using someone else's quick or h3
implementation
but that might be one of those cases
where if you needed those acts to be
available and no implementation did it
that could drive you to doing a lot more
work so i think
if we can get a clearer picture on
the actual places that we need
certain features i think we have a long
list of pros and cons of each side
and we need to kind of figure out which
ones actually matter and which ones we
don't care about
we haven't gone down this route but one
of the problems with the control
with datagrams um is that you don't know
when the packets could be dropped by web
transport so you have to
implement your own congest control on
top and you kind of have almost like
uh two two algorithms and you take the
minimum of both of them so
if for example chrome is using bbr for
sending and then you're
using cubic on top of that to avoid
overwhelming the web transport api you
just
you have a really low throughput um so
it would be great to get the low level
either some back pressure or expose some
underlying state
uh and for the duplicate axe i i didn't
realize this until we talked about it on
github
um but because datagrams don't have flow
control there's definitely states where
the quick packet could be
act yet the datagram was actually never
delivered to the application um so i
don't think you can use the underlying
acts of the datagrams unfortunately
thank you
that's a that's a really good
distinction because i think the
reliability side of that is definitely
like if you had that signal then you
wouldn't have to build a second thing
but if there's a case where
it can be act and not delivered then
you've got a problem thank you yeah i
run
i ran into this with data channels uh
with webrtc as well with the
sctp um where i just wanted to reuse the
existing axe under the hood
um but i had to build my own on top of
it and it just caused double the packets
but it was unavoidable all right
uh sorry folks i cut the cue after alan
which i'm
hoping that everyone heard because i
wasn't sure i might have muted at the
time
um and uh daniel i see your videos on if
you want to speak please join the queue
using the
andreas thing uh or
oh you're just saying all right all
right cool sounds good um all right then
we're gonna go on to victor's next
presentation
and let's try to keep the conversation
or
the comments a little bit shorter now
because we are like running into our
time and we really want to make
decisions at the other meeting so thanks
everyone
and victor you're up
okay apparently i didn't configure the
camera in advance so
uh i'm sorry you can't see me but
i want to give an update on the
one draft we've actually adopted that's
the web transport overview draft
so the goal is roughly to sum up what
the requirements in web transport api
are and
what are the common properties and the
semantics we expect from web transfer
protocols
now the specific uh
this we adopted it it i presented it
last time and i think
we adopt we adopted it even before the
previous meeting but there is one big
update next slide
uh yeah it's just a reminder that like
there is a github repo and it has issues
and
i'm not sure we might want to set up
i don't believe we have like an
automated email to summarize all of the
issues but we should
uh but there is a github uh
repository for the tripo and it has some
issues which i discussed at the previous
meeting but
there is a new pull request that i wrote
and
that's the request which relates to the
idea of headers next slide
so out of proposed transport the two
transport already have headers
h2 transport and h3 transport naturally
had http headers and we were just using
those
so h
so quick transport first didn't have
any headers uh and we had some clever
tricks to get
away with not sending them that did not
work
uh then we added a very bespoke
unidirectional header format called
client indication and that is what's
currently in the chrome
uh implementation in the origin trial
and in the latest revision of the draft
which is still
yet to upload because i also need to
solve some issues with error handling
there are actual fully featured headers
which i tried
to basically replicate the
http fields where there was an
equivalent http field
and there is but that's uh uh the fields
defined our origins here authority path
status
uh and the proposal
is that since all of the proposed
transports
uh have those headers we should
expose we should define those headers as
a shared property
of any transport that's web transport
just like having streams and having
datagrams and having
origin chat is a shared property and i
wrote up a pull request
and everyone is welcome to review and
comment it
and that's basically all of the updates
from the very draft
uh anyone has any questions or comments
well thank you victor that was
incredibly fast
that really brought us back to uh the
agenda time
yeah um i'm getting reports
from a bunch of people that
medico is going through some serious
technical issues
um if you're
trying to speak or join the queue and
it's not working please like
say oh i was gonna say say so in the
jabber but apparently
the meet echo chat is busted as well go
ahead lucas
uh yeah so my my hat's available for
free
on the snapchat filter thing uh i'll
send links around later
but the serious point um victor uh just
a question about this change i just
wonder if
um depending on the direction of like
whether people want quick transport and
not the rest of them if
if this proposal is still like the thing
you think is the best option
um but so it's gonna be http style even
if
we don't use the http style transport
i wondered if you could clarify please
i'm sorry i kind of misheard the end of
that uh
question was that aimed at me or at
someone else
uh victor okay that's what i thought
victor
it appears the doctor is dropped off the
list
list uh oh yeah and he's sending me
messages on chats saying that he can't
get into medical anymore
um it's okay
uh yes thanks lucas please bring it to
the list or ideally even an issue
uh and we'll we'll get that sorted um
yeah that's not great um
all right i think we'll move on to
eric's presentation so what i'm getting
from folks is apparently j if you
you're in meet echo now and you can hear
us don't touch anything it'll keep
working but if you refresh or anything
you won't be able to get back in
so um all right um eric if you wanna
uh join uh audio and video
oh i don't see eric in the participant
list anymore
uh okay um
well this is a mess um
do you want me to talk to the h2 slides
uh so that's an option
uh yeah because i was gonna say we could
also do the next presentation then come
back but if victor's gone
we can't do that so
yeah let me um yeah let's do that out
and if you can uh
uh yeah i haven't practiced but i'll try
to keep it short yeah
all right cool awesome thanks so eric
was saying that it was pretty short and
then you
yeah go ahead okay go ahead and roll to
the next slide
uh yeah next one
okay so uh we'll just give what's been
going on since the last itf
uh there's um some github issues have
been
filed and a little bit of discussion
there's some outstanding prs
um and basically all of hq transport is
kind of in a holding pattern waiting for
the working group to move forward on
what are we doing with http in general
uh because h2 is definitely
you know sort of the last on the packing
order uh in terms of transport so we're
not going to do http at all we're not
going to do http 2.
next slide
uh okay so one of the issues uh in the
draft was about
uh the original draft didn't mention
unidirectional stream support
uh and a question about whether we want
to uh
sort of have streams that are half
closed by specification
or just sort of have you know
bi-directional streams where
you know it's the one side just doesn't
send and i think
uh this next slide just talks about like
the
proposed uh pr and there's like
basically adding a a flag kind of like
speedy had which was like
just starts uh one half and the half
closed date
um and this kind of maps to the way uh
quick streams work more naturally
next slide
there's an issue open uh about being
able to um
open streams that additional round trips
uh for people who might need a refresher
so that h2 and h3 drafts
because they can multiplex multiple web
transport sessions on the same
connection
they're sort of one step where you're
sending uh
you're opening a stream that's defining
your session and then
you're opening additional streams that
are
uh kind of hanging off that session and
so uh
there's just an open issue to discuss
like is there a way to do that in one
round trip can you
um hang can can you send uh
the new web transport streams
referencing the connect stream
before you've received acknowledgement
from the other side that it's going to
that the handshake is going to succeed
um and uh
the there's sort of an interesting
interaction with h3 here because
h3 uh the streams could also arrive out
of order in h2 they can't
uh so you could end up the receiver can
end up with an h3
street if we allowed this the h3 draft
you could
end up with a web transport stream that
has no session established for it yet if
you were trying to do it in a single
round trip so i think this issue is
still open
we have any proposed resolution for it
next slide
um datagrams there's still not a
definition of what exactly the
datagram support looks like in h2
transport again we're not working on it
hard because we're waiting for
a nod from the working group here uh i
think on the issue
i proposed a strawman h2 frame
uh that we could use to transmit
datagrams that would be perfectly
serviceable
next slide
uh okay yeah i've covered all that next
okay i haven't read the slide yet so
give me a second
i mean i think and this will just maybe
feed into the broader discussion about
http versus quick transport so you know
the http
transports you know have this feature
where you can multiplex the sessions
right whereas quick transport doesn't
have that feature so
if you want to have you know multiple
column web transport sessions with quick
transport you have to open multiple
connections each one's sort of
independent
um and i you know i hear people saying
complexity
uh around uh the h3 draft and
i'm trying to like put my finger on what
is the complexity there
and uh one aspect that one aspect of it
is this sort of
being able to to pool or multiplex
multiple sessions together
uh obviously h3 has just you know some
additional complexity some of it i think
is trivial
and some of it i think you know like for
example you know q-pack or
headers is like non-trivial um so anyway
you know the ability to traverse
intermediaries uh
using these uh you know session streams
and multiplex together i think is one of
the sort of key differentiators between
the http world and non-http world next
slide
i think that's it point of order as
a chair i have been informed by the ietf
chair
that the data tracker authentication vm
completely fell over and they're gonna
reboot it but it means that it's gonna
at some point it's gonna kick everyone
out of the meeting it's gonna take two
minutes to reboot and then you're all
gonna be able to join again
so i'm gonna say like keep let's keep
going let's keep talking but if you're
kicked out
uh go make yourself a beverage and
come back in a few minutes and we'll
resume hopefully it'll be good so
but otherwise yeah keep going on let's
do it
uh okay i'll take questions if anybody
wants to talk about h2 but i kind of
recommend that it's we should move on to
h3 and
frame most of it in terms of where are
we going to transport wise i don't think
arguing about the details of h2 is
important
right now
the queue is open if
anyone is still in here
go ahead daniel uh so you
enable your microphone by clicking the
uh
unmute audio button can you hear me now
no yes oh okay great
yeah i was just wondering i'm sure i
misunderstood but i i thought
okay so quick transport has multiplex
streaming
um is that is that not the case so i
mean that is definitely the case i just
didn't understand in terms of https
so quick transport allows you to have
multiple streams on one connection
but it only allows you to specify a
single web transport
uri whereas h2 and h3 transports
let you open multiple sessions within
the same connection
using different web transport uris and
directing subgroups of streams towards
these different virtual sessions within
the connection
i think that's um like i said i think
it's a key difference between the sort
of two transport worlds and i think
um it's also where some people i think
that's where some of the complexity that
people point to h3 or h2
and say oh it's complex i think that's
where some of it's coming from
uh testing can anyone hear me it sounds
like we're
somewhat back yes
great um
[Music]
yeah well this is not ideal
but um got kicked out did you get an
answer to your question or would you
like me to
repeat i did i did as soon as as soon as
i heard uh uris
i i understood we do not have i see i'm
a transports person
so i'm like what do you mean we don't
have multiplexing we multiplexed the
streams in quick
but we do not have uris so that that was
that was the confusion
great
right um eric kinnear since you were
gonna give this presentation
and uh i'll ended up doing it is there
anything you want to add by any chance
yeah mostly just a thank you column
um thank you alan i don't think there's
anything else major tad i think
a really nice job of covering a lot of
this um in terms of
other other items
in here
there's intermediary stuff we talked a
little bit about that
i think the main thing is just can we
leave the zoo and can we actually
make a decision
thanks eric do we have any and seriously
thanks alan for
stepping in uh eric can probably meet
echo
both oh alan and beer
daniel the question uh yes what exactly
does it mean uh
leave the transport zoo oh
the uh no worries
it was at a previous web session that we
have all these transports that we're
trying to figure out
which ones we should build and i think
victor
called it the the big transport zoo the
first time and so
now the running joke is let's get out of
the zoo
okay so when you figure out whether it's
going to be h3 transport h2
transport uh tcp transport udp
transporter or whichever set of that
it's going to be
then we will be out of the transport
suit
exactly it's so the main question is
saying
which of these do we need which of these
should we build and like in what order
and we're hoping we have some time at
the end of the session uh tonight
uh that we're hoping to really answer
these questions
all right any of course yeah and i
should
i've clarified that my apologies um
any further questions on h2
or should we move on to h3
all right let's move on uh is victor
back yes i see victor in the participant
list victor you want to
re-enable um audio
there you go all right
you're you're marked as not muted on
meat echo but
i can't hear you
sorry i had other layer of mute
okay so i'm going to give update on h3
quick and then
uh i'll give update on the transfer zoo
uh so next slide
so just as a reminder h3 transport
is h2 transport but that's over h3
uh it has the datagram support
through quick datagram uh
and the specific mechanism for embedding
uh datagram vintage free is described in
draftskin as a quick date-free
datagram uh their draft
we are currently converting it with
design decisions and hd transport there
is a pull request i wrote
uh everyone is encouraged to take a look
at it
it includes switching from
using transfer parameters to negotiate
web transfer support to using
an http free setting because that's more
application layer and that just makes
more sense
there is a uh redesigned to
use stream ids as like identifier for
web transport sessions
uh that is also design decisions that
was in h2 and that made more sense and
that allowed me to deliver
two paragraphs of text from the specs so
that's nice
uh and that's basically it uh i did some
other minor adjustments but everyone is
welcome
to take a look at that pull request for
all of the details
next slide uh
quick transport quick transport actually
get more update and not publish a draft
because there are still i need to fix
the
story with error handling and error
codes but the basic idea of quick
transport if you're not familiar
it's a quick but it has a handshake
in front of it but after you're done
with the handshake you can treat your
web transport connection as if it was
just a regular quick socket
uh so it has lpn values that's dedicated
for it and that's not http
and that allows us to avoid cross
protocol attacks
it has its own dedicated uri scheme
called quick transport
quick dash transport column slash slash
and it has the same syntax as http urls
uh so we re so as i mentioned before we
used to have a very bespoke
header format we have a new format
that's bespoke but now
it's used to have numbers as keys now it
has strings as keys
and those follow roughly the same
semantics as http
and the reason i want this is one having
header names as strings instead of
keys is greater for extensibility
because this lots
people who are rolling their own things
on top of this
to uh add their own headers without
having to fear any collision
uh because otherwise it'd have to work
with numbers
uh and that's the main reason uh
uh it's still easy to parse it's
basically 16-bit lens prefixed
strings everywhere and
one of the main conceits of great
transport is that you get
exactly one quick connection per your
instance of your transport
uh that is step optimal if you open a
lot of web transport connections
uh because you do not get any pulling
and this
also allows another hand allows you to
do a lot of things like
swapping in your custom congestion
controller on the server side etc
uh that's you would not be able to as
easily get away with uh if you are
uh just using uh http free
and one connection for everything next
slide
uh so this is an example of how quick
transport
url scheme uh if you do not remember
this says i've not updated this slide
but all of the highlighted values
are now sent completely in
the handshake so that's another update
slash improvement uh next slide uh
as a reminder that that's this draft is
actually implemented in chrome there
are instructions on how to uh do
things with it if and uh i think corey
bernard went earlier today so i'm not
going to go back into this
uh now let's get to the
great transport zoo uh i regret to
inform everyone here that we've been
uh approved for a third season of this
the great transport zoo is where we look
at all of our transport and decide which
ones we want and which ones we don't and
there are four options which means that
there are
two to the four power two to the power
four
variants uh and we're largely arguing
for three or four of them
i think at this point but uh there are
three of four dimensions there is a
hypothetical fallback transport which i
didn't think
i think is this point no one seriously
considers because uh
if you want to do that uh it was ideas
that you could roll a transport on top
of websocket but you can do it
completely yourself so we don't need an
atf working here for this
uh next slide
so as an overview there are like very
easy
axis uh that you can split
dedicated versus pooled quick versus tcp
and those are the kind of defining
characteristic of those
those used to be less defining with last
updates to quick transportation free
transport etc i feel like they're
most important in characteristics of all
of those
uh next slide
so here is however there has been
some interesting details that happened
on api layer uh so one thing we did is
we've
we updated the api somewhere in
september and that's
in the very latest versions of chrome
where we notice that there is a very
similar redundancy if you look at the
old approach
you will notice that the choice of
transport is indicated twice
once in the constructor name once in
the euro url scheme and of course
that's redundant so we renamed the api
entry point to web transport
and that had a very nice side effect of
uh basically now uh before that
in order to implement all of the
transport we would have to write
uh codes for all of those javascript
classes
and that added a lot of cost but now
that this is
entirely dispatched by url this moves
the problem
of actually picking the transfer down to
the network layer which
removes overhead from shipping multiple
transports or
uh both
on technical level but also i feel
on conceptual level uh martin uh you
thanks victor for noticing so quickly
i'm sorry about being so slow to
jump in um so um
point of clarification there when you
have these two
say quick transport or um https one
the fallback methods aren't necessarily
done by the browser
are they in the quick transport version
so they might be doing the http version
in the new quick transfers there is no
automatic fallback
if you because quick transport only
exists over quick and you
basically get to do this manually
and in http version you
have to delegate this to the browser
because
the browser is the only entity that
knows the state of your socket pulse
uh so it if if it knows whether you have
h2 or h3 that means uh
uh it will find the appropriate socket
and
opens the session on that yeah yeah um
i guess my point was that uh if you pick
the
new approach number one there's
potentially a fallback
involved that requires new api surface
of some
shape there is a potential
for new api to add
more control over what exactly happens
uh but the basic point i'm trying to
make
is uh that there is still it's still
much easier conceptually because you can
just
this is now just a knob you tweak
instead of like completely different
uh things that require completely
different code paths
good good thank you thank you uh
next slide
uh so just to clarify conceptually the
difference so
this is uh this is the first
the very first this is how it looked
before
and on the next slide you can see that
uh
thanks to this uh there is one less box
and actually one less arrow is what's
more important because
a lot of implementation expense here is
uh crossing
the sandbox boundary uh
next slide
so uh here is so i've made repeatedly
the observations
that as i've
uh as we've refactored more and more
both quick transport and each free
transport they become more and more
similar semantically and at this point
i am there is some debate to this but at
this point i am basically convinced that
http free transport exists primarily as
quick transport with uh connection
pooling
uh and that kind of makes sense because
if you think about it there
is no really substantial difference for
them to be
different entities uh next slide
so one of the ideas i had is uh
we have quick transport and http free
transport
uh but uh
we could uh so currently we
disambigate in by scheme but it
is actually like that's a choice made by
client and that makes them semantically
different
but we can also even delegate that
decision to the server
by uh offering
both http free as and web transport as a
lpn
so if you just want a quick transport
you just offer a quick transport and
then it will
offer both of those and you get quick
transport and
that is perfectly simple from the server
perspective
and if you want http free transport if
there is an existing socket and
existing http free connection in the
socket poll that supports that
you will get http free transport on that
http free connection uh alternatively it
will
establish that connection a new to that
server
and uh i
the reason i like this is that this
allows us to make progress
uh without making any assumption of
uh what we're actually uh what
transports we're actually using
but i do believe uh
uh we still should make progress on that
because
this this this is logical but
we still should actually decide which
transfer we're shipping
uh next slide
uh okay so uh i
have uh my observation here
so speaking of path forward
uh i am basically at this point
convinced
that uh the question is not like which
one of those we want but
uh should we implement http free
transport and is it worth it and let me
elaborate on that now that you've
imp now that we've implemented uh
like once you implement the top layer
which is uh like the web api
and the middle layer which is your the
things that crosses your sandbox
boundary and make sure
that flow control etc is preserved
now the only there's a bottom layer
which is a protocol which is the only
parts that's different between those two
but
if you're implementing http free
transfers the measure
marginal cost of implementing quick
transport for both
web browser and even the server but
web browser is the only one which really
has to ship both
uh is a fairly minimal the google
implementation is 2 000 lines of c plus
plus
and that's not that much that's at least
10 times less than
our http stack that's approximately
five times less than just a file that
decodes all of the quick frames
uh it is very little code comparatively
and those 2000 clients includes the
integration test uh and the unit tests
obviously
and the reason i believe that quick
transport is particularly appealing
is that if you think of the other
elements in the ecosystem as http 2 as
http free
uh quick transport is kind of http one
of web transport because it is the
simplest thing that can
work uh and it is sufficient
and optimal for a lot of cases for
instance
if you're doing video streaming and you
have a dedicated server you connect to
and you do not have any form of pulling
that you care about you will probably
want to have a quick transport and
that's
as that is what luke mentioned and
this is also true for instance for
youtube youtube does not use http 2
for video serving it always uses http 1
because http 2 is just a necessary
overhead
that it doesn't benefit from uh so
that's
uh one example and
so the main the two main questions are
do we want right pulling and do we want
to provide tcp fall back now before
we go in depth into the stew and like in
the discussion i kind of want to give my
perspective
uh my personal feeling about one is yes
so
i will know that this is hard and the
reason is that we
as we've observed every sufficiently
advanced protocol
eventually evolves into supporting
pulling http does that
websocket does that even though there
are some obstacles to shipping that
so this is like an incremental step
uh number two the reason i believe tcp
fallback would be good is not that it is
of immediate use to
everyone who uses web transport right
who would immediately adopt web
transport right now
because if you're adopting web transport
right now you're probably
someone who has a lot of resources to
experiment
and you probably have an existing
solution which works over tcp so you
would not want to
replace that now the reason if you're
building a solution from
a new i believe that web transport will
be
widespread much earlier then
we will get rid of all udp blocking
which is i believe we will probably
never get rid of
because i do not see firewalls and
enterprise policies ever going away
so i believe there will be demand for
solutions that
are architected from completely a new
uh to support
automatic fallback and
this is a
this is not something we might benefit
immediately
from the immediate users we've talked to
but this is definitely something that
makes sense long-term
uh that is my perspective and i would
now like to
get into discussion
um all right thanks victor actually
maybe go go back one slide bernards as
we that way we can still have the
questions on the screen uh so yes folks
uh please join the queue now and alan
you're up first
uh okay so the i mean i think the
question i want to highlight is that
pooling can mean two different things
one of them is
i can pool multiple
like web transport uris together in the
same connection as i was talking about
the other one is can i pool web
transport on the same
connection as my http traffic and
they're
kind of two separate questions right
quick transport as it's currently
defined will never let you do the one
where you
can stick it on with your http
connection you'll always need a second
connection
um and i think personally that there are
i want to speak to pooling web transport
with http together
um because it has some distinct
advantages uh
so all of that traffic will end up
sharing the same congestion controller
the streams on that
connection can be prioritized with
respect to each other
and there is some non-zero amount
of server-side cost uh for having
connections so uh if i'm
doing something in uh as a client and i
have an http connection and then all of
a sudden i want a web transport
connection
uh i don't have to have two connections
i can just keep using the one that i
already have
that's all
uh okay eric
i like the framing that you've got here
for
uh how can we kind of unify this down
into
an api that is just i'm doing web
transport and i'm not trying to pick up
front
i think in a lot of other areas we talk
a lot about expressing the properties
that we need from the transport and
having it
do the right thing in terms of providing
you those properties we saw
i think was bernard's table uh of the
different use cases
you know some of them said i need
unidirectional some of them said i need
bi-directional some of them said i need
ordering some of them said i need
unordered um and then there's a whole
set of things that
uh are perfectly fine if you don't have
uh unordered or unreliable data um those
being distinct items
uh some of them are you know i am not
willing to even consider
having this conversation with whoever's
on the other end if i can't have x thing
that i believe is critical
um and so i think having a having an api
that we can use to
express that spectrum of need from
i'd really like this to i'm not even
willing to show up to the table if i
don't have it
uh is potentially of value
i'm not totally sure that we can distill
all of that down into just
do we want pooling in his tcp fallback
necessary but i think
if we can focus in on um
how does someone as a consumer of this
api interact
with uh what they need and how do they
then
use what they get back from it um
we're probably going to be in good shape
because
some of the concerns around is somebody
going to implement x versus
y seems a little bit like they have to
do
you know amount of work something
uh and so it's not super clear to me
that that's a
that trying to guess it at what people
are willing to support
is as useful of a benchmark as
the what properties do we get from these
transports and which ones
do we need and which ones can we do
without
look i think you're next
uh hello again um so
in regards to pulling connections um
i do want to at least talk about what
situations that would be useful
um as it would actually improve the
experience for connection pooling
uh and in my mind you get you share the
congest control
um uh calculations which is great um
but you kind of need to have two
connections to the same host
that max you know that that uh both of
them need to transfer a lot of data
as well for that to even be a benefit so
you kind of have this
case where you have two uh you know tran
web uh web transport connections of the
same host or
and they're both using a lot of data or
you need to have an hdb connection and a
transport connection again using a lot
of data otherwise quick does a pretty
good job of connection pooling
um you can use the same socket you know
zero rtt if you wanted to make a new
connection
um i'm just failing to see the use case
as which
pooling is actually um an improvement
over
dialing a new uh connection um
so that's that's at least my feedback in
there and for number two
tcp fallback um i think the problem is
that the
web transfer api is the same for all the
transports but the functionality is not
the same
as in we may you might get that nice
like pretending like we're using
datagrams for pretending like you're
using you know
multiplex streams but if you're actually
under the hood
you have head of blind blocking because
using tcp
there's no point like i mean it's nice
it it
encourages adoption if you can have the
same api
um but it would be something that for
example i would explicitly try and
disable i would not want tcp because
that would just ruin my application
i would need to disable that
functionality for that fallback
okay by the way can yeah someone hear me
we can hear you okay because i've been
doing cue management for a while and i
realized
that no one was hearing me so grumpf
uh okay so i had to reconnect audio and
we're back all right thanks a lot luke
uh victor you're in the queue apparently
uh yeah i had to i
yes i wanted to say something i have
first
to regarding to looks remark it it is in
fact the case that we do need
to add a knob to api to express last
something like
i only want quick or i don't care if i
get
quick or tcp or i want quicker tcp but i
want to know which one i'm using
uh and there i do
agree with that now my remark is
another aspect of http i
forgot that i realized long time ago
is that http is due to metadata
is more amenable to intermediation
namely things about think about aspects
like priority
you can in http provides you with a way
to communicate priorities of your
individual streams but
uh that's not something you can do on
real quick because real quick has no way
to communicate that kind of metadata
and all of that metadata is just an
api call uh that's
an example of another consideration that
i think that was mentioned sometime
long ago but i forgot uh anyway uh
that's my remark
martin it takes a little while to come
through
um so victor's point there about uh
priority
is an interesting one but i don't think
it's particularly relevant here
um because you're not going to be able
to use the http level signaling
to get priority signals back and forth
and
quick has priority or any quick
implementation should have priority
anyway
and it's just a question of how you're
signaling it i was going to get back to
the intermediation
question though because alan made a
couple of points about
mixing these in with http and
i wanted to ask alan who when he gets to
his
point in the queue can answer
what specific benefits are you looking
to have
because my experience with at least
websockets has been that
they tend to be terminated by different
machines that deal with different
sort of services and how
how do you imagine the relationship
between the the http that's going on the
same connection and the
quick that's and the sorry the web
transport streams that are going on the
same connection
to be such that you're gaining benefits
from that i can see how you might
benefit from that a congestion
controller
being aware of um the current
path state but i can't see very many
ways in which the
the co-hosting of the same two things
can can be of benefit
and there's um uh yeah the other thing
was
victor pointed out the um
intermediation point and i think it's a
really important one
we saw with web transport that not a lot
of intermediation goes on because
it is there's no application level
semantics being expressed in these
protocols
there's no generic functionality that an
intermediary can
hook into to provide value so they tend
to be just dumb
connections back to back end servers
and with no value added by an
intermediary no extra load balancing
capabilities
what have you so i i am sort of strongly
now leaning toward the non-pooled case
in fact
but i'm very much still of the view that
only one
is necessary of the quick options
makes sense daniel
uh you're muted
muted i'll be brief because this has
been touched on twice already in the
queue
i was just going to say that you know as
far as the api goes you
absolutely have to be able to inform
the the caller of what the heck what the
heck we did
like i can't just if they if they ask
for quick i can't just switch to tcp
they have to know
i mean the the principle of least
surprise
am i still hello
my screen just went oh okay
yeah uh um that's all i wanted to say so
i wanted to to
not only second second the idea of of
informing the
the user um through the api but also say
that
very emphatically in support of it thank
you
cheers thanks ecker
um so with regard to both these points i
think
um i agree with martin that like there
should be one quick transport
um um i've got back up back and forth
with a fair bit or there should be um
h3 or quick um i sort of read victor's
uh victor's met under the mailing list
about how quick was growing more like h3
kind of confused me frankly
um because it seems like maybe they're
the same thing um
um so i mean i guess i am also trying to
figure out what pulling means
and not saying a lot here on benefit
there um i'm not sure that
but i'm not sure that actually dictates
the question of which which which uh um
uh we which quick base transport we
should have
um you know i think it's really quite
disappointing that we're going to end up
apparently with mask
um having um being based on http plus
datagrams
and the web transport based on some
other thing that seems like kind of like
really ideal to figure out like if you
want to push data raw datagrams over uh
over quick um to http servers um whether
you should do that with these
what kind of transfer that should look
like um seems like really something i
want to be able to do
and i remember as i recall the time when
mask
and in fact rick proposed there's a
bunch of discussion about how it might
be should ought to be in principle
possible
to implement them entirely in javascript
using facilities offered by the browser
that obviously will not be the case
if we um if mask is specified on http
and
quick and web transfer specifies quick
transport so
um i do think like that there should be
only one but like that the scope of
there should be only one probably like
it's like somewhat wider than this
working group
um on the topic of tcp fallback um i i
certainly agree with what i've heard
it's a number of times which we need to
um
uh notify people we there's some knob of
some kind to let people control slash
notify
whether they have tcp or not um i do
think sometimes people are necessary all
the data shows
that um you don't you don't reliably get
um ddp transport through like a like a
large
large number of connections and many of
these connections although they have
inferior performance if they have tcp
um still can do acceptable performance
of various things over tcp
um and so um you know
if you want people to if you think part
if you think part of the problem
with you know as i think people do with
websockets is the api stank
and you'd like people to have one api
that having forced them to switch it
between web sockets and web transport
when they really wanted to go like a
datagram extraction that kind of works
um seems like really kind of a bad
choice so i do think we need to pee
um and i'd better think we maybe you
turn it off or or be sad if you got it
thanks ecker uh eric kinnear i saw that
you were at the top of the queue and
you're not at the bottom like
was that a mistake or did you
intentionally go down
uh i removed one comment and had a
different one so let's keep going and
we'll come back
cool sounds good uh alan
so um to address martin's question um
so i mean i think one of the primary
drivers is scale
so um you know so i work at facebook
and uh we that you know
basically every phone has in the world
has a connection to facebook it's
probably an exaggeration
but there's lots of them um and
we do http stuff right there's lots of
reasons why there should be an http
connection
from every app but then
there are also non-http use cases uh
that are going to go to the same place
particularly
sort of more published subscribe based
models
um or notification real time things
there's obviously ways to kind of clue
to that with http but
we get a lot of asks from people who are
trying to develop these abstractions
and so now we're faced with okay well
we're gonna have one
http connection from every phone and now
we're also gonna have a
web transport connection or if we don't
have any ability to pool
multiple web transport uris into the
same connection
we're gonna have one web transport
connection for potentially every
user of web transport um
which is just not really gonna work um
you know these things are all
end up getting terminated at one place
and in terms of what intermediation or a
proxy can do there it's not doing very
much but it is
routing right so you might have you know
some uses on the phone which are
being terminated in edge pop and those
web transport use cases are being
grounded to a data center
where that service is running but other
web transport uis are being routed to
other data centers
um off the same connection to the pop so
that and
in terms of okay well you guys have your
own app why don't you just write your
own extension
and why are you bothering the ietf with
this use case which maybe is only
specific for you um you know there's
more and more push to use native stacks
and so this we're a little bit out of
the web context of web transport but
since we're
talking about a protocol here um
you know we for example like we would
love there's there are lightweight apps
that would like to not use our http
stack but want to use the native stack
or they want to use a thinner
stack than the one that we've developed
and it's very challenging if there's not
a standard way
to do this kind of thing over an http
connection to to get that implementation
happening
uh in other contexts and there's also
you know then we have the same thing of
all those products that run in apps also
we're going to run the web
and the web developers are don't want to
or the people who are developing that
code don't want to know like oh
i have to write it one way in the app
but then i have a totally different
protocol or way i handle things
when i'm running in a browser context
okay so it's got a long-winded answer
but i think i covered it
uh jonah
thank you uh can you hear see me
hear you you've pressed the camera
button but i
i'm seeing like a red thing where it's
failing to come through but at least we
can hear you
as long as you can hear me
um so alan's making me think about this
but uh so i i came up this i'll say i'll
say what i can represent
and also see what talent's making me
think about
so some others have also noted this on
the jabber chat but
i just want to generally draw gently
draw
attention to the fact that this i fear
that this might be trying to do too many
things
at the same time and in doing that it
does seem a little bit
like taps and that scares me
partly because that's that's uh
when when something's not driven very
strongly by one application
that tends to have a flavor of trying to
satisfy a lot of requirements
so with that i'll ask the ques i want to
ask the question of how many of these
are actually use cases
that are currently uh in play how many
people want to use which particular use
cases the question i would ask
now i i came up to say this sounds like
if we wanted to be an evolution of
websockets then
quick transport seems like a good step
forward
with a backup as something like web
sockets it would have
be easier to see this as an evolution in
that sense
but um and and therefore i would answer
the questions that you have there as
well maybe pulling connections is not
that much worth it and tcp
fallback i would say in general uh you
definitely want tcp fallback if you want
whatever api
you are using to basically work all the
time it's because we can't assume that
quick will work all the time um
but yeah uh alan allen is uh ireland
has made a good point that there are
cases and in fact he's
strongly suggesting that it might be
necessary to pool connections
um in which case then i would ask is
quick transport necessary
should we just go to http 3 transport
thanks jana bernard
or yeah go ahead uh
janna asked some question and i'm trying
to remember what was the very question
at the beginning
oh the question was are there use cases
that are for each of those and my answer
is
i believe that for each of the proposed
uh transfers there is at least one uh
person who is like
actively interested in it existing which
is why those web transports
uh which why we defined all of those in
first place
uh but that's my answer anyway bernard
okay um yeah i wanted to
follow up on what alan said uh because
i'm hearing some of the same things that
um there is a desire to pool http with
web transport
and i uh and not just web
transports with each other but but it
pooling them together
some of the scenarios i've heard if you
think about it
it's both for the scalability which
allen mentioned um also the traversal
issues just just to have everything go
over the same
connection but also because i think
there's
a desire to significantly extend the web
so that you have not just uh
request responses that are reliable but
can also get datagrams
um coming back now
so in some ways with what they're
looking for is an entirely new web
ecosystem
that supports datagrams kind of natively
as part of as part
naturally as part of the web um it is a
big ask because you're essentially
you want all of this you want web
transfer to work with http 3
to work with masks so it's kind of like
an entirely new ecosystem so it's a very
big bet
um you know and there are many many ways
in which that that could fail if pieces
of it
don't work together um but that's
that's kind of what i hear is that is
that there's a
they would see that if you could make
everything work and get the pooling of
both that would be the biggest win
it's also probably the hardest thing to
actually make work
um which is the tricky part because when
you know i've gotten into trying to
figure out what would be needed to do it
it
does seem like there are a lot of moving
parts but it is
it is a big win if you can make it all
work
yeah i would second a lot of what i
think
ecker was saying uh which is that
i think it is it is very important that
we end up with just one thing
um but i think if we want to be able to
deploy this stuff
everywhere we're going to need something
for the cases where
quick isn't getting through and and we
know we have that
for web pages that are using http
uh because we can fall back to h1 and h2
um but we haven't defined what you do
for
the rest of the things that use quick
as a transport without http and i was
uh really excited when we when we were
doing
quick and separating out the kind of
multiplexed streaming
side of things from the http semantics
side of things
uh but i think either we need to hop on
the hdp bandwagon and use that to go
across everything
or uh and i i say this not particularly
caring
uh what we end up with as long as we
meet those needs
or we go with some of the kind of
fallback transport style thing which i
think
victor had in the other section of that
grid
of options but i think we need we need
some way
both for web transport and potentially
even
just in the you know rest of quick and
the other use cases for quick
to be able to have that fall back either
it seems like we end up pushing
everything that needs that fall back up
to h3 and then
you know kind of side going sideways
stage two
or we need to define something that
allows us to do that kind of
uh uni bi-directional stream
multiplexing
uh over something that does traverse the
corners of the internet where quick
doesn't
um and and we can do that without http
and that would be great
but it does seem as though some sort of
a fallback is necessary
thanks eric um so
to try to get us to converge a little
bit
here and uh i'm
i guess speaking as chair trying to
formulate the consensus that's emerging
but please feel free to speak up if you
think i'm getting it wrong
i'm getting a sense from the room that
most of the folks who have spoken up
agree that of at least
if we look at the quick base transport
so quick transform http 3 transport i
think we have consensus that we only
need one of the two
um i like is the
main sense i'm getting from most people
in the room uh then
if that's the case and we need to pick
one
uh let's tease apart what proper
what are the pros and cons of each and
the main ones i'm seeing and please jump
into the qtad
more is h3 transport
allows pooling so what that means
is if you you know you you
sorry what just just a point of order
maybe we could get consensus on that
point you just made about there should
be only one
and then we can move on from there
because i think that i think that
yeah actually that's so that's a very
good idea uh thanks hecker um
yeah uh bernard does that sound good uh
to try to do a hum about the
of specifically quick transport and b3
transport if people agree that we there
should only be one
you're muted bernard
i'm going to assume yes so we tested out
this
uh virtual hum
tool at the beginning of the session and
it seemed to work so
let me type in the question
victor says he has a question before the
hum
uh go right uh speak up victor
i wanted to ask specifically ecker and
martin
since they repeat as his point why do
you believe that there should be only
one
um okay uh martin recker if one of you
two wants to
speak up uh about this
i would have thought the burden of proof
is on people asking for two
um i want fewer things and
i don't necessarily see that we need
the complexity unless until the
complexity is justified
i haven't seen any real justification
for the complexity
thanks yeah now that that makes sense
like at the end of the day
um our job as you know writing itf
protocols is
generally not to make the biggest buffet
available is to
try to find one thing that works i i
think i'm from a personal level not as
chair really in agreement with martin on
that one
um david um
if you don't mind um i think
that there's been a parallel
conversation going on on the on the on
this
on the channel chat channel
and you might want to hear out what
philip has to offer he's been in the
queue
just because it's it might help people
make up their minds the idea here is to
offer an alternative way of doing
pooling without having to do http 3 this
would be mask
and quick transfer right i'm just
suggesting that
before you ask the question it might be
helpful for people to consider that as
well
okay um philip if you want to jump in
and make your case go ahead
hi so um i
when we had the discussion about whether
we want pooling or not
um i came with the idea that we can
implement part of the pooling
just by adding mask beneath web
transports
so with this you'll have don't have to
care about another
layer of hole punching or session setup
because you can
just reuse the http three session you
used
um and then piggyback on this session
with
mask all the web transport streams you
need within a pool
you could also try to add some kind of
prioritization
uh of fate sharing within this
and so you could get away with pooling
at this layer
and still having the simple um
quick transport uh semantics beneath
also this
if you have a multiplexed use case where
if a load balancer
only this you load balancer needs to
talk http 3
and you can get the much easier quick
transport
at the back end systems so this would be
a compromise of both designs
without having to define those protocols
at the web transport level
thanks philip so to add to the context
as uh
someone who is enthusiastic about mask
uh so that that would definitely work it
would involve double encryption
for um for quick and on top of that it
would also like require browsers to
implement mask which well
i'm okay with but i'm not sure if
everyone is but that's definitely an
alternate
view as well but um thanks uh we're
we're 10 minutes to time so i'm gonna
switch now to the
um to the to the hum so the
and of course because i switched away
forgot what i typed
thank you but so here's the question um
the um the tool is going to say
do you want to raise your hand or not uh
and so if you
raise your hand it means there should
only be one
if you do not it means you think we
should do both
so all right i clicked the button so
if if you believe we should only do one
of quick transport entry transport click
raise your hand
now if you think we should do both click
do not raise your hand
here click do not now right here i'm
done
disappear before i go to click it oh
sorry i messed up i pressed the wrong of
the button again
uh let me let me restart it i apologize
people
i'm nice thank you all right uh
yeah the the button from the cherished
perspective
looks like a confirm your choice when it
means just
stop everyone else from voting which is
really what not what i was trying to do
apologies everyone
um all right let's all let it sit for
for a bit um
but i think the intention actually was
to ask two questions if you want to have
one or the other
right now the question is if you think
we should only have one
raise your hand if you think we should
do both do not raise your hand
what i'm saying is if you think we
should we should do both should be a
separate
question or separate show hands or
whatever that was the intention but it's
fine
i'm not sure i understand maria but
maybe we can take it offline
because you could ask both the questions
and then you could just say
people could just not raise their hand
for any question indicating that they
don't care whatever that's why you
should ask two separate questions but
anyway
i see that that sounds like it would
take longer though
but normal by not doing anything yeah
all right uh i'm going to end it now in
the next
10 seconds if you haven't voted go right
ahead
all right um
so then i i guess
in the i'm not so i i i see the numbers
i don't know if everyone else
does i don't know if i'm supposed to
share them in the spirit of the hums
um you can see them all right well then
so it was 19
19 raised your hand and 10 do not raise
your hand so
let's say two-thirds one-third so not a
clear
absolute consensus that's for sure
um victor you want to say something
yeah i actually have the proposal that i
believe
with which i want to believe which would
allow us to move ahead
and i i want to first reply to my ideas
of why i did not raise my hand
and if you don't mind that can i
sure but make it quick because we have
five minutes left so my basic logic
is that there can the argument for
is that when our web developers who have
different
uh opinions on the pulling slash
complexity tradeoff
and argument against are we should not
define too many sayings
and that's too many things to implement
for browser and the reason i'm leaning
towards
argument 4 is that i personally and i'm
not sure if there are ietf documents but
i
personally trying to favor uh problems
of web developers
against concerns of browser implementers
or theoretical people
now my specific proposal is that we
adopt quick transport as a starting
point because it sounds that it
satisfies at least some use cases for
everyone
but we do not preclude adoption of http
transport in case we decide that the
working group
in case there is a practical experience
that shows it's beneficial and the
working group has resources
to ship that draft that way
it's kind of we are learning to walk
before we're learning to run
that is my opinion um
ecker do you have a is that a response
specific to this
however the chairs won uh or i'm asking
are you gonna respond directly to what
victor is saying or do something yes i
was
i was go ahead okay um yeah i guess i
would not be in favor of that proposal
um because that seems to bake in quick
transport and then have a high priority
we'll end up doing both
so i think like we've i think we are
getting close to having the information
we need to make a decision and if we're
not we should induce that information
and make a decision rather than
rather than deciding on one would like
them maybe we'll adopt another later
so thanks thanks uh ecker um
so i'm thinking so it sounds like
there's a majority of folks who
would prefer to only do one and
one of the interesting things here is
that we're
we're not time-bound so my
gut tells me that maybe we should pick
one
to start only adopt one of the two for
now
and we can always adopt a second one
down the road
that sounds like something where i am
yes effectively kicking the can down the
road but at least
we it allows us to pick one for now and
to focus on one
for now so we can actually like get
going and adopt one and
like start you know interop testing as
opposed to only having chrome
implement this um do folks have thoughts
on this proposal
and i'm realizing we're getting really
short on time so
please keep your your comments as short
as possible alan go ahead
okay i i think i just wanted a second
what ecker said which is that
uh if we if we're adopting quick
transport
now and there's it just creates a high
bar
to adopt a degree when it sounds like
there is consistent about which
direction we're going
i mean i really view h3 as a superset of
what quick transport can do
and you know you don't have to use the
features that you're not using
or that you don't want to so i just
don't think that adopting quick
transport right now is
what i've been favoring okay
thanks alan erkinear
that i think there's a there's a risk
here i don't necessarily
care as much about which one we pick
although i think we do have a set of
needs that we need to fulfill
but i i think going with one and then
telling ourselves that we're maybe gonna
go with the other uh
it would be really unfortunate if we
ended up in a place where we're trying
to get a
the earliest implementers of everybody
to actually interrupt
and we find out that you know half of
people do one and half of people ended
up having to do the other because they
needed some
thing that wasn't available in the first
one
okay um uh all right
i hear you back in the queue if yes
please 30 seconds because we're almost
at time
and then i'm cutting the queue
um so yeah i mean i think i i'm happy
for us to choose one
but i think we should choose one of the
pieces that's the one we want and
then yes we could always add one later
but i think we should choose one the
theory that we're like just getting
experience we should choose the one we
think is the right one um so i guess i'm
saying like i don't think we should
shortcut that discussion i think we try
to decide it
oh no absolutely and i wasn't proposing
to pick anyone in particular i was
saying that we should
pick one and but clearly we're not going
to pick one in the room today because
we're out of time
the uh the av issues did really
hurt our flow here which is unfortunate
um
so uh we're we're at time on the session
we
did not come to a resolution on
getting out of the transport zoo i
sincerely apologize as chair for that
um but we will do better i i'm thinking
that
we should need to accelerate this
because uh having
progress happen every four months at atf
is not good enough
so i'm thinking that an interim might be
a good idea here
in the near future so we can try to hash
out so like
maybe get all this discussion happening
on the list and then have another
like interim meeting sometime in the not
too distant future to really try to
drive this home
i would really love us to like get to a
point where we can
pick some number of the protocols to
adopt them in the working group so we
can actually
move from zoo visiting to protocol
design
on that note we are exactly at time
thanks to
all our presenters and to everyone who
took the time to attend especially
folks who are in unpleasant time zones
so
thanks everyone and uh bernard you have
any closing statements
uh no just we will set up the interim uh
scheduling requests and get going
all right thanks everyone and enjoy the
rest of your day or night
cheers take care everybody and remember
nobody escapes from the transport zoo
that easily
we'll get out of there someday we will i
promise you that
keep the faith thanks guys
cheers