uh welcome everyone i think the others
will just
tag along uh as we start
uh but yes welcome my name is melody
patri
i am advocacy director at accessnow and
i've been working on the keep it on
campaign
even before actually i worked at access
now so i'm
really honored to start this press
briefing and to
have this conversation today discussing
um
the internet and elections or actually
the lack of internet during elections
which
unfortunately seemed to seem to become a
trend
so i'm here today with
my colleague felicia antonio
who is the lead uh who is coordinating
the keep it on campaign
a lot of you have maybe uh have uh
have heard her via the kill switch
podcasts
which we will be uh linking as part of
the resources that are available
um and then of course we have great
speakers
today who will be available to answer
questions and they will be introducing
themselves and
say a couple of remarks in a minute
but just as we're starting i wanted to
put a bit of context
into the reason why we're having this
press briefing because
at some point i was having a bit of a
deja vu and
um last year we had another press
briefing
also on internets shutdowns and
elections
and unfortunately the reason why we have
another one
this year with a similar uh
theme is because what was last year
let's say like the premises and the
beginning trend
is turning into a real concern that we
have for democracy
we've been able to identify new patterns
uh when it comes to internet shutdowns
and election
and by internet shutdowns we refer to
like complete internet blackouts or kill
switch which is when
governments completely pull the plug and
disconnect
the country but also to um when
platforms of being censored especially
communications platform and information
sharing platforms such as twitter
facebook
messaging platforms like whatsapp signal
or facebook messenger and so on so um
the the trends are moving the the
environment
is really moving when it comes to
elections and shutdown
this year we counted 50 incidents of uh
internet disruption since the bits since
the beginning of the year so in the past
five six months really and a few of them
of course
uh occurred during elections that was
the case in uganda
we heard about congo
so they were it is a it is a concern
and so i really want to make sure that
we have the space
to discuss um many concerns but also
challenges and if we have them
solutions uh if you have specific
questions for
our speakers uh they will present
themselves and you will know exactly
their
area of expertise as we have a few
elections coming up
so it will be really relevant to hear
from them and to also feel
prepared we actually launched
a handbook on elections and shutdown
destined specifically for reporters
uh covering elections and for um
elections monitors so that's another
resource that we'll be
sharing with you all and i think that's
it in terms of housekeeping
uh this press conference is recorded
so you know like uh although we're not
all in a room but just consider that
it's re
it's recorded and uh the the question
and the answers
will be publicly available afterwards
so if there is something maybe like
sensitive that you would not want
uh to be shared publicly uh please
be mindful that this is recorded and
that there are other opportunities to
also
connect uh with the speakers and with
access now
so without further ado i'm just gonna
hand over to my colleague felicia if she
has extra words and then we can
immediately kick off with our great
speakers and the questions that
i hope you all have
yes thank you very much melody and
welcome everyone
um quickly as melody said
this will be recorded and we have our
friends from the media
um joining us so if you have questions
uh you have the option to turn on your
camera and meet your mic
and speak um if you're doing that please
introduce yourself and your organization
or affiliation and then
you can also use the chat button but we
encourage you to use the video and
mic so that um the session is
interactive
um as we go on so
i would quickly ask uh um
speakers uh who have made time to join
us
to quickly take two to three minutes to
introduce themselves
um so you tell us your name organization
and the current state of internet
shutdowns in wherever you are speaking
from
all right so i would hand over to amir
to kick start hello everyone
uh uh i'm
uh thank you very much the uh
organization
accessnow and everyone who participated
to this first conference
uh my name is amy rashid i'm the
director of internet security and
digital rights admin group new york
based organization
human rights organization we are working
on
a violation of human rights and
definitely access to the internet is a
rights for everyone and we're trying to
basically
monitor the situation of internet in
iran from the perspective of
connectivity
to uh cyber attack and provide as much
as we can support for the civil society
and activists
people who are at the risk and
uh minority uh ethnic minorities
inside the country uh the current state
of internet
the last internet shutdown we had was in
february 2001
uh in province of syston and balochistan
for
three days uh internet mobile data
only mobile data
was shut down and uh
almost every single year we have we have
it shut down in in iran
and yeah i think for now that's it we
can we can we can go over the
details uh later
all right thank you i'll move to
richard and one of our particip speakers
is here to join us
so hopefully should be able to make it
through so i will move to richard
to introduce himself
thank you very much felicia and
greetings to everyone in the meeting
i will uh beg that uh i keep my video
off
uh so that i can leverage the bandwidth
uh because i'm
out of town you know in zambia the fact
that you move away from the
capital city the the quality of internet
also deteriorates
so to avoid that disruption uh i will
beg that maybe i can just um
speak without the camera actually i had
to drive a few uh kilometers
to access the network i'm actually doing
this from
from from the car that we are using you
know so
i will um i would like to do that so but
anyway
uh my name is mulanga richard i'm the
team leader at
bloggers of zambia we are a
growing enterprise in zambia our work is
primarily focused on three pillars
internet governance and digital rights
media rights and freedoms and then
online
creative content and platform management
so
do our work through campaigning advocacy
trainings and just everything that just
influences
law and policy everything that draws
attention to
what we think must be done about uh
making the internet accessible you know
affordable and
to keep it on to keep the the internet
on during all this time um
example we haven't had uh
an internet shutdown we shall say we
usually put the word yet
at the end because we are going towards
an election
and the internet in zambia has become
a very special area of interest by the
state
so they are weaponizing the narrative
that
zambians are abusing social media
platforms like facebook and twitter
where they are insulting and criticizing
government leaders
and so they have come up with a cyber
security and cyber crimes act that has
got
several provisions that are parallel to
the constitution
and other subsidiary laws like article
18 of the constitution that guarantees
and protects freedom of expression and
article 17 of the constitution that
guarantees and protects the right to
to assembly so there are also public
order laws
like the public order act the ngo act
that are used you know in the physical
space to
just tie for people's assembly and all
that so as we go towards an election
we expect the cyber security and cyber
crimes act actually to be used
to shut down the internet
because we have seen examples are used
like uganda zimbabwe
and look what is happening there so
sometimes you think it is
to maintain public order and hygiene and
it's better to switch off the internet
so it's shut down but in the past we
have had um
like internet uh uh jamming filtering
and website blockages like we have the
xamarin watchdog that's really great for
the government so
we wouldn't accept the access the
website because our service providers
have been asked to
to what to do to block the access
so that is that is um the the synopsis
where we are and i will just pass the
button back to felicia
thank you very much um so we um as
speakers
are from countries that are having
elections um this year or have already
had elections
um in 2021 and we're trying to
see how we can strengthen our advocacy
on international terms and elections
and so i would call on harold
to introduce himself
thanks felicia uh you heard me
okay thanks
specialist of cyber governors
organization
and president of internet society
benefit
so thank you for this opportunity
uh to talk about international
and what we're going to fight
so my organization is up
i stopped being a national chapter of
indiana society
and uh how a cradle is and remains
uh two different and open internet
globally connects accessible and secure
for
all and uh evening we are done
different things created freedom full
project and action
with height impact so
uh our last action
is to document all major events
to internet as experienced in our
country
full publication of the book of
the history of internet in benin
from starting to present
sorry and
i'm making transition to for this
sentence to
conserve
many relatively stable periods uh
in terms of international uh
censorship of internet sales
we have experience uh experienced a
period of
censorship large enquiries we were
in internet access costs due to
over retest
from social networks and it completed
down
in during the parliamentary
election in april
2018 so it's easier
guessing on a traditional i can come
back
to explain
another
yesterday um yes definitely thank you
very much
um all right so i would call on marie
marianne my colleague to introduce
herself
because she'll be stepping in while we
wait for
one of our speakers to join so marianne
yes hi um
[Music]
i am marian diaz i am a researcher from
venezuela
currently living in chile and
i have been working on several issues
regarding
censorship and human rights and
basically the whole spectrum of human
rights online
for a decade now and every time i say
that i feel very very old
but right now i'm working keep it on um
on shutdowns and internet disruptions
and it is a very
important year for us in latin america
because we have elections
all across the region
venezuela itself has
mega elections at the end of the of the
year
is what we call mega elections means
that we
get to choose i can't vote but we get to
choose
um different stages of
government chile relief has
two lf big elections this year
and we also have elections in nicaragua
we just have peru
um honduras and the different
kind of democracies across the region
make it um very different in the
circumstances
of the uh a blockbuster and a general
internet blackout
of or or internet censorship of certain
size
can occur so it's very different for
instance
what might happen right now in colombia
with the protest
or to what can happen in chile or in
uruguay
and so we need to be very very aware
about what
a main trend that i would like to
highlight
is the the use
of inter infrastructural failure
to disconnect regions entire regions or
towns or cities
or even the whole country that has
happened
in cuba a few times
which is extremely hard to track
extremely hard to
attribute and for us is
a really big challenge that we need to
be aware that it's going to be happening
more and more in the coming
year or so
thank you very much marianne um for
um stepping in to speak on what's
happening
in latin america um before we dive into
the
questions or the discussion properly i
want to remind
our participants that you have the
option to ask questions
and contribute to the discussion so you
can use the
raise hand chat button
and we'll be i'm happy to call you to
speak
and then um for the speakers also we
will be taking
screenshots that is okay with you in
order to promote
um the session the session after
we upload it on um we make it public
so please take note all right i'm
handing over to melody to kickstart
sure so as you saw we've got
representation
from various regions various continents
around the world because
one of the conclusions that we were
already able to draw
after a few years of doing this
campaigning and doing research related
to
the keep it on campaign is that no one
is no one is excluded
to be fair unfortunately
every region has been concerned by
internet showdowns during election
and so a first question that is quite
broad and general but to keep us started
and maybe to put
everyone on um to give like background
context to everyone is that
we've noticed that governments
have used uh international dance in a
way or another whether it's
as we said like a total shutdowns or
just like a
a targeted one or the targeting of
specific platforms
they've been doing this just before
during
and or after elections so to all of our
speakers my question is
why do you think that government
governments are so quick
to hit the kill switch during these
important national events
what are they afraid of what reason did
they give
how how did they match reality
okay richard go ahead so
in our case um our from our experience
why the internet remains targeted
uh is because the our government would
like to
control our freedom
they would like to control
our our freedom of expression
uh assembly and association on the
internet
that we should be limited in what we can
do with the internet with regard to
speaking truth to power um
ensuring that this transparency and
accountability you scrutinize those that
are in leadership
who scrutinize those that want to
that are vying for political office
because
people use the traditional media but it
is so gagged
and the censorship and certain critical
voices actually
the civil society and journalists the
radio stations here
are closed without reason journalists
are beaten when they
write critical pieces some media houses
actually attacked on
live phone ins because of what they said
or who they are hosting
for as a result everyone is going to the
internet that is open and inclusive and
participatory and so the government
doesn't like that
that people should be free to just
you know participate in the democracy so
you see freedom of expression is the
engine of democracy in our view that
without a freedom of expression
democrats cannot function
without participation and inclusion
democracy is dead
so our democracy is actually dying
because
the government doesn't want people to to
speak people to
offer their opinions and ideas so the
internet is at the center of this and we
are going into an election in
in less than 50 days and
the inspector general police the
ministers and just anyone who has access
to
the national broadcaster they are
threatening people
who are abusing social media now we have
taken time to study what they're calling
abuse of social media these are just
critical voices that
are that are critical of the government
the president his wife
and just all the wrong that is going on
so they don't like it and they're
calling it upbeat of social media that
zambians are insulting the president
that his wife
and the the ministers so um the internet
is a bad thing
uh it must be regulated it must be
controlled and the
uh everyone who puts bad content like
insulting the president
must be arrested and the in the
the law that i i talked about earlier on
the penalties are unrealistic they are
they are unjustifiable they are harsh
they are they are too hard to compre
comprehend
just for people who are exercising their
right to freedom of expression on the
internet
so that is our story
may i add something from a perspective
to this good question
um it's very clearly like the first
factor that um has a way
in that is that governments want to
restrict freedom of information because
they don't want to um
they don't want information about police
abuse to get out
that's the first line basically
but a second thing that i think we need
to consider
is that centralization in latin america
is a thing an actual thing
there is one isp in most countries
that holds 60 percent of
[Music]
traffic and is often controlled by
government
it's public and so it's very easy
to use a kill switch in that provider
using that provider
and radically reduce the capability of
people to access the internet
and that that seems very not close like
it's okay this is something that we do
in order for more people to be able to
access the internet because
um infrastructure is is expensive
and then governments need to get take
care of that but then
it becomes very dangerous because it's
very easy for them to do that without
any kind of procedure
and this is something that repeats
across the region
and it is uh
very difficult to handle because it also
means that there is no transparency at
all
when the shutdowns happen there is no
explanation
it's very difficult to run technical
tests in order to find out what's
happening
and it is it is a original thing
may i add uh one more point
so i i i think i just
i i totally agree with uh uh things that
uh my colleagues and friends they they
said and
um my experience is one of the reasons
that they
shut down the internet is because simply
they don't they want to shut down the
communication
they don't want people to talk to each
other to mobilize
and you know basically to act against
whatever is the will of the the
government and the state
uh and and now now these days they
shutting down the internet but
before the internet were really popular
and you know
uh everyone in iran had access to the
internet back in uh
2009 the the time that the stila was in
iran
that we saw a really widespread a
national white protest
after the i would say that was the first
widespread process after the revolution
in iran
they the internet was like we had the
main connection was dial-up so it was
not like really
and they were not really 3g and 4g back
then in iran
uh so what what they did was shutting
down the mobile phone
and and text messages so you see that
that we are
seeing this trend is shifting to the
internet because
now internet is the main tools of
communication
between all of the activists and all the
people
uh who wants to protect their rights so
uh
so shouting down the communication with
activists and people
is one of the main goal and of course
they can have
the because they have the estate media
they can have their own narrative
publishing their own narrative about
what is going on and why uh why people
are protesting
i actually have a follow-up question i'm
here about what you just said in terms
of
cutting access to communications because
in the past and actually it's also
related to what you said marianne about
um centralization of internet service
providers
we know that in a in a number of
countries there is also a centralization
of the media some of which also is
controlled by government and so
i'd like to draw this parallel between
you know like when governments were able
to control
and influence the media in that case the
censorship or the
the control over the content was maybe a
bit more pernicious
as opposed to what we're seeing now
which is when governments decide to
censor the internet uh not just via
removing some websites here and there
but really shutting down the internet or
shutting down part of the internet or
part of the internet services
what can you say like what do you think
it says about this new trend which
or or is it different is it the same
thing because it feels the perception
feels different when you just
don't have access it's different to have
access to something that has been
you know like tempered with or or or
or control so yeah that was my question
to you in terms of
the differences and and um what do you
think
that means as as a threat maybe or as
not so much of a threat to to democracy
and the electoral process
sure that's that's a very good question
um i mean
in a country like iran the the state
media radio and tv they are
absolutely under control of the the
government and by the government i don't
mean
uh the the administration and
presidential office i mean the office of
the supreme leader
so it's like a level higher than a
regular uh
uh government that we talked about in in
uh countries it's basically like kind of
having king and then like like another
position
so so they they want to have absolute
control over the
or everything that people are are here
list
hearing or watching uh and this is not
just about the news it's about like a
culture
movie uh you know about like like
blocking netflix
uh obviously blocking it releases both
sides because of the text sanctions as
well
but but blocking like uh watching a live
stream
video and you know news everything but
something that is completing uh
basically
this puzzle in iran is the
the local infrastructure of the internet
the localization of the internet
so the goal uh in iran is
to tell people to sell this idea to the
to the
to people that you don't need to access
uh internet or what they call it
international internet you don't need to
have access to that you don't need to
have access to
anything outside the country we are
going to provide
whatever you need inside iran
and in order to sell that idea to the
people they are even
subsidize the internet traffic in iran
if you see
the if you use the local services in
iran you're paying half a price than
using the international services
so that's include all the news media all
the news website all the
uh broadcasting inside the country
as well as communication tools messaging
apps
email services and and everything so
so the the the final goal is to keep
everything ins and right now 70
of internet traffic is local traffic
inside the country
so we are not really far from uh
being totally cut off from the rest of
the world so
that's that's the main goal localization
and selling the idea to the people that
whatever you need news communication
whatever you need is inside the country
and forget about the outside
can you compete uh
uh i don't yeah we can hear you
okay uh just to complete uh
i mean talking the reason often given to
justifying
a shutdown is uh to fight against the
spirit of fake news
to prevent the submission of a message
of hesitation
to hatred uh
culture for popular cuisine and
sometimes for reason on national
security
but that corresponds to variety of
those and then penetration in my country
for experience
has not become a significant enough
factor
that could have has been the
2019 not international down during the
election
so we can construct uh please
fema phenomenally uh way learning now
today at almost every election
in your country we can expect an
international dome
the last example is the congo
congo white despite the campaign to
prevent either
simply touch the simply cuts through the
internet
organization so uh
this is to say how the parent is
actually has become
social media outlet primarily uh affect
service
and can easily bypass with a complete
outage or
affect the antenna network and has
global
impact that for just for
censorship so he's my i think
thanks
yes um thank you all for your
um submissions and i do agree they
resonate very well with
the findings that we come across under
the capital
campaign and um i
normally see that the government seem to
be learning from each other
once a government shuts down the
internet during the election
whether it solves the problems
or the justifications they would
normally give or not another
country would repeat
something similar in response to
elections
and one thing we've also noticed is the
um
correlation between offline and online
repression
so um normally you know or have reports
of journalists being arbitrarily
detained or arrested or
human rights violations being
perpetrated on the ground and then
um shutdowns actually make it difficult
for the same journalists
and human rights defenders to
access information around these human
rights violations
and this is very dangerous
for the human rights community so before
we
continue the discussion i just want to
find out from our participants
um do you have any questions at this
point
and if you do please
raise your hand or unmute yourself and
speak
if that's okay with you
okay um retrieve
hello my name is beatrice i work for the
bbc
in the united kingdom and i've got a
question for marianne
you talked about infrastructure
failures in south america cutting off
areas
in terms of internet connectivity are
you suggesting that their infrastructure
failures
because of lack of the genuine
infrastructure failures because of lack
of investment and that
is a threat to democracy or are you
suggesting that they're deliberate
infrastructure failures on the parts of
government in order to shut down the
internet
that's an excellent question beatrice
thank you i am suggesting both
there is infrastructural failure that
happens
for lack of maintenance and for lack
of investment and this is
a reality because we are mostly
a poor region with
variations somewhat drastic between
country to country but
still poor but
as a work that
my colleagues have done and myself have
done
suggests in some places the lack of
investment in infrastructure for
telecommunications
is a political decision so if you are
deciding
to put that money into social control
into technology for social control or
into the military
instead of managing your infrastructure
in a way that allows people to connect
at
an adequate level then that's a
political choice
when you have a failure of that kind on
the other hand
in places like my country which is a
failed state
when you have a certain kind of
infrastructure
failure and then they say oh this
entire city was cut off from from the
internet
for three days at the same time i
protest what
was happening and thanks for coming in
to
deal with the protesters but this was
there was an absolute blackout so
there's no information from that
and but no it was an iguana
that ate the cable because you know in
my country
iguanas like to eat cables like it's
very delicious to them
so that kind of restricts their cut
it is very much not an accident and and
when you are inside
um i mean it is still difficult
to prove from a from a technical
investigative
standpoint but for a person who is
inside the blackout it is very obvious
it's very easy to see that it is
intentional
so yes i think that those two things are
at place
at the same time thank you
thank you very much teachers for your
question okay i have another hand queen
sorry if i mispronounced your name and
no that's fine
uh my name is viland van dijk i'm i work
for nrc in the netherlands
and i have a question really for all the
speakers thank you all for your
interesting
um i was wondering that
for uh for a regime to shut down the
internet there's a troop
there's there's costs
it disrupts businesses it takes down
electronic banking it's not something
that you can
uh easily do without harming your
economy the further economy outside the
the internet and i was wondering if
you're seeing
um uh keeping that into account
uh developing their technical
capabilities to
to um to limit the
these consequences
so uh well interested in your
opinion on that
can i answer that please do thank you
well that that's that's really very very
uh good question um i cannot speak
about iran so your your point is right
but uh it's interesting to know what
iran is doing
to basically reduce that cost as
as much as possible the entire reason
that they created this local
infrastructure
as they call it national information
network or we usually address
that like national internet
right but the official name is national
information network
the entire reason that they want to
localize
everything inside the country is to
reduce the cost of internet shutdown
the the the the internet shutdown that
we had in
uh let me check my calendar in in
november 2009
more than 12 days actually was a test
to see if they can reduce that cost
because
when when they encourage people to come
inside the country use the local
services and infrastructure
it was because when they shut down the
internet the local services they
they they can work like we have like
iranian uber
uh snap that it was totally working uh
online banking was totally working
and it's interesting to know there is a
there is an international angle that
actually helped iranian governments to
do that you know the u.s takes sanctions
when the entire basically
encouraging program subsidize the
traffic everything that they did
to encourage people to move inside the
country and use the local services was a
failure project simply because
no one trusted the government but
because of the usa
sanctions people were kicked out from
the international infrastructures like
aws digital ocean and all of things
and the only solution only option was
moving back inside iran
and that's actually the reason we are
seeing uh in
november shutdown that local services
was working
fine and they were happy actually it was
a test
and international services was uh uh
inaccessible to the iranian government
so the things that makes me honestly
afraid and scared
of the future of the localization it's
not because of the technical
infrastructure which is good
it's good that you can access to the
data
fast and no cheap that the technical
side is fine
but the policy maker how they use this
infrastructure makes me
really scared to see the same pattern on
other countries that that is going to
happen it's going to be a really really
scary situation
thank you thank you thank you very much
okay um we have jian hi
i didn't realize i had to use the raised
hand
feature in the chat so i was waving my
hand beforehand
to all the panelists uh have a question
um
so from from what i've understood there
are in some cases some
legal measures are they are underpinning
some of these shutdowns
such as for instance in zambia so i was
wondering in order to
challenge shutdowns is there any
way to use courts is that effective are
leaders in these countries going to
really take notice
or is the solution to this problem going
to come from
why the i don't know diplomatic pressure
or
technological disruption what is going
to end this
are courtrooms going to be one way or
should we just wait for
something new to arise some kind of
more decentralized internet structure
or i don't know by them being very angry
can i go from zambia since it was
mentioned
yes absolutely yeah so uh
in zambia that is that is
what um an ideal situation in an ideal
environment
the courts uh were supposed to have um
hope
in the courts were supposed to have um
that relief
but that is not how it is you know uh so
you find the the appointment of judges
and
how the judges behave when down the
benches
it's very biased and you can see the
influence of the ruling elite in court
decisions so
but not all hope is lost uh
we we currently have a petition
before the courts because we have
challenged the cyber crime the cyber
security act
and sometimes
you just have to do the action so that
you exhaust all the
the the the processes but the courts in
zambia especially when it comes to such
issues
they are not seen to be helpful because
they seem to agree with the state
they they you know because the courts
are
the old judges and all that so they
don't like the internet
they think the internet's a source of
problems social media and all that
so even if their rulings are
and are not pro internet freedoms
but in zimbabwe for example they went to
the courts and it was challenged based
on the constitution and all that
so we it's a 50 50 thing but the
confidence
that the courts would protect our
interests and all that
is is very low it's very low because of
what has happened in the past
there's a very strong political
influence in most of our lives
most of the public institutions here uh
because of
intolerance because of abuse of
power you know the departure from the
rule of law
policy inconsistency and all that so
when most decisions are based
only on the political affiliation
so that is the problem we have maybe
also i can respond to another question
like
the the impact of internet shutdown
like how do they how do our leaders see
it
so in zambia for as long as
anything that threatens those that are
among the ruling elites
it doesn't it doesn't matter
but they'll just go ahead and make an
unpopular decision so even if the
internet shutdown is costly on the
economy here
they'll still do it and they pretend
that they did it because it was
threatening national security
and hygiene and this is our our what
our argument like what should we
prioritize between
national security and the freedoms
especially internet freedoms
because often the way the phrase
national security actually does not
defeat what action is being
discussed so we find that anything that
someone says or
when there are these hackathons when
all these online protests they say no
this is threatening national security
and
what is national security come on yes
national security we want that because
we want to be
safe and secure but also what is
national security
in the absence of freedoms you cannot
have freedom without security
you cannot have security also in the
absence of freedoms
so i find that the national security has
been weaponized
for to is to inspire
uh the invocation of all these orders to
to you know to shut down internet to
to digitize all the wrong things and it
doesn't matter whether that also
has has an effect on how the financial
technology is running and
just everything else so we the biggest
problem we have here is that of
growing repression and intolerance to
divergent
views and opinions that is only thing
that
that matters that are those that are
critical they must not speak
and we can they can shut down the
internet based on
on those criticisms very unfortunate and
that is that is it
from yeah thank you okay thank you very
much um
richard i we are running out of time
and so i just want um to call um harold
in
um benin had elections in april this
year and
um there was no internet shutdown and we
did mention that the
internet was disrupted in 2019 during
parliamentary elections but um
could you take us through what happened
and i have to be
very mildly with my time so can you use
like two minutes to let us know what
happened
what changed in benin to
ensure that there was no internet
district
thank you for a question uh
to 2020 we reserve warning
that's a possible international ground
for more municipal elections
you know last year and for this year
it was reported on sale reaction so
we decided to a theory of proactive
action
had to be taken to prevent a possible
international
before during and after election
so for for first action
we wish to keep it uh
we felicia for myself now to sing
the open letter that was being
written uh which was done and i thank
her from the opportunity
secondly uh we have posts on social
network to promote a platform to fight
against signals
that we have helped to develop food the
internet community of union
we will write and post on our
website support by antenna society
global
to explain the disaster is consequence
that an international down would have on
the country but for economically
financially socially politically
executed
we we have made
an interview we were
situation that and the concern we
felt we were feeling
so uh in locally for
action with a question of
other civil society organization we
launched a very large campaign
on social media
with tips posters
which explain each day a consequence of
international
a message of human rights
that will not be respect if is happen
this companion which began ninth
nine days yeah nine yeah and then before
election
on let's
and we organize up
with another civil social
civil society sorry organization
a public conference
to inform rise
denotes a possible shutdown
and the date the day of election
we have set up a monitoring limit
to detecting on internet credit
and uh we we post it previously
uh publica with
the state of network in three countries
which are
either we have
we also wanted to initiate a person and
first like this
to prevent better we have no time so
that these visas
the different action of that web we have
put
in place and uh it was a great joy for
us
to see that until the day after election
we had online and without my
technical problem so after that
it's okay okay
no change okay all right thank you very
much
and it's indeed it's always a great joy
to
see that people enjoy their rights on
the internet
because the impacts of international
talks are very devastating
and um just to add on to what you said
um they keep the capitol um campaign we
have
a an election struck up which we
launched beginning of this year
and so we have all the elections we have
um
noted as high risk that is risk of a
shutdown happening
um and that at the time of those
elections and so
um it's on our website michael leaf we
shared in the chat as well
um if you are in countries that are
identified in this
or not and you anticipate an internet
disruption please feel free to reach out
and we are happy to work with you or we
would reach out to you
and to work with you so i'll hand over
to melody
um so
uh sure we still have to begin yes of
course and we still have some questions
online but
uh of course uh if reporters in the in
the room have
questions please raise your hands uh or
wave
and uh and we'll make sure to to give
you the
virtual mic uh and also just wanted to
pinpoint that please do have a look at
the chat and all of the resources that
uh my colleague felicia is sharing
including some positive
news when it comes to court cases and uh
court victories when it when it comes to
internet students it's something that we
definitely want uh
as a coalition to to invest in a bit
more and to put more resources behind
but
of course it depends of of the content
on the context sorry and how
we can rely or not on the on the
judicial
process so i have a question to all
speakers
when it comes to because we have
several reporters in the room and so how
can journalists
report on internet shutdowns and and
digital repression
and support the work that you that
you're doing so i'm not asking about
like
tools that they can use to circumvent uh
shutdowns and so on like
these uh these tools i mean if there is
interest let me know but
we we've published some material about
it and we're happy to
that would make us succeed
exceed the timeline but more in terms of
journalists and reporters
working on on that topic when they do
cover elections
what would be helpful to your work
and how should they report on internet
shutdowns
i have things to say about that
it is important to me that when
reporters cover
internet shutdowns or any other kind of
internet disruption
um that they make space to tell the
story of people affected by it
because oftentimes they just focus on
numbers
which is understandable because numbers
are hard and
facts and journalists are or about
facts and facts are very important of
course but if you tell me
that i don't know ten thousand people
were affected it really doesn't
sound like much for people it sounds
like it was a small village and
sometimes it depends of course
on the people on the country but
for those people it's terrible it is a
lot
and it affects their livelihood it
affects their ability to
study if it affects their ability to
work
more so over during this pandemic
and if they give space to both maybe
two facts and also stories but also
stories are facts
there are just no numbers and if you
keep that in mind
i think it makes for a more
comprehensive approach
to reporting um something like this and
it makes for people for the general
audience
more easy to understand why a shutdown
is important particularly for those
that haven't lived through one
thank you marianne any other perspective
uh from our speakers
one more point uh based on the
experience of the last
international shutdown in province of
system balochistan in iran
um i think when it comes to like uh
uh so i i i think one of the best things
that they can do is uh
maybe it's all work actually to provide
resources
to let the journalists know who you need
to listen
to because in the last internet
shadowing somebody just done
almost three days before the shutdown
some political opposition for their own
political agenda
they said internet is shut down in
system
which was we hadn't shut down back then
three days after
that announcement uh we had shut down
and the new the entire news was
killed actually just because of the
false at uh the internet shot an
announcement
for their own political agenda so i i
think you need to basically verify your
your uh sources to see if like some
anonymous
person on on twitter is saying it's shut
down and
these people are not living inside the
country
so that that that's that's a problem
when we need to
basically pay attention to the horrible
things that happening
so i think listening to the real expert
local people uh or like keep it on
campaign
people they they have access to
resources and access to the local
activities
i think that that's the most important
thing uh journalists can do
thank you any thoughts from richard
maybe
or harold or has it all
been covered
oh sorry
i miss your question oh no sorry i was
just asking
um what would be helpful for your work
when journalists report on internet
shutdowns
so what is helpful in terms of maybe the
information that they
share or the people that they they they
speak to
okay uh about january's uh departing
is is christian
to educate citizens onshore progression
yes just like that
yeah so and from from our perspective
in zambia we feel even journalism itself
is uh
is affected is impacted by by internet
shutdown whether it's filtering jamming
and
and all that anything that restricts
access to the internet or blocks access
to the internet
is detrimental to a free
and an independent press but with regard
to the content
and all that the the products of
journalism we think it's very important
because it takes the information out
there
in order to influence internet law and
policy it informs the other people
it informs the stakeholders it helps to
increase the the standards the the best
only
regional and global norms
on on what only on the right to internet
access
we feel journalism plays a critical role
in informing in educating if you
journalism is critical to to all the
narrative because it just
creates that platform for engagement
that
platform like i said for influencing and
for for networking for for people in the
west in the north
and everywhere to be able to know what
is happening this side
so that we can be informed about the
trends
and then we can come up with better
advocacy
and campaign strategies and and just all
that so
we feel it's very important to do that
thank you
thank you and i just want to sorry
felicia
i just wanted to quickly um follow up on
one of
actually a few things that our speakers
have shared when it comes to
sharing data or sharing statistics
because
whether it's the number of people
affected uh it's also the case for
the the number of shutdowns and we've
faced this because we publish this
annual report and
and um and periodic updates about the
number of shutdowns and so if you look
at the numbers since 2019
the numbers have been decreasing which
could you know look we could celebrate
it
like yes to keep it on campaign has been
great work and we have fewer
shutdowns and it's less of an issue but
unfortunately we can't celebrate
uh in this way because um
while the number of shutdowns has
reduced last year for example
and since the beginning of the year
we've seen a
deep as well compared to the the first
half of
the first half of half of the year of
the previous years
uh but what we've noticed however is
that the
shutdowns last longer or that the
the networks that are affected can maybe
like affect more people
and so on so it's always tricky even for
us
uh working on this issue to convey
um what exactly is happening or who
exactly
is impacted and what we can
learn from and the different patterns
when we look just at the numbers and
that's why that
we're trying to always provide this
additional context and this additional
information
when it comes to the nature of shutdown
and um
and their impact and very often actually
it's multiple
uh multiple impacts and multiple
consequences so
just a quick note from me on sharing
numbers and and sharing statistics
but fetisha over to you
yes i actually wanted to add um a
suggestion
that i think would also be relevant um
we do have
um journalists or media that are very
interested in the work that we do
so um let's also proactively identify
them
or reach out um to let them know our
plans
and um the trends that we are noticing
in our countries
and um i'm sure they'll be interested in
covering or listening to us
once we need a platform to do that
um all right um
i have one question before we
wrap up melody and um
i am
and um richard you have elections i mean
we are working on they keep it on
campaign for iran
um and the elections is on the 18th so
um what should we
expect this is not to say uh we need you
to predict
what will happen but then what do you
what does the
landscape look like and the same
question to you richard
your elections are scheduled um for
august
and um we will be working with you
on a campaign so if you can also let us
know what
we should expect and how should we
prepare to prevent a shutdown that'll be
great
richard you want to go ahead i can go
back down i mean
you you mentioned first so i'll go after
you
thank you so i
i i think we so so far what
what we are seeing is uh it seems that
the outcome of election is already
decided so
because uh speaking of the going to the
court for the
like shutdown uh we don't have the rule
of law in iran right so going to the
court we don't have that kind of
luxury unfortunate unfortunately in iran
so
it seems that the the outcome of
election is is
clear we know who is gonna win the
election
uh and this person definitely everyone
gracie
he is not definitely in favor of
internet freedom and his team
uh i i talked to a couple of people from
his team on on different rooms on
clubhouse and it's clear that
they are not in favor of internet
freedom at all and they are not
familiar with the basic definition of
the internet freedom
and right now this person is important
why because he is the head of the
judiciary right now so head of the
judiciary right now is running for the
presidency
and and that on his
watch uh basically uh we saw
that based on the judiciary order they
block signal
they block telegram they blocked
also clubhouse is blocked on some of the
mobile provider in iran
some of them they didn't blocked it but
clearly the head of the judiciary they
don't want to take
any action uh in terms of uh if he's
he's saying he's in favor of internet
freedom in in
verbally but he's not taking any action
and
we are seeing a kind of uh
disruption on network in iran uh based
on the information that i'm receiving
from
from different people uh uh uh different
uh basically still convention tools
developer and and
like ioda map and things like that that
you're seeing kind of coordinated
uh network disruption in iran so that's
all of that together is concerning uh
as i i think richard said about the
national uh security
in iran is the same is the case as well
so
uh when they see the national security
is is
in danger they would do anything to
protect that national security so
so uh again uh um having said
all of these things i think uh uh we can
expect
uh at least a disruption if if people uh
want to protest against the outcome of
the election or in any shape and form
they are already contacting journalists
and asking them to
not criticize a brian gracie in any
shape and form
on social media and article everything
so so the the
the general atmosphere is a fear
atmosphere
uh and and again this this guy was in
charge of
mass execution after the revolution in
iran
uh so i i'm not an automation
of the internet freedom and i think we
should be high alert
uh for for worst case scenario hopefully
not
no shutdown but who knows with this
situation everything is possible
thank you very much and indeed it's
always important to be prepared
and i always say that um it's a very
nice
feeling when you prepare very well and
there's no internet shutdown and that
was the same feeling that
um harold cited when there was no
international town in benin
all right um richard thank you felicia
so
what are what do you expect in zambia
our elections are on august 12th it's a
debt that is in the constitution
so every five years we have elections on
the fifth year on
august 5. so what we expect
and this is based on the trends the
statements and how
all these ict laws in zambia we are
i think we are first tracked in
parliament you know they
they suspended all the standing orders
like the standard rules of making laws
they were suspended so that the
ict laws could quickly become law and
this is what happened like
within a week before we could blink and
open our eyes like oh we have ict laws
so you can see that there are
tools that would facilitate what
the the west that we expect the quan
we expect a total internet shutdown
and uh also we expect um
many people to be arrested before
during and even after the elections and
by the way
in addition to the i'm saying this
because
in addition to the ict laws that we have
the
the elections law the electoral
commission of zambia act
has been amended to include a section
where
it is the only institution
that will have the legal mandate to
announce
election results at any level
so in zambia we have got people
transmitting elections from polling
stations from the polling centers
under sharing and they are comparing the
numbers and all this and that
so with the amendment of the elections
act
is good that all that is going to become
illegal whether you do it in twitter on
facebook or in whatsapp
so you can see that all of us who
like to do this because at bloggers of
zambia we monitor elections using
technology
so we will have like turtling centers we
have
monitoring electro malpractices
and transmitting results like um
number verifications and all that so all
that work is gonna be illegal
but we're still gonna do it anyway so
you should look out for names in the
media like oh these guys have been
arrested
so that is what we expect shutdowns
arrests
all these prosecutions um
so with what what we need and
perhaps what what we are doing what is
go what is happening
so we need to capacitate civil society
journalists and lawyers and
artists with digital hygiene
like practical we are trying to prepare
people with the visa like they are visad
we are preparing the cohort like to just
keep a certain people
online and mount the campaign because
it's it's just gonna be vicious and
um we think that kind of skill
that kind of knowledge is needed in
order to just prepare
about all these negative expectations
coming out of this
because of the the deep interest the the
deep campaign against internet freedoms
that is going on in them
so that is it thank you
thank you very much um and um
yeah we'll be in touch with all of you
um to
work around the elections all right um
over to you melody
yes i don't see any uh more raised hands
uh from the attendees so i think we're
ready to
wrap up uh as discussed we are available
as a community as the kipidon coalition
so
access now but also all the members of
the kipidon coalition
are always more than happy to answer to
specific queries or we also have a
digital security helpline
if you need support in terms of securing
your communication
or um support to prepare
ahead of a ahead of an internet shutdown
if you're in a
in a country um that is likely to
to shut down the internet so our
helpline is always
available to to members of
independent media and it's free free
it's a free service
for for a civil society so
please although this is the end of this
press briefing if you've got
any uh more questions as you are
preparing
your pcs and more uh reach out
to us and let's stay connected if we can
uh to keep it on thank you very much to
all of our speakers
uh and thank you everyone for attending
we really believe that this is such an
important issue
and so that's why just having the
opportunity to discuss it and we're
always
um pleased when we see
um shutdowns mentioned and
reported on the media not for our ego
and not just for our own
uh the the pleasure of seeing or working
the press or the issues that we care
about in the press
but really because we know that shutting
access
to the internet the the primary goal of
that
is to disconnect people and to make them
lose their voice and to make them lose
their ability to share information
very often with the outside world but
sometimes even internally and so
of course when there is a lot of media
coverage
it kind of defeats the purpose sometimes
it completely uh
it completely it proves to be a
completely
unproductive technique so we believe
that actually
journalists are part of the solution
when it comes to the fight for keeping
on
so thank you very much for for joining
and
let's stay in touch if you have any more
questions
thank you everyone bye-bye
thank you
you