[Music]
hello everyone that was a remarkable
film that we just watched about a truly
inspiring journalist
what's more we have here with us at
right scorn maya
thank you so much for joining us it's an
absolute privilege to have you here
oh thank you for having me you know maya
you don't need an introduction so let me
introduce myself
my name is supriya sharma i'm the
executive editor of
scroll dot in one of india's independent
news websites
that the government now wants to
regulate through new sweeping
information technology rules
that have caused such consternation that
can you believe it facebook has sued the
indian government over privacy
what we're seeing in philippines and in
india is of course part of a larger
battle over information that's unfolding
across the world and mario you've been
right in the thick of
it you were among the first to point out
how
silicon valley companies in their search
for profits
were enabling the rise of populist
leaders and authoritarian governments
and the film brings that out very
powerfully i wanted to start where the
film
ends which is in the second half of 2020
when president duterte issued a threat
to facebook
because of an investigation that rappler
did
tell us more about that mario what did
it take to get facebook to act against
those accounts
so a lot but it wasn't i think it's
called enlightened self-interest right
we've
been we are one of two filipino
fact-checking partners of facebook
and we started pointing out the problems
in 2016
because that was the time when we came
out with this
weaponization of the internet series
three-part series i wrote two of the
three parts
and the second part the one of the
pieces i wrote
talked about how facebook algorithms
impact democracy we could see it then
i had given that data to facebook right
uh in this last one i gotta say
you know we know the people we know
exactly
what happened about a year before the
takedown this is the fourth takedown
that that facebook has done in the
philippines since 2018.
um we noticed that
government agencies the police the
military
were targeting uh progressive voices
and it's it's like our version of
mccarthyism but they call it
red tagging red communist right so
they were red tagging journalists human
rights activists
opposition politicians and that is
dangerous at a time when there's an
anti-terror law where you can be a small
group of cabinet secretaries can declare
you a terrorist
and then you can be arrested without a
warrant and held for up to 24 days
so it's quite dangerous at that time so
ah
what we saw what we saw were networks
disinformation networks that were
targeting
we gave that we did stories and then
gave it to facebook and
what was interesting with their
september 22
2020 takedown is that they took down two
networks one was domestic
this one that we had we had pegged and
they went a step further by
pointing out that there were military
officials
that were actually and military accounts
masquerading
as human rights activists right so here
you see the duplicity they exposed
uh but the second one was even more
interesting because it was
influence operations from china
and it was targeting all of southeast
asia but it was most successful
in the philippines where it was
campaigning
for the daughter of president duterte
for our may
2022 elections i.e next year right so it
was already campaigning for that
it was attacking me i guess i'm a little
favorite of theirs but that's
fascinating that campaigning for a
duterte and attacking a journalist
and then the other thing it did was to
create fake accounts
using ai generated photos for the us
presidential elections so these two
were taken down by facebook so you can
kind of see
global the global power dynamics playing
out
in these influence operations
so what happened next i mean facebook
took down the account president duterte
issued a threat
what have the last few months been like
have things turned a bit frosty between
the president and facebook or not
not yet i think in the philippines
facebook is in the
phase of docking right i mean in a way
journalists deal with this all the time
right we hold power to account and we
know we are going to get clobbered in
the time before social media
uh this is you know we know how to
handle that and you know you have to
speak truth to power which is also part
of the reason
i kind of laugh at the at the new
definitions that the social media
platforms
are giving editorial decisions because
make no mistake about
it what they call content moderation is
just
kind of renaming what journalists used
to do
which is to gatekeep the public's fear
and you know of course well anyway i'll
shut up and just say you know
they got a little bit of what we get uh
every day um i think that you know it's
sobering
to know to to feel that um
but not much beyond that i think you
know the danger is there and my biggest
worry
is the may 2022 elections because
if facebook doesn't significantly change
if guard rails aren't put in place then
i i don't
imagine i can't imagine how we will have
integrity of elections
which is what i wanted to ask you are
you seeing any of the election integrity
initiatives that were put in place
last year in the united states which by
the way we've not seen in india yet
yes absolutely no same as you right i
think
india and the philippines share a lot of
have a lot of things in common
i mean thank you for the chat we had
right before this right uh
populist governments who use
the social media platforms to
insidiously manipulate people to make
you
distrust everything so it makes civic
engagement
impossible and the voice with the
loudest megaphone
controls the public sphere this is
whether knowingly or
unknowingly what facebook and social
media platforms have done
globally right and that's part of the
reason that you know from
2017 when freedomhouse.org you would
have heard this from me in the film you
know they said there were 27 countries
around the world
where cheap armies on social media is
rolling back democracy
to january this year at the oxford
computational propaganda
research that they came out with 81
countries
so 27 to 81 and you know
this is murder genocide in some of the
countries in the global south
uh there have been of course myanmar
that's your best thing what we've seen
happen in february in myanmar yes
facebook took resources and put it in
the myanmar
elections but here's the thing when the
virus of lies
hits real people it changes the way they
view the world
and our own cognitive biases make it
very
difficult to go back to where it was and
i think this is the
biggest problem we have not discussed is
what do you do with emergent behavior
right when when you get a mass of people
there's more than three billion on
facebook alone the accounts that are
there
they behave very differently from an
individual
and that pressure exerts the individuals
do things that they would not normally
do
every psychological study has shown us
this the solomon ash studies
you know the the six degrees of
influence rule that has now
on facebook gone down to 3.5 degrees of
influence right
so so what i worry about is is how
the way the medium delivering the news
the world's largest distributor of news
is actually shaping human behavior
and until someone takes responsibility
for that i worry about our future
not just democracy our own future right
like as human beings and
and free and having free will and the
agency to choose our destiny
yeah well um i was i was hoping to hear
that in the last few months you're
seeing some changes
that are sort of more than that one
action that facebook took in philippines
um but you know elsewhere in the world
maria we're seeing that this rather cozy
relationship between the platforms
and governments is sort of fraying a bit
you know twitter was banned in nigeria a
few days ago
in india the police landed up at
twitter's offices
in turkey as well with friction over new
rules and as i mentioned
in india facebook rather whatsapp which
is owned by facebook has sued the
government over these new rules
um do you think something is is kind of
shifting
slowly but steadily where the uh you
know
big tech has woken up to the fact that
the authoritarians that they enable
can finally turn on them
i wish it was that clear but i i think
what has been most effective
has been public pressure right there
were and look they haven't even really
worked
right look at the stop hate for profit
july last year in the united states
facebook didn't feel it
um last year uh the net income of
facebook was still a very very healthy
29 billion dollars the incentive
scheme of surveillance capitalism is
still there but
the good side is i think they're
starting to realize
that speaking truth to power has cost
and i think this is the difference
between having journalists with a sense
with standards and ethics with the
mission of journalism
being the gatekeepers versus tech
companies who are run
by people whose incentive is
more shareholder value right ultimately
i hope
because in the short term if we continue
this incentive scheme
we will continue and deepen the dystopia
the entire world is in
it will enable a rise of fascism
globally we have
already seen this and your country and
mine
i mean i i covered
look i remember 2004 when modi like
duterte was facing charges of human
rights violations
and then 2014 when he became
this wasn't this is a while ago right
2014 when he became your prime minister
here president duterte
a mayor in in power in davao city since
and then he takes power with the help of
facebook
um in 2016. and so i guess
it's existential and certainly for the
philippines the may 2022 elections
given that president duterte's daughter
sarah duterte looks like she's running
for office
isn't that interesting that chinese
influence operations were already
campaigning for her right
i'm hoping that there is greater
transparency
that the social media platforms uh open
up
and you know moderate the greed
take some real leadership and and
and show us a mirror of humanity so that
we prevent the worst
of what human beings can do to ourselves
supreme you know that i always think
about that time period
post-world war ii after the atom bomb
and it was the united states that did it
but when when we saw the
the the heart of darkness
when we saw that the world came together
to try to prevent it from happening
again
this is the same type of moment
and the global institutions the united
nations
governance is weakened
and isn't functioning so this is this is
really a call to arms
for those who have power to look at the
world again
and to create a better world because the
world that was
is gone and there's something very
new and and painfully
it's a dystopian world that is being
created now
we either go with it or we make it
better
you know mario i've been thinking that
even the small steps that we're seeing
the platforms take how much of that is
just the trump effect
you know the crisis in american
democracy forcing them to acknowledge
their role and take some
corrective actions and i wonder now with
trump on
is the pressure this public pressure
that you speak of is that going to
slacken because you know they've never
really bothered about
what those of us in asia have to say as
much as they do
for the united states asian lives don't
matter
yeah isn't that horrible that we're the
ones saying that but that's certainly
what their
behavior has shown right i mean look the
announcement
last friday was it only last friday that
you know trump would be off the platform
for a period for another two years
right uh for two years even that
had this announcement that facebook was
not
responsible for for january 6
for the violence that erupted on capitol
at the capitol on january 6. well
you know if you go back and i do go back
facebook in 2012 actually did a study
on the role of emotional contagion on
its platform
and the results of that study said
that the network spreads back which is
seated
it spreads emotions so if anger
and hate are the emotions that are most
amplified right this is now proven by
study after study
lies laced with anger and hate spread
faster and further
than facts on social media right if that
is the case
then i think
i don't see that the announcements
the palliative measures the too little
too late like
it's great you know to take to take
to be proud of taking trump off or to
sheepishly
admit that they can take a powerful
figure off is frankly way too little too
late and should never even
have gotten to the point where any
leader around the world
can lie repeatedly to their
constituencies right it isn't
everything is slightly twisted when it
comes to interpretations of free speech
and not surprisingly they're slightly
twisted
to help protect the business model that
has been harmful to its users
as facebook or twitter have they
moderated political like speech by
politicians in philippines at all
no no no but and and i think it's
interesting right like i'm going back
because i'm i'm writing a book and i
think it's interesting that uh
that they've separated into two the
political
uh disinformation networks from the
commercial disinformation networks but
you know like when you cover the rise of
terrorism
and social networks physical social
networks of terrorism
they are hand in hand these come up
because politicians need them and they
these gain greater power so for example
the rise of terrorism in southeast asia
began in 1988
when osama bin laden sent his
brother-in-law muhammad jamal khalifa to
the philippines
to actually begin the financial network
that underpin the terror attacks that
were
co-opted by al-qaeda at that point it
was it wasn't al qaeda yet
right so i'm just saying we know this
already so
why are we pretending not to know it
absolutely um yet you know maria for all
the problems with the platforms and
they're plenty
they're also powerful instruments that
give voice to journalists and citizens
yeah absolutely both rapper and scroll
are digital natives we built our
audiences here
in fact in india at least
you know with the mainstream media
entirely towing the government line
um in fact sections of it even turning
into disinformation machines
in the worst case spewing hate against
minorities
the platforms really seem like the last
available space for independent
journalism
and for critical voices and you know
so it's that even as we're trying to get
the platforms to clamp down
on disinformation and hate speech
there's also
an attempt to get them to not buckle
under government pressure to close down
legitimate accounts
um is that something that you're seeing
in the philippines as well
yeah absolutely and guess what news
organizations have dealt with that power
dynamic
for for decades right we know how to do
this so i guess
part of it is that look uh
we are we're all familiar with in 2011
with how
social media was really uh credited with
the arab spring which then became the
arab winter because
after the students and the activists use
social media here came government to
exploit it
and i think the social media platforms
weren't prepared for that
and this is you know it took until 2015
when i peg it to instant articles
bringing in news organizations
and then when we came on board the same
algorithms
were used to like for a story on the
scroll story and rappler and the new
york times on bbc
for distribution as the joke
that this guy told at dinner or the lie
that another neighbor is saying and
guess what
the algorithms again by design
actually promote the greatest use and
how do you do that
by anger unfortunately right because the
top
rapper has a mood meter and what we know
before
2016 is that the emotion that always won
in the philippines
was happy or inspired anger was second
and it didn't shift until 2016. so
i think the first is truly to go to the
core of the problem which is that social
media platforms
take lies and facts and they treat it
all
the same right they treat it like data
and they don't differentiate
journalists differentiate we take out
the lies and that's
human moderation which is far more
expensive
than having an algorithm that has the
coder's bias
built in to actually do it automatically
right and i i also laugh when they say
but how do you do it at scale
uh shouldn't it be the question be the
other way around
why are you doing it at scale if you
don't know how to do it
right and and why is it the user's
responsibility to protect ourselves
i sound like i'm so anti-facebook or
anti-social media i'm not
i know it's powers i drank the kool-aid
right we helped spread twitter facebook
we
helped bring users on board because
precisely
up from 2012 which is when we began
until 2016
2015 it was an enabling tool
and then they got too greedy and then
they
realized that they could make a lot of
money but the cost
is to humanity right so this is
i think this is leadership this requires
leadership on both on the social media
platforms and
american social media companies and
governments
and and i and i'm going to pull this out
broader with coronavirus
i think this is ushering in an age
where communities of action you know
rappler's
uh elevator pitch in 2012 is that we
build communities of action the food we
feed our communities is journalism
well look i just saw the latest oxfam
report
where they pointed out that
power and money companies and
governments those who have power
and money have largely failed their
citizens
and the effort to provide a social
safety net has actually come
from the citizens themselves here in the
philippines it's the it's the community
pantry
when we just see you know our government
focused on either consolidation of power
or
our upcoming elections uh and
not enough on a social safety net it it
gave
the first two laws that it passed for
the coronavirus
so it gave a safety net to the large
corporations
so i think this is the time for citizens
for
those of us who are in democracies that
are faltering
to come together now how are we going to
do that this is why social media
is so important as i castigate them
i also am their biggest fan but please
moderate your greed guys
otherwise you're gonna wreck our world
well yes absolutely but you know again
um what complicates this further
at least in india is that my
disinformation is spreading
not just on open platforms like facebook
um but increasingly so in fact much more
so on whatsapp
and you know when we had lynchings a
couple of years ago
exactly yeah i mean
that was that was the story out of india
that made global deadlines and that
yeah uh i mean oh you're frozen i'm
gonna answer
that uh so
i think if you look at facebook's
reactions
post cambridge analytica right what
we've seen
is right after the cambridge analytica
scandal
uh facebook said we're gonna change our
algorithms
and we're going to emphasize family and
friends
and at that point news organizations
around the world
saw a decline in traffic from facebook
of anywhere from
40 to 60
and and then you know there was some
slight
shifting once facebook realized this
right but
the the reality is that when you focus
on family and friends
you also focus on disinformation because
it's the news organizations that
actually give you the facts
and when you when you down when you
when you push the dial down then the
facts
become harder to get to right and we do
know
facebook has the capability to turn the
dial up on
quality news on the facts they did it in
the u.s
elections they just choose not to do it
because
it makes less money at least that's my
thing i think the other part is
there's a lot of initiatives where
hundreds of millions of dollars are
spent
a panel the facebook oversight where
it spent two years and a lot of money to
bring in
really smart people but in the end all
of these are red herrings
because we already know the answer based
on the data
and all of it seems to be tactics to
just
delay to give you just enough so that
you are distracted from the fundamental
problem
of how you are being manipulated and i
think the hardest part here is that it's
insidious manipulation right if
you haven't seen the social dilemma
that's one way of looking at it that
every post you have is pulled together
by machine learning and a model
of you has created a model that knows
you better than you know yourself and
then ai
artificial intelligence comes in and
takes all of our models
and serves your most vulnerable point to
a message
to a company that's the new advertising
or to a government the new propaganda
and regardless of what you do
right whether you click or don't click
that
ad or that message it becomes part
of what cnn from mit calls the hype
machine um so
now the question is with that oh there
you are they're back i'm so happy i was
like
vamping for you i just
thank you thank you for uh for picking
up the thread even as
as you know i think my wi-fi is acting
up
well uh you know uh maria i was trying
to sort of uh get your thoughts on
on you know this this new challenge that
we face now
where we're talking about algorithms and
open platforms
we're also now dealing with a lot of
disinformation spreading on messaging
services
like like whatsapp in india whatsapp
introduced features to
reduce the virality of messages uh after
the lynchings took place but
to ask for any more regulation of the
service
seems to run the real risk of opening it
up to government surveillance in fact
that's actually
what whatsapp has sued the government
over where the government's basically
asking them to
break end-to-end encrypt encryption to
reveal the identity of the first
originator of messages
which kind of just makes me wonder that
is it that we now have a much bigger
problem on our hands where
technology has left the genie out of the
bottle but
technology alone can't put it back in
you're absolutely correct of course
you're absolutely correct and i'm really
glad that facebook took the position it
did and
you have to continue doing that story to
make sure they continue
taking the position that they did right
um
look this tech has
made billionaires out of people
right i mean out of out of tech
people but the reality also is that
there is
a lot of it that have been legislated
again so
let me take it out of the information
ecosystem and talk about genetic
research
right technology has actually allowed
geneticists to be
able to to look at our dna
and almost construct a human being in
end real we can actually change the
color of your eyes or
you can actually do this by design
design human beings
but is any
even geneticist is any human being
really
ready and able to play god
right and i think this is where in in
the western countries
crispr technology has put western
nations have put guidelines
in place around manipulating genetics
and that's important because they see
the potential
i think that same thing was very delayed
when it came to into the information
ecosystem and
and you know why should it have why
should it have been delayed
i think you and i became journalists
because we knew information
is power and this information now
has warped the world worked
because now ally replaces a fact
authoritarians are moving forward our
democracies
are dying and you know if the western
nations can't hold the line
what happens to our countries and who
takes responsibility for that so i
let me address the the what's up i was
actually there
there were so many meetings uh where
where this was discussed what do you do
and the very easy one is to just
limit the distribution but
it goes back to maybe throwing spaghetti
against the wall when it comes to
humanities
to shifting our behavior when it comes
to information
must be done within very specific
guidelines and this is where
i do look forward to i don't trust
facebook or or google or i mean google
has done a little bit better job but
depends on who you talk to right
youtube is right twitter
india knows this better but you know all
of this technology has got to have
regulations in place it's kind of like
pharmaceuticals
we put guard rails in place for this why
do tech companies get a free pass
we now see the impact of that and that
has to stop
so i look at the eu its democracy action
plan the two drafts of legislation and
you and i should keep putting inputs
into that so at least
the global south gets a voice at the
table the uk
has its online arms bill and then the us
has
is still playing with section 230 so
they're a little left behind but
i look at what the states are doing the
attorney generals of the states are
actually
filing the cases right if we don't fix
this now
the emergent behavior and this is the
thing
emergent behavior in india has led to
these mobs
emergent behavior in myanmar has led to
genocide
emergent behavior in the philippines has
led to
okay i'm gonna watch what i say here now
um
i guess i'm just saying that we are
creating
humanity's character you know we
are it is actively shifting
like the devil and angel are individual
battles for
integrity when you can make more money
because you tell a lie that spreads
faster and further
we see people a lot more people doing it
so these
incentives have got to stop and you know
i'm looking forward to twitter for
example they're trying
uh a paid a subscription model
because if that works then we have the
power of social media
without us without our data
without being insidiously manipulated
by it
absolutely i mean the platforms have to
take
far more sustainable corrective actions
and yes i mean it is
it is a complicated world and it is as
much now a political problem as a
technological problem but the two
are intertwined yeah and
their values have to be clear right i'm
sure you're gonna agree with me
uh so i'm putting words in your mouth
but
if their values aren't clear they're not
gonna be able to stand up to a
government
in this particular instance they stood
up to a government right so they
kind of have to put their money where
their mouth is and they
should really stop the spend on
palliative
measures and get to the core of the
problem and
you know i have there's real reason i
say that
and i ask for solutions quickly because
if this isn't in place
this year when we walk into elections
next year we will not have
integrity of elections number one and
number two
i could go to jail i have real skin in
the game
absolutely i mean this this
has real life implications for millions
of people
and directly for us as journalists
fact as i was watching the film i was
struck by how far
you were through all of that and you
remain so calm you're right here with us
you're you know it's it's just really
inspiring to watch that
but you know it also made me wonder that
these
attacks on journalists one thing that
it's doing is it's making
us the story and personally i found it a
bit unsettling last year when my name
trended on twitter because there was a
police case against me for reporting
that i did from the prime minister's
constituency
and i know there's a positive side to it
because there are
many many journalists who are facing far
worse without any public attention
on their cases and yet i do wonder what
the spotlight
on journalists is doing to trust in news
uh we don't see ourselves as the
opposition but we are being put in that
box
we are being valorized on one side and
being called enemies of the people on
another as someone who's faced this to
an intensity of a hundred thousand
what are your thoughts on this what do
you think is happening
i'm gonna take it apart into two strands
the first is
trust in news that you brought up and
then the second is the impact on
journalism right
so trust in news it's it's not just
trust in news it's
trust right so if lies spread
faster then you have a situation where
we have no facts because not only
do the algorithms spread the lies anger
and hate
faster which means disinformation
conspiracy theories
um you know thinking fast the the system
one
of our because that's how they keep us
on the platform
so not only does that happen but if you
don't have facts you can't have truth
without truth you can't have trust it
isn't just
in a way news organizations we're kind
of naval gazing because
we think it's the destruction of trust
in us it isn't just
us it's the destruction of trust in
everything
right so i i kind of joke when i put two
movies together to describe the world
today i
i think now we are living in the matrix
right and we each are performing our own
little
3 billion plus truman shows and the
question as i i have is
who is watching who is listening
listening which is critical to a working
democracy right what do we do with
information in the public sphere
uh you have to listen to that and then
safely debate it to change each other's
minds to find the best
path forward that's what that's the
implicit assumption of a democracy
uh so it isn't just trusted news i would
say right
i think social media has destroyed trust
and everything and
it does spread what it's seated with
right so again i go back to
online violence does not stay online
and social media spreads this stuff i
think the second thing of journalism
the destruction of journalism as we knew
it began a long time ago
and you know if you look at even things
if you remember in
my gosh was it 2018 when when we
discovered that facebook had given us
all the wrong
data about video and how far it spread
right to the tune of like their numbers
for video
were 90 inflated right
when they sorry say again
i said that that led so many news rooms
to pivot to video
exactly right that's and that's the
point and so what happened the
incentives for distribution led to bad
journalism that's one and
news organizations that maintained the
standards and ethics
then looked at this number that was 90
inflated
and fired editorial people and hired
video people and only to find
out a few years later that oh that
wasn't the truth so
that we don't even know what the truth
is this is part of the reason i call for
greater transparency
from the social media platforms right
and instead what they've done is
over the years including the most recent
announcement of facebook
they've narrowed down the data that
is available for researchers to hold
them in check
that is disturbing right so look
the mission of journalism has never been
as important
but our business model is dead and
you know in many ways i think rappler is
lucky
because when we came under attack before
coronavirus
uh we our advertisers were the first
people
to be scared you know in 2018 when the
government tried
you saw that in there when the
government tried to shut us down
uh i by april 2018
so we're fighting all this in court but
by april so a few months four months
after we dropped
49 of our advertising revenue and it
forced us to pivot
and create a new product based on what
we do
as investigative journalists right how
do we find disinformation networks
and then create a product that would
allow us
to you to do give that to a company
and that's i think that's the new world
we have to create this new world
but how do we do it how do we do it with
the standards and ethics
the mission of journalism intact the
incentives are
very low who wants to stand up to a
duterte right if
i mean i joke part of it is because i
came of age
in journalism's golden age i'm a little
older than you and i'm really glad
you're doing what you're doing
in india but we hold the line
because we see the impact of what would
happen
if we stopped
thank you maria that that was just most
wonderful we can go on
and on there's so much to talk about
that's a really good note to end on
thank you so much for for joining us and
all the very best for 2022 i hope things
are better this time
fingers crossed and good luck to india
as well
good luck to your team i mean we're
navigating a really difficult world
to human rights defenders to journalists
hold the line
okay um
maya there are some questions for you uh
sorry i should have
noticed those popping up on my screen um
well plenty of questions let's take some
um yeah well
do you think the pandemic in the
accompanying flood of health
disinformation has prompted any positive
changes
in terms of governance accountability of
tech companies
absolutely it showed that they are
gatekeepers
right it showed that they could actually
stop it
it showed that you know it would require
money
as all news organizations take
but that they can the same way that the
u.s election showed
that the tech platforms can do this they
just choose not to
there's no incentive to do that but this
is a time when lies
kill that's what kobe did but i would
actually carry that over into the
political sphere
and our political lives and governance
it may not seem like it but lies
kill and whether that's covid or
governance facebook youtube
twitter should take the exact same
measures
to make sure that the facts win
right right
uh well there's another question maria
it sort of circles around some
some of the stuff we've been talking
about which is it seems that now with
the draconian new i.t rules in india
big tech is being forced to do a
delicate dance between protecting their
users from their own government
and continuing to operate in the country
to chase huge growth
uh what do you think is the end game and
how do you see this dance play out
i hope that the leadership of the
platforms gain some balls
i mean because they have the power
right and again any large
company has a responsibility to the
public it serves
i would put that above shareholders
although the incentives
aren't as clear-cut and so i hope that
as it navigates india i mean there's
there have been a lot of
stories that have come out from india
about you know the
the people the facebook head working
with the bjp you know there's so many
what you talked about in terms of the
pakistan and india that riot the mob
that formed that came after people
here's it's a delicate balance and it
will take leadership
and i think that will determine the kind
of company
that facebook will become and like
everything if they don't
define the problem i'm going to use
their own words against them if they
don't define the problem
they can't solve it and as long as we're
looking at
paleo solutions like the facebook
oversight board
um disclosure um i joined the real
facebook oversight board with carol
cadwallider who broke the cambridge
analytica story
and shashana zubov who wrote
surveillance capitalism right
a whole bunch of other folks who really
it's time to say enough is enough
you've made enough money please show
real leadership because
this they will determine the way our
world works and
i guess to look for what can happen
right let's look at 19th century in the
united states
i it's kind of a similar time period if
you think about the robber barons right
the sweat shops
because if they kept making a lot of
money using sweatshops at the expense of
their people
then there's a price to pay as well what
did fdr franklin delano roosevelt do
right he came in with a whole bunch of
other things after that but i guess
i'm just saying those robber barons they
gave a lot to charity to assuage their
guilt
of what they've done this is that time
period
and enlightened self-interest on their
part
real leadership that's what we need and
i really look forward to it
frenemies
um one final question maria which is
what would be the differentiating factor
in a subscription model for twitter
content surfacing algorithms are still
in place would the spiciest most
inflammatory content still rise to the
top of the pile of what people see if
they're paying a monthly fee
not necessarily we have to see how how
twitter
rolls this out right uh because it's
very
easy it's relatively easy to change the
algorithms
uh you know for many many years
facebook sorry twitter was chronological
right but then it grew to a point where
then it personalized it here's
here's and that's the main problem right
think about what personalization
actually meant i mean when when the tech
guys were talking about it really really
early on i was like thinking
what do you mean like i can make up my
own reality
which is exactly what personalization
kind of allows you to do right that's
why we're in our own little truman shows
when the business model is not dependent
on advertising their incentive scheme
completely
changes uh twitter also has another
initiative
i think it's called blue sky where
they're looking at
technology solutions for these problems
today right
the algorithm changes if they're getting
if more of us uh subscribe just like
with zoom
or with microsoft teams right you don't
see those platforms manipulating us
in fact they make it easy for us to do
these types of events well once twitter
shifts to a subscription model
it must keep the subscription the
subscriber happy
and being happy means that i'm able to
uh get the news well that's me most
people are on twitter for the news right
so i'm hoping i don't know this is a
time when we should be throwing
spaghetti
against the wall and i guess one of the
worst things that i
keep seeing is that the social media
platforms
refuse to throw spaghetti against the
wall that would
actually help prevent the worst abuses
so
for example right like we'll say hey
uh you you can take this down and then
they'll say but
how and then they'll dive into the a
rabbit hole of exactly like what does a
woman
what does breast mean is it this that's
like that's
atomizing to meaninglessness it's the
principle of it right go back
uh if you are and now i'll shut up on
this
because i don't want iran because i
really do think there are people there
trying to
find the answer but their level of
denial and obfuscation
this needs to stop so they can truly
find a solution
and i have great confidence that once
they define the problem
the same way everyone around the world
seeing it
they will find the solution
maya just one final question what would
you say to the rest of us who may care a
little easier than you
who also want to speak truth to power
i think you're doing it right uh i'm
going to quote this
last op-ed of george schultz which he
published in december of 2020 he had
been a
a diplomat for a hundred i mean he was
100 years old and he died earlier this
year
and the reason why i focused on that is
because
the lesson of this hundred years on
earth
was very simple and i'll summarize it in
two statements
he said what he found out in negotiating
all these treaties was that when you
have
trust in the room everything is possible
without trust nothing
is possible you can take that all the
way from nations
to individual my best advice to some of
our managers
is has really been to be vulnerable
because the only time when we can
really listen is when we open ourselves
up
meaning you are vulnerable when you open
yourself up that way
you see new views you listen
and you can find something that's why
trust
happens so what the social media
platforms have done
is to put us in our most defensive
to turn us into attack dogs and destroy
trust
and that is extremely worrying for me
both at an individual level and at a
nation-state level
thank you maria we'll end on that note
then
thank you so much for all that you do
thank you for inspiring us
same to you thank you for having me
you