hi all my name is patrick hicilios i'm
representing
the company an isp and
mobile operator and tv provider in the
nordic and
baltics and if you want to know more
about helia company
please visit our homepage
teliacompany.com
so i'm glad accessnow
provides access to a database on
transparency reports and now also gives
access
to this event about transparency
reporting
and thanks for inviting the elia company
although i understand our reporting is
one of the most read
pieces on our homepage it's difficult
for me to know
what you watching this event are looking
for
and how therefore for us to improve
so please have a look and give us
feedback
on how to improve
both positives and negatives thanks
atelia company we say law enforcement
disclosure reporting and not
transparency report
because we do transparency in all
areas of sustainability that might be
children's rights or environment or our
work in the supply chain
gender equality and so forth
and also on human rights impact
assessments
the following are the two starting
points for
tla companies reporting first and
foremost
we encourage states to be
transparent themselves about their use
and scope of surveillance we welcome
therefore the yearly transparency
reports published by the governments
in such as
sweden denmark finland norway and
lithuania
so please do encourage states to do
transparency reporting to supplement
those
reports from states our aim
at taylor company is to contribute to
meaningful
and oversight and discussion
so we publish these reports twice a year
a full report with context and other
information
each march and then an update of the law
enforcement
requests each october and we've done so
since 2013.
secondly as a side effect our work to be
transparent helps us
in getting things in order because when
we publish
information it needs to be correct
over the years we've added additional
transparency
to the actual statistics of law
enforcement
requests so in in addition to
our statistics statistics on the
day-to-day thousands of conventional
lawful intercept requests we also
provide information on
unconventional requests and the number
of such
that's about blocking shutdowns new
legislation etc
and how we have dealt with those
secondly we have added links to laws
providing states with direct access
three we have also added links to laws
mandating operators to do
data retention for surveillance
we have also added the links to the
government's own reporting
and we've added information on the
extent of use of
cell tower dumps and lots of context
and more so i invite you to have a look
into our latest march
2020 report one feature
of talia companies reporting which i
don't know if other companies do
is that our figures are audited just is
our financials
so deloitte look into our figures
and also ask sometimes about supporting
documentation
so that they can audit our figures
so which are the main challenges as to
this reporting we have a chapter in our
march report on challenges
and omissions the biggest challenge
notably is that the statistics on number
of surveillance requests
don't provide the full picture
governments also have
direct access real-time network access
without requests regarding such direct
access
till a company has no insight into the
extent of surveillance
when who and what and cannot provide
statistics
what we can do as we do in our reporting
is to publish links to such relevant
laws
in our respective markets and as part of
the global network initiative the gni
we address this salient issue of direct
access
another challenge i wanted to mention
here is that some readers try to compare
figures
between the countries several factors
make it
difficult to compare the statistics
between countries
thalia of course had have different
market shares in different markets
and also the working methods within the
authorities differ and we don't know
about
their priorities and working with us
so a very short summary thanks accessnow
for arranging this important event
i myself look forward to
look at the stream on our reporting
first why we do it well our
responsibility
is to respect your privacy
but there are laws which mandate
us to hand over data for surveillance
what we can do is to be transparent
about that how many requests we get and
the context about
on such requests some things
i try to highlight in this intervention
one is that
telia company statistics is audited
and also a main challenge for
transparency
is direct access where we cannot provide
statistics
so do give us feedback positive
negative and on how we can improve
my twitter handle is pottwick underscore
hisselius many thanks
and take care thanks