well hello everyone um on behalf of
accessnow
rightscon and our co-sponsor of this
event bsr
i want to thank you to for taking time
out of your day to join us to talk about
transparency reporting
ten years ago google released a public
report the first of its kind
detailing how they responded to
government's requests for user data
since then other companies have followed
suit accessnow launched our transparent
report in index in 2014
to compile these reports and highlight
trends and indexes noted over 70
companies worldwide releasing
transparency reports
however some challenges still remain
though transparency reporting has become
more common for tech companies
non-tech companies who increasingly use
and hold our data
have not called onto the practice and
within the tech sector fewer companies
have been consistently releasing reports
the larger picture of reporting also
presents important questions
over the last 10 years has transparency
reporting truly been effective in
holding government surveillance in check
and how is reported aided in trust
building between companies and their
users
the goal of this event is to reflect on
these questions and more
to note gaps you need to be filled and
to look ahead to the future of
transparency reporting
we're grateful to the wide range of
speakers who have joined us today to
address these topics
as you can see we have a very packed
agenda for the next 19 minutes
and we encourage you to keep a
conversation going after the event
please feel free to share your questions
for our speakers in the chats
and we'll try to get to them at the end
of the q a section
it's now my pleasure to welcome nicole
karlabach the global head of business
and human rights of verizon
and michael samway president of the bhr
group
to join us today to talk about the early
stages of transparency reporting
thank you etc and thank you to access
now and
to bsr for co-sponsoring this important
and timely event
nicole and i have worked together
for nearly a decade and we have had long
winding
discussions about technology and human
rights and we have also had
brief and urgent discussions on matters
of freedom expression and privacy
across the world so we'll try to
condense
those two types of discussions into a
fireside chat in just a few minutes
and we hope it sets the stage for a
deeper discussion
over the over the next 90 minutes so
thank you again to access and bsr
so let's begin nicole i think it would
be helpful if you give us
more background um on yourself and your
role
uh you're the head of global business
and human rights at a major technology
and media company
um and then if you can set the stage and
give us context
on how your role uh interacts with the
concept of transparency and why it's
important to the company
yeah so thank you to access and also to
bsr for having us
and um thanks michael i'm looking
forward to a conversation
with you today on these topics um
as you said i head up the business and
human rights program at verizon where
a dedicated team providing centralized
leadership and guidance on the ways our
core
business products services operations
strategy intersect with human rights
issues including issues like
privacy free expression the right to be
free from discrimination
and our efforts in our efforts were
building on a foundation for this work
that began at yahoo over a decade ago
which i know you know
a little bit about so while the core of
our approach to
managing addressing considering um
the human rights impacts of our business
hasn't changed all that much
in these last few years um
the issues that we're managing i think
it's fair to say have
considerably evolved and arguably become
more challenging and more complex and
i think the year 2020 of course has been
like no other in terms of highlighting
societal challenges and also the role of
technology
in our daily lives has been
perhaps never so evident and never so
important
as it is now so as a result of all of
this the responsible development and
deployment of technology
that takes account of human rights
considerations i think has become
increasingly paramount and so the
conversation that we're having today
about transparency reporting
um in this space i think is very timely
um
as well in in light of the fact that
we're coming up on the 10th anniversary
of the un guiding principles on business
and human rights the ungps
and you know despite that there's been i
think significant growth in
the business and human rights field
broadly over the past decade and that
connections in particular between tech
and human rights have become better
understood
um there's still room to go in
mainstreaming these topics across
business within organizations and more
broadly
and part of that is sharing information
communication and being
transparent so transparency reporting
being a critical part of that
it's sort of a unique time to be
discussing these issues in that wider
context
and of course michael you've worked with
companies with civil society with
governments
um in the field of tech and human rights
you know over this
last decade and and even beyond that so
maybe you could share a bit about your
background some of your
work and and give us your sense about
the origins of transparency reporting
and
you know how it's evolved over time
thank you nicole um and you've really
covered uh
kind of the present and the importance
and timeliness of this topic
now and i'll try to um rewind the clock
about 20 years to the early 2000s
and i guess i should begin by saying i
currently do
public policy advisory work for tech
companies and for civil society
organizations on
tech and human rights i teach as an
adjunct faculty member
at georgetown school of foreign service
and probably most
relevantly for this discussion i was at
yahoo for 10 years
and was a deputy general counsel i was
there from 2000 to 2010.
so the early and mid 2000s was really a
period of global
expansion for the technology companies
that existed at the time
so i would say principally yahoo
microsoft
google hardware companies like cisco
that led to what are some now well
documented challenges
in international markets including china
that in turn led to a call for a code of
conduct around freedom of expression and
privacy
or intensive negotiations uh that
culminated
in the 2008 launch of the global network
initiative a multi-stakeholder
initiative made up of technology
companies civil society members
press freedom advocates socially
responsible investors and academics
and a cornerstone of the gni was and
is accountability
and a core component of accountability
is transparency
so if i could just offer one anecdote i
recall where i was
although not the exact date we were in
the offices of the center for democracy
and technology in early 2010
and a colleague from google approached
us in this small confidential kind of
trusted setting
and announced that google would be
issuing
a report it was not yet called a
transparency report but would be issuing
a report
[Music]
giving information on the law
enforcement demands
that google had received and it would
include information on numbers of
disclosures and types of disclosures
and i have to say at the time
given that i had worked closely and
regularly with
yahoo's global law enforcement team on
public safety
national security related issues and
speech and privacy
issues i was surprised
i thought it was bold and i have to
admit that there was concern
in the industry but i looked
10 years later and i think
that is the norm it's a standard across
industry
um if i can misuse kind of a public
policy concept
google essentially shifted the overton
window
and i should also note that there was
successful important advocacy by groups
like the electronic frontier foundation
cdt itself and others
who had pushed for transparency in
particular on the u.s
side um and google really um
took a bold step and what i um
i i want to kind of close that anecdote
by note in
there's a lot more work to do and and i
think we can
talk about that as as we continue the
discussion um
but i want to come back to you nicole
and
ask you about your role leading a
business and human rights program
and describing for us how transport
transparency reporting kind of fits
inside the company in the broader
kind of cons inside the broader concept
of transparency
yeah and i mean i think that the history
that you shared is so important to sort
of understand as we
you know consider where this fits within
um companies
you know where it's fit over time and
where it fits today
at verizon our work rests on a set of
key pillars and
one of those pillars is accountability
and transparency as you were
alluding to and i think you know we
in our company recognize that
transparency is an important way that we
can communicate about
how um how how governments are
impacting uh human rights through their
law
and through their policy and also about
the role of companies
and respecting human rights and it's for
that reason
or those reasons that our company has
placed a high priority
on transparency reporting for um
a long time now really since you know
the origins of this program
and all the way back to yahoo
and so to give a little bit of an
example i was sort of
thinking about you know the evolution
just within our company of these
practices and
when verizon media our tech and media
arm
was formed a couple of years ago
following yahoo's acquisition by verizon
um we had as a first priority really
among
you know what we were working on at the
time post acquisition to publish a new
transparency report
transparency reporting hub really for
verizon media that would house the
transparency
um reports and information for our
house of brands including brands like
yahoo and aol
and at the time we were really bringing
together a number of different
internet technology media brands and we
had this opportunity so we set out to
standardize reporting on government
requests for user data content
moderation
produce new and combined sets of
disclosures
that went beyond what any of our
individual brands had done before
and i think part of why we were you know
maybe
poised and able to take advantage of
that opportunity that came about and do
some advan
make some advancements in our
transparency reporting was
partially because we have a dedicated
team in place in our company who's
focused on these issues for
the duration of its existence um and was
able to step in at a time of significant
transition and transformation and
realize that transparency and
accountability are premium
in this work and that there should be
attention on those early on
but also you know that our team and our
company had been engaged on these issues
in discussion with external
you know partners groups organizations
so i was thinking back
when i first started at yahoo the first
conversation i
joined in the global network initiative
the multi-stakeholder
organization in this space was actually
around
practices in the transparency reporting
area
there was a new practice around
government
reporting on government requests for
content removal and at the time you know
that was sort of the next
generation um step from
the government uh request for user data
and what had been reported on those
and so it was an early conversation
about you know what was best practice
what was emerging like what could be
learned
um and those conversations in gni have
only been
you know rich over time and helped
inform our our practice
and of course we've also engaged with
other groups that have come up over
more recent years like ranking digital
rights that's looked at what is
meaningful transparency and how does
transparency impact
uh practice you know and how can you
think about that especially as a
someone who works on these issues within
the company that's been a useful
dialogue to be part of
and then of course we've had so many of
these type of discussions
um at access now's rights con over the
years
so you know really without this sort of
engagement um
i think the whole practice you know
wouldn't be as rich as it is today
so i know we're almost nearing our time
um
to wrap up michael what do you see can
you give us your forecast for the
challenges the opportunities
ahead you know look into the future and
tell us what's coming
um i'm not sure how far into the future
i can look but i will
note that i think the challenges and the
opportunities are really
one and the same and i thought that um
we could just spend a minute on on
three of the challenges slash
opportunities
the first is audience and i think it's
important to think about transparency
reporting
and have to step back and think about
who the audience is
for these reports but really for the
concept of transparency overall
it's consumers it's governments
it's academics it's civil society
organizations
um it's the press it's um
really it's all of those it's not a
single one
and that leads to kind of the second
area with where i think we have both
challenges and opportunities
[Music]
these are the most among the most
innovative companies in history
but i feel like from that first moment
when i heard about what became a
transparency report and when i
subsequently
saw it a few weeks later in 2010
there hasn't been sufficient innovation
there are some kind of companies that
are noteworthy in the user friendliness
and digestibility
of the transparency reports that they
publish and credit to them and i
hope that some of those steps become
more standardized
across industry in the u.s and outside
for certain but it feels like there's
much more room
on kind of understanding the various
audiences
and making a tool and the same way you
would design
you know a really useful and well used
product
um to think about transparent
transparency reporting in that way
the third challenge and opportunity
for the companies and i look forward to
the to the panel discussion
afterward is really around breadth and
depth
i think we need to think more
holistically about transparency as a
cornerstone
of accountability and not just
focus on law enforcement demands
whether in the u.s outside the u.s and
there can be more detail we need we need
that we need more detail the snowden
revelations
showed that sort of multi-stakeholder
advocacy
could lead to advances in transparency
reporting
but we need to think about it in the
same context
but i would give an example of diversity
equity and inclusion
and i don't mean just in hiring or in
the composition
of companies but in the design
development deployment of products dei
principles need to be a core part of
that
and we need to have companies sort of
think
holistically about how they're
transparent
with the entire community stakeholders
that i mentioned we need more
certainly on law enforcement more on
content moderation more on political ads
more on general consumer data collection
activities and you mentioned nicole
ranking digital rights
and that project and the indicators i
think um provide us all really a good
starting place
and and a road map um so
i'll kind of close by saying that google
did indeed
[Music]
move us forward it was a it was an
enormous leap and credit
to the company um but if i could for the
runners
kind of among us um
note it's been more like kind of a
corporate
walk or a corporate race um you know
leisurely moving steadily with a goal
but the stakes are too high and it feels
like we need
an olympian effort and um and i look
forward to
hearing the panel discussion and seeing
the questions i feel like there's much
much more to do
here and credit to those who have been
innovators in the space and thank you
again
to access send to bsr for hosting us
well thank you so much to you michael
and to nicole for that insightful
conversation
and we've asked a few companies to
present in their reports as well as
greg walters from the sustainability
accounting standards board
to talk about transparency reporting
metrics so we'll also hear from patrick
cacillius of taylor company
from cacao and from uttara sivaram of
uber
on their approaches to transparency
reporting
hi all good morning uh afternoon evening
uh wherever you may be
my name is greg waters and i am from the
sustainability accounting standards
board
most often known as sasby so thanks so
much to accessnow for for allowing me a
few minutes to speak
here and plug an important research
project that's ongoing
at sasby so we are an independent
nonprofit standard setting organization
and we're dedicated to facilitating the
disclosure of financially impactful
environmental and social issues from
companies
to their investors we exist because we
believe that capital markets are a
critical level for for achieving a more
sustainable and just
future our standards are industry
specific and designed to capture a
subset of information
sustainability information that is most
likely to impact financial performance
of companies
and we are actively backed by a group of
investors with around 60 trillion
dollars in assets under management
and we are being our standards are being
used to
report by about 500 different companies
uh
across 70 different industries and that
growth is about 350
year on year so we're really excited by
the momentum we've achieved
as an organization in driving for more
comparable and complete
sustainability disclosure
this this audience understands why
transparency around things like data
privacy and content governance are
really important societally
but there's also this financial impact
angle and that's why sasby has gotten
involved so i thought i'd spend a moment
or two
speaking to that so the first line item
i would say
is on the revenue side and i think if we
think about content governance as
what users see on a given platform and
when
that really is critical to you know a
company's business strategy how they
attract and retain not just users
but also advertisers and that balance of
um
you know monitoring for harmful content
while protecting user freedom of
expression
we see different approaches and
strategies taken by different platforms
depending on the design
of their platform from the cost
perspective
uh of course we now know that thousands
if not tens of thousands of people
at various companies are are reviewing
content
uh and uh that's obviously it's a
significant form of investment uh the
other would be the capital expenditure
associated with automated flagging
systems using techniques like machine
learning
and the last thing i would mention on
the financial side would be the
regulatory piece
in that we we know that the u.s and the
european commission as well with the
digital services act
are mulling proposed changes that would
severely uh potentially impact
how companies not just moderate but also
kind of you know really show content to
users so
uh major implications there in terms of
you're thinking of this with an investor
lens in terms of risk return profile
you know how might a different company's
platform be impacted by different
regulations is
clearly clearly of interest so in terms
of transparency reporting
obviously they're critical for
accountability to a broad variety of
stakeholders but
also the metrics that have been
developed and are being used by number
of companies
on areas like content moderation are
also of interest to investors
so sasby standards actually already use
a number of transparency reporting
metrics so these include
information about law enforcement data
sharing as well as
content removal requests from
governments the next piece for sasby is
we are now
evaluating potential changes to our
standards to include
voluntary content moderation and content
governance themes
so really really eager to uh to hear
from companies and subject matter
experts
such as the people on the panel that's
about to come up here
uh we are we're open we're a market
informed and consensus and stakeholder
driven organization
in terms of understanding what are the
most important uh issues and the best
ways to be capturing uh
the performance of companies on this
topic so so eager to connect
so so thanks again to accessnow for
having me and allowing me to to plug
this project
and uh looking forward to the discussion
take care everyone hi all
my name is patrick hicelius i'm
representing
the company an isp and
mobile operator and tv provider in the
nordic and
baltics and if you want to know more
about taylor company
please visit our homepage
teliacompany.com
so i'm glad accessnow
provides access to a database on
transparency reports and now also gives
access
to this event about transparency
reporting
and thanks for inviting telia company
although i understand our reporting is
one of the most read
pieces on our home page it's difficult
for me to know
what you watching this event are looking
for
and how therefore for us to improve
so please have a look and give us
feedback
on how to improve
both positives and negatives thanks
atelia company we say law enforcement
disclosure reporting
and not transparency report because we
do transparency
in all areas of sustainability
that might be children's rights or
environment
or our work in the supply chain
gender equality and so forth
and also on human rights impact
assessments the following
are the two starting points for the
companies reporting
first and foremost we encourage states
to be transparent themselves about their
use
and scope of surveillance we
welcome therefore the yearly
transparency reports
published by the governments in
such as sweden denmark finland
norway and lithuania so
please do encourage states to do
transparency reporting
to supplement those reports from states
our aim at taylor company is to
contribute to meaningful
and oversight and discussion
so we publish these reports twice a year
a full report with context and other
information
each march and then an update of the
law enforcement requests each october
and we've done so since 2013.
secondly as a side effect our work to be
transparent helps us
in getting things in order because when
we publish
information it needs to be correct
over the years we've added additional
transparency
to the actual statistics of law
enforcement
requests so in in addition to
our statistics statistics on the
day-to-day thousands of conventional
lawful intercept requests we also
provide information on
unconventional requests and the number
of such
that's about blocking shutdowns new
legislation etc
and how we have dealt with those
secondly we have added links
to laws providing states with direct
access
three we have also added links to laws
mandating
operators to do data retention for
surveillance
we have also added the links to the
government's own reporting
and we've added information on the
extent of use of
cell tower dumps and lots of context
and more so i invite you to have a look
into our latest march
uh 2020 report
one feature of telia companies reporting
which i don't know if other companies do
is that our figures are audited
just as our financials so deloitte look
into our
figures and also ask sometimes about
supporting documentation so that they
can audit our figures
so which are the main challenges as to
this reporting we have a chapter in our
march report
on challenges and omissions the biggest
challenge
notably is that the statistics on number
of surveillance requests
don't provide the full picture
governments also have direct
access real-time network access without
requests
regarding such direct access till a
company has no insight
into the extent of surveillance when who
and what and cannot provide statistics
what we can do as we do in our reporting
is to publish links to such relevant
laws in our respective markets
and as part of the global network
initiative the gni we address this
salient issue
of direct access another challenge
i wanted to mention here is that some
readers try to compare figures
between the countries several factors
make it
difficult to compare the statistics
between countries
thiele of course had have different
market shares in different markets
and also the working methods within the
authorities
differ and we don't know about their
priorities and working with us
so a very short summary thanks access
now
for arranging this important event
i myself look forward to
look at the stream on our reporting
first why we do it well our
responsibility
is to respect your privacy
but there are laws which mandate
us to hand over data for surveillance
what we can do is to be transparent
about that how many requests we get and
the context about
on such requests some things i
try to highlight in this intervention
one is that
clearly company statistics is audited
and also a main challenge
for transparency is direct access
where we cannot provide statistics so
do give us feedback positive negative
and on how we can improve uh my twitter
handle
is patrick underscore hisselius
many thanks and take care
thanks digital responsibility for
protecting user privacy
cacao transparency report
warm greetings from korea we are kakao's
policy team
and we are honored to be speaking to you
at writescon about our transparency
report
cacao makes a better world with people
and technology
as a mobile platform company the privacy
and protection of our users
is top priority our goal for the
transparency report
is to present a comprehensive data set
on the requests
and status of requests made by
government agencies for user information
this is one of the actions we take to
strengthen transparency
and ensuring the digital security of our
users
since 2012 we have been publishing the
transparency report
every six months here we see the
statistical data
that are included in the transparency
report for the first half of this year
we report the number of requests made by
the korean government regarding user
information
and the status of cases and accounts
duly processed
the type of information that the
government may request for
are as follows communication data
communication restricting measures
communication confirmation data
and search and seizure warrants cacao
does not process requests
for individual user information by
government agencies
without respecting official procedures
we make great efforts to increase
people's access to information
by improving the readability of our
content we present
clear explanations on the terms
standards
and procedures relevant to the
disclosure of user information
in simple language on our website the
transparency report
is a part of cacao's efforts to fulfill
our digital responsibility
first of all it is significant in terms
of the protection of user rights
it allows us to transparently report and
release data
on how we are handling government
requests for user information
secondly as cacao observes due processes
on requests by government agencies we
believe
that it is our responsibility entrusted
to us by users
to disclose such data in the
transparency report so that everyone may
view it
lastly kakao's transparency report not
only encompasses our endeavor to ensure
user rights
but it also expresses our pride in
keeping our users information
strictly guarded according to legal
procedures
in such a dynamic and unstable digital
environment
we make every effort to protect our
users rights and to fulfill our
corporate responsibilities and promises
committed to the promises we have made
cacao strives to provide
open and resourceful information for our
users
in light of the kovan 19 crisis we have
published the kakao kova 19 report
and aims to support the public with data
and to share the ongoing national and
global efforts in overcoming its
challenges
as korea's leading digital daily life
platform
cacao reveals analysis results on the
pre
and post-pandemic changes in user data
of cacao services
and the cacao coven 19 report please
contact our team
to learn more about our analyses let us
all safely
and wisely maneuver through these times
take care
thank you very much hi everyone
i'm uttara sivaram and i lead uber's
public policy work on privacy and
security
including the publication of our
government transparency report
first of all thank you to access now for
hosting this event
transparency reporting is incredibly
important to holding companies
and governments accountable and it's
good to take a step back and see how
this practice has grown
and evolved over the past decade uber
published its first transparency report
for a ride-sharing business in 2016
following in the footsteps of some of
the companies being featured today
but in addition to counting the requests
we received from law enforcement
our report was the first in the mobility
space to include
regulatory requests for data from
government agencies like the california
public utilities commission
and the new york city taxi and limousine
commission and that's because our
business is a little different
our technology connects riders and
drivers both online and in the real
world
a world that's regulated by agencies
overseeing things like transportation
energy and construction and the data
they usually ask us for involves uber
trips
where people go by using our platform
but even after names are excluded from
this data
this information still carries the risk
that passengers can be re-identified
by examining patterns of movement and
combining them with publicly available
information
for example if someone takes a ride to
the grocery store from their home
and the origin and destination of that
trip is disclosed to the government
it can be a simple matter of using the
yellow pages to identify who took that
trip
and that's why in every case we work
closely with government agencies to
understand the legal basis for their
request
and make sure we're not we're only
providing what is strictly necessary
beyond that we use technical privacy
methods like coarsening the resolution
of location data
and time stamps to reduce the uniqueness
of every trip
by doing that we reduce the risk that
this information can be used to identify
our
users and in many cases regulators have
altered their requirements in
recognition of the privacy risks their
requests can create
by publishing this report and including
requests from these types of agencies
we want to stimulate a much needed
conversation about government access to
data
both within and outside of law
enforcement and for every year we've
released our report
we've seen a steady rise in the number
of these requests
as well as the number of users impacted
as people turn to connected mobility
options
that they can access from their phone
moving forward
it's really important that we not only
urge more companies to release
transparency reports
but also encourage a greater variety of
companies to participate
that's the only way to fully capture how
data flows between the private and
public sectors
furthermore having a fuller picture of
government data sharing across different
sectors
can help inform better and smarter
regulation
addressing how governments can and
should access information about users
we can all i'm sure envision a world
that's powered by
smart uh data-driven public policy
as well as a user base that feels
empowered and in control of their
of their own data that's why in addition
to publishing these reports
we as an industry need to invest in
solutions that leverage
aggregated and anonymized data that can
drive positive social outcomes
without putting consumer privacy at risk
there's a tremendous opportunity to
learn from one another and improve
transparency reporting
and i know uber is eager to work with
many of the companies and consumer
advocates here today to accomplish that
thank you and i'm happy to stay on
afterwards for for any questions
all right thanks everyone for
joining us today um that concludes the
the presentations and
the videos so now we're going to go to
the live
content we've got an amazing panel
of speakers here today and
without further ado we'll get started
i'd love to hear reactions to that we've
heard from um speakers all over the
world from a variety of types of
companies
um those who are you know around this
process 10 years ago and before
as well as those who've just started
about half the folks on this panel
work at organizations or companies that
didn't exist
10 years ago but we've grown with power
comes responsibility
with user growth comes abuse reports and
disinformation campaigns
search warrants and even executive
orders
um in my perch at access now leading our
business and human rights work and as
general counsel
um i've been able to watch this trend
and i would argue that
outside events even crises have driven
reporting
voluntary disclosures are not high on
the list for most startups or even
maturing
tech companies looking at the access now
transparency reporting index we see a
bump of reports
in around 2014-2015 i would argue that's
due to the revelations of mass
surveillance
that edward snowden brought to the world
civil society jumped on these moments
and others in 2016 like the brexit
campaign the 2016 u.s presidential vote
as well as the me too movement to drive
reporting on terms of service and
community guideline enforcement
as well as advertising transparency and
i'd love for the panelists to refute my
theses
but i do think that most tech companies
like other institutions
know that transparency builds trust and
can even help
keep other stakeholders in check so
we'll ask this
panel what trends they're seeing in the
coming years
how we've gotten to where we are now and
how all tech companies
uh including you know any number of new
sectors
who exist now or who are coming online
can
better get her get ahead of their curve
on reporting
and respect the human rights of their
communities so without
further ado i think it's it's proper to
go straight to
to google to alex walden
who is a veteran of the company now
global
head of human rights this is as we've
heard the company that pioneered
transparency reporting 10 years ago
i'd love to ask alex why google started
reporting um is there lore have you
heard stories
um but perhaps more importantly uh given
the downtrend
in some reports a lot of companies put
out one and they're done
um as well as the the rather notorious
reputation at google to to start
projects and then kill them
um why has google continued and even
expanded its reporting
um thanks alex
peter um and thank you to access now
again for hosting this conversation
human rights transparency and tech is
near and dear to my heart and is really
core to
the work that i do at google
um so why did we start doing
transparency reporting
if you rewind and some of this is what
michael and
nicole hit on but if you rewind back to
the early 2000s that was really the
early days of when companies started
receiving
government requests for user data
government requests for information or
to remove content
um and so as we started to get these
requests
and push back on them we started to feel
like they're
it was an important principle for us to
think about what it meant for us to be
transparent with our users about both
what the company was doing
and what governments were doing the
interaction between the two
uh and so you know over a decade ago
we launched this effort to provide some
of that information publicly
then in september of 2010 it actually
uh became itself a transparency report
and for us
we really do think it is about our users
trust and it is also of course our
commitment to human rights
and both of those pieces are important
to how we continue to think about it
uh since then we have launched i think
we are now
at 12 different transparency reports so
it is something that we remain committed
to
we started with user data we went to
government requests for
um removal of content and now we have
reports on things like copyright
we have think reports on things like um
traffic
uh internet traffic um regarding ads
and um in 2018 we launched the youtube
transparency report so we really
have continued to iterate and expand on
the breadth of areas of the business
where we think it's important for
us to share with users both how we're
interacting with government
and how we're enforcing our own policies
against our products
thanks alex yeah i think one area um as
well that that google and others have
started reporting is around uh
demographics and staff data and i think
uh building off michael samway's remarks
maybe we can hear more about that
um cool um i want to swing
over to uh to reddit um actually we are
going in in order of uh seniority here
reddit uh was started in 2005. it's
mature despite its image
um it was started on the the east coast
it's a social news aggregation and web
content rating and discussion forum
app and website uh with up to 52 million
daily active users
globally that's up a lot during covid
and uh i think we want to hear from
jessica xu the director of policy there
about how their reporting has innovated
over the past uh couple of years with
reddit being really at the heart of
social movements as well as the the
covet 19 response
um jessica welcome
thank you absolutely happy to speak to
those issues so reddit
um issued its first transparency report
in 2014
in the bump of transparency reports that
you just cited
um we're proud that we've been doing
them for so long and we're proud that
um we've been expanding them um every
year
and also that we've been recognized as a
leader in the transparency reporting
space so for example
we were the only company to receive a
perfect score in the last eff who has
your back evaluation of company
transparency
and so we really do think um deeply
about this and
it's important to us especially because
of reddit's unique structure
so we follow is your familiar community
moderation model where the users
themselves on a volunteer basis are
highly involved
in our content moderation operations
so you know a statistic that is in our
transparency report that we disclosed is
that actually
more than 99.7 of all
content removals on reddit actually
happen at the user level
by these volunteer moderators and so
because
the users and the public really are
partners with us in
moderating the reddit platform it's
really important that we
disclose this data with them so that we
can um
have a healthy relationship where our
policies are under
interactions are understood um like
other companies we used to focus only on
government requests
in our transparency disclosures um
but as i mentioned before we've been
expanding that out
and now it includes um reporting on
content removal actions that we take as
a company
in line with our content policy
um and that was a really kind of big
expansion for us we've been doing that
for the last
two to three years now and it taught us
a lot about
um how to do transparency reporting
and how to work cross-functionally with
partners in the company to kind of get
the data that you need
and i think that this is one of the the
biggest perceived barriers to
companies doing transparency reports
especially for smaller companies like
reddit
um you know we're only around 700
total employees right now um but
you know i think the biggest hurdle
that's perceived to reporting something
for the first time is making sure that
you actually have the data
tracked because of course if you don't
track it you can't disclose it
and so there's actually kind of a
year-long ahead of time preparation
process that needs to happen
um before you do your transparency
report because it may entail
tooling adjustments which takes um
engineering resources that are often
pretty constrained at smaller companies
but what i say when i'm talking to kind
of
my colleagues at smaller companies who
are thinking of transparency reporting
or they
want to do one but they don't think that
they have the data or they don't think
that they have the
right data is that it's really really
important not to let the perfect
be the enemy of the good um because you
know if you don't have a specific thing
tracked or you don't have it tracked for
the whole year
you know you might have an approximate
data point tract or
you know you could report for the data
that you have and then kind of start
tracking it and do a full one
next year it's important to think
creatively
about what's meaningful to disclose for
your platform in particular
because i think it's important that to
recognize that a meaningful transparency
report
is going to be really different for
every platform because we all represent
kind of different
models and different services and
products
and that's okay and i know that that can
sometimes be
frustrating for researchers and others
because they want to see
um in apples to apples comparison
of transparency reports across the
industry but the reality is that these
are not
apples to apples services reddit is very
different from google is very different
from uber
and our transparency reports each
reflect that
um and then kind of thoughts on
continuing to expand
transparency reporting and where the
trends are going in the future i think
it's very important to remember that
transparency
isn't just something that needs to
happen once a year twice a year
or quarterly or whatever your cadence is
with with your
reports um i think it's important to
think about transparency
as kind of a company value one of our
values is default open
and also think about how you can
integrate transparency efforts into the
things that you're doing
all year and so for example you know
2020 was a very particular year with
very particular challenges
and one of those challenges was the
racial justice reckoning in the united
states
and as a part of that national
conversation that we were having
um reddit updated our content policy to
more explicitly um prohibit hateful
content
um and when you're making a significant
um content policy update like that it's
really important to
measure it and see if it's working and
so you know while this might be
a deep dive that's not kind of
appropriate for the
um format of the annual transparency
report
we really wanted to communicate with our
users about what we were finding what we
were seeing
and so we created a dedicated subreddit
where we
talk about kind of interesting things
that we want to disclose to the users
but they
might not be right or fit into the
transparency report
and so we discussed statistics um that
we had found about
how much hateful content we had found on
reddit before and after the role change
and we also discussed you know who was
that hateful content targeted at
and that's a really important point
because one of the really great things
about transparency reporting
is that it helps you understand your own
business better and there's a really
strong business case to be made for
doing transparency reporting
because um i can now go to my trust and
safety team and say we've got
statistics here that say that most
hateful content on reddit
is involving racial issues and
kind of less hateful content is
involving kind of
other types of issues so that gives our
safety team
a lot of really valuable insights about
where they want to direct their efforts
and so um there's a there's a powerful
business case there um that you can make
because it ultimately
um saves some resources because we're
not misdirecting
and valuable engineering resources or
valuable trust and safety resources to
something
that's not going to end up having a
significant impact on the platform
thank you yeah um so many great points
there i think
uh you know and you really pulled out
your dependence on
those i guess volunteer moderators
they're not paid right and
with i think this was a necessity being
the mother of invention you're you were
a small company and i think you you
still are relatively small
despite these 50 million active users
and i'd love to hear more also about
your your global reach and so how do you
ensure that these policies that you roll
out
are understood and are respected when
even when you're dependent on volunteer
moderators
yeah absolutely that's um it's a
conversation that we're actively
thinking about in the company
um but i think what's great about kind
of the decentralized community
moderation model
is that it internationalizes and
localizes a lot better than a
centralized
um enforcement model
because you know for example something
like hate speech is
hugely contextually dependent it's
you know very sophisticated language it
relies on slang it's often coded
in the community moderators who are a
part of that community
are going to be able to recognize
something much better than
will be able to recognize it you know
sitting in san francisco we're sitting
in new york
or wherever we are so um we've been
focusing
on having more intentional conversations
with these moderators and kind of
creating moderator councils really where
we um
speak you know directly over zoom with
kind of groups of our moderators to just
understand what they're seeing so that
we can
um better direct our resources to
building things that are going to be
meaningful for them for keeping their
communities safe
thank you yeah i imagine uh you'll get
some up votes for that response
um let's uh let's move to yeah the other
uh company on our platform and i and on
our panel and i am going to pri
prioritize the companies here first uh
sean lee at
an even smaller firm discord even newer
only about five years old but
uh also growing a lot during the covid
pandemic while folks are at home and
looking to reach out and make social
connections
discord has been called slack for gamers
but uh
it's as rapidly expanding right beyond
that community
and you've done a lot of reporting
around trust and safety i want to say
you're the only firm that actually
reports the raw numbers
of all the user flags you get so i'd
love to hear about
um about your work there and just to
call out that you are the third usf
law alum joe dawns on this panel so
thanks for thanks for joining us sean
yeah absolutely happy happy to be here
and thanks to access now for for
um putting in all the hard work on on
such an important topic
um i i mean actually as jessica said
right like i think
meaningful transparency reporting is is
different across companies and
and i think that's actually where sort
of our uh
focus on on user flagging and and on
enforcement came from that i think a lot
of what we
sort of saw uh in the
really in in our user base and in the
discussion was that there was kind of
right like enforcement is often a black
box right and you don't
really know why decisions are being made
you don't know how they're being made
like there's just a lot of like
uncertainty of like oh like
why did my account get banned why did
this post come down and so i think we we
really approach it from that level of
like oh
this is an area where there is a lot of
uncertainty where there's a lot of
lack of clarity and and we wanted to to
address that for
for us i think the the transparency
reporting really comes from right like
it is about
showing users like what is going on and
users civil society right the press
like what's going on what it looks like
we i think the analogy is sort of that
like we look at these transparency
reports especially on the enforcement
side
kind of like um annual crime reports
that like a city or a state
issues right in the same way that you
sort of probably want to know what like
a city's crime rate looks like across
various things before you move there
it probably also makes sense that you
would kind of want to know what your
online space looks like before you go
there
um and so that that was sort of the rule
of um us us driving us
i i do think that there are a number of
companies now that are reporting you
know content
uh enforcement actions to some degree um
and
i think it really like depends on the
the company right on
you can imagine that at some of the
right like because discord tends to be a
more
private company um right like you have
to have an account you have to join
servers
you can't just sort of like drive by and
browse right like i think the reporting
metrics are different which is why i
think it is hard
um as mentioned to sort of compare these
things apples to apples but i think by
and large right the more transparency
that we can sort of bring on any of
these topics right the better it is
um the the one other thing on being a
small company yeah we're i think
we're a little bit over 280 people right
now
and we've done transparency reports now
for uh
three cycles so six months right a bit
over a year and a half
um i think it really is about just
prioritizing it and making sure that you
make those investments early right the
earlier on you spend time and resources
on
uh on being able to gather the data
collate the data and make sure that
you're presenting it well the easier it
is later on you don't have to wait right
like we
we went from you know sub 50 million
users to 100 million daily users over
the last year or so
and we just put a lot of that
infrastructure in in 2018 and that's all
paid off now
um i think as with a lot of companies as
with i think every company really here
certainly
you know we continue to try and make
transparency reporting better
and part of that is giving more context
right part of that is
uh making it accessible not just i think
to civil society that is interested in
sort of seeing what things look like
from uh from
across every platform but also like
talking actually directly to our users
and being like hey
when you report a user for harassment
this is what happens right this is what
it looks like this is like
what you can expect because i think at
the end of the day right like having a
model
that kind of is more maybe a little bit
closer to for example the american
judiciary model right where you
in most cases can actually see like how
a case went down
and what happened to it right like what
the entire sort of like steps in the
investigation
in the prosecution in the assessment
were right i think that engenders the
trust
in the company right in in the process
really that i think we're all looking
for
so yeah thanks sean yeah
i did want to ask you because you were
in tech i think your trust and safety
even before going to law school and then
came out
were there rules it sounds like you you
took a lot from the process of law
um and you know maybe in due process and
are applying it here are there
are there rules are there substantive
rules say the unguiding principles on
business and human rights
that you're also drawing from uh in the
law yeah absolutely i i mean i i think
that the fields of trust and safety and
and um content moderation and the law
are are pretty close right
not just for i think you know regulatory
reasons or stuff like that but i think
that
fundamentally the study of law is really
right like a study of the systems
you know contractual systems that allow
society to operate
um and i would say that you know from uh
both of course like
history and how governments currently
operate and of course the excellent work
that all of these ngos are doing right
there's a lot of stuff that we draw from
to understand
how trust and safety processes at
discord should work
awesome thanks and uh yeah i i think our
next speaker is going to be able to
provide that
that macro overview again dunstan
allison hope is
vice president at bsr bsr predates even
google founded in 1992
um and has really been was at the
forefront and continues
at the forefront of the trend of
business uh respect for
sustainability and human rights um
dunstan i'm wondering uh we've drilled
down from you know some of the largest
tech companies to
to some of the newest and smallest um
where
uh is the tech sector in comparison with
with uh the rest of the business
universe
um i i'd love for uh you to give us an
overview thanks
great thank you peter and i was going to
open by saying as
nearly 30 years old we're probably the
oldest organization on the on the panel
here
and you stole my line um so first of all
thank you for hosting this important
discussion we have been working with
companies
on issues of transparency across a range
of different issues
going back to the early 1990s and so
it's been really encouraging to see
the evolution of transparency reporting
in the technology industry over the past
decade or so and so when i think when it
comes to
issues of transparency around
relationships with law enforcement
agencies
how companies share data with law
enforcement agencies
as well as the broader sort of content
governance field
i think the technology industry stands
way ahead of other industries
and i think in reflecting about the past
decade of transparency reporting and
thinking about the next decade
the key sort of thought that came to
mind for me
is that what we'd like to see over the
next decade are more transparency
reports
published by companies outside of the
technology industry
so you know while the scope of
transparency reporting has evolved over
time i still think at their core
it covers the relationships companies
have with law enforcement agencies how
they
manage those relationships and how they
share data
with with law enforcement agencies but
of course tech companies are not the
only ones that have those relationships
tech companies are not the only
companies that share data with law
enforcement agencies
um whether it's the retail industry
financial services health care
travel automotive logistics all of those
industries in different ways have
relationships with law enforcement
and shared data and so what we would
like to see are reports from companies
across
a much wider range of issues um
sorry much wider range of industries
covering some of these
similar issues to those that are covered
in uh technology industry transparency
reports
now somebody made the point you know who
are the audiences transparency for what
purpose and i think for us
we undertake a lot of human rights due
diligence with companies and we find the
transparency reports to be a really
helpful contribution to that human
rights due diligence
and both because the company has got its
own sort of house in order ahead of time
and so there's an organized way of
understanding the company's impact on
privacy or other human rights for
example
and but also gives us a sort of head
start you know if we're doing a human
rights assessment for a telecoms company
or an internet company
a transparency report gives you a head
start on that process
and my fear is that when we do human
rights due diligence with companies in
other industries
we lack some of that insight on how they
might impact rights to privacy
or how other rights may be impacted as a
result of violations to privacy rights
and how that might manifest itself in a
range of other
contexts
and this isn't just voluntary i mean i
think when this started this was largely
voluntary right but we're moving to a
world where
where regulation is going to be driving
company
action right um can you tell us about
what might be coming
um in the eu especially around human
rights due diligence
yes so in the eu there are proposals for
mandatory human rights due diligence by
companies
and so that would be pretty much all
companies of all industries of of all
sizes
and they would be expected to apply an
approach that's very similar to that
which is in the u.n guiding principles
on business and human rights
and so that means reviewing your all of
your
activities across your entire value
chain against
all human rights and so what intrigues
me is if
companies from non-technology industries
do that effectively they are inevitably
going to come up against
how we share data with law enforcement
agencies and how we collaborate with law
enforcement agencies
so i wonder whether that a regulatory
process
is going to result in greater
understanding of these issues
in in other sectors and you know we were
founded
uh 30 years ago have you before many of
the technology companies that exist
today
exist so we're working on human rights
uh impacts with
companies from a range of other
industries and so that's something we're
really looking forward to
over the coming decade
thanks so much dunstan so
we've heard from the people producing
the reports we've heard from the
the person uh telling the companies to
produce the reports
and uh now i think it's time to hear
from those who actually use and read you
know who's the audience for these
uh this is the point where if we're were
at writescon i had asked a poll of who's
actually read a full transparency report
that that they didn't write
um and uh and and who's found them
useful in their work
um so maybe you at home can just raise
your hand
let's go to luis matsakis an experienced
journalist
at publications like wired in
motherboard is now writing out a
fantastic new non-profit journalism
project
rest of world founded by a former tech
exec rest of the world tells stories
where tech
culture and human experience collide
louise welcome and uh can you tell us uh
who are these
reports for and do you think they're
successful at telling a story
might be muted um we needed one person
can you hear me now yeah okay uh so i
think one thing that's good to note is
that rest of world
doesn't cover the west so that's sort of
where the name comes from we only cover
asia africa south america latin america
and sort of eastern europe so these
reports are incredibly important to our
reporting especially because these are
often governments that
are not transparent whatsoever and these
transparency reports give really
important insight into how these
governments are behaving
for example we saw india block tick tock
this year and it was really interesting
to look at tick tock's transparency
report and see
that india was one of the top uh you
know governments that was requesting
data from the company and that indicated
to me that they were you know
potentially upset with some of the
content on the platform right they had a
high number of removal requests
and you know that told me a story that
was different from the story that the
indian government
was saying which was that this was about
you know india china relations
uh but to me the transparency report
kind of showed that instead this was a
story about perhaps censorship
uh and about wanting to you know clamp
down on free expression so these reports
are incredibly important for showing
those sorts of trends
uh they really provide a lot of uh
insight into what governments are doing
in places where they don't really want
to speak to journalists like me
i think that there are ways that they're
not working for example
i have noticed that a lot of companies
turn to transparency reports
long after they have faced scandals over
content moderation
or over government surveillance for
example we saw that a lot with zoom this
year
and zoom actually missed the first
deadline to release its transparency
report and it's still sort of tbd about
when they're going to release it and
that brings up another point that
dunstan was making is that
we see a lot of companies like google
have a great legacy here with
transparency reporting but
i really want to see a wider range of
tech companies that are handling user
data
that's you know both like telcos that's
sort of like software like
uh zoom and i really want to see sort of
like not
just the major social platforms take up
this initiative and i hope that sort of
pressure from government regulation will
make that more possible
uh but this is a really important
practice and i think that uh you know a
lot of journalists like me would be
worse off without transparency reporting
thanks so much um yeah and uh can you
can you expand though and tell us more
about
um how this is useful uh in other
countries and
and whether this practice is actually
being taken up by non-western companies
uh we had i think just one
uh we had cacao give us a video as well
as was telia based in
europe but um the rest have been mostly
us companies we're talking about
yeah so this is not really happening in
a lot of places right i think both
because of government pressure and
because there's not a lot of other
incentives for companies to take up this
sort of reporting
but we have seen tick tock for example
which is a chinese company that's now
operating in you know
western countries take this up i think
because of the sorts of pressure
from governments from civil society from
journalists to open up about this data
because the nice thing about this data
and making it as public and as
transparent as possible
is that you know it allows you to kind
of escape a lot of the questions because
you can say look the data's all here
this is what we've seen
and it's important for it to be as
comprehensive as possible
and you can sort of see trends over time
especially you know i've seen some
companies take up this practice for a
couple of years and then say ah like no
one's really looking at it
uh and that's a huge problem because
it's really
you know a big indicator for us to see
okay you know
five years ago egypt was only sending 10
requests a quarter to this tech company
and now they're sending a 100 or you
know 200
that's a huge increase it indicates that
there's something happening there
between
the user base of that platform and the
government another
big uh factor that i really like to see
or a big
reporting metric is how often are those
uh requests denied because that tells me
that there's some sort of overreach
happening there right like if most of
the requests are accepted then it's
perhaps you know there's a good
relationship there between law
enforcement
and the platform and that's not
necessarily a negative thing but if a
high percentage of those requests are
getting denied that indicates to me that
that government is maybe you know
overreaching into people's privacy um
and it's good to see the platform sort
of standing up in that way right it's
not a good sign
if a tech company is accepting every
single request they get from every
government that's a very bad sign really
so you know seeing those sorts of
metrics can be really helpful
to understand how governments are
interacting with tech platforms
um and also just to see sometimes when
they're they don't seem to be
intervening at all
um because that also tells me that
there's maybe you know potential
problems there i think there's sort of a
good balance
where you know law enforcement and
governments do want to interact with
these platforms you know do want to
participate in safety
in legitimate cases um but the
transparency reports are the only way to
sort of see
to what extent that is happening and how
that relationship is evolving over time
right and you can track the rates of
compliance and and it seems like
governments are learning better how to
request data and demand data from
companies right
thanks great so
um another key stakeholder group that
has used these reports and really made
the numbers
meaningful uh is is of course academia
and uh we're
glad to welcome elizabeth ranieres i was
affiliated with harvard's car center
as well as the berkman client center but
is now
interim policy at ranking digital rights
um the fantastic foundation founded by
um rebecca mckinnon a project of the new
america foundation
um and elizabeth uh i'd love to hear
more about um
where you see reporting going and where
really ranking digital rights is
is leading uh the reporting towards um
as uh uh as we passed ten years
thanks peter and thanks to access now
for hosting
so ranking digital rights has been uh
publishing a corporate accountability
index since
2015. in 2015 we ranked 16 companies on
31 indicators and in our forthcoming
2020 index
we'll be ranking 26 companies on 58
indicators so
it gives you a sense that norms really
are starting to emerge
and consensus is starting to build on
both normative and non-normative
standards
um but it's still challenging because as
you noted peter this was
uh this trend really emerged in part uh
after the snowden revelations and so
what we still see
is a residual imbalance between
transparency on
government demands and versus
enforcement of companies own
internal rules and policies things like
terms of service enforcement
and this is also of course partly due as
some others mentioned to
things like gni membership which focuses
on government requests
um but for example in the 2015 rdr index
not a single company reported on terms
of service enforcement
and over time we've seen uh you know
more detail and improvements
in that area um to the point where in
our forthcoming index we've actually
created an entire indicator family
around things like
enforcement of internal policies so for
example in terms of service enforcement
separating things like account versus
contact restrictions
um we've also asked for more details
around
advertising content and advertising
targeting policies
and internal enforcement of those so um
the changes are there although they're
incremental
um but one of the biggest challenges we
see and an area of focus in the future
is that um companies are still defining
the nature and the parameters of
transparency and transparency reporting
um really we can't let industry set the
terms we do need government civil
society academia and researchers
and really importantly um communities
who are really effective and who
you know stand to have their human
rights impacted to be substantively
involved in the process of developing
the standards and the the indicators for
these transparency reports
um another thing to note is that we are
getting more um sort of
quantitative and substantive
transparency so the what
right around actions taken posts removed
uh things like that but they're still
they still tend to be aggregated and
aggregation is a huge problem
um when things like types of content or
restrictions or even types of rules and
force are aggregated it really blurs the
picture for some of these stakeholders
particularly in civil society
academia and researchers and really
undermines our ability to understand and
interpret the reports
um so there you know we would strongly
encourage looking at the santa clara
principles
that really break down the effective
type of reporting metrics there
but an important thing to note in the
future is that we need to get
more of the one but we also need more of
the why and the how
so we need more qualitative reporting we
need trans process transparency
the process transparency is really
important because what it does
is it creates sort of replicable
standards it creates the basis by which
we can
actually implement effect and design
effective accountability standards
and then process transparency this is
data about rationale around how rules
are formulated how policies are
developed
how actions are taken and decisions are
made and even things like the
relationship between
human versus automated decision making
how moderators are trained how training
data sets are developed
from the rationale you know for for
those methodologies
um and you know as jessica pointed out
the companies and services are
really different um nevertheless the
process transparency is sort of an area
where there can be more alignment
and in some ways it's even more
important because it forms the basis for
these effective
interventions that i outlined so in
terms of the substantive transparency
you know we are seeing better
uh we are seeing better disclosures
there but again even on things like
very basic things like data collection
and use um we're not seeing enough
information around for example
inferred or ambient data which we know
are really fundamental
and have a really profound impact on
people's privacy and other fundamental
rights and we need more transparency
around the use of algorithms and
targeted advertising
uh which as um a co-panelist noted will
be a focus in the
europe's digital services act as well so
that's an area where there's likely to
be regulatory intervention
um we still lack context a lot of
information disclosed is
decontextualized
um so without recontextualizing the
content it's not going to be
reproducible and it's not going to form
the basis for
the emergence of norms and standards um
and really as i noted at the outset
um these transparency reports are still
largely a matter of corporate best
practice and goodwill
but we are at the point where we do need
legally binding requirements
um so some of some of the you know
promising interventions
or excuse me promising developments in
that regard are that we're seeing better
data for example on appeals so um
appeals is an area where traditionally
we haven't seen much information
we often just got raw data or numbers
but we're starting to see more
information around for example the range
of enforcement decisions
um but they can be better right so
instead of just knowing you can appeal a
granular decision
can you appeal things like downranking
or algorithmic manipulation or other
interventions or automated decision
making and if you can one of the factors
there
so um there you know there's also
obviously room for
improvement as i go down advertising
policies um often those things are not
even in transparency reports but they
may be
things like informal company blog posts
um so that is a
sort of an area for potential process
standardization as well
um i'll stop there peter in the interest
of time and happy to take specific
questions
thanks that was amazing yeah you hit um
algorithms without without saying
artificial intelligence i think which
we all appreciate so now that that's
fantastic yeah and we are getting
questions about um
whether any companies are reporting on
algorithmic transparency on explaining
um their algorithms opening up that
black box um and we've got that
as well as a couple other company
focused questions so i think i'll
probably go there
but um one is around the auditing of
transparency reports i think telia gets
their report assured do any others
um is it effective um we've got a
request on
um canadian authorities requesting info
i don't know if there are any secret
canadians on this panel uh
and then um yeah but i do want to go
first to
to alex i saw you shaking your head and
nodding a lot
um at what elizabeth was saying around
process transparency especially and then
if you could just tell us um you know
what what google might have planned uh
for your reports
well i'm not sure i i there's anything i
can share about what we have
planned just yet but i do really want to
underscore the importance of everything
that was just said
um around the importance of context and
qualitative transparency i think we have
been really trying to think about
you know we have all of these
transparency reports that provide
metrics and that's obviously very
important to have the numbers around
enforcement what we're removing what
we're responding to
but at the same time how can people
understand what our policies actually
are
and how we enforce them and how we
develop them and so
you know we've begun to do that in
particular ways like we have a
disinformation white paper and that
really walks through
how we think about the issue how we have
created policies across each of our
products
how we enforce those um and so that's
one way where we've been thinking about
how can we
help folks understand what we're doing
on a particular issue
and how that relates to content
moderation we've done a similar paper
on information quality that's focused on
how we
remove raise up reward
content across all of our products as
well and so that's another effort to
help folks understand
what we're doing with respect to
removals but also what we're doing with
respect to ranking too
um and the other piece i just really i
think we even think that that context is
important
when you look at things like our legal
removals
um that's our shorthand our uh um
a report on government requests for
removal of content
uh and we do include annotations as part
of that report and so what that does
is help um the purpose of that is to
help users
and anyone using the report understand
why there might be spikes
in the report and so you can see that
for example
um on russia where the year that we
implemented
our compliance with the vpn law and you
would see a spike in the urls removed
across search
and you see that happen in other in
other countries where you can see
when a local law was implemented and how
we responded to that
so it really is i think it continues to
be about companies and governments
that is one important piece that i think
we should not lose and
continue to advocate for governments to
be transparent so that we have a
holistic
understanding of engagement with each
company but then also
what the government is doing um but then
really to help folks understand our
products
um the other thing that we've done is
start to develop
entire sites that are focused on helping
people understand the product so
we launched how search works earlier
this year we have
um sorry we launched how youtube works
earlier this year we have long had how
search works
um and another site called how play
works and that walks through
all of the policies sort of how we
implement them the way that we think
about the product because certainly how
we think about it
that gets back to what we should be
driving for in transparency and how it
looks different across each of the
products
um kind of type of service so what we
want from transparency on search is
maybe not the same thing
that we would want from transparency on
youtube what we're trying to learn
and so when we think about comparability
across types of service
understanding how the product works is a
big piece of that
when it comes to um algorithms and how
they work we are also spending a lot of
time
working on that and trying to figure out
what is
what does meaningful transparency look
like how much are we talking about
explainability
just understanding what in fact we're
doing and what types of transparency are
meaningful
to our users to the public to
experts like the ones on this panel who
are probably more
familiar with what companies are doing
um as well as regulators
and so how do we you know make that
information more usable to all of those
audiences
those are things that we are currently
focused on um
and i think you know things like the eu
dsa
um and other regulations and other
policy
conversations are helping to move the
move the discussion forward for the
industry
right yeah uh certainly is regulation
coming around the corner
um and and to that uh dunstan can you
tell us about assurance and um how you
can actually
are these reports trustworthy and and
who says so um
and then maybe also talk about ways that
uh reporting here and these rather
limited reports can fill
um the much larger gap around the range
of human rights that are impacted
um by tech companies i did just want to
pick up on the point about
assurance so assurance exists for two
reasons insurance exists to make sure
that the things in the report are right
but it also exists to make sure that the
right things are in the report
and we often think about assurance as
making sure the things in the report are
right in other words making sure they
are accurate
that they are comparable over over years
over time
um it's less common to think about
assurance as making sure that the right
things are in the report in the first
place
and so that for me is an interesting
angle when it comes to the lack of
reporting
by other tech companies or companies in
other industries
so if they're doing effective
full human rights due diligence that
covers the full list of human rights
and you ask the question are the right
things in the report in other words the
cumulative disclosures that they
have i think you might identify that
there's a big gap here
in many companies so when we think about
assurance i guess my point is
don't just think about it as other
things in the report right but also
think it
think about it in terms of are the right
things in the report in the first place
peter i forget the second part of your
question however
yes asking how can these reports fill
the general gap around reporting on
non-financial matters like human rights
and
governance yeah i think
one of the really interesting trends
over the past decade
of which the transparency reporting
trend has played a full part
has been increased disclosure by
companies on
very specific issues of interest to very
specific target audiences
and one of the things that i would like
to see from companies going forward
our reporting strategies that on the one
hand
meet the needs of investors or other
analysts who might want
the strategic overview of the company
you know in on one page what are the big
issues we're addressing and how we are
addressing them
and then on the other hand provide the
really detailed
uh complex information that specific
audiences
want and achieve both in combination
and i think often we have this
conversation about well does anybody
really read transparency
reports in my experience they do and
there are very specific
very important audiences who then use
that insight
to inform their interactions with with
others
so i i think i would answer your
question by saying we'd love to see
strategic approaches to disclosure by
companies of which this very detailed
information about law enforcement
relationships and other
elements of transparency reporting would
be an important part
thanks dunstan um i want to throw to
uber uber innovated by
showing requests from airport
authorities right which is a
key stakeholder for them and their
clients um
there's a specific question about uh for
uttara can we get data on country
specific government and legal requests
from uber
[Music]
yeah absolutely um i would say visit our
transparency report
site you can access it from the the main
uber page
currently our transparency report is
limited to the us and canada but we're
actively looking to expand our report
um and i think that you know the
complexity with that is just that you
know regulatory reporting isn't
is enormously complex and you'll see
that when you
take a look at the report trying to
identify you know other regulators
transport regulators
land use regulators globally has been a
challenge
but again to the points that every
panelist has made it's an investment
worth making
and we're we're looking forward to
taking that next step
thank you so much um is anyone else want
to jump in we've just got about one or
two minutes left um
love to hear any closing thoughts um
burning what's really in the in your
nerdy heart of uh
desire um yeah uh all right
well i just want to thank everyone for
for joining um
i think uh everyone is is all in this in
terms of trying to
decide and understand what people need
to know about
how their companies work and how you
process data
uh and how we can make reporting more
meaningful
uh and uh want to thank all the
panelists for joining
um i will be handing off next
uh to our illustrious rights con
director and not
secret canadian um and uh
she will take us away thanks nikki
gladstone great thanks so much for that
very kind introduction peter
um thank you to all of our speakers for
joining us and to everyone for tuning in
to this
uh first event in our 10th anniversary
series for rights con
we're really looking forward to over the
course of the next few months in the
lead up to our 2021 event
celebrating a decade of convening for
human rights in the digital age and our
next event
will take place on june 7th to 11th 2021
2021 fully online right now our call for
proposals is currently open
until january 19th and it's a great
opportunity to continue conversations
like this on
transparency reports and a lot of the
other really critical
program areas that will be explored in
the rights count program so you can
learn more about that at ridescount.org
and we
really hope to see you there i will
throw it back to
essejua to close out the panel for today
yeah thank you nikki and thank you to
peter thank you to
um nicole and michael and our
whole host of panelists who spoke today
i think the conversation we had was
really insightful
and minis helps give us a clear idea of
where transparency reporting needs to go
moving forward
and so i'd encourage everyone to keep
this conversation going after the events
we'll follow up um with a link to watch
this video for those who couldn't watch
live
and and find other ways to continue to
engage this community
in how we can improve transparency
reporting going forward so yeah just
thanks again for taking some time out of
a friday in december
to join a panel about transparency
reporting and we really appreciate it
and wish you a very good day
thank you