hey everybody hey everybody how's it
going
okay I'm gonna stand right here because
protector is kind of right so my talk
today is using Kratos principles to
secure a diverse accounts using service
control policies so a little about me I
love AWS and I've embraced it for at
least five six years now I knew that it
was going to be either things so kind of
just jumped all in it and I know you
know I run the consultancy that helps
CTOs or security minded CTOs
get their security up to speed I also am
really into coffee so this is my coffee
set at home drives my wife crazy but you
know I can talk about single version
coffee and brew methods all day long so
a little offset leakage there if you
want to you know get to me temp equal
coffee I also have a podcast called
getting at info SEC and what I do there
is I interview folks on how they got
into the
to get into the field can also be
encouraged and learn from their
experience and kind of save some time
and I'm sort of the book so if you were
to sit down with coffee in an hour to
tell you you know how to get in with
Fring zero this would be everything I
would say frankly and I'm also really
into white shirt so if we see them on a
Friday I like wearing Hawaiian shirts I
think it's really important to you know
keep it Lively
and I'm really excited about the car so
coming up so you know might throw some
Star Trek references here and there
okay so a little bit of a survey how
many folks here have nativist accounts
like ten or less accounts or run or
manage ten or less okay and then how
about 25 accounts okay great
and then 75 or more accounts okay so
this talk is really it's geared to take
advantage of ADA based organizations and
when you have a lot of accounts I'm
going to take advantage of a diverse
organizations that run as an
organization level so little private or
what's Pareto's principle the idea is
that you want to make 20% effort to have
80% results so 8020 rule theorem read
the 80/20 rule of it's actually called
Kratos principle so let me so
and who here has an eight oh six okay
okay great so comments cause security
issues many you know not sure the
audience don't you're just going to go
over this something you might know this
or not but let's go over so I am for
example so many times there's keys in
source code so that's a common issue oh
he needs a key this operation certain
type to these keys and so a lot of times
developers are lazy and or don't know
and may put keys in source code also
adding a lot of provisions to instance
so yes you might be using role based
access which is great but then the role
itself might have easy to start I am
starting I have actually seen this out
there so that's kind of problematic
storage a lot of leaky buckets we've
heard about s3 bucket
a little bit later and logging so a lot
of blogging and the thing is with the
cloud if the cloud is everything to
reference it thinks this is what
everybody thinks of the cloud and I'm
going to be able to do this and you know
you're essentially giving a lot of power
in the hands from at a keystroke or the
CLI with not really cool things that are
locally not knowing like what was
necessary you kind of end up with this
and in a way so that's the you know the
power clause so we kind of you know as
security professionals we want to help
guide your folks and kind of get them to
curtailed so leaky has free bonus well
somebody has to read it a give up page
all that s3 bucket leaks that have been
out there right you know even GoDaddy a
salesperson leaked a lot of information
FedEx a lot of companies so I don't need
to go to a public
look at look at it this is as of last
year nine million pieces of data so we
don't need a reminder on why a three
buckets like that I mean I'm sorry I'm
leaking s3 buckets so let's talk about I
am I am is the new perimeter right I
think we can all agree in the cloud
space I am it used to be the network but
I am is really the new perimeter so was
a security access key and the secret key
like this you in any permissions types
where you can do whatever you want so we
want to stay away from this now who here
knows about the codes basis who's here
okay so code spaces was a company that
offered rock-solid secure and affordable
github hosting okay so if they say it's
rock-solid it secure than must be right
so this was their website of Serbia
they'll say like this was a row site
where they were in production this is
what the rogue site a couple days later
so that was our website Jude 14 this was
the 17th what happened was
had their root keys of the company
leaked online and this attacker went and
literally just terminated all their
instances and their backups and
everything so there's gone and so
literally the company went out of
business overnight and so this was what
their web page look like on the 17th or
companies there and in summary this this
is what they said so everything was
deleted so this is why I am is really
important okay so why a tow makes
organizations an SCP well so a little
background this talk is really to raise
awareness it's not like super it's not
rocket science right but there's a lot
of our folks that are not taking
advantage of this and so it's really to
kind of increase awareness because you
know again it's where you can just
deploy a few lines and you kind of get
everything set up and with only a few
lines of code you can really secure a
lot I mean amidst accounts so that's the
idea and you want to have it as a garden
go through all the security best
practices you're not going to be super
secure from justice but it really helps
make your job a lot easier
so here's a little overview say you have
multiple accounts and you haven't
organized according to our database as
well architected framework okay so you
have a security account our networking
account shared services and then
developers may have their own accounts
or not and then you know your production
and your pre fraud in your staging
things like that
so god forbid maybe some of these other
so this is a lot to manage okay and so
it was a CPS does is it applies at the
org low so ideally you would have this
set up in in different organizations
such as this okay so you've taken your
accounts and now you applied some sort
of logical separation to your accounts
to like say ok it's dev test fraud and
you create go use it you could have
several use and you can apply these
scps at any level of oh you okay you
just apply it at the top of you or some
level we'll use anywhere you'd like and
moving your accounts is like super easy
I'll walk through it in a second
and so here's really like a playbook
you want to do if you don't have a
reason organizations in STP set up okay
you want to just you want to create a
Messer accountant with no resources
create the organization and naval all
the features create no use and then move
those accounts of you literally just
dragging and dropping and then enable
policies I'll go through all this and
the next few slides but this is really
like everything my will talking works
like then you know setup blogging
because it's best practice so centralize
your logs and then start applying SOPs
up that we're gonna go through okay
really important do not apply resources
or do not apply scps
onto your master account okay the whole
reason you have to migrate is usually
you start off with your master account
your master bath has resources and so
you have to go through this whole
headache because it's just a rule okay
so if you apply at least you master how
do you lock yourself out I think you
it's just you get this like kind of
feedback for your master account you
want it to be no resources and just
really proceed from there so it's really
bad okay so migrating your mess right
now
well depending on the size or in
addition all around
it's gonna affect your billing you might
have reserved instances or like
Enterprise billing discount so it's
gonna be a medium to big deal right you
might have signed a new contract and
they still live over paper it's uh kind
of weird so hopefully it's changed past
few months so the simple yet complicated
you know you're also going to lose your
billing history on your town so if
you're you just if you're using the GUI
for that let your folks know so try to
stay away from the budget season you
know doing this during budget season I'm
working with a company right now and
they're like yeah we can do this right
now is everybody still using cost
Explorer can you let me do this please
so yeah so you'll need to sign a new
agreement and and then you will create a
new organ unlink it link your accounts
and then check your bill because you
might get a blip you might see like a
like a hundred other dollar increase and
then a hundred thousand dollar credit
the next month so be kind of funny
okay so then no we just want to organize
our organization how does your
organisation to work do you do you have
you know everything separated fraud and
staging and you know nice and clean and
logically so this might take baby steps
in one place they have a lot of
acquisitions and these acquisitions they
didn't want to mess with them so I just
created another
and it's through there and I didn't do
anything without because I don't want to
rock the boat
you know insecurities have to choose
your balance right also a request some
limit increased so by default in 2010
I'm sorry to take votes but you want to
ask for more accounts proprietary
organization so this is how it looks
like so now you're you set up your
organization you set up on stage 8 dev
another and you just literally commit
drag and drop and in any other boot camp
you can have multiple use so that we use
I think apply to three or five levels
deep that I documentation online and
they're just enabling yes there's
nothing wrong with doing it just click
enable you're not doing anything yet you
don't have any NCP's so it's okay
alright now we're ready to apply to be
someone's getting the card okay okay
something - no you know scps take effect
immediately
so please test appropriately don't do
this on a Friday afternoon okay not a
good idea so test test test test on
on your own test account make sure it
works really I mean you know the first
time I did this I was like super scared
I mean I was still like even when I
still do it I was still coming okay
so if we're gonna take these one other
thing that you take advantage on your
nice view well-organized account
organization it is the Quatro you can
create this cloud trail at the master
account this is one resource I would say
you can do and you would see this dialog
right here so you can apply this trail
to your whole organization so any new
account that comes up will automatically
have this trail yeah and you'll see why
I do this later it's just easier to
manage from SOP perspective
unfortunately we don't have the ability
to do this at the OE level I would like
that to happen put in a request form a
dough guess but we know that's not gonna
lie to me yeah so so now that we have
this cops real account our cloud shall
set up in this particular bucket set up
now we can put an SCP to block this
voucher from being deleted and so
basically you would apply this ICP this
is an
you buy your knee like start the pride
and the dev levels and that's a haven't
even you know it's like what is it's
like six lines and this would prevent
someone from deleting your cloud trust
so this is super important now also
protecting your root account so you
don't want Australia oh so here's an
example of me trying to delete the cloud
show and I'm doing this as a root so I'm
logged in as root in one of the accounts
and don't let me do it so these NCP's
are really really powerful and open to
taking questions this is not going to be
like a whole 45-minute talk so I love
any questions throughout so feel free
and
questions so you can see faux locs so
also again protecting your logs you want
to have these full-on set up here's an
example ICP to protect those loggers
between it to your life
so
okay eliminate your regions I like this
one a lot
so you know your cradle reproduction
probe only ones in the u.s. East maybe
us West one but it doesn't run in
asia-pacific it doesn't run in EU it
doesn't run in Ohio so you know if an
attacker were to get into account the
first thing I would do is create a
resource or great DC - it's a summary
that you don't check right so we want to
stop that we also it's also helps from a
Billy perspective so you know where all
your resources are and so if a developer
or someone wants to set up a coin mining
instance that's what we do right
so again understanding where your
resources are and just kind of walking
that down now this might break some of
your laundry because what i'm doing here
is denying easy to describe all over
except for these regions so if you're
relying on this on this api then you
know might read you some results and you
can see here this is me trying to launch
something in a region
of us east 1 & 2 OS - and it's not
working going okay now there's another
with denying instant Sykes
so again comes to buildings so if you
don't want everyone launching you know
for GPU instance and racking up you know
lots of dollars and trying to answer
questions on that so this is a way to
kind of limit instance types that you
could run so you can do you can take it
two ways you can take it to deny it's
the time so say you might not know
exactly what everyone wants to allow you
can do take the deny approach or you can
take the whole lot of approach I'm gonna
allow a is the T threes and m5s and
enforcement now I know buddy you take
money is by a lot of only like the
latest generation instances so at e3 is
cheaper than the t2 so even from that
perspective you can save money so you
know you kind of want to show us
security and good like hey we're saving
Mike so our customers
so yeah based on you know can we do
carry customizer based on the role yes I
don't think so we could put a condition
or abuse yeah maybe there might be a
condition actually that you can apply if
I am role is this yeah yeah so in about
the mayor March SCP are eight of us
added I am light permissions to se PS
which really increase the scope of what
we can do with SVP so yeah Rose our
oyster as long as it's within the
condition statement again the minibrute
actions so we don't want actions to be
done as route that's you know we want to
stay away from that the best practice
your route account is to apply MFA and
then blocking way make sure that very
few people have access to it but of
course apply carefully and make sure
that they're you're testing properly and
here is a screen of myself trying to go
in and look at the ec2 dashboard I can't
do anything this is what that's to be in
place here's another one for requiring a
Syrian Christian so you want enforced
make sure your compliance and best
practices oh here's another one
and then we're ending as three
public-access right so when you know not
allowing someone to create a button with
public access
no troubleshooter so again as hippies
are using I am like syntax so you know
there's a lot of you know can be tricky
especially the condition walk you know I
spend a lot of time trying to get
somebody's conditions right and I found
like some really tiny obscure like
documentation after you know voter fraud
you know I recommend you know just you
know whenever you're frustrated walk
walk take a walk and come back to it you
know let that self-conscious do the
processing but this is an example of you
know trying to do the initial box so if
you look here you know this is this was
where I was kind of like where that
where that was helpful also doing some
of the little nuances of AWS so you know
I tried to change the date here to that
because I was just trying to be like a
little goofy does anybody know this date
November 5th 1955 it was a date in that
Back to the Future you know anyone back
to so but you know any rest
was not
that they fund and then also limiting
principles so you know the principle
syntax and SCP is a little different
than then I would like so this was this
was something that I little tip there
okay
and really probably valuable site that
has a whole new recipes more than this I
talked to the developer and he does not
want to share his name but it's a really
useful website a securedoc cloud and
there's tons of Confirmation templates
and things there that are I found this
super useful so that's and that's about
it and thanks so no minutes of questions