right hi everybody so uh something shot
with somebody about this earlier before
I actually begin the talk we'd like to
read you a very famous film quote that
really resonates with what I found while
I was doing this research if you haven't
seen the film you know you've probably
been living under a rock so because I
can't memorize the bloody quote so this
is really will resonate with what you'll
see here I've seen things you people
wouldn't believe
attack ships and fire up the shoulder of
Orion watched c-beams glitter in the
dark near the Tannhauser gate all those
moments will be lost in time like tears
and rain time to die so um that
resonates a lot with the subject matter
of this which is a talk about complete
fucking train wrecks and disasters that
are in your fucking house right now so
hopefully my computer will stop being
shit so Who am I
security researchers like us one of my
favorite things do is dick about with
embedded stuff routers which is anything
that's a bit weird I like to play with
I'm jabbing at it for ages I mean it's
always been a bit of a passion mine
before this I was a forensic student I
actually qualified in that so I'm
actually a forensics person allegedly I
can do fingerprints before that I was a
pharmaceutical student and before that I
was an Internet miscreant causing havoc
which led to some consequences but
whatever a fucking Hey XML XML can die
in a fire which is really unfortunate
because just about every single thing
that I'm going to talk about today
involves XML so it's like I was studying
the things I hate so um what works you
can talk about is to6 for how it's shit
and related stock vulnerabilities that
have been related to it some kind of
protocol level issues where the
specifications specifically make shit
terrible um you know and why some really
bad things have happened and I'm
going to talk about heroesx knotting and
why it's a terrible idea
I'll go into a bit of back history about
some of stuff that's up in the past some
of the prior art because it was
important to you know checks that
somebody else hasn't done what you're
doing first and then I'll tell you how
to pop ACS servers take over the world
for little to no effort so if you want
some you know global domination you're
going to get it here and there's some
other nonsense that's in there no order
because I'm really crap at ordering
slides so it's all in there somewhere
so four of again I'd like to point out
that there is some brilliant prior art
in this field shower tile he was with
checkpoint of time and now he's worth
celebrate he gave a couple talks he gave
the island taro six nine admins talk I
think that was Def Con and then there
was the misfortune cookie research that
I saw at CCC at thirty-one see three
brilliant pieces to work it's worth
checking out and that's kind of prior
art that got me interested into your oh
six nine again because I'd looked at it
before and I'd kind of gone I look at
something else and then shower was like
hey shits fucked yo and I was like well
of course shits fucked
the Cirrus decline and it was like no no
but you should look at this shit fucked
when I fell is talk and I was like oh oh
oh whoa whoa whoa whoa this is bad so
when I look and I saw some things
there's fun stuff there for everyone you
can have cutting-edge research tomorrow
if you just take a look at it also in
the slides all of a couple links to the
specifications of the protocols I'm
going to be talking about and I'd advise
reading them advise getting some coffee
they're quite lengthy they're really
dull and I'd have also advise like
having a counselor it's like Hyatt rest'
and Cole because you go fucking mad
trying to make sense of them so yeah
have a go for yourself you will find
some stuff so what is key or blah blah
blah Kyra blah blah
protocol specifications they're not or
FCS like we know RFC's like all the
nonsense researchers in RFC like TCP and
DNS and all that crap Kirra blah blah
blah
our DSL forms backs they're made by a
bunch of idiots who like to design
things like committee and it's basically
a specification for how broadband works
and these were caught up by people who
didn't have a Scooby and they made
things up by you know having committees
and then the subcommittee of the
subcommittee of the subcommittee and I
think one of them probably was like
working for a vendor that sold an XML
parser because all of this shit involves
XML it defines the specs for the
protocols for managing broadband
networks for ISPs so this is stuff that
I don't think BT user but a couple of
other UK ICS used and we'll get to that
in a bit and that's going to be comedy
gold
so these are specs that you can follow
you can implement you can ignore you can
completely disregard and they manage a
lot of stuff so what I'm going to be
interested say is the O six for no six
nine ones there's a whole bunch of
others in that namespace and they're all
terrible like this tier 1 1 1 which is
tier 6 9 but for shit inside your LAN
like your smart TV and that's going to
be the worst idea in the world and
they're pushing to have it implemented
and yeah meaning need to look that in
the future because it's a bundle of crap
and they're actively pushing to have
this pushed out so yet Kiros explored
start is called a landside DSL CPE
configuration yeah so the spec outlines
this soap based protocol because
everyone loves XML and you don't have
enough XML because you just want more
fucking XML because XML Paris is the
most robust piece of software in the
world allegedly and so it allows
configuration of your CPE consumer
premises equipment I eat your router
that you rise to be shipped to you from
the land side so back in the day for
those that for at least people you know
I'm not sure how it was in the UK but in
Ireland when aircon rolled out broadband
you got your router you plugged your
router in and you got a CD that had a
Microsoft Windows executive element do
you put into your Windows XP machine
because this was when we got broadband
you put it in you ran a program and the
program configured your router and gave
you
Internet and magic give broadband it was
slightly faster than dial-up like just
slightly it was like dial-up without the
noise so it was dialogue without the
free chiptunes so um yeah you know
heuristics for was for the broadband
setup bullshit they shipped to consumers
and the specification is there download
it read it cringe smash your head off
the desk it's worth a look it's comedy
gold
so Cairo six nine is CPE consumer
premise equipment one management
protocol CW MP and these guys love their
fucking acronyms so it outlines how from
the is CN how the IFP manages your
router how they access it how when you
go
hello tech support my router don't work
they can log into your router remotely
and they can check shit and they can go
oh you've got like 500 devices connect
to your router of course it doesn't
bloody work or they can go oh your
routers in a fault state turn it off and
turn it back on again it's the protocol
they use for managing it it's a
management protocol and it's again soap
and when you look at it at first you go
nope because soap means nope just say no
it's a bit like string copy just say no
it's a gateway drug to bad shit so um
you can download the specs there it's on
amendment fucking five I wouldn't be
surprised if they go to amendment six
soon and yeah have a look it's hideous
so I'm going to start with hero's
explore because terrorists for going to
hit everybody kind of blindsided them so
it's on you know it's what they use for
the broadband set up speedy stuff and
it's how you manage the cpe from the LAN
side you know from inside the trusted
zone it's how you manage the device it
aspect for doing that and it is toll
read/write for like all the config
variables on the device so you can
override DNS servers or the NTP servers
or whatever wireless security settings
you can get and set the keys yes I leave
all that I need the crap you can access
through the web interface you can access
it using this in a lot of cases and when
I read the spec I did a double take and
paula was hallucinating
some shit because I saw that it had a
section called security about security
requirements and I only read the spec
after I've been taking a good look at it
by reversing something so I oh whoa whoa
whoa whoa stole the bolt is actually a
section here it says security when this
shit's fucked so um it's heroesx for
security specification states access to
any action that allows configuration
changes to the CPE must be password
protected access only password protected
action must require H speed digest
authentication sensitive information
such as passwords must not be readable
at all and it's also it doesn't specify
it in the spec but it's implied that
it's only meant to listen on the land
side of the network but you know we know
where this one goes you you know you
might as well go to Matthew's talk about
anonymous credentials and shit because
it's going to be way more complicated in
this stuff it's going to be way more
interesting chair to hear means doing
some cool stuff he's in track two so if
if you see where the winds going now and
you want to just walk out and vomit and
see something cool go to track two
because this going to be bad so yeah I
quite like this you know when they say
must implementation people go and maybe
next version if the ticking gyro fuck it
we'll fix it later so you know dreams
and reality will eventually collide and
you know we'll have a nice glorious
place where specifications will be
followed and where's like most can and
cannot will mean what they mean in
English but the glue-sniffing fuckwit to
implement this shit these words are like
vague notion somewhere the fuck over
there where it's like oh most maybe
we'll stick it as a ticket you know next
version or path it's not a critical
issue was sorted out later so um the
reality is this shit why call tiros
excel is posture protect oh fuck no I've
only seen a couple of devices that
actually fucking support having
passwords 4006 for those are fritz box
and some other shit that was a bit weird
um that's bit about not being able to
read your passwords ah that's really
hard you know you can actually just pull
the creds from the box so Wi-Fi keys
they're reading
in plaintext if you send the right soap
request that lead me into something
funny in a bit oh and not bit about you
know I'm not listening on one you know
only listen I fuck no 0.002 dear is
where we bind our services all access
all the time
maximum portability oh and it just so
happens that because a bunch of this
crap calls out the shell we've got bonus
command injection bugs because you know
we want the whole lowest top tenets bug
bingo baby
so obvious outcome where does this end
you know what happens you know what
happens when you put this shit on the
internet at scale we're pretty much most
of you people in this fucking audience
have a box in your house with this shit
on it right fucking now in your trusted
network a lot of your clients will have
this shit in their trusted zone you know
it'll be in the you know it oh it's
inside our line it's cool no fucked up
this shit listen the internet so what's
the outcome what happened this was like
somebody had gotten like a big pile of
flammable shit pour petrol on it and
then put a sign saying smoking area
beside it it was an accident waiting to
happen
and guess what shit happened shit
happened so I'm a reg wrote this
beautiful thing so the first kind of
indicator that stuff was going deeply
wrong in the internet was when Deutsche
Telekom had some issues when like a
million people suddenly can't connect
the Internet in Germany country is quite
well connected you got some problems
because some stuff happened and people
kind of twigged this isn't just going to
happen in Germany but it was too fucking
late it was already game over game was
over a long time ago but it happened
talk talk post office err calm in
Ireland my own country my favorite I
have been stuck with Frederick's a
nobody else serviced my area demon arm
basically every fucker ships shit
routers people had some issues so
yep stuff was getting wrecked um outages
outages everywhere worm you know I got
really excited and kind of giggled a bit
about this and probably nearly wet
myself because somebody had written a
fucking worm that did worm things you
know and it was hilarious just just the
scale of the chaos this cause and it was
you'll we'll get to why in a minute but
yeah the complete fucking mayhem that
this accident waiting to happen cause
this accident did fucking happen and it
probably affected some people in this
room some who did it where is the
attribution party can I roll my dice and
say North Korea was it Russia was it
around was it China now my script
kiddies
it was scrublords who want to ddos
things and i accidentally took out the
internet for shit loads of people code a
bonus win you try build a botnet to
packet people you accidentally you know
fuck the internet for loads of people
said so that was um yeah that's pretty
difficult to read because Lowell syntax
highlighting etc but basically you send
a soap request within spec saying change
the NTP server you're using to backtick
some fucking commands here and it will
run the commands and because it's
Internet of shit it'll run it as root
because there ain't no user but root so
yeah you know the predictable happened
somebody went this is trivially
exploitable
I'll make botnet and yeah the expected
occurred so here we've got because you
have to have a screenshot apply to Pro
if you're talking about malware worms
otherwise no one the fucker takes it
seriously Ida Pro screenshots or how
people know that you know what you're
fucking talking about in this industry
so here we've got a screenshot of Ida
Pro that tells you absolutely nothing
except that the thing is sending a soap
request so malware happened that's the
proof I opened up an Ida so this ain't
the first time either
you know Ida is like this shit when it
comes to attribution so this wasn't the
first time we had some problems with the
particular piece of software rompe
that caused this accident to occur so
before two euros expel which is what I
named it there is Miss fortune cookie it
affected the same ROM pager piece of
software except affected the o-69
component
it allowed remotely accessing the device
with no auth cuz fuck off due to what
was effectively like the bug with Miss
fortune cookie was actually really
fascinating when shard was giving his
presentation he didn't give the game
away he didn't tell you how to exploit
the bug you know because they were still
trying to get a fix and it was a global
problem but me and one of the guys were
on a workshop earlier we're sitting in
the talk and we saw that it was what he
was describing was a right wat where you
could clobber global variables used by
the device by sticking shit in the
cookie so you'll see what I mean in a
second I got somebody far smarter than
me wrote a reliable exploit for it arm
and this is all you saying you sent this
like a snippet from the proof-of-concept
exploit the Kenza wrote now Ken there's
an interest in shops have no idea who he
is
he discovered the other vulnerability as
well Lisa Myers dude I've no idea who he
is
Ireland's a pretty small country so we
all kind of know each other and this
wild carrot comes out of the blue
instead it's like writing sploit for all
the things and just causes havoc and
then disappears up the face of the earth
so what's interesting with this fortune
cookie is that so you've got these key
value pairs and cookies we all know how
cookies work know what miss fortune
cookie the key in the cookie was
basically represented and offset to
clobber and the value is what the fuck
you want to clobber the offset with so
it's the most trivially exploitable bug
of all time all you do is take apart the
firmware find binary go oh here's where
the bit that says requires a password to
log in lives and clobber it with an ami
it's all fine or authentication
successful so you know yeah pretty grim
and this particular value here will
exploit the blah blah blah rebranded
excel piece of crap that air come ship
everyone there's one of my parents house
I looked at nose like oh my parents like
you got hit by the trro 64 worm air come
sent out an advisory told their
customers say and
yo you might want to change your
wireless password because somebody
jacked it some Beebe reporter went to
talk talk with a hundred talk talk us to
his wife like he's got stolen and got
dumped online and went yo yeah your
customers not only does their internet
not work anymore but their Wi-Fi
passwords have been jacked and talk talk
being talk talk just said no no didn't
happen didn't happen didn't happen
only a hundred of them only a hundred
them we've only seen 100 I've seen the
dump I stumbled across it by asking and
begging going who the fuck did this shit
and eventually I got a hold of it
there's 77,000 talk to our customers who
you can just connect their Wi-Fi because
the creds are on the fucking Internet um
those creds also incidentally happened
to be the admin passwords for a lot of
the routers because Lal talk talk you
know we kind of know what to expect from
talk talk I mean you know sequel I in
2016 and now we've got this you know
it's the norm I feel sorry for them
though they're kind of fucked legacy
stuff or they're implementing what
they're told implement because best
practice so those six nine oh six nine
again is a DSL forum certification it
again has a little bit in it about you
know doing security because apparently
you've to put in a little notice saying
do security and you know so people can
ignore it so at least it's there but oh
six nine is a bit more it supports TLS
it supports authentication the protocols
are mass um as I said before I'm not
going to complain about that much more
it's just a disaster it's basically like
everyone and their mom brought the
technology they liked to the table and
when there is like they were designing
the protocol they said okay we'll keep
you all happy we'll put all of it in you
know we'll make it do everything the
kitchen sinks in there so you've got the
SSL TLS it's optional some setups a
decent you can have mutual or you can
have clients you can have client-side
search you can have start pinning all
this other goblins and other people just
you know Yolo plaintext fix for crypto
kryptos hard you can do alts as well so
in a lot of cases the router to the ACS
the ACS is the device of the ISP that
can
trolls all of the shit it's like the
best part net command and control server
in the world because it's designed to do
that you can use base of goats you can
authenticate your clients or you can use
the shared secret or you can use client
certs or whatever in a lot of cases I
found the CPE TAS fit it's kind of
irrelevant what they're interesting is
that have a static password for all
their customers and the username will be
an identifier username be a per device
ID so they can you know go this is Joe
Bloggs router or he's having a bit of a
problem it's out of sync will just
reboot it remotely or we can snoop this
traffic etc etc because there's a lot of
undocumented shit in some of the
implementations but you know it's not as
if they're going to spy on you but here
is six-nine it's XML it's so but it's
got other XML shit as well because you
know if you want if you're doing stuff
with XML you might as well put more XML
so you've got stunned
you've got soap you've got UPnP you've
got XMPP and you've got basically any
protocol you can think of that involves
a bit of soap or a bit of XML they'll
probably jam it in which means you've
got the world's greatest attack surface
because I looked at this shit in a way
whoa I don't even know where it is
start with fuzzing this you know this is
this is a bit too much this is too hard
to handle so we know the CP n we all
know that in bed advice and routers are
fucked
you know routers or routers they're
going to route you know they're going to
hire Koda creds blah blah blah they're
going to get wracked by Annie blah blah
blah you know okay they ship crap
devices to consumers but surely the ISC
cuz they do billing and stuff they're
gonna you know they're going to have
their shit together they're an Internet
service provider you think they know
something about internet so um of course
it's going to be rock-solid enterprise
software you know probably written by I
know the IBM's the Oracles of the ISE
world or whatever and it can't be that
bad because you know it's enterprise and
it's used by serious people with
billions of dollars involved or billions
of pounds or billions of euros or
billions each well quadrillions a yen
you know this is a shit ton of money
they're they use this stuff for billing
so cool
which is going to be secure right
because ISPs like making money it's kind
of their job so that's what I want to
talk about in the second act of this in
which we hacked the planet because rock
solid enterprise software it can go fuck
itself so we're going to talk about
world domination and this kind of sums
it up and this what you can do right now
with the state of affairs things are
because lulled so we're screwed
so I you know when I was thinking the
threat model of this after Annie
happened I sat down and I said to myself
what's the realistic threat model I know
to think through old beer on or China or
nation-state and I thought no sada I'm
not mine I fire on I'm not fucking clown
strike by me so I'm gonna think like a
15 year old script kitty who wants to
make the biggest DDoS botnet in the
planet because that's what happened with
previous vulnerabilities so we want to
own loads of routers everywhere to do
some crime right that's the threat model
is some idiot going I want to pop all
this shit and I want to do some serious
crime so um but we pick a lazy 15 year
old I've been a lazy 15 year old I I
know what the mindsets like it's like I
could get you know botnet and scan and
hack all these devices one at a time but
oh my that's like effort and stuff and I
want this cheap I want this quick I want
this easy I don't want to rent a big box
the Gigabit pipe to scan because that's
it sure my mom's credit card won't
stretch that far on doing this on the
cheap we want to nail all the shit in
one go so we do so we take so by the way
if you're looking for like advanced
memory corruption or stuff I'd advise
going somewhere else because all the
bugs in this are disappointingly
hilarious
you're not going to find some advanced
rap chain bullshit like with browsers
this is going to be like entry-level
stuff because my threat model was 15
year old so um you know some of you
might have kids you know your kids could
probably pull this shit off overnight
faster than me so we want them all in
one go so we figure you know we have a
thing we've got a slightly smack 15 year
old
you know who goes okay so I wanna hack
loads of boxes so I hacked the box that
has access to all the boxes so that
somebody who's got a bit of a clue we
got somebody who can read so we've got a
literate fifteen year old who's got like
enough patience to wade through a few
pages of stuff for the Gulf fuck this so
I started auditing ACS servers my free
time just kind of a bit of a hobby
project initially before I thought I'd
give a talk on it I was like this would
be fun I'll just have a look for the
really low hanging fruit we found I mean
I don't you know there's probably a load
of fruit in the tree but like you're
knee-deep and low-hanging fruit here I
have you know you'll see in a minute
it's like you're in an orchard and all
the apples just drop on your fucking
head and you go oh okay then don't even
need to pick them they're just there
so so far I've done a quick and dirty
audit with the attention span of a bored
15 year old of free ACS which is shit
because written Java open ACS again crap
libre CS which I found out a bit of time
in was actually a fork of open ACS same
bullshit not maintained bad
documentation a terrible Java crap and
then I looked at somebody written a
terroristic sign server library in PHP
using laravel and all this you know PHP
developer nonsense so I was like is PHP
I mean they're basically glue-sniffer
monkeys I'll find an easy win there and
people might find it a bit funny to look
up yeah I had a quick look I found
something within two minutes we'll get
to that in a bit
so the disclosure timeline for the first
blog with free ACS um at some point in
the last while I can't remember when I
found some bugs between their napal I
worked on weaponizing the bugs April I
disclosed them now they haven't fixed
them yet so you can take the exploit
from today and run rampant the Internet
and cause chaos and be the bored
fifteen-year-old that fifteen year old
you wanted you to be you're something
that's a very clunky sentence but you
get rid of mean so free ACS has been
around for a while and you know it
it's been around the block and I'm not
sure if it's a very small group a
developer is like two of them or one
person or one person with schizophrenia
I'm not sure but you know it seems to a
one-man operation and it says that you
know it says a lot of things and based
on Tomcat Java on my sequel so I was
like okay then things like hey so they
call themselves this is the most
complete trro 6:9 acs available for free
and the MIT license that's copy pasted
from their website so most complete to
me rings alarm bells of most attack
surface so by the way with regards
attack service I've not even scratched
the surface the surface is pretty much
intact if you go digging for bugs you
will find heaps of them you will give up
because you will find bugs that make
your other bug on exploitable because
it's so fucking buggy we'll get to that
in a minute there's bugs in your boat so
how do you install three ACS um so you
double you get the shell script over
plaintext HP is the H moderate and you
run it as root and that's how you
install it and then you read chapter
four do the other 10% to the nonsense to
make it work and even then it barely
works and this is things that you know
you'll see it it's out there people use
this and so I looked and I created some
shodhan and Google queries I did some
stuff with census and Bing
because there is some default logins
admin necks APs
and nobody changes default creds default
creds are default you know you leave
them you make a new user something and
finding how to change the password took
me a few minutes when I set up my local
one I was like where the hell is the
password change form it's not here it's
not here
most system ins ago yeah screw it'll be
fine
there's quite a few in the internet the
lovely people are binary edge run some
scans and they found quite a few you
know there's a lot of these out there in
production at some quite large ISPs on
the public internet so you can find them
Google being whatever so then I started
looking I thought I'll look at post dot
first and get a feel for what the
application is and
what discovered is basically it's like a
cross site scripting testbed that
optionally has like an ACS server as a
bonus you can just you stick in an ejs
anywhere and you'll get some exercise
out somewhere and these were all postdoc
bugs which it wasn't very interesting
but there's some screenshots just just
so you can see what kind of stuff I was
dealing with so I was like oh okay then
we got an alert box followed by we got
another alert box followed by a started
number of my fucking alert boxes because
there's alert box in my alert boxes so
um yeah I mean yeah I mean like this
would be a really good project for like
find a cross-site scripting bug it's
like the XSS testbed you can probably
use it as a good benchmark for XSS
finding tools so but we don't care about
post off we want pre off we don't want
to rely on default creds or brute
forcing a login or students and Craig's
we want pre old we don't want have to
deal with silly nonsense like passwords
it needs to be remote we don't want any
of these local bugs so this cut down my
scope it needs to give us privileged
access and you see they give us root in
the box or an admin account in the ACS
and needs to be easy because again
threat model is bored fifteen-year-old
you know we want it on the cheap and we
want it now so I'm pre old attack surf
is pretty fucking great right so if you
just pretend to be a tear as a client
client ie a router ping going hey what's
up bias hey I'm a router here's my stuff
you know you're sending a big blob of
XML to a probably buggy parser and so I
start down I act above it and I create a
valid CW NP notify which the first
message a router sends the ACS so create
it one of those messages to foes with
and so you know like borrowed it from
some bits than you know used other
people's stuff and created this is kind
of my test fuzzing packet and I looked
and went oh no oh no not not XML make it
stop make it go away
no can we not just move to JSON at least
I can read JSON I don't like
angle brackets no my so no I mean it's
hard enough to Paris you know with
computers mean the hell of it looking at
I'll give you a headache so I tried
puzzling the XML and my test box kept
falling over which is indicative of a
denial of service bug somewhere but it's
XML NEX ml is like denial service bugs
with an optional markup language thing
that you can put Cobbins in so I got
bored really fast no went nah this XML
message stuff is a bit hard this is too
much effort for your 15 year old trap
model so I said and the XML move knob
too difficult we'll come back to it if
we don't find out the knell so I looked
at the base of golf you know there is no
all header in that one those like this
does some magic with the base of got no
yes it does so the username in the base
of golf field is used to know what
device it's a device ID because we use
authentication as identification because
we don't know ours from our elbow so
it's used the unique ID in a lot of
cases and free ACS is no different so
it's an input it's an input field that
we can play with and it turns out basic
goals lets you put a whole lot of crap
in there and it doesn't really care what
you do you know you can it's a pretty
good fuzz vector for stuff like this so
this is what I mean by bugs in my bugs
so um the basic auth username gets
popped into a sequel query there's no
sanitizing sanitizing you know we
haven't got there yet
these are Enterprise Java developers
they're still stuck you know before
sequel injection was a thing you know
somebody might want to let them know so
in theory there's a lovely sequel
injection there that's super trivial to
exploit now it turns out this slight
slightly wrong I thought there was a
character length limit which was why it
was breaking I have no idea anymore it's
not a character length limit and put
loads of crap in and you can do the
sequel injection it's just that you
don't get immediate output it's blind
it's second-order it's a bit of a chore
like the injecting your sequel query is
easy the sequel query then executes and
you don't get in the output but it
execute immediately it executes some
arbitrary time in the future so you'll
need some kind of side channel gubbins
or maybe make a really really really
well-crafted sequel create a user
supplement but the funny bit is is that
if your sequel query syntax is not
correct the entire thing shits the bed
and falls over and refuses to come back
to life I discover this after resetting
the VM revert back to fucking snapshot a
lot of times and I got really sick of
doing this so I decided to look for
something else so I said username the
basic office son sanitize the username
that a router sends the username also
pops up in the UI when the admin is in
doing admin things in the admin thing
and they don't sanitize this equals so
and we know it's basically made of XSS
so you know I kind of started thinking I
might be on a summit here yeah so on
alts client can send a thing that does
XSS in admin land you got some payload
limitations I don't think it's actually
a character length anymore I have no
idea but then I realized your cross-site
scripting payload must not fuck up the
sequel injection sequel query gubbins
otherwise you screw the box so you got
some restrictions there because you've a
bug within a bug you've nested bugs it's
bugs all the way down like turtles and
Discworld or some shit or not Discworld
in Stephen King's magic planet world
thing of Derrick Towers so yeah we got
some problems so when the admin logs in
they get in the lerp box cool sweet and
then I thought to myself well I've got
all these weird limitations so I've got
to do something cool with this excess to
do something interesting so I loaded a
remote script and it worked fine so test
worked so then I thought how do I take
over the ACS well add an admin user
because these people haven't heard of
cross-site request forgery protections
or any of that so this will be easy
right except I'm lazy and I hate
JavaScript like I refuse to write
JavaScript for whatever reason so I
built the exploit by copy and pasting
from stack overflow
and guess what it works so you send a
post request when you're logged in and
it'll add an admin user and again yeah
just copy and past and stock overflow
because I didn't want to write any jazz
because saw that I like to occasionally
go outside and go to the pub and things
and I can't be arsed learning jazz
properly so fuck it stock overflow mate
the JavaScript developers Bible so I
wrote an exploit and it works so you
inject your cross-site scripting payload
and then you wait a bit sucide logs in
the next day to do ACS things you can
trigger the system in logging in with an
isp by maybe ringing up their support
helpline and then they'll have to log in
to do stuff and then the payload fires
and it adds an admin user and then it
tells you hey buddy about an admin user
this is he is now yours so game over for
them and really easy to do you know you
get a login that's an admin user and
yeah you get outed and is admin flag is
set to true blah blah blah so you've
just racks that entire iousy and one go
you know you'll have to go clean up your
cross-site scripting afterwards that's
outside the scope board fifteen year old
they just want access and they want it
now so yeah you can log into the ACS and
you can play about with things and you
can do magic so what we do next well if
we're the script kiddie we scan the
internet or we show down since this
Google Bing binary edge whatever way you
like to find boxes to find the free ACS
boxes you spray out your cross-site
scripting magic payload by the CWAP
notify would know off and then on Monday
when ISP people come into work they sit
down they log in you own the ranked game
over and planet hacked so and then I
start looking at you know free ACS cool
so I looked at open ACS Libre CS which
is the world's shortest software audit
so the problem with these is the
documentation shit and I could barely
get them to work when they work they
fall over all the time I couldn't figure
out if I was triggering a bug or if it's
just soft ravine crap and it was kind of
a bit of both so I sat down with the
setup guide and for like making sure the
testing is repeatable
when I set up a piece-of-shit software
to break it I set it up exactly as they
tell you to do it because that's how
most people will do it and it's you know
it's how the developers intended you to
do it how God said you should do it it's
JBoss my sequel of shit docks the usual
step one set up cyber blaster fuzzing
and probing it knows the freaks out and
then I stopped and I went hold on a
minute
this was a total pain in the ass to set
up I should look at the config see if
there's any problems there yeah there is
though it's actual I call it the misc
configuration server because it's JBoss
face anybody familiar with jabe also
recognize these URLs
these are endpoints to give you a remote
code execution with no effort so you can
recommen
it turns out that all the Installer
Doc's end up creating my sequel root
user with a blank password which reminds
me somewhat of what allegedly happened
to a company called Stratford so you're
getting fucked if you're using this
stuff because it turns out that the
blank paths were a bit hard-coded
somewhere it seems to go and do some
magic to make it work so yeah we were
able to pop shells all over the shop
when I tested libre CS and open ACS and
that was a bit boring and I was like who
installed at this shit
so I decided look at another a CSP
software because I didn't want to bore
you guys with like boring bugs from 10
years ago that still pop up because
Batman's can't Badman oh yeah by the way
these are in the wild there's a there's
a national ISP somewhere that runs this
is a few others I stopped looking
because I'd end up drunkenly popping
some ISPs or something you know testing
is it really there so I said no no hands
off but these things are on the internet
and I think some are getting replaced
after emails got sent but I doubt it
legacy stuff in it so I want to break
through Java so it's like look at
another piece of ACS crap I didn't want
look any more Java so I look at this one
in PHP that's the github link PHP stuff
to do stuff with laravel to do ACS it's
written in PHP so I had a quick look
yeah basically this shit happens
this was yeah you don't Justin serialize
the ones you might as well in serialize
it every time
and because laravel is basically magic
and older loads a ton of crap in you
don't need to look through your
application for like a magic pop gadget
or a constructor a destructor because
turns out laravel autoloading will
helpfully do this shit for you and give
you loads of pop gadgets to create your
PHP chain to get a shell it's like it
wants to help you I mean somebody wants
call PHP the HTTP API for remote code
execution they're not wrong so yeah I
mean it's exploitable there's a couple
of ways you can mitigate but nobody's
going to do that because PHP devs lul I
mean even if you mitigated it by killing
the pop chain you could still use you'll
find one of a trillion memory
corruptions and uncie realized like how
pornhub got racked by the bug bounty
people if you use this library you're
getting screwed and people do use this
library and production that was written
by some guys a little hobby project bit
like open SSL and big in math um you
know people's hobby projects become
infrastructure so what do we do with the
hacked ACS well the easy one is change
everyone's DNS servers do mass farming
maybe Jack everyone's Wi-Fi keys maybe
change their NTP servers to screw with
them maybe reflash their firmware and
change the ACS server URL in NVRAM so
the only way to unscrew things is for
the ISP to ship out new devices or send
an engineer to every customers house or
you could mess a billing revision new
stuff launch the biggest DDoS button in
the world whatever the hell you want to
do the world's your oyster you're
basically the poor man's NSA with a
cross-site scripting bug and a few
configure issues and the fact that you
know everything shit
so the defenses I sees you say triaxis
restrict that's a waste of time they do
oh it's on a management subnet we pop
one customer's router it's game over
they do this mutual SLO stuff oh we just
pop one of your customers routers and
again you're screwed or they layer these
defenses to do defense
in depth and you know they still get Fox
because they're relying on pieces of
crap hardware that are made for like 20
cents so yes game over
mitigations aren't going to work just
crap the law next on the agenda is
ongoing research audit more acs servers
you should all audit an ACS server
there's a load of them out there every
10 vendor out there is made one audit
more the CPE end stuff there's some
stuff out there's not run pager I know
that orange the telco in France of
open-source Derek tier of 69 client bit
gubbins and crap ins written in C I need
to look at Tier one one the smart TV
stuff in the future sky BT virgin any of
the crowds who do TV as well as ISP will
probably implement this and it's got the
same issues so you can you can write
exploits for the future by looking at
that you know you can be a time traveler
I know everyone wants to go back in time
you know bring a note a back with them
and hack the planet you can do this
right now um yeah yeah just thanks to
all these people in the whole bunch of
others who aren't named um who just
helped me along with this yeah
[Applause]