okay so
thank you everybody thank you for
representation so i'm going to talk
first a bit about a liar
that means ada library repository
and the talk has three parts
that's why we have we are three people
i'll first talk a bit about
general things about the project how it
started
where it's now and a bit of the
internals
and then comes the fun part which are
two demos
one about how to begin a project with a
liar
and another one on how to contribute
your projects to ally
so let's go
yeah why in the first place
this project exists well i think that
nowadays every language every platform
has a
way of installing dependencies
installing installing
other projects and truth is that
we have become used to be able to do
this
yes sorry
and well this is true for for
more for john languages but it's also
true
by for other well-established languages
and platforms so a question that gets
asked
from time to time is how do you in ada
find new projects to use or
how to install dependencies and
well we have to say there is no way in
ada you have to
fish the projects around and install
them manually and then you can use them
and the truth is that when i started
this project there was
to my knowledge no related projects for
foreign
besides the outstanding efforts for
debian which has very good support for
ada
packages then there is a project from
uh the bs the guy luis merino i think
it's the name
which is a kind of system package
manager so it's not for ada
but it has very good support for ada
packages and then
we have now liar which is really
oriented to
to support the the eight hour
so another more for the list and then
besides the the
express expense expectancy of having
this
or the comfort of having this
there are real advantages on using
package managers
for starters um it simplifies
reducing code if you are aware that
other libraries exist
and you can install them quickly and
easily
and also if libraries are classified
with proper descriptions and
tags you are more likely to find
something that you can reuse instead of
rolling your own solution
um a cross-platform library manager
will help you in making your
libraries available in a number of
platforms not only in the
on the platform you are working
it can help in to providing reproducible
builds if you say this project builds
with those dependencies
and if you build them you will get the
same binary that i am
providing for download you can verify
that you are using the proper
dependencies
and finally in and the fast evolving
world
of of software it might help on
updating your dependencies when new bugs
are found vulnerabilities and so on you
you just do an update and you get all
the new versions of libraries
if they are properly maintained and you
get a fixed
executive and
well that's about the motivation but now
moving
in particular into one to our project
i just checked for the for preparing
this talk
uh when this all started
and the community has debated from time
to time
about this but it was now
it's crazy but it's now four years ago
that
i opened the first repository to have
discussions about this and we had some
talks
also in the news group them for two
years nothing else happened
and then is when i sent the first
version to other europe which was
rejected properly because it was
really rough at that point in time
the same year in 2018 i i did a research
visit
with adacore and for other matters
that you saw this morning if you were
here
and that gave us the opportunity to talk
about the
the the ada community was asking for a
project manager there was none the core
was also interesting on having something
for this so from from that
we kept in touch and last year adacore
also
gave support to the project which
allowed me to
work more time on it and also people
from idaho
is also contributing now so yeah it's
not
a single single person effort anymore
and just a couple of months ago
um fabian i think it was you that you
invited some people to
start testing the project to find
what's what's okay and what's missing
and to have new points of view and so on
and
he also suggested that today is a good
day to since we are
in a developer environment to announce
that
we can start the public beta so all
feedback is welcome
in particular we are developing online
linux so feedback from windows and mac
os is
more more needed and and so it is
that's uh from the historical point of
view
but in terms of functionality
my personal feeling is that right now is
when the project is starting to come
together in the sense that it's starting
to be really useful
as part of the of the closed beta
we got many contributions of projects
that
of course people in data world know that
are
that exist but now they they are
starting to be accessible through a liar
and also um we have a better picture of
what is missing versus what is done
because uh up to this point um
at some time sometimes i felt like a
programmer
doing a programming a game but not
playing
his own game because it's busy
programming the game
and so i'm doing the things in a liar
and i always use the same features but
i don't have the perspective of other
people and this
internal data and the collaboration with
with adacore has given me
a much better perspective on what's
missing and what can be done so
for the immediate future and well of
course
what can be done you are going to see
firsthand from the demonstrations
and and i will talk just a bit about
some basic capabilities but
um if everything goes to plan i expect
that 2020 is going to be a very big year
for the project because
with this knowledge and and the momentum
we
have gained in this past year i think we
are going to
close the biggest holes in the in the
project
and so some things
can be done but are very inconvenient to
do
right now like the publishing workflow
it's a bit
you can do it but it requires
some knowledge and some well you will
see
and and there are features that we want
to have that are not there like
reproducible builds for example and as i
said
well if we want to also put out the
first
star stable release with binaries
the project is already compiling in the
three platforms
it's going through continuous
integration um
but as i as i said we are using it
mainly in linux
so feedback from the other platforms
will be
very welcome and that's more or less how
the project
is right now um
you are going to see two demos i have
planned to do a
little demonstration but the computer is
offline i'm not going to do it but
the gist of this demonstration was that
even if you are not
an ida developer or you don't want to
use
ada dependencies a liar may serve to
test data software in a simple
simple way by using the get a command
you retrieve all the sources needed to
build the project with all the
dependencies and you can test it
immediately so
i mean that even if you are not
interested into learning
about a liar or digging into a
development this
is a tool this can be done already i
mean
and of course you can search the
projects that are available
we're moving a bit into how the project
is
is done i will talk
about a few internal few internal things
and
and i will finish for starters the
project is in github
there are several repositories that you
can find there all under the umbrella of
the liar project
project and they contain the community
index
the main executable and library and
other supporting projects
and here a note about terminology
in the alar index repository we have the
community index what those
mean the community index is all
composed of open source projects
contributed projects
a layer supports handling several
indexes
if for example you have private indexes
with your private software that you
don't want to publish
or that is not ready for publication yet
or things like that
so this kind is the kind of the official
index from the project then we have
two ada projects that for now live in
the same repository i guess at some
point they will have to split but for
now
we have a library component that could
be used
maybe to create a nicer interface
and then we have the command line tool
that in the spirit of other tools like
git and so on it's a three-letter
command i find myself sometimes mixing
the git analyzer commands already
and well that's a notable terminology
and what kind of package manager is a
liar
of the many possibilities well a liar's
sandbox in the sense that it's it's not
going to touch your system
it will create a folder inside that
folder you have everything you need for
the current project you are working on
is oriented towards the ada language we
are doing it
for the open source data compiler which
is
gnat and so it's not intended to
to manage a platform
or a system but only to give you
development for ada
it works with sources
ada is highly portable so there is
no pressure to distribute binaries
everything is downloaded and compiled
and finally it's a community effort in
the sense that there is no
it's not sanctioned by any official ada
body
in the sense that for example rust cargo
is part of the tooling of the language
officially
so that's where a liar is located
well a liar if you have worked with
package managers it reduces the same
ideas
which is named releases with semantic
versions
and we reuse the term crate
to really refer to uh
several releases from the same project
because the other
possible names are taken in the aid
award for very precise
meanings this was a kind of maybe
controversial decision but
it has a very precise meaning that other
developers know so that's
how it is semantic versioning you
i'm sure you know that is the way to
ensure that you can update your packages
without breaking
the build if everything is properly
packaged so i will not stop
too much here and well here we see
an example of how dependencies are
realized once you retrieve a project
we we can specify that we need two
libraries
and those libraries are solved uh
recursively incorporating their own
dependencies
finally you reach a combination of
dependencies that
allow the build the solver in a layer is
complete so if there is a solution it
should find it and
to conclude here's how it looks on disk
when you
work in a in a project you have your
project
with your files whatever you want and
everything else is
within an alarm folder which is intended
to be put
into the ignore list of your version
control system so you
don't need to know anything about data
internals ally
internals and in there you can find
mainly
the dependencies that are needed to
build your project
and this is the end of my introduction
now i
leave you with fabian
and thank marie
try to turn it off okay
so do you yeah so pearmary will be
typing for me
uh we will be a little bit
sorry let me try to fix that
okay so the first demo is going to show
how great package manager
especially allier is to start
prototyping projects in ada
so there are many libraries available on
the web for either but the fact that
they are all
in a layer makes them very easy to use
and so very easy to create
a new project quickly so the project
that we are going to do
is going to take going to read the
configuration file
in a domain format and generate a pdf
with a square in it and the color of the
square will depend
on the configuration in the thermal file
so first we're going to start by
creating a project so
primary will use the alar init command
specifying bin because it's going to be
an executable
otherwise it would be lib so
okay you can you can create that if you
go
ah yeah demo effect
so you do have so yeah you do have to
right now you have to
compile a layer yourself because we
don't have binary release yet
and of course you have to add it in your
path so the project is created now so if
you go to the
to the my project directory
so allia is already creating some
base files for us so we can already
do a layer build to compile it
that should that should work uh so now i
want to so i want to
have a terminal file as input so i'm
going to search
in a layer to find if there's something
available so a layer
list so here we we use a local index
to not rely on the network for this demo
so there's only what we need
actually we're missing a few characters
on the left but there's there's an
adatomal project here so that's
exactly what i need so
pierre marie will head oh what's going
on
well i think it's gonna be okay uh so
yes right perfect so now we
want to use the adatomal parser so we
are going to specify that
it's a dependency of our project with
the uh the width command so a layer with
adatomer and so that's it
uh so here everything is local but
otherwise you would download
the the sources from the from the
network but here everything is local so
now we can
open the the project file
and add the dependency in the project
file so with
a data tunnel that's it
okay and now you can close and recompile
and
now we we can compile with the
dependency
so a layer will also compile the thermal
library
and so now we can start working in our
source file
and first we will with the the the
add-on package
uh maybe primarily you can start copy
past from
the from the thing we prepared that
would be easier
[Music]
so yeah we're gonna weave the thermal
file
and also add a textile to have some text
output
okay we're going to create a result
variable actually it's a constant uh
that is
this is the result of opening a thermal
file
so that's the adatomal api and then yeah
the first
the first if statement we're gonna check
if we
we could open or not the
the thermal file so yeah
okay so now we can go back to the to the
command line and you can
compile the the project okay everything
work fine and if you do a layer
run this will uh actually execute
our program and of course we don't have
any thermal config file so we see the
the error receive here so now you can
open
config.tamul file create a config.tml
file
and we are going to put some parameters
in it so we are going to set
rgb values in floating point so
for instance r just r equals
0.5 and g
equals 0 0 and
b equals 0 0 for instance so that's our
thermal configuration
so you can close and if you run again
this time we should be able to
load the tunnel so now we have
the ability to load a configuration very
quickly and now we want to have the
possibility to export to a pdf
so we are going to look in the uh in the
list of projects that we have
in our year and we see that we that's
very nice
thank you got here we have a project to
generate pdfs
so same procedure a layer with
apdf
so now it's a dependency we can open yet
again the the project file
to add this in our project
[Music]
no i don't think the name is it's the
same actually you have to look on the
because uh pdf out i think
all right yeah pdf aussie audit
so you can remove a pdf okay
nice now with the go back to the to the
source file
we can copy paste the value so here
we are reading so from from the
from the thermal result we are going to
get the r
g and b value and convert to pdf
output real types
so this is reading the the configuration
from the
from the thermal file yeah
till the end and then we open
uh yeah
we create a pdf uh we set the color from
the configuration
and we draw a rectangle and we close the
pdf
so if you save and do
a layer run actually because alairan
will also try to build
before and hopefully this is going to
work and if you
open the pdf we should have
a somewhat red
square uh
so that's it for the demos just to show
you how uh
quickly we can prototype stuff with our
ir that's otherwise it would
would have been possible before but you
would have to search on github and
download things and you don't know how
to install them etc etc
with this it's extremely quick to do so
so now to pr marie for
now that you have benefited from the
contribution of the community how you
can
now contribute back
okay thank you fabian so yes we have
this great project
and now we want to make it available for
the outer world
so there are several steps to do it so
i won't do it here because i'm offline
but
the step is to first clone the git
repository that contains
every catalogue of every
ada project registered in a layer
then you add this uh index you make
uh or it should be should be a liar uh a
lli here
three-letter acronyms anyway uh
you make a liar aware of this index that
you have cloned
and then you have to so write some
configuration file to describe
the project that you want to make
available to uh the author world
so this uh this file has
is so it's a it's a thermal thermal
filtermal is a
it's uh it's a it's a syntax that looks
like
any files for those who who know it and
it's very simple
but most importantly so what's what data
you have to put in the in the in the
file it's described in a
in a in a document that describes all
your what you
what you need to to put there and
so yeah so
we'll do this in a moment but just for
the
what we have to do so it's we want to
put the name of
the project that we want to contribute
to uh to contribute
uh some kind of text uh purpose text to
uh to
describe what the project is about we
can put a website
we can give a list of authors we have
also
a list of what we call maintainers so
it's the people that
so you when you write tamil file in in
layers thermal files in a layer it's uh
you are a maintainer you have
you are the person not necessarily that
wrote the project that but
the person who makes this project
available to uh to the other world you
are the maintainer
and yes and really specific so
generally uh software evolves you don't
want to
so you when you publish a project it's
the first
version but you want sometimes to
publish other versions
updates and so in
in the index you have one file that
describes all the
the various releases and so it's time to
uh
to do the demo okay so
as i said i want i want to do the uh the
regular clone because i don't have
internet here but
uh okay so we have this nice project
and actually the index
effect version of the index is here so
what does the index looks like
more like this so html file describes
one
project that is made available uh
you have this this file that is a kind
of manifest
and here well this is not what you
should have usually i mean
this these two archives are the sources
of the project we want to contribute
you are not supposed to put them in the
index in the index you put
uh you say oh okay this uh this source
package for
so for the release one of my project is
we'll download it on github on
from somewhere else but here we put
there here just because
of the demo effect we don't want to rely
on the internet on being able to reach
the internet
all right so i don't know the format the
format by heart
and i think nobody should bother
actually learning it so i just take
another something else as an example and
write my own
so yes first of all
so my project is called my project so
i'll create a directory to put
all right so i'm creating this file to
describe
my project so first of all
i have to put some general information
about
the project so i can put a description
here we are so
who wrote this library well it's fabio
thank you you are the author on the
other hand i am the maintainer so
because i'm the one watching the thermal
file
and something important
it's the logins because the um
so this is my my login on github
they're contributing to the community
community index
on github is special we are
making approvals so that when you write
when you contribute a project you are
the only one
able to modify it in the future
so putting my login here make sure that
future contributions to this file
will be uh only i will be able to do
them
all right so now i give
the list of project files that are part
of this
of my project so here it's simple
all right license i don't think it's
it's optional okay because we haven't
chosen the license for your project so
no no light sense all right
and then so this is the first release
of this magnificent project so this is
release
0.1 and oh
so yes i need to create a source package
so that a layer can pull the
get the sources from somewhere so let's
create a source package
i'll be right back so my project is
inside my project folder so let's do
this
ah
oh i should have written if you want to
do things right
okay so we have a source package
actually i should have sorry about this
i should have removed the a layer
directory
in it because it's not supposed to be
part of the sources
all right so i will create my source
package
and then moving it to the index
again you should your this specific part
you're not supposed to do it
uh you just publish a source archive
somewhere
on the internet it's just fine but here
we don't have internet
with github it's really easy to push an
archive on the repositories
all right i don't want to have to make
typos
alright so back to my description
so so it's a local file
there i am all right so now
my my software is
registered in in the index let's try to
uh
to actually use it
and oh the maintenance should be an
email okay
so there's a lot of checks on what needs
to be on the required field etc so don't
worry too much we will check before we
add your your thermal file in the index
and yes something important so i gave
the uh a source archive
but a layer wants to he wants you to put
some uh
checksum integrity so that
[Music]
so that when it downloads the source it
needs to be sure that it's actually the
source
the exact source that was intended when
the uh
when the project was registered it's a
security check
so we have to compute
512 some so let's do this
format source archive
where is it
okay so this is the checksum
it's very secure
okay so now i've added
the sun so
it's great allow layer i know it's not
this one
yeah this one so
i have the sources and uh and some
some sources now i should be able to
build it
but no no i forgot an important step
which is
telling a lawyer that might put my
project depends on
other projects so it's it's important so
that a layer actually when it gets
my project it also downloads a data
model
the idatamo project and the apdf1
so actually
it was wrong so let's fix it
let's fix this here so how do we declare
dependencies well it's simple we say
something like this without typos
and we say okay so the the release 0.1
of my project depends on
so it's a data model
and we depend on so here we
depend on version one and this is the
kind of
special syntax to give constraints about
because generally you can depend on
version
version 1.0 of a project but this
is also supposed to work with version
1.1 etc you don't want to list every
release possible
so there is a special dsl to express
the dependencies i won't cover it here
and so a pdf
if i remember correctly it's 5.0.0 i'm
not sure
let's try oh but wait i can ask a lawyer
no so i meant yeah show
a pdf it's version currently
okay i can read it here but yeah five
oh yes great so it's five not uh great
okay so this is my new index now let's
try again
to get the project and build it
so i can use i don't remember if it's
build or compile
okay thanks and what's wrong
could not resolve it
ah i it's no it's not supposed that
there is no
i ah yes right a diatomal is not it's
not version
zero uh it's not 1.00 sorry about this
yeah so it's uh now the difference
now the dependencies have been currently
set up alar is
able to properly set up the project
and now yes
it worked we have our output the pdf
okay so small and simple there are
several gotchas and we are
running out details but uh this is a
quick that was a quick demo of how to
contribute a project to the
outer world you want to yeah yes
thank you
so as you can see the process is a bit
uh tedious to to contribute and that's
why
as errol said that's one of the things
we want to improve in 2020
make it make this process easier and
quicker
uh so to end the presentation i'm going
to show you
the the prototype or
more or less proof of concept website
that we have on so it's at
a layer.ada.dev so this is the main page
it's actually a copy of the readme from
the repository so you have instructions
to get started how to compile a layer
and how to start using it
then you have two main pages you have
the crates which is the list of crates
available in the system and you
also have a search
so if you if we look at the crate so
here you have all the
the the the projects that are actually
in a layer available today
uh so we have the list here and then we
are going to open one of them
and so you have at the top you have some
the
actually the information that you saw
pierre marie enter in the tamil file you
can find it
uh here so we have the name we have the
short description
website etc and then you can also
put a long description with a markdown
format to provide information to your
users etc
so this one has no dependency but the
dependencies are also
also listed here and you can click to
navigate the dependency
you can also have tags uh to be able to
search for other projects
related to this one and so that's going
to be the last one
actually it's it's when you click on a
tag it's like searching in the the
search box and you can see you can
see the for instance here i typed game
and i see all the game related
crates available and so when you
contribute a crate to the index it will
automatically everyday regenerate the
website to have your
your crate available uh and so i think
that's it for our presentation
uh we are really excited about alar
because
we think it's a game changer for the
hidden ecosystem
and hopefully will make it a lot easier
for people to collaborate
with ada and so as alejandro said now we
are
in an open beta period so we expect a
lot of feedback from
from you all and of course new projects
to put in the
in the index thank you maybe i should
add
yes if you know if you want to uh
sorry so if you want to uh to check it
out
go to the uh to the alligator projects
from the aliyah project uh projects on
github
and so if you if you have issues you can
open issues directly on github
and uh yeah that's the that's the right
way to give feedback
is to go to this repository and open
issues and
i even pull requests if you want to
contribute that's uh that would be great
uh yeah thank you jeremiah
thank you
do we have time for questions
yes so i starting here
right so the question is are we using
the default gpr file that come with
each project so yes that's right
we we try to not uh
have specific requirements
for a layer in each project so in theory
if you are already
using gpr build to compile your project
it should work in a layer as well
my actual question to this is
this is an option for you to make some
restrictions on what can be in there
the problem with gpr it is near to
impossible to overwrite some values that
are defined inside the gpr file
so for example if the developer says
this is a dynamic library it will always
be the dynamic library
in some context for example you need
aesthetic library so
okay so the question is about
configuration of the
gpr build project for instance you can
have variables to say that you want a
static library or a dynamic library
the answer is that you have some ways to
declare those
those variables in the thermal files
actually so you specify
in in the an inner layer you specify
that this project has different options
and so they are visible from the from
the
allier point of view
you can also you want to talk about this
uh yes so yeah actually and that's the
way so in india
in your ally ortomal file you actually
declare what are the variables from your
project file uh and then with alara
build you can specify them like you
would do with uh jpr bill
so it's yeah
the problem is that if you need a
specific dependency and the dependency
doesn't define what you need to build
the dependency with your project
for example if you're targeting a
specific platform
so okay so i'm not sure
where you're going so you just said if
you if your dependency doesn't specify
what you need
right there's a problem
independently independent executable
okay and the library didn't define
anything that we could tell the compiler
okay compile this library
okay so so i think i think the answer is
um
i don't know but maybe we can talk after
because it's a bit complex
so there's also there's also going to be
in my opinion
a discussion between people contributing
libraries and people
using them so if you find a library in a
layer that doesn't have what you
need you should contact the maintainer
and say hey maybe you should have this
and for the next three days et cetera et
cetera
but uh it's it's it's so far we are
let's say it's uh we're not looking that
much uh into the details on
of how things are built uh and and so on
and so forth
and also here we are relying on gpr
build so if there's
uh limitation with gprb's we have to
deal with them
honest yes
is there a plan to integrate the
modifications and
like work with the gpr file even further
because when you do a liar with
why does it is there a reason why it
doesn't add the width
to the gpr file and the other way around
if you
if you create a new project and you
already have a gpr file to
determine the dependencies at this point
the reason is that i don't like tools
that modify my files
so when i did this files data layer
generates are
as complete as possible but my files my
project file is not modified
we discussed sometimes about this we
might perhaps add some switch that you
tell alright okay go ahead and modify my
project file i'm okay with that
for example but that's the actual reason
right now
yeah yeah this happens this happens
so yeah the the one something specific
as well is that sometimes
from one uh a layer crate you will have
several
gpr files and you don't necessarily want
to use all of them
so it's not it's not a we are living in
a
in an ecosystem where there are already
projects out there and
uh they do not necessarily fit perfectly
the
the alar scheme so there are there are
things that are
you know a bit different from the the
basic case that we show here which is a
one uh one project with the one project
file and uh
and
a if the uh files were listed in the in
the crate
like what i can do with from that crate
and
then maybe like okay if you do alive or
with it could tell you like
if you want to start using the package
please add with
yeah that's a good suggestion
yeah the question was that when you do
the alarm with
it gets added to the dependencies but
the project file is not modified so it
won't build out of the box
so you have to manually add it to the
gpl to your own project file
and yes the suggestion is to inform the
user that the
dependency dependency that you just
added
has all those project files available
for use
no sorry there was a second question
that was uh
tell me if i'm wrong uh couldn't a liar
read an existing project file and guess
what packages
are should be added as dependencies so
it could but it um you don't have the
version information
in the gpr file so for instance if
your project file depends on the adatama
library
which version should allow you we could
add the heuristics and so on but it's
getting much more complex
than the other
so it's it would sound nice as a feature
and useful but it's not clear how how it
should work exactly
right right the hints could be
definitely useful
and actually what you said about the you
know telling the users they are this and
that
project file available actually we do
have the list of project files
in the terminal it's available so that's
i think yeah that's something that's
definitely doable
so i invite you actually to open an
issue and
share your feedback
yeah if you want to implement it that's
fine as well
and there was the mentioning that the
maintainer say email login
and it can't be changed
so once you're declared to be the
mainstay you know
and when you just kind of lose interest
what happens
so the question is about somehow
somebody else can take over yeah i get
it
so the question is about the uh
maintainers and maintainers logins in
the
in the thermal file um so
we said that it's to make sure that you
are the owner of the
the thermal file and that you're the
only one who can change it
actually what's happened so we have we
have a maintainer field with
emails uh because we want uh
to be able to contact you at some point
we also have maintainers
logins with github logins and that's
actually for automated checks
so when you contribute to the layer
index you do a pull request and there's
a check
that you are allowed to modify this
this file but actually
if you want to transfer the the
ownership you can modify the file to
remove your name and put someone else
login and that's how you would transfer
the
the the ownership and uh
so far we'll see in the future but so
far everything is uh moderated so we
have a we have a manual review so
even if someone disappears we can decide
to transfer the ownership at some point
uh nothing is really a set in stone for
the maintainers we can
we can work around things like that
okay so the question is do we plan to
package ada drivers library which is a
project for embedded development uh in
ada
uh the answer is yes but the
the real question is how because uh
i actually i actually started there's
already uh
embedded uh crates uh available drivers
for the
7051 microcontroller uh the problem
right now is that the architecture of
the ada divers library project
does not fit very well with uh with a
layer because
it's not modular enough so we have to
find a good way to do it but
yes absolutely it will be in a layer at
some point
okay i think that's it thank you thank
[Applause]
you