and the room is very full that's
we're very glad to be here
my name is emily
yes and my colleague is frederick we
only have one mic so we're going to
switch in the middle sort of
uh but let's get started uh
i have an agenda here and at the
beginning we see
i planned to walk through the definition
of a pipeline but
considering the audience i think that's
unnecessary
so i'm going to skip that and
me i'm coming from ericsson which is
not open source of course it's a company
but we do contribute to open source
and that's why we're here today and i'd
like to start off with describing what
kind of challenges we've seen
uh considering the communication uh
between different cicd tools
and then i'm going to present the way we
solved it
yes and i'm going to speak a little bit
louder
and also how we open sourced our
solution
and how frederick and his company axis
started using the same solution
so let's skip this part as promised
and instead go straight to the
communication challenges that we've seen
at ericsson
so first of all why does cyrix don't
care about cicd
well any company that produces software
should care about
ci cd obviously and
we have a very complex environment we
have a lot of different products going
out to our customers
and different configuration applied on
top of them considering
if it's going to be to customer a or if
customer b wants them
so and we have many different pipelines
and different pipeline tools
used to produce our software
very often they're integrated into each
other they're called connected pipelines
and that's what we like to call them
and i'll go through that what i mean by
that later
um we are a very large organization we
have like hundreds of teams developing
our products
each one of them use different toolings
and
and the demands on traceability is very
high
we need to keep track of our software we
need to go see which stages does it go
through
in in in the pipeline no matter if it's
stops at delivery or if it goes all the
way into deployment to customer networks
we need to follow and see where does our
software go
we know we also need to be able to
monitor it independent of whichever
technology we use
in the background we need to be able to
keep track of the
important kpis and
i guess also visualize it in a good way
and one visualization tool would be nice
so i spoke about connected pipelines and
what i mean by that is we usually
integrate our products
into each other sort of so they're
hierarchies of products
so you've got product a and b to the
left here and they're produced in their
own separate pipelines
before they're together integrated into
the next level or the next connected
background producing the product a b
and this is a very common phenomenon at
ericsson where
we have multiple integration spots and
it's tough to keep track of all of these
dependencies to integrate upstream
and see where does this software come
from and how it has been tested before
we integrate it
and again traceability is important here
all the way
so i try to summarize into a few
questions of
what are the exact challenges we see
what are what is the problems that we
need to solve
one thing is when we use different
pipeline environments
how do we communicate about when our
product has been
delivered or released let's say our
product a
is done here how does somebody
downstream become aware of this
how can we announce this to the world
and how can we if we have another
perspective how can we
become aware when others release their
software automatically
the independent of whichever technology
stack would use it
would be nice to become aware of oh hey
this
version xyz is now available so we
automatically integrate it into our
pipeline and go for it
and how can we visualize these
connections
how can we see what kind of tests has
been done
upstream but also downstream on our
software later on
and how can we see how many has
downloaded our products it'd be nice to
know
were their tests successfully into their
environment or not
and why so
um the solution for this was that we
we focused mostly on the communication
how can we communicate across different
tools
so we came up with a solution that's
like a
common language if you will across these
different pipelines
across different tools across different
visualization tools that could based off
the same information
and we called it eiffel now ifill is and
created in 2012 so we've been using it
for a lot of years internally
a couple of years back we open sourced
it and it's now available on github
but what it is it's a message protocol
is event-based it's defining a set of
events
that you can use to communicate about
different concepts used in your pipeline
be it artifacts be it tests source code
changes
you can communicate about this
independent of whichever technology you
use
doesn't matter if it's a java
application it's uploaded somewhere to a
maven repository or if it's a docker
image you uploaded it to docker hub
and you can still communicate about it
in the same thing
in the same way and
what's uh what i think is great about
afl at least
it's you can share your pick whichever
events suit your needs
you don't have to take all of the
protocol it's a lot of events
you can share pick the ones that you
specifically need in your use case
so let's say you're only interested in
the test case related events then you
only
care about those and
the events are also linked together
and that's very important for us at
least to maintain the traceability
between them
so you can trace back from the latest
event you can go backwards in time and
see
the whole pipeline chain can represent
the pipeline
and with afl you can answer some of the
questions i
post previously for example
when we have a new artifact available
you can send out
an event saying that i've now created
this artifact
you see to the left of the in the
picture it's called a full artifact
created event
what comes after that is could be a
published event
whenever you upload it somewhere you can
send additional events
linking back to the previously created
artifact
and the linking here is important the
protocol itself defines
how you can link your events if they
must have or if they
if it's optional links and
these are all in json format against you
wondering
next question could be how can we
visualize our pipeline
it's a pipeline consists of many
different steps right
independent of how it looks you want to
maybe tell the world about what has
happened
how do we visualize this
this is a very simple ci pipeline
it's a git lab syntax so you build your
product then they test it
it tests it some more and then you
upload you build binary somewhere
and very standard case
and the some of the afl events that
could be used for this
are for example these you can have an
artifact create event
to signify the first build this is where
you actually build your
binary or whatever it might be and then
you start some
tests and then you might want to send
test case events
so you've got the triggered started and
finished events for this
and these can be sent of course these
jobs are in parallel
in this pipeline so you can send them in
two sets
and then comes the artifact published
event
as the last one to signify that hey now
my artifact is available somewhere for
downloading and i'm going to show you
the exact same
set of events only connected in an event
graph to make it clearer
so start to the left we got artifact
creator event this is the first one
in chronological order
then comes the test case events which
links back to the artifact because this
is the what
uh what we're testing and the link name
in this case
is called item under test makes
makes perfect sense to me at least and
then comes the test case started event
linking back to the triggering
and then we've got the finished event
test case finished event
this one contains the result of the test
if it was successful or not now of
course if you have
several test cases you might want to
group them under some sort of
label that's saying yes i've tested it
to this extent and i want to label my
artifact now
this is ready for the next level of
delivery
somewhere then you can call
you can send a confidence level modified
event
this is a very free formatted in a way
that you can name the conference level
whatever you want to
as long as you standardize it shouldn't
be a problem
and then you point back to the artifact
that you've created
so this is very useful for us as
listeners or consumers of this product
we know
once it has been tested enough we know
when it's reached the
confidence level we want it to have
before we actually start using it
and once the last event comes in it's
the artifact published event
we know where we can find it where is
the artifact located where can i
download it
and i have one last wrap up here as i
said we
are we have open sourced this and
it's available on github and
we really hope that the community keeps
growing
and getting more contributions because
we see
that a lot of different companies and
organizations have the same
problems that we faced
and one thing i liked about afell is
that it provides one common language
across different technology stacks
across
different tools you might use so you can
base
visualization tools on the events in
this data for example
and what's also important is the links
between the events it enables
traceability so you can follow
a complete set of pipeline you know what
has happened to your software
and you know where it might go even
further downstream
and i'd like to invite frederick to
this side of the room so we can switch
mike because he's going to tell you
about how
axis started contributing and using
eiffel
see if we can set this up here
okay so um so i'm from uh from a company
called
axis communications and and we do uh
surveillance cameras which is a kind of
a scary thing but
there are a lot of there's no software
running in these cameras
and uh somebody said
roughly around 20 lines of code in the
camera so there is a lot of software
going into it this small
thing it's a kind of a it's basically a
linux box but but still
and we have nowhere the scale that
ericsson has we have about
a thousand developers in total and the
the team that that does
the teams that do the the cameras are
about
400 developers uh and about 150 testers
and we do
we like to think we do continuous
integration at least because we
commit to master a lot of times every
day
and i'm going to try to tell you our a
full story
so emily gave you a good background on
what i feel is and
i'll try to to go through some kind of a
timeline how we
how we found out about afl and how we
adopted it and how we now
very much would like to drive our all of
our pipelines
using it that's at least that's the
ambition for
for the future
and first i would like to give you some
context on on
what exactly it is that we do so so
access is a it's quite an old
company and we we've done
in the history we've done network
connected stuff and and which is it's
basically just
making uh some kind of hardware putting
in a box and selling it that's the
standard access way that we've been
doing it for for a lot of
years and and it's basically what other
companies do also they they sell
cardboard boxes with
tech stuff in it uh but but
more and more we've been seeing a demand
from our from our business and from our
from our customers that they want
complete systems they want cloud
integration they want
they want a lot of stuff which which in
turn gives a lot more software
that has to be tested has to work
together so
that's where in there that comes the
challenge of of knowing how which which
versions work together which software
stacks works best together and so on so
that's that's kind of our the similar
challenge that ericsson has
but back to our story uh the first
recorded presence of the afl protocol at
axis
uh as as i've heard
there were a couple of engineers
attending some kind of a conference or a
meeting where somebody from erickson was
presenting some kind of visualization
tool
how you could visualize your software i
don't think it was called
i didn't i don't even think it was
referred to as a pipeline but but still
some kind of
software flow and and they found that
this was something called a fold which
was
underneath here and they were they got
intrigued so they
they started doing some tinkering on
their own and trying to trying to
make something with a full in the axis
context
and and which was which was fine but it
really didn't lead anywhere
and then it resurfaced in some kind of a
in a research
academia industry project that axis had
where
some of the researchers had found out
about eiffel from erickson also and
and it resurfaced then they did some
more tinkering and some more engineers
got interested but it was still
kind of under the radar stuff just
engineers
like technology enthusiasts that did
stuff but nothing that really
drove the business or was it was a thing
and in like the next next
big thing in my opinion was was when
axis
actually released something that had to
do with afl so these engineers had been
tinkering more and they wanted to
to make something of it they wanted to
able to produce something that was of
value so so they
they we used jenkins as almost everybody
else so they they made a jenkins plug-in
which was very basic it basically
produced
uh artifact created event when we we did
a build that was all we did
so it was kind of worthless on its own
but still it's kind of a
footprint that now we're actually
producing eiffel events we have a
message bus where there are events
coming out
but uh anyone there there was really
nobody
listening which was which is kind of a
problem because
it's it's uh when doing uh
these type of things you the the whole
point is to somebody listening and
acting on the events and there is like a
chain
created and a flow so so our biggest
problem here was
was nobody was listening in and if
nobody's listening in a
pub sub culture it's kind of hard to
know if you're making sense if
you if you in the beginning at least
because because you have to know that
that
in the beginning you have to have some
kind of acknowledgement that your event
it was useful there's a value to it so
we had to to create some kind of value
in our minimal a full implementation
and this is basically where i where i
came in in the in the eiffel
ting i i was a part of a team that does
test automation
and we were struggling with our ci part
of the testing part of our ci pipeline
it was kind of old and we didn't really
want to do what we wanted to do with our
testing
so we we started looking
to uh rebuilding it basically or
changing it and so on and i had a
coffee discussion with a colleague of
mine he he was one of those
uh eiffel tinkering engineers he said
you should look at eiffel if you're
going to do things from scratch
you might as well look at eiffel because
it's pretty cool you can do cool stuff
with it
and we looked into eiffel and we a
colleague me and a colleague and we
really liked it we
we saw that this was this is something
that could that could probably
not solve our immediate problems but
there was a bigger issue of of the
system of systems talk and and knowing
uh
information about the software that goes
in from from everywhere so
so we decided to make our new
testing part of the ci cd pipeline uh
talk a full
and understand afl and in this we
started listening
to the jenkins events the lonely guy
over here
that was playing a full music and nobody
was listening
so we actually started listening to that
and we started triggering
our tests based on those those events
which which gave us a
much more better understanding of what
it is like to have an event-driven
pipeline and what
what it was like to adhere to a protocol
like eiffel
and and we actually wound up being a
great listener today for
protocol and during
during the development of our our
testing pipeline
we had to learn a full basically so we
we wrote a bunch of uh python libraries
uh
and two of them which were kind of
important at least we thought
we we we said we had to we have to
contribute back to since it was an open
source
if it was an open source uh community an
open source protocol we said we can
contribute here we can learn people how
to
teach people how to how to use afl
uh and these two libraries the a full
python lib which is a
kind of a small library that lets you
publish
a4 messages and listen to a film that's
just uh
on the message bus it's it's
very useful if you want to get started
with iphone and then there's something
called
eiffel graphql api which is basically an
api
on top of the the
the event repository which is basically
a storage for events because if you want
to look at events
back in history you have to store them
somewhere you can't just keep them on
the bus
so that's basically our graphql which is
kind of useful
if you want to start tinkering with with
the storing events and looking back in
history and so on um
and this this open sourcing of this got
uh
access more engaged in the community and
we actually there's a
there's a conference called uh called
eiffel summit
uh it's a very small conference but we
actually access actually hosted it
um uh this fall uh
and uh in in moving forward we're going
to try to to keep the backlogs
working with an open backlog concept as
as we learned about afl how we are
our journey will try to contribute
directly to the
to the community rather than just doing
stuff inside and then just dumping it
outside which is kind of a bad thing
and then moving forward um as afield is
now a thing
at axis we actually have a small team
that work with afl and we're we're going
to
really going to try to to drive all the
all of our pipelines we see them being
event driven
in some way moving forward
and also also we're going to try to
to contribute more to the afl community
trying to to like emily said we want to
spread it want to
make more people try it out and then see
if it can become a thing
so we'll try to to contribute more of
our experiences
uh moving forward in 2020
and that's that's that's my act is a
full
journey basically
and we'd like to thank you for listening
to us and here's some some contact
information
uh the eiffel community on github and we
have a google group and a slack channel
and a youtube channel also with some
some videos if you want to learn more or
get a more basic tutorial
of what april is
and now i guess it's squishy
[Applause]
is there integration for gitlab
and if not how can i do it like
in the jobs or stages manually to
send events to
so the question was is there some kind
of a git lab
integration for for rifle
uh not that i know i'm currently on on
github i don't know if no
not yet so and i'm i'm not
quite sure how gitlab works so uh
so uh i i it should be possible there's
no i don't see any
like big technical blocking it it's just
that somebody has to
to contribute it and do it but it's say
let's say i want to use that and i want
to use it
because we don't use checkpoints yeah
how would is there any
like is there and we could have any kind
of power to do it
within my like manually like
triggering events
there are some if you look at the the
python library
there is some there's some basic basic
tutorial how to set that up how to send
events and and
receive events and then there's also
also something called i think it's
called a full easy to use or
which is basically a set of docker
containers that you could just
spin up and you get a full like a small
pipeline
which produces events but i don't it's
it's that's something that erickson
contributed i don't know if all of it is
open sourced yet might be but it's
basically something you can try out
to get some messages going and then try
to get a feel for how how it works
if you would like to for example reduce
lead times
yes absolutely uh so the question was uh
since we've been sending events for
several years now within ericsson
uh we have of course a lot of data
accumulated
so we the question was if we can look at
lead times and see where the bottlenecks
and the pipelines and yes of course we
do have that possibility and that's one
of the
great benefits that we've seen
internally at least
and that's why i think i don't know how
many millions of events we have
stored but there's a lot of them
so it's indeed possible if you have like
a
implementation of a storage somewhere
and then you can look it up and you can
see
because all the events are time stamped
so you can also see lead times between
the events
between different activities in your
pipeline which is very useful
and yes frederick mentioned i'd just
like to add because
aside from the protocol we have some
example implementations of services
surrounding the protocol
helping to send the events helping to
visualize them i think we also have open
source and they're more
coming the more planned for that
it's just a matter of prioritization and
so on
any more questions yes in the back
so the question was have we tried to
use eiffel outside of development to
trigger some manual activities
if i understood it correctly and
not i'm not aware that we
listen and act upon these events
and then doing some sort of manual step
of course it
it's at all possible but the
listeners usually are performing some
sort of automatic task afterwards
and as far as i know we mostly focus on
up until continuous delivery sort of
deployment stages don't really trigger
on eiffel events
later on yet at least
i can add something to that so so there
are there are
like more generic a full events like
announcement events
that say say something that something
has happened and you could
definitely use that for for for
signaling
other people in the organization and we
actually use that to
a sort of a debugging thing that we so
we know that we've gone a certain
path through our testing ci system we do
announcements here and there to see okay
we've gone this far because it's
it's a microservices architecture it's
kind of hard to keep track of everything
so so it's it's a handy thing but there
are announcements events that are very
generic so you can use them for
for almost anything
any more questions
okay thank you