my next duty
is to introduce the next speaker
jean-pierre rosen that's myself hello
and i'm going to
give you a general overview of the ada
language for those who never heard about
it before
so unless you have any questions about
the organization
okay that's fine everybody's got a
raffle ticket
yeah okay
there it is
okay
let's go before i start i'm working for
a company called edalog
i have wrote some flyers too and so
that's a company doing
training consultancy and etc about ada
so you may think oh that guy is telling
us
how nice it is because that's his
business okay no in fact it's the other
way around
in a previous life i was a teacher in an
engineering school
and i was a mother responsible for
the teaching of programming languages
and compilers
and it's because i thought that ada was
a very nice language
that i made my business with ada okay
so it's not because it's my business
it's the other way around
so when talking about ada you hear
certain
[Music]
dates and numbers
ada is not an acronym the name of ada
byron
contest of lovelace and she was
she's famous for being the first
programmer in history she worked on
babbage machine
if you heard about that and um
so she she could never run
her programs because the machine never
worked
however they were later recorded in
pier one i think and worked right
out of the box so the first program had
no bugs and the first programmer was a
lady
we've changed that since
oops so come on
the first version was in 1983.
don't tell me it's very old it's much
it's much more modern than c
and it's approximately the same time
that c
plus plus appeared so it's not
older than a must use
programming languages to nowadays
at that time is quite it was quite
revolutionary
by already having in a well designed
set exception generics tasking
and many features that you could not
find
in the same language
at that time there was
my mouse is jumping um
and i think
yeah 1995
was a major rework
introduced object-oriented programming
a kind of mechanism a synchronization
mechanism called protected objects
and a way of organizing
the various modules of your design into
a hierarchy called hierarchical
libraries
by the way it was the first language
that was object it was the first
object-oriented
language to be standardized at least at
an international level as an iso
language that was about three years
before c plus
205 brought some improvement
from other languages especially the
notion of
interfaces that work mostly like java
interfaces and also some
more and more libraries and
services that are that are
added to the language in the form of
extra libraries
and in 2012 which is
the latest revision to date
eda was has been going more formal with
contracts preconditions
post-condition what is called
programming by contract
so it's moving to be more and more
formal
and more and more not exactly provable
but checkable a trend time for various
conditions
so especially here
it's my pleasure to say that eda is a
free language it does not
belong to any big industry
or any major brand
it is first of all an international
standard
and it's entirely controlled by its
users
the the evolution of the language
is made by a group from iso
and those belong to various companies
and
all work to improve the language
you have three compilers
well gcc has an ada
version you know gcc is all languages
compilers so
what we call math is actually the eda
front end to gcc
and it's like all of the cc distributed
as free software you also have
proprietary compilers that's normal
that's
a world of business many free resources
are available and you have a dynamic
community so you have youth group
and groups on all the usual
social media
so you may think that you don't see
much ada that's true but that's because
the people
who use ada are not generally
those that you see everywhere i mean
if you take the tiob index for example
you'll see eda completely down
in the ranking why because the tiob
index
is based on the number of software on
bit github
and the popularity in the social
networks
now euro control
for example has 2.5 million lines of ada
i don't think they are on github they're
not
of course and when palace design
civilian and military radars
they're not on github okay and the
software for the ariane e6 rockette
is not on github and so on it's an
industrial language
and those people don't put the software
on github
okay so if you know as a physicist
when you measure something you have to
know what you are measuring
the tiob index is a very good index of
the popularity
of the languages for hobbyists
but not for industrials okay so it
doesn't prove so here are a few
examples of where you can find eta
software the tgv has
lots of ada software in it
the a 380 and many other airplanes
at airbus and boeing
the automated uh metro line in paris
that that works so well that it has been
sold to the american it's also
the system in automated subway of new
york
this was the rosetta probe
that explored a comet
it worked for 10 years and then woke up
and
achieved successfully its mission
this is a brand luxury goat
that has been entirely written in nature
and so on
so why would you use ada in general
it uh forbids a lot of things
you know most languages tell you oh our
language
is very it's very good it
allows you to do a number of things with
eda the other people will tell you
our language is great it forbids you
from making
many errors okay it's a language for
safety
it's a language for uh software that
works
out of the box
so thing when i hear people complaining
about
buffer overflows or the attacks or those
kind of thing
well this problem has been solved since
1983. so there is no reason
nowadays to complain about buffer
overflows if you have one it's just that
you do it you don't use the proper
language
and so as i mentioned the idea of ada
is to check as much as possible at
compile time so
when you write something in era in
general it will
never compile the first time the
compiler will always find something
that's
not correct in your code the good news
is when you run it for the first time it
very often runs out of the box and that
is very
satisfactory okay i write something
the compiler helps me run
write the test run okay it works
go to the next problem
so what's important in a language is not
what it allows
what's important in a language is what
it forbids
okay because that's where the safety
comes from
if you have a language like c that
allows
everything well that's normal it's a
portable assembly language
so you have to take up the
responsibility
of safety if you allow everything there
is nothing you can prove
the only thing you can prove is when you
have
rules that forbid some
for some incorrect constructs
so here is a little picture that
summarizes the shape of ada
you have a big concrete
basis each language the syntax
is based on pascal it i was
designed after a competitive
competition and readability
was very important a very important
criteria
in that competition all the languages
that made it to the half
final were had a syntax based on ada
and pascal honestly
i don't understand why all the new
languages find it obligatory to have a c
based syntax c
don't misunderstand me c is a very good
low level language certainly the best
low-level language the requirements for
c
was to be a portable assembly and as a
portable assembly it's very good
we'll see that with eda we work at a
different
level of abstraction okay
but having a high level language with a
syntax of c i don't
understand quite well the benefit anyway
we will have lots of examples
on top of that you have a very strong
typing system i think yes that's it
so the typing system is
really the backbone of the language
everything is directed
after the notion of types so
almost every other language appears as
weakly typed compared to
error so we'll have some examples
and then you have a number of pillars
here that are features of the language
that serve
each precise goal of software
engineering
packages is the way to split
your program into well-defined
independent modules it's strange that
few
languages address that question of
modules
even name spaces for example in c
plus plus a way to control
visibility but you can
add anything at any time to a namespace
so there is no control
of the modularity of it okay here we
have
the ide that we build
an application from software components
with someone who provides a software
component someone who uses the
software company exceptions well now
it's quite common in most languages so i
assume you know what it is that the way
of having
runtime safety in ada
everything that can happen that's bad
will be translated into an exception
the requirements were that anything that
happens
at run time will translate into an
exception
because when you are writing software
for a missile
for example you cannot run after it and
press ctrl alt l
okay the missile has to care for himself
whatever
happens okay so
even memory vibration in c
code for example that you call from eda
will be translated
into an exception or an
io error or an overflow or whatever you
have
will be translated into exceptions
generics well they're a bit like
templates in c plus plus
or should i say templates in c plus plus
were inspired from edit generics
it's a way to have reusability
in the presence of strong typing if you
write an algorithm for a certain type
you cannot use it for another type so
it's a way of parameterizing your
software with so you can use it on
various types
task multitasking is an integral part of
the language
and because data is also used
for embedded software you have
a lot a number of features that allow
you to
access the low level without losing the
high level
approach
and all that is
supporting the roof the programming
methodologies
that's very important itada was designed
to support methodology
now nowadays some people say well it's
important to have good methodologies
nobody would dare saying the opposite of
course
however some people say well we have a
good design methodology so
we don't care what the coding language
is used after that
okay in error we say no why would you
stop
the methodological effort when you go to
the coding phase
if you have a language that actively
supports
the methodology which means that you
have a direct
traceable connection between a
methodology and according language
then you can trace it all over and there
is also an
effect it's hard to prove but we
witnessed that every day that if you
have a
error in your methodology and your
language
matches the methodology
then a design er will translate into
something that doesn't compile
i cannot tell you how often i've seen
people coming to my office saying
well that done language i wrote that it
won't compile
look at what you've written is it
consistent
don't you think that there is something
that's
misguided here oh um
yes i'll change that and when you think
the designer around magically it
compiles
so because your types all the features
matches exactly the objects of your
methodology
so the idea of ada is to
further the methodological effort
into the programming language including
now since 1995
of course object orientation
and you have the dog houses on the side
here
that are called spatial need annexes
because not
everyone has the same needs and because
every ada compiler is validated against
a very
difficult validation suite
if you put something in the language you
must provide it
no subset no supersets is allowed
by the way i have here the
data reference manual if some of you
want to have a look
but don't take it it's fine um
[Music]
and although nowadays you have it on the
on the web
it's nice to have it on paper sometimes
so extra services
that are not required from
all compilers are put into the annexes
for special purpose so uh
i'll talk later about the distributed
system annex
you have some analytics for real-time
systems
you know it's for system programming
analytics for
um information system for numerics
and so on so people who don't care for
numerics do not need to bring in all the
numeric stuff that's what it means
so it when you look at it
it looks like an improved pascal it
looks very classy a classical language
but when you use it you discover that
it's much
more different from other languages than
the syntax
seems to show
okay something to understand
is the building block approach of ada
you've heard that ada was an
object-oriented language
you look at the list of keywords
surprise surprise
class is not a key word in that language
actually the idea is to
make building blocks and to construct
paradigms by assembling building blocks
so i i'll give you
an idea about what it means you have
the lego the primable against
lego approach if you have primables you
have
very nice pictures that are designed for
a special purpose
and cannot be used for anything else
than their intended purpose they're
ready to use but if you want to make
something different with it
it's not possible
if you take a piece of lego a single
piece of lego
there is nothing you can do with that
just that that's not funny okay but if
you assemble those pieces together
then you can make very simple things
like this one
or very sophisticated ones like this one
or even this
so the era approach is
to have various building blocks
and you assemble them to build your
paradigms
so let's see at some data
as i mentioned it's a pascal like syntax
so if i have
a type color and i want to iterate over
over it i can say for say
in color loop and every
construct every statement is terminated
by a matching
and loop so you don't have curly
brackets beginning and
if you have that you need if you have
only one statement and so on
you always have a clear beginning a
clear end
and uh an interesting property of that
syntax
is that if you copy a line
and paste it somewhere else
it won't introduce syntax errors
you cannot say that of many other
languages
also the control
object i don't say variable c here for
example
is considered a constant by the rule of
the language
you cannot change it in the middle of
the loop
and it's local to the loop so you are
certain that you
don't have any remaining value that you
use
incorrectly after that because you don't
have it
after that you also have the usual
uh while loop
you can give a name to a loop
oh yes i have it here so you can give a
name to a loop and if you give a name to
the loop
you must repeat it to at the end and
that's very convenient
because when you have several end loop
and loop and loop and loop
you can document which loop you are
closing
don't tell me oh yes i'd see there i can
do that with a comment
because you never know if a comment is
true
while here it's checked by the compiler
therefore you can rely on it
okay
so you have the usual if else if acif
a stretcher you have a case statement so
for
the c language people it's a switch the
equivalent of a switch case
but there is a very nice feature of eda
given the type of eye did i mention aid
i was strongly typed yes i did
um you know all the possible
values because a type data is a set
of values with a set of operations it's
mathematically well-defined
and knowing the set of value the
compiler will
check that every possible value
is provided in the various branches
of the kit statement or you can have a
one of those to cover
all the remaining ones and that's a
very important feature of eta awa users
love that feature because in general you
avoid when others close and therefore
if you change anything in your type add
new values or
change it in any way the compiler will
automatically
tell you all the places where change
needs to be made
if you add a new value and forget some
case statements
it will not silently ignore it it will
tell you oh here you forgot to give me
that value
and if the instead of chasing a bug for
two days
you'll immediately fix the compiler
error and that will be all
okay
also ada makes every attempt
to allow you to work directly with
high-level
objects and not go down
to loops into loops into loops over the
individual elements for example there is
a notation called
aggregates if you want to write
the value of a matrix you can write it
directly
like that okay you don't have to assign
to individual
elements or for example here i have a
piece
of a linked list so in my
head i create a node initialized by a
certain value
and the next element is itself a node
initialized by a certain value
and uh well we'll stop there so the next
element is
no you describe globally your structure
you don't have to go down deep in the
structure
with every element and
needless to say all the
consistency of the values is always
checked at compile time
so if there is anything that's not
correct
you'll know immediately
so i said strong typing what does it
mean
imagine i have the
age the age of a person well when you
design a type types in data
are abstractions of real
world objects well you cannot
add the age of a person
to a number of flows it's meaningless
okay so in eda you define a type and
every type
is different if you have here something
that says
if it says type is it's
always a different type that's
incompatible with
any other type so we have if i have the
age of a person
and the number of flaws in a building
i can use the appropriate values here
but if i can if i try to mix them up
it will simply not compile
tell that to a six years
old boy and he
he will look at you with glass eyes
saying well it's been
a certain number of years even at that
age
that he's been told that you don't mix
apple and oranges
but ada is the only language that allows
you to check that at uh
compile time at language level
so the id when you design a software
okay you should always do it this way
first you model the problem space
there you have edges you have flaws
you have things like that okay
and then you have to map those high
level types
to a matching level where you have only
bite inks
and things like that
that the language level okay
with other languages you have to do the
mapping
even with supposedly high-level
languages like
java or simplestress and so on
all the integer types you have are the
machine types
so you have to do the mapping the new
thing with ada
is that ada gives you access directly to
that
level and therefore it's the compiler
who does the mapping
it means that it relieves you from many
portability problems because that level
is completely machine independent
therefore the compiler chooses the
compiler knows
the machine and it will always choose
the appropriate representation for your
types
but your types are by nature machine
independent
packages i mentioned that you still have
seeds but just be careful with my
little wire hair um
packages are the way to
make
modules with a well-defined interface
and the main principle is that the
user of a take it as a library for
example
does not know how it works
and the designer of a library does not
know
who will use it okay so
it guarantees the independence of this
point of view
so a package has a specification
for example here i have a column manager
and i define a color type as private
it means okay i tell you there is a type
it's called color but i don't
tell you how it's it's made inside
and then you can provide operation
here we have the
here we have the redefinition of
operation
so i can add two colors
to make an another color or multiply a
certain color by a certain density
i announce those properties but i don't
tell how it's done
there is a problem because the compiler
needs to know the implementation if you
want to be able
to use that abstraction using only the
visible part
so a package can have a private part
where you tell the truth to the compiler
but the external user cannot make
any use of that private part it's
completely checked by the compiler
and then you have the package body that
the implementation
of the package where you
give the actual code for all the
provided operations okay
and an important feature of ada is that
you can use the package
as soon as you have compiled the
specification
you don't even need to
have written the body okay
so you can write a specification then
you write the users of the specification
this allows you to check that what
you've specified
matches the needs of the user
and once you are certain that what you
have proposed
is what is needed only then you think
about the implementation
so that says a lot of time because too
often
people write a lot of code just to
discover that it's not what was
necessary
okay with data you can check it
beforehand
okay and then well you just
when you you when you are using one of
those packages
you must always mention them
in a ways clause so every dependence
between modules
is explicit in error which means that
you can have
automated makers i should say
without the need of a make file and so
without errors
in the make file because that's
something i
[Music]
never had a good explanation about how
do you
prove that the makefile is correct
well make files are supposed to
have less compilations let's face it
every time you use the make files if you
have a doubt
you say make clean make right
that's the exactly the opposite goal or
the make file which is supposed to save
you
compilation okay but because you don't
know well
you could as well recompile everything
every time
so the idea is to enforce abstraction by
separating
specification from implementation
and so as i said you have no make files
a feature of data that is uh
that you won't find in many in most
languages actually i don't know if any
other language that had that is a
possibility
of having parameterized types they are
called discriminated types
so the same way as you could define
parameters
to a subprogram you can define
parameters to a type and you see i can
have
a component here whose size
depends on the parameter or i can
even have case parts where
the elements that are part of the record
depends on the variant of the parameter
so it's very convenient when you have
flexible
types like here it would be a student
record
so we have students may have various
majors
and if it's in letter they have a
grading relating and so on
okay so variant records
[Music]
object oriented programming
be careful the model of ada
is somehow different from what you can
know from other languages
that's where you see the building block
approach
we have seen the packages support
encapsulation
there is a special kind of type called
tag
types that support dynamic binding
a class is a
type with dynamic binding
which is encapsulated therefore
it's a design pattern in either it's a
tag
type within a package so typically
that's not very original i have a widget
so i call my package widget and
i give the type that corresponds to the
data
a special name that's not required by
the language it's just a good habit
called for example instance so it's a
tag type because you have the word
tagged here okay
and then i can have procedures that
work on that those procedures that are
given in the same package specification
as the
tag type are what you would call
methods in other languages so
presumably you've heard of c plus plus
in c plus plus you define a class
with data members and
function members okay the function
members
are the methods in eda if you want
the package played the role of the class
the data members are gathered into that
tag type and the operations
are the methods so it's not that far
away
from what happens in c plus plus except
that
all the data parts are grouped into the
tag type
and then of course you can inherit so
you can define a new type
as inheriting from
the type of above where is my mouse it's
here so it inherits from this one
and you can add a visible part
or a private part you may want to give
the extra components
to leave them visible or to hide them
in the private part so
an important feature of ada is that
object-oriented programming is not
related to pointers
much most languages allow you to do
object-oriented programming only
with will use pointers in ada
you can write huge programs including
object-oriented ones
without any pointer okay
so the whole issue of the
memory management becomes much simpler
so this model gives you an important div
that's what the important difference
and others here i have a hierarchy of
those types
and there is a different type called
the class wide type that includes
the whole tree in eda we make the
difference
between a single type called the
specific type
and the whole tree most languages
confuse
those two notions and so you can have
for example if i have a procedure move
with a parameter of type widget
class it means it can work on
every value from the whole tree
okay the set of value for the classroom
type is the union of all values from
each type that's in it okay and so you
differentiate with that
operations method that are on a single
type
and class wide operation that operate on
the whole
tree and of course if i'm calling that
move here at compile time i don't know
which kind
of type i have here therefore it will
introduce
dynamic binding okay
so time is running
starting with 205 there are interfaces
that work
roughly like java interfaces
you can define type as an
interface and they can have only
abstract
or no operation by the way small
improvement
and every operation that claims to
implement that type
must provide the operations
and you can inherit from one real tag
type
and as many interfaces as you want
like in other languages
as i mentioned every runtime error
results in exceptions
and every exception can be handled
so this is the mantra once you have
taken care of the unexpected
take care of the unexpected unexpected
okay at the end of an inner program you
can have a one-horse
when other handler that will catch
everything that can happen at run time
generics as i mentioned are algorithms
that work on any data type
so you can say that you have a procedure
swap
and that you have to give it a type
is private means it has
only the property is known to all
private types which are
assignments and comparisons and look
and therefore for every type that
matches
a certain number of minimal properties
you can
you can instantiate that generic
like this you can add the compiler to
build a procedure swap edge
by taking that generic swap
and replacing everywhere age
item by age okay but there is a
major difference between eta generics
and zebra stress templates
in that generics are compiled checked
and provided that the type
or any other thing that you provide
match
the requirements then the instantiation
is always correct okay you don't
turn you don't check
at um right at compile time
if it's correct it works okay i hurry
so you have tasking i'm afraid i was a
bit slow
just a word uh but
the low level so you can speed you have
here record you can specify
bit by bit exactly the layout
of the record
and therefore if you change a bit you
keep the high level
approach and you get at assembly level
exactly what you want so the idea of it
is once again that you specify the high
level the compiler
takes care of the low level
okay i'll have to skip these ones
i mention here are the various annexes
and that says that really it's very nice
i
often develop on my laptop that is under
windows
and i take the code i recompile and i
put in
in survey in operation on my linux box
i don't even run the checks again
because if it works on one side it will
work
exactly the same on the other side
okay we have a good compiler with good
error messages
a number of
libraries so you can check with you can
google any library space ada and you'll
find that there is an implementation of
it for it
so in short conclusion you might expect
that i tell you use ada
no i won't you are grown up people
you are responsible i don't have to tell
you
what you have to do in conclusion i'll
just say
please please
try it okay you have three compilers
you have a number of benefits try it by
yourself
and then you can decide if it fits your
spirit or your needs or everything
that you may require from a language
okay
questions yep it's i think it's the
oldest language
i know for the moment because the five
three year growth
it exists already so i have a question
which will be
a suggestion ah it's very
something similar to pascal to have a
comparison
between pascal and well
in a sense you could define ada as an
industrial pascal
pascal was too small it was designed to
be a pedagogical for universities
and it doesn't grow up to be an
industrial language
same thing as you cannot extend a
language design
for web to a real-time language
if you see what i mean okay
yeah we learned about packages and
generics is there a way to specify
properties of
the methods that you define like
associate associativity or
symmetry so that when you implement or
instantiate you know these properties
well associativity is very difficult
okay there is a for the next revision of
the language which is by the way
scheduled for next year
there are some reflections about that
but it appears to be extremely difficult
especially if you consider associativity
of floating points
for example that's awful okay
[Music]
there in 2020 in 2012
you have contracts so those contracts
are checked as runtime there is a
special subset of ada that allows
much more provable thing called spark
it doesn't cover the the whole language
but where ada will check at runtime
spark will prove at compile time
but of course in that case you don't
have the full language because not
everything is
provable okay
anything else okay fine thank you for
listening now it's time to make the
drawing
so please
[Applause]
141 who is the lucky winner
you've got it
one one seven
okay one one seven
here you are
okay you're not a beginner
thank you so 140
one for zero
left already
too bad
okay next one one five five
okay with pleasure
and the last one
one five six
here you are
okay you've got something from four of
them