hi everybody I'm Steven hem injure
I work for Microsoft but I'm also very
much involved with the DVD K and the
Linux kernel I am NOT one of the PPF
developers even though there's some EPF
in this talk it's not the main focus I
just wanted work see the button there we
go
I'll skip the table of contents to save
time so when I started this out it's
looking around I said you know in
America there's a proverb that says you
know a bad only a bad workman complains
about his tools and since I was coming
to Belgium I looked up it turns out it's
an old French proverb but bad workers
never finds a good tool but then I
started look around it there's actually
a Chinese proverb so it says to do a
good job
a craftsman must sharpen his tools and I
do woodworking and I've learned the hard
way that unless you sharpen your chisel
you destroy things and I think this is
the same thing as truly the tool sets we
work with but before I go too deep into
tool sets I kind of want to throw up a
big red flag
so people don't get too enamored with
the tools that's not what the most
important thing is the most important
thing is figuring out how you're gonna
do it with good methodology so start out
with a problem statement up what are you
trying to solve
what's your workload look like and what
are your targets and use a good
methodology to actually do this in a
structured scientific process manner not
just throw it at the wall and see what
sticks and I'm not the person to go into
detail about that but you should really
look up any of Brendan Greg's talks on
Linux performance analysis and the e BPF
textbook that it's now out from O'Reilly
do some research learn how to do it
before you get too deep into playing
with tools but after I've shown that out
now I'll go talking about tools so in my
life we spend a lot of time working with
DB DK applications
and in a DB DK application there's
really two ways to look at it one way to
look at it doing analysis since tune
analyze the data as in what's coming in
and what's going out this is traditional
TCP dump packet filtering so you
basically have a mechanism to get the
data to see what the application why
you're dropping packets what's good not
going in the other way to look at it is
programmatically and that's what's
tracing is tracing is all about let's
insert something into the program and
see what we got the poor man's way of
that is print K this is doing something
smarter than print cake figure out
what's going on
both of these are useful and both of
them are part of the solution and on the
packet capture side traditionally the
early days of DVD K there was nothing
like the first user survey feedback we
got was I need TCP dump so Intel and a
few others developed a packet dump for
DVD K called P dump and the way it works
is your application is writing is your
primary application and you have a
secondary application that shares a ring
with the primary application and
captures packets and the packets are
outputted in pcap format and you put
them somewhere the problem with this is
the implementation of this is very
limited there you have no metadata so
you don't even know be LAN tags are gone
you have nothing about offload flags
what flow rule matched so you have very
little state in this packet capture the
implementation of this is not very
robust and the timestamp happens at the
far end of the thing kind of like you
saw earlier when they talked about with
collecti it's the same thing only at the
DPD k level the packet isn't being
stamped when it's arrived it's being
stamped when you
finally pull it off which is pretty much
useless you have no direction
information so if you're capturing
receive and transmit you don't know
whether which way this packet came from
and the current implementation only
really handles a single port so if I've
got a router I want to have both ends
captured at once put in one file or you
have to do something where you've got
multiple files and try to correlate by
timestamps it's pretty hard and lastly
there's no filtering so there's nothing
you just basically you get the firehose
and because of all this the performance
is pretty poor so for what I've done
working it's not actually upstream like
the probe patches are still in progress
is to support P cap and G in the DB DK
with that you get nine is the second
time resolution we can put system and
interface data if you're in the cloud
it's really important to be able to know
I got this no data file I captured on a
some node what was the hardware on that
node
what was the versions of the firmware
all that can be put in the file that you
got captured it supports multiple
interfaces so you can have some 16-bit
number of interfaces and put them all in
one file and put them together pcap ng
supports flags for direction and you can
put the hash value of the packet and
even comment strings of any other data
you want so really it provides all that
so we're working out the details and all
the API and ABI but it'll definitely
roll through the next thing I've been
working on leg 2 this is putting packet
filtering into the packet capture so the
traditional way of doing that is with
TCP dump is you start out with some nice
text string like show me all packets
with the IP destination of FASTA org and
Lib pcap does all the magic and produces
a CB PF program so the problem is we
don't have a
classic BBF interpreter in DB DK and we
really don't want to put one in so we'll
do the same thing the kernel does which
is translate that into an EP PF program
I've just worked with of several people
to get permission to take the same basic
code loop that does that in the socket
filter and the kernel make it BSD
license so that we can put that in the
DB DK so you just type at the outer
level you put in the filter string you
get in the lower level you get the EBP F
program and then we can execute that in
the DB DK with a JIT and everything else
that's there how am i doing on the
tracing side there's several options on
Linux I will have to admit doing him in
user space none of them is ideal but I'm
gonna describe two or three of them that
I tried and how that how they work
together and what it would look like so
first one was Linux trace toolkit it's
been around a while it's very easy to
use and very well documented using it in
user space a typical way to use it as
usually to find trace points where you
put trace points in your code and then
you can run filters at those trace
points and it produces common trace
flight trace format data which can then
be digested and it's a from a user space
tracing point of view it's very high
performance it uses RCU and ring buffers
all this kind of performance tricks the
DB DK does to basically get a firehose
of trace points and in the user space so
my example with DB DK implementing the
test P of D application DB DK the one
most commonly everybody seems to use oh
great well I got messed up license never
use tabs and in flights but if you look
the court loop of sending a burst of
pass
rockets in the l-3 forward application
has a there and there's put a trace
point and that says hey I got some
packets so you want to do the same thing
with EB bf kept from D trace that now
have the ability to do this in userspace
I'm kind of going fast so the same thing
in userspace this is what SPMD receive
you put a DTrace probe point in and you
get the same kind of thing you want to
use it you end up using BPF trace and
you say I'd like to pick up the
user-defined trace point in test PMD and
I'd like this trace point and you give
it an expression of what you want so I
did an example doing BPF trace with test
PMD and rx burst and tell me the hash of
how many packets do I get each time
through the loop do I get a little or a
lot and this lets me decide if I should
use bigger birth size how much memory I
should use a whole lot of things well
the downside of this is you run some
performance testing these are not real
performance tests that's what these
slides are trying to say this is not
analytical statistical write of paper
tests this is do a hack do it unboxing
what am I getting so I got two systems
one sending to the other one at full
speed 25 gig NIC what does it cost me
well if I'm doing packet dump so we've
packaged up turned off having the
infrastructure in place cost me nothing
but as soon as I start capturing I get a
36% performance loss now I did a hack
say what if I had EB bf in there and I
said and my capture filter I evaluated
so don't capture this packet so
everything it was just a null program
that says no that's that went from 36%
to zero so that says capturing with EPP
F is going to work for what you want you
still have the problem of why is it
taking so long and packet capture but
it's a different problem as far as
tracing with LT TNG putting the trace
point and cost you an insignificant
small amount of time less than 1% and
when it's enabled it was down to in the
noise so basically at 25 gig that trace
point was costing me nothing now that
day that may cost me something BPF trace
putting the trace point and cost me even
less because it's just a bunch of no op
instructions but turning it on and to do
that hash program would cost a fifty six
percent drop in throughput so kind of
rushing here but so we've got a bunch of
ongoing work at the DB DK packet capture
to try to give it full filtering i've
got a new versions of program because i
want a user interface that looks more
like tea shark and less like a DVD kay
application because users don't care
about all the models and wonderful
hardware flags that we love in DB DK and
there's ongoing discussion on the man
list of how DVD k we can have a
standardized set of trace points so that
other tools can get in and use them and
i wanted to leave some time for
questions so i sped up as soon as the
flag went up what OH
so I will now open the floor for some
questions for a minute or two yes we
have a EP bf Virtual Machine and DVD K
it's fairly limited right now in terms
of there isn't a lot of hooks that use
it and it doesn't support maps and all
the well the neat tricks you can do with
EDF so it needs a lot more work but it's
there already
it started out from a common code base
but it's maintained separately
and it was agreed a lot of this is
shared work with the developers EVP of
harmonics so it's like well are we
willing to BSD licenses and that's the
biggest hurdle often other questions
back there right the prop a two things
one with LT TNG you can't do the at
scale run a program on the node to give
me the results and that's where a BPF
shines so where p PF shines is if you're
trying to scale out by using compute
resources at the at the trace point
where LT T&G works really well is if
you're saying for security or other
reasons i can't run things in that
environment or it's an embedded system
or something get me the data and i'll
process the data later so my
recommendation is abstract but what you
the classic debian thing if you can't
make a decision make both decisions so
have an abstraction that says here's the
trace points and document that and let
people choose for their environment
which tool though use to put the trace
point in i get the times up yes Thomas
that's a good question I really wish you
could
I haven't volunteered for too many
things right now a volunteer to help
that's but all I can do thank you
[Applause]