thank you for the introduction
uh what was it introduction sorry for
the
talk before because it was really great
introduction for my talk
i want to build on top of that um
so i'm uh friedrich i'm the maintainer
of the
android sdk of blockstack and i want to
talk about
how you can use decentralized identity
in a way
that well i'm really excited about
it's kind of new technology
decentralized and everything
society might not be ready and if
there's blockchain involved this is not
financial advice
so just disclaimer i'm
android developer for many years and the
concept that really
excites me is the android content
providers
the idea is that many apps can access
the same data
this happens on android device through
this
type component is content provider and
it's backed by
files or also maybe by the cloud but
really the interesting idea is that
your contacts your images your calendar
sits at one place and many applications
can make use of them you do not have to
type them again and again again
and now the question is how can we get
this to the web
um and this is possible
because we have now identities
that are decentralized identities that
you can use to make
to well to associate your data with
um so we heard decentralized identity we
have a w3 working group
um it is self-sovereign other people can
verify it
we had a demo really here five minutes
ago great
so it's really about cryptographic keys
once we have a cryptographic key then we
can make work
uh with the with the data
and um there we have
this authenticator that owns the private
key that manages your private keys
and application can ask this
authenticator
to give you some information
some piece that you can prove
to that you are the owner of the key
um so i i skipped this we had the
introduction how this the id
looks like so you do not have to have a
password any anymore
you have 45 different ways how you can
create your decentralized identity and
blocksec is one of them we saw ethereum
version
in the talk before so the idea is
when you log in when you auto can
authenticate to your device
um you are creating with your
cryptographic keys
some kind of a proof that you own this
key
and um yeah
so for ethereum there's for example
three box as well
uh they really have a nice uh concept
where you associate a way your identity
is represented with a profile and
this is the ethereum address and you get
some information about the user
and blockstack using
a more human readable way to represent
your identity
but it's really about that you
can have a proof that you own this
private key in the end
and the app wants to have this proof so
that they can
act in act on behalf of the user
interact with other users exchange
encrypted messages
talk to other services or other users
so once we have this proof uh
we might want to store our data at a
place
uh that where they know i am the owner
of this data
and that's where we come back to the
android content provider
so we want to have a concept where
the user can access or give applications
authority to access this data and
decentralized storage there are
different possibilities
the idea is that we don't want to have
these honeypots anymore
we had to talk yesterday web3 why
this is really bad and they're different
possibilities
but the applications in the end they
don't want to
[Music]
don't want to manage all the data of all
users
but the idea is that the user is
managing their own data
so we want to get get away from the
state where we now
that applications databases
manage all the users several times for
different application
abcd facebook google and so on
we want to move to a place where one
user can manage their own data
so for the content provider what does it
mean on the device
so we have the authenticator and the
user can now give proof to the
application that they can act
on behalf of the user and access for
example the images
so there's one particular key that
allows you to access your images
somewhere in the cloud probably there's
a concept of identity hub
but this standardization details
i just want to make sure that the idea
is
clear you can give another key only to
one application and then this
application is allowed
to access your contact data
and so this these are web applications
so they are served
from the web but they are sitting on
your device and they're working locally
and um
so the uh yeah it's it's about
oh let's see we have the two examples to
compare a bit the authenticator
block stack uh you have a web app where
you authenticate yourself so they manage
your keys in a web app
running on your device three box has the
web three authenticators so there you
have different
browser extensions also on to manage
your private keys
and then for the storage there you have
in
three box um orbit db that is based on
ipfs
and you have it's key value based and
in block stack you have gaia protocol
that is based on
existing cloud storage so really fast in
performance and cheap
it's firebased and what is kind of
missing
for them that you have the data schema
and i'm gone
thank you
[Applause]