secure foreign
so i'll start with a brief intro about
myself
i studied electrical engineering at the
university
then i got my phd at uc berkeley on
cloud security code
and then now uh technical director of
botanics
were basically uh building security
platforms
um so first
way to write your enclaves from scratch
and um
okay we'll talk later or you can read
very specific use case
and that is network services
sgx using being secure
being easy to use and the glass was also
very important because
i don't know tried using some of the
other
like into sjx sdk or something like that
getting something running it takes
some time so i'm gonna go
through each of these things and like
show you how it was how
i dealt with it and hopefully at the end
i can show you some demos
and yeah
sorry about that
okay so uh yeah let's start with the
designing for security
right um one of the interesting things
when you look at
you know security is you know which
program language can you use this is a
picture from
from microsoft actually where they
showed uh
you know of all the bugs that they have
in in their software over the past you
know 12 years
what which of those are caused by
by memory safety issues and which were
other types of bugs so about 70
of all their their security issues were
memory safety issues
right so uh sure i mean
uh if you are really focused on
something and working on your own and
you can probably write
like memory safe c uh but doing it
at a scale of a large company is
or just any large project it's just
basically impossible
um so that's uh why i think rust is the
the best way to go for secure enclaves
right you're you have this
this kind of minimal
uh environment so you probably can't
pull in all the dependencies that you
would need for like a jvm
or or or or something like that and so
you're kind of
stuck with choosing something like lower
level uh
but you know of course this is you
you've identified something you want to
be super secure
um so so why why uc
right so we're using rust so some of the
cool features of rust are
guaranteed memory and type safety there
there's like
static analysis built right into the
compiler right
uh 25 years of programming languages
and static analysis research that is
just right available right there
um very good way to deal with errors
uh right so you cannot ignore errors in
rust but it's it's not
it's not hard to deal with them either
so that's really good uh very good
concurrency
uh primitives and uh like i said
basically no runtime right you can just
compile it down
to the bare metal which is what we need
to do in in this environment
okay so the next thing that we're
thinking about you know
when you're designing something that for
security purposes is like the interface
that you expose to the outside world
right the interface is like the
number one attack point uh for for an
adversary
uh so you better like think think long
and hard about like what are you gonna
expose there
and uh how are you going to deal with
with whatever an attacker might throw at
you
uh right so if you
if you use an interface like a binary
function call interface like you might
find in uh
you know just any like the c calling
convention or even like the linux cisco
calling convention it's very hard to get
these things correct
uh you can have variable variable length
structures you can have time of check to
time of use issues you can have padding
issues uh and and things like that
right so uh regarding the padding issue
you know this was an issue with the
intel sgx sdk so this is now an excerpt
from the
developer guide from intel where they
say okay you know you've got to be aware
you don't put padding in the structures
that you're using in your enclave
interface
another thing from from
intel's manual or intel's
developer guide uh right uh they had
this
functionality to allow you to uh specify
like variable length inputs
uh well that's that's gone now right so
um why why are we trying to mimic
these these seed type interfaces across
an interface that's just not compatible
or well compatible like not not suitable
for it
right so i would say you know
look look somewhere else right if you
look at network services they are
designed
to work with untrusted inputs right like
everyone has some web servers and
they're connected to the internet
and right they have been for 30 years
and they're like really focused on
dealing with untrusted
inputs
[Music]
so why not do the same right so in in
the edp
we just provide a byte stream
abstraction
and then you can run any protocol you
want on top of that
including like tls or not right
but you can run grpc or http
or anything like that and you know you
might think that a reason for not
running like a full protocol like that
is is that parsing is hard and you know
we're an enclave we don't want to deal
with like parsing issues but you know if
you're using
anything but c parsing is actually easy
right um so that's not a reason not to
use it
okay um so
moving on to the threat model you know
if you're talking about network services
this is what you can think of right you
can basically
get your your your remote compute
infrastructure from anywhere
it doesn't matter as long as they have
the secure enclave capability it runs on
the server you don't trust the
administrator you don't trust the server
right so this is like a cloud provider
or anything
uh you trust of course the client and
the user um
and um for for secure enclaves
specifically kind of you know we're not
considering availability here
uh but you can of course get
availability by by
deploying your things in a like a
redundant fashion across multiple
providers or something like that
um so the the secure enclave is the
network server
that is what you would what how you need
to think about this here
right uh so you're not talking to like a
host
that has is running some server but
you're talking to directly to the secure
enclave
right so
how does that integrate with remote at
the station well easy right
client connects to the secure enclave
there's some
uh there's a some protocol that you do
where you verify
you know is this a real software that
i'm trying to run is running on a legit
platform
something like that and then
you can move on so
um in a very
uh you know first first idea of like how
you would implement this maybe you can
like save the hash of your of your that
you expect on the server side in your
client program
and you verify that um you verify that
when you do this connection
this works right but but now you really
you have an issue because you can't do
updates on the server side
uh and you need you need like one client
per service like every
because the identity of the server is
baked into the client you need a
different client
every all the time right so we have this
ability to to verify
the code identity on the on the server
side but
how do we know which which identity we
want here
uh that's that's that's a big question
um
but this is uh something that you can
solve in a different way right so like i
said we it's a byte stream abstraction
so we can we can just use tls
so if we take a private tls private key
and and assign it to the enclave and
then make sure that the enclave
never exposes this private key to the
pub to the world
right uh then if you are able to
establish the secure channel and the id
the enclave identifies itself using its
private key
you know you're talking directly to
enclave right because
the secure enclave is only the only one
that has access to this key
[Music]
so um you don't actually need to do
a a live remote at the station challenge
uh if you use this uh scheme
um you can just you know attest to the
the the public enclave the enclave
can have its public key attested to once
and then you can rely on that
going forward and then you can just set
up a standard tls connection right so
this makes the whole life a whole lot
easier because
now you can use uh you don't have to
write your own custom protocols to do
security and things like that
um so similarly to like how a
standard tls certificate kind of binds a
subject name to a tlsp public key you
can use it at the station to bind the
public key to a software
so now we have a binding all the way
from subject name to
to the enclave right so
you can you can use this in your trust
model so when you say
i'm going to a particular web service
like my webmail.com
okay i know that you know mywebmail.com
is actually running
a particular piece of software so um
right through hop through the cervical
and then 3d at the station
you know exactly the server side
software that's running on mywebmill.com
so like you can't do something like the
lava bit thing right where where the the
private key is leaked
uh or ordered to be leaked because the
private key is not owned by a human it's
owned by the enclave
and you know that the software that
you've written that's running in the
enclave
it cannot like it will not release the
private key
right so when the enclave starts you
just
check you know do i have a valid private
key if not i'll make one
and then and do is to have a valid
certificate if not
you know i'll put a certificate signing
request and then
i just you know once i get a certificate
i can i can run i can be a tls server
uh okay so that's the services part uh
like and how you integrate services with
enclaves
um so then um
talking about you know portability and
ease of use um
if you want to write run an intel stx
enclave
all you need to do is write a simple
rust program and i'll show you that in a
bit
uh and that's because uh the rust
standard library
uh upstream includes a
a back end for for sgx that that we
wrote
and so you can just uh rust has very
good support for cross compilation
um so you can easily just you know
install the standard library for this
other target
compile for this sjx target and now your
program is just running
or is able to run in an enclave
right so a lot of people or a lot of
designs for
for using enclaves they make you think
about splitting your application in
halves
like one half runs outside the enclave
run one half
runs inside um but you know then you
need to write two
two pieces of software so that's a lot
of work um so because of the simple byte
stream interface that that you know i
defined as the enclave interface
we only ever need to write the piece
that runs outside the enclave once and
you can reuse that for all
enclaves all right so this is just
available you can just install that
once and you can run all the enclaves
and then right this runner program is
just in charge
of shuttling traffic around
between the outside world and the
enclave right because it's just
forwarding a byte stream right so if you
have a tcp listening server or something
like that right that needs to run
outside the enclave
it interacts with the os to do that when
you get any connection that gets passed
through the enclave and the
read and write operations are just
passed directly through
so it also means that you know this
enclave uh
is kind of like independent of like the
operating system right because
it doesn't depend on anything so you can
use the same enclave
on all os easily
um cool so
there was a bit of a whirlwind of the
overview of like you know the thoughts
that i put into like designing the
system
um so um uh
yeah you take sgx you take rust you take
a service
uh network service idea you combine it
and that's what uh what the enclave
development platform is
website is edp.fortanix.com you can
download everything there
um and there's like a quick guide a
quick start guide and everything so
in the future we're gonna work on
supporting sgx2
and and other extensions that are come
up coming
we're going to do better support for
asynchronous io so
rust has very good support for for
asynchronous io using futures
so that's going to be supported soon and
i'm looking at like adding some binary
analysis tools so that you know once
you've built the enclave you want to
like make sure that certain things got
compiled correctly
to guard against miscompilations and
programmer errors
just again to add like another layer of
security on top of this this interface
for the enclave
um okay so let's move to a quick demo
here uh one of the tools that is
available is just you know
checking if your system is configured
correctly to run sgx
right so it says sgx detect tool uh and
it will just check everything do i have
it enabled in the bios do i have the
right
system software installed to have the
driver all that stuff
um then here it looks like we're not
running a piece that's needed
on on older systems so you know intel uh
i'll get to that in a bit so we'll just
start
start the software that's not running
and then if you run it again
you can see okay you know i was able to
launch enclaves good you're good to go
um so why do you need this aesm service
well on intel processors before like
late 2018 uh there was actually like a
drm built into sgx so you couldn't run
your own software but that's all gone
now if you buy a new enough processor
you can run whatever enclaves you want
without intel's whitelist
okay so let's run some actual enclave
code right
so i'll just do a simple hello world
demo here first right so i'll just you
know write a standard
hello world um
it you know it's just the standard thing
you get when you start first start a
rust project
uh main function print hello okay
run it so i just ran it for linux cargo
run
because i i was running this on linux
right so
uh but now i'll just run it on sjx so
all i need to do is specify that i'm
cross compiling to a different target
uh the uh botanics on osgx target
run it boom okay so the command to print
hello world
to to the screen here that actually was
came from inside the enclave
yeah yeah yeah so in this in this this
this is really fast
uh in the next video i have sped up the
compilation
a bit but this this is this is actually
how how fast it is
it really is yeah um yeah
um okay so uh well but
this is just a hello world program i
told you i was wanted to write net
like network services so let's let's do
that right
um i'm going to use the hyper library
which is a standard way sorry
nope i'm not using the rocket library
which is a way to write
web applications in rust
and then while i'm editing this file to
add the rocket dependency to my project
i'm also going to configure
that i want a certain number of threads
so in
version 1 of sgx there's a maximum
number of threads that you have to
specify
at build time
okay so uh yeah in order to uh to use
rocket you need to enable some some
features in rust um i'm gonna
import the uh the rocket crate the crate
is basically what what does a
library in other languages so i'm just
defining the
slash hello endpoint for my api
right because we're doing hello world
here so instead of
printing it to the screen i'm just going
to return hello role you know as the
output of my api here
and then in my main function i'm just
going to run
the uh the web server with this one end
point here
yeah no uh depends on what you do right
so
here the question was you don't need to
use macro use anymore
macro uses you need it if you don't
explicitly import the macro you're using
using a use statement
so macro use is like a blanket import of
all macros from a rust crate
yeah okay so uh
it's compiled it like i said this was a
little bit sped up but uh you know
you can see it's running uh on port 8000
um and uh yeah so
um that's it right we just uh we just
built a web server
a web web application that's completely
contained in the enclave running in
inside
an osgx enclave yeah
so uh cargo uh i think normally it will
uh so so all these crates can be
compiled in parallel
uh well depending on how your dependency
tree looks right so it will just fill up
your uh
your your cpus but but sorry so this was
sped up because you know i don't want to
wait here during my presentation for
everything to compile
uh so this uh this was actually doing a
plain text response uh so yeah i was
just returning a string um so in in
in rust uh um
there's difference between like
references and owned objects so
um that's that's why that was there i'll
talk about more later yeah
uh any other questions so far
yeah well i i wouldn't necessarily call
it serialization deserialization
um right so so um
there's a special calling convention
that is defined
um and um that has
a
[Applause]
uh like a bunch of calls defined uh
right so this is the full list of all
the uh what is called user calls
right so when the enclave needs to call
out it needs to go to user space
so i call the user call and then right
you can then forward that to the system
right so this is this is the whole list
of all the user calls that is supported
right now um and this is like sufficient
to build
basically any network service um
yeah so you have the standard primitives
like
read write and you know there's some
networking stuff to to
open streams and then some some
event management and some some memory
management and then
that's basically basically it
uh yo um
yeah yeah so so the the example that i
just showed was
uh unencrypted http um
right so if you depending on like
your security model you probably you
might want to use https instead
but yeah
well
it depends uh right so when you're
running a network
server you might
[Music]
in addition to like all the protected
apis that you want to do over tls you
might have some management apis like you
know
stop the server or something like that
uh right so there's no security needed
because that's
availability is out of scope right so
that can just be given by anyone who has
access to the host system
and so then you can you could do that
over http instead of https because
yeah that doesn't really matter right
but then you wouldn't want to
expose that over the network probably um
right
yeah i suppose
yeah you could use a reverse proxy of
course but you know as soon as you
um if you want to use um
if you're planning on using tls for
security right you want the tls
connection to be terminated inside the
enclave
uh because otherwise you get you can
easily do a man-in-the-middle attack
between the proxy and the enclave you do
use
ssl you're going to have to create a
certificate belonging to the end play
yeah
and i assume that at this point you do
have to do the complexity
to validate the thing that
yeah yeah so there's two different way
there's a couple different ways you can
go about it
oh uh sorry i'll repeat the question the
question was um
uh i showed a slide about you know
issuing certificates
um at certificate issuance time do you
need to do like any complex validation
yeah so
um you could uh like one
approach you can take is that your ca is
in charge of checking at the station so
uh then you need to make sure that you
know when you get your
certificate signing request it contains
a an
extension that you know also includes
includes the attestation
that might include the public key and
you verify that the public key is the
same as the public key and the
certificate signing request you verify
the attestation you verify that
against the list of software that you
trust or something like that
and then only then you actually issued a
certificate
that's one way you can do that um there
there's other ways where you can like
publish
all the attestations in like a public
repository
um so that clients can go and check that
in addition to checking the certificate
um but uh yeah
um so uh
no currently we don't really have any
any plans on on having
uh that kind of functionality uh
as part of the uh this project yeah
um
um right i mean the we do have the the
the standard attestation primitives
that you get from into sgx and like how
you can use those um
and um yeah but no
like ca server or something like that
yeah
uh it depends on on uh
yeah i mean uh
depends on like how complex the policies
you want
are yeah
you basically don't um the server
environment because it's running
yeah and you assume that putting a
private key in private storage that only
the actual sdx
makes it secure right that's the whole
fundamental concept of
uh given all of the abilities to extract
data from sgx these days
does that all true yeah so that's a good
question you know we have seen a lot of
vulnerabilities
oh yeah sorry you're right sorry i'll
repeat the question okay so we're
putting a private key inside the enclave
um given all the attacks we've seen on
sgx
you know do you think it's reasonable to
expect that you can actually keep the
private on
sorry your private key secure um
yeah so there there have been lots of
attacks uh but
generally um they've been able to be
patched
with microcode updates um actually there
was a
some report earlier this week uh on
on on on with the cash out attack
but if you go read the paper you can see
that the
the researchers had hyper threading
enabled which you know is no longer
kind of if you use remote at the station
with sgx if you have hyper trading
enabled it will no longer pass
remote at the station so uh that's the
the
i believe that the attack that the
attack that was shown last week it
doesn't actually work against the
standard sjx environment anymore um so
so
but to get back to your question yeah
you like once an attack is discovered of
course you can leverage it to extract a
private key so
sgx has this tcb recovery mechanism
right where you need to
basically update to the latest version
of everything and then
provision some new keys so you can do
the same thing here
all right so you need to use short-lived
certificates but that's that's already
standard practice these days right so if
you use like let's encrypt or something
like that
you know that uh if you keep patching
everything you know within three months
you'll have a
valid certificate again for for like the
latest updates
um so yes somehow
right so um if you can tie the
the
so the microcode version is uh
checked as part of remote attestation um
right so as long as you know that you
have a new enough remote at the station
that is valid
uh then you know you were on a new
enough microcode so you need to buy yeah
that's so you just need to get a new
gls private key and then you're good so
um
right so so you need to build somewhere
in your
in your trust verification mechanism to
ensure that you know
there's a way to get like that at the
station that was used for this private
key is not too old
uh sorry i forgot to repeat the question
but i think it might have been clear
from context
okay
[Music]
um possibly so currently
um there's not a lot of off-the-shelf
hardware
available with with security
capabilities are as good as sgx
um right so sgx gives you
like integrity protected uh memory
encryption
so you really only have to uh to trust
the the the one cpu chip and not like
the rest of the motherboard and the
supply chain and everything
uh it gives you um multiplexing right so
multiple
secure enclaves that are isolated from
each other as well
and um yeah so if you look at other
technologies like
trustzone or the recently announced amd
suv smp
you just don't quite get get there yet
um but
uh you know once once it makes sense to
to support
uh new cool technologies that are
probably gonna come out uh yeah i'll
definitely look at it
all right so the goal is to do the same
thing
uh uh do the same thing
right where we just you know make it
make a small
like run run the same code in in the
enclave and have like a small proxy
um yeah just to run the same thing
um yeah so sorry the question was should
i support
or are we going to support other ocular
technologies
[Applause]
uh okay so um
am i doing one time
five minutes okay so uh um
i just gonna show you real quick uh the
next step right i just showed a very
simple api but now i want to do some
some json
computation types thing so i'm going to
add um
add some dependencies on 3030 is
rust's serialization deserialization
framework
it's uh i would say the best way to do
to serialize data in any language it's
it's it works really
conveniently and easy and interacts very
well with the type system
so yeah i'm just going to import these
extra crates that i added as
dependencies
and then i'm going to define a type
uh i'm going to import some more stuff
um
yeah so i'm gonna i'm gonna going to
define a type
that implements deserialize right so
i'll be able to
to turn json into this type the type is
called
two vectors which means i'm going to
call hold two
vectors in the mathematical sense um
and um because uh the function i'm gonna
implement
is the dot dot product right so uh
i'm gonna pass in uh two vectors in json
and then
compute the dot product and output it
again so oh
sorry i said i meant cross product
um right so i just i just have to define
the api here so the previous api was
that slash hello this one is at slash
cross
as input i'm going to take this json
value
of type 2 vectors and i'm going to
output
json value again and then
i just need to
kind of get these two values a and b
from the json
from the input compute the uh
compute the cross product the output and
then uh
yeah send that on back to the client
uh so this is going to be like maybe
like another 10 lines of code or so
so here i need to figure out what the
right
elements are to multiply
don't worry i'm coming back to to change
the indices
[Music]
and then last thing i just need to add
the
api to the list of apis that my web
server supports
okay save quit
compile run
okay
so yeah i'm just running compiling the
rest
normally uh on my laptop this takes
about five minutes so you know
but here we're on uh presentation time
uh so yeah i mean here again i'm just
running the api with some input data and
then we'll see that it works
you know defensive security demo is
always so boring because it's just you
know you should just show that something
is working
um yeah well there we go the cross
product of one two three and four five
six is minus three six minus three
uh computed inside an enclave so if you
had a more
sensitive computation where you wanted
to be sure that it was correct and you
couldn't do it on the client you might
you might use this
uh sorry can you repeat the questions
okay uh the question is why shouldn't we
use this
this this framework is very big and we
should you shouldn't use it because of
that
um um so
um you know you have to make certain
trade-offs when you're building security
software
i think here
letting the programmer use familiar
primitives that are familiar to them
lets them folk like build software in a
more in a
more common way um right so that makes
it more accessible
to people so people you know they might
they might have some familiarity with
like building a
web service with an api that is somewhat
secure and so this lets them do that
uh yeah you get you get a slightly
larger tcp
um but um
you know i think that's that's uh
countered by
uh like the the using the rust language
uh having a very well defined and
interface that is very small and and
interpretable
uh yeah so any other questions
oh uh yeah so in terms of future
developments uh
there was a so i uh uh mentioned you
know support for upcoming features in
sgx and rust and binary analysis
already uh in the future we might
support you know different platforms
when when those are
uh you know have grown up to be as good
as sgx
uh and uh yeah
okay yes so should there be other
architectures that actually have an
enclave similar to yours yes there
should be
i assume that there should be a process
in place where the
people behind the software support for
that can get in touch with the rust
community
and youth or similar people
uh okay so uh the question is um
if there are uh you know new
architectures that want like similar
support for this type of enclaves in
rust uh how should they go about doing
that
um yeah so the rust uh community uh is
basically just pull request based
um no no
no so so currently yeah and rust if you
want to add a new target
they're super flexible about it um you
know maybe once the grit list grows to
they'll they'll get put a more
bigger process in place uh but right now
it's just uh yeah you send a pull
request
if you need any like uh help or advice
uh on like building a new target that is
like similar to this i'm happy to help
um there's a slack
channel that i'm generally available on
you can find the link on our website
uh so this is a slack channel for for
sgx expert and things like that
so yeah
thank you very much thank you thank you