thank you
if we can quickly re-welcome megan with
a huge round of applause
thank you thank you thank you okay oh
i'm gonna use this
and i've got this no feedback wonderful
well i am megan
and i am so excited to be here today to
talk to you about leadership
and as i was preparing this i was
wondering have any of you
ever been working in open source and
just
thought to yourself oh my gosh i wish
someone would just
lead just point us in the right
direction or
just can you get us all working better
together does that sound familiar at all
yeah i know i have felt that way too and
it can be really frustrating
but what if you could be the leader you
need in open source
well today i'm going to tell you how you
can start doing that
but first i do want to thank you for
being here
excuse me i think leadership's a really
important topic
and if we can all increase our
leadership skills we have the
opportunity
to make our communities more healthy
and our projects much more sustainable
so i'm going to use this time to talk
about what leadership is
and go into a few tips of how to
strengthen your skills
and tell you some techniques that you
can use starting today
and so um does that sound good to you
all right oh sure
absolutely okay good so then why don't
we start with a story
this is a open source leadership story
that i ran across
while working with the project that
wanted to improve their contri their
contributor experience
and what we did is we interviewed a lot
of contributors to understand
how we could make it better for them and
one story in particular stood out for me
and it was a contributor who really
wanted to make their first
contribution and they looked in the
forums
and they looked in the issues and they
looked around all the different
communication channels and they felt
really intimidated and they felt that
people were talking in ways that
made it a little scary to step in and
ask for help
and they waited an entire year before
they finally made their first
contribution
and what they ended up doing was
reaching out to a mentor
and asking someone would you please help
me and that person
took the time and walked them through
the steps
so that they could finally make their
first contribution
and fortunately this person had a
learning mindset
and they learned the process and they
practiced again
and again and now today this person is
one of the
top contributors of their project which
is really amazing
but it's also really unfortunate it
makes me wonder
how many contributions did we miss
because this person was intimidated
by the way people were interacting in
the communication channels of this
project
and the answer is actually about 400
commits a year
and then i wonder about how many people
didn't persevere
like this person did and walked away
from the project and never even made a
contribution and the answer to that is
just too many
now as a pro as a community as an
industry we have gotten
so much better and so much more aware of
how we need to communicate with each
other
which is great but we still have work to
do
because what happens in open source is
we all want to help
that's how open source works but when
you step
in to help often you are stepping up
into a leadership role and you don't
realize it
and let's face it is anyone getting
training in open source
especially on soft skills no
probably not and so that's one of the
reasons why i like to give this talk
just to start raising awareness on the
topic of leadership
so i think that we have a lot that we
can be doing together
and to learn these leadership skills so
i want to unpack this a little bit for
us
so the first question is who were
leaders in
this story anyone
that's okay i'm going to tell you so the
people
in the forums especially people
moderating their leaders
they didn't realize it they're stepping
in to help there are people in the
issues that are
reviewing them they are also leaders the
mentor
who stepped up and helped this person as
a leader
and actually the individual contributor
is a leader too or at least displaying
leadership traits
and i'm going to unpack that a lot more
later on because
we don't normally think of an individual
as a leader but i think we all need to
start seeing ourselves
as a leader and understand how we can
start having leadership skills
and what is leadership there's actually
no
one definition but they're all generally
about the same this happens to be my
favorite
from a leadership expert by the name of
kevin cruz
and its leadership is a process of
social influence
which maximizes the efforts of others
towards the achievement of a goal
and what is so important about this it's
about influence
it's about influencing others you can't
make someone do something especially in
open source it is
all about influence and it is also about
bringing people together and interacting
with them
to achieve a common goal and sometimes
to understand what something is
it's easy to define what it is not so
leadership
is not a title or a role right
anyone can lead from any position
and it's not a personality type you
don't have to be some
extrovert there are lots of great
leaders that are introverts too
and it is not management it is not about
people getting jobs done on
time on budget it is also very much
not about power it is about influence
and there are three types of leadership
and the first
one is leading organizations so the most
common one might be the ceo leading a
company
in open source that might be
someone like an executive director who's
running a non-profit
it could even be the bdfl that's running
the entire project and all the comm
and the entire community another type is
leading
others so that might be a product
manager in a company that's working with
all kinds of
functions to get a product out the door
and promoted
in open source that might be that mentor
that's helping people learn how to
contribute
and then the last one is leading
yourself
and this is very much what that
contributor was
he was showing a leadership type of
leading himself and that means
that you know how to manage your
emotions
and be able to control and shift them as
needed so that you can have a productive
outcome by working with someone else
and the reality is is you can't lead
others
until you can lead yourself because as
you take on more and more responsibility
and more people are looking to you for
direction
you have a lot of stress to manage
and you need to be able to control those
emotions
so that you can make everyone feel calm
and confident so they follow you down
the right path
to achieve something together
so what do leaders do well research from
harvard business review
shows that leaders do several things as
they're working with groups they shape a
vision
they translate that vision to a clear
strategy they bring
teams together and reward them and
motivate them
and they also focus on measurable
results so there is a clear outcome
they're all working towards
they foster innovation in learning and
they are leading themselves while they
do all of this
and this is exactly what that individual
contributor did actually
this person had a vision to make a
contribution
and he had a new strategy instead of
just watching and waiting he actually
asked for help from a mentor
he recruited that mentor they became a
team and together
they wanted to achieve that one goal
that one commit
and of course he did foster innovation
and learning
got really good at the process really
good at understanding the project
that's how he became a top contributor
and the whole time he led himself
through that whole journey
so that he could achieve that
so all leaders do what they do what kind
of skills do they have to use
does anyone know you want to call out a
leadership skill
communication's a good one any others
yup negotiation's a great one too
well research shows that there's a lot
why are you laughing because there's so
many well what's interesting about this
is you inspire and motivate others you
display integrity and honesty
communicate collaborate and when you
look at this what you realize is that
whether you are running a company or you
are working in open source
to lead means you're not really relying
on those technical skills that you have
and all those
amazing cognitive abilities you're
actually relying on soft skills
and research shows that
there are all the soft skills research
is showing that
two-thirds of leadership is actually
reliant
on emotional intelligence and that's
something we don't talk about
very much in open source actually we
don't talk about it much in the world at
all which is a bigger problem
but you know if you think about it we
talk a lot more about our cognitive
abilities how smart we are
and we are really smart we solve
incredibly hard problems
but we need to start embracing
emotional intelligence in our work
because it's clearly
the key to being good leaders in open
source so i want to take some time to
explore what emotional intelligence
is because we should really want this
it makes us better at our work as
contributors
dan goldman who literally wrote the book
on emotional intelligence like it's
called emotional intelligence
he said that the difference between good
and great
90 percent of good degrade is based on
having emotional intelligence skills
and what that means is that if these two
people in front of me have the same
cognitive abilities but this person on
this side
has more emotional intelligence they're
going to be able to
be a stronger uh or top performer
stronger contributor in the community
and primarily that's because they will
have the ability
to set a vision with others and
influence others to work towards a goal
and you can make a much bigger impact as
a group than you can by yourself
so what is emotional intelligence well
simply put it's really learning how to
manage your own emotions getting really
in tune with yourself
and also understanding how to attune
with others and influencing their
emotions
and motivating them so that you will
work together towards that common goal
and dan goldman broke it down into five
pillars and of course we do not have
time to unpack
all of these but you should know that
self-awareness
self-regulation and motivation are all
about
managing your own emotions and
empathy and social skills these are
about
controlling your emotions and then being
able to influence the emotions of others
we're just going to focus on
self-awareness and self-regulation
there are two sides of the same coin
and actually when you strengthen these
two pillars
you create a strong foundation and
strengthen the other pillars at the same
time
so let's dive in just a little bit into
what this is self-awareness
so self-awareness is just really being
in tune with yourself
in any given moment knowing how you feel
knowing how
your emotions can affect others
and the other side is self-regulation
that's being able to control those
emotions
being able to shift them so that you can
have a more productive outcome while
working with others
so in the example of the story earlier
the contributor was stuck with fear
and he knew he was stuck and so he
shifted his emotion
so that he could be more proactive and
then he reached out to someone and
shared his
request and his need and his vision and
motivated them
to help him and that person donated time
that they didn't have to do
so that's self-awareness and
self-regulation now let me ask
how many of you think you have strong
self-awareness
raise your hand
yeah all right well you are
right in line with the research
this is a problem it's not an us problem
it's a humanity problem
and research found that 36 percent of
people
are able to identify their emotions
and well that is just kind of shocking
but
it's okay because we can work on this
together
and we want you because you know when
you're born with
cognitive skills they're only going to
grow so much right
and at where we are in like our open
source careers
we might be learning more from each
other but it's really going to be
diminishing returns at some point
and if we really want to go the next
mile we're going to want to lean into
that
emotional intelligence and becoming more
self-aware
be able to self-regulate is the place to
start so
let's talk a little bit about how we can
do this
this is kind of an interesting thing the
answer for improving emotional
intelligence
is mindfulness and google's done a lot
of research in this area
and has started a program called search
inside yourself that helps teach
leaders how to use mindfulness so they
can be better leaders
and if you don't know mindfulness it's
really all about being present in the
now
having a calm nervous system and
it really is something that sounds easy
to
attain whether it's meditation or yoga
or journaling but i don't know about you
but when someone's like oh you want to
be a better leader just meditate
i was like i'm not doing that like it's
just not
something that you naturally do it's a
practice you have to build
and with any kind of change you have to
know why
and for me i needed to know why
i needed to meditate how it was making
me a better leader how it was
changing something in my brain so that i
was doing something that i wasn't doing
before
and i got my why from dan siegel
and he is a interpersonal neurobiologist
a psychiatrist with a specialty and he
has
this great way of illustrating how
mindfulness helps the brain
now if i switch to this mic you can't
hear me can you it doesn't work
it does work all right if i put this
down it's going to get
louder and annoying okay i'm going to
try to demonstrate
for those like the first three rows i
can see i mean the rest of you can look
at the screen
and it's not it's a very simple
demonstration of how the brain works
um but simply put you have
the spinal cord here going up into the
brain stem
and then you have your downstairs brain
as he calls it
it's your limbic system it's all of your
emotions a fight flight freeze
and then you the four fingers are your
cortex
and your prefrontal cortex that's your
upstairs brain this is your logic your
reasoning
and what you want is to have an
integrated brain where the upstairs
brain is working with the downstairs
brain
because all day long you are getting
stressors
and they are coming up the spinal cord
into the brain
and your body's going oh my gosh oh my
gosh
and then the upstairs brain is saying
it's okay
we've been here before we know what to
do
we can stay calm and when you have this
integrated brain
what you get here in the prefrontal
cortex is emotional intelligence
this is where you get your awareness
this is where you get
your self-regulation your empathy
everything happens here because of this
connection
but you're going all day long and you're
getting stressors and this connection
is not a very strong connection
unfortunately and
eventually you get that one email or
that pull request
or that tweet and you lose it and you
flip your lid
and that is how he describes what is
happening to your brain
all day long and it can take a good 20
minutes
for that to come back down so that you
can re-engage and have
your the capacity of emotional
intelligence again
and so that helped me really understand
why mindfulness is important because it
starts to really strengthen
the bonds and helps you keep that
upstairs downstairs brain together
while you're dealing with stressful
stressful situations
and you especially need that in open
source
because the environment in which we work
in
is more apt to make you flip your lid
and that's because we're using
asynchronous communications
and what social neuroscience has found
is that
we are wired our brains are wired for
face-to-face communication
not asynchronous we are constantly
looking
for social cues and body language to
help us
regulate how we interact with each other
and when we don't have that and we're
working
in asynchronous communication like
github and slack and twitter
we are at a disadvantage and yes we have
emoticons
but it doesn't close the gap to what our
brain needs
and so research found that there's a
couple things that happen where we're
working in asynchronous communication
that you really need just to be aware of
and the first one is that when we don't
have eye contact
we have less empathy for the person
we're working with
and also we have this weird thing that
we do
where we project a tone or a voice on
someone's
tweet or email or whatever the
communication channel
is and nine out of ten times it's more
negative
than what they intended so we are really
setting ourselves up to flip our lids
way more than we should
and so this is happening all the time
and if we could practice on
staying calm using mindfulness
techniques
to be more present as we're
communicating more aware of what we're
dealing with as we're communicating
we will be in a much better situation
because when we
don't what happens is we are all just
communicating
with our pure emotions we have flipped
our lids
and when it starts to get really bad
like in twitter when we are just
really arguing our point suddenly our
brain just flips a switch and we are
fighting for survival
because being right suddenly becomes a
form of survival
and that's when you see flame wars and
we all know those are terrible and we do
not need to go there
we just stay a little bit more present
with our online communications
so mindfulness obviously is something
that can just help set the brain it's a
practice
that we can use to have more resilience
in our brain
but it is truly not enough you need
strategies
you need strategies that you can use in
the moment when
you need to reset when you start seeing
things getting a little heated or you
start getting that
message that really kind of makes you a
little unhappy
and so some ways that you can reset are
some count to ten
just count to ten and give yourself some
space
you can also take some deep breaths and
there's more science coming out exactly
how breathing helps calm the limbic
system
you can take a walk maybe you need more
than a breath maybe you have to go for a
walk around the block before you sit
down and decide how you want to
communicate
and my favorite is sip hot tea
there's a great practice of um taking
hot tea
and and trying not to burn yourself you
suddenly become very present when you
don't want to burn yourself
it's amazing it's a great little hack so
you want to reset yourself but you also
need strategies
so that you respond you respond
logically
you respond with the intent for
productive interaction
you don't want to be reacting just from
your limbic system purely from emotion
and there's a lot of techniques that you
can do to improve the way we communicate
to each other
one that i like is yes and i think you
probably have heard this in improv
you build off of each other you don't
have to agree someone might give a
proposal
and you don't really agree with it you
could just say yes
and i also think we should consider this
right you're not
going right at them and you're not
starting that whole
i need to be right issue the other um
approach that i like is a design
approach of i like i wish i wonder
so if someone has a proposal or someone
has submitted
something for review you can say i like
this but i wish you had also consider
that
and i wonder if we could explore this as
we you know talk about this topic
right and it just helps frame it in a
more constructive way
i also encourage people to explore
non-violent communication
that's a lot to unpack but there's some
great communication techniques that you
can use
and i also encourage you to use active
listening skills
i use this all the time it's a great
opportunity to
repeat what someone just said so i'll
say oh what i hear you saying
is and it gives that person a chance
to hear what i've understood and correct
it so that we can have a shared
understanding
as we go on and keep discussing
also the last one is when things start
getting tough in online communication
it's up to you to know
when it's just time to go back to that
face-to-face communication
it's up to you to call someone go on
video
and just pull it out of the online
communication because sometimes our
brain just really does
need all the social cues
so that was a lot that's a lot to learn
about a whole new way of of
managing yourself and managing others
while working in open source
so i just want to do a quick recap that
leadership you can lead from any
position and every time you're trying to
help an open source
you are stepping into a leadership role
just no one's told you that
and remember that you can't lead others
until you can lead yourself
so you really need to work on that
self-awareness
self-management and also
you can strengthen self-awareness
regulation all those emotional
intelligence skills
by starting a mindfulness practice
because it's going to change the way
your brain functions and make it much
more resilient as we're working online
in this asynchronous communication and
again
you want to learn what these strategies
are to reset and
to make sure you're responding and not
reacting
and i hope you do because we have a huge
opportunity remember you have new
community members joining you and
they're looking to you
they're looking for cues of how safe it
is in your community
or how they should behave and you have
the opportunity to
choose how you're going to interact and
it might make the difference
of scaring them away or inspiring them
to be your next top contributor
so i hope you choose to lead and be the
leader that we all need
so thank you very much
you