okay
buzzers i hear buzzers excellent um
okay hi everybody uh i'm georgia bolin i
am the executive director at simply
secure
um i'm going to talk today about some of
our work around designing with
tools that are focused on safety and
security and designing with that in mind
so simply secure if you haven't heard of
us we are a 501c3 nonprofit in the u.s
and our mission is to support capacity
education and capacity building in sort
of the
intersection of vulnerable populations
design
and usability so we believe everyone
deserves technology they
they can trust and that that is
something that we can be designing
for designing to protect people's safety
and privacy
so how do we do that um to do a just
quick intro to us
we sort of have three main types of work
that we do um
one and the biggest one and what i'll
talk about most today is we do direct
design support and ux support for
projects so that means user research
wireframing testing things like that we
also do some of our own
independent research and we publish as
much of that as open resources and tools
available to the community
as we can they're on our knowledge base
on our website
and lastly we try to run community
events so
um in the last year we did a week-long
residency where people came and worked
on their projects with us
and other mentors we've run workshops on
human rights center design and ai or
human rights center design
and technology generally so things like
that
so the challenge which probably all of
you feel hopefully all of you feel
is privacy and security and safety are
critical most teams
um open source projects might not lack
designing ux capacity
and the challenges that all of you are
facing are complex and overwhelming
for the developers honestly as much as
the designers a lot of the time
and the users right and so the goal is
to try and solve those problems
so how can we try and design for safety
you're in the design room so hopefully
this is something you agree with but
focusing on user needs
so we take a human center design
approach but we add a level around
to thinking about threat modeling and
risk which i'll talk about
um and so that sort of comes from two
aspects one is the
how does the technology or product
affect someone's safety
how is it is it being introduced to help
but is it also potentially introducing
new challenges like
if you're collecting data you are
introducing risk to your system
to the people like who is holding that
data what's happening
um are they expected to use it in ways
that we
that might introduce risk in their lives
that we don't totally understand
and a lot of what matters there is
context so our design choices can cause
security holes
uh confused people create workarounds um
if we like over preach or try and push
people to do exactly what we want to do
they can get annoyed and tune it out and
walk away
and people will do there's a lot of
research that suggests that people will
do whatever they can to not have to
think about security in depth
so you might be saying how can i start
to do anything about this
uh and so some of you some of these
slides um if you came last year with
molly some of these you may have seen
before but the
our secret sauce suggestion is to do ux
research and design research
you can do that remotely but talking to
people figuring out what their needs are
understanding the context in which they
work and getting that feedback and
feeding
back into the process understanding how
people
their mental models for the how the
tools work so a lot of times especially
the closer you are to the tool that
you're building
uh which if how many people in here work
on an open source project
yeah okay thanks to all of you um we
we forget how close we are to it and how
well we understand that and so it's
really important to talk to people and
understand
what of that matches um because that
helps you understand
the difference between what you know
about the way it should work and the
design from the way people are
understanding it in the interface
um there's a lot of there's some folks
that sometimes think like oh the users
are wrong and we need to fix it for them
or we need to teach them how it should
work um i vehemently disagree with that
concept
people learn technology in so many
different ways and we need to figure out
the gaps between how they've gotten
there what they might know
and what we're trying to support them
with doing with technology
and find a way to meet in the middle and
that has to do with onboarding that has
to do with design
ux generally but one of the great ways
to start is to say like
what do you think this does how does it
work talk me through your process
watch them use it um watching people use
tools
lots of people have trouble with this
because if you sit next to someone
watching them use your tool you want to
tell them how to do it and show them
what they're doing and it's really hard
to watch people stumble through stuff
but it's really valuable to get good
feedback about
what you thought made sense and totally
doesn't to the person
so we suggest actually talking to people
doing those interviews and observing as
much as you can
a big piece of this too is to understand
their context so tools need to work for
all of your users in all contexts we're
kind of always
it's it's a sort of standard practice to
design for the best case solution
but the reality is people aren't always
their best selves when they're trying to
use your tools they might be in a rush
they might be under stress for any
variety of reasons
so this is a quote more around like the
terms and conditions accept buttons that
we see
every day on every website like i know i
should read these terms and conditions
but i just really need to do this right
now i'm up
you know i'm applying for my benefits
i'm applying for a job i'm applying for
a grant like
accept we've all done it we know other
people have done it
you can't assume that people are going
to take the time um and because
it's just not the reality right there
they have other things other goals that
have nothing to do with that experience
um we do some projects we've done some
projects working with journalists
and so they'll have this is a specific
context that has
specific needs so if you're working if
journalists might be some of your users
they need to know that their sources and
their information are safe so if they're
putting data into a system
how are they protected how is that
system protecting
the source itself a lot of them will
avoid using any types of tools and
systems because they don't trust
anything other than what they can keep
in their possession or what they
understand
sort of on a very different type of
context this is an early career
researcher in academics
uh and talking about harassment and
bullying and the threat of
retaliation from within the community on
a tool so they're
they're really worried they really like
the fact that this tool asks them to
review the code of conduct every time
because it helps them remember
that the community is intended to be
safe and constructive and so if we're
actually creating that friction point
asking people to
do you did you actually adhere to the
code of conduct
that actually helps this person feel
safer on the system
so user research can help you develop
concepts of who your users are
sometimes called personas it can help
you understand the journey that they
take through the tools and help you
understand where you can provide better
controls to give people
that transparency and that agency to
make changes
or to to review their data to review
what permissions they've set
things like that so our big uh
advice of most projects is don't just
focus on the majority a lot of times
we're saying like oh how can we solve
the problem for the most
people but if you actually focus on the
stress cases the people who are in the
most
like high risk settings what works for
them
is likely to work for most people and so
if you can solve that problem well
you can actually probably support your
entire user base well
um that didn't that cut off funny but
yeah so a lot of this starts with asking
like who actually are your users what
are their needs
what challenges do they have now um and
one thing i'd like to throw in there and
this came up
as i've been talking to projects
recently is you actually probably have a
lot of data a lot of people don't know
where to start like
okay i don't know how to contact my
users they might actually already be
contacting you every day
through support forums discussion uh
platforms like chats
and depending on the type of tool you're
building like developers or users too
and they you know you can look at the
challenges that they have
as well so um
yeah so users need transparency and
controls to evaluate the changes they
need to make
so we're big on on good starting with
good defaults
um but making sure that it's things that
then people know how to do something
with
so this quote comes from an interview we
were doing where
um a user is allowed to change their
profile and i'll show a screenshot of
this in a minute
but my pseudonym keeps me safe safe if i
need to change my account name i know
that i can do that in the profile
so starting with that good default
allows people to opt in rather than
forcing them to opt out
so let's talk about some examples more
specifics uh
so last year and if folks here were at
um
at camp the chaos camp in the summer you
might have seen my colleagues molly and
eileen talk about this project
um but over the summer last summer we
worked with noscript people familiar
with noscript
raise hands nodding okay cool great um
so if you've used noscript and you think
yourself
a a pretty good technical person um
you've probably still been really
frustrated because it's hard it sort of
seems like it's geared
towards a really specialized set of
knowledge um we've talked to a lot of
people and there
their answer was when i can't tell if
it's working i just turn it off
so it's strict by default it's meant to
be interactive it's not something you
can set and forget
and it's actually sort of intending to
be a place to create friction to have
you
question you know how this tool is what
you want actually on a website to load
um so for the challenges it's got too
many confusing choices there are terms
that are contradictory in the interface
and it's hard for users to know
what settings will just work and
actually protect them
so we worked with giorgio the
maintainer and did lots of prototyping
work we
made like high fidelity mockups we
interviewed people interviewing people
allowed us to
create sort of three core personas so a
super user
a privacy advocate and someone who's
just curious about
how they can be protecting themselves
better online
um we also looked at other ads and
script blockers
uh we analyzed the data that we were
seeing from the way um
the way noscript works uh and we kept
iterating on prototypes because it was
just such a complex system we actually i
don't have it in this presentation but
if you go watch the talk
from camp over the summer which is
linked and these are i will be online
but that is linked from that
blog post i we actually have models of
the flow of the different options
and choices it's very complicated there
are many ways you can
you can actually block a site or script
or use it in one instance or another
but our main takeaway was uh people who
want we need to figure out how to make
those controls easier for people to
navigate
on a basic level and then easy to
configure for power users and so those
are sort of the two
primary audiences that we aimed for
because
it's not that noscript is keeping you
safe specifically or makes browsing
easier
or it's just working for power users
like the idea is that noscript buys
you time to make informed decisions
about who you want to trust
so it's starts as strict and backs off
so hopefully this is coming soon um i
know giorgio is working on it
uh but we i made it so that you we
actually introduced a new feature which
is that you can have settings on a
per-site basis
so you don't just always have to block a
script that might appear on multiple
sites you might need it on some right
like
on the new york times you might need the
new york times as scripts
um if that's what you want to be doing
so uh
that's sort of a new feature that was
introduced by this um you have
sort of clear fine-tuning hopefully
and ways to just turn it off when
nothing's working the way you want
and move forward at your own risk
so hopefully that will actually be ruled
out sometime this year
another project i'll just talk about
quickly is one that um this is in the
open
science space that's called pre-review
preview is a platform for crowdsourcing
pre-print reviews
i'm happy to talk about that more later
if anyone wants to dig in on the science
part but basically it's like
early research so drafts of papers
before they
are fully accepted and published by a
journal and so the idea of the tool
is to create and cultivate more open
feedback in science
and supporting the development of
expertise in
in open peer review so it's a totally
new process there are no tools in this
space
at all yet um and so we actually have
been playing with two iterations
which are linked up there many
researchers are still learning how to
work in the open
at all i think it's there's been a long
i don't think openness in science is new
but there's a adoption of openness and
sciences
growing in popularity i'm seeing some
nodding from folks who seem
familiar with that generally no matter
who you talk to
researchers main fear is retaliation
from others so if they give a
strong critique of something they are
worried that people will find some way
to attack them
either in the feedback processes
themselves or
through other channels right it's a
small community and network people
look for jobs have grad students that
sort of thing so there's lots of ways to
be bad actors in the space these are
just some screenshots of the tool
there's a browser extension
for the rapid pre-review which is this
what these screenshots are from it's the
outbreak science
link um and it has a little like
it lets you read a paper and write
reviews which is
it's very early beta i'll put it that
way
um this is a tool where anonymity is
something we've been playing with a lot
so
at the moment this is a screenshot from
the profile
users can actually switch back and forth
between their anonymous user and a user
id that's tied
to an identity system called orc id if
you're familiar with it
and so this is something that we've i
we're just trying to put some stuff out
and get feedback so it's in really early
stages but it's an interesting idea that
you can actually
swap when you're working in the open or
when you want to work anonymously
you can swap back and so you're you have
a context of
your anonymity status and your actions
that can apply in certain contexts which
makes it really complicated
but is meant to be something that
enables people to interact in this
community in ways that they can feel
safe
and hopefully geared towards everybody
working in the open but allowing them to
start from a place where they feel more
secure
some stuff that we're working on right
now just in the interest of time but
things if you want to talk to us about
it
uh we are working on improving the
usability of python um
the pep cli tool so if you're a python
user and want to chat with us you can
talk to me or bernard
and uh yeah and that's i highlight that
mostly to
to make the point that developers are
users too and we can be thinking about
usability in those contexts and there's
a lot of security challenges that come
up
so like one of the things in that
project that we will be looking at is
um uh how the dependency resolver works
and
making sure that people know that the
packages they're pulling together are
all
safe packages that might not have issues
we've been working with aura design
and the global leaks team to improve the
whistleblowing
and admin interfaces of that tool we're
working with some funders to make it
easier to apply for money
i hope that starts to help all of you if
you're people who apply to funding so
we're working with the moss program at
mozilla
and the open technology fund um and then
we're doing some work around this
information and working with tor around
metrics
um so that's some stuff that's coming up
if you have are interested in any of
those i'm happy to talk about it more
after um and as i mentioned we have a
knowledge base on our website and
included a link here to like a ux
starter pack so if there's
if you just want to be able to read
through some resources if you're getting
started with user research for the first
time or with user research with high
risk users for the first time
that's a good link to start with i'll
leave that for a second
um and i think i wanted to leave the
rest of the time for questions because
we have
a little over five minutes yes okay um
do i realize that that was just a super
quick
set of how we approach it what we do but
this is me i'll leave this link i'll
leave that link up but
um questions because i covered a lot of
things very quickly
yeah thank you
so if you've got a question shoot your
hand up and if you can
repeat the question for the yeah
no questions
yeah i hope so um we
are we need to do some fundraising to be
able to run it again um but we are
hoping to
and what we've been trying to do is feed
sort of the experience that we
did in the residency into workshops so
um
there's a uh yeah into along these lines
we run a community slack
so if and i realize it's on slack but
um if you're working in the space and
want access to folks in the community to
ask questions or just find out about
interesting opportunities um
i will i should have added the link here
but it's i have a
short link that is i think anyways i can
pull it up
but um i can also just add you on my
phone right now if you want
um we've also been trying to do a little
bit more organizing around human rights
center design
tech and security design uh so we have a
mailing list for that as well
so i'm happy to add folks to those if
those are things that you want to
know what's coming up but we're trying
to do things at events where people are
um so maybe at fosterm next year could
be cool uh
but we there will be something there'll
be stuff at wright's con
if you go to rightscon we're thinking
about allied media conference
and internet freedom festival or some of
the ones that we're looking at this year
so iff at the moment where hopefully
we'll have like two days of
kind of like design jam workshops that
maybe if any of you will be at iff
or at least in valencia around that time
um hopefully that can be like a mini
residency type of thing
but yeah we're hoping to we've just been
trying to do it in
um formats that we haven't had to
fundraise for that way
yeah so the question is about scale like
how many interviews to get enough
information
for different um persona types uh so
the terrible answer is it depends um and
the other terrible answer is we do
what we can based on the resources we
have so in the no script case i think we
did a total
of um about five pre-interviews just
like talking to people understanding
if they already used it and what they do
and challenges they have and that we
tried to we did a mix of existing users
and people who had never seen it before
um and then uh on like a totally
different
we did testing with a handful more so
probably in total we got feedback from
about 10 people
but that was still super helpful there
was pretty consistent alignment in that
so we felt pretty confident about where
we were going with it
um with some of the work that we're
doing around like the funding
issues um there we're getting closer to
like 20 interviews and it's partly
because there are just so many different
groups of people that they're trying to
serve so we try to scale it based on
the diversity of focus if that makes
sense um but yeah
sort of a yeah i was wondering you very
quickly
remote uh yeah yeah and i was wondering
would you comment a bit on that like
what are limitations in terms of types
of research
and how do you deal with less tech savvy
yeah yeah
we've had a lot of pretty good luck
using like things like jitsi and zoom
for remote sessions or google meet
whatever whatever the video conferencing
tool that the people we're talking to
are comfortable with and we try to meet
them at those platforms sometimes we use
whereby
just whatever the video conferencing
tool is the challenge there is that
yeah if anything goes wrong technically
like some things won't work
uh on the pre-review science project we
were talking to someone and for some
reason there were
tons of bugs that happened in safari and
they were safari user and we didn't
um we couldn't figure out what's going
on and it kind of like made the whole
interview go a little bit awry um but
then we also that helped us find some
bugs that we didn't know about
so we kind of try to roll with it a bit
the other
the problem we've run into the most is
if you're using tools
if you're testing tools that have a key
like login stage
people usually everybody stores their
passwords differently i could write a
whole separate research paper about that
just based on interviews we've been
doing is people have to log in
and that can be challenging because a
lot of people are nervous they're like
scared to show you what they do
and so just trying to be supportive
around it's okay like i'm not looking
like i don't mind how you do it and just
sort of let them not feel bad about how
they
store their data that can be that's sort
of the main thing i would say where
we've run into
interesting people will like turn off
the screen share to log into a system
and then
um turn it back on once they feel
comfortable that type of thing
um but yeah it's been i think the
challenge more has been in people's
low latency environments so if they
don't have good connectivity and really
don't want to screen share
or don't want to be on video um the
video conversation just helps so much in
understanding emotions that are unsaid
right being able and being able to
support the person as they talk about
something that might be difficult or
might
relate to you know whatever is cause the
thing that causes them stress
so those aspects can be challenging but
it's still better than
not getting access to those people um or
only getting access to them in context
like this which can be
overwhelming in and of their own right
so yeah
hopefully that helps answer that yeah
any other questions one concise
question because we're going to uh
move the room for the next uh talk
anyone's got a nice short question to
ask
okay i was interested in that you've
worked on a
command
no no no it totally does i will say it
totally does one of the we're just
getting started um and bernardo and i
are working on this project together
um and uh i mean one of our big
questions has been like how are we going
to be
testing the new features so we have to
be set up with
test dev environments which means we
kind of have to onboard as developers to
be able to
run through all of that which could be a
project just on its own to like improve
onboarding for developers um i have a
feeling we will end up giving them lots
of feedback on all of these things
um but yeah i mean i think the other big
piece in those types of projects and in
any big open source project
is there are so many pieces and we name
things in what seems right at the time
and that's really hard for like new
folks in the community no matter what if
they're users designers
developers right so trying to figure out
we could probably work on a million
things related to this project in the
next year but we only have
x amount of time so how do we make sure
we prioritize and like
log the right things to come back to
later maybe help with how that process
works out so that's kind of when we mean
capacity building thinking about
introducing processes to the teams to be
able to get that feedback more
consistently
but yeah i think we'll it'll be lots of
interesting challenges but we do have to
wear this like developer and designer
hat
which i think is fun but it means it's
hard
to sometimes approach projects like that
yeah
next year yeah
hopefully yeah yeah okay so thank you
very much
thank you
you