my name is dalai
i've been working nowadays i work as a
development coordinator
for blender at planner in amsterdam i
started coding for blender
10 years 11 years ago my first patch
into blender
and although it's fascinating to talk
about the blender projects for 20 20.
i think you can all find these in our
official communication channels which a
lot of you don't follow
so i recommend going to code.blender.org
this is our
main communication page from developers
to developers
we just recently posted uh something
about the main 10 projects for this year
but for this moment here
things more interesting i think it's
more
interesting to take from all these
projects which can
see how it's going to be affecting for
the end users
what it's going to bring to blender
leave them aside
for a little bit and talk about a
particular project
which for me is a particular pet project
it's a area of
technology and blender which i'm quite
passionate about virtual reality
virtual reality or augmented reality or
xr which is
an umbrella for all of those and from
this project
try to illustrate a little bit how do we
get new developers in blender
how to get new features into blender how
is our communication
where does that happen how it is to be
transparent
and open and big at the same time so
let's start our journey here in 2014
we're starting to play with vr in
blender
so this is the gooseberry project
was there was at the same time the one
of the open movies we had in blender
was starting who here knows about the
open movies
okay good after open projects made by
the blender institute
language animation studio and i was
playing with one of their files and
starting to
to render with stereoscopic vr basically
creates two panoramas you put an oculus
and you can look around
2014 like six years ago it was actually
really well received
at the time the mother of the director
of gooseberry
or the cosmic laundromatos they actually
were like fascinated oh my god
and for me was this is because that was
something that did not
start as a feature for vr
it started as something for full domes
is a different kind of technology
and i started working on this as a
contributor as a volunteer
and at some point made it to blender on
mainstream
start on 16 we're saying okay we can
render in vr
but what if you can
sorry what if you could
give one to tom as well to be very
thankful
what if you could also alter nvr if you
could experience
and see how the project is going before
you go all the way to the final
rendering
so this is we're starting to experiment
with the storyboard
experimentally storyboarding into
blender but then putting
one of those headsets and looking around
at that time
whatever plug-in using the oculus sdk
totally known gpl compatible totally
experimental
non-official but it got things going
like it actually
the technology is very interesting
instead we're starting to
get some traction 2016
the brand animation studio they had the
caminandis one of their
open productions over there and they
said what if you could partner up with
google
google at the time was promoting a lot
of the cardboard their
cardboard headsets and they wanted
content and they wanted authoring tools
this is c they called digital content
creation tools
and blender as a big umbrella was never
afraid of
partnering up with someone as big as
google if it was of common interest
there was nothing that was violating the
openness the freedom is the other way
around
they allowed us allowed blender to
actually move forward a little bit of
its vr agenda and produce a very
interesting content
at the time they're using open hmd is a
was a linux based reverse engineering
based
uh html vr support
for blender and linux
what i'm saying that because at that
time i say i one of the experiments i
was showing was
using the official oculus sdk the other
one was using
some reverse engineering linux but how
does it become mainstream
how do we how can we take something like
this and make into blender
the interesting thing is there are a lot
of people interest on that
project i was showing here something i
was actually developing
personally myself like in a research
facility in brazil
because people from the oculus
animations oculus
story which was a mini group inside
oculus
the company was bought by facebook they
wanted to experiment
storyboarding for our vr experiences and
the alternative was to
draw something animate compile the game
and then see how it looks like
and then do it over and over again and
if you could have something that
the same offering that authoring tool
for the game can also be used to preview
the game
exactly uh very impressive but you have
people like the mpx project which are
people that were already involved in
blender
i have guys who here knows what is the
grease pencil in blender
some grease pencil is what allows people
to do those kind of 2d drawings
in a 3d environment and the whole
greece peso team is actually composed by
people that are not
in the payroll of the blender
foundations like confirmers and they're
being voted for a few years already
and they
went to the next well went to the next
level sorry
and decided to think how what if he
could also draw in vr
it could be working with blender put an
oculus and work a little bit
and take it out so that was the whole
idea and what they wanted is
as seamless integration they wanted to
be able to
not have to learn a new ui not have to
learn any way to interact
so then for example they wanted the
whole blender interface
inside the vr space and they made it
they had
someone hacking their way around blender
it was a really nice prototype
had people like blender xr which is a
company called marui
they developed a plugin for maya for vr
basically a plugin where you could do
all sort of operations
immersed in vr so there it's only ui
it's on ux
and they wanted to start supporting
blender but they had the same problem we
had in the other projects
how can we do something that's
compatible with gpl with the blender
license
and at the same time compatible with the
industry standards for you know the
oculus or the vive or the
microsoft lands interesting problem
benfx is a group in germany it's also
been involved with the blended
development
of the contributors so users artists
that use blender
giving us feedback sitting together with
developers to think about the features
and we're taking some of the open movies
and re-render them as a panorama and
have a small tv
that you see immersed in the city video
playing there
and they are also interested on using
blender and if you are for scene
inspection
they are doing architecture
reconstruction you want to be able to
look around and then
look around and before rendering the
final thing they wanted to use blender
they're using blender
and surprising ubisoft more recently
they joined the blender development fund
it's a way that
if watch a tone stock probably
he covered most of the history of how
the funding happened to blender
where we are today but basically ubisoft
not only joined the blender funding
giving a blender money
but also promising to allocate some
development time
on their own team ubisoft france to
actually implement features into blender
and they're particularly interested in
vr because they want tools for set
dressing so you have your set you want
to put
different furniture or peebles or stones
or if you're a director and you want to
see how a shot is going to look like
before you render out
since everything nowadays goes through
computer also 3d
maestro also have authoring tools for
the director to be immersed
so how do we consolidate all those
different tools and what's the role of
the foundation in all of that
because you think about it there's the
foundation can grow
until a certain point but the
fundamental role of the blended
foundation
i would say is to make sure the
collaboration can happen to provide the
infrastructure
to provide the onboarding and to make
sure
it cannot work together luckily for
everyone involved in that
last year in june was the first release
of open xr 1.0
opex open xr is a standard by chronos
chrome's the same group behind www uh
html
behind opengl so all those acronyms
we got used to and it started they tried
to unify
this whole ecosystem for vr while before
every time a software wanted support
either oculus or
5 or microsoft hololens you need to
support their sdk you need to be
compatible with their
cdk yada yada they created a whole
abstraction layer where
blender does only needs to worry about
openxr
and the same way opengl is integrated in
a low level in the operating system
it just com lice is compatible i don't
know the details
it shouldn't matter but it allowed
blender foundation to say you know what
we officially can actually
help bring vr into reality so last year
we had julian eisel to participate in
the google summer of code
we still use the google summer of code
to bring new developers on board
and he basically got as far as i'll see
quite far
the whole scene inspection this is again
one of the open movies we had at the
blender animation studio
and he was using open structure the
whole thing only on windows i believe
because on linux they still don't have a
head tracking
but we say you know what we can
as a blender project can support the
basics of vr vr is a very niche project
that is a bit overkill to the to
dedicate
con we have to hold that fund right to
dedicate like car
money to future creep and try to get a
really smooth vr experience which
who here has um a vr headset
oh my god there's actually a ginger
glass
oh
[Laughter]
i've seen a lot of people we are like a
very biased sub-sample
but it's a very interesting topic and we
developers geekers thinkers we like to
think about that so we the idea was to
at least
get the basics running the fundamentals
you know julian actually been
a contributor to blender for years
already so six years
he'd been on and off in a blender
contract he participated in two google
summer
codes first commit was in 2014 and
nowadays
after the google summer of course was a
nice project
uh julian also was available so you know
what come on board
we we had enough funding at the time to
have him like working for time
and that's not he's not there only to do
vr once working user interface
and basic but fixing strategy and
everything else
but it's also part of the process here
okay this is working well let's get him
involved in let's commit both parts to
continue this relationship
of course the we do again we don't do
anything
only by ourselves and for ourselves so
for instance the blender conference is
here
actually got one of those like a small
representative representation of those
groups
i was talking about people from blender
effects
danielle from mpx people from ubisoft
where they could sit together it's okay
what can the foundation do
and what can everyone else do so i agree
that the first two milestones is by the
foundation which is basically all the
things
open excel support it is the basics
inspection
and api for drawing in vr but
what's going to be the experience the
usability into vr
no one knows still it's going to be a
few years until that's consolidated
so then i was going to lead a third
milestone
toward basically drawing and sculpting
interaction
the mottoey which is not represented
here will make sure their plug-in can be
run into whatever api we come up with
they're going to have like ubisoft
keeping us in check because at some
point you're going to say hey
they basically is there go have fun and
give call back give call back
well we cannot have people gathering
physically at all times it's
not practical and at the same time
we later as a project has years 20 25
years
way too many years 18 years
since it's open source but it's since
1998 is when uh
when it was online and
the whole infrastructure blender of the
communication was built on top of
you know mainly at least 2002 here
i see which in a way didn't aid it so
well
when it comes to competitive twitter to
facebook people are going to use the
chain of their
their use to use so so we're trying to
modernize a little bit
so this is a rocket based online rc
it's like so we have a generic
we call blender.chat is the website
anyone can go there it's where the
developers now talk among themselves is
where we work
we even as an example we have like a
whole vr room channel only dedicated for
that topic
and it's really the place where people
are supposed to work we have a dev talk
which is a discourse
based website where again
we try to separate user feedback and
usability from general development
but the idea is that the user the cycles
module the grease massive module the vr
group
should be able to use that among
themselves and everyone can read and can
follow
they can in a way interact we keep
everything open and transparent
we have the every monday every monday we
have like
uh development meeting and keep
everything there posted
what happened what didn't happen the
progress reports of every single
developer
jesus christ shame on me
it's only one more slide and we as
mentioned before
we have a nice blog po blog where we
encourage
not only our own it's not a place for pr
we're not here about pr not here to talk
about marketing but a place where people
can share development
we are the grease expensive team which
is working you know
in spain in argentina and we kind of
creep taps on their work and and have
some collaboration they can go there
on that space the blender infrastructure
is placed for everyone that contributes
to the blended project to really
take ownership from and of course use
this for also
outreach for the community where using
youtube using twitter
so overall we are in a bit of a
transition
from going over traditional irc
and mainly and lonely developers working
their own
little projects to try to be a bigger
and try to
get more people to collaborate so
basically you hope we yeah we hope that
that given insight in the project and
more people can join us
thank you
i also believe you might have five
minutes for questions
so if anyone has any question or
comments
more or less
if you go to the code.blender.org we
posted this last monday
uh there's an overview of the 10 big
core projects there's
even more than that but those are the
projects that's everyone's
responsibility
every single developer in the core team
would be like
be responsible for this the criteria we
didn't put there but basically if a
developer goes away
and the one leading a project here
someone would kill it in for them
if the vr developer goes away maybe we
won't have developer for
vr for another three years yeah that's
the reality right
those are the core projects we're going
to make sure is delivered
let's see hand here uh
when you actually use vr and you see the
same
thing in your screen and the mvr it
actually is really different i mean the
feeling of seeing the models is really
different from
so exactly how does uh
how does it help the productivity to
have the vr
uh is it just for making vr or just for
example you using vr will help you make
like a movie later
i'm just curious about how vr helps the
productivity because i will assume
if i get something off the screen we
could people may look it on the editing
screen
but if you make it on vr then in the
screen is going to be different
so just my question how yeah could
anyone hear it
what's the point of vr if you're not
only doing vr if you're doing vr it's
very obvious of course
but again ubisoft for example they'd
like to
even immerse they can still have a
traditional virtual camera there
like a preview in the virtual set if
we're
doing our character modeling i want at
some point that's more ar
you are here in blender and you put your
glass and you see for modeling this
you know lecture room you can see the
whole lecture on and go back
uh if you're doing character modeling
try you know you probably have seen
those making offs of disney where you
have these sculpted
characters you can also you know could
also use these to inspect them
i'm totally biased but
for sculpting can actually sculpt in a
more natural medium right
you actually see and move around and
touch so
but the real answer is no one knows but
we're
willing to give it a try for a
technology as long as
there is this other part from the
community like embracing that as well
it's kind of the process
we need to create people to come back to
work
is it good maybe it's a good mid term uh
middle
a good compromise between digital and
analog do you have a question
for today i don't need to use oh to use
a blender
for 2d people well there's a whole
roadmap now
for storyboarding uh with
tools like blender for even like 2d
because even for 2d it's so handy to
have a camera where you can actually pan
around there you can reuse assets for
different shots
that's a whole discussion i think you
might have for one last question
it's not
we do have a developer rickard antalik
who has been
hired to work full-time with trying
to help the infrastructure as a whole
but also to try to tackle the video
sequency editor
but it's one of those projects that if
he had for whatever reason decided to
walk away
we won't be able to prioritize however
is in the agenda this vulcan for
instance is in the agenda as well
more storyboarding for 2ds in the agenda
more sculpting tools texture painting
tools there's a lot of work being done
just we had to draw the line at some
point and these we can promise
everything else is circumstantial and
again
anyone is welcome to to add to blender
to bring
ideally to see what the roadmap of
blender try to help
on top of that otherwise might get too
complicated
but everyone's welcome to where is a bit
of an open end what's going to be there
we only can only tell once ready oh
thanks everyone for the time we have
seekers here
and that's what time have thank you
[Applause]
you