okay
our next talk is going to be about bpf
as a revolutionary technology for the
container landscape by daniel bogman
he's one of the bpf kernel maintainers
and get started yeah thanks a lot for
the introduction and it's really great
to see so many
people here that the room is fully
backed
so first off i want to start with the
container landscape
it's i guess obvious to everyone the
containers exist for a long time
but like how do the production
deployments look like and i found a nice
usage report from
cystic folks where they looked into
various aspects
i i picked out three points from there
um one is the that i found very
interesting and
um as a trend and one is the uh lifetime
of a container
and we can see here that there's a
continuously decreasing lifetime
many of the containers seem to run as
you can see here on the chart for
10 seconds or less and
that basically doubled over the last
year
and that trend seems to be increasing um
the other thing is how many containers
are running
on i hope you can see the numbers good
here
um how many containers are running on a
on one single node
and that number also has doubled from
the last year and now it seems to be
30 as a median um
and the last one i guess it's pretty
obvious but what is the main
orchestrator if you
uh deploy containers and that's
kubernetes so in including
if you include openshift and ranger here
as well then it's 89
so that's quite vast majority and as a
common
denominator a common base platform for
all of this is of course the linux
kernel
and it has to provide all the building
blocks that we know
for the isolation in terms of name
spaces so you have
various namespaces network namespaces
recently time name space code merged
into the kernel
and also for resource management which
is done through the c groups
um it has to provide the network
connectivity and in case of the network
namespaces it's either to reef devices
ipv line devices or various others
and security policies that you can
implement
and that can be done in terms of linux
security modules or
firewall policies and so on and so forth
and all of this
also has to withstand all the um
increasing scalability needs and the
higher and higher
churn frequencies of containers while
also coping with the subsystems
that exist for a very long time in the
kernel for 10 years or more and that
have been designed back then
and of course the newest column has the
paradigm of never break
user space so all of this has to still
keep working
while you optimize all of that and
just to pick out the two examples in
networking
so there's tc and iptables net filter
they both have been designed long ago
and
they're both generally extensible but at
the same time
their framework is inflexible for
today's needs
because in case of tc and
iptables like their the whole processing
pipeline is part of the api contract
with user space
for example tc has classifiers and
actions
um you can load them and you really have
to
uh specify how to package this process
if it doesn't hit this classifier then
you create another classifier instance
and if it matches this then you have to
go through this action and
similarly with iptables you basically um
in the worst case end up traversing like
a linear list of rules
that you have and yeah so if it's
getting really complex
then basically it slows down your fast
path because it's sitting right in the
middle of it
and system software today basically has
to
support the wide range of kernels
because people in production are
running old kernels or the latest
kernels ideally
we would love that everybody is running
the latest stable but that's like
not always the case and then basically
you end up
baking policy in like deeply into your
code base and there's significant effort
if you want to rewrite it
um just a random pick and loop network
it basically encodes
um the arguments for later on shelling
out to ap tables
and that's not really great and i found
this x uh kcd
uh where it says here to itself to the
future self
if you want to fix it you have to
rewrite it and it's kind of creepy
but yeah not only uh lib network but
also kubernetes relies a lot
on iptables specifically for its service
implementation
through cue proxy and there are also
issues in terms in terms of scalability
so some of them are for example low and
unpredictable packet latency
because if you have many different
services
and the way that ip doubles is basically
programmed and traversed
you end up either hitting the first rule
which is really the best case or you
have to traverse all the different rules
and then you end up at the last one and
that's not really
a nice outcome and
there are slow update times because you
have to replace the entire blob of rules
and this can really take a long a long
time if
the kernel has to pause and make sense
of it and
basically install the rules into the
data path
there are also reliability issues i will
get to that in a in a bit
and in flexibility because what i
mentioned in terms of the contract with
user space
um in terms of performance even when you
do like
basic measurements um from host to host
you will see that
in a lot of cases even with just very
few rules
um in the kernel if you run birth top to
see what are the heaviest hitters in
terms of
cpu cycles that are consumed that is
often case
ip tables
and there are also other issues so
probably
many of you that run kubernetes in
production
might have hit this bug where you've got
basically dns delays of
five seconds or more because of a
connection tracking race
my colleague martinez he submitted
actually a patch
in august 2018 but the patch could only
merge like
around half a year later and he even did
some research like the first occurrence
in the bug was actually in 2010
uh that people were hitting it um it's
fixed now which is really good
but like until it really goes down all
the way downstream to
users in production it takes a lot of
time actually
there also some other issues along the
way uh for example i
copied here the documentation from
kubernetes for cube admin
so now iptables is being replaced with
nf tables but they're basically
um issues with the don't break uses base
part where they recommend that you
should
um yeah basically run the old
iptables binary and don't upgrade
because rules are getting installed
twice which breaks cube proxy
in terms of debug ability if you only
have a few rules that's good
i think that's fairly easy to follow you
can also
see like the counters if you write ip
double safe dash c
so it's easy to debug but if you have a
lot of rules
for example here in the left side uh
i we deployed basically 100 services
only
all with the same back end but that
already gets complex to follow like
where my
packet is dropped right and the other
thing is also that
um gproxy periodically resets the
counters in ip tables so yeah good luck
with the backing it's
um to show you the basic packet flow
um basically you have an skb at the
beginning it hits the tc
ingress path and then later on all the
yellow boxes
are net filter related you do a flip
lookup and then if you want to
push the packet back out the kernel you
hit the tc egress path and then
you send it to the device and
just to show you an example how cute
proxy installs the rules with iptable so
that you have a clearer picture of it
if you for example create a server's
engine x in this case which has a
virtual
cluster ip of 3g3 and it has two
endpoints
then basically how it looks like in ip
tables
that's the way how cute proxy installs
it it basically first creates a
rule in the net table for the
pre-routing where you redirect all the
new
traffic to the cube services chain and
then basically there you you will check
for the
virtual ip and if that's happening and
if that matches you basically go to the
cube service engine x and there you have
like a random
selector with the probability of two
like because you have two back ends and
then you either select
the first one or the second and then
basically packet
goes on right and if you have many many
rules
you basically have to first match on all
of the service ips before you
end up at the right one but you can
actually optimize this path by only
going from
dc ingress to tc egress with the help of
ebpf
i first mentioned in the beginning that
um
dc also has issues in terms of
with exposing the processing pipeline
but the module that we wrote for ebbf
basically bypasses this because you can
do all of it
in ebpf and then directly return a
verdict without having to process
many many dc rules there so it's
actually efficient
and i would say it's probably the only
efficient
module that is there in the tc software
path
um how does it work basically so you
have a piece of code it's similar
it's c like syntax you can compile it
with lvm
lvm has a bpf backend and
that generates an object file there's a
bpf loader in user space for example
ipro 2 or
there's libpf which is maintained in the
linux kernel tree as well
and it basically creates the maps it
links the maps into the bpf program
and in the end it calls a syscall for
the
for loading the program then in the
kernel it
goes through a verifier verifier make
sure that everything is
safe and sound and then basically
it hits the just-in-time compiler where
it translates
um bpf instructions into native cpu
instructions and basically all
major uh kernel architectures they have
support for jit
these days and then it creates native
code and basically your user space agent
that you have
can access bpf maps to update state at
runtime or to fetch state from the ppf
program if it wrote
into maps and again like if traffic is
coming then it hits the bpf code and it
can either redirect it to another device
or basically can drop the packet that's
also possible
and an agent itself can also like
periodically update ppf programs
so that's um yeah that's that's the
basic
uh workflow there and so yeah so why is
bpf a radical shift in
um because you can get full
programmability right so it allows you
to
uh it allows the user to tinker and to
change the kernel
data path in any way it wants but still
with the safety belt on it's not like
kernel modules where you can potentially
crash the kernel so i've been talking a
lot about networking and this whole talk
is actually about
container networking here but it's also
uh there are also different areas like
tracing and security tracing you
probably
heard a lot from bren greg where he's
doing great work there
and security there are recently
proposals for linux security modules to
make it programmable with bpf as well
in networking it allows you to fully
define the forwarding pipeline which is
great
and the thing is like ppf has a stable
api guarantee so it's pretty much
similar to syscalls
where you don't break it once it works
and you in it the verifier passes
and the other thing is you get native
speed so similar to kernel modules there
um you can update your bpf programs live
at runtime without having to reboot
anything without having to
even tear down services so it works
without service disruption
and it's really designed for performance
in production use cases right
bpf is basically developed mainly by
facebook and some folks from from our
site
google red hat cloudflare many many
people and it's really great
that there are so many contributors
there's really a long tale of 280
um seven contributors in the kernel
since the beginning
and they're also large-scale users of it
so facebook is running it in production
and all of their
infrastructure whenever you hit
facebook.com you will go to bpf
um netflix are using it in a large scale
for tracing
google is using it in terms of traffic
shaping to optimize their tcp stack and
many others cloudfare
folks they're using it for their load
balancer and ddos protection
in production and it's even available on
rel
kernels which means something because it
probably means now it's mainstream
because people are back putting it to
rail which is a good thing
and yeah and even like the old iptables
maintainer rusty russell he admits that
yeah beatables used to be good enough
but these days there's it needs a
radical shift
um and that's basically bpf right so
how does this all link back to
kubernetes networking um so basically
there's sodium which is an open source
project
it's a cni for kubernetes
and it implements its full data path in
vpf
it supports the kubernetes service
implementation which is the focus of
this talk but there's also many other
things there uh network policies
uh multi-cluster um accessibility
encryption
and so on and so forth so you can look
it up it's all open source
on github um yeah so how did we get to
the buff and psyllium of replacing two
proxy with bpf
where you can basically then end up
deleting the cube proxy daemon set
and don't have uh you don't even need
your long list of iptable rules anymore
then so basically
to give you an overview of what cube
proxy does you basically have different
services
one is called cluster ip cluster ip
basically allows you
an in cluster access of a virtual ip
where basically you can either access
this from a part or from the host name
space
there are services which are called node
port which allow the access
from outside um but also at the same
time from inside
you can you can view it as an onion so
for example
the noteboard also makes use of cluster
ip
and yeah there's also external ip
which means you have an access to an
external ip you can basically override
it with your own back ends
it also again works on top of
node port and there's last but not least
a load balancer service which is usually
when you have an external cloud provider
and then it redirects buckets to your
either external ipo and output services
so you can access it from the outside
world
right and in psyllium basically
in prior versions we implemented
the whole thing in bpf the following way
like the cluster ip if you have part two
part connectivity
if you basically connect to a virtual ip
like going back to the 333 example from
previous slides with the engine x
service
you basically have your own part here
which has an it's all network namespace
you connect to it through reef devices
and basically
in in on this side you're hitting the
tc ingress path in the host namespace
and basically there bpf is
attached and what it does inside bpf
in the bpf program is basically a
service map lookup
it checks whether the uh whether there's
an endpoint for that address and then it
does the
dnat on the back end in bpf it creates a
connection tracking entry
so that it can make sure that the
replies are coming back in and are
translated correctly
and here you can see like the content
basically of a service map
it has different backends encoded here
and for the connection tracker we can
basically make sure that whenever
replies come back in that there's
connection tracking entry it will hit it
it will do the reverse net and go back
to the original client
so yeah that's like the basic path um
and how is this all plumped down from
kubernetes to sodium basically
sodium listens to events from the cube
api server
and there so whenever uh
there are service updates it listens to
it for example here and then
back end updates and then it basically
pushes this down into this ppf service
map that is sitting in the data path
right so recently we
reworked the cluster ip access with
something even more efficient
so the linux kernel has support for
attaching bpf programs to c group v2
there are different ways you can attach
to it so just to walk you through it so
if a client again connects to
an engine x service then basically we
already attached to the connect syscall
and we can see that
the client is trying to access one of
the servers ips we can already do the
map lookup
right from there and then we can
basically rewrite
the destination address to one of the
back ends and that's much more efficient
because you don't have to do
actual dna you don't have to mangle
packets in the data path
you can just rewrite the address that
was used to pass down for the connect
system call so basically the kernel
there so basically
it looks like as if the application
directly connects to the back end
but it's still like the kernel um
makes it think that it's actually
connecting to the service ap
right and the same for connected udp so
there's connected udp and unconnected
udp in the kernel
and you can do the same there from the
connect hook
and if you have unconnected udp where
you only use send message and receive
message you basically don't have any
state
and there you need like a small
translation table
for those two hooks where you can then
uh if the packet goes up
like back to the application to receive
message where you can then rewrite the
back-end ip with the service with the
virtual service ip
right yeah so i think that's really
really powerful
feature in saves overhead
then the case of noteboard services so
basically here we have this external
client
it tries to connect to a service on the
nodes ip
within the node port range and the
packet arrives on the physical device
uh ppf program which is sitting there it
does the service lookup and it
is automatically then doing a um dnat to
one of the back ends
it checks whether it's so psyllium has
the knowledge whether the back end is
local or remote and it checks
when it's local then it just redirects
it into the parts
network namespace so that's the trivial
case where the backend is basically
local to the node
if you have the more complicated stuff
where it's remote
again then you will connect to
the same nodes ip address where there's
the ppf program running
and then it determines how so the back
end is not local
i have to go i have to go to the remote
node
and basically it's doing a first the dna
and then it's also doing an s net and
that s net is also done
in bpf so we basically wrote an ad
engine in bpf
it's doing the translation and when the
reply comes back
it has to do all of the reverse s-net
and d-net and pushing the packet back
out and that basically works
we have it in in our soleum code base
merged and
it can go over direct routing or also
over a tunnel mesh in psyllium
yeah so all done in bpf then there are
some something that's called
external traffic policy local in
kubernetes
where you basically say um that it can
only connect to
those back ends that are actually local
to the node so you don't take this extra
hop
and basically the packet would be
dropped in this case if it tries to
connect there
and something that we merged just
recently in cilium is also direct server
return
so there we basically save the overhead
of of doing the asnet
and whenever a service again tries to
connect to a backend that is remote to
the node
basically we encode the um
the service ip so that basically the
back end then in bpf can rewrite
uh the packet with the source as the
original service id and can reply
directly to the to the client without
uh going back to the to the other node
for this extra hub
so that's more efficient even and that
all happens
inside bpf without any of the other
dependencies needed
so we did some performance benchmarking
on aws
with sio renetworking and compared
basically
uh the whole thing um to ib tables and
ipvs
and um we were running net births uh tcp
crr
gcp crr is basically a net perth test um
where your your you're establishing the
tcp handshake you're exchanging one byte
of information then you're already
tearing down
um the tcp connection and it's doing
this as many
times as you can and we were basically
running this against the notepad service
and as you can see here with the default
baked in
q proxy implementation you're really
hitting the
limits if you have 2700 services
that really is noticeable in terms of
overhead
because you have to traverse all the
lists and ip tables
um yeah and
it's it's it's being done for all the
new connections right
and yeah so
the second uh benchmark is basically the
tcp
rr which means that it's creating a tcp
connection
and then it's only is sending one byte
of data as a ping-pong
and then tearing it down so you don't
have the new connection
every time so you can see here that
iptables is actually
performing not as bad as before
but bpf is still the clear winner and in
the dsr implementation where you save
this extra hub
gives you the lowest latency
the other thing that we are currently
working on right now is basically to
move this
um extra hop that we had where the
backend is remote to denote
into the xtp layer xdp layer is
basically
another hook for bpf in the system where
you can where you can run bpf programs
right at the driver layer
without even having the overhead of
allocating a socket buffer in the linux
kernel without even having to go through
the
g0 engine and higher layers
so it's it's been running at much
earlier hook than just the tc
ingress and we can already dare if we
determine that the packet at the back
end is remote we can already there push
it back out the driver again without
having to go into higher layers
and all the three cloud providers now
they have finally support
so the last thing that got merged was
from what
into the kernel was the ena driver that
it got xtp support so you can run it
also in aws with siu v networking
and this chart here is basically from a
presentation
from netdefcon from facebook folks so
they're used
for a long time ipvs for their main l4
load balancing
and basically they switched all their
uh front and load balancer to bpf and
xdp
in production and they see much better
throughput so they don't publish
concrete numbers
but they said it has a performance gain
for 10x and more
which is quite impressive so yeah so
that's for the
psyllium 1 8 release we have scheduled
that
to pour it into xdp and
basically to recap with with the with
the whole
um data path and bpf you get a much
better performance and lower latency
you can have faster service updates
because you don't have to go
to um to then to the netlink and you
don't have to
replace the entire blob
and you just do like a bpf system call
for updating dpf maps
it's much more reliable you have less
lines of code overall
and you don't need to wait for a new
kernel if you have a fix that you
desperately need in production you can
just patch it live because
you can just change the bpf program on
the fly
you get much better visibility i didn't
really talk about that
in this talk here but there's something
called the perfect buffer output where
you can basically
export custom data um to a perf to a
high performance per ring buffer and
then
collect all of this in user space and
it's not
it's not subject to any um kernel you
api restrictions or something you can
really define your custom structs and
see that you want to push down there
and then we can also correlate traffic
with container traffic for example
uh you don't have to shell out to
iptables and you're able to
much more customize your data path you
can change basically the behavior on the
fly which is great
and it's fully integrated with the rest
of psyllium so this aspect only covered
the
load balancing integration but there's
also policy and much more
in psyllium so yeah with that said
um if you want to try out the cube proxy
free how to it's just like
three or four comments to run it there's
a cube admin
integration where you can deploy cube
admin without q proxy
and then you can basically run solium
and enable it with the cube proxy free
feature
uh the code is all on github if you want
to check it out and there's also a slack
community so
yeah thanks for that are there any
do we have questions are there any
questions there
oh yeah
sorry uh privilege mode so does it
require privilege
mode so if it's working like on a from
behind so you
the question is whether it
requires privilege mode or
yeah yeah so most of the ppf features
they are in privileged mode so basically
the psyllium part that you deploy runs
basically on a host namespace as well
and it has to install all the bpf and
manage all the ppf but that's basically
privileged
we disable the unprivileged ppf by
default
so yeah other questions
uh it's uh the first time that uh
i'm i'm seeing a bpf if i understood
well
it's all in user space and i'm concerned
about security because you never talk
about security
is it possible for a
a container to tamper the rules or
something similar
so basically all the bpf programs that
are loaded into the kernel they have to
pass the verifier
and the verifier does um strict security
checks it checks for example
whether all the types are saying whether
you don't do out of bound access whether
you so basically all the stuff that you
cannot
crash or destabilize the kernel and it
even goes that far
that you you've probably heard of all
the spectre stuff it even goes that far
to mitigate
uh potential spectre issues um
in by rewriting parts of the bpf program
that are loaded but still to keep the
logic the same
so it's really doing a lot of work there
to um
make sure everything is sound safe
other questions
so while you're walking if you want some
stickers there are also some ppf
stickers
have you done any performance comparison
with the the good proxy free project
when you have a small number of services
but the number of cluster nodes
increases
like is there a performance gain there
so when you have a small number of
servers but the number of cluster nodes
increases
so there's still a performance gain
because the um ip table so comes at a
much later point in the networking stack
compared to the tc
ingress so dc inquest is basically run
right after
geo is executed so it's still earlier
and also
all the bpf stuff is just in time
compiled it tries to void
all the indirect calls as much as
possible
as opposed to iptables so there's it's
still a better performance and there's
still less overhead in the fast path
okay we're out of time thank you very
much thank you
you