welcome everyone
uh my name is majin rochowski i was
working for a couple
last couple of months on housing net bsd
kernel
however this knowledge also applied to
filing other kernels
it shouldn't be hard to get this working
also on freebsd i was also doing some
work to get this on free psg so
you can also apply this to fast your
freebsd kernel
so the outlet of the presentation first
of all
what we are trying to achieve and this
talk
also assume that you don't have a lot of
knowledge about the fuzzing
and breaking the kernel so this will
give you a
pretty good overview what you can do
what techniques are available and some
background knowledge
like how these things works under the
hood
so we'll talk about the coverage as a
kind of feedback
for our father that is used for the
fuzzing uh i will also mention a little
bit
sanitizers but i won't go too deeply to
sanitizers because this is also one very
wide topic
however yesterday was a very good talk
about sanitizers
on vmware so if you missed it and you
want to learn more you can also
see the recording and we'll also
show how to do the basic uh setup for
the fuzzer
and as a demo we'll try to run fuzzing
on the ffs on
net music kernel as a virtual machine
so hopefully we may find something
interesting
uh sure uh
okay so a first thing uh
to justify why are we why are we trying
to break
things or why why i'm doing this
is essentially a need for having
multiple different ways to improve the
quality of software
and as we all know kernel is very
critical part of the
operating system if you break the kernel
you have
serious issue and there is no
known silver bullet to solve
all the issue and ensure software
quality
so usually what people does is multiple
parallel actions
to improve code quality and software
quality in general
because we know we always will have some
bugs or some
issues but from the other side we would
like to have
reasonable quality software and
something that won't break
very easily so we can have some list
things that we can do to improve our
software starting from stuff like
getting code reviews applying best
practices
and so on and so forth this list is far
from being complete and probably it can
be couple of other slides
to just list different techniques that
we know but i think
one of the most important and most
interesting
or some other people may say boring
things is about testing the software
so for me testing is like the
time when software uh meet the truth
so if you just do the reviews if you are
just doing
uh analysis of your code without
testing without running the software of
course
it's not good from the other side
technique is also very wide
area there's a lot of resources how
people do testing
but i think in our context it's fair to
say that fuzzing is also
a kind of testing for our software
so first of all what the fuzzing is
usually we call fuzzing when we have
some way to test the software which
in which expect some input and as a
as a as a testing technique
we are trying to give our program some
strange
unexpected input and we are observing
what is the behavior for this particular
input
so this simplest father that can be
written
is just for example let's say we have
some binary that you like to fast which
is called
uh fuzz binary and this binary get us an
input
1000 kilobytes
and some raw byte input and so what we
can do
you can just write some very dummy
father in couple of bash lines or even
in
one if you like very long sentences and
just get some random input save it
somewhere or pipe it
to the binary and then run binary and
the funny thing is
if this if the program is not written
having
validation in mind in that way you
always you all
you already can break some programs
which is
very funny uh but the good thing
i would be to think how we can improve
our dummy father
so what we can what we can do uh
to get the fuzzing smarter and
one thing that came usually to head is
how we can generate the input in more
intelligent way more smarter way so one
of the technique
is mutation based fuzzing as a mutation
based
essentially i assume that we can came up
with some strategies that will be
smarter or have some logical sequence
instead of just getting the random bits
and we can
based on those strategies we can mutate
the input
and provide this input to the
application
by definition mutation based fuzzing
doesn't really care about the state of
application
because we are just caring about
strategy so we have some
strategy to flip certain bits or
the strategy can also be aware about the
grammatics so for example if you are
fuzzing the
http requests you can get some
payload which is like in order with html
standard
and then play with different tags you
don't have to have just
raw bytes that you are modifying
so in that way we are able to much
easier find some interesting inputs
uh than in just a random way and also if
you get the random
input usually if you your program
expects some
different tags some different header in
the input format
usually just stopping on some first
couple of checks
that are making sure that your input
is have some for example certain
header certain and pattern at the very
beginning
another way to improve the further is
introducing the feedback loop
so in the feedback loop essentially get
some feedback from running application
about
application state and this state can be
measured in different ways the most
popular one is the coverage code
coverage
but we also can think about other things
like
timing cpu resources and
stuff like how applications behave with
uh how application behave with the
environment
and it's a funny thing when i was doing
those slides i just put timing because
first of all timing is known from
cryptographic software so for example if
you have some cryptographic software
which
uh have different timing for different
requests based on the execution path you
obviously have security
issue but i was thinking yes i'm that's
a good example but from the other side i
didn't so many like um
timing based fathers and yesterday when
i was waiting for my
uh fosdem t-shirt i met my colleague
he's working for thor project
and we started talking and i told him oh
yeah i'm doing the talk on bsd dev room
about the fuzzing and he was like oh
really i have a friend
who actually was doing a fuzzing based
on mutation and
he used a timing for execution of this
program to the firmware and based on
this execution time
he was doing modification to the
software and by this way he was able to
break some
popular electronic device maintenance
different device
so i was like oh really so that's mean
this this really works
uh so yeah i will also try to department
here
in this timing timing
way to this way to measure
the feedback from the application yeah
so it was
pretty funny uh also from the testing
world we have stuff like
we can think about our filing based on
ad application that we fast so if for
example
as in similar way as we are doing
testing so we have
white box testing black box testing if
we don't have for example
all information but we have some
information we can also say we have
gray box testing and so this feedback
loop also
depends what kind of fuzzing are you
doing in our example we'll be doing
a white box testing because obviously we
have a kernel that you can compile we
can instrument the code
and then you can monitor the state of
the application based
on those informations
so coverage tracking as i said that's
one of the main
technique how you can get the feedback
from the application
and that is how many fuzzers works
main coverage trace is pc trace
program counter it tells us about the
execution path
and the good thing how we can
start under our our understanding of
this format
is essentially the way how it's stored
in our program
so whenever we run the program or
whenever we have a kernel because kernel
is also kind of program
we need some array we need some memory
location where we will be putting
the sequence of pc counters so in our
example we have
a array of size 100 with 100 entries but
it can be much wider
and when the program is executing this
can be done for example
per threat per process or if you are
running the parallel it can be
also something per kernel thread but
also you can think about
some global array for example if you
don't care about the threads but
you care about the execution path
because what can happen if you are
pausing the networking you can put the
request to the networking queue
and then another thread will be getting
this request from the queue
so if you are fuzzing based on the
thread then you will be just seeing the
path when you put the packet
to the queue instead of seeing the
another thread which can be different
that will be processing your request
and so how this exactly works as i said
those are compile compile time uh
instrumentations
so they are put by compiler so on the
right we have a program very simple
which have main which called bar which
goes for which core bar
so what will happen during the
compilation phase our compiler will put
some
magic instrumentation at the very
beginning of all functions
and those will execute when we are
executing the program and
won't interact with our program but what
are those magic instrumentation so i get
a code listing from netbsd kernel
and it's a little bit modified just to
give you some
brief idea what is going on so
every time when we hit the
instrumentation uh we
call this function instrument code and
this function i need to get
our uh our our
memory that we reserve for present in
the
pc counters and we obviously we get the
index because we need to write
another entry we also need to do stuff
like border checking because
based on also your intention you
sometimes may overflow
and if you do the questions for you what
you would like to do but
the most important part we are just
getting the
pc from the function from which we were
called
by just compiler macro so if you run our
very simple program
i will end up with array of three
entries
main full bar so it's very
straightforward
and we don't have only pc trays we have
also a couple other different trays
we have cmp and gp what they are
cmp trace uh is used for
for application is used to
instrument dash comparation instructions
div is for every time when you're doing
division between the arguments
gep is for manipulating indexes
of the arrays so compiler
have some understanding about those and
when it's compiled the code it will put
the instrumentation
before every instruction is performed so
then you can have
better understanding why you need to
have different
i have different types
and so you can imagine like based on
your program
uh you may doing some mathematical
operations like
you can compare the argument you have
some graph or some tree that you are
traversing
so only the pc counter doesn't give you
full information because
you may always see the same path however
the path is not the same because
you are just you know getting different
arguments
or if you are manipulating a lot of
indexes of array
you may also see the same function
called over and over again but from the
other side
you use different arguments so right
here present the cmp
trace is a little bit different than pc
trace
but from the other side is something
that also you have in all bsd kernels as
far as i know
and also other one are similar in terms
of format
so instead of for just one or just one
information
you have arguments of of the operations
we have the numbers that we are
comparing
the types tells you about the size
of the arguments so if it's 8-bit r16
30 to 64 zone and also you have pc
trays so you have a sequence of those
sets of four um values
inside your array and as i said
everything depends on your kernel
on your code that you are fuzzing so it
depends which part for example
the kernel are you trying to fast it's
always good to think okay so if the pc
trace is the only one that i would like
to
see in my father
other important tools sanitizers as i
said i won't be going how they
actually works but i'm trying to
convince you that they are very useful
and the reason why they are very useful
is when you meet any
issue in your code the code may not
exit after invalid operations perform
for example you can
have memory corruption but this memory
corruption won't expose
easily so in that case
you can run the fuzzer and then don't
have any crash even if you
corrupted some data so
if you get the sanitizers
and here we have three kernel sanitizers
other sanitizers
leak sanitizer and memory synthesizer
they are
available in net bsd you can also have
under undefined behavior sanitizer
there's
thread sanitizer i didn't know too much
about trade sanitizers at this moment
but
i am also looking about them
so the very simple one to start with is
kasan because it's the texts things like
out of bounds for cheap stack
and other like a common mistakes
from the software the downside is
you cannot have all at once because some
of them are mutually exclusive with
other ones
so for example you cannot by definition
you cannot have a
asan and and some other scientists and
members in charge because they are
relying on the same data so they are
overlapping each other
so in lldm is specified that you cannot
use
both and from the other side they also
provide some slowdown because there are
compile times and they also
introduce another instructions
but as i said they
allows you to fastbacks easier and
faster so i think
uh is very very big leverage
for the fuzzer to actually run your
fuzzer uh with address sanitizer or any
other sanitizer depends on so
what kind of bugs are you expecting
let's go to the bowser the one that i
was using for a couple of months
is american fuzzy loop i think everyone
know american fuzzy loop is very popular
you have
very good record for found bugs some
people also claim it's
pretty old at this moment but i think
like
as a starting point is very good because
first of all it's very easy to use
as rock solid but from the other side it
didn't
have a goal to fuss the kernels but just
the user space
like but just the user space program so
you cannot use it directly to pass your
kernel you need some modification
um so what that modifications are
uh we can think first of all what we
have from the kernel site what we have
from
uh afl site what format lfl
require so unix's linux freebsd
netbsd open bc and other
expose the coverage using coverage
device slash
dev slash takeoff using this device you
can get
for example pc trace cmp trace the way
how you access this data you
configure the device using ioctos and
then you then
you do the memory map then you run your
program
and after you finish your memory your
map
memory i should contain uh those areas
that i discussed
previously from the other side afl use
its own specific format
where afl focus on par pairs of the
pc counters so and
it stores a unique it stores unique pc
counter pairs which mean every time when
we perform another
when we perform another instrumentation
which means we have another pc
we remember the old pc counter or zero
if we just started
and then get the old pc counter and a
current pc counter
extor them together very easily make
sure that we don't
overflow and then increase one in our
map which gives a
compiler which means a faster hint
this pair of those two pc counter
just happened so then then the father
can
analyze this array and say okay so i got
another pair that i didn't saw before or
maybe i always get the same pairs of pc
counters which mean i need to do
something different
so it's very easy to convert pc trays to
afl
trays because they look the same
but from the other side we don't even
have to do that
we can just store because it's just
storing redundant data
we can just do this on fly so we can
store two values
and this map and this is everything that
our afl needs to work
in order to do that we did some work and
modified a little bit and that bsdk cuff
and essentially we allow
you to plug in another kernel module
which will hook to
the coverage functions that are already
there
by doing that you don't have to manage
the default resources but you still can
use them
if you like but from the other side you
can do things like as i show
like a converting one input from
coverage to another one you can think
about any other
type of any other type of hazard that
you can use
and you don't have to copy all cake of
code and then manage
file descriptors make sure that threads
are open closed all of those things that
you need to copy from kickoff
you can just focus on coverage functions
and
map that's what you really need and
then you can leverage on what is
written already
okay so how this looks i first of all
when i
think about the fuzzing i first of all
think
what is the input what is the output
and so here we have my setup for um for
fuzzing the
ffs mount so my input is my
file image my output will be the result
of
mount or kernel clash and
and this and this sequence
i also require a couple other things
like a wrapper
and as i said earlier there's like a
plug-in for
a for takeoff and
it's works like we have a browser the
father create the
file system image we need our wrapper
that will prepare
the file system image to be mounted but
also will execute
the code that we need so it will be
executing the mount
also we do not uh we do not trace the
wrapper
this is just a thing that help us to
trigger the
execution path in the kernel and then we
do the man
mom is calling skull vfs
file system layer on all of those layers
we
call we get the coverage data
discoverage data then is transformed by
our afl
plugin this plugin is exposed to the
fuzzer as this
map of the pairs that they showed before
and then after every
run the fuzzer will get the input
around the input we'll get the output
from the short memory
we'll see okay so what different
strategy as our
feedback we should change or did we
found any interesting things
and after the feedback phase it's just
perform another operation over and over
again
um until we hit something interesting
um so what so i would like also to talk
a little bit more about
the wrapper it's all because also it's
interesting uh
so the way how you usually write those
wrappers
is i write them in shell i focus okay so
what kind of operation
i'm doing and then after i'm done with
shelling i need to translate to some
other
better performing language i usually
just use c but
you can use c plus plus or anything else
that can
expose your interfaces like system calls
because you don't want to
run on top of live bar someone else
libraries you just want to have
the simple the simplest maybe not even
the simplest but
the shortest code that you can do
and this is also well documented on
every father that
the performance is very key even if your
father is very smart
and doing very good guesses about
different inputs and then
analyzing the output very well it still
can perform
much worse than much simpler fuzzer
which is just faster
because uh in order to find some bugs
you'll need to
run this 10 000 times
million times iteration maybe even
billion times if
iteration if you have some very well
tested software
so in that in that regard you need
something that is performing operation
very quickly
as i would remember performance is the
key to use raw interfaces
other things also that are useful uh
when we are doing the
when we are doing the fuzzing is how i
can see
what is going on inside my fuzzer and
for example
what the problem that i had was um
when i ran my first father into the
first father i saw like
it's very it's not very slow but from
the other side
is very uneffective so i was thinking
okay so what's going on inside this
father how i can debug that
so then what i did i run the takeoff
on my fuzzing wrapper and i
monitor what kind of execution path is
inside
so by the fuzzer and i realized for
example in net bsd
we have much more verbose kernel and
we got a lot of operations from a
virtual memory even if you are doing
mount you see more
virtual memory operations which mean
you're actually not forcing the amount
you're fuzzing
stuff related to the management of the
pages um
so this is also this is also a bit
tricky and
for example in this way in this way you
can get the input
you can understand what is actually
going on under the hood
uh other thing that you can also do
before you start or
if you would like to tune something it's
also doing a coverage benchmark
a father benchmark so you can see for
example
if you want to understand if your
wrapper is
fast or slow you can for example put
some very dummy code inside the kernel
what i've done was create some simple
cover some simple character device we
just
get some input
come like compare this with the pattern
and then
if the pattern match you want the
lottery so your kernel crash
if it doesn't you just run over and over
again
but then i can see how well my
because this code is very simple i can
see how well my operation
in my wrapper perform and from the other
side also you can compare this
this kind of check with user space which
also gives you some intuition
how well are you doing
uh so to do the local to do the local
setup
of the fuzzer uh we also need to have
some
initial corpus uh so this initial corpus
you can create the corpus from for
example
just raw zeros as
it's very well documented that uh the fl
is able to reproduce
some uh different formats so for example
if you are fusing the jpeg or some other
images
afl is able to reproduce those images
but from the other side
if you are running a little bit slower
because you are in the kernel space
and also you don't want to spend like a
initial cpu cycles just to figure out
what is the header
or what is the magic number for the file
system
inside the inside the image you can just
create one
and provide this as a raw
initial sro initial data for the fuzzer
so this also very helps with speeding up
the fuzzing
and once we have that we can run our
fuzzer
with option k which was added
in it was added in afl by
a guys from oracle when they also were
doing their housing of
file systems so essentially i reuse
as they work and integrated this with
net bsd and freebsd
to make them work for both and then you
also need to specify
the wrapper so the important thing is in
that case
you're running on the same you're
running on the same car
you're trying the same binary that
you're running on so do not
shoot and yourself in foot because
if your camera crash then your data may
disappear you may
even not see the latest output
in the afl so you need to
make sure that you know what you are
doing so if for example
you are fuzzing something what is
unstable
and you will be finding a lot of bugs
maybe it's good to get
this input and output somewhere outside
of your kernel so you can mount this on
nfs for example
it will be slower but from the other
side i will have less issues and then
run this process remotely because if you
don't then every time when you crash
you can lose the data that you are
looking for
but from the other side if you have well
tested software and
you just will be happy if you will find
couple of bucks or maybe one bug even
you can just run this natively on your
kernel uh what i've done for example was
connecting the debugger to the kernel
run afl if anything crash i can just get
output from debugger and see what's
going on
i can also get crash somewhere
sometimes i realize that depends on the
path that
crash you still may not get the
actually may have some problems with
getting the output
so because the ideal scenario is you get
the output
which is the latest image that you were
fusing
and then you can get this image and
check okay so if this image
always break my kernel of this was
something that
was from some before testing so usually
it's very nice if you have output that
is a payload that you can just mount and
then it every and
break your kernel
okay so how many iterations to find the
bug
in fuzzing ffs so what we'll be doing
will just run on the same virtual
machine
the father and that's actually some
other issue that i
found at the very beginning but
hopefully we can
we can find something interesting
okay
okay so i need to get
i don't know how big it can be because
then the
father need to also okay uh
so we have here the father it's modified
version we have inside
in um a file which is our
prepare it's not zero so the name is a
little bit
misleading but we can see
that oh this is zero okay
i was fuzzing this anyway
and it's actually this is zero so i was
fuzzing this before and
i think
yes thanks
okay so it's not zero
uh so you can see this is the legit file
system image so we have the
offset which is eight i think 8k
and we have some some magic
from the headers of ffs i won't go too
much
in depth details but we see the
structure is
it's not it's not just a zero file um
so the way how we run it
and we can have this okay so i won't run
it yet
because i usually also get
uh proper absolute buff
wrapper
so we run afl fast minus k
i from input out from output
didn't remember exactly but i think this
definitely will work
if we will get the
the wrapper itself okay uh from the
other side
this running on gdb so we have connected
debugger
because this is just a virtual machine
and
this is debugger that is debugging the
kernel so we can stop in every time
we can see the trace we can continue
retrace we can also see that because we
stopped
virtual machine just froze we can just
continue
so then our virtual machine is still
living
okay let's let's
run this thing
oh we already got something so this
around the
dry uh so this
this round so it was running the dry
input at the dry run at the very
beginning so
dry run it's just do some simple
modification
and what you can see here
as yeah usually it also should show you
the
afl console but because we hit something
probably because i was
uh testing this before so we have some
old history
so it was also running something that
was found before
but we can go here and
this is already running in getting the
core dump from the kernel
okay but we have um operations that
uh crash so we have vfs reclaim
uh which uh was called uh on
the on the we know that was reclaimed
from the v cash
so that's kind of a moment when you
start
debugging the kernel and i won't right
now be doing this
because it's required some time and also
i'm not in right now great position as a
presenter to start debugging that
uh but this is some this is something
that
uh it break broke our kernel
uh so this might be related to them
to the data from the v-nodes and this
we can get this as a car or we can start
debugging this
you can start debugging this in gdb
okay and i think we can just
okay uh okay so conclusion uh so fuzzing
surfacing the kernel is another way as i
said earlier we need a lot of different
ways to
test our kernel and that we can
just we can just do to make sure that
our quality of our drivers our file
systems
is better also if you like to you know
start searching for some bugs this is
also very
easy way to start and
we have recently a lot of good work for
improving
things that allows us to run the fuzzing
so for example
gathering the coverage in bsd and other
bsd in general improved
also sanitizers in particular in that
bsd become
much better over the time it's very easy
to start as you see
it doesn't require much knowledge so i
think
in this half hour i gives you almost
everything that you need to start your
adventure with the fuzzing
and also you should run the sanitizers
by the way this was not random sanitizer
because we didn't have any scientists or
output so future work
i would like to have some also
discussion with other
people i saw a andrew presentation from
that he's also doing something on afl so
maybe we can
came with some similar way that we fast
bsds
i saw previously on linux they
introduced another
device it was slash diff slash afl
which community didn't like it and it
was not upstream at the end
so i think if we will try to get this on
common interface that will be beneficial
for everyone because then people from
security projects can just you know fuss
our kernel in the same way
i also need to spend more time on
improving the
remote fuzzing because it didn't scale
very well
if you want to find many bugs and just
continue with
fuzzing and fixing the bugs
the resources so our net bsd block
there's also paper
oracle paper yes from 2016
my collection of mount wrapper clinic
documentation was very
useful source of information and i will
be happy to get any questions
some questions
okay so thank you very much thank you
on one group justin we can listen the
questions
and the answers
okay so the question was can you use afl
for remote fuzzing not for the fuzzing
readers presented
the answer is yes but you need to do
additional setup because
as i said afl used the same data on
use input and output directory so you
need to mount to have them
remotely you need to run this as a pro
you need to run this as a process and
then you need
also some way to send back them
send back the information to the fork
server that crash happen because
your process just stopped and the thing
that i'm currently
looking on is how to get efficiently
the kernel down because then you have
the dumping process
so this allocation for dump also need to
be mounted
for something like nfs again or some
other protocol i mean nfs is the
simplest one
but you can potentially came with some
other good ideas
and i don't know how hard it will be to
get
afl console to real life to analyze
those crashes to say
uh because when you're passing the user
space like
user space library or user space binary
you see those
unique crashes for example so afl is
going through the core dump
of the process and then saying okay so
this one occurred
before so then it's not unique it's like
something similar
or this one is not unique because it's
something different and then
i have also take strategies from those
crashes
to improve so that's so i think as i
said
that part about analyzing the
core dump from uh kernel is some unknown
for me
other things can be done go ahead
okay maybe someone wants to leave the
room
before the second question okay