hello everyone
my name is of china i'm working at
wrestling digital
for the next generation platform
technologist at the cto
my team is leading a female toolchain
efforts for risk 5
and today i want to present you a
feature that we are open sourcing it's
called
cacheable overlay manager for s5 in
short we call it comov
it's a software paging mechanism which
we
i will introduce in a second so the
agenda for today is
i will talk a little bit about solving
code space limitation
with software is a small introduction
some basic concepts and use cases for
this feature
the building blocks that we need in
order to make this happen
on software and tool chains and the
deployments
let's start with short introduction so
on the early days of computing
there was a technique to load code on
runtime on the moment it was needed
actually one of the first example we can
see is by nasa using this technique
on the early days of shuttle flight
control systems
when the code itself was replaced betw
from the moment uh
there was the launch sequence and then
there is the ob sequence and the code
itself has changed
so this is a a well-known technique
we're just
reviving it and this technique
was called overlay it gave his easy
interface to the user
the software engineer there was no need
for any
complex outdoor ips like mmu etc
and it was traded with the toolchain and
the firmware itself
today iot devices have the same problem
with memory
they have a very small footprint of
memory and
they need some some solution alongside
reduced five
issues with code density uh it just
bring up the the usage of let's use
overlay
some basic concepts
okay so the basic concept is like there
is a
there is an engine in the middle of the
screen here
this engine is running on the fast
memory and it's uh
responsible to decide what to be loaded
and what not to be loaded from the
storage device
on the right which is the slow memory it
can be
whatever storage you wish
and then you decide what to load into
the fast memory
to the sr we call it a cache area
we call it in a cache area uh or nip and
this is uh
where uh the code is running according
to the running flow
the main engine uh workload is to invoke
the overlay calls and also to decide
what to evict and what to load
now let's look how it looks today for
just normal function
so for a normal function where there's
above and full full calling bar then the
tool chain will generate a jump to bow
this is by the way an instruction for s5
and now it looks when you're using an
overlay
so when you're using an overlay all what
is needed from the user just to put an
attribute saying
my function is an overlay and then i
write this function as as it is
foo is calling baron that's it but
beneath that
the toolchain will generate a token or
descriptor as we call it
here and push it into a jump address
that we are
entering the common of the engine itself
so
inside this engine the engine itself
will decide what to load
while it will pass this token and
understand where it is where it needs to
be loaded
etc and another thing that's very
important to say that
once we are inside an overlay function
then all the calling
for functions and all the colors going
back to the function
have to run to the engine that's because
when you're coming back from a function
sometimes your color can be evicted it
was not there anymore or
it got moved that's why you're going
back to the engine to decide
if this function was loaded or not or if
it if it was evicted then
it will load it again
let's talk about grouping and what it's
mean so since we are loading from
low speed storage we want to load much
as much function as we want in the same
context
meaning grouping so in grouping
we have functions overlay functions and
read-only data of overlay
when a runtime module will decide or to
load the function it will actually
load the entire group and this will show
us the painful storage load time
we can configure the grouping in size
between half a k and four kilobytes
and it's a it's it's it's not fixed
meaning that you can get you can get
a size of groups between these sites and
4k so you can have
all kinds of permutations on this
grouping size
in resolution of ffk
so it just makes sense to group things
together right that
relationship together like when you're
calling a spy feature or you're calling
a sleep model or whatever
that you're developing you want to put
those all in one group
in order to make just one shot of
loading so we
we provide several uh features in order
to support that there is the obvious
feature that which is we call manually
manually grouping when the user just
registers his uh functions to a group
he knows what what he needs and then he
registers to a specific group
and that group will hold its functions
there's not another option we call it an
automatically option
which will automatically trigger by the
by the grouping tool
invoked by the linker you will need a
ppp preparatory
a profile file that we provide to the
linker we need will
invoke the automatically a grouping tool
which i present later on
concepts of how it works and the obvious
solution that you don't have
don't need any grouping so if you don't
need any grouping you don't care about
performance at all
then each function will be in its own
group
another concept we are calling calling
it a multi-grouping
it's a it's a very special unique for
for this feature
uh and let's look at an example and
explain it by an example
sometimes different software scenarios
can run the same function
for example let's assume that the cache
area the hip that we have is very small
it's just fitting to this
for just one group
so in this example we can see my full
function is in group a
it's used by function 42 in that group
and also needed by function 1003 which
is in group b
meaning we need to evict we need to
evict a
when b is running and back to a when my
full function is done running
okay so when function 1003 we'll call
that function
we need to evict b and go back to a and
inverse vector
as a result there are going to be too
many loads it will take just too much
time
the solution is that for multi-grouping
is that my full function
can be live in the same group in
both of the groups it can be in group a
and also in group b
then when function 1003 will call my
function full
you will see it's in its own group and
no need for evict or load
group a
so a little bit about the logic flow of
the engine and this is very little bit
uh overlapped function will pass through
a common v runtime engine
here okay the engine itself is written
in c and assembly
and that's why it's traded with a target
for s5
the main engine itself
sorry the maintenance itself will will
do a few things that's the main
workload it will load or evoke invoke
overlay function it will also handle
evict algorithm
as a cancel with cash case sorry cash
concepts
so like an lru or etc this is what the
grouping do itself
so this is what the engine is doing and
it also have a fragmentation algorithm
in order to do
you know close holes in the memory when
you evict
groups
the building blocks we needed for having
this
tool box so with our collaborator from
because them
we did a lot of changes on the tool
chain
as a compiler we choose the lvm and the
clangers frontend
the compiler will just create special
calls for the overlay functions
as we see earlier
for linker we choose the new ld uh
these few changes are on the bfd
creating descriptors tokens as we saw it
for functions and offset table for
overlay functions
those tokens and over on the in the
tables are being used by the engine
itself
on runtime so this is also all for the
engine itself
as a debugger we'll choose gdb to
provide easy interface to the user for
debugging overlay functions and overlay
calls
because sometimes you want to do a step
into a function and just get into your
function don't want to hold the
mechanism of the overlay
but sometimes you do want to debug the
oval engine itself
so we need awareness from the debugger
side
other utilities the grouping tool some
extension to map file
and other service utilities that we are
going to provide
that's all to make the life easier for
the engineer to develop and to design
and that's all coming
so grouping so i want to share with you
the grouping tool techniques
okay but uh that's that's like a very
high level uh concept of how it works
uh so you can see here in instagram okay
of
of time and each color you represent an
overlay function
which is being called 12 times for
example here and 10 times
for example here that's the orange ones
and there is the blue ones
etc then we can see there is kind of uh
in each stage here that's a lot of
activities here and then
a lot of the activities here here and
here
okay so what this uh
grouping tool need to do is need to
follow and split all the activities and
find their hot areas
in order to make a recommendation to do
a grouping
so let's separate that and see how it
works so we can see
so the grouping tool will get a
pre-paper profile as i saw as i
mentioned earlier
for all of the functions and then we
will start building instagrams for each
function
so we can see here for example the brown
one there is activities for function a
activities for function b and activities
for function c
if you merge everything together one
above other then
obviously we can see that there is a
something that recommends
recommend doing grouping about about the
brown in blue and also
green is by himself so make it a group
by himself but if it fits of course to
the first ones then we would like to
merge them also
so following what we saw earlier this is
like the
initialization stage and this is part of
the steady state stage
now for deployment
so first of all comma v is open source
it's already on the github
we can access that you can see it it's
there
it's designed to fit bare metal software
and with autos based software
we are currently targeting free autos to
support that so it will be
threaded with friatos
the first first draft of bermuda is all
the open source as i said
and the support for fiatos is on the go
so it will be soon and also on the
github we can see a draft of the tool
chain itself it's already built
for debian targets uh but we all but
soon
it's all going to be also open source so
pay attention uh by may 2020 we're going
to have a full deployment of core rv
running on a real other platform with
the os currently it's running on a few
other platforms and it runs on iss
which is cool but because it doesn't
depend on any other
solutions then it can run on any any
other but it have to release five
following next small demos for usage of
each common v
api the target is that we want like an
sdk
for developers to see all the demos all
the apis
and it can start design is uh
it's called based on com movie
this is the github that we are providing
it
and soon it's going to move to cheaper
lines but so far it's here
and also we're going to provide the
two-chain branch to support it
that's it thank you very much questions
i have some time
you would be totally loading your
modules from
land flash and it's because you don't
have no flash that you cannot
directly
that's correct uh yes
the question was where we are targeting
to load the storage itself we are
targeting for an end
or something like that right so the
implantation
itself it doesn't care if it's an end
flash it can be even a network
because we are providing a hook to users
saying load this function for us
we're going to provide him the address
where the source destination and the
the map for the the function and we'll
decide how to load it but yes your
correct
observation it's it's target for an end
when we are talking about western
digital
right yes
uh linux re-implementation
okay if it's a really implementation of
the loader mode model in linux so the
answer is no
it's something that we are working with
many years it's very bare metal very
embedded solution
i would not recommend using that on
linux for example there is a performance
impact every time you're going to end
the engine
it's doing yeah it's doing almost the
same thing uh with
varsity of changes yeah and the tool
chain support of course
yes two questions uh do you have any
plans
to use this with zephyr at all
okay so the question was if you are
going to use this
with a safer so the answer currently is
no
there is a it all depends on how much
effort we are going to do in friatos
meaning if we are going to do this very
model very tiny changes
in the candle itself then it will be
very easy to move it to any other
atos right so you can do it for example
for tradex
you can do it for cypher you can do it
for whatever
that's that time time will tell but
currently it's fearless
and the other question um so the other
question i had was
um could you use this um more
as a caging system where you could
execute
say from uh nor flash
but there's a performance here that
anytime something is used if it's used
frequently
you pull it into um
the like high speed memory that you have
have you explored so that's that's a
long question
i will not repeat that but if i got it
right you're asking if uh
the cash concepts work uh like a like a
real cash right like
you're using nru if functions are very
hard not to evict them that's what you
ask for i'm more
keeping track of how frequently a
page might be accessed and then only
loading them
frequently because you can yes yeah yeah
yeah
yeah so yes the answer is yes we're
investigating other options to
to to monitor the cache itself not only
using just lru for example we can use
lfu which is last
this frequently used so yes it's on its
own
it's on the plan more questions
i have time right now uh just a minute
so a minute okay
um so you have to modify the tool chain
obviously to yes
how does that interact with the link
time optimization
okay that's a good question so it
doesn't
okay so uh for example uh not only
linkedin optimization also
for uh inlining for example okay so each
function which is an overlay will not be
inlined
and also we not participate in the lto
because it's very unique
functions very unique
within a group that's maybe a good idea
right
yeah we can examine that
that's it thank you very much