um
all right my name is brian richardson um
it's weird i actually get paid to talk
about firmware
it's an odd job so the fact that you're
actually here and interested in
listening to it justifies my existence
in the corporation so thank you very
much
they paid for the plane ticket so you
know we have to do that
um i put this material together with
help from people from tiananmen corps
project at intel
vincent simmer and mike kinney also i
had invited richard hughes who maintains
the
lvfs to come and talk he wasn't able to
this time so i've incorporated some of
his slides into the materials
so even though some of those will have
an intel logo in the corner we didn't
make them and i'll
i'll point out where those are okay so
a quick check of the room uh who likes
firmware
or is interested in firmware anyway if i
say who likes firmware some of the hands
will go down
who has had a great experience updating
firmware on a device
yeah yeah great experience yeah okay
i have recently actually that the hand
has done this over the years and i used
to like
be paid to write firmware like an
assembly code for money
so updating is hard it's harder than it
should be
and we're going to try to fix that
and it's actually now implemented in a
way where it can be done in the open
so i can talk about the entire process
and how if you're doing development
especially on linux how you can start
working on
making sure that that code works as we
move forward
so first let us define the problem space
tech presentations do you have
infomercials here
they probably if you do are you familiar
with the infomercial right
who's who's jet lagged and stayed up in
their hotel room and watched a terrible
ad
about like some tape that covers over
leaks or
a knife that cuts through every that's
called an infomercial we invented that
i'm very sorry
it wasn't my idea they didn't call me
but the infomercial always has
three things you have something stupid
a proposal to fix the stupid thing and
how to get the thing that we just
proposed to fix the stupid
so first here's the stupid um
in technical terms there is a low attach
rate for firmware updates in the field
by end users
in my southern vernacular um
from america y'all ain't updating your
firmware
now if you read cves you all should be
updating your firmware you saw the last
couple of talks yeah we probably ought
to do that every once in a while
we made it hard for end users to do it
in in the old days the 90s when i
started doing firmware you got a floppy
disk
that's a 3d printed version of the save
icon you put it in the system
because we didn't have usb and you ran a
program you would download it off of an
ftp
site because we didn't have proper we
just got an over gopher at this point
and this beard is gray naturally and
then you would run that program and you
hope you had the right firmware
for the right uh board and then you hope
that there wasn't a magic jumper you had
to set to make all that work
so you have to open the system to update
the firmware and sometimes you would get
what we like to call
a brick which is something shaped like
your computer but now doesn't boot
the process was designed for nerds like
me who got engineering degrees and
learned why we use xor on a register
instead of move
a zero into the register answer takes
one less opcode
users need to update that thing
otherwise every time you go home to
visit your family for the holidays
you're doing the updates you don't get
to actually hang out with your family
that you get that answer stupid
questions and update their laptops
so it's creates an environment where we
do a lot of work in the industry to fix
all these problems
and do cool security talks about them
and get paid to go to conferences
in las vegas and then nobody actually
uses the work
which is just entropy that's that's bad
all right in linux it's worse
one because oems ship windows
they might not be testing linux so if
you get
a nice shiny ultrabook style thing and
you put your favorite distro on it we're
not going to say which one because if i
name one it'll be wrong
and i'll get thrown out of foster so
they're not testing that thing
now on windows typically it has been a
windows pe
or some other type of windows runtime
service
to update the firmware which means in
linux they didn't implement it
now let's think about the technical
complexities of doing this in linux
runtime
so on x86 intel firmware is mapped to
a four gigabyte space or it's within the
four gigabytes space it takes up you
know the size of the spi part
and it's mapped below a four gig
register even if you have more than four
gig of memory
why old people reasons address mapping
um so okay you have to if you're
updating the firmware what you're really
doing is writing to a fixed address
now anybody who's in protective mode
programming in the linux kernel knows
you don't write to a fixed address
things that do write to a fixed address
on windows unless they have special
permissions set off virus protection
and in linux are normally done in kernel
drivers now does
do all the oems disclose how they update
their firmware
they do not which means would be a
closed-sourced linux kernel driver
which means it would have to be compiled
against specific kernels
which means it would always be the wrong
kernel because you all are rebuilding
your kernels all the time
and kernels evolve and the drivers would
not follow up
so it creates a different environment
where the
updates that are done are not applied to
a subset of users that would love to
update their firmware and are probably
more technically capable
but can't so
there is now a solution space which
solves a couple of problems one it
standardizes the delivery format
so you can do things in a standard way
it's written down in the spec everybody
can read it
and it's os independent it's called a
capsule i'll explain that coming up
an infrastructure for update delivery
you must have consistent
protocols you must have a consistent way
of doing it no matter the operating
system
so if somebody in bsd land decides to
implement it same process
and it's os based staging that means the
os delivers the firmware
to the system but does not necessarily
do the update
and then you have this modular firmware
thing the firmware should be smart
enough to update itself
if you don't trust version one of the
firmware coming out of the factory you
have a different
security problem that i cannot solve for
you it usually involves hiring a very
large man with a stick
and he makes sure that people don't put
you know if you put the wrong firmware
in hit him with a stick
i'm not advocating violence but that's
usually how those things work
um so that that's a chain of trust
problem different topic probably already
presented here but let's assume you
trust version
one of firmware that's probably the
thing that should do the version two
update version two should update version
three and so forth
again if you don't trust that guy stick
all right
so let's talk about capsules so uefi
actually recognized that this was a
problem when we wrote
the spec now i'm some of that spec is my
fault i apologize
the initial chapter in the ue520 about
usb 2 with high speed
i copy edited sorry
so the idea in the spec is that uefi
capsules define
a way to encapsulate firmware this is a
standard way you can take a firmware
payload
and deliver it to a system now
how that's processed is system dependent
but the capsule should be the same
so it shouldn't matter if it's an
expansion card shouldn't matter if it's
inbuilt firmware
if it's the graphics driver use the same
system
so some developer somewhere generates a
capsule and they sign it
they sign it we don't deal with unsigned
capsules anymore and they don't sign it
with the test key
and they definitely don't put that test
key in their shipping firmware
i have to say it because somebody did it
i'm sorry it's like on the airplane door
when it says do not open during flight
that sticker probably wasn't there on
the first airplane but it's definitely
there in the second
we're not going to the toledo let me get
out here no that's
we're not doing that you go to a
distribution system of some type now
it's nice to have
a repository windows has windows update
we're not talking about that here fosdem
we're going to talk about linux
vendor firmware system lvfs this does
the same thing because it's all
standards based
lvfs works off exactly the same system
as microsoft does for capsule delivery
if you have
a windows surface device it uses capsule
and it has
for since the first surface if you have
a lenovo laptop
you probably have started seeing more
updates available for those in linux
those are all using lvfs lvfs then
allows the system
to distribute the same capsule to the
same model of platform
and allows it to locally update
so capsules are in a spec you're not
going to read it i took part of that
and put it here and the spec by the way
it's not a novel you have to read the
whole thing pick out the parts that work
for you
and apply to your work um i have read
the whole thing once and i didn't do it
again
so the capsule has a standard header
that says i'm a capsule
and it has other information fmp which
is firmware management protocol which is
the protocol that actually processes the
stuff on the firmware side
authentication info because we
signed our capsules okay uh the payload
header which
describes what you're dealing with and
how the local machine
should process it and the actual payload
now what lvfs cares about in the
delivery
is actually the capsule header the
capsule header tells the system firmware
hey this is this kind of firmware can
you process it can you process the
update forget about the payload
look at the basic header can you deal
with it and the system firmware has fmp
drivers
uh it has a set of grids everything in
ua5 runs on grids
so the driver's got a grid that matches
and says yeah i can use that
i get a big table called esrt an efi
system resource table
tells me all the firmware in the system
what are its grids what versions is it
running
and then through that process it can
verify the keys they should be signed by
the same people who made the first
version of the firmware
again that whole why we use certificates
so that driver is signed same public
keys as the original version
and it updates in the flash and you
update the esrt so that somewhere in
operating system land you can observe
the results of the firmware update
because way early on the only way you
could tell if the firmware updated
was to go into the bios setup or look
for the screen that just blinked past
you as the monitor warmed up
and figure out oh that was version 102.
crap i didn't write down what
version i just updated over i hope it
was 101.
nobody knew and then the operating
system couldn't get that information
until we started publishing it in esrt
now i am presenting on ue5 firmware
which means i am
obligated to show at least one slide
based on
the progression through the boot i don't
the if you want to see hey is he going
to use the big green h yes i am
those always show up in ufi
presentations you can just play uefi
bingo that's the free square
so read this left to right
you have the phases of the uefi boot
process
and then top down how we go through each
cycle so you first do a normal boot
the os has an agent running or you go
out and you're on say ubuntu sorry i
know it's the wrong distro for most
people
and you click on the software update
thing and it says ah one of your updates
is system firmware
i can go get it for you if you want sure
that sounds cool
it gets it stages the capsule staging
the capsule just means i put it in a
magic space in memory
and i sent a note to the kernel that
says i put a thing in a magic space in
memory when you reboot
please tell the firmware there's some
magic thing in memory so that it doesn't
do dram initialization and wipe out the
thing i just put in memory
so it does the reset firmware reboots
and goes ooh there's a thing in memory
i should probably do something with that
now there's a couple different ways to
load the capsule in most systems it
happens
at the bootloader like a grub or windows
update kind of situation
in other cases the firmware just
directly deals with it on boot
but either way there is a update capsule
routine
which then causes what we call a
coalesce you could have multiple
capsules staged in memory
from different lvfs agents it could be
the embedded controller the me firmware
lots of things can get updated on the
system a modern system is really just
20 coprocessors in a trench coat it's
it's not a piece of firmware it's pieces
of firmware that interact together
so you coalesce the capsules and go
through the loop of processing them
until you run out o capsules and because
the firmware is up
doing that process it can say yeah i
know that capsule
it's native firmware it's the uefi i'm
going to update that
what's my next capsule that's an
embedded controller there's an fmp
driver for that from the manufacturer i
don't know how to do it
but they do i'll pass it to fmp or in
the rare case something slips through it
goes
i'm not supposed to up i don't know why
i have this i'm going to throw it out it
doesn't match anything on the platform
or it doesn't validate because
somehow maybe the signature got broken
and then you update the asrt and you
have updated firmware
so that you don't look at a blank screen
in the open source implementation we
actually implement uh two different ways
of doing the update
uh process one is graphical and one is
console
because some of us still use serial
ports
yeah i know it's 2020 really we're still
using serial ports okay modular
philosophy
so uefi edk2 which is the underlying
open source project that most people use
for uefi um that is
modular so we have this modular idea
that if we componentize everything in
manufacturing
then we make it easy to update using
capsules when we ship the system
not that we get very granular with it
but we can at least group into a couple
of clusters
there is an open source implementation
of this intel has gotten
in my opinion way better about putting
out more code for actually running on
platforms
so we've come up with an idea called
minimum platform implementation
sometimes it'll show up as mpa
most people call it min platform just
means that
we put out a reference design say
whiskey lake which is a 8th generation
core product i know that because i
looked it up on arc
we've got open and closed source modules
for that there's an fsp there's
some redistributable me kind of stuff
that goes along with it
we also have a whiskey lake rvp
reference validation platform model in
tiana core so you can build the minimum
amount of uefi you really need to
boot a uefi thing now
that means that you could morph that and
say put it on the aeon up extreme
available for 299 dollars it's not an ad
it's just letting you know it's a cheap
board that you can actually work with in
tiana core
so now this gives you a way of playing
with this code and
doing some development that say if you
were going to make your own device
you'd need to write an fmp dxe component
not the whole driver the stuff in blue
on this slide is standard in open source
it should not change generation to
generation
you know very much for supporting you
know aside from bug fixes for supporting
the
fnp update process but if you are the
device vendor
you want to write a library that
implements fs ff
fmp we have too many acronyms for that
device
if you want to be a platform vendor and
determine how that is processed
you write a capsule update policy
library that's the policy for the system
okay so that gets the basics of edk2 out
of the way
if you have questions hang on till the
end i want to make sure i get through
this stuff before we hit that level
all right now you want to distribute it
and this is the part where
i pinged richard and said i understand
roughly how lvfs works but what would
you want the audience to know what are
the top things you talk about
because richard uses the basically the
reason why you can do this in linux
even if i did all the stuff in firmware
if you don't build a distribution system
that's consistent everybody uses it the
whole thing falls apart
so richards built lvfs basically because
he encountered the same problem
on a lot of other kind of embedded and
maker style devices
they had weird proprietary firmware and
they had
kind of weird protocols that weren't
documented he didn't care about
disassembling the firmware he cared
about updating it on the system he was
using
so sometimes in lvfs you implement a
protocol that's completely closed and
you blackboxed
sometimes they give you the protocol
just enough information to write source
code
and then they endorse you're using that
information like headers for instance
and in some cases the whole thing's open
and you can do it soup to nuts
so lvfs has two main components one is
fw upd
which is the update mechanism the thing
that runs on the system
uh that's 100 free and open and that
is used by the users typically with a
gui so if you've run
the ubuntu update system and you see the
firmware shows up
that's running under as lvfs and it's
it's seamless enough now to where a lot
of people just do system updates
and don't realize they're taking a
firmware update until the reset
lvfs website is the data source that's
again free and open it's used by the
vendors so the vendors interact with
this to upload the information
and get their stuff in there richard's
built a trust model with the
manufacturers to make sure that he's
only getting the verified binaries
his phrase is lvfs it's just a website
a terrible slogan for a bumper sticker
it does mean
that there is some vendor secrecy for
permissions just to ensure the right
things go up there
and it can be mirrored mirror the whole
thing and take off if you want to build
a mirror of it great
it's just a website uh but it's a
website that is supported by
so many vendors now this list is a
little hard to read
i would have not designed it this way i
always hate saying this is an eye chart
i'm sorry
but this is an eye chart i'm sorry um
the
left to right is time so it's months
and then uh bottom the top is i believe
number of i can't remember if it's a
number of website hits or number of
instances of firmware
but you can see the number of vendors
going up as they sign the adoption
agreements
and the nice thing is because it's the
same capsule that everybody else uses if
they are
building and signing that for windows
they just take the same thing they gave
to microsoft windows update
and put it in lvfs so they're not
building a different thing for linux or
a different thing for bsd
they're building a thing and
distributing it differently based on the
os target
now there is some back-end uh processing
that goes in
um there's another layer of security um
that richard does
um through standard ssl and there are
some verifications run
um he checks things on the back end to
make sure that things are formatted
properly like did you follow the spec
for the capsule header because if the
capsule header is trashed
it's not going to do anything good when
it gets to the other side
and firmware analysis this is pretty
cool he's actually
checking to see if oh i don't know the
dell firmware doesn't have any
attestation checksums now we can't stop
del from putting it up there but he can
make little green and red check mark so
you
when you pull it down understand what
you're getting
and then by having these verifications
by running things like chipset for
instance in the background
you can do checks on say whitelist
blacklist i know
there's a grid out there for a driver
that's been blacklisted
it's got a known issue i can flag it if
it shows up in my system
lvfs should be its own 20 to 25 minute
presentation here i'm not going to try
to cover the whole thing
but he does have a very good long-term
roadmap set up
and it's something that you need to i
think if you're interested in firmware
updates as a problem look at this
because it covers way more than just
uefi
it gets down into lots of different
components and different ecosystems
so it's definitely something worth
looking at all right
so i told you about the thing that we're
doing that i don't want to do anymore i
gave you a
potential solution for stopping doing
the thing that i don't like
and now i'm giving you homework not like
real homework it's
you won't be graded attendance isn't
mandatory um
but in summary basically edk2 supports
an industry standard for capsule update
we have a
full implementation of it it can be used
on hobby boards as testing so the
minimum board max
that's based on bait trail the aeon up
squared and up extreme boards that we've
supported
i don't know how much arm stuff is using
capsule but i'm pretty sure there's a
few of them out there that at least
could get it wedged in
the arm guys are doing this notion with
their heads good
but this simplifies authentication
system update pre-check did i plug in
the power adapter on the laptop before i
started the update process that could
break it
you can check for that kind of things
and have the firmware uh
decide it doesn't want to do the capsule
update at that point and through
something like esrt again documented in
acpi
notify the system if the firmware update
was good or bad
all right so if you're building a system
or you know somebody who is you should
probably sign your capsules and
make sure they get distributed in the us
we have a thing called nist
national institute of standards and
technology they put out guidance for
this sort of thing
and the guidance is please have
updateable system firmware in the field
please have root of trust involved in
the update so that you know the thing
that's supposed to be doing the update
is doing the update
with the thing it's supposed to have um
i know
eu and and england have the similar kind
of regulations or references to it and
if you want to sell to the government
this is in their purchasing agreement so
if it doesn't meet nist and you want the
sweet sweet tax dollars back in the form
of buying your product
then you're not going to get it
if you do updates i'm sorry when you do
updates
update your firmware um put it in lvfs
and microsoft windows update
i'm not here to plug microsoft but if
you have a device and it ships both
configurations make sure both
configurations can get the update you
worked hard on
resolving those cves make sure somebody
actually benefits from it
uh if you have a device vendor put it in
the requirement to them
you're going to sell me a thing it must
have capsules for its firmware update so
i can incorporate it in the manifest for
my system
and please have a recovery solution if
you encourage more people to update
their firmware
this the rate of failure won't go up but
you'll have more instances of that rate
of failure
like point three percent isn't a lot but
it is when more people do the thing
so it works 100 of the time except when
it doesn't
um nist 800-183 or 193
is the requirement for that and there is
a recovery solution in the tiana core
solution for capsule if you're a
developer hi
that's most of you um you're working
with an open source community make sure
that
you're trying the stuff out if you make
a linux driver and it's got a firmware
impact
go get a board that supports it and see
if it works
these are all links the slides are
already up because i paid attention to
the guys in the blue shirt said poster
slides before you get here so thanks for
reminding me i almost didn't do that
there's also information on the dk2
threat model some of the risks in
capsule are based on that threat model
and there is some information on windows
update only because
they they do actually document some of
the process of formatting the capsule
fairly well
and edk2 we tried to make it easy by
using a bunch of python scripts to do
some of the things we thought were
harder
all right i said myself a couple minutes
for questions before we get to that
thanks everybody for sticking around i
know it's late and we should already be
having a beer right now but we'll solve
that in a few minutes
i mean after the next talk okay uh i'll
take this one up here first
uh can we leverage well do you think
that vendors are approachable so that we
can use capsule
to also supply custom firmware images
not just the vendors so
they may audit and sign them
okay so the question is because we have
this this
mechanism that you know is open friendly
could we get a vendor to
do another version of firmware like a
custom version so
essentially you want the oh i'm owning
my system now
so i want to put my own firmware down
potentially but it's not initially
designed for that because of the signing
mechanism
you would have to have the vendor sign
that firmware
or the vendor give you the private key
that probably won't happen on purpose
um if you get the private key by
accident don't go signing other people's
firmware that's rude
um but it's tough to implement i think
you would have to have a vendor who's
friendlier to that sort of situation
but that vendor might also assume that
they're going to do a physical presence
i.e i open the box and put the thing on
it and then you're going to cell phone
the firmware by establishing your own
key and signing your own stuff
so i think that's uh quasi supply chain
issue and quasi-friendly vendor issue
uh there was a question i'm going to
skip you only because we can talk when
we have a beer later yeah
uh when you are updating
on what i'm updating
so the question is when you have
multiple capsules what is the order
uh the answer is the order is not
deterministic it's as far as i know
on the current implementation of tiana
core and leif correct me if i'm wrong in
this it's just when they show up
so they get they get put in memory and
the firmware
has a process to coalesce which just
basically means count all the capsules
that are sitting in the magic space in
memory
so i don't think you can have a
deterministic order unless you
explicitly went in and changed that
policy
but you can't guarantee that everybody
has that policy
and there's a sign there we can talk in
a minute
but again appreciate everybody for
sticking around and find me afterwards
i'll be around here tomorrow a little
bit
or my contact info is on the slide find
me online thank you
you