great
all right thank you very much uh
everyone um the next talk is uh by
michael he also spoke in this room
last year um and he'll talk a little bit
about code workload management
um thank you very much thank you
welcome and uh let's let's hit the road
and get going come on in find your
favorite seat
so my name is michael hopefully you can
all hear me okay in the back let me know
if not been at red hat for
almost eight years now this is my i
think at least third maybe fourth time
at fosdem
i've been working on container tooling
and technology at red hat for
the last uh at least five years
basically since docker became a thing
and everybody decided wait a minute we
need to get in on this docker thing and
start shipping docker containers and so
on
in the last two years i've been very
focused on
[Music]
cluster orchestration workload
orchestration workload management
deployment tooling all that kind of
stuff on top of kubernetes
and that's we're going to talk about
some today in particular
what the intersection is of the control
plane for kubernetes what we use to
control
infrastructure and kubernetes itself uh
and the workloads that run on top of
that
and the tooling that manages the glue
between all of that
so uh we need to understand a couple
things about the kubernetes api
to really dive into that so let's let's
dive into some details now kubernetes
itself of course
we're familiar with that runs
containerized workloads across
some collection of machines some
collection of nodes right
and the api that enables us to do that
includes a number of primitives
like pods pods are the way we run a
container
at a very simple level services that
give you a network presence and this
sort of thing
and if we look at that api we see
uh some interesting things about it has
anybody ever used this uh
cubesee tail proxy command before few
hands
very handy if you want to explore the
api and see what's actually there
so you can run proxy and it'll just
start up a local proxy for you
unauthenticated that you can connect to
and just start hitting kubernetes
endpoints so here
i did exactly that and i just curled the
root uh
of that api and we're getting a listing
of
api groups so this kubernetes api
it's it's a web api uh some people call
this rest
um it's not really rest if you know rest
but you know it's rest ish
it's what a lot of people call rest but
really it's a web api
hierarchical in the way you would expect
and uh
it has these api groups so many of the
apis you're familiar with
are under this core uh api slash v1
url space that's where a lot of them are
but
you can see the beginnings of this list
we're only into the a's
in this list in terms of what apis are
available you can add these groups and
we can in fact
add our own and that's one of the like
really special and unique things
about kubernetes its api service will
allow you to automatically uh to add
your own api endpoints your own kind
your own data structures
it will serve them for you it will track
them it will even validate them for you
and all that stuff
uh and that's really pretty amazing and
that that's central
to what we're gonna do with kubernetes
today
and uh and then this api is declarative
we'll dig into that in a moment but
declarative is a very important part
of managing things in kubernetes
uh so just as an example you can see
down here i just made up i completely
made up i have no idea fosdem uses
kubernetes or ever will
but we could have for example an
apps.fazdom.org
api namespace that we could then put
apis underneath
in a kubernetes cluster
all right let's dig into an actual
resource and and what how resources are
structured
so if we were going to look at one
individual resource like a pod
or like a service or or something along
those lines we would see these kind of
things so let's start at the top
and we start with an api version what
api is this
endpoint a part of so this could be
apps.org
for example this could be i work with a
lot of openshift.io
endpoints for obvious reasons so you
have a namespace and a version
so versions are things like v1 alpha 1
is where most of us start
it could just be v1 v2 these are
semantics they have very specific
meaning within the kubernetes context
and then the kind the kind is like a
table name in a traditional database
kind uh
is like pod kind is service
we could make up a kind like wordpress
and have a kind that describes what a
wordpress deployment will look like
that could be our custom kind now into
this metadata section
name and namespace are the way that we
uniquely identify
one individual record of
the type that is defined by
group version and kind with me so
name that's a unique id within a
namespace and of course the kubernetes
namespace itself
divides resources up within the cluster
largely for reasons of role-based access
control and quota control
and then this is the really interesting
part spec
spec is where you declare what you want
you specify
what state you want to exist in the
world
so you as a user of the api
the spec part is for you the status
is not for you to write it the status is
for you to read
the status where a controller of some
kind running in the cluster
will get into what a controller is in a
minute status is where a controller can
write some information for you to find
about what is its understanding of the
world
what has it actually done so in the spec
you may have
asked for a certain number of things to
exist i want uh 10 pods i want
uh 15 of something else the status is
somewhere
that it might tell you how many
currently exist
and is it trying or not to make more
or remove some is it encountering
problems while it's doing that
the status is your way to get feedback
from a controller about what it's been
doing but remember this is all
asynchronous
so when you create a resource you define
the spec
then you basically wait around and watch
that resource for changes
and eventually you'll see some changes
to that status that will inform you
about what's actually happening
so here's examples a pod so let's just
look at the one on the left
a pod so we've got the api version
uh the group is implicit it's part of
core kubernetes and the version is v1
and the kind is pod so we got that down
the name
uh it's got a name now there's no
namespace here but there's no namespace
listed here because if we were going to
create this resource
whatever namespace we are creating it
inside of will be implicit in the create
action
i have a namespace as part of that
create action
uh so that namespace will really just be
implicit at that time
uh in the spec we've specified the
typical kind of things you would
anticipate
a pod to have what container image
should be running
what ports if any need to be exposed and
you can imagine other kinds of things we
could
specify here storage do we need to
attach some persistent storage
do we need to mount some secrets in here
all that kind of stuff
also notice there's no status here why
is there no status
because this is a resource in the form
where we would
we're about to create it we're about to
hand this to the to the api
so no controller has touched this yet
after we created this pod resource
then a controller would start acting on
it and start putting a status on it
and then we'd find out what's going on
okay
now this is the real exciting part
custom resource definitions enable us
to tell the kubernetes api service
add an end point add a new endpoint
among all the endpoints that you're
serving right now
and we can tell it what is the structure
of the of that resource
what is the specific data structure that
would go into the spec
of that resource and
we can then use those just like any
other native kubernetes resources
we don't have to write any code to do
this we don't have to run any new api
services to do this
all we have to do is of course in yaml
because kubernetes
fill out a yaml resource there is an
actual core resource called
custom resource definition we just
create one of those
and poof the api service starts serving
this new endpoint and a new data
data type it will even do validation of
that data type
uh using open api v3 so you can you can
tell it things like
this field is a string this field is a
positive integer
this field has a minimum value of zero
um you know whatever other kind of con
validation
mean is meaningful to you and meaningful
to your data structure
it's really powerful of course
once we've done that all we have is a
data store
all we have is well i can create a
resource called wordpress
i can read them i can update them uh and
and this
api source will keep track of them but
nothing is happening in the background
we haven't any action yet nothing's
taking action because we don't have
a controller yet
so this is an example uh what if we
wanted to deploy memcached
we could make a memcache d custom
resource definition and then somebody
could come along and create
one of those resources and specify a
size of three for example
uh later on we'll see the operator sdk
mentioned if you wanted to go through
the the getting started guide for the
operator sdk for making an operator
you're going to start by making a
memcache d
operator nice simple example okay
but what is an operator so an operator
is three things
one is a custom resource we make a
custom resource
uh something like wordpress so if we
were gonna make a wordpress operator
our goal is to make an operator that
understands how to deploy
manage wordpress in a kubernetes cluster
and we would start with a custom
resource called wordpress
that describes what would a wordpress
deployment look like what's uh
what's the title of the blog what's the
contact info for the person that runs it
color scheme you know those kind of
things i'm not much into blogging so i
don't do that
but you could next we need a controller
because with just a custom resource no
action is happening so we need a
controller to be running
in the cluster what is a controller a
controller
is typically a pod running
a container running in that cluster side
by side with all the other workloads
and it watches the kubernetes api
for the resource types that it cares
about and whenever it sees one
and sees an event happening related to
one of those resources it cares about
it runs what we call reconciliation and
reconciliation is where
that controller will look at the spec it
looks at your spec that you just
specified
what do you want what have you declared
then it looks at the real state of the
world what actually exists right now
and then it makes changes to the state
of the world to bring that
closer to what you've asked for
that's what a controller does it's a key
part of this pattern
but there are lots of controllers what
makes it what makes an operator an
operator what makes a controller an
operator
that is the operational knowledge
all the things that an sre team might do
for example in the course of managing
some service all that stuff about
how do you deploy what steps you take to
deploy it how do you
monitor it how do you repair it when it
breaks every ops team
understands a certain number of common
failure modes for their application
right
something shows up in the logs or some
alarm gets set off you say ah
i bet i know what's wrong here and we
just got to go do the thing and it'll be
back on the road in a minute you can
automate that process you can code those
kind of repairs
custom kind of scaling if you're going
to scale based on custom metrics
based on queue depth for some particular
service you can customize scaling
all kinds of things around managing the
full life cycle
of your workload you encode into a
controller
and that's what makes an operator these
three things make an operator
and what can an operator do so deploying
and managing an application is the prime
use case that's what we talk about like
a wordpress for example
but that's not all sometimes people
write operators to
either report on or even enforce
policy so you could ensure uh
pick some resource type that uh
you want all pods to have some
particular
annotation on them or all all name
spaces need to have a certain quota in
them
you can imagine other kinds of things
you could write an operator that watches
those resources
and if it finds one that does not have
whatever state you want to have
either uh it could tattle and and tell
you about it
or maybe even enforce it maybe just put
it back the way it's supposed to be
and if somebody tries to change it it'll
get that event immediately slap that
away
and put it back the way it's supposed to
be then managing external resources this
is a really interesting area
a little bit newer of an area but you
can manage things like
a network switch imagine reconfiguring a
switch
that's in use by a cluster from the
cluster zone
api so we're natively in this kubernetes
native way
interacting with and managing physical
infrastructure around us
from the kubernetes control plane by
using this controller and operator
pattern
and you can imagine some other examples
so here's the pattern illustrated
we have this controller that's watching
events
it's going to tell the api service which
resources it wants to watch
and which name spaces it wants to watch
and it'll get an event anytime one is
created updated deleted
it gets an event and that's it's it's
time to run
this reconcile function now if you
wanted to go implement your own
controller
uh normally there's frameworks that will
will help you with this they'll scaffold
out even a basic
skeleton of a controller for you and
your job
is to go to the reconcile function and
start implementing that
so the reconcile function starts usually
with something like
let's just retrieve our wordpress
resource
and okay let's now start looking at it
so this person has asked for a wordpress
with a title
of this does that exist is there a
wordpress deployed that has that title
uh if not let's go to poi one or maybe
it is deployed but it's got the wrong
title so let's change the title
uh maybe the version that's deployed is
not the one that's supposed to be
deployed so let's initiate an upgrade
and you can just imagine you you
validate the entire state of the world
and then you make changes
that bring you closer to the spec and in
a traditional
operator what pops out as the product of
this is
an application all the pieces of an
application
pods services secrets config maps
persistent volume claims
other services it depends on all that
stuff you would orchestrate
the creation of and the life cycle of
from your operator
so this puts you in a good position uh
this is thinking of an example with
prometheus
uh there's a prometheus operator you not
be surprised to know
so by having a prometheus operator we're
being proactive about the management
when something changes inside the
cluster that's relevant to this running
prometheus whether it's good bad
uh immediately this operator gets an
event and goes and checks out what's
going on and make sure that everything
is still the way it's supposed to be
as opposed to being reactive we're not
paging somebody and then waiting for
this to get fixed we're not submitting a
ticket
when traffic increases asking for more
infrastructure
and then getting approvals we're just
taking immediate action and doing it
so how do we make an operator so we have
this operator framework
that has a bunch of pieces but the
operator sdk in particular is your
starting point
operator ck lets you make operators in
different ways you don't even
actually have to know go goes what we
typically think of for operators and
what many operators written in but
that's not the only way
and it will scaffold out for you the
skeleton
project and from there you mostly
implement reconcile logic
and uh and it's pretty easy the operator
life cycle manager
is like a packager packager for a
package management system even
for operators you can think of it like
yum or dnf
or apt or pick your favorite package
manager
and then metering is a more advanced
feature that you might find useful as
well
there's three primary ways you can make
an operator
helm is a very good way if you already
have home charts which many people do
and you want to start participating in
this operator pattern where you're being
proactive and immediately responding to
events
related to uh to whatever resources
you're managing then
you can take one or more helm charts and
actually in one command you can convert
a helm chart into a basic operator
there's limits to how much you can do
with a helm based operator because helm
by its nature is is mostly about
templates
uh it's harder to code into a helm chart
this kind of active management but
ansible is something else you many of
you are familiar with
ansel is very powerful you can do just
about anything with an ansible
and you can make an operator with
ansible uh i pretty sure i give a talk
about that here
last year uh you can make an operator
where that reconcile logic is written in
ansible it's a great fit for that
so that's something you might consider
and then go of course a very popular way
to write controllers and write all kinds
of tooling run
around kubernetes
so we've been talking about operating
controllers we dug into the api service
and uh what's it really boiled down to
what does this mean
what have we done so we have an operator
one way to look at it one advantage we
have here
we've created a higher level api so
somebody who wants to deploy wordpress
rather than needing to go to the
kubernetes primitives of
making their own pods or deployments
and having secrets and persistent volume
claims and services and doing load
balancing
and all this other kind of stuff
deploying databases deploying logging
infrastructure whatever else might be
involved
not to mention having an upgrade
strategy having some kind of tooling
that's going to manage that upgrade
strategy for them
we've abstracted all of that and you
know software just love abstractions
we've abstracted all of that behind
just a wordpress api where someone can
just describe i want a wordpress that
looks like this
and maybe this is the version of
wordpress i want to be running
and then all the rest of that is taken
care of for them um
our workloads are starting to look more
like managed services this is a really
key part of this pattern
so uh you're familiar with i'm sure
working in various public clouds if you
want a database if you want a queuing
service
on any number of other services you can
just get
a fully managed service and just use a
database service provided by whoever
your cloud provider is
here we can approach that same kind of
experience
but running in your own cluster by
having this
operator this automated piece of
of management running side by side in
that cluster
right next to your actual workload
managing it babysitting it
and scaling it up and down as necessary
fixing it based on common things
upgrading it as necessary we can start
to approach that same experience
infrastructure and workloads side by
side so infrastructure is not
just uh the load balancing it's not just
the the primitives that we normally
think of with running workloads on
kubernetes
it's storage it's the
like the real core networking
infrastructure in some cases it's the
cluster itself
the virtual machines that the cluster
itself is running on
managing all that side by side with one
api
and that means we get to use our back
one rbac system for the whole thing
so we can put quotas around uh
and other controls around who's allowed
to deploy wordpress in this cluster
how many of them can they deploy or how
large can their wordpress deployment get
api discovery so kubernetes is really
powerful for api discoveries
much like an application um platform in
that way
and using the same api discovery and
service discovery mechanisms
across that spectrum of infrastructure
and workloads can really be very
powerful as we combine them
and when we start thinking of all this
together this is what starts to be what
we think of as kubernetes native
so we could take something like
wordpress that vastly predates
kubernetes but if we expose it in this
way and we manage it this way
it's not only running natively on
kubernetes it's being managed natively
through kubernetes through that same api
one set of tooling so you can use cube
ctl
any any tool that can be acquired for
kubernetes can manage
uh that wordpress now that's what we
often think of as kubernetes native
who does this sort of stuff software
vendors of course if you're a database
vendor
you gotta have an operator these days
and you probably do
you can imagine why uh databases are
sticky things and there's a lot to
managing them especially in a
containerized environment
cloud providers have made operators to
expose their services
natively inside kubernetes and then ops
teams this is really
probably the the heart of this for you
is ops teams for your own customized uh
software your own in-house proprietary
software
whatever it is you're responsible for
running on your infrastructure
many many options are building their own
operators to
automate that in this kubernetes kind of
way
super powerful if you want to see some
examples of these
you can go to operatorhub.io there's
i don't know something probably
approaching 100 now i think it's about
80 the last time i looked
at at least a couple months ago
different operators from all kinds of
vendors all kinds of providers and
projects
that'll show you a real good
cross-section of real world use cases
for these kinds of operators uh
and then just a couple of interesting
use cases here real quick cluster api
fascinating project where
people are making controllers so for
example there's an amazon
controller that if you want to scale up
your cluster
you can go change a size from like
10 to 15 and that controller will go
talk to the amazon api and get you five
more virtual machines
ensure that they've got kubernetes
running on them add them to the cluster
do all that work for you and you've now
just scaled out your actual
infrastructure
there's the metal cube project that we
unfortunately didn't hear from earlier
uh that is all about doing that with
bare metal
so it's taking cold dark hardware and
actually on demand provisioning images
onto it and adding that to kubernetes
rook seph running storage natively in uh
in the kubernetes cluster not just any
but even on bare metal
managing data resiliency and redundancy
on bare metal machines inside a
kubernetes cluster interesting problem
space
some hard challenges but they're using
extensively controllers and operators to
to manage that and make that viable make
that something that's reasonable to do
cubevert really fascinating you can run
virtual machines inside a pod in your
kubernetes cluster so you can now
schedule virtual machines the same way
you're scheduling
pods and as controllers that make that
possible
so that's that's all the time we have
i'm going to step outside
and answer any questions that you guys
have and i'll be there as long as you
like
and if you can't do that right now feel
free to contact me here email is
probably the best
i'll be around this weekend and happy to
chat with you guys about operators
thank you very much thanks michael
[Music]
you're a very good speaker thank you