okay
next up we've got simon margaret who's
going to be talking to us about
containers and steam
hello um so unlike most of the people
who've been speaking in this room i'm
not talking about
like mission critical services i'm not
talking about like securing your
database or anything like that i just
want to play half-life
so i'm sure you all know about steam
it's valve's app store
for mostly games a few a few non-game
apps as well
um on windows on mac um on
their own debian derived operating
system steam offs
and on generic linux the games are
labeled as
steemos but actually they work fine on
most distributions
sort of um i work at a company called
collabora
we are an open source consultancy and um
my current project is helping valve with
the steam runtime
which is how their linux games
manage to work mostly correctly on
steemos
on debian on fedora on arch whatever
the problem is if you buy a game quite
reasonably you want to you know play it
you want it to work on your computer
um but linux distributions are all
different
um it does it use lib jpeg 6 or lib jpeg
does it use live ssl
1.0 or 1.1 or something from the distant
past
um you you can't really know
quite what you're targeting um or you
sort of can
because the lsb exists but that's got
like three libraries in it and
um no operating systems actually use it
anyway
so it's not a great baseline for running
all your games on
so valve invented this thing called the
steam runtime
um this is from like 2012 2013
something like that um so you have your
host system
um i'm a debian developer so my host
system is obviously debian
um and inside that we have um this box
where um this is um there's a
horrible shell script um that sets up an
ld library path about this long
um so that a bunch of libraries from the
steam runtime
get used instead of the ones from your
host system
um so this is the traditional solution
for portable games you bundle all your
libraries with your game
except valve have bundled all their
libraries with their
launcher so that all the games get to
share them
and the steve runtime releases there is
one so far are named after team fortress
2 characters so this is scout
um and
if your operating system is similar
enough to ubuntu from the distant past
you can run your game and it works
um yeah that ld library path
uh is massive oversimplification it the
the real one is huge
the problem is you know you know i said
if your operating system is
similar enough to ubuntu from the
distant past
turns out in a modern operating system
this doesn't work
so um the major things we have to get
from the
operating system are the graphics one of
them is the graphics driver
so in the open source world we all want
to use mesa or
potentially some other open source
driver but yeah it's nicer
um and if you and mesa
needs a bunch of dependencies no i don't
want to restart steam
right thank you steve
offline mode well respected um
so we need dependencies for the open
source drivers uh we need the llvm
libraries which are enormous
we need the standard c plus plus runtime
because of that which is pretty big we
need libdrm
um we need libgcc that's kind of
core thing kind of important and we need
um gdpc obviously
and um if your gpu
is from like this year you need a
version of mesa that supports your gpu
so really recent as well and there is
kind of anecdotal evidence that if your
colonel and mesa are about the same age
um that's probably going to work best
it's meant the kernel is meant to be
perfectly backwards compatible at all
times
but that's really hard so it's just
mostly backwards compatible
and then the other side the other side
of things we have the proprietary nvidia
driver and historically the proprietary
um fglrx driver for um
ati stuff as well and these are
um similar to mesa they have a user
space part and they have
a kernel side part unlike mesa
they require the kernel module and the
user space part to be exactly the same
version
the communication between them is not
backwards compatible it's not forwards
compatible they have to match
so you can't bundle the user space part
of the graphics driver
because then it won't match the kernel
part for most of your users and that's
not good
also i mentioned gillipsy glibc is kind
of fundamental
we can't really get away from that um
and it has this thing the dynamic linker
which is what actually starts your
program like your game or whatever and
the path to that is hardcoded
it's part of the elf headers of every
binary
um you can't change it it's part of the
api
um you don't get to choose what path
people are using there
it calls into lib dl which is the actual
implementation of loading shared
libraries
if they don't match their assumptions
are going to fail because it's like
call this function this private function
in libdl that does the stuff we want
oops it's not there call this other one
oops it does something different
bad news similarly lipdial is
inextricably linked to lipsey and lipsy
is linked up with a lippy thread which
does locking and stuff that kind of
thing
and if they don't match you're in a
situation that the glibc maintainers
have never tested
can't really be expected to have ever
tested
it's like this is not going to work so
we don't have graphics drivers in steam
runtime and we don't have glibc
and unfortunately if you are using
the um graphics drivers from the host
system
they will depend on a version of level
lvm and all that
that is at least the one they were
compiled against
a reasonable assumption except if you
have replaced all the libraries with
ubuntu from the distant past
that assumption breaks your game crashes
which is why the 2013 air esteem runtime
stopped working
so what we now have you'll notice the
the same diagram
but the box is a bit paler now um
because instead of having
we're using the all the driving
libraries
from the runtime we are now looking at
those libraries
comparing them with what's on the host
system
and um picking whichever one we think is
newer
so if you are running the steam runtime
on
something really ancient like um
ubuntu 12 or steamos 2 which is pretty
old by now or something like that
um a bunch of the libraries in the steam
runtime that valve consider important
for games will have been upgraded
so for example we have a newer version
of canoe tls we have a newer version of
sdl
and it will prefer to use them if you're
um others of your system libraries are
going to be newer like in practice you
will have a newer like
jpeg or gtk or whatever and we'll use
those from your host system instead of
ours
and again the ld library path is a mile
long
even longer in this case in fact and it
works great
except uh comparing versions of
libraries you might think oh yeah yeah
you just look at the sim link
it's a sim link to like libco.so.4.1.2.3
you compare that with libcurl.so.4.3.8
and you can see which one is newer
except a few libraries
um the the so name the um
like canonical name of the library is
just a regular file not a sim link
so you can't easily tell which is newer
um we have some code in progress
to improve on this by looking at the
symbols exported by the library and the
version symbols and that kind of thing
and making
a better educated guess but it's still
fundamentally a gas
um if your lip curl is newer on the
whole system as it often will be
it might not be the same api we've got
as a result of
some with hindsight bad decisions um
made several years ago in debian that
have since been fixed
but the steam runtime is based on a
version before that was fixed so
yeah and openssl um removes symbols from
its abi when you turn off support
for insecure ssl versions
um so um if you have a library that
calls into it like lipcurl or something
um it may not work with the hosts live
ssl because
even if the sony name is the same that
symbol has gone away
so we have to hack things like lib curl
to not try and use the old ssl versions
even if it detects them also um
the dotted line on the my diagram is not
a hard boundary
um game vendors will often
compile their game test their game it
works good ship it
even if some of their dependencies are
in fact
things that came from outside the
runtime and
we never shipped a copy of that if you
happen to have that on your host system
their game works great if you don't
problem so
big thing i have been working on lately
is pressure vessel
this is a little open source
program recycling a bunch of code from
flat pack
so steam is still in it in the old style
runtime
but as a child process we have um bubble
wrap
represented by here by his mascot of a
bobble wrapped cat
um this makes a little container so
um quite similar to what flat pack does
much of the same code
in this container it's a very strict um
scout environment you get the libraries
from scout and
no more if your library is correctly
done
was built in a scout environment like
half-life for example
it works fine if your game is one
from a less strict publisher
it probably won't work but it didn't
work for some people anyway right so at
least they can qa it
um if they test in this very strict
container it should work for everyone
a hard part of this is we have to hoover
up the graphics drivers from the host
system
and we have and because they have
dependencies
we still have to get the dependencies
into the container somehow
and there's some mad hacks in pressure
vessel to make this work
uh remember i said the ld.0 path was
hard coded
we have to bind mount the right ld
that's so over the top of it to make
this work
we wish we didn't have to do this but
it's kind of necessary
um because the graphics driver in your
container wouldn't support your hardware
because it's old um as an experimental
side benefit we can do other fun
container things
so we can give you a separate home
directory for each game
so that um anything in that home
directory
we know it came from that game we can
send it to the cloud to the
um steam cloud you get your set of games
everywhere
except uh currently this feature um the
actual steam client doesn't know about
the separate home directories so cloud
autosync
is worse with this feature and the steam
workshop also doesn't know about this
yet
unlike a lot of container stuff we are
not trying to do security here
it's not a security boundary it would be
nice but it's not the priority right now
meanwhile uh you may recognize this guy
giving a talk
in a room similar to this one two years
ago
so flat pack has come along um people in
the community not me
um have um made the steam client
into an unofficial flat pack app so
here we have flat pack on my debian host
system
starts the container using bubble wrap
this container is using the free desktop
sdk
which is a set of libraries done by
freelance.org people
and inside that we have the traditional
scout runtime
just the way it was a few slides ago
um so
this is a security boundary at least a
little bit
it's kind of porous right now but we'll
get better um
as far as the steam run time is
concerned the um
the free desktop sdk is like in the role
of the host system
so we get the graphics drivers from the
flat pack runtime we get some libraries
we'll talk about runtime
and a unique feature of this thing is
that um there is um
some madness with an ld audit plug-in
inside the container to
force uh broken games to work even if
they bundle libraries they shouldn't
which is great and i'm amazed it works
and we should steal it
unfortunately combining these two is
pretty difficult
um because some of the constraints that
are put on
flat pack containers mean we can't enter
another container
so the stuff we want to do in future old
games have to keep working
even if your gpu is new for new games we
want new runtimes
so more team fortress characters um we
currently have a
um we currently have a
runtime being tested called soldier
which is
somewhat newer than scout heavy and
spy are slightly older ones that we
tried but abandoned
um and
when we go into this newer runtime
environment we don't want to repeat the
mistakes of the past
and have your game not work reliably um
[Music]
in the i in a new distribution in like
five years time
or ten years time um so
we want everyone who is testing their
game in soldier to be testing
a strict soldier environment that um
they can't accidentally pick up
dependencies on libraries we don't have
and that kind of thing
so one strategy for this is that um
because we've got a pressure vessel uh
we don't need to pick the same runtime
every time
so if we imagine that half-life had been
ported to be built in soldier rather
than in spy
we could just make a different container
and this means
not all the games have to have the same
runtime the games don't have to have the
same runtime as the steam client
everything's great
another possibility is where because
mistakes have been
made and blame was ascribed some games
have dependencies that are not in the
scout environment
but those games basically work on scout
in debian 10 we have like empirical
evidence
that that works so why don't we put the
old runtime
inside the new runtime and use the fact
that the new runtime is pretty similar
to a current
version of for example debian and
that might well make um games more
reliable
and again we don't want to do this for
future games it's just for current ones
um and finally um we have uh
this setup that i have been trying to
get working
flatback now has support for what they
call sub-sandboxing
where instead of making another
container inside your container
which you're not allowed to do you can
send an ipc request out to flat pack
and say please make me a container make
it look like this
go and so you have the steam client in
your original container in the free
desktop sdk environment
and then over here you have half-life
in your scout container flatback
can't currently do this there is not all
the code yet
to be able to ask it to use a totally
different runtime
but the flat pack developers seem to be
fairly receptive to the idea that that's
something they might do in future
so hopefully we can get that working and
have these parallel containers and flat
pack users will be able to benefit from
this multiple runtime thing
any questions or alternatively do you
want a demo
right so
here is the reason steam was nagging me
to update it
this is not a special magic hacked up
steam this is just the normal public
beta
of the steam client i don't even have
access to the private ones
um and uh
the only thing i've done a bit
differently is i've run it with this
magical option
um to ask pressure vessel to give me a
gui
um instead of just running the game
straight off um you can
you can get the magic incantations for
how to control pressure vessel
from the source code um
so this will take a moment because it
may have to unpack my runtime okay
so i have this little test ui that i've
asked for normally you wouldn't get this
normally you just get a game
this is my development version that has
all sorts of inadvisable options
like making a process id namespace which
doesn't even work because it confuses
steam
so i'm running it in the scout runtime
it's giving me a choice of runtimes i
have a copy of soldier available
i have this option here to put an ld
library path runtime inside the
container that doesn't work yet
and i'm going to tell it to run a shell
instead of actually running half-life
so this is a thing i think i put in for
debugging the environment um
this is an x term inside my container
so if i catch etc is release
you can see that this is not my debian
host system this is
a purely scout container slash edc
and slash user and all the rest of it
came from scout
um except for this overrides directory
which has all the stuff i've yinked in
from my host system to get my graphics
drivers working
and um this
shell has the command to run stuffed
into this variable
so you can run your game a bit of
logging happens
and welcome to black mesa
and we are off time thank you
you