okay uh this is the
coverity you know says fuzz issue
solving thing so what i've done here is
i've left out all of the simple stuff so
if any simple bugs reported us
not really yet at heart here it's just
the more
interesting things uh techniques to get
rid of
more complicated coverity warnings and
ways to solve some of the uss fuzz
uh issues that arise as well there will
be lots of um
3d slide transitions to keep you
entertained and also to make sure that
they work
i did all my development version where
the slide transitions worked perfectly
fine
and then they didn't actually work in
the fedora version which can be tracked
down to a change in how glm works
and there's a fedora updates testing
there since yesterday that has slide
transitions working for fedora again
so i guess tradition as a traditional
traditional
going to the conferences make to use
your own software to realize what bugs
need to be fixed
all right so the configuration we have
for coverity uh where coverity works is
that you build
it locally on your side and then that
outputs a great big blob
which is uploaded to their server and
their server does the analysis and that
so in the at least in the open source
version that we use
you don't check results locally you have
to use their website and their output to
see what um
the results are the way we've configured
nowadays is that it's fully public
and passive it defaults to private you
get a chance to look at the bugs first
yourself
and decide whether to make them public
or not
once we fixed all of the bugs we decided
to be public
because we had no legacy issues that we
needed to be concerned about anymore
so if you have ever applied to be a
member of any of these projects you
don't need to be a member of the
libreoffice when all the issues are
public
um in the older versions of coverity
your project was either c plus plus one
or java one now it picks up both java
and c plus plus
in uh libreoffice and reports issues on
both
languages uh coverity does not support
uh c plus plus 2a but does relatively
recently support c plus
plus 17 which means that we patch our
configure to
uh go down back down to c plus plus 17
to get it past
the converity tooling and we only scan
libreoffice itself we don't worry about
any of the third party projects that we
use
some of those are scanned separately and
some of them other people's issues
this is how the website that you see the
results looks in
the results are emailed to the list but
the ui
on the website is superior when you have
a non-trivial issue
there's an example case of something
where there's a uninitialized
members and it's just reported like that
a lot of the warnings that coverty gives
are kind of heuristic based
as opposed to like a guaranteed
well our heuristic base in the sense
that um if there are no
members initialized in your structure
won't warn about that it assumes you
know what you're doing
if you initialize most of them but then
not one or two it'll warn about that
the same is true for a lot of the cases
that it'll look
kind of statistically whether or not
things are out of
abnormal so your code can be unchanged
somebody can delete a couple of
lines of code and that means the
statistics for this particular pattern
changes
so you get new warnings even though new
no change has been made to the code
that's been warned about
the overall state has changed so
warnings can appear and disappear
not with nothing to do with the actual
lines of code being reported
so you'll see like if there's 55 times
somebody checks the
return value and then the case is
introduced and it doesn't
then that's something that's worth
flagging but if it's 30 30 and then
somebody changes
one of them then the changes is from 29
30 and then you might get 29 warnings
saying that
return value isn't checked so that's why
things sometimes appear and disappear
if you want to wave a warning you can
just do it directly in the web interface
you can say this is not a warning this
is a false positive this is intentional
but if you do that and you have two
issues first issue is that if the code
changes efficiently that converges can
no longer track that it's the same code
the warning will reappear
and then that only affects that clarity
instance inside red hat
we run another instance of coverity and
we put libreoffice through the paces on
that one as well
so if i get rid of false positives in
one i don't get rid of them in the other
unless i do something that can be
detected by both instances
so we have the annotation stuff here
there's two possibilities for annotation
which i know work and i've seen
documented
in our own internal documentation red
hat but seems to be hard to find
out on the public web which is that if
you use the
um warning name that i'd highlight in
the earlier slide you'll initialize
members put it between the brackets
converted whatever
and put an optional comment it becomes
marked as an intentional
issue inside in the web interface but
then if you use the
space full colon false it's marked as a
false positive automatically
which is convenient so here then the top
one is inside in calc where there's a
struct
that's deliberately not initialized it
has some
an ou string member which is a default
constructor so some of its
members are initializing others not you
can say that they're all deliberately
not initialized with that one it's an
intentional issue
and then the other one is where there's
a copy and paste error which is just
completely spurious
and that can be marked as a false
positive
then the other annotation is that you
can set a a a function to be told that
it's like a
fatal function that this function is
called that's your program will
terminate at that point
and that's automatically in place for
things like assert and abort obviously
and then you can add annotations in our
case to the cpp
unit um call that reports an error how
it actually reports and errors it throws
an exception that's unhandled
so if you leave things in their default
state you get 5000 warnings saying that
you won't handle exceptions labor office
but they're all from the deliberately
it's meant to deliberately fail in our
cpp unit test
so that's annotated as being a fatal
function once that's called
um a coverity knows that it's uh the end
of execution and that any of follow-up
issues
are can be just dismissed automatically
we run the converting runs with the
enable assert always abort so any
a search that you put in will also if
triggered uh terminate flow
so if you were to run without that flag
you would find that there are warnings
inside libreoffice that
would not be handled but because we say
assert is fatal which means that we
really mean what we
save when we have an assert we say and
assert will not happen
so they're not for use for like trivial
issues use your warrants instead
because you are removing them from the
source code analysis if you use an
assert that's not
true assert that's really difficult
um sometimes is the tainted data you
want to know if something is chained to
data if you're reading data from a
a file farmer to microsoft office binary
file format
if the values are untrusted if it says
that there's you know
minus one uh values to follow and then
you try to allocate minus one value then
you have an issue there
so you want to know that this data is
untrusted but there are cases for
coverity
i will say this data is untrusted but
you happen to know that that data is
data that's shipped with libreoffice and
it actually is
trusted data so in this case
in this example we don't want to say
that all values that come back from that
function are trusted but just in this
specific case we trust
uh that data and this markup here uh
calling converity chain to down to
standardize
will say that this data is trusted and
that removes that issue
uh this all comes back from the the
heart bleed
issue in openssl and at that point uh
coverty added this support by
detecting common bite-swapping
techniques as being
a way to know that certain data is
tainted so the other solution um
whether it still works or not i haven't
double checked is that if you use
the then documented non-standard
swapping pattern
then coverity will not consider that
that as tainted
so if you wanted to say that all data
that comes back from this function can
be trusted
despite the bite swapping you can bite
swap in that style and
apparently it will consider it untainted
and if you just wanted to actually test
your data properly in the case where you
are reading
untrusted data then any kind of a check
at all on the data
will consider it to be validated so here
i've checked to make sure that
the link to the resources is is possible
within the lend of that file
it's unsigned so there's no need to
check for less than zero if it was
signed you have to check both
ends of it otherwise it'll be considered
unchecked you get a lot of that
especially in the image filters uh
yeah sliding stuff um the other thing
that's difficult to deal with
in uh coverity is its handling is
its tracking of exceptions it's very
good at tracking where an exception
could be thrown from which gives us a
lot of
exception warnings in areas where in
practice it's not going to happen
typically you get something like from
the configuration where the
configuration could
throw but that configuration is going to
throw the first time it's red
and typically like you read maybe it
started a constructor and then you read
the same
configuration data in the destructor
when it comes into this structure and if
there's a for instance a standard unique
pointer which cannot have any exceptions
to ensure
it's going to uh you're going to be told
that it's going to abort it ever
happened
but it's not going to happen i mean it
could happen if somebody deleted the
configuration while your program is
running but
in practice it's not going to happen so
how are you going to get rid of these
you can either come up with a really
convoluted scheme of catching the
exceptions but it's all just going to
make your code
a complete mess or just accept that it's
not going to happen
you want to hear about other cases like
that but just not in this specific case
so when you get that warning the most
recent one was just yesterday before
and you have your standard knee pointer
you can pass in the deleted parameter
and the data parameters of that o3 tl
default delete which when it's not
running in
when it's not compiled and converted it
just does the standard delete
and you assume that that exception isn't
going to happen and just to tell
conversion not to worry about it you
have
effectively that it's not exactly the
same code i shrunk it to fit in the
slide
and then you can see that if underscore
underscore converity underscore under
is defined you know that you're running
under converting and then that silences
uh that whole set of warnings so that
you don't have to
worry about all right so those kind of
uh
trips and tips and techniques we've been
using to get conversion numbers low
to get it manageable and what we always
want to really hear about is
changes in warnings from conversion so
this is yesterday's uh stats and
converted in 20.
so we just fixed um the last warning
there again so we're back down to
zero warnings and the number of code we
have you can see that we're analyzing
6.1 million lines of code
we're down from about 6.5 million lines
of code since
2018 so we've actually shrunk our code
quite a bit which is
nice hasn't happened for a while and
those are the figures we have there
the other set i have as well is a
timeline
of how many bugs he started off with
back in 2014 and shrunken all the way
down
and the various gaps and then you see
there's a gap there where we didn't have
the ability to run covertly for a couple
of months
because we required c plus plus 17 and
there wasn't c plus plus 17 supporting
converting until
whatever july last year so the numbers
rise when it's not being constantly kept
under control
yeah so that's the end of the coverity
section
so the oss fuzz that's where there's a
huge big giant set of
uh core set aside on google's
cloud where it poses documents
for us in this case
they build on their side our project
on their compilers and their hardware
they call our script
uh that script which we'll find in our
source tree which uh builds
uh the various buzzers in our
configuration so we've fortified them
fuzzy targets we've got all of the
graphics file formats bmp
gif png jpg etc etc then the file
formats such as like doc
excel and all those ones our own file
formats in the flat version so flat odt
flat odf and all them
so there's 45 individual targets and
then they build them on their side in
three different configurations
uh two lib photo ones the address
sanitizer
uh the undefined behavior sanitizer and
then there's one with the american fuzzy
lap
fuzzer which basically is the address
sanitizer version of that as well
so the three of them are build or run
continuously giving 135 running away
constantly
what's real problem for us is that the
configuration on their side is with no
dynamic libraries at all
you can find the configuration in that
directory there if you're interested
the what we do there is we reuse that
disabled dynamic loading thing which is
intended for ios
it's a little bit fragile because tar he
manages it effectively and he manages
for ios so when there's ios changes
there there can be
unexpected changes for the fuzzing as
well so new
new components added to ios will end up
getting compiled
on the different configuration forces
fuzz
and it doesn't always succeed uh the
individual photos are still
unfortunately very large
about 300 megs per fuzzer when they
really should be
you know a tent of that as an
individually quite large
uh we don't run with a configuration
layer inside in the footing lens so we
just hard code various defaults
and then you can use that at runtime to
determine whether or not
you are being fuzzing or not whether the
configuration is being avoided and
putting some other kind of default if
anybody else is interested running
forces against us
uh that's the url you can find our seed
corpses for the 65 formats
the 45 file formats are mentioned there
and an edition of 15 from the
document liberation project with the
extra filters that are fuzzed
separately so you have corpses there
which are
not our full collection of file formats
for that file format
but a cut down set of the minimized set
that exercise the most cold pets
without exceeding i don't know it's
about half a megan size or something per
individual case
that's what the oss fuzz website looks
like their documents
their bugs are again private and they
remain private for 60 or 90 days until
after their report after they're fixed
something like that so a lot of these
issues are now publicly available you
can examine them if you wish
but by default they're private for the
first time what's nice i find is that
the minimizer there you can start off
with a large test case
in this case it's not too big 324 bytes
but then it'll minimize it itself down
to the smallest case so you don't have
to
work with a large document when you do
get something reported
so let's see kind of a more recent
actual bug that came in
the original top line is the original
code and then there's a kind of an easy
hack underway at the moment to find
better integer types
so it went from the cell underscore you
long which is
effectively a size t and it was changed
into a size u16 because in colors is a
size u16
but that means then during the shift
operation with the wonderful c plus plus
promotion rules
becomes an int at that point then you
have two signed ins and then you try to
add them together and the numbers are
too large defeating signed ins
and you get this undefined behavior
warning like that
and then at the bottom is a a simple fix
to send it back to an unsigned type
let me get rid of the issue again so
that's the kind of um
the kind of bug you get out from uh
ubison
what complicates things in or says fuzz
is mostly the timeouts and the time of
about 25 seconds at which case at which
point they log bugs saying
your target is slow uh they'll only
report one at a time so you get one
timeout bug per target if you fix the
timeout bug for target you typically get
another timeout bug a couple of days
later for a different issue
so it's a real treadmill um some of the
file formats we seem to have gotten rid
of all of the timeouts because it hasn't
been any reporter for ages so
noel seems to have solved the odf
timeouts for example
uh what's outstanding at the moment is
various timeouts in the doc filter
uh lwp filter the lotus wordpress filter
and a few other ones like that
some of them come and go we're just
barely on the threshold
and we slip below it for a couple of
weeks it disappears and we rise above it
again
and it reappears so how can we help with
the timeout
obviously if we're processing infinite
data you're going to timeout
uh at some stage so they're all
uh there's a dot options file inside
that vcl workbend directory that says
the
maximum input you can deal with normally
it's it's the 64k
some file formats take longer than that
so we slip it 32k
or some number that gets it all in so
you can adjust that
some of the file formats though no
matter how small you
limit the input they have basically
effectively near infinite decompression
abilities you give them
10 bytes and they can generate you know
hundreds and hundreds of megs from that
by just saying you know
putting in an integer and saying that
there's going to be this many zeros
following it
so you have to have some way to limit
that so when we're running under
um the oss fuzz and if that fuzz max
input length which comes from the max
then above is set
then you can say that decompression is
limited to
some arbitrary multiple of that value so
depending on some filters some filters
are 256 times that value sometimes there
are a thousand times
but there is some sealing limit to the
amount of decompression that's allowed
given that the input
and obviously of course sometimes the
timeouts are just reporting that there's
an infinite loop
so here's an example of a true infinite
loop inside one of the file formats
where
there's a chain of properties red each
property tells where the opposite of the
next chain is
so a simple technique that's commonly
used in a lot of the filters
is just to track what places have been
visited already what off sites have
already been visited
so if you've already visited one
particular link in the chain
and then you return to the same link
again then obviously there's something
wrong your loop is corrupt your document
is bust
and you just break and move on that's
the most common um
solution for the real case of the
infinite loops
the one then is out in memories there's
another issue as well as that you're
limited to two gigs
and or you trigger that uh jpeg itself
there's a couple of examples of simple
files that will break right through that
limit
that are perfectly legitimate jpeg files
the jpeg turbo we got some patches into
that but to convince them that we could
um
set and honor the old flag for jpeg
memory which already existed but to
honor it
so that it would you could set some
ceiling for how far
jpeg will allocate similar inside and
calc you can set
max matrix elements for some of the calc
file formats to help limit that
and similarly nutrient calculation
brings things under some kind of control
as well
there are various tips and tricks there
in code for the practical but the most
useful thing is of course is just double
checking
how much data is available uh and
setting and comparing that to what the
headers of
especially the image filters claim the
image is claimed there's a huge graphic
coming up
you can check to see if that's possible
some of the file formats of course are
decompressed so you have to look at
whether or not the decompression
would uh be able to fill in that data so
some of the filters have known max
compression levels you know that if a
gif cannot produce more than that
ratio against its input data so we do
that for a number of the
binary file formats we compare what
their max possible
decompression of the input is and if it
sees that we failed that again so
they have practical real world
implications
yeah so that's the results
for um the amount of reports you've been
getting
so in the last three years we've gotten
basically a thousand of them which is
roughly about one a day but they've all
been front loaded the first two years is
a huge tail off
last year uh we've been adding them
incrementally over those two years every
time
a particular fuzzer was added and began
to not give constant results
we can add in the next fuzzer so it was
kind of kept to that limit we've stopped
adding fuzzers now i think we've got
most things covered
and we're still getting this constant
trickle but it's nowhere near the flood
it was beforehand
and that's it of course anytime anybody
makes any changes to a given
filter they tend to reproduce some
problems as well
so there were some changes yesterday to
the lotus word pro filter
and i can see that i have five or six
new issues reported against that already
so uh yeah it's very dangerous and
fraught to change any of those
kind of hacky binary file filters
right that's what i've got it's the end
is there any questions
does it mean that they
not for us but i think they have their
own they reuse all these for chromium
so i think uh for chromium they have
different platforms that they test
chromin on separately on
but for our case it's it's just it's
just linux that they work on
so yeah all of the stuff you see here is
they they reuse it for their own
software and they just let us
have a little bite at it
okay thank you