so it's 11 so let's start welcome to
March
[Applause]
my name is Thomas brass I work in Red
Hat check in Brno in Czech Republic and
I am a principal software engineer in
the crypto crypto team basically we work
about all the cryptic technologies in
Red Hat Enterprise Linux and also fedora
of course what we'll be discussing today
we start with some motivation we will
talk about crypto policies in general
about custom crypto policies which is a
new addition to this tool and we will
also talk about we will show some
examples of custom crypto policies we
will talk about future a little and
early summary for the motivation
cryptography and cryptanalysis goes
hand-in-hand and basically the evolution
of algorithms and protocols is faster
and faster you can never be sure fully
sure that once you deploy something that
in like next year you it will be secure
enough so you need to accommodate for
the changes here is some example of
change changing technology in terms of
crypto protocols TLS you can see here
how the protocols were when the
protocols were standardized and when
they were insecure that's basically
where they're aligned stop to be full
where they found to be insecure of
course they were insecure from start but
nobody know that so we currently have
still one point two which is fairly
secure still and one point three is new
thing so you have some pretty nice
guides
to set up your web server ssh server
whatever other application how to set up
in so it's very very secure and uses the
up-to-date algorithms and protocols and
so on but these guides here is one of
the example are very very long and you
have to go through then setup change
configuration files so on what if you
need to apply these crypto settings and
changes for the current configuration
regularly to like hundreds of machines
various various kinds of machines on
your on your network and some of them up
virtual machines maybe and containers or
whatever and the other thing to
complicate things even more by Rashmi
various machines usually have different
needs or levels of needs to communicate
with legacy devices various old hardware
Cisco boxes I don't know what you what
you can have on your network click the
course policies came to rescue because
they send our centrally managed on the
system they provide you multiple
pre-designed policy levels and they also
simplify flips support if you care about
it if you are Enterprise want to sell to
US government or related institutions
central what mean what does it mean it's
central managed on the system there is a
single command update crypto policies -
they're set and you provide a level you
want to set on your system it this
single command manage manages
configuration for
all these crypto core crypto libraries
as they're called as we call them and
although some applications on the on the
fedora or rel system is basically all
the core libraries that that are used by
the by the base based system
applications so when the update crypto
policies command runs it transforms a
simple policy definition file into
separate configuration file snippets
that are loaded and or included by the
configuration files of these libraries
or applications let's talk about the
levels that we provide which we are like
kind of pre-designed
the most lenient level is legacy which
provides you 64-bit security about its
it also enables rc4 and three days but
only for some applications for the
applications or libraries where we
decided that it's not longer relevant at
all
it's it's also disabled Fergie's the
default level here are the levels for
fedora actually the default level still
enables TLS 1.0 until at one point one
but disables all the rc4 and the next
policy level which is actually the
default for Red Hat Enterprise Linux
eight enables only TLS 1.2 and it also
requires diffie-hellman parameters to be
larger and two kilobits the same for RSA
and DSA but there was at the time when
when we started
for federate was like not acceptable
because it still broke some websites but
I suppose that in the next release we
will drop or change the default for
fedora as well to this level the future
level is kind of special because it
allows you to test whether your
application or system or whatever is
prepared for some some of the future
changes of course it cannot enable
things that are not implemented in the
libraries but it at least drop support
for 128-bit symmetric ciphers which
basically in this particular part it
will prepare you for post quantum
situation and the fifth policy is
special because it removes support for
all algorithms that are not approved for
phase so and the simplification of the
FIPS mode with the crypto policies is
provided also by having just a single
command that will enable the system FIPS
mode for you because previously for
example on rather than to price linux
seven or older releases you had to
follow a few steps that you would have
to do to enable the system FIPS mode now
we will just promising low current entry
boot so to summarize the system crypto
policies provide central management of
the system by single command that
controls all the core crypto libraries
and applications using crypto there are
multiple parties and pleasure levels
which provide up-to-date security also
communication with legacy systems or
preparation for future and there is a
fifth support
in provided as well and simplification
of it ships moat and emblem and and when
you can where you can get these this
tool on current federal reversions all
the supported for reversions
and rather than the price in book state
but what if the predefined policy levels
don't match your requirements
now custom crypto policies come to
rescue which is a new improvement of
this tool with this feature you can
define your own crypto policies from
scratch or more if you can modify
existing predefined policy levels how to
do that with when you define your full
policy from scratch
you place all the place the full policy
definition file into this one of these
two directories and the file needs to be
named policy that dot Paul with the
uppercase in the name in the file name
is important because otherwise the two
won't recognize it the format of the
file is kind of simple although you of
course have to know the names of the of
the algorithms but as you can see here
you have hash it's a simple like key
equals volume format where most of the
volume values are lists of algorithm
names such as here we can have all the
various hash algorithms
this is actually excerpt from user share
crypto policies policies future pool and
provide as you can see only shot to and
Shari hashes are enabled future policy
here is the setting for key key
exchanges the group this is the group
key again you can see here that these
are Dan bears or the safe crypto cars
and here are normal list curves and
normal deficient
meters of these lines and in future
policy you can see the minimum dealers
version is one point two minimum size of
the RSA keys are three killed kilobits
of course there are other values for
symmetric ciphers signage shrubbery
things other other parameters but you
might probably not want to design your
policy from scratch with full policy
from scratch one of the reasons why not
to do that is because the various crypto
backends have or the the way how the
policy is transformed into the actual
configurations file for the libraries
has some limitations basically the
limitations are due to the way how the
libraries are being configured we did
not like we added some some changes but
we did not try to like really really
arrangement all the configurations for
for all the libraries so so there are
definitely some limitations on what you
can set with one library and
another and for that reason it might be
a good idea to just modify existing
existing policy with with the so-called
policy modifier module these modules
need to be placed into the modules
subdirectory and they have a different
sub suffix P mode again the uppercase in
the name of the module is important so
here will be some examples of the
modifiers for example you can disable
sha-1 hash you just basically apply
these changes to the original policy
that means - sha-1 means remove shaaban
from the list of the hash algorithms
- Parris IPSS sha-1 RSA Chauhan ECDSA
Chauhan remove these signature
algorithms from the list of sign
algorithms in the base policy how to
apply this modifier basically with this
command you append with : no shovin you
append it to the base policy and the
policy will be modified accordingly you
can of course there is no limitation on
if you have a module on which base
policy you apply it can be applied on
any other policy like future but in
future for future policy it has no
effect because there is already the
sha-1 is already disabled there another
example by default camellia is enabled
only for like non TLS applications or
protocols with this plus name of the
other
you add edit to the list of the enabled
algorithms for TLS here
just for there is no problem if you just
if there in the base policy if the
Camellia is already enabled if you edit
again there is no like error or no
problem with that
so it's a good idea to buy to be for
sure that I enable it everywhere I put
it for both TLS and non TLS ciphers the
other option is to put the plus on after
the name of the algorithm we just
changes the order where the algorithms
output because if you put the plus bit
before the name of the algorithm it will
be inserted on the beginning of the list
if you put it at the end of the
algorithm name it will be put lost or
appended to the list you can for example
disable all TLS protocol versions in
legacy policy by these settings there is
a kind of duplication because some of
the back ends of the libraries don't
allow to selectively disable protocol by
protocol and for these back ends there
is the mentalist version or mainly TLS
version for the others you can like
selectively use this list to disable all
the cause you don't want SSS tree by the
way or they like dropped remove disabled
no no no need to disable it anywhere
because it's already dropped from the
libraries here is another example - just
make the future police a little bit more
lenient because by default or most of
the websites have only two k2
it's RSA keys for certificates and so
this is the most probable reason why if
you set future policy you won't be able
to connect on too many websites so you
could adjust your future the future
policy with this modifier and you would
be probably almost possible to use for
future policy for like regular web
browsing or you can only allow for
example ECD edge and ECD edge with
pressure keys this is basically the
situation for open SSL on TLS 1.30
already because it does not support the
f FD h groups on TLS 1.3 and it supports
only forward secrecy enabling changes so
this by this way you just remove all the
remaining algorithms from the key
exchange there is a kind of deficiency
because what would be logical more
logical would be to have the policy
modifier to just set the ECD H and H th
PSK to key exchange but the current
version doesn't support this yeah and
the policy modifiers can be applied like
multiple policy modifiers can be applied
at once so basically you just put all
these one after another
the important thing to understand is
that the the generation of the actual
configuration files for the libraries is
done at the configure time basically
when you run the update crypto policies
script this is important because this
allows for like changing changing things
in new versions of the update crypto
policies for example OpenSSL back and
could allow a more fine-grained
selection of the algorithms because
currently it's kind of simple and or
even new back-end could be added to
support to be supported for example we
can we are planning to have for example
go language support it with a separate
configuration so you would you would not
need to like regenerate your policy
files or whatever you would just by
automatically on the upgrade of the
package the configuration was updated
and so to summarize with custom crypto
policies you can define your crypto
policy from scratch in the way in a
simple policy definition file or you can
modify existing predefined policy levels
by adding or removing enable algorithms
or protocols and the generation of
back-end configurations is done when
objective the policy script is around
the future plans one big thing had is
handling of shavon deprecation this is
one of the reasons why I need why we
need to change
back end for OpenSSL we need to be able
to basically selectively disable shavon
currently this is not possible and yeah
that's basically what I've already
talked about the fine-grain back end
configurations for new TLS is already
improved it was in previous versions if
it was on the more similar ladder to
open SSL and yeah we would like to at
some point to think about data at rest
support but that's much harder topic
currently mostly the crypto policies
affect only the protocol usage for
algorithms in data in transit so quick
summary single command to rule them all
the algorithms and libraries multi
prepare assign codes political levels
custom crypto policies can be created
from scratch by policy modification and
very simple policy definition format
thank you
any questions do these policies also pi2
containers running on the operating
system they would apply to containers
only if you if you inside the container
you have the system with with the the
policies basically if you have federer
inside the container then or or l.a you
will have crypto policies the depends on
your use case
is there any support to distinguish
between client and server connections so
say you're trying to insist that clients
connect to your service with this
particular level but then your service
then has to connect to another service
with a different level so make sense
like it means what legacy system say if
you if you have like multiple systems
gonna like but just between the
connecting client and then say you say
your service has to include connects
another legacy service which has a you
can't control the the crypto you can use
on it yeah can you define a policy for
the incoming connections to be at a high
level say for the clients on the general
internet I don't understand the question
really but basically the policies
applied to this whole system they don't
like selectively apply to servers
clients whatever that they are like kind
of general things to be simple right for
the admin too so so if you have any
questions for your I will answer it
outside
[Applause]
you