so
it's already been said like this talk is
about sharding graphs and how to
query them and because this
uh this talk is only for 20 minutes we
can like we can evaluate all the
all the approaches all the possible
approaches so we are going to focus on
one that we sort of like found very
interesting and feel a very good results
and we implemented that
and that's basically uh splitting uh
your graph your graph database into uh
into these general subgraphs that
basically have no any physical
connections between them
and then introducing basically very
language extensions that will
enable you to easily work with those
with those graphs as if it was one graph
and to make it more interesting
basically we are going to
show this concept on an example and the
example is going to be the
ldbc social network benchmark so
basically
uh ld social network benchmark is a
benchmark that emulates a
social network and it defines the data
set
uh data model and query that are
basically part of that of that benchmark
and
what is interesting about is that the
data set is
the graph is very strongly connected
basically we have a colleague who
is sort of an in-house expert on lbc
benchmark
and when we when we told him like we
want to basically do a
shorted version of dbc benchmark he was
like you are crazy that that can't
perform well
and we sort of prove him wrong so first
like uh before we go into the sharding
let's show the introduction to the lbc
model so we are
in the picture it's a little bit blurry
uh
so basically it's a it's a it's a it's a
social network so
uh you have people and they have some
relationship they basically have a
relationship between them that's
basically the core of every social
network
then uh the main domain uh
workload that people do is basically
post messages
in forums so
you you have you have forums date which
has
which have members and owner and also
basically the main workload is that
uh people put uh posts in those forums
and
uh and also they can comment on the post
and comment on
comments and of course each post and
comment
has an author or they all also can be
liked
by a person
and uh uh there are uh
each uh each forum uh each forum uh post
or uh
comment uh have tag basically
representing its content
uh tag have uh a class uh hierarchy
basically
in hierarchy and people can express
interest in some topics basically saying
i'm interested in
topics marked by those texts
and also people live in cities cities
allocated in
countries and each message meaning post
and comment have also
basically country where they created
from
linked to them
and because like sharding as we learned
is not just like about the data it's
also like about the workload that you
want to
perform so basically you have to when
you want to charge something efficiently
you should look both at your uh at the
data
and also basically what you want to do
with the data so just like example how a
typical ldbc
uh query looks like uh first
in this example it's a query 9 from the
interactive complex category
and given a start person you are looking
for
messages created by friends of that
person or friends of friends
that were and the messages have some
filtering criteria they have to be
uh created before a given date so
basically this query cannot transfer
transfers quite uh
traverses a quite big portion of that
graph
uh yeah so uh the interesting part
so how we just for inspiration how we
decided to
chart shardis model uh
what is interesting about the approach
we took to sharding we basically like
evaluated many
many approaches and this is sort of like
the model we came up with
uh what is interesting about is is that
is asymmetric basically that means that
not all the shards hold uh hold
basically have the same data model data
set we have uh
always one person chart that basically
contains all the
information about the people and
basically the relationship between them
and then we have something that the rest
of the charts are what we called
forum charts basically we distribute
distribute all the
all the forums on the remaining uh
this is a big advantage because the
forums are sort of a forest so
from craft perspective and they don't
have any
interesting relationships between them
so
this is this can be done kind of easily
for some kind using some kind of
easy sharding functions for since modulo
forum id what's also interesting about
this model is that
basically person also sort of is
represented on those forum charts
but they are sort of like not full
representation of the person
it's basically just a node with
person id you can sort of like see it as
a refer
like a proxy note or a reference to that
to that person charlotte actually
contains like the full information about
the given person
and also like for efficiency some of the
data is are replicated like across all
shards which person's the
uh the location structure and the tag
structure
which isn't such a big problem because
the data is a very small part of the
data set
basically like the from the data volume
point of view the
biggest part are the messages and the
forums and that structure
and now when we have the data model
the interesting part like how we can
easily query that and work with that
right so assuming we have our data now
split
over uh some set of disjoint sub graphs
how could we use cipher to to query
across those
so we introduced two new
constructs to cipher
which are use and call subquery
and use quite simply dictates
what graph what subgraph a certain query
part should go to
so the match here will go to the
graph a graph and match only from that
graph
and the use is allowed
for each sort of query part so in a
union for instance you can
uh select two different graphs
and the other construct is the call
subgra subquery
uh clause which
is very similar to calling a procedure
in cipher
uh except it's an inline cipher query
that is the body of the of the call
and like any cipher
clause this call block the subquery gets
executed once per incoming row
so in this case it's gonna get executed
three times each for once for each
value of x as we unwind this list of
three values
and the return
values the return columns of the
of the subquery are then exposed and
available as new variables in the outer
scope
so here we return the number of movies
and then we have access to the number of
movies
variable outside of the subquery
and these can then be combined in
interesting ways
so we can have the use clause of course
to dictate on what
on what subgraph the uh the sub query
should execute against
so in this case we would just go to some
graph a for the duration of this
subquery and then we return to the outer
context
once it's finished executing
and we also have support for correlative
subqueries
meaning that the subquery can
access variables coming from the outer
scope
and we have opted for an explicit
approach here where you need to
specify each parameter that you want to
each variable that you want to access
inside so that looks like this with
x imports the x from the outer scope
and the most powerful
use of call and use together is the
dynamic use lookup so
where you can go to a different sub
graph
depending on data that's coming in so
this is again
sort of a correlated subquery because
you sort of
choose what graph to execute against
based on the value of this graph id
variable so each execution of the
of the inner of the subquery goes to a
different sub graph
right so let's look at this in the
context of
uh one of the ldbc queries how would the
cipher actually look to implement one of
these so
this is interactive complex number six
from the ldbc queries and
it reads like this i've expressed it in
some sort of
pseudocode here so we're given a person
and we're given a tag
we want to find friends and friends of
friends of this person
then we're going to we want to find the
posts made by these friends
that have this tag tag and then
the final result is basically all other
tags of
this set of posts that we have found
okay so how would that look
so we would start with the subquery that
goes to the person chart
uh remember we have the person's uh
network in one chart and then we have
sort of different
forum shards containing the posts and
uh the bulk of the data so we go here we
match
uh persons and
friends of friends uh and then we return
uh just a collection of the friend ids
so now we've
taken care of the friend of friends part
of this query
and then we continue by
going to each of the shards each of the
remaining shards the forum shards
we import this friend ids to each of
them
and we basically reboot the query at
this point
by matching for friends
where the id is in this friend ids
collection so it's sort of a manual uh
passing of data through
to the different parts of the query this
is
um all right and
at the end we do a final global
aggregation
so what we actually need to return is
the
tag name for each of these tags that we
found and then we
aggregate on the we aggregate the post
counts for all of those
so we did a local aggregation first on
each of the shards
and now we do another global aggregation
of those
already sort of summed number of posts
and then finally we limit everything to
20 because that's
what the query expresses
and using this sharding scheme
most of the queries in the ldbc
interactive complex set of queries can
be expressed in
very similar ways this is another
example
where the the first part is quite
similar we again go to the person chart
and find friends of friends
that's a common pattern in these queries
and we then go
to uh the forum charts but this time
performing some other
uh matching and some other
kind of aggregation
all right uh
that's basically all that we have uh
for further reading uh we have a blog
post out
uh about our implementation of this
inside of neo4j the language constructs
are released under the opencypher
project
and those are open sourced the
implementation the engine behind
this sharding scheme is not yet open
sourced
we're hoping that parts of it are going
to get open sourced in the future
right and michael has asked me to say
that
neo4j is currently hiring engineers
in all in all positions
right thank you
for the user to just fire your old query
and the query processor knows how the
graph is started
and then compiles the
simple user query in the extensive
right so the question is couldn't this
uh directing what shard to go to in the
queries be
solved automatically by uh by the system
and yes it could and we're sort of
exploring
things like that but neo4j
is currently schema-less and we're
looking at solutions of introducing
schemas
that would dictate where data lives in
shards
and going that route to eliminate these
sort of annotations of where to find
your data
i'm glad you asked
[Laughter]
uh right so we saw uh what else can you
do with
uh with the fabric uh with this sort of
up so other use cases of course is like
data federation where you might have a
bunch of
already separate databases and
you want to run some sort of analytical
queries
across all of your data across your
let's say you have a microservice
architecture where you have a bunch of
different
neo4j stores that are not connected
you might run queries like this to
to aggregate data across all of them
more questions
good thanks
you