all right let's get started with the
next debate which is
should licenses be designed to advance
general social goals we have
john sullivan molly de blanc james
mazziel josh simmons pedestrino
so i will uh
give the mic to
john sullivan who's going to start
fabulous
all right but i have a mic right i
haven't like it's working is this
working
[Music]
i would hand it to you but it will burn
me if i touch it
let me get my timer
yeah literally
hello everybody i'm john sullivan the
executive director and vice president of
the free
software foundation uh but like the
slide says
what i'm saying here has no relation to
what i actually think
individually or what the fsf thinks i
want to say that in the november issue
of the fsf bulletin newsletter i
actually wrote an article
that starts to try and address some of
these topics so if you're looking for
what i actually think
that's a that's a good place to look but
i very much appreciate this debate
format
i think it helps me understand other
people's feelings perspectives
and positions a lot better it helps me
determine my own positions
and helps improve my critical thinking
and believe me that needs a lot of
improvement
um so with all that in mind molly dash
and
i stand resolved that yes licenses
should be designed to advance
general social goals
we're discussing this topic because
there have been multiple new licenses
written
which are largely in the spirit of free
software and that they allow
much more sharing modification and use
than typical default copyright law
allows
but they also include provisions seeking
to prevent certain harms to society the
environment
humanity and we're not here to
necessarily defend any of the particular
licenses or even
the idea that the best approach is to
tackle these problems through individual
separate licenses
but i want to run down some quick
examples of some of the recent ones and
the harms that they're seeking to
address
kind of set the stage for what we're
talking about
so we have the problem of climate change
which as we know will end the planet
unless we do something
citation needed but sure but look at the
weather outside at fosdem that's not
right
we all know it um the atmosphere license
that lewis mentioned seeks to address
this
by requiring you to divest certain kinds
of
investments and fossil fuels if you want
to use the software
the precondition second of all we have
labor exploitation
the anti-996 license which is immensely
popular i think it's the number two
starred project on github right now
um says you cannot use the software
unless you comply with good labor
standards which do not include forcing
your employees to work 9 a.m to 9 p.m
six days a week
licenses are supposed to ensure that
people have
freedom while using the software but can
we really say that people
being forced to work 72 hours a week
have the freedom necessary to have the
freedom
to modify uh share distributed software
as compared to the people who have power
over them who can in fact use that
software
um to enhance their exploitation over
the people they already had some amount
of control over
we have vaccines uh we have infectious
diseases we know they have caused
you know massive amount of death over
history that's that that's why we have
vaccines and
and why people take them people refusing
to take vaccines
uh cause other people put other people
at risk of dying the vaccine
license says you have to get vaccinated
and make sure that everybody under your
legal control also gets vaccinated
before you can use the software
the final example i have is
militarization that militaries
and police departments are actually
using free software
to violate other people's rights and
kill them that's not good
so various licenses seek to forbid that
specific use
of the software or distribution to
entities
known to engage in that kind of uh
activity
we need we need to be reasonably we need
to be alive and we need to be reasonably
healthy
in order to have any kind of meaningful
freedom when we're interacting with
software if we're dead we don't have
software freedom
uh nor if we're melting or you know
drowning from sea level rise
we also need to be free in other ways in
order to be able to exercise our
software freedom
and we inherited militaries and we need
our police forces to behave ethically in
order to have a democratic society to
begin with
so what we're seeing with these licenses
is that
you know first of all they use the law
to prevent
uh the software from being used directly
for bad things
and second of all they're doing things
to create incentives or leverage to
discourage bad behavior and encourage
good behavior you can't use the software
unless you
act in a certain way which is beneficial
to society
and important for avoiding really
catastrophic kinds of harm
and yes there are other ways to address
these problems there are laws
uh there's economic incentives are
purchasing power boycotts things like
that
but just because there are other tools
doesn't mean we shouldn't use all the
tools that we have available
especially when the consequences are so
extreme
and especially because we can use
multiple things in parallel they don't
compete with each other
and in fact people are turning to
software licenses
because other kinds of tools are not
working or are not working fast enough
and software licenses are something that
individuals have very direct control
over and also make a very clear
statement if you decide not to buy
mcdonald's does not know that i do not
eat at mcdonald's i promise you
that is not sending them any kind of
message but if i put their name and a
software license and they see that then
they know exactly what kind of behavior
you know i or another developer is
objecting to
um and let's remember also the companies
aren't people they don't have individual
rights
uh because they don't have the
accountability that comes with an
individual rights either
and also even when it comes to
individuals we accept certain kinds of
restrictions on our freedom
and the interest of private in the
interest of safety and security you
can't shout fire in a crowded theater
and you can't use my software to destroy
the planet
these licenses indicate that people are
very interested in the ethics
of technology and software things that
are you know at the heart of free
software
so to tell these new ethical hector
hackers to get off our lawn and go read
do that org philosophy is uh not gonna
help
we should encourage their participation
even if we think that it might be
imperfect
and you know maybe if we listen instead
of talk
uh then if we're welcoming these social
goal licenses end up being a stepping
stone
towards traditional free licenses like
some people
argue that creative commons
non-commercial licenses are a way to get
people more accustomed to the idea of
sharing their work more and then
eventually they become more comfortable
enough to use fully free licenses
and you know sure there might be some
problems with this approach the negative
team will tell us all about them
but i don't think these problems will be
world ending or
threatening the planet on a global scale
and i think the problems that we're
talking about actually are
so we better try harder and we should
use licenses to do it
[Applause]
okay all very very persuasive
the first question that i that i have
for you uh draws on a question that came
up a little earlier in the previous
discussion
which is uh how do we handle
shifting norms around ethics
because sometimes ethics shift in a
positive direction sometimes they
regress
and that depends on where you are in the
world as well
if we are to codify ethics and
a license um
how do we how do we make room for the
fact that those things are going to
drift over time
yeah i think that's a fair question but
i don't think it's that much different
from how we
deal with that in our laws you know and
i think that licenses in fact are
are more flexible than many other kinds
of instruments that try to
address ethical questions you know
religious texts foundational
philosophical texts
statutes these things all have to be
revisited and
i think that we've had the benefit of
living with software licenses free
software licenses that have had
great staying power and been around for
a long time but it doesn't necessarily
have to be that way
we could put out a new edition of gpl
over here
that sounds very representative
along those same lines how do we if
if we are to make room for advancing
general social goals through licenses
how do we prevent uh regressive
ethics uh from from entering those
licenses
so what do you mean by regression so
at the license that may be uh given the
culture that it's created in might
restrict uh reproductive autonomy for
instance
well i think that's kind of similar to
the first question and that you know
ethics are
their territory for disagreement and we
have to have ways to
you know have conversations about that
and
on one hand you know licenses there's
other people will not use them unless
they agree with the stances that are
taken there so there's kind of the basic
democracy aspect and then maybe we have
bodies that are responsible for
you know that are end up being trusted
for making decisions about which kinds
of provisions are acceptable and
licenses licenses
and which aren't and the conversations
can happen under their umbrella
so lastly as we pursue more
ethical technology and more just world
which are all lotable goals
how do we uh work against how do we
weigh against the unintended
consequences
knowing that there are projects that are
built on the foundations of the four
freedoms and the open source definition
today
that are making a dent in these problems
how do we how do we know
that uh adding ethics to the licenses
will not uh adversely
detract from those efforts that already
exist
um well we have to i mean that's kind of
the question about keeping them up to
date and revising them
i think thanks i'm so glad to hear that
we're ready for gplv4 i have some ideas
[Laughter]
seven minutes
so it has become uh fashionable to start
this talk with a disclaimer
that you i don't really believe any of
the things i'm about to say
i barely mean these words as they come
out of my mouth you cannot hold me to
them
at any point in time so we've had a lot
of
community discussion over the last few
months
around this question of what is the role
of ethics in licenses
what is the right place to locate ethics
in our community
and nobody up here and probably nobody
in the audience thinks that there is a
reason why we should not have any ethics
at all in the work that we do
and the question really today is just
why would we put them in licenses or why
wouldn't we put them in licenses
and our position on this side of the
stage
is that the licenses are the wrong place
to put
the ethics because there are better
places
and putting the ethics in the licenses
makes your job
harder not easier it's not only less
effective than some of these other ways
of going about it
it's ineffective so let me talk about
that a little bit right
we have all of these licenses right i
know people in this room
really care about licenses but i don't
give a about licenses
i think licenses are kind of stupid i've
spent a lot of time thinking about them
i spent a lot of time working on them
and i regret every second of it
i have wasted years of my life
thinking about the least consequential
end
of the free and open source software
world
right the the magic in the freedom we
get
is not in the freedom it's what we do
with it it's in the collaboration that
we have
it's in the people we meet we talk to we
work with
we get to do things together that are
greater than what we could ever do alone
and it's not because of licenses
we don't really use the licenses
half an hour ago people tried to recite
the four freedoms the people on the
stage tried to recite the four freedoms
it was a lot of
i don't know if i can count that high i
can't recite the four freedoms
i don't know what they are i've read the
licenses
every time i have a question about them
i have to go back to them who here has
actually
read gplv3 all the way through liars
lawyers all of you put your hands down
even if you did read it i bet you just
skimmed it
and i bet you didn't even understand it
because it's not written to be
comprehensible
right
we have these licenses they're like
flags that we wave
we point at them we think they we all
think we know what they mean but they
each mean a different thing
to each of us we have no common
understanding of what they mean because
we never test the damn things
we never take them to court we never
litigate them right even when we do
it's a quagmire that we just want to get
out of as soon as we get in
sorry bradley the whole point of the
license is
when we get involved in them is not that
we're going to use them to change the
world to make everything better
the point of the licenses is to have a
common point around which we can gather
and start working together and what
truly controls the behavior
of the people around the licenses is the
norms in the communities that cohere
around them
when we get together we decide in this
project the gpl means x
in that project the gpl means why
and they're different things right
people disagree about what these
licenses mean and that's okay
because in each community where you want
to participate
you adopt the local definition you adopt
the local norms about all kinds of
things
both what's in the license and what's
not right the the codes of standards of
behavior
the way people are going to interact
with each other just the method of
getting a pull request into a project
those are all norms that aren't in the
license
we enforce those norms by saying if you
want to come play with our community
if you want to access the value the
magic of the collaboration
if you want to be here with us you have
to behave in a certain way
the licenses are not what makes that
happen it's the community that makes
that happen
if you want to enforce ethical norms and
standards of behavior around your
software
the answer is to build strong
communities where there is so much value
in participating in that community as a
first class participant
that you are going to collaborate
alongside with those norms
that is how we have always done license
enforcement
that is how we have always done
community enforcement around codes of
conduct and behavior and
ethics in all sorts of ways that have
that have preceded
the current set of conversations so that
is what we are standing for on this side
of the stage is just that notion
that if you want to do licenses you have
to ground it
in your community we don't enforce the
licenses we don't actually use that text
for anything
nobody understands what that text is and
so we all end up falling back
to this notion of community and it's not
perfect right there's always going to be
places where that's going to end where
your community does not have
the power and the control
but the same is true of the licenses
right most of the time when there's
license violations
nothing ever gets done about it the vast
majority
of software that doesn't comply with the
licenses
we just let it go because the cost of
fighting is so high
because the cost of collaboration is so
low
and so we end up at a place where if you
want
ethical enforcement putting it in the
license is pointless
unless you have the community behind you
putting it in the license is pointless
unless you have a strong community that
is worth participating in
so why put it in the license what do you
get out of it
if you get nothing out of it what does
it cost you it costs you
the rigidity of being stuck with a bunch
of license terms
that might meet the needs of your
community today but might not tomorrow
right when we were working on gpl v3
linus famously said that he couldn't
adopt it even if he wanted to
now i think he didn't really want to but
the point is that he had this large
community of people behind him
and getting all of them to sign off and
moving to v3 was a non-starter
if v2 had included a bunch of ethical
clauses that were no longer relevant to
his community
he stuck with them right so that's the
problem with licenses
they're rigid they're friction once you
start trying to enforce them you're
talking to lawyers
who are not doing you any favors they're
just getting in the way
of actually getting people talking
directly to each other which is where
the community conversation needs to
happen thank you
given that i would given that i was name
checked i would love to do the cross but
i am just the moderator i believe daesh
from the affirmative side will be doing
the cross
thank you bradley um oh am i still up
yes yes thank you james so question you
james are all users of open source
software ethical
yes yes they are all users of open
source exxon
for instance i mean in their use of free
software if they're complying with the
license i think they're doing
they're they're meeting their ethical
obligations comprehensive ethical
obligations
like beyond the license yeah oh no the
license goes as far as
you know what the license covers and is
climate change a good thing
no definitely not is child labor a good
thing
no
if you knew that a company was employing
child labor
would you have standing to do anything
about that
i certainly wouldn't if you if that
company was using software
that you had licensed to them under a
license that
prevents anyone from using the license
software should they employ child labor
would you not have standing then to
enforce that against that company
i don't think i really would have any
ability to do anything about it you know
i'm not a
i'm not a child labor crusader right i
don't have access to
a whole bunch of lawyers at my disposal
who are going to fight that battle for
me
i don't have access to any of the
resources i would need to fully
understand the situation
to even get into that conversation the
notion that i
as a random free software hacker who
happens to have commits in that tree
and the software happens to be used by
this company is going to have the
ability
to even begin legal process let alone
litigate that process through to a
conclusion
that harms them more than them just
saying screw it we'll rewrite your
commits
is farcical right exxon is not going to
say oh
oh james has 300 lines of code in that
tree we'd better listen to him
no they're going to hire some guy to
rewrite those 300 lines and tell me to
go screw off
stories no there's no scenario in the
world in which i become some sort of
effective social
justice crusader for children's rights
because i have a few commits in a tree
it's just it's a it's a it's a power
fantasy that developers have
that their free software is this giant
lever
that can change the world in ways that
it's just not realistic it's just not
any any way that's going to happen so
you should just complicate all the
licenses
for the sake of this fantasy it doesn't
make any sense this is good to back to
you drowning out the questions it's
really small
but no i mean so are you suggesting then
that it only applies
to um software for which you're a small
developer that
indeed if you had developed a piece of
software that exxon could not simply
rewrite your commits out of
that everything that you just said then
would not apply i think it would be
really difficult to find
a developer with that kind of level of
uh
level of contribution certainly i don't
know of any and
and sorry last question how does putting
ethics in licenses make them make your
job harder
[Applause]
the this one because i need two hands
this is molly for the second affirmative
seven minutes seven minutes
um and those mics don't work if you
don't have pockets
uh so i would like to lead off with the
statement that
james made an argument against licenses
in general and i think that's an
important thing to address
because software freedom in the first
place is based on licenses and copyright
in order to make those things happen so
i want to kind of lay the basis to begin
with that we do need
licenses and i think that's a great
place to start
i'd also like to respond to the comments
about the power of developers
so for example the hillary for america
campaign
was using debian for some of their stuff
the international space station uses
debian um
government organizations use debian and
build software off of debian
so if it's the case that that actual
piece of software is that important it's
been in development
for a significant number of years
creating an easy replacement for it
is not so easy um so by a large project
making that adoption
you're creating like a major use case
uh and that's really important um
sorry i'm not quite ready
oh um uh reaching out to communities
uh to encourage building a commons is
possible so
one of the other things is the comment
that like
we're going to need to reach out to new
communities to get them involved and it
is possible right
so you have people who are currently not
developing in this sphere and not
participating
because they're concerned about use so
suddenly
not just talking about definitions of
freedom and openness we're building a
commons that we weren't capable of
building before
five minutes left okay um
[Music]
uh great um in addition to that i would
like to
make some comments in support of what
john had said
um which are noted on my phone
somewhere great no that's not it wow
thanks for your patience everyone this
is not
uh great anyway um let's see what i
remember
um so from the environmental perspective
um i would like to add that we look at
software in terms of one of the ways we
can look at software and environmental
impact
is things like processing speed and
server load
and making significant changes to make
our software more
efficient will have positive
environmental impact
so it's easy to argue that that will be
more effective if you have free and open
source software
but in addition to that you're going to
be able
uh to better reduce that load because
you're going to have
more people focusing on it since it's a
thing that they care about
right um in response to the
concept of military and police use
um so one of the things that happens
should we reach a point where things
like facial
facial recognition technology and
different surveillance technologies are
under free and open licenses
they're going to become better and more
effective and this creates an even
greater threat
from police forces right so if we're
able to build into those
forced ethics it's going to make a
bigger difference
for these individual communities out
there and the people who are already
at risk right in terms of labor
practices
um we see abuse
of labor um all over the world uh
like and and things that limit labor
right so
one example i really like is in saudi
arabia how there's a culture
of women being unable to work especially
with
like without support from their husbands
or their fathers
and by creating licenses that ensure
this sort of behavior
we're creating an opportunity for them
to participate in the creation of these
comments
um i'd like to add that one of the
things people brought up
is the confusion of licenses and the
incompatibility of licenses
right there's nothing to say that you
have to create licenses that are
incompatible
and there's nothing to say that you need
to have 50 different licenses each
addressing a different social issue
i would propose the adoption of a
creative commons-based model
um where there is a base license written
off of which people can add things um
so that would mean that you can have
your no ice claws and you can have
your no child labor clause and you can
have your
equal like equity and equal
participation clause
um how much time do i have okay great um
you can add those clauses
without forcing yourself
to deal with incompatibility in the same
ways right um and i would go as far to
argue that while ethics
change and what society views as ethics
change
the ethics of individual contributors
might not change as much
so they're able to own these decisions
and choose how their software is being
used
but also how their software uh is
affecting the world and having an
impact now i think the like the obvious
question to that
is like what if somebody creates a like
only nazis clause
um and i would like to immediately
address
uh that that sort of problem is
something that
we can deal with uh managing by things
like forking projects
by looking karen's frowning at me
are you sure okay
and making adjustments and building code
and all those other wonderful things
um so uh in general i think there's a
lot of opportunity
to reinforce the good uh that licenses
can do and
like in another like immediate response
um i believe
licenses can have teeth and i believe
that licensing
is really important not just because it
creates an insurance software freedom in
the first place
but because it has impact even when
things like uh employment price like
pressure from employees doesn't work
like let's look at google google fired
people who are doing organizing
for their company obviously like
companies maintain
power right and companies maintain
uh control over our access to things we
need to survive
like health care uh in some countries
sorry i know europe different than the
u.s
salaries which uh for which what enable
us to
buy the things we need so companies will
have more power
uh companies do have more power when
there aren't forced ethics
hit me with your best shot okay so now i
have cross-examination from the negative
side who from the negative side would
like to cross
no i thought you were going to do it no
i'm not i i would like to but i
am the moderator oh god okay three
minutes please i'm ready
all right so you mentioned earlier
that debian could change its license and
force
nasa and everyone else to suddenly adopt
something i'm not sure what but
what are the practical ways that it
could do that how many tens of thousands
of people would it take to get
on board in order to to change debian's
licensing
well i i think you could run a general
resolution
uh to manage that i'm not positive i
should know this
and in which case you'd only need a
significant percentage of a thousand
people
to agree to that decision and then you
cross off some who won't vote
um so i think it's uh possible for
debian to make a decision like that
so so debian can re-license all the
software in debian with
with a vote of the debian people i think
you can re-license a certain amount of
software
these are things i'm not sure about like
these are guesses on my behalf
um but like the project itself has a lot
of power
the individuals in it have a lot of
power and any member of the project can
put forth the general resolution
to make a significant change to the
community so for example
instead of re-licensing the whole
project they could make the decision to
pass a general resolution
that will mean all future packages and
all future work
are required to be under one of these
ethical licenses
if companies already have decided that
they are
avoiding things like copyleft how do you
how do you go about
convincing them to adopt one of these
license that have the ethical clause
that's a really good question um i think
because because companies are afraid of
copyleft and i have lots of stories
about that
um and i'm sure people here have even
more um
but uh when you're looking especially if
we can look at the foundational
technologies
and the things that we're using as the
basis on which we're building everything
then suddenly it matters a lot more
who is putting these requirements onto
things
um now the
well no i won't tell you what question
you should ask me next in response to
that
no please go ahead no no it's good it's
all you all you
so i think my last question really is if
you really
need communities
in order to do this enforcement how does
locking yourself into one rigid
framework around a license
help you when what you really need is
that community power in the first place
that's a really good question i think
one there are social issues
that we need to handle at a time scale
that's a lot shorter
than things that can be um accomplished
by having a community
make enforcement and make social changes
i think we can say with high confidence
that they're terrible people in all
communities
and that social norms aren't being
enforced uh
to change that so by having something
like licenses you are forcing a very
sudden change
now we have the second negative uh
construction that's going to be done by
josh simmons
thank you destructive i'm new to this
debate stuff
okay disclaimer right
let's start with that
so first i want to say that
i think we all share a desire for a more
ethical and just
world i think that is something that we
have broad alignment on
however i am here to persuade you
further that licenses are not the way to
go about this
first i just want to ask the audience a
question how many peop here by show of
hands
think that your code of ethics are
universalizable to everybody everywhere
bold bold
realistically realistically i'm not here
to make an argument for moral
relativism i think that's a sticky
wicket but i do think that ethics are
complicated
and that they're highly localized and
that what's right for us here may not be
right for
people everywhere and
even though there are there's much to be
said about their
the organizations like the united
nations who have definitions of human
rights
which are reasonably universal
i don't know that we can truly trust
these organizations
to maintain those definitions in good
faith
i mean this this is going to be an easy
one who thinks the united nations is a
good thing
yeah right but but how many people feel
good about the efficacy
of the united nations exactly
okay so along those lines uh you know i
also want to note that the united
nations has a has this
this way of governing such that you
could have a single
bad actor a single nation state say
no to a proposal to limit a really
important expansion of rights
thus i don't think that we should hinge
ethics
in licenses on on a united nations or
other body similarly there's the
american civil civil liberties union
or the red cross only one of those
really has opinions about ethics
but both of them do valuable
philanthropic work
however neither of them are an
unalloyed good both of those
organizations
have a history of causing legitimate
harm as well as all the good that
they're doing
i don't think that we can outsource our
ethics because there's no institution
that we can rely on to truly capture
this
now do no harm night do
do no harm style licenses ethical
licenses
we we can't capture all of the ethics in
these licenses and so
i think we would need to outsource them
to organizations and to my earlier point
i don't think there's a single
organization that we can really trust to
do that
further i want to say a little bit about
the unenforceability here
you know there's even people who are
proponents of ethical licenses
concede that these things would be very
very difficult to enforce
can you really legislate these in a
court of law
tbd we really don't know but even if you
could
who would the amount of enforcement
action that's happening today
is practically nil and so using licenses
as a vehicle that just seems like an
ineffective strategy
and then there's the issue of vagueness
you know some
licenses are well crafted most of them
not so much and a lot of these things
leave a lot of room for
uh leave a lot of room for
interpretation
and as far as i understand it
judges don't like it when people are
trying to be clever and if something is
vague and arguable well you're not going
to be able to make a convincing case in
the first place
i also want to note that there is more
than one ethical framework
the most well-trained ethicists
understand that for any
sticky problem we need to bring multiple
ethical frameworks to bear on that issue
in order to really see our way through
it
such that in most cases we need to
approach ethical ethical decisions
on a case-by-case basis it's really not
universalizable
we cannot capture this complexity and a
license
and i want to speak to some of the harms
that people have have noted potential
harms
one of the reasons that we have the four
freedoms and the open source definition
and we have these organizations that
steward licenses generally is to limit
license proliferation
we limit license proliferations that we
can encourage adoption of a standard
that gives us a give us gives us a solid
baseline from which we can build on
to the point about incompat about
compatibility
it may be that we can design a license
that provides a solid foundation and we
can have these additional
uh layers on top of it for you know no
ice or no child labor or
uh nine to six but if we do that
do the components with those different
licenses are those interoperable
i think that's an open question and i
think that's one that we need to answer
before we experiment here
i also want to note that i i think that
this has the potential to drive
down adoption of open source and free
free software
and limit the very real good that's
already happening through things like
humanitarian free and open source
software
we've got sahana and usahidi for
disaster response my myfast initiative
for the unbanked
libre health for health systems in the
developing world water project and open
air quality for detecting pollution
we have projects that are making a
difference in all of these spaces that
people are
raising rightly raising concerns about
the projects that are addressing them
using the existing frameworks
i think that licenses are an ineffective
vehicle
and a vehicle that could cause
unintended consequences
i think the other proposals the other
options that we have on the table
are the ones that we should really be
pursuing now i'm all for an all of the
above approach
we are faced with extraordinarily
massive challenges at this time in our
in our existence we should try all of
the things let's throw the spaghetti at
the wall and figure it out
but i'm of the opinion that even though
we may try with licenses
that is not the right vehicle codes of
conduct
refusing to support accept issues pull
requests from bad actors
refusing to grant use of the project
trademark how
seeking regulation from governments
doing labor organizing so
that we can say no when we're asked to
do something that we know is wrong
thank you
we're going to have cross-examination
from the affirmative who from the
the side's going to do it dash all
righty
um okay so uh first off
um so if if the point
if we shouldn't be enforcing licenses at
all what what are we doing here
i mean specifically in this room in the
legal and policy room at fosdem
i didn't say we shouldn't be enforcing
licenses i think we should have more
enforcement frankly
okay what does it matter if ethics are
localized because aren't licenses
personal to the author shouldn't it only
be a question of whether
the ethics embodied by the license are
those that the author releasing their
work under that license would want them
to be
you know i think every author has a
prerogative to license things the way
they see fit
and i think that's that's right and
proper however
the whole point of ethical licenses as i
understand it
is to move the needle in the world at
large
and so if it's only uh addressing the
concerns of that author but limiting
the possibility for their their software
to be adopted by other people
then they're cutting off their nose
despite their face i'm curious as to
what you think as to why that would be
limiting but i've got some other
questions so i'll proceed
you mentioned the un can the u.n sue you
for something unethical you did
i have no idea i don't think so i
believe the answer is no i didn't
research that but i believe the answer
is no
whereas if a license or had licensed
software to you on ethical terms and you
had breached those would the license or
be able to sue you for that
i believe so presumably yes so it seems
that licenses with ethical licenses then
offer a lever that are larger than
perhaps
these other community pressures and you
know organizations
i will note that though the u.n may not
be able to sue me the u.n does have
uh does have mechanisms for exerting
pressure and
so would you concede then that a bad
actor can be pressured by
positive actors to change their behavior
yes and that's why i made many
alternative proposals okay
and if someone was to kill me for
instance
they could be tried for murder correct
yes so if they could be tried for murder
why would there also be a framework for
my family to bring a wrongful death suit
it seems that you're arguing that if
there's an existing framework for
addressing a problem that
redundant frameworks aren't necessary
i think that grossly mischaracterizes my
argument
okay i'll take that um what would you
like to
would you like to reinstate what you
meant then by saying that there are
better mechanisms than licenses why
can't licenses also exist as a mechanism
to reinforce what already exists to
police ethics
because they are friction they are rigid
they are difficult to change
because there are better mechanisms that
we could uh have
disproportionate impact with
and so you mentioned that licenses are
ineffective how are they ineffective
well let's look at the level of
enforcement action
okay and then i guess finally sorry
i'm trying to struggling with this um
i've got to admire this
so why why why does it that ethics have
to be vague
so uh both teams have agreed to do only
one rebuttal so we can get the question
so we'll have the first uh negative
rebuttal i think is it right yeah
so who let's
i think what this comes down to for us
really
is that the effort you put in
to putting all the stuff in licenses
might
theoretically if a whole bunch of
improbable things happen
eventually result in somebody somewhere
being pressured
to act for the public good and the list
of things you would have to do
that would have to go right is just kind
of
amazingly long and impractical right
you'd have to convince communities
to adopt it and maybe you could do that
that actually seems like there are
definitely some communities that will do
it
i mean there's there's certainly some
free software communities that want to
consign themselves to a relevancy
in one fell swoop i believe that that is
true
then you would have to get knowledge
of a violation understand it well enough
begin some sort of process to address it
have that process fail begin some sort
of enforcement process
have these clauses even recognized
anywhere in the world as
valid and enforced and reach a point
litigate something all the way to a
conclusion
and then try to enforce a judgment
that's a lot of steps
really improbable steps i don't know
many free software projects that have
that many steps it's not a cost-free
process to get there right the notion
that we will get benefit out of this
is all very theoretical very attenuated
and you end up with a rather small
effect out the other end in isolated
instances
but you pay a big cost for that right
every license
bifurcation that splits a community into
two where we've got the same piece of
software being written 20 times for 20
different
ethical license offshoots and none of
them are compatible with each other
because
the climate license says your stuff has
to be climate compatible and the labor
license says your stuff has to be labor
compatible
and those two can't cooperate with each
other right the cost of splitting these
communities
is very high the only reason free
software works so well why it's on the
ascendancy and the way it is
is because we've created this massive
pool of common value that is worth
accessing if you split those into
smaller pools
they become tiny puddles that we can
just hop over
that's not going to work at the end of
the day if you want
ethics if you want ethical use of
technology
you have to do it without the shortcuts
you have to do the organizing
you have to do the community building
there are no cheat codes here
so if you want ethics go back to your
communities and talk to them about
what your community is worth and why it
is worth being in that community
that is how we're going to win this
battle not by writing a bunch of rules
thank you
[Applause]
so we have the final affirmative
rebuttal
because we you agreed that we do we
forego the last rebuttal for audience
remember
you agree to the beginning
[Laughter]
i apologize if you didn't agree okay
feel free to jump in okay go ahead
am i unmuted now yes okay
okay well so the world's gonna end we
know that uh
we really need to try to do something
about this um i understand
and i feel uh it's the concerns for free
software as a model are serious if we
start thinking about adding new things
to it but
um i also think the free software has
succeeded because because it's an
ethical foundation and that's why people
who have
uh when they achieve other social goals
are turning to our free software
licenses to modify them to try to
achieve different goals it's that
ethical foundation that's bringing
people
to it you know it's it's github that
made collaboration tangibly easy
not the four freedoms the four freedoms
the four freedoms are the ethical
foundation and that's why people are
interested in what we're doing
now will these licenses be enforced uh
maybe maybe not but i think they will be
more likely to be enforced than
uh than copyleft licenses for example
because they're embodying
uh things that are very tangible and
immediate harms that people feel very
strongly about
but as we know even if they're not
enforced they still serve a a
strong function i think the argument
about community norms is actually an
argument for
having ethical for having social goals
addressed in license drafting
because that enables different
communities to more concretely define
the ethical reasons and the social
reasons that they're working together
would we have incompatibilities
maybe but remember that people can
release their work under more than one
license at the same time and make them
available for all of the causes that
they care about
we also still have the option of having
an omnibus license
and a body that vets you know different
parts what can be added to that
and really what's the cost of
incompatibility anyway it just means
that someone has to write code
that really they shouldn't have to write
because it's already out there well
that's not as big of a deal as global
warming so i think we can stomach it
um you know and i'm also a little bit
confused because free software is an
ethical value
these things that we're talking about
are ethical values so kind of every
argument against
the rigidity of an ethical value or the
you know ability to come to agreement on
these things to me is an argument also
against free software in general you
know how are we able to agree on any
ethical value why is it
free software alone that gets to be the
rigid ethical value
but not opposing labor exploitation
uh and i think that uh
you know we have laws that are very
complicated to enforce
but they still get enforced and they
still serve a deterrent effect even
though
you can also list all the steps that you
have to go through for a police you know
a police officer to catch somebody
doing something prove it in court not
make any mistakes along the way
not have any appeals succeed like
enforcing any laws a really difficult
thing
we think we can do that with licenses as
well fundamentally we think we need to
try
and specifically we should try in the
drafting stage see what happens we know
a lot of people want these licenses so
adoption
really isn't a concern people have
already asked them for them and they're
already doing them
thank you
so i want to thank both the teams again
for for going their final rebuttals to
have uh to have audience questions
i'm going to ask them that more than any
other debate we've had today this slide
obviously applies um but i'm going to
ask
everyone to stay in character for the
audience questions if you don't mind
because i think it'll be more fun
fontana's going to bring around that's
mike for questions i think
hello hi hi here so
this is the first time i'm asking a
question like that so
uh psychedepoint was mentioned earlier
that
having a policy like say this software
has to be
green or try to improve reduce the
the impact the environmental impact of
the process making things faster
a friend of mine his working in uh
in construction road construction they
say that
if you build more roads there will be
more traffic
so if you make a software faster it will
be used more and more
it's really a very temporary at least
based on that idea very temporary
the opinion is that it's temporary if
you make something faster
if you claim that this software
is used to make things faster or to
improve the
to reduce the let's say the
environmental impact
we are just it's a very temporary fix
i'm sorry do you have a question
that's what i'm saying it's a temporary
fix we are
by playing uh
but is this a question so the opinion if
it's just a comment i'm sorry
we can respond to it and then move on do
you want to respond
yeah sure i mean i think i think the
point one of the points that i think
that you raised is that when we create
tools those tools can also
enable the various behaviors that we
don't want to see happen you build roads
and you're letting traffic happen and i
think that software is a great
um allegory for that you build software
and then people use it to police their
societies to drill oil to do all these
things but that
that because of that that's all the more
reason why it's incumbent upon us
to build these ethical guard rails in
place so that people can develop
software knowing and confidence
that as long as they enforce their
rights in it that it won't be
applied towards these you know means
that you don't want to see happen
um i would like to add to that that
let's say you're building a fundamental
piece of software like an operating
system and you're making it more
efficient
it's way better for people to adopt the
more efficient operating system
than it is to use something that's heavy
clunky and uses a lot of resources
thank you great panel i have a question
do you understand software freedom as
the freedom of the user to choose
how to use the software or is the
freedom of the developer to restrict how
the user uses the software
in that the developer has the ability
to define the purpose that they are
making their work for and the user has
certain rights as well but you know we
have examples all over society
of rules about um users not being you
know there are limits when as soon as
your use of something causes harm to
another person that use can be
restricted
likewise if that heart that uses a
public health risk it can be restricted
and that's where i think the ability
that's where i think the ability
of developers to have some more control
comes in and distributors
no no no no
um i'd like to open up if there are any
women
uh i
i agree uh
it's i don't i don't think that means
i'm conceited conceding
uh to the resolution but i agree with
their response to that
uh i'd like to really quickly just
uh ask if there are any women or
non-binary folks in the room who would
like to ask a question so do you want to
respond
yeah yeah sure while we're waiting for
more hands i would just uh to to follow
up on the response to marco's question i
think that it is definitively if we look
to the four freedoms the freedom of the
user receiving the software and that
is what free software depends on but i
think going back to everything that
lewis so eloquently addressed in the
previous talk
that sometimes you have to decide where
these freedoms need to cave
in order to accomplish other goals that
are just as if not even more pressing
and important and i think that
that's what the core of this discussion
is
very quick addendum we're advocating
putting uh the the items in the license
not in the four freedoms
um yeah well hi um so
first the disclaimer is also for me and
my question is for the affirmative team
over the last
decade or so pretty much all big open
source projects
in addition to having an open source
license have in code of conduct
and everything that depends on
governance and
ethics and describing what is right and
what is wrong in the community
is defined in the code of conduct and
how to handle that
so my question is if it's easy to do all
that in the license
why do we have code of conduct and where
are we all wrong in the last 10 years
that's a very good question that i feel
like i'm the one who's supposed to
respond to it
i would make a few quick points
um which are perhaps that is a place
where we need to
be looking at including in licensing
um codes of conduct uh govern
the behavior of individuals uh and how
they're interacting
um and also tie into a lot of their like
fundamental rights
um so challenging that with a license i
think is a much harder question
like how do we look at what this means
in a legal context especially as the
legal context varies so much country to
country
um i would also kind of add to that that
codes of conduct are like not
always effective so i want to i want to
thank these
uh debaters here of of all the debates i
think this is the
where the people most had to take
positions they don't necessarily agree
with
and i thank them for doing that for the
pedagogical purposes
of this debate thank you
and so so uh we're doing questions
uh brief questions of the whole audience
after each debate since we're not doing
winners
uh by raise of hands how many people
learned something about these issues
in this debate they didn't know about
before they came in
and how many people's minds were on one
side of the issue and now are on the
other after this debate
only one three three okay
but many but it looks like a lot of
people learned something and we're
really glad that you did
uh if the debaters for the next uh
debate could come down here
please