hi everyone
i'm mamini ratzin bazafi and today i
will talk about
the design of high-performance
multi-threading framework
so the multi-threading framework is
implemented in nim
but everything i'm talking about is uh
something that you can also do
in c rest aida
any kind of language and my hope is that
after that talk you will be able to
implement your own multi-threading
framework in a weekend
so let's see how we can do that
so a bit uh of things about myself
uh i've been using nim from uh for three
years now
and i'm a blockchain developer
during the day and a high performance
computing developer
and also data scientists during the
night
you have my twitter and my github
accounts
so how did i start doing a
multi-threading framework from scratch
three years ago i discovered nim i
wanted to do some high performance
computing
in nim and i had two threading models i
could use
one is openmp because nim compiles to c
and you can add openmp annotation to
them
so that makes it very easy to do
parallel for loops
the second shooting model is a simple
thread pool
with just a spawn and a sink
statement and
uh so i used openmp uh for starter on my
multi-trading run
on my uh high performance computing
and tensor library but a year ago
i was dissatisfied with a
lot of the internal including the
threading
[Music]
so i started to re-implement everything
from scratch
and the goal today is as i said
uh end up with a multifading runtime
that you can implement in a weekend
and to go there we need to first
understand the design space
second understand what are hardware and
software multithreading
so definitions use cases parallel api
and the sources of overhead how to
benchmark them
and the design constraint that those
bring
so first thing understanding the design
space
one thing that you hear often is that
concurrency is not parallelism
so here you have a coffee machine over
here two coffee machine
concurrency it's the ability of uh
the hardware no sorry of the os
or the scheduler to switch between
to interleave two threads of execution
on one single resources
in case of a parallel runtime
you have two threads of execution and
two resources
another thing that you will see a lot
is probably one one threading
and one threading and then threading so
this is about
on the left the number of application
thread
and on the right of hardware free
hardware thread
and so this is something that is often
seen
at the os level so when you talk about a
very old os
they had sometimes n1 threading or one
one threading
but this is something that also happens
at the
language or the runtime level
it's just a definitions and we won't see
it again
so the problem is
for multiflora runtime how to schedule
end tasks
on n hardware threads
and another thing on the design space is
latency versus throughput so latency
is for a single task
if you have like m tasks and
you have a single task maybe you want
uh the single task to be fair like first
in
first out so this is what happened when
you have multiple clients
a single server and you are supposed to
serve all your clients let's say a web
page
and you don't want
to clients to spend an hour waiting
until
every everyone else is done or for video
decoding
if you have multiple frame and you need
each frame to be
processed one after the other you need
some fairness so this is optimizing for
latency
the other thing is optimizing for
throughput for example in scientific
simulations you don't care about the
single
computation you want everything the
whole
work package to be done as fast as
possible so
even if the first task waits for one
week
as long as everything is done as fast as
possible that's fine
another design axis is cooperative
versus preemptive
cooperative multi-threading you probably
heard about coroutines
fibers green threads first class
continuations
in scheme for example
the characteristic is that those are
lightweight
and you cannot use hardware threads for
those
second preemptive multi-threading also
p threads used in openmp
tbb or silk if you dive into multifading
runtimes
those are scheduled by the the os
they have easier context switches and
you need synchronization primitives
because those are real threads let's say
so synchronization primitives can be
locks atomics
and also things that are more
less known like transactional memory or
message passing
and you have io tasks and cpu tasks so
io tasks
like uh you're waiting for
network connections and
or files and you create tasks
so those are usually latency optimized
and implemented via async await while
cpu tasks
they are throughput optimized and
the terms that are used usually are
spawn and sync so there is a
parallel let's say between both api it
shows that the internals are completely
different
and the requirements are different the
skills
for maintenance are different the os api
are completely different as well
so for the talk i will focus on cpu
tasks
optimized for throughput on preemptive
scheduling so multiple hardware
offerings
so now we have a bit of definitions and
let's see
the different forms of multi-threading
that exists
at a hardware level we have four kinds
there are many more but the four main
kinds are
ilp instruction level parallelism so
a hardware let's say a cpu
arm or x86 has multiple execution ports
for example to do an addition you have
two or three parts available
they are called 0 5 6 something like
this
and you can schedule multiple
additions in parallel that's done by the
processor
as long as one execution port is free
themed single instruction multiple data
so if you heard about
sse avx or on arm neon for example
those are also called vector
instructions you have an addition and
it works on four floating points at the
same time
sims single instruction multiple thread
so those are gpus basically
and on gpu you have 32
thread for nvidia gpu volts are called a
warp
and they have to do the exact same
instructions
and for example if you do a if branch
on a gpu it will execute both branches
and the last one simultaneous
multi-threading
also called in intel speak hyper
threading
it's a a way to use all the execution
parts
by having uh logical threads uh
sharing the same execution resources
same memory bandwidth
because it's usually quite hard to use
all execution ports at the same time
and it's not always two sibling calls
that are using per trading if you use
xeon phi it's a four
sibling calls that you have now
let's talk about the form of parallelism
that you might want to implement
or support in your runtime first one
data parallelism
easy it's just a parallel for loop if
you use the openmp
or if you used on c plus plus intel tbb
parallel 4 or
on rust rayon that's exactly that
it's the same instruction multiple data
use cases
scientific computing you have vectors
matrices you do a for loop on
all data challenges
uh how to support nested parallelism for
example openmp doesn't really support
nested parallelism and there are other
load balancing challenge so it might
seem surprising but splitting a loop is
for multi-threading is actually complex
because if you split before
entering the loop maybe you might try to
split
a loop in 10 even though the loop is
super small and you don't need to split
it
if you split well i won't enter in the
detail because
but you have free spreading strategies
that you can research if you want to
[Music]
implement data parallelism
the main one task parallelism so this
is uh spawn and sync
it's basically a function call that may
or may not
be executed on another hardware threads
and the may or may not is managed by the
scheduling runtime
an example intel tbb or openmp tasks
since openmp version 3.0
use cases anywhere you want a parallel
function
for example a parallel tree algorithm
like
depth first or breadth first search
divide and conquer algorithm
and there are multiple challenges
the api now most of
the runtimes are using futures
uh in weave and in neem i'm using flovar
to distinguish from io tasks that are
using futures
and cpu tasks that are using flowva it's
just a name
other challenge synchronization
scheduling overhead
and memory management because
you need to save tasks okay five minutes
left
let's go fast we have another
kind of thing data flow parallelism
four names pipeline graph stream
data-driven parallelism
the main thing is you can express
dependencies between
tasks like dependency independency
outs and in-out clauses parallel api
you have i think launch
a thread that may be parallelized
await a wait for a result so this is
for io tasks and we can use uh
sponsoring for
multithreaded tasks data probabilism i
talked about for loops
that are flow parallelism there is no
established api
but you can use either declarative one
where you ex create a flow graph
explicitly before entering a parallel
section
or you can pass a handle like a promise
to set a task ready or not
so sources of overhead and
implementation details
you have scheduling overhead because
switching between tasks is costly and
switching between
a channel when you need to create
threads or destroy them
is costly as well easy solution use a
thread pull
memory overhead you might
if you use the fibonacci tasks it
fibonacci 40 for example we create two
at the power of 40 tasks meaning
trillions of tasks
and you need to deal with memory
management
when there is nothing to do so you will
need
some clever memory management with
memory pools to deal with that
and also on memory pools sometimes you
have one thread that produces all the
tasks and another thread that consumes
everything and you cannot use caching in
that case
so you need to handle that as well i'm
skipping on the cactus stack and
segmented stacks
but it's a complex research
and a go and rust tried and failed
and abandoned cactus stocks and the new
gcc
from three months ago also
is stackless to avoid cactus task issues
load balancing the meat of
the talk let's say
the issue with simple thread pool is
that usually you have one global task
fuel
you dispatch a task to already thread
but
you have a contention issue because uh
this task queue is if you have uh 10
threads that are asking
uh uh give me a task give me a test give
me a task
the task queue will be very
busy and the best way to scale a
parallel program is to share nothing
this is andal's law and it tells you
that if you have 95 percent of your
program that is parallel
the maximum speed up that you can get is
only 20.
so you need to avoid serial parts as
much as possible
and serial sources of sterilizations are
the single task queue
if you have a memory pool that is also
global
and you need to distribute everything on
multiple threads
so one way to do that is to have work
stealing you have multiple worker
one ip everyone has
his own task queue it push and pop
from one end of the queue and when you
run out of tasks
it gets from another worker
a task this way the synchronization
happens only if
the queue is empty
this is a summary of every
uh relate things related to work
stealing and there is
mathematical proof of optimality
asymptotical
optimality which is why almost everyone
except julia is using
work stealing julia is using something
called parallel depth first scheduling
it's also proven optimal but it has a
different
performance profile and hovered profile
it's still in development because it was
released in september and
it's uh you can look into it
uh one thing that you should look into
are memory models
i've given the talk from help center
inside
uh it will if you want to use atomics uh
relaxed atomics
acquire release it's very important to
watch it because it's written nowhere
i'm skipping on load balancing you have
a multiple strategy to
uh share tasks
still one still half adaptative
but i don't have the time to go inside
so the end work stealing in a runtime
in a weekend you need a task data
structure
with a function pointer and a blob for
task
inputs
or closure you need a start stop step
for data parallelism if you want to
express a for loop
press next field for intrusive cues and
dqs
a future pointer to send the result back
to the caller a work ceiling dq with a
head tail filled and push first pop
first and still last
operations and for the api in it
to create your thread pull exit to shut
it on
shut it down and spawn sponsoring to
create tasks
and retrieve their results
some references those are also on the
fosdem website
and that's it so
sorry yes
so uh currently my uh run time is
actually uh
at least as fast or or faster than uh
any other runtimes uh openmp tbb
rayon hpx
julia so really
if you have a challenge on benchmark
speed
i'm ready to take it