we are
a bit behind schedule but um now we come
to our
last lightning talk for today it's omar
akram and he will talk about desk on the
secure cross-platform ipc on the network
please welcome omar aquam
hi
okay so i'll quickly quickly
start and make it quick and make sure
that we end on time
uh my name is omar kram i come from
pakistan
and
well i come from pakistan and i have
been part of the
a core developer team at crossbar io
it's a german company that that kind of
sponsors the development of autobahn
websocket and ramp libraries we also
developed the crossbar
vamp router um recently we are actually
working on developing a
data market that is distributed so that
no single entity controls the data
so we are working with different
companies uh
as part of that project which obviously
should show something in in the next few
months
um i've been part of the ubuntu
community for more than 10 years
and maybe the next month would actually
be
a the 10th year where i become where
when i became the ubuntu community
member officially
and ubuntu kind of sponsored my
trip here as well and uh and finally i
was a q engineer at canonical before the
famous layoff that happened
uh so uh i'll quickly talk about the
wamp protocol itself vamp was initially
defined
as a sub protocol for web sockets
uh the proposition was that because
websocket itself was
end to end and then you have a you have
a server and you have a client
so something that was missing was if if
someone wanted to do remote procedure
calls
or if someone wanted to route that
traffic to other computers they would
have to develop those semantics
themselves
what the vam protocol does is it
introduces
remote procedure calls and publish
subscribe on top of websockets
and it kind of allows you to be able to
write responsive websites with
decoupled services um
so with feedback from implementers we
actually
changed the protocol uh like
in such a way that now any
bi-directional reliable transport could
be used so
it's not really tied to websocket now uh
any other transport could be used maybe
we will be doing
uh transport based on top of quick that
someone was talking today as well
so and all obviously zeroconf is a
technology
that's uh uh that's used for service
discovery and
name resolution on the local network uh
and seems like someone disabled
multicast on this wi-fi network so i had
to
create a hotspot on my own device to be
able to do stuff
uh i'm assuming that's due to making
sure that
the traffic doesn't go crazy and the
routers
are able to sustain that
so i the main thing is this this is the
project that i wanted to talk about this
is called desk on it's your connection
to your uh it's your computer's
connection to different things
uh your computer could be a raspberry pi
it could be your desktop itself
uh in in some cases uh it could be your
mobile phone which is right now for
example my mobile phone is connected to
my computer and it's actually
controlling
uh these slides i'm obviously not
pressing keyboard buttons
there but i'm doing these
rpc calls that are like these procedures
are exposed by my computer and i'm just
pushing them from here
this is not something like a
groundbreaking or this software is not
groundbreaking obviously
many people have done that in the past
as well uh but i just hacked this around
last night so i could do something for
this
um how it started well as most of the
open source projects start it started as
something that i was trying to scratch
my itch like i had some use cases at my
home
i wanted to control the gpio pins
running on an ubuntu core device on my
home
i have this home automation project
which kind of
balances load on in my home uh using
solar power for example
in in the time of 10 am to
4 pm i want to be able to run as much as
load on that
as possible and so
i wrote this thing to be able to control
these gpio pins from a mobile phone or
my computer
for that sense and obviously at a later
stage i wanted i worked in a co-working
space
and one of the a problem that came up
for me was
in some cases you forget to dock your
desktop screen and you move away
and you have this constant fear that
someone might poke into your computer so
what i implemented was i wrote i exposed
an interface from my computer and
hooked it to that diamond and ultimately
it was controlled by my
mobile phone so whenever i stepped away
from my desktop i could actually check
my phone
and that if i forgot to lock it and i
could
actually lock the desktop screen uh
obviously this was
working on most linux distributions i
tested the kubuntu
uh ubuntu and a few others well light dm
was working gdm and a few other display
managers were working quite
fine um and then this thing
um so i think most mostly we know that
if you watch netflix on your mobile
phone when you go to full screen it
automatically raises the brightness of
the device
this is something that was missing for
desktops so i wrote a chrome extension
to be able to do that
a chrome extension would send a request
to the demon running on my desktop it
would raise the brightness
uh well while talking well not talking
direct well it would actually write
those
values to the backlight driver on my
linux based system
so these were some of the use cases that
called me
to write that thing initially it was all
coupled together but
with time given the use cases i kind of
broke it down into different components
so that it could be
reused by different people trying to
implement different use cases or
any scenarios that may come up from them
so
at the core of this technology is a
router it's called crossbar right now
i'm using that router
you could implement something for
discovery obviously i use this python
library python xerocon for discovery so
whenever this server starts on a local
network
it's discoverable by other devices and
you could hook in different clients one
client obviously in this case is my
mobile phone
the other uh could be a raspberry pi or
it could also be my desktop well there
is a client running on my desktop as
well
the cli used to do the pairing you run a
command on your desktop to
generate a key code that then you put in
your mobile phone which actually allows
you to create these devices for security
reasons
and obviously it's cross-platform the
technology that's
being used here pretty much
runs on all platforms uh it works
on windows on linux on mac uh the core
thing the thing that's doing all the
routing
and all the remote procedure calls and
the security layer uh that is cross
platform and then the multicast dns
which i already said
isn't working on this environment but
obviously uh it's pretty mature enough
that apple itself uses its in most of
its devices and
uh many uh many
amazon tablets are also using that uh
well in on linux we have awahe but i'm
not sure if we are using it that much
apart from the printing stack but
uh that is how it is
and okay so i came up with this little
piece of code that i
wrote last night for the most part this
is
what's exposing the functionality on my
desktop this is
talking to you input to
send key events so these are four key
events that i
assigned to different room procedure
rpcs uh
so which i'm calling from here right now
obviously
uh that there is one for stopping and
starting and then there is next and
previous
this is being controlled this is for the
most part sending key events then
the right arrow key the left arrow key
well actually
and the f5 and another key i don't know
which one is that i don't remember it
right now that's page down page up
escape
and uh f5 key okay so this is the
simplest code that that is running on my
computer which is exposing this
functionality
and here is the overall picture of this
thing uh i wanted to do
like this architect of this thing the
diamond itself which is running
uh which is the router is running on my
desktop
i've called it tescon b inspired by lexd
and systemd
the naming obviously um then
there is an android client there is a
chrome extension which is called
bright flicks uh which tries
uh to like race which obviously monitors
netflix.com and whenever it goes full
screen it sends a signal to the
diamond which forwards that signal to
the other component that's running on my
desktop and
that raises the screen brightness and
for my home
use case i already told about the picon
that is also another project that's
sub project of this umbrella project
pycon is your
raspberry pi's connection to things and
right now that component is only
being used to control the gpio pins on
that thing and
which is producing quite a lot of saving
for me
as as it comes to uh using that solar
system in my home
and so this is
snaps obviously since i mostly use
linux-based systems on my computer so
much of this is being shipped as snaps
and they are the first their first class
citizens here
obviously they they simplify application
delivery story very much and due to the
fact that snaps are
uh you can use snapcraft to build
different packages remotely on
on canonical provided servers uh you get
free rbhf
bills that that are very essential for
me to be able to run those
my software and on the raspberry pi
because trying to build something on the
raspberry pi
is a is a resource killer and it also
takes quite a few
hours in some cases to do that so
this service obviously kind of helps me
do that and obviously they are secured
because
you input in itself is very dangerous to
expose to anyone
uh right now i've been talking to the
ubuntu guys to be
able to allow that they haven't allowed
there isn't an interface for you input
to be accessed in a
confined snap because you are talking
directly
uh to slash flash u input which which is
very
a let's say open for
a key in key event
and we cannot afford that because a bad
actor could do lots of different things
that
most of the people wouldn't really want
things
to be and what's next
i the project obviously is hosted on
github i've been doing
active development of this thing for the
last few months uh
well i was quite busy for the last two
three months so the development pace
isn't that fast as it used to be
a while back ago but uh now that uh
i do uh plan to do most of the changes
that i have planned in the next couple
of months so that
uh it's shippable so that many
people in the community could also
contribute to this project so
i invite anyone uh
if there is interest to just clone the
projects
fork them report any bugs if you are
able to run them on your systems and
i'll happily try to fix those and
any questions or anything that's
i try to finish it
and you could contact me
thanks oma for your talk and we still
have two and a half minutes so if
there's someone who wants to ask a quick
question just um
raise your hand and i will bring the
phone microphone to you
nobody okay then thanks again
oh there is one there is
the router where um where does the
router run on
on my pc yes on your pc because that's
where
these apis get exposed
so your route as soon as the router runs
on your pc
uh it sends its name on the local
network
using multicast dns so that other
computers on the network
are able to discover that so that
enables
easy access okay it's for the local
network yes it's
totally around the local network in
future there will be support for remote
access as well like
the router running on your computer will
be able to connect to a remote router
provided by me maybe or you would
also be able to host that and then you
could
do all these calls over the internet as
well there
the technology is there it's just a
matter of doing it
so another one yeah
thanks again
you