all right
we're about to get started um the next
session is by uh
dennis he's from the naturalis museum in
leiden who's leiden yeah in leiden and
he will uh
talk to us about the infrastructure
they've they've built there so uh
enjoy yes hello everyone
um this talk is about something entirely
different about dinosaurs
and let's start with an introduction the
i mean you see
trixx which is an actual t-rex that
lived about
66 million years ago
and she is now one of the main
attractions in our
natural history history museum in leiden
also introducing myself a bit i'm living
and working in leiden as well
um i put it like i identify as a homo
sapiens
a meager 38 years of age
and i moved to leiden to study political
science
and i ended up as a member of the i.t
crowd
at nataralis a couple of them are
sitting over there as well
in my free time i work as a volunteer in
a social center called
freyplatzleiden so if you happen to be
in leiden
please come and visit us or contact me
if you want to organize an open source
event a hackathon or something
and talking about open source i've
i'm an open source enthusiast since ever
since installing
debian for this first time in 2004
already
and i've been coming to frostlam ever
since 2012 so this is my
ninth edition with my first talk here so
that's
quite nice and it's always been really
inspiring overwhelming sometimes and
for sure exhausting experience two days
of talks and talks
and information and as a result
uh the last couple of years we've
applied
all kinds of tools and practices
at nativalis inspired by talks at fosdem
and i think that's also a big part of
the job as
it operator is to actually trying to
determine
the right approach the right tools uh
and how to use them best for your job
and there's a really a lot like uh
because of the 800 talks or something
here at
fosdem
so in this talk i want to present a
kind of a real real world use case
i skip skim through the program and a
lot of
developers are talking about what they
made
for for me for example as an operator
but this is the other perspective um
and i hope it's useful and i like to
give you a glimpse
of the way we dealt with the challenge
of
applying all those wonderful powerful
open source tools
to a um
to a domain that has been
up until recently really fixated on
proprietary solutions
and the goal of this talk is not to try
and paint as if we
have the ideal universal solution or
something
it's just uh i hope it's interesting for
you guys
and girls to see how we managed
with the problems of building a museum
um and we're actually quite proud of
course
of what we achieved with our
implementation but it's
really far from perfect
um and i want to basically
after uh explaining a bit about the use
case
show uh tell me tell a bit more about
the circumstances we had to work in
uh our the approach we took the things
we achieved
the end result and and at the end i'll
have some
closing comments
so what was actually the use case
um we were asked to
deploy and manage an entirely new
natural history
history museum consisting of
10 exhibitions and experiences uh with
all kinds of
technologies like media players
projectors microcontrollers
interactives all that kind of stuff
a campus network
because it was a new building and all
the management tools
around that
and to get a bit of id about the
circumstances
a bit about our institute nataralis
biodiversity center
uh first and foremost we're a uh
the manager of the national natural
history collection
we have 40 million specimens stored in a
big tower
and also a new part of the building
with lots of old artifacts small insects
all elephants anything you can
can think of apart from that we are a
research
institute as well so like we have at
least 100
researchers doing all kinds of research
related to biodiversity and
we're in natural history museum which is
really popular with families and kids
but that poses a really fundamental
challenge for us as a support
organization because
basically the bio diversity in our
institute is kind of the
central theme and basically anything
people can think of what they can do
related to biodiversity they do so and
we
have to support that so building a
museum
having a cloud for researchers doing
their analysis
all that kind of stuff so that is
difficult to do everything
really well
starting the project
at start of the project we uh already
had
quite a bit of technical expertise
in-house so we have
like an it department of 30 35 people
with operators developers support
uh and in the the operators were
relatively
well first in conflict management
already we used
puppet and foreman specifically
for deploying web services
of infrastructure based on openstack and
ceph
we've done some experiments
so to say on kubernetes
we also cancel these
and uh for example with uh uh
an analytics based on senzu the oak
stack graphana
so that's also not normal for a regular
museum doesn't have this
i.t stuff in the netherlands at least
as i mentioned we built a new museum and
what you can see here
is the museum actually being constructed
the part on the left that's the
new part and that's
also the museum part it's completely new
and when actually running the project
this wasn't
ready so we had to start building stuff
when we couldn't actually access the
building
or when we it wasn't even completely
finished
when we started building stuff in the
building
and apart from that we had to work
together
we worked together with an internal
museum department
which was really used to working with
suppliers
that just were fixated on proprietary
solutions
media players all kinds of show
controllers
and in general the museum building
industry if you can call it that
is well on a positive note it's just
starting to be influenced by
best practices from i.t and devops
i put their cattle versus pets it's like
a big question mark for them and they
didn't even consider it's like
everything in the museum is considered
like a
this special special thing and they
basically are used to just making that
thing
and then uh well here you have it and
you
you maintain it or something so
um also in a museum uh
you have to deal with a broad set of
technologies
as i mentioned earlier video players
unity games
in this uh
instance show controllers knx gateways
microcontroller all kinds of stuff
and of course with a tight schedule
also known as no proper time for testing
we used to have a testing phase but
it got squashed
and basically we didn't have any testing
phase
so in similar situations
in other museums basically museum would
hire an external company or
several companies would then build and
deliver
a infrastructure if you're lucky
according you could set requirements as
an internal support
organization and then if you're actually
really lucky
it they would deliver something that
integrates with
the other things you do
so in an effort to keep the diversity of
technologies
that we have to manage to keep that down
and limited
our approach was to actually build on
the existing
infrastructure and know how within the
organization and to get involved really
early in the process
with a bit of a struggle to keep
to get that message across internally uh
yeah so there was quite a bit of
politics
involved but we
we just hold on to our ideas
and as a publicly funded institute i
think that's
also really important and just believing
in the power of free and open source
software
our aim was to use as much
open source components as feasible
and and to combine this with a infras
code and devops practice
so ideally our idea was that basically
every variable that actually determines
the workings of the museum we would have
under control
under version control and have it
managed
that was our ideal to make everything
like deployments repeatable
so quite early in the process we made
this kind of architecture diagram
to make a bit of an overview i'll go
over it
uh quickly
the the basically the issue was that
on the top you see
different groups
these are not the visitors but the users
of the management
or the technical infrastructure so to
say but
also those are a diverse group and on
the bottom
you see let's say an illustration of the
diversity of
all the equipment we had to to manage
the blue line involves quite a bit of
open source management tools i won't go
too into
too much details about those
we use gitlab for version control
metamodes for
kind of chat ops you go for a
documentation
next cloud for content management sends
in prometheus for
monitoring and also we have to use stop
disks
for some reason
and of course in the middle of it all is
ansible awx
it's kind of uh basically the design is
put ansible in the center and make it
like the lingua franca of the of our
automation
and it was this this
diagram didn't really change much during
the
during the project it's kind of filling
in the boxes so it was a
useful overview also to explain to
others in the organization
okay this is roughly what we're going to
build
and also the choice for ansible we
didn't have
too much experience with ansible at the
start of the project
but we have to i'm going to admit
something here
we have worked for a
another museum in in leiden museum
and that was a bit of our guinea pig
testing ground i'm not sure if they're
watching but
now basically we they asked us to help
out with their new exhibition
but there we got involved really late in
the process so basically there was
already a supplier
and he had already installed ubuntu
linux
on computers by hand and then we had to
deploy the applications
so what we did was just make a simple
inventory of all those computers
and with some ansible playbooks we could
actually
manage that part and i think that's an
important feature
although we we couldn't we didn't have
control
on the whole situation we could manage
quite well that
specific thing and ansible allowed us to
do that
it wasn't an or nothing situation
and the choice for ansible also was that
um
it was really the most popular conflict
management tool for
network automation so
the um the promise of being able to
use the same conflict management tool
for basically across the
entire spectrum of the museum and maybe
even the
rest of our infrastructure that was
really appealing for us
so i'm not going to try to get
get give you an impression of how far we
got with that
so starting with deployment we have
the network switches we use cumulus
linux
for uh for the switches so those are
the idea is that you have white box
switches like servers
where you can install linux on the
switches
we use a a process for deploying cumulus
linux
on those switches based on the only boot
loader and said
ztp like zero touch provisioning to get
cumulus linux on those switches
but as you remember we didn't have
access
to the building
and we also didn't have
switches so we started testing on
virtual machines because it's just
debian basically
we could just build the entire campus
network
uh in a virtual environment uh for
computers
so we have small form factor computers
for
all our interactives and media players
we deploy those
with ubuntu metal as a service so we can
based on ansible scripts from awx
we can commission and deploy computers
from scratch
config management so for the
switches we have some base walls
that are shared between all the switches
and then we use template
templating ansible templates for the
spines of the core switches
and for the leaf switches a lot of
vendors have their
specific ansible modules with cumulus
linux we could just use templates
the same for our computers so we have
several base roles like for the intel
all the interactive computers museum
computers and then on top of them
we would deploy
games in basically we all run unity 3d
games because
they don't make anything else
mpv for media players and chromium
based digital signage
but also we do content provisioning
well not on the switches but on the
computers uh
we selected next cloud so we would have
a place for
our content provider software providers
to put the content on
and then with a small script we have
item potent
content updates on the computers
and based on that we do also some kind
of
orchestration workflows for example that
in one
workflow we would configure a network
port
for a specific device in the museum and
then actually deploy
the computer from scratch ubuntu linux
all the the specific role of that
computer the content
of it and at the end of the process you
would have a functioning
thing
but yeah we got started with automation
and then we thought okay we have also
microcontrollers
running arduino so we selected
platform io to actually deploy the
firmware
on the microcontrollers as well so we
typically
would have a computer with an arduino
microcontroller
connected to it mostly usb based
and then basically as part of the
deployment
it would also deploy the specific
firmware
for that setup we
manage uh projectors unfortunately
the suppliers of the projectors don't
have like open firmware or something
like that
on the projectors but also we didn't
implement that
but we did some basics like the network
configuration of those things
sends you checks on it turning
as a part of the workflows turning on
and off the
the projectors when starting an
exhibition stuff like that
and also for example we have a knx
gateway to actually
stop or start the power supply in a
exhibition
stuff like that and we actually did that
by mapping
knx data points or addresses
to ansible hosts so you can use the
groupings in ansible
just like you used to so as you can see
it's already quite a bit of scope and
the nice thing is
we use awx ansible tower
uh to actually delegate this whole
package
to uh to uh
personnel who isn't experienced in all
this automation stuff
so for example turning on the entire
museum
is done from awx by someone who works
for the security
every morning and we can also just
schedule it
redeploy something entirely from scratch
it's six in the morning before the
museum starts we can do that
so and this is kind of the end result so
we have uh
uh this is one of the exhibitions
about geology we have a ice age
exhibition with with games and
and microcontrollers projections based
on mpv
and plenty more
so to wrap to wrap things up
i think in general i think
what we learned at least is that
our specific local circumstances are
really
really vital to for the choices you make
technical and organizational choices we
make
for us uh a kind of
relative simple and first dollar tool is
really ideal for organizations like us
who has to support a really wide range
of services
and also ansible is really
suitable for uh and forgiving
for imperfect environments so you don't
have to
fit your entire world into kind of the
paradigm of the tool uh ansible so like
uh forgiving and simple that it
it can work in an imperfect environment
as well
and of course although we did not
succeed using open source
tools for every aspect of the museum i
think we came pretty far
so to conclude i think dinosaurs
are definitely doomed because even in
the
these kind of challenge challenging
circumstances like
tight schedule a a
sector that's not really uh happy to
change their ways in
proprietary solutions uh
i think our case shows that it's even in
the in those circumstances
possible to give the proverb proverbial
dinosaurs of your industry the boot so
if you want to know more we can have a
chat
there's two more presentations about the
museum
tomorrow i'll give a lightning talk
about our usage of
mpv on monday on
i do a talk on config management camp
i'll go a bit
it's like the sequel of the dinosaurs
are doomed one
and i'll go a bit more into detail about
our workflows
you can come and visit us in the museum
or check out our code
thank you