my name is Vasily Sirocco and I would
like to present you the actors from work
the first question which I wanted to try
for answer for which I want to try to
find is why do we need another framework
because because a lot of frameworks why
another one so just for the cup
intelligence or for new system
components or calling cliffs in clays
are part of user space applications and
they isolated from the code on data of
enclave's is related from that of adding
clips so an N cliff can let's a call
from an cliff can access data allocated
in ring for inside application but
cannot access dated and code inside
another clip and in place are protected
from a text based on physical access by
the use of encryption of physical memory
removes the P rating system and the
hypervisor from the rustic computing
base and offer very interesting features
like local remote attestation and data
sitting in and more Intel offers
intelligence decays this is decay
provides you necessary primitives to
program in claves and they do this in a
very straightforward and easy way so you
can create a function and decorate it in
a special way then compile this function
together is the intelligence SDK and SDK
generates a binary or multiple binaries
of increase and glue code which allows
to start or deploy enclave's and this is
a very intuitive view so is it just an
LPG like manner of programming of in
class however there is a problem to
enter into an cliff you need to perform
something called alcohol so there are
mechanisms for switching between
untrusted and trusted execution
environments and those transitions are
very very slow compared to ordinary
system called
switching between trusted and untrusted
I'm slower and more than 50 times slow
it's only for the beginning and you will
need to leave your enclaved very very
soon because inside and clave you cannot
directly interact with the kernel so if
you want to interact with the kernel or
use the function which is not located
inside a nuclear you need to leave this
in code again 50 times slower for
example you have two threads those two
threads need to pass a critical section
they need to use mutexes mutexes
requires the involvement of the kernel
boss thread needs to leave the in clave
we have more than three 200 times slower
synchronization mechanism compared to
ordinary middle mutexes so it's very
very slow it's a response for this issue
researchers provided several frameworks
frameworks like heavens corn Griffin is
jigs as jig so KL pan apply and maybe
some other so more than five different
frameworks well and they follow same and
different approaches at the same time so
you don't need to leave an end clip if
you can do everything what you need
inside and in clave
so for example you can emulate some
unavailable system calls inside it in
clave and therefore you don't need to
leave them in clay and virus projects
abstract different layers of the
software stack so someone or substract
the leap steve interface another project
abstract the whole deck let's say in the
kernel interface but conceptually
conceptually those frameworks have
problem it's a monolithic design with a
lot of these a very huge drastic
computing base so this is the kind of
irony you wanted to remove the
complicated kernel from the trusted
computing base but to run your legacy
application you anyway put parts of the
kernel inside this trusted environment
so latch GCV is the problem however
there is another way and a single host a
single process can host multiple
enclaves and this is a very interesting
feature of LG's and clips inside the one
memory in the lated environment you can
multiple and in process you can put
multiple enclave's so your program can
consist of multiple mutually distrusted
components located inside different in
claves what can be what application can
be for example you have a message server
like XMPP server and you want to make
group chats you can put a one group chat
inside one and cliff
another group chat another another in
cliff so they will be protected in in
the case of intrusion this date will be
protected obviously and at the same time
since it's the one single service client
or should have a mechanism for to
interact through in place another
example was considered by people from
Microsoft thank you very nice like that
multi-party computation when you have
multiple mutually distrusted binaries
but those binary so bill which belong to
different owners should perform
mathematical function or find the
consensus or make a decision together
without involved without exposing of
internal values in the simple case you
have several in isolated parties each
party has is located inside a link layer
for example this in clave has a secret
value inside and three parties should
perform a mathematical Sun without in
exposing of urban values so for that
again you need to have multiple in place
you need to have a mechanism for
interaction between them and at the same
time it should be one unique application
but not a distributed set of desolated
or distributed set of different
applications and to implement such
applications you need to have a
programming framework and you need to
have necessary system support and I
think the right way is to do this by the
applying of the actor of the conception
of actors because actors conceptually
are not blocking entities and and
therefore and they follow the conception
of no sharing so you don't need to
involve synchronization primitives so
you don't need to leave an end clave you
don't need to develop mechanism for
synchronization is using the
clave so it's very easy so they don't
use logs in conception they're very
lightweight so it's very nice from the
point of view of another problem related
to ethics in claims it's the EPC problem
so there is a problem of paging if the
size of following claves reaches let's
say near ninety two megabytes so Actos
and of course there are many actor based
systems and the problem that they very
heavy
it's very complicated well it's not very
complicated to pork let's say a long VM
into SGX the question is what our head
view you have if you port this so we we
can use but this very high overhead
everyone Java and conceptually those
frameworks are not tailor it for trusted
execution environment so yes you can run
it but they are not you they they don't
use features of in class and let the
reason why I decide that we need to know
different work and I will present it
today so it's a actors is an actor basic
framework as many other factor basic
frameworks to describe it I will answer
three questions what an actor is what is
an actor how the stock to communicate
and what system support the framework
provides this figure shows a general
view of the actor of of the application
of an application written in this
framework so derived several enclaves
wanting to and there are actors they
colored a actor in the notion of an
actor in this framework so there are
four actors and two actors allocated
inside one in Clips there are doctors
located in another clip and there are
workers workers technically are patriots
physical threats that provide execution
context for actors so actors itself a
passive entities and they can act only
if they have
execution context and there are bindings
between actors and enclaves for example
you see two actors inside this in clave
two actors and said this in clave
workers two CPUs it's the CPU a finicky
you can say that this threat will work
will be attached to this CPU that can be
very useful from the point of view of
performance and intimidation and actors
two workers as I said provokers provide
execution context to create this
application you need to have the
framework the source code of your actors
and the XML file that describes the
deployment scenario itself so they'll be
the number one aim of the framework is
to provide the very simple tools which
help you to build a very flexible
application today for example we wanted
to put all actors inside one and cliff
tomorrow let's say you want to have five
different in clips and the switching
between actors between and clips should
be very very easy from the point of view
of the developer and deployment
scenarios are encoded in or store it
inside an XML while you don't need to
fix the source code of your application
if you want to change the deployment the
framework itself generates binary binary
of enclave's so for example we have five
way enclaves the framework you generate
you five different enclave's and each in
clave you have only use it inside this
in clave our source code of factors so
they very lightweight without the
unnecessary code inside and this is a
very simple application so there is a
constructor for an actor so this
constructor initializes usually
initialize communication interface
between other actors and actors this is
the baldy function of the actor so by
definition an actor can interact with
other actors only by messages so
actually what's going on we
you receive or send message and we will
act with this actor reacts if this actor
receives a message Punk from another
actor question number one how the actor
can interact with each other and they
use nodes it's obstruction which
describes it's a fundamental obstruction
for messaging for messaging so it's
technically it's a part of memory and
this part of memory can be trusted
located inside a net wave or can be
untrusted located outside and then cliff
it consists of two components there is a
header and there is a mode so it
suggests there is payload as memory for
data and with hid or header is used to
include and to include multiple nodes
into queues and all notes allocated at
the start so part of the framework the
framework provides API to deal with
those queues of very obvious W at least
with Lea four and five for interfaces
synchronization of nodes are protected
by the use of have very low collision
it's a very very high performance
synchronization mechanism without any
side effects compared without any side
effects and this primitive can be used
by multi producers and multi consumers
so you just have a queue you have set
the factors that can write to this queue
and set of factors that read from this
queue
let's consider an example we have two
actors pig and pork and they're located
inside different you click to send a
message from and travel to the claves to
the first actor should have access to
pool of empty messages and to inbox
obstruction so firstly pink needs to DQ
an empty node from pool right and after
that the first actor will get exclusive
access to this node no one else can read
and write it and even access to refer
somehow then a cliff can that actor can
write that inside decent life side is
known then
no it must be Hewitt internal inbox so
Dayton and by the way can be encrypted
and unencrypted should be including two
end box at the same time the second
actor tries to DQ messages from the same
inbox and look succeed and will get
success it will get exclusive access
again safely read data inside it and
clave decrypt it if it's necessary and
then it needs to read it need it need
return it needs to return use it note
back to the pool so very simple and this
obstruction can be as I said really can
be used by multi producers and multi
consumers but by default communication
are not encrypted so you mean because
because of multiple reasons and the
flavor provides more complicated
abstractions on top of this very simple
interface those abstractions are called
Carcosa connectors and they provide
encrypted again can be encrypted and
unencrypted with absolutely the same
interface so for example today you have
two actors you places those two actors
inside and in clip and obviously you
don't need to use encryption because
because those actors are protected by
geeks itself so therefore you don't need
to spend time to encrypt it but tomorrow
let's say you want to create two
independent in clips put two different
actor in two different in clips and
obviously you need to have a mechanism
for which you encrypt your messages and
Cardosi connectors offer this
abstraction so with the same source code
just by switching one or two source line
of code you can turn your non encrypted
messages into encrypted messages however
of course there are it's not for free so
this interface can be used only by
single producers single consumer
peer-to-peer form but the framework for
mechanisms for remote for local
attestation using the key exchange
procedure so if you have let's say five
enclaves with five different actors and
those actually
have five in the for let's say
independent communication channels the
framework will generate necessary glue
necessary check sounds which will help
you to establish encrypted connections
by the use of local attestation what
what else the framework offers several
system components because you cannot use
well you shouldn't use equals inside and
in clave and therefore you need to use
messages to get access to system
components that are unavailable inside
and click for that the framework offers
system actors and they are untrusted
they are working outside enclaves and
they interact with all other actors by
the messages because it's an actor based
framework so for example and those
actors implement mechanism so that can
be a system call for read for write for
pipe for interaction this pipe read
write to the file system if you want so
it's just mechanism and then you for
example if you want to open the file you
need to send a message this actor will
perform this mechanism of it will open
the file and send back file descriptor
so the same system actor can be
simultaneously used by multiple other
actors because because it doesn't store
it doesn't have a state another thing so
now we can have access to any hardware
from our in case it is the same
interface and but anyway sometimes you
need to have a mechanism to to don't to
store data inside and in cliff is out
share the statements sound a bit strange
I will explain so conceptual actors
cannot have state and cannot have access
to share it entity but at the same time
instead of saying for example have one
message and you need to send this
message to let's say 5 or 10 actors and
this message is absolutely the same
sending five or ten sequential messages
is inefficient so in in actual basic
framework there is a conception of
object store which is not a store as a
share identity so you might consider
object stall as a set of cues a set of
persistent cues where you put data but
into this queue but this data can be
accessed by or ridden by multiple actors
without without any problems so the
framework offers the Oireachtas object
store it's technically it's atomic key
value store it can be private or can be
public so it's not an active entity it's
a set of api's so a set of api's that
can be invoked by actors so any piece of
memory if it has a necessary size can be
turned into object store and actors who
has access to it can read and write to
this talk also this store can be
persistent for example you can map a
file into untrusted memory and turn this
puppet memory into an object store so
you'll have persistence on demand that's
all
regarding the design the question which
i want to show you the answer later is
to show you how to how fast is the
communication primitives because the
original motivation was we want to omit
the use of equals and or cost and for
that we use the synchronous messages are
how how fast are they for that let's
consider two and two actors located
inside different enclave's
and in this case they use equals to
leave an end clave to send the message
to another one and the messages use it
by and unboxers users by two different
written on top of different book so
there is this very simple ping pong pong
example with 1 million messages with
those messages have different size
starting from 16 bytes up to 1 megawatt
half of a megabyte to thread so the
straight one destroy everything is
honest again different threads just the
same actors just different
synchronization mechanism this is the
performance of of the SDK as you can see
it is a pike which is near 32 K it's
exactly size of the first line cache
because when you transfer message from
trusted area to trusted by the use of
all calls there is a Marshall in
mechanism which copies data from one
memory to another and obviously if this
memory fits into the l1 cache this works
very very fast so this is the end of the
cache and it has let's say steady aware
after 128 K and this is the performance
for you actor so much much faster very
fast and because I was using in this
example cargo so as I said you can very
easily to switch from just switch a
cargo from encrypted into non-encrypted
former vice versa this is the
performance for encrypted cards so
encrypted even encrypted cargos
approximately three times faster than
non-encrypted non-encrypted a cold basic
messages and the difference between
non-encrypted cargoes and equals
approximately 30 times so this interface
is very fast and you can write very very
high performance application on top of
this framework sources are available you
can check if you want
there are several examples here with the
template so which which shows an
ordinary hello world application there
are there is a set of virus pi
songs that use encrypted non-encrypted
carbon-based non-character basic
messages also there is Network version
of this fine funk application and there
is a huge set of various forms of local
attestation diffie-hellman and something
else so at least three different pine
points which use different mechanisms to
establish an encrypted connection also
there is an example for secure
multi-party computation it's a secure
assume some the Yocto subject store and
there is an HTTP webserver which
provides ssl connection yes this is
wrong but there is a service prima dot i
BR here should be pre mod it's the title
it's a group site it's a site of our
group and this site is hosted on top of
the framework so it shows how how
exactly you can terminate SSL inside and
in clave and how you can write HTTP
based application on top of this
framework let's talk about future plans
because this project was a kind of
research project it's written in C very
safe language obviously you may ask a
lot of questions about the preak ability
of this framework in general and one of
the primary problem is how to make the
programming language and environment
more let's say more safe so currently
I'm working on the hardening of of of
the framework here will be
instrumentation mechanism provided by
LLVM which will limit a matter of memory
acts that can be accessed by different
actors so we exam this mechanism will
help solve problems related to
uncontrolled access to memory by the C
language mechanisms for partitioning
because the framework provides mechanism
for easy deployment and obviously it
will be nice to have a mechanism to self
deployment or self partitioning of
actors because actors are independent
that they can be splitted without or
partition it without any any
dependencies and problems so this is the
another direction of the work of course
moulting cliff applications so though
the framework was developed to to give a
tool to build such multiwave
applications the HTTP server will be
improved will support multiple domains
and the rest there is additional ideas
related to IOT and currently the
framework relies on the Intel SGX SDK
which is not very good from performance
from security point of view so probably
we will try to remove remove this legacy
so thank you very much questions yes I
cannot give you numbers but conceptually
all the synchronous queues a synchronous
call by AGC SDK this interface they
absolutely I mean conceptual is the same
you have to thread one thread and side
of the clave once a month ready now they
are outside of the clave and there is
Charlotte memory which is used to incur
in DQ a data so it will be the primitive
as a pretty primitive it's near the same
as a permutation
well I cannot compare me switch less
call by calls but
there is no many things that you can
apply so you can use atomic instructions
you can use heart very low collision and
you can use nothing else so maybe two
two approaches or and spin locks so
three different approaches so they near
the same performance actually these
scales differently but conceptually are
the same so you can assume that switch
let's calls mean has near the same
performance yes please
so the question is how local attestation
works I will paraphrase this if you
don't mind so the framework provides
[Music]
primitives to create encrypted channels
by the use of local attestation and
during the compiling files the
environment generates signatures so a
Merlin clave if you know what is it
signatures of each in clave and you need
to have let's say the root of trust so
some one in 12 that includes all marine
claves scientists inside so it's a
sequential process there is a root of
trust with the first and clave dissing
clave has a set of all or maybe subset
of enclave's
or communication channels and then you
establish one two three four five let's
say and sequentially they perform local
attestation so of course it cannot be
very general approach so currently it's
tailored for sequential initialization
of in place and sequential generation of
encrypted channels but this job
significant this environment
significantly reduces the complexity of
this procedure so if you can map your
application to this design so like you
can sequentially establish connections
between several in place yes you can
apply in this framework immediately and
the framework will generate necessary
parts otherwise well bother wise you
will need to
great let's say ye God or something very
initial very very read of root of trust
and this root of trust will establish
connections between different and clave
so this will require you to modify the
framework very very good question the
question is what about namespace inside
it inside the network inside the
framework to distinguish different
actors and I would say no the reason
mechanism there is no mechanism for that
because you are absolutely right so name
discovery so this car or mechanism which
maps that Maps actors to unique names
well would be it's very complicated in
general in distributed systems so in the
framework the reason mechanism for
naming and identification of actors at
the source code level so a tool which a
tool that generates binaries know
something about source code of actors
and their names but there is no
independent mechanism for name
discovering yo your question
I will say that it's a very recent so
this diagram let's say two years old I
would say that each each micro code
update cuts performance they're very
very significant I would say so this is
the problem the question is do it is
this a right way to use messages instead
of equals at the beginning I did not
consider so at some moment for some
applications I thought that the use of
equals is okay but now I don't think so
I still believe that and I see these
numbers that a synchronous interface is
much better
however it has significant drawback
because you cannot stop thread inside
the Dan clave and this trade anyway will
need to leave the enclaves at some
moment so and which means that anyway at
some moment for some reason or due to
the reasons of scalability on any of my
thread will leave them in class or
in some form or call still exist but the
programming model doesn't rely on this
that lets the pot this is important yes
please please
first of all yes distributed problems of
distributed computing applied for this
design absolutely without any except
let's say I also consider this form of
secure multi-party computation is a
mechanism to improve performance exactly
so instead of let's say five different
separate machines like servers located
in different countries which say you
have a platform where you upload your
binary see you there they represent your
original server and in this local in
this local place they can compute much
faster and then go back let's say that
so that's the design in the background
but but of course the problems related
to try I mean the consensus very funny
BFG our raft and other stuff can be
applied and should be of course we don't
solve this and we cannot solve the
setting
firstly you can provide some mechanisms
for some of the mechanism for setting
affinity was exactly for this so when
you want to co-locate your code and data
within the same cone with the same call
and if you want to and if you need a
mechanism for scheduling that this
mechanism also can be implemented at the
assignment level not inside in the
source code
however this not it's not the primary
approach to solve this problem I mean
the problem when you need to leave an in
clave and the best way I found it's not
a part of the framework but you need to
have them let's say at some moment when
you cannot get a message you need to
leave an end clave manually but you do
this for not random but let's say
statically identify a statistically
identified impure interval of time there
is nothing better oh I don't know thank
you
[Applause]