okay hello everyone
so i'm really glad today to be uh in
this new room
which is all about open science and
tools and technologies
and so i'm here to speak about uh
empowering social scientists with web
mining tool
so we will see together what is web
mining and how we can like
teach researchers how to do so and uh
what tool we developed to help them
achieve like amazing tasks
so uh hello everyone i am guillaume
blick aka younger real on the internet
it's a youth mistake and so i am a
research engineer for a
research laboratory uh in french which
is called science pro media lab but i
will talk about that a bit more uh
later so uh what is web mining so who
here
knows about web mining
okay that's nice so then i will skip
so what is web mining just a reminder
for everyone so i will
only talk about web mining as a tool to
be able to like collect data from the
web and afterwards
how we are going to analyze this data
and like produce insights
from this data so basically on a
technical point of view web mining is
actually two or three things
the first thing the first thing being
scraping so what is scraping scraping is
the act of
retro engineering the html of a web page
to be able to
extract back the data that produces the
html page
so for instance here you have an example
which is a page from
the echo js website which is actually
accurate news for
javascript basically and so scraping
would be to like
open your inspector check how the html
has been written to display
this visual page and try to like extract
from the html
the data that we are interested in so
for instance here
it would be the title of the article
shared and the link to the article share
and so on
so this is the first thing scraping so
extracting data from web pages
using uh retro engineering and retro
engineering
and so on so scraping the second thing
web mining is is actually crawling so
crawling is a bit different
here we are going to design a bot or a
spider or a program which is going to
browse the web automatically and that
will like slowly
uh compose a network of pages of site
etc
and we are interesting in two things
what is the actual content
on those pages and what is the network
that's that is drawn by
like this whole navigation on the web
so scraping trolling and the third thing
is actually like
collecting data from apis so nowadays
for instance facebook
or twitter or linkedin share share
some data with you and so we can use and
leverage their apis
to be able to collect data and then gain
some insights
so uh this is it webmining here for the
purpose of the the talk will be scraping
crawling apis so the question is
why is this useful to social sciences
i'm putting social into brackets
because basically it could be useful to
any science i guess so
physics or chemistry also on but since i
am working for social scientists
i will speak from the point of view of
social sciences
so why is this useful to collect data on
the web
so the bad take on this is actually okay
every social sciences data collection is
biased if you do like for instance
questionnaires
or if you do interviews you have biased
data which is mostly due to what we call
the observers paradox
so when you ask people something they
will like be buyers because you are
asking them
the thing and you are in the room
observing them and so on
uh the thing which is really interesting
with internet is that people express
themselves
without being asked to so they are like
just going to express their opinion but
nobody is
observing i know lol because i'm
observing
right now and uh so it's less biased so
web mining would be
a superior source of data for social
sciences because it's not biased so this
is the bad take
the good take on this is that internet
data come with its own biases for
instance if you collect data on google
trends
of course you have like other biases
that you will find
and you should be aware of those biases
and so to be able to control and manage
those new biases
you have to apply media studies and
science and technology studies which is
a
a large field of social sciences which
study those those
issues and so the conclusion the good
take on this is that
web mining is still another very very
interesting and
very large data source so why not
collect it
we should collect it because it's just a
good thing and we can
so yeah the issue here is that web
mining is hard
okay to be able to perform web mining
tasks
to be able to scrape to crawl you need
to know the web and when i say the web i
i say the whole web so you need to know
how dns work http works hdm networks css
work js
the dom ajax ssr csr xpath and so on
you've got a lot of things to know and
learn about the web to be able to like
read through engineer it
so how do you teach researchers and for
instance social
social scientists those web technologies
so basically the same as everyone else
so you could like teach them
css and html and so on and uh
and try to like empower them through uh
the stitching
but what most consider as an easy layer
of technologies i don't know here but
there is a like a misconception in
technologies that says that
the web is actually really easy it's
really not
and we are really standing on the
shoulder of giants that someone here
has already tried to teach someone who
is like new to
the web technologies how the web
actually works
did someone do does this job okay
usually when you do that
you you remember like you notice that
you are standing on a huge mountain of
skills
which is actually really your daunting
so it's not really easy to teach people
about web technologies so
another question here is how to teach
researchers
how to scrape for instance so they know
about what technologies they know a bit
about javascript and python
so how can we empower them and teach
them how to scrape
and then you also have other issues
which are a bit different which has for
instance you are fighting the platforms
and their
apis platforms will try to like prevent
you from
applying scraping and crawling you've
got some legal issues in some countries
in some countries except for example
denmark
like teachers avoid teaching people
scraping because it's considered like a
lux
lock picking for instance it's
considered a bit illegal or gray
and you have to wiggle when you publish
something using scraping because
sometimes you have to say oh no i did
not scribe i had a monkey army clicking
on the button really fast
so you have a lot of hoops to jump
through
and what's more and this is something i
really want to stress today
is that uh jupiterizing uh researchers
is not a solution sometimes we say okay
we are going to empower researchers we
are going to teach them
everything they need to know they are
going to learn python to fighter
web technologies and they are going to
scrape by themselves
this is a really good solution but it's
not really appliable
to the real world so for instance and
what's more in social sciences some
researchers don't have the time no the
will
to learn all those skills and we should
be
okay as a community we should be okay
with that it's okay
researchers don't have to to learn the
skills
and the question then is how are we
going to empower them
all the same and what's more and this is
some
the second point again against the
jupiterization of um
researchers is that web mining is
actually really
really really hard it's really a
craftsmanship basically where mining is
a job
it's not a skill so internet for
instance is a dirty dirty dirty place
so you've got conventions basically so
you are supposed to code a website like
correctly uh cleanly but basically
everything is
really badly implemented and so brothers
to
today are really like heuristical
wonders they have a lot of
routines and programs to make sure that
the the webpage that you send
which is really messy will be read by
the browser correctly
so you you have to know all of those
things when you want to to do web mining
what's more you need to know about like
things which are kind of considered
advanced
in informatics which is for instance how
to multi-thread
a program how to parallelize things how
to throttle your ap
http request and if you don't know how
to do that you will harm
actual people for instance at the
beginning of our journey we did not know
how to throttle http request
so we basically cut all our university's
access to google
which is a bit problematic not too much
and you need to know all about those
kind of stuff which are really
complicated if you want to be able to
actually perform web mining you need to
know a lot of skills
so what i mean here is that it really is
a craftsmanship it really is a
job and you can't expect people to be
researchers and web miners
so the question then is how are we going
to empower researchers all the same
and the answer here is by designing
tools
suited to their research question so we
need to have designers
who is a designer in this room him
yeah so we need more designers
and so how did we do that so i worked
for a laboratory which is called sanspo
media lab
and the seminal idea of the lab was to
like gather
three kind of people so social science
researchers
uh designers such as this guy and
engineers such as me and so we're going
to like mix those people
and we are going to design tools which
are suited to the researchers
questions and work this is basically it
so what i propose here is to uh
to guide you through some of the tools
we designed
to be able to like empower really
empower
social scientists to perform web mining
tasks
and so the first one we did was called
r2.js
so it's a bad pun on r2d2
and the idea here is um was uh was
beginning from the the following thing
if you know about like modern web
technologies you will uh
you will fastly encounter something
which is called like
uh dynamic rendering which means that
the the page is not rendered on the
server
it's rendered on the client using
javascript and so on it's really
complicated
and if you want to emulate them emulate
this to be able to scrape it's kind of
difficult
so the idea was to actually parasite the
web browser to perform some web
mining tasks but i know it's a bit
abstract so i'm going to
try a small demo time so everything will
break
now this is how it works so for instance
let's say you have a researcher who
wants to
scrape this webpage get the whole list
as a csv
table so you're going to go to the page
and then you are going to inject
some parasite code to help you like
scrape the data and provide the
researcher with the data
so i use a bookmarklet which is called
r2
which is loaded directly into the
webpage context
and r2 is going to help me to do some
stuff
fast
it can do some sound which is its most
interesting feature
then i will be able to use like
something like uh
all the old-school jquery
and using like css stuff very basic
stuff
i will be able to scrape data so here
i'm just
attempting to like scrape the data from
the website but directly
within the web pages uh javascript
context
and when i have that i'm also able
to help the researchers
by doing this thing
yes it doesn't work because i don't
know
sorry it's a bad life cutting situation
yeah yeah
yeah and so now i have like the the data
that does not work
so basically i've scripted the thing as
a csv file and i'm now able to provide
it to the researchers
the main point here is that it's still
code but the fact is you can like
use this same code to generate uh
bookmarklets custom bookmarklets
for the the researchers so i it means
that i will go to this kind of interface
i will paste my code here and then i
will create something which is actually
a bookmark for the researchers you just
have to copy
it on its web browser and then it will
only go to this page
click on the button and it will download
the csv form and so
uh for this kind of scenario we have
researchers that like
do some really qualitative search on
website and just want to like
pick some list and aggregate them and so
we use this tool
r2.js to provide them with this kind of
like haddock and tailored bookmarklets
so this is the first thing r2.js
the question here is that can we
which is a bit more hefty so we created
something which is called now
mynet and what is the goal of minot
so the goal of my net is actually to
provide you with some common line tools
which is going to like handle
all the pesky details of web mining for
you so basically all the things which
are in bold
are the thing on which you are going to
focus and work
actually work all the thing which is
around is the thing i handle for you so
you don't have to
so multi-threading multi-processing and
and so on i will do that for you
you you just focus on the fact which is
i want to get for instance one million
page from the web and then extract
the actual content and data for uh for
it
do we have time for a demo
no maybe so so basically mynet is a cli
tool
it's a unix tool which like complied to
the unix philosophy
so it does one thing only one thing well
and this thing is
web mining which is a big hefty thing
but it does it well
and you can like pipe commons and so on
and it looks like
that for instance so basically you are
going to use the common line tune to be
able to
for instance fetch a lot of pages from
the web then scrape
massively and in a parallel parallelize
the fashion
from a lot of web pages you could also
extract
raw content from articles so you can do
like nlp stuff on it
afterwards and so on so it's a really uh
it's it's a
swiss army for web mining which is a
scalable
and which is a lo-fi it doesn't run on
any database it works on csv file
it pipes to the std out and on the pipes
and it's really like
yeah lo-fi uh
and what's more uh the thing which is
really important for us and which is
like
true for r2 and minute is that it's
relocalized data collection on the
researchers computers themselves
sometimes you need a service
but sometimes you don't and it's
important for the researchers to be able
to like control
uh his or her data but by being able to
do this stuff
on his or her computer so they are like
really in in control
and basically in social sciences we
rarely do what we call like big data
tm we don't do this stuff everything
stands and is able to fit in
a single computer
and what's more if you really want to do
some jupiter stuff
and that's all right uh you have a
programmatic api which hides all the
complexity for you so if you want to do
something like
okay i want to fetch 1 million pages
from the internet and i want to do it
right
you can just do a simple for loop and
you will have all this stuff handled for
you
and so then we have seen like how to
enable researcher to scrape
to collect data from apis and so the
question is what's the next step can we
design something which is a bit more
ambitious something which is more like a
gui
and we actually can so for instance in
the lab we are
developing a tool which is called hive
which is a web crawler
which has a dedicated interface which
enables researchers to like
crawl the web crawl a subset of the web
and be able like to make sense of it
without having any kind of
technical and technical knowledge so how
do we enable researchers to crawl the
web
using this tool so hive it looks like
that for instance so you have an
interface
everything is like you push button and
you input things
using the keyboard you don't have to
know how to code you don't have to know
how to program
and you are still able to like crawl
millions of webpage
and be able to like construct build a
corpus
which is a subset of the web on which
you are actually
working on
and so finally we use this design we use
designers actual designers
to be able to serve a robust methodology
which has been proven to work on
mainly like social sociological and
works
and we like we designed the tool to be
able to represent
this kind of methodology
and what's more i just want to emphasize
uh
last time that it's really non-trivial
uh some people have already tried to
like build a crawler and crawl the web
using a spider here to build and program
the spider
is this really easy no so you have to
make some things and like for instance
on this particular interface we had to
like
build our own indexing database to be
able to like index
multi-layered graft and we have a a talk
which was given here like two years ago
if you want to check and it was it was
yeah it's called the trough basically
that's the job
yeah so uh as a conclusion uh my
main point here is that researchers
should not be
expected to like learn uh all the ins
and outs of
web mining and programming and so there
is always a trade-off when you design
tools for them
suited to their needs between
scalability so how much
data they can handle and fetch and
usability so how easy is it to use the
tool and to
to do this kind of stuff so we need to
be able to design
a user path and to do so we need to be
able to take a step back on what we are
doing and take the time to like abstract
or design a path and i hope that's
what we are doing right now so what's
the future
we would like to do a gui for mynet so
the researchers are able to like use it
without
needing to learn the unix command line
and so if anyone is
up for it we need we need people we are
recruiting
also and thank you for listening
[Applause]
yes
i will say to you officially that i do
but
i do not
know basically it's for us it's not an
ethical question it's more of a
technical question because it's really
heavy
for us to like fetch the thing and we
don't know how to do that
very well so we don't but we could
we could do it
yes we use crepey on the hive for
instance
so they but i think the version we use
does not respect the
that tasty yes
yeah we try to use those tools with
researchers a lot so those are basically
tools that um
scrape automatically by learning what
you are trying to extract
it did not very it did not work very
very well we also tried to design our
own tools but failed uh miserably
basically
uh and uh it's something we we are still
interested in but we haven't found
the the thing which really works yet
with
our researchers
yes something about the kind of social
kind of questions that the social
researchers were attacking with these
tools
yeah sure for instance right now we're
working
what yeah so the question is uh is there
an example of a
like actual research project or a
question we are actually using web
mining for
and so uh currently we are working on a
project which is uh
which aims at uh studying how people in
france
share and read medias and so we are
using web mining in a multiple of
fashions for instance we collect all the
articles text from 400 medias
we collect all the tweets mentioning
those urls we collect all the facebook
posts mentioning those urls
and many more so youtube videos
from those media outlets and so on so we
collect a really large
amount of data to be able to see whether
like
media's polarized around political
questions or not etc
yes
okay so for for facebook there is a
trick which is actually uh interesting
which is that
they still need to serve a mob a mobile
application which is heavily used in
india
and in india uh like they can't restrict
it because
else you will like block users so you
can like hit on it
like a madman and it still works it's
not really a good
it's a good option but the fact is they
won't serve you like they actual data
sometimes you have like relative dates
and you need to
parse those relative dates to be able to
find things but it's
usually a good solution to be able to
scrape massively facebook for instance
so we found workarounds and if we don't
find workarounds we use like a proxy
meshes which are able to like hit
from multiple angles fastly
uh not yet it will soon because we need
to
but if you want you can help us
any other question
thank you thanks