so yeah let's welcome him uh
and some core distributed algorithms
all right thanks very much so as you
said my name is greg i work at red hat
as a principal software engineer and
i've been on the sep project for over a
decade now
which at my age is a little scary to
think about um
every time i give a talk in europe
someone tells me that the content they
understood was great but i talked too
fast
so if that happens to you just start
waving wildly and i'll slow down
and i'm happy to take questions during
the presentation if you raise your hand
and
i repeat it and answer back or maybe
i'll tell you that you're three slides
ahead of me and just wait a minute
so i assume you all basically know about
sef but it's a distributed object
storage system
we have three demons although only two
of them are three principal demons
although only two of them mattered today
we have in the middle here the object
storage
daemons or osds which are responsible
for storing data
serving read and write i o to clients
and when
something happens to the cluster that
changes the state making sure that all
the data is located on
all the osds it's supposed to be so we
maintain our replication and durability
guarantees
we have the monitors which keep track of
the other participants in the cluster
they maintain a series of cluster maps
in particular for this talk the osd map
which says
what osd's are part of the cluster and
whether those osc
d's are up or down right now and what
their addresses are and things and then
also
we have a metadata server which today
doesn't matter or for this talk doesn't
matter at all but you know you heard
about
earlier with patrick and jeff and may
hear about later
a radio's cluster generally consists of
three or five monitors and a whole bunch
of osds
working together when we serve rights
out of rados
an application connects to the cluster
which means it goes and talks to the
monitors and says hey what does the
cluster look like i want to talk to it
and they get their osd map and other
other maps describing the state of the
system
they say hey i want to do a read or i
want to do a write to this particular
object foo
and they run our magic crush algorithm
which says which osd
is responsible for serving serving and
processing
operations on on the object foo and
that's called the primary osd
it sends that right operation to the
primary the primary runs a bunch of
validation
to make sure the client is allowed to do
that it does some pre-processing it
sends out replication io
to the other peers or replicas that
share that state and then once the
replicas are replied then it returns to
the client
visually speaking you know one round
trip to the monitor and then we can do a
whole bunch of writes off of that one
round trip to the monitor
and it looks like this
so for the purposes of this talk which
is about stretch clusters and stuff
then this is what we mean we're not
talking about big wide area networks
with hundreds of milliseconds of latency
stretched around the world
we're talking seth is designed for a
local area network it expects
fast interconnects but a thing that has
become more popular or
that we see more and more often and that
occasionally shows up and that people
certainly ask for
is that they'll have two or three data
centers you know
pretty close on dark fiber and so maybe
they have five milliseconds of ping and
fast interconnects
or they're run or they are running in
different available availability zones
inside of an amazon cloud or some other
cloud provider
so we still expect low latency and high
paying but
you are a split into two two or three
data centers or similar things
so the particular risk we're worried
about is that
you might have an asymmetric network
split that's a lot less likely to happen
when you're in a single if you were in a
single data center because you probably
only have one link between each site
and it's become pretty likely that
instead of losing like a single rack at
a time you might lose a whole data
center
and that data center might represent
fully half of the cluster
or certainly a third of it and losing
that much
of a set cluster when it's on a local
area network is possible
because you might lose a whole like
power unit that powers the whole thing
or half the thing but
the ways in which it happens will be
different and you hope it's less likely
so people can destroy stretch can deploy
stretch clusters today
with three data centers you know a very
simple one you probably wouldn't really
do it with two of usds
in each data center but looking like
this or they might do it with
what they ask for although we mostly
don't encourage them to do
is with two data centers and then a
third monito third offsite monitor that
might be in the cloud or a vm just
running
somewhere and the reason that you want
three is because you have
two monitors in one data center and that
data center goes down you can't make any
progress
anything that the monitors are in charge
of they are a paxos consensus-based
system
so making a change to any of the cluster
maps requires more than half the
monitors to agree
if you have three you need two of them
to agree if you have five monitors you
need three of them to agree
so if this happens and you lose your
whole data center then you might have a
surviving data center with all of the
data still available in it
but you only have one monitor it can't
say oh hey there's only one data center
alive so just continue with this one
it requires manual administrator
intervention um
so the big problem well when i was
i i was asked to make this possible
because of some red hat product needs
with
um the openshift computer or openshift
compute storage that
or container storage that we were
talking about last session
so monitors have to elect a leader
that's because they're consensus based
and so
when you send a request to a monitor you
can send it to any of the monitors but
they want to pick
one guy who decides what order the
operations happen in and who maintains
membership and so all updates go to the
leader and then he distributes those
changes out to
the other monitors which are called
peons and i'm talking too fast
okay so a request goes to the monitor
cluster
they if it's a peon or one of the not in
charge monitors they forward it to the
leader
that has some interesting consequences
in that
in during an election everyone talks to
everyone else to try and
to try and pick a leader but once an
election happens the leader talks to all
of its peons but the peons
don't need to talk to each other
and i've written out the algorithm here
i'm going to go through this really
quickly just because i've got a bunch of
pictures that will make it much more
obvious
so an election starts for some reason um
generally either a monitor turns on and
he sends out any start and he joins the
cluster by starting an election
or else some kind of timeout happens
because they have leases over the data
that that they can serve reads off of
and so
for some reason the matter goes i want
to start an election and i'm going to
propose to everybody in the system
that i be that i become the leader in
this new election epoch and we have an
election epoch
to make sure that everyone's on the same
page and that it's not old messages
and then everything after starting an
election is driven by receiving
by receiving messages from from the
other peers
when you receive a propose you can do
three things you can say hey
that monitor is not in the quorum and i
want to help him get in the quorum
so i'm gonna start a new election to
help him join
and i'm gonna do that by sending out
proposals or if this
sender has a is a better candidate for
leader than me and the way
classically that we decide someone's a
better candidate is they have a lower id
number
then we'll defer to them or if the
sender has a higher id than us then
we'll say hey i should be the leader and
we'll bump the epoch and propose again
and then to win if we get a deferral
message from all of our peers we win
if we time out the election but more
than half of the peers including
ourselves have deferred we win
if we time out otherwise we start a new
election so visually we have
three monitors here one two three hurray
um they have numbers zero one and two
and monitor number one says hey i wanna
be the leader
it's epoch one so maybe they just all
turned on and
monitor two gets that proposal and he
says oh well you're a better number than
me
so sure you can be the leader but at the
same time that's happening monitor zero
gets that message and says no
i'm a better number than you are so i'm
going to bump to epoch number two and
proposed to everybody
and so even though one got a dif a
deferral he also got the propose
and he says oh you're better than me
zero and two obviously says you're
better than me
and so that until one and two both refer
to zero and zero becomes the leader and
sends out a victory message
so that works great normally but if you
have a net split
very exciting things happen in this case
you know
they were already together and we just
kind of net split from zero to one
and so monitor one eventually times out
because he's not getting any updates
from monitor zero and he says hey
i'm gonna bump the epoch and propose
that i be the leader and monitor two
gets that message and says oh well sure
you're a better number than me you can
be a leader
and after i think five seconds or
something monitor one
we'll get we'll say hey i won because
number two agreed with me
and so i'm forming a quorum but it's
only two of us it's just monitors one
and two
but meanwhile while that was happening
eventually monitor zero goes hey
i haven't heard back from my peons in a
while and i think i should be the leader
so i better run a new election in case
one of them died and so monitor zero
sends out a propose
also with epoch 3 because he only saw
epoch 2 and bumped it
and monitor 2 says oh hey i got a
monitor that's not in quorum sending me
a proposal
i'd better propose an election to make
sure that they get in from everybody
and so monitor two proposes with epoch 4
that he would be the leader even though
he knows he'll lose later
and monitors 1 and 0 both get that
proposal from two and say hey
you can't be a leader i've got a better
number than you so they propose back
and they try and propose to each other
but they can't because the network's
still broken
and you know monitor two will get one of
their proposals first and agree to them
but then i'll get from the other guy and
go oh no
and this cycle just repeats and so you
never ever get a working quorum
because the monitors are trying to elect
a leader and keep one stable
so this was the first problem that we
identified when i was asked to make
stretch clusters work
and we came up with a plan the first
thing part of the plan was make it
possible to change the code at all
the election code in seph is some of the
oldest code in the system it's from
like 2004 written by grad students and
if you've
ever read grad student code it can be
really exciting
you know we were pretty confident in it
because it had been stable for a long
time and we run a lot of tests where we
do things to the system
and it didn't break um but we actually
just saw a new bug like a month and a
half ago that was from this and that the
other people assumed was from some of my
earlier changes in regression and it
wasn't
so there were some issues um and and one
of the things that made it particularly
difficult was that
the code mixed message passing from
monitor a to b
and the election logic about what to do
with those messages in the same
functions
um and that made it hard to test and
hard to update
and in particular i wanted to maintain
multiple
strategies for running elections i
wanted to maintain the classic one we've
been using
and the new one that i'm about to talk
about and so i decided to split that up
into
a new election logic function or sorry a
new election logic class which would
decide what to do
when you say we got to propose and the
message passing elector class that we
already had
and then once i made that split i also
wrote unit tests for the election logic
class
which was very exciting for me um
because you know if you want to test
this
in a lab we need to set like we have a
big lab we can use for testing
but it still needs to run for tens tens
of minutes or several hours and
it's hard to like create specific
scenarios whereas in unit tests i can
just poke it directly at the code and
run it and it all runs in line in one
process and we do time step advancement
and it does what i want
and that made it a lot easier to work
with it made it easier to iterate an
experiment when i designed an algorithm
because it turns out that i designed an
algorithm and like the core idea was
fine
but i needed a bunch of new invariants
that were always true
when you're just going by id numbers but
that you need to make true when you're
using more complicated systems
so here's an example of my unit tests of
the unit tests i ended up building
this one is just a demonstration of that
thing i showed you graphically before
we we the call the function is called
blocked connection continues election
um and then we pass in an election
strategy
so we might pass in the election
strategy classic which is what i named
the old one that i talked about
and then we create an election class and
this one has
five electors or fake monitors in it and
we give it the
strategy which is usually classic and
then we say hey
we're going to block messages between
monitors zero and one and then we're
going to turn all the monitors on and
have them start going
and then we do this run timestamps
function and this calls into the test
harness
and it says hey like i want you to
advance up to 100 time steps
a time step is the amount of time or
when it advances the time step it like
calls to every elector and says hey you
get to advance one time step
and so and they process their incoming
messages and then can cue up outgoing
messages and so
delivering a message is a one-time step
process
um and if the and it'll run up to 100
because
if everything it becomes stable then
it'll stop advancing time steps if
there's
if the electors have no timers waiting
for something to time out and if they
don't have any messages pending
and then here we have a bunch of
assertions so we have this test for is
the election stable
meaning that there are no timers if an
election is stable there are no timers
or messages queued
and since in this one we blocked the
messages we expect that they can't
resolve so it will not be stable
election
and we will expect that the quorum has
changed recently um
so by recently i doubled the number of
of timer steps that's how long
a timer less because it takes two it
takes two time steps for a rapture
message
so things time out after three time
steps and i just doubled that
for how long the quorum can take without
changing
and so we say hey it didn't finish
but then we unblock the messaging
between them
and then we run forward it for more time
and and we expect that once the there's
no net split
everything works and indeed it does we
have a few extra
assertions i check here that we want to
be really sure that all the leaders
or that all the monitors agree who the
leader is i can't imagine how they
wouldn't but
if they somehow managed to segregate
into different groups or one of them
like
lied or then that would be bad
in particular you know you might have a
thing where well one of them might
have have a logic bug and and agree to
two different
monitors in the same election or who who
both take that or something
um and that would be bad and then we
also check that they all agree on what
the epoch is
because if they're all agreeing the
leader but some of them think the epoch
is 10 steps behind the others
something went wrong test harness is
about 500 lines
this is one of the simpler tests in
particular this one you know
this passes on the classic strategy but
once i fix that split
net splits like blocking progress then
this fails so i don't run this on my new
strategy
and my new strategy is called the
connectivity strategy
and i said hey we want the most
connected monitor to win
so we're going to run heartbeats between
all the monitors
and try and maintain a and try and
figure out like how stable they are
and and generate scores for them and
these scores are for every connection
between ever pairwise these scores are
this connection is alive
and a number representing how alive we
it has been
over the past time period um we have a
it's not quite the right formula but we
have a half-life of 12 hours by default
and we will ping every two seconds or i
think every second
um and assuming that ping comes back
within a two second period then we say
the connection is alive
and it has been alive since the last
time we got a ping and so we increased
the score
otherwise we decrease the score and mark
the connection is down
and those scores are and so a monitor
maintains scores for all its peers but
they also widely share those scores
so i as monitor zero know exactly what
the current scores are from me to
everyone else
and i have a slightly out of date view
of what monitor one thinks
the scores are and what monitor one is
seen from everyone else
and then when we get a proposed message
instead of looking at the id number
we look at the total score and the one
with the higher connectivity score wins
and then we still tie break based off of
id number but that's not super likely
once anything has died we can also
specify that monitors are disallowed
so if you have two data centers that are
close to each other and a tiebreaker
monitor far away
you don't really want everything to have
to go
through out to the tiebreaker monitor
who might be hundreds of milliseconds
away so we say he's disallowed
his only job is to pick one data center
to win
and there's a lot of nuance to that but
that's basically the idea there's a pull
request up for this now
um and visually speaking
you know we got our three monitors
they're pinging each other happily
and they're maintaining i've just got
their local scores here but everyone
says everyone's up and they have a score
of one
if we net split then after a while zero
and one both say that the other person
is down
and they've decreased their scores but
monitor two can still talk to everyone
and he says that and and so the monitor
two scores for everyone else are still
high
and everyone scores from honor two are
high so after a timeout period
um monitors zero and one both will
propose to
monitor two because they can't talk to
each other and monitor two gets those
gets those proposals and runs the number
and says hey i got a better score than
you guys do
so i'm going to propose that i'd be the
leader in epoch 4.
and both of those guys say yes i agree
you have a better score than me you can
be the leader
and then monitor 2 wins
but if you then go on to disallow
monitor two and i don't remember if
disallowing will cause an election but
we
but you know we were running before and
then we said oh i don't want monitor two
to be in charge
so we disallow monitor two and a new
election happens and
if one or one or zero proposed to
monitor two then monitor two will say
hey
i am not allowed to be the leader and so
um what it actually does is if you're
disallowed you just have a score of zero
um but he'll say oh well monitors one
and zero both have the same score
but i'm gonna pick one of them and
monitor zero is the one i'm gonna pick
because
he's got the lower id number and there
was a tie
normally there probably wouldn't
actually be a tie just because of timing
and so
one of them would win randomly but
whatever
and then after the timeout period
monitor zero says hey i won
i have a quorum of zero and two
keep in mind though that while that's
happening even though the quorum is zero
and two
one and two are still happily pinging
back and forth and they're and
maintaining
and changing scores and those scores are
being propagated back out to the world
back to the other monitors through the
working connections um
and monitor one is also like i want i'm
running i want to be in a quorum i'm
going to propose to everyone i can see
so we can send out those proposed
messages um
but monitor and one but but in this
strategy when monitor one rece or when
monitor two
receives a proposed message from from an
outer quorum peer
he says oh you are out of quorum and um
he'll like run a test and he'll say oh
well if you're in
if i to run an election right now i
would vote for which guy
and if he would vote for the current
leader or sorry if he would vote for the
same guy he voted for last time then
he'll just ignore the proposal
if it would change it then he might
respond to one or bump up
and say hey i want a new election um but
in this case he just says nope
you're not like you setting a proposed
would not change the outcome of where we
are right now so i'm just dropping you
um that
question so what happens if instead of
the cards there is an overload
so if the link the question is what
happens if you have an overloaded link
with highlight into your packet loss
and but not a full break often an
overloaded link with high latency or
packet loss will look too ceph like a
completely dead link
just because of the amount of traffic we
shove through it so
if if it keeps serving all the all the
messages quickly enough
then it might then it might stay and and
we'll have a problem
but eventually we would expect it to get
expect that link to get backed up
and the pings will stop happening and
the pings will stop happening
or the pings will stop being replied too
quickly enough and so
um things and so the clock will
migrate workloads well the monitors will
migrate away from letting that one be
the leader
and they'll start you'll start getting
failure reports from osds and
monitors and stuff so if you have a
partial failure
stuff will have a partial detection and
it may be slow for a while but
it's a better state than where we are
now um anyway
going back to the unit testing now that
i have this cool connectivity strategy
we want to test it and and so instead of
testing it in the real world
we can just set it up to look the way we
want to
so i have the strategy here where um the
connection tracker
is the thing that keeps is the thing
that keeps track of all the scores that
everyone sees
and then a connection report is i
monitor zero
have these scores for monitors for
myself and one and two
and so that's one in connection trackers
all of them so we're getting so we're
grabbing out a connection report
and directly editing the history as the
score
and i guess i didn't change the liveness
and bumping up the version
so that this propagates and we can do
this to a bunch of them
and then i disable the pinging between
monitors and what that means is that
those well they'll stop sending the ping
messages so they will not change the
scores away from 0.5 so i know exactly
what the scores are
and the only time the um these scores
propagate is when they send a less
is when they send election messages to
each other
all right yep and then i run forward
some
forward in time with the start on and
run the time steps
and then i make sure hey we resolved a
score even though or we resolved on a
leader
and that leader is stable and the quorum
is stable even though they had
disagreeing scores for what each other
were
um and we checked that the leaders agree
and the epochs agree
so that's sort of like that's an example
of what i like to test
so with those changes the monitors are
happy and mult in multi-site
you can have them in a cluster they deal
with net splits
they can deal with you know dropping
half one of the data centers if we need
to for some other reason like
perhaps because of what we're doing with
the osds
so when a cluster changes in the os
when an osd comes up or down or
something about the cluster map changes
the osds look at that change and they
say hey do i have any data i'm
responsible for now
that someone else is supposed to be
responsible for and if that's the case
they they send out a note a notification
saying hey you're supposed to be primary
for this piece of data now and when you
find out your primary
then you need to make sure you have the
newest version of the data
and that means going through the osd
maps and
finding the old peers who might have
data that you don't
and then you query those peers and ask
what version they have and then
if they have newer data you ask for the
update logs and you ask for the updates
um graphically speaking let's say we
have here in this case we have two osds
and the one on the left
just rebooted or something so he's got
version whoops so he's got version five
of the data and
and then and then the one on the right
has version eight um so he asks for the
version and he gets it back
and he still knows that he's got the
that he's got version five with with
content a but he knows there's newer
updates
and then he asks for the updates and
says what are they um
probably what this is is this is a
collection of objects and so he's asking
for which objects changed
and he gets back oh it's these ones
and then he says hey send me the new
data um and
like this is a series of messages
because we don't want anything to be too
large so you might get two at a time
and then nobody has one left and then he
asks for it again and he gets it back
um to get through it's objects make
sense
generally speaking okay so that's a real
simple example
in real life we generally have three
copies of all the data
i'm not putting that on the screen
because it's harder to draw and
harder to show the problems
and so we have three copies of all the
data but we generally have a minimum
size required to go active to serve any
reads or writes on the data
of two and the reason for that is that
we're a very consistent system
we notice if we aren't consistent we
notice if we might be inconsistent
and in particular if we go active with
one osd
holding the data and we accept a right
and then that osc goes away
we've lost data and we can't get it back
and if you are running a system with
three copies and we tell you that one
osd died and now you've lost all your
data and
now you can't access your block device
you're going to be really angry at us
now and the way this works is that the
osd's know the specific version that
everything's at
we don't want anyone else to know the
exact versions they're at because that
would mean
talking to them on every update um but
the ocs are the exact version they're at
and the monitors know that updates were
allowed the reason
like we do work to make sure that's the
case and the reason for that
is that when someone becomes a new
primary they need to know who to go ask
for the data
and so before and so the osds report
into the monitors hey
i am like going to going to go active
and so
mark down that i'm allowed to make
changes
and this is one of the things that we do
just to make sure that we can stay
absolutely consistent and so we know who
to talk to
so if we have a two main data centers
and one
off-site tiebreaker monitor model and
this is a really simplified
version of it obviously but the problem
exists even with more complicated setups
so let's say we have data center one on
the left and data center two on the
right
and osc 1.0 1.1 and 2.0 and 2.1
and they're only appearing straight
across for whatever reason
then they might all you know your
cluster's running and everyone's at
version 8.
but then we lose osd 2.0
and you know life is sad but hey we
still have osd one
and so he can keep on serving the rights
and everyone can keep making progress
but now we've lost data center one and
the
and so that's bad because you know osd
1.0 had
the newest version of some data that no
one else had and in particular
maybe we get osd 2.0 back
but we still can't go active and serve
reads and writes because he knows
oh like osd one went active
he he probably did some i o and is it a
newer version than me
and so even though you had this thing
you built it for for
fail for like data center lost tolerance
it no longer has tolerated
data center loss because of just one bad
osd that wasn't up to date
and that makes everybody sad
and you know there are systems where
this is okay there are storage systems
where if you
do that to the system it just won't even
notice that you went back in time
and maybe your application won't notice
either and maybe you won't notice either
but maybe your application does notice
and things go horribly horribly wrong
so we don't let that happen um and
you know the example i've given you is a
toy example but it's not super unlikely
that you have you know
dozens of osd's and one of them rebooted
because
you know a server you were updating a
server software or you're you were like
upgrading ceph and so one osd was
rebooting
and it was continuing to process data in
the other data center
and then the data center links broke and
so
you know most of the data is still
available but some of it isn't and we
really need
all of it because of the way we
distribute virtual block devices and
things
so this is work in progress what i'm
about to start talking about i'm working
on it now i was hoping to have it the
pull request
option to direct you here but not quite
very very soon
so the design target for our stretch
mode is having two main data centers and
then a third tiebreaker model
or a fifth tiebreaker monitor somewhere
else and we're going to have two copies
of the data in each data center
the reason for that being you know if we
um well that's mostly because of what
red hat supports
and what i felt comfortable letting out
into the world
we do support two copies within size one
if you're running on all flash
and so if you lose a data center out of
this you still have two copies
of all the data and it is on its own
even with the dead data center like the
surviving data center and set of
monitors are a supportable configuration
if you just like
cut it down we
restrict the osd monitor communications
so they stay within the data center by
default the osds are allowed to talk to
any monitor they want to
but besides the fact that you know it
might be higher latency to go out and
talk to someone else
um the we also want to notice when osd's
are not split from their peers
and so osd's ping each other just like
the monitors do now
and they will report and they will
report when they can't talk to their
peers to try and mark them dead
but if an osd can talk to any monitor
that's in the quorum
he gets to stay alive and so we don't
want a net split between the data
centers and for
the losing data center to have all its
osd's talking to the tiebreaker monitor
because they can reach it
and having that tiebreaker monitor keep
them alive that would be bad so we say
you are only allowed to talk
to oses we're only allowed to talk to
monitors in their data center to stay
alive
and then in addition to requiring a
minimum number of
osds to be alive to go active we say you
have to have
osds from more than one data center um
or availability zone or whatever it's a
configurable thing and that means that
if we lose an osd
um then you know it will have to make
another copy on the same day or
by default you'll have two of in each so
you'll lose an osd but
we will make sure that we go active with
at least one osd from both sides
and probably all three of them
and then let's see
right so i already went through this
cool
and so visually everybody's pinging each
other
we lose the old osd um but everyone
keeps
and and the cluster keeps running and in
this case oh no osd 1.0 isn't allowed to
do anything
so like you have a data unavailability
which is not great
but you know you can go work and get osd
2.0 back online
and meanwhile osd's 1.1 and 2.1 are
updating their data
but then when the links break we can
still we like the mon
the tiebreaker monitor chooses osd 2 or
sorry data center 2 side for whatever
reason
and they make their own little cluster
and they change the rules to say
you are allowed to go active without
having osds in multiple data centers
and we are disallowing the monitors in
data center one for becoming the leader
and
then we can keep making updates to osd
2.1 and when osd 2.0 comes back he can
keep making updates
and life is great and i have five
minutes if you guys have questions
everybody stunned i guess
so you mentioned there's a half-life of
12 hours
why did why did you settle on that
number it was completely arbitrary
i needed to write a number down it's
configurable but basically
we want to not immediately forget if a
connection died but we also want it to
age out because
like if a mod if you reboot the server
monitors on its score will drop
and we want that to age out
the question is when this is coming out
and the answer is it's gonna be in
before
before octopus is released at the end of
the month or in march
[Laughter]
or else i'm gonna be in a lot of
i got trouble right uh you basically
suggest to have uh if you have two data
centers you'd like to have a copy of
four of them the question was if you
have two data centers do you
i'm suggesting four copies instead of
three copies yes that's correct
um so i like i said during the talk
i really want that if you lose a data
center because if you lose a data center
maybe it's temporary but there's a good
chance it's a very long term
and so i want the surviving cluster to
be supportable on its own
that's you know some people may be sad
about that and so in that case you can
run with three data centers which
will mostly work although still might
have trouble with net splitting on the
osd side
i'm planning to get to that after after
the octopus release
but for the product needs that red hat
red hat gave me then that was sufficient
we could go to four copies
the question was if the reason we have
ping statistics in the manager novelists
are because of the teacher and actually
no it has nothing to do with it
it's just good good information to have
network issues instead network issues
under underneath step in general
have resulted in a lot of like problems
that are hard to diagnose
so we want to expose that more carefully
and make it more obvious when they're
probably
an underlying cause of an issue
ah so yes the monitors use their own
statistics i think the ping statistics
that you get in the manager are actually
just from the osd heart beating
although i'm not totally sure about that
so i guess we can plug these into the
manager as well but we don't yet
someone in the back had a question yes
the question was if five milliseconds is
a hard limit or something that we ride
up by testing and the answer is
i i was just five milliseconds is sort
of like it it's not
completely arbitrary but it's not a hard
limit it's just that like we have run
ceph in a lot of data centers that had
latency up to around two and a half or
three milliseconds
and five milliseconds when you add up
the latencies on doing right ios
it's you know not great but it's sort of
in the range of what you may see in a
cef hard drive based cluster anyway
so it's plausible whereas you know if
you do
100 milliseconds then some of your
primaries are going to be across your
remote link
and your reads are going to be slow and
your rights are like
two and a half of those hops or
something and so they're going to be
really slow and everyone's just
miserable so it's just
it needs to be you know kind of data
center-ish
all right well i will be oh
thing so we are running our monitors
in a rounded environment and just use
vfd so directional forwarding detection
resist
which is within our ospf protocol that
we use anyway
so i just was wondering why you invented
the wheel twice
ah
so the question was why i'm talking
about having our own pings and so i'm
writing down ping but it's actually a
normal seth over the wire message
that goes through the normal ceph
communication pipeline it's not a like
it's not a network primitive and that's
on purpose we want to make sure that the
entire
stack is working properly because you
know if
it may be that the monitor is still
alive technically
but if it's like got gigabytes worth of
data and swap and it can't handle
messages then we want to market as as
not behaving
ah the question was about messenger v2
and it is not necessary for this
although i mean you'll have it and you
should run messenger v2 if you have it
but
this is at a higher layer
uh the question was about if this will
be in a specific
um linux distribution and i have no idea
this is going into the next upstream
stuff release and
distributions will get it when they get
it this has nothing to do with what the
clients are so it's all server-side it's
just part of the packages yeah
okay okay thank you thanks all