hello welcome back again
our next speaker is leo van der wusstein
he will be talking about
what he would like to see in catalog
zones but this talk is aimed at
dns developers floor is yours
in 15 minutes hello uh welcome and
thanks for being here
uh this is my first presentation ever so
i'm
nervous so i'll try to calm down if i'm
talking too fast then
let me know uh also i think it will be a
short presentation after
andrei's fair and the other complicated
uh
uh presentations um well my name is leo
frustein
i'm a dynas operator
i operate a large anycast for the second
largest
registry and besides that
we have other name servers that do a lot
of domain names
uh a couple of million and we tried to
maintain those
and i came across catalog songs which i
found very interesting
but uh was wasn't that scalable yet
but uh still the concept i found
interesting
it is uh
so there's not much new um
shall i put her in the back yeah maybe
that's better
sort of intuition uh so it's it's
already a working concept
and another warning is that the
presentation was
prepared very uh quickly
uh and i have code examples that have
tiny fonts so if you want to see the
codes then maybe open already the
the slides on your laptop so you can
read it because maybe you cannot read it
here
okay let's go well
i as i said i run anycast and
of course i need to generate
configurations so
i run uh like seven top level domain
names
uh on on many locations and i run them
all in separate demons so
i ended up with hundreds of demons so
the the
the way to configure this uh the usual
way i think is
to use uh python jr and yaml
uh and then synchronize that
configuration and then you have to
reload that configuration to yeah to be
loaded
um yeah that needs uh
a provisioning a place where you
proficient where you
where you start provisioning to those uh
demons over out of band
and uh yeah um so that's that's i think
an uh
a common uh setup uh catalog zones
uh contain the information
that's uh like variable in your
configuration so basically the list of
zones
that you need to be loaded that you need
to have
loaded in your daemon
the configuration of the daemon is not
so addressed but
the catalog zone is so this is an a
code example that is working
um uh yeah what what can i tell about it
uh
yeah yeah simply you load have it in the
master
and your your secondaries will
load this and then the ptrs on the right
side you see the domain names that
need to be loaded and on the when you do
a ddns call on your master
the ptr record will be added or be
removed
and then all your secondaries will load
that zone or
delete that song
yeah so that this
yeah is simply working i did that it's
fine so
but what i did is extending it a bit
because
uh not at the moment only bind supports
catalog zones and you want to have
you want to use this concept also in
other demons
so uh with the additional section on the
bottom
i can iterate over the zone oh wait
uh i'm already at the next slide so uh
at the bottom here you see
uh additional config that you can put in
there like your masters
like uh where to um
allow notifies from uh allow transfer uh
transfer form uh but yeah
the main important thing is the the the
stuff on the top
so the here's the the the stuff that i
added
it's simply a zona md record
which i use for the integrity of the
data
and it's a new record i think it's still
still a draft
and you see the number 240 in there
in that line that
is a field that
is reserved for uh private use so you
can use it for
uh um make putting hashes of parts
of your uh of your records
and even just a part of the value of uh
of a resource record that's that's all
up to you
and i use it to generate
a list of domain names uh that i can
compare
in in other demons if they're if they're
present or not
and then run commands uh the the the
vendor-specific commands to do your
mutations
okay so yeah the benefit is that you
don't need to reconfigure it it's it
because uh
automatically by by uh the the
how do you say when when the catalog
zone is being refreshed
so yeah that doesn't evolve
that much work anymore um
well you don't need fender specific
commands for
maintaining it
well actually there's more like a future
thing because
right now it's not that's uh supported
yet
and you don't need additional support
which
i usually use rsync or sap or whatever
you use
to to have your configuration proficient
and for that you also need the user um
plus yeah let's say you are a dns
you perfect you serve dns for multiple
registries
then you can have a catalog zone for
each of your customer
and they can maintain that catalog zone
uh
and then your secondaries will add and
delete domain names that in those
in those demons
yeah and it simplifies a lot uh
i did a little bit of abuse of the rr
type
in the beginning to to come to this
resource initially i wanted to use the
nxt record which is uh yeah absolute
uh yeah it's the next record uh
yeah sorry um then i tried the the
the
and what is it the zona status record
uh which is uh assigned by uh by icon
but it does not have a real rfc only
that only had a draft
and therefore it's not supported in dns
python
nor in not and not not in lsd so the
record does not
exist in there but
while i was experimenting then at the
same time
cloudflare made the info record
unobsolated
and that's the then the record that i uh
yeah kind of abuse
for this so i
still have a wish list of uh that that
um
i would like to have added in the in the
expired draft for uh catalog zones
uh which is uh yeah uh doing uh
define your masters with the srv record
[Music]
let's see so you have to read from my
slide
yeah and do your your your master's a
bit different about the gods
example uh speak uh speaks for itself
so yeah to to have this uh standard and
i think uh
additional work needs to be done um
so i think uh we i have to convince
vendors of uh
authoritative software to to use this
but yeah first it needs to be a standard
and i don't know how much enthusiasm and
to share some there is
for it um
yeah so imbined it's supported and the
others is not so for the ones that it's
not supported and now you
have to use additional software and that
i don't like so much of course so
i will put code examples on
my my websites which is dns dot company
slash catso that there's at the moment
not
not that much yet but i will soon put
more stuff there
this is a list of references which
contain all the the white papers and
tutorials i think yeah
you have to read it later on if you're
interested
that's the last slide questions thank
you leo
[Applause]
oh
this is andre isc so thank you leo i
think thank you for
being brave to doing your first
presentation here
um so uh with the catalog zone the
situation is
a little bit complicated because there's
a draft lying in itf
which nobody has a time to finish for
the catalog zones too
so if you wanted if you want to be
cauter of the draft
it would be great because it needs more
work
and then yeah then
our implementation in bar needs to be
updated to to match the
new draft we also have some uh other
ideas what could be put into catalog
zones and
uh but still um well we had some plan
and then the oh came
and we just need had to like
replant the thing so so doh is the new
kid on the block that's blocking all the
health consuming all the time
well not not all of it but but it it
consumes some of the time which we had
to reserve for the catholic zones
um and then we need to synchronize with
like
these faults that those falls and the
seas that nick
who isn't here but i don't know if even
if they are going to implement
our catalytic zones yet but
yes any help that anybody using
catalytic zones can
give us the dls developers in terms of
specification
or even like testing it or even patches
are
always welcome so so if you are a dns
developer and and
care about catalog zones and can you can
you help with the bind code or
nsd code or power dns code
we all would like to accept patches from
from anybody a good patches
okay thank you
as well okay that's nice to hear this is
william of vanellet labs who said he
would like to help with that as well
well as it's question time i can also
ask you a question did anyone
tried it in the audience catalog zones
in general
[Laughter]
okay that's not that much but yeah maybe
if people understand
the benefits of it then yeah speaking uh
from power dns the problem we see is
that we know everybody wants this
but none of the people that want this
are paying customers
yeah there's no overlap there which
means we're not going to pull that card
which means you i think like
actually in my code example if you look
in my code example
it's here so you see on the right a
number
an id for the domain name yeah and
that's actually the power unis
domain id yeah so and then
we said you were doing an external
implementation the current net
experimental
implementation is also external it talks
to the api but i
still i i in in 1999 i used
powerdns i think and then i still have
this this database the naming is still
the same
right and okay and the other field that
you see there
left to the id is the is the soar
so there then you can use it to look up
in your local authority
if you're in sync with the master yeah
all right any other questions for leo or
from leo
okay thank you again thank you
i'll be back in five minutes with a
final speaker