so hello everyone welcome
our next speaker in security the room
lorenzo fontana
and his talk about uh falco internals
internals101
hey um i feel a lot of pressure just
because
i mean it's saturday and it's lunchtime
so you're all here to listen to this so
it's very very it's very very high
pressure situation so
we have been we're going to talk about
the falco project
and how we have been able to
put cisco's to user space bring cisco's
user space in a very fast way with very
low throughput
the thing is that i didn't really wanted
to talk about the falco project which is
the
cnc project i work on but while doing it
actually discovered that we have been
making
something very interesting for everyone
to listen to so i actually wanted to
to tell everyone if you already knew me
it would be probably because of my book
linux observability with bpf
and maybe because you're involved in the
kubernetes space or
cabinet space in some way and also
because they've been engaged for them
for
the past five years probably
first things first i will i want to give
you some context
to to let you understand falco is a
project
that basically takes every cisco that
happens
when no one is looking at that i mean
every cisco is brought to user space and
with those c schools
falco process a set of rules that gen
gives you alerts
based on uh what happened in the system
it has been started four years ago and
two years ago it had been donated to the
cncf
so that everyone could contribute and
make it better it's written you see plus
splash with
which is already makes it crazy enough
but we wanted to add cisco's cisco's a
very interesting mechanism it's an
api to the kernel it abstracts the drive
the
the hardware to you so that you can
just do things without actually
destroying this machine and you can
interact with the kernel
if you think about cisco's whenever you
open a file as it's called done whenever
you establish a connection that is
called it's done whenever you do
anything that's just got it done
even if you use a very high level
language at some point that cisco is
done
and the cisco interface might be
obstructed by libraries like gfc
these things ciscos are very scary
whenever whatever library that deals
with cisco we have
to actually map every single cisco to
to deal with that and this already makes
uh this already creates a very high
buyer for every
for any security implication because if
you have a kernel
and you have cisco's the next kernel
version will have
you know maybe a new cisco maybe a new
parameter maybe a cisco changed version
these kind of things um if i keep saying
the words with ad suffix like change it
it's because i'm italian i do that and i
cannot deal with that so
sorry ciscos are
very powerful are very good for kernel
space
but are not very very good for user
space to bring
every cisco to user space guess what you
have to do
a cisco so it's already
you know a very very hard problem it's
like the kitchen egg
and uh if you don't believe me that the
problem is that try to have a system
with you know a throughput of five
millions of cisco at a second
it's crazy you have five millions of
ciscos and another five millions of
cisco's to
actually deal with the cisco so and and
so on
and it's not 1998 anymore i mean
it was like five but um
the candle was very very simple back
then
things like multi-trading and stuff and
you really need to know
that when you want to deal with cisco's
and when you do a security tool in
general
you also have to deal with time and
guess what you need to
do with time a cisco nice
or you can deal with things like you
know registers like you can go get the
time from the processor but processors
are not obstructed
so you have to deal with time for every
single architecture you want to support
and it's another maze like this place
and also if that wasn't enough cisco's
are not enough
because you get a cisco that tells you
hey someone open this file with these
permissions
thank you but we
are in a different world that 10 years
ago was like
oh 1998 is nothing more than years ago
we're a different world than 20 years
ago
and you uh don't have just
a system that runs apache with some php
you might have containers so you have a
very complex infrastructure
and you want to know in which container
this is collapsing
in which network namespace if the
network namespace was in
what was with the mountain space or if
the attacker actually
you know did something nasty maybe they
change the c group of the networking
spaces kind of things
so having container information is also
useful
and for container information you have
to deal with systems that are very slow
because you are going to take the
container information from
the docker daemon or from container d or
something like with their api
and those are apis designed to go at you
know
with a latency of 100 milliseconds but
cisco's are very fast
five millions a second and you want to
correlate every
c school to
it's crazy to every i
we didn't solve this problem yet in a
very good way
so how to do that um we've been asking
ourselves this question
there's a third answer that we didn't
develop yet but
it's secret and
basically two ways so you just implement
your own kernel module
like you know it's like when you install
virtualbox in your linux machine and
then you need to
you know you need to restart nice
or when you operate your kernel when you
saw some modules imagine
having your company with 100 servers
updates restarts
the machines and that wasn't very handy
so we also implemented any bpf probe
which everyone knows what is it because
my talk is not done in vpf
and they don't want to explain and you
know ibpf
okay great um like 20 so
i will explain very fast so with the
kernel module you can just go in the
kernel implement your code
and you know it will do whatever you
want pros
you implement whatever you want it's
very efficient because it will carry on
panic your machine and then as soon as
you
do a mistake your servers are all done
and you don't have a way to reboot them
and you know it's very hard
um with an mbpf probe the mechanism is a
bit
more sophisticated you can't implement
whatever you want because there are some
limitations
but you can still go to the kernel and
ask for information in a very efficient
way
so how does this look like
well i initially wanted to do this
presentation in the terminal then turns
out today to do diagrams
so my diagrams are not very good but i
mean
gives an idea so you have the kernel
space and user space
separated you have the kernel module
on the lower band and you have bulk on
the upper bound and in the middle there
are a set of libraries and
tools that you know allow you to process
the cisco
in a very efficient way let's start from
the from the bottom the kernel module
is the first implementation it's still
there and still works with
also and it basically go to the kernel
and attach to every cisco that gets
executed when it
starts executed and when it exits the
execution like imagine putting
uh a jump at the start of every function
and a jump at the end of every function
that
executes the ciscos that's it
when this code executes it sends it
to a ring buffer which we're going to be
talking later
that then is consumed user space profile
descriptor
you know like a device like the device
of your printer because this is a
current module
and then this is consumed by another
library
that enriches all this stuff with
container metadata and stuff which is
called lib scenes
we will talk about this more in details
later and then falco can
you know match the rules
so this is crazy
uh first things are in buffer
i think buffer is a data structure that
is basically
imagine a link at least but that links
to itself
this is to avoid that you have to
what's happening with the microphone uh
actually uh shuffle back the buffer
to the point the starting point of the
execution so that you can continue
putting elements and you know the last
element
was was overwritten like first
infrastructure
and um in falco we decided
the perfect size would have been eight
megabytes for it
because it fits well in most of
registers
it's very uh handy to to use
both from kernel space and bottom user
space most users
that have very strange use case they
adjust this but it's a compile time
thing
i personally never had the problem
the kernel takes the events and it mem
copy
the event to the next pointer in the
ring buffer that's why this is fast
so the memory is never uh ever
copied it's just copying the pointer of
the memory
so i i thought the wrong thing and
contradicting myself
the memory of the
the pointer is copied to the ring buffer
so that you have access to that memory
and at that point you can uh
load this data from user space by
reading the dev falco 0
files
this is basically how the structs looks
in
the etc file and these other files
shared between
the user space and current space so you
basically
what's in what you're interested in it's
in the head and detail
and then there's some uh metadata for
for you to understand if your buffer is
performing well
um i'm showing this because uh
i mean we are all used to very high
level code
i mean object oriented programming all
the stuff you know functional
programming all interesting things that
i love
but when you have to do these kind of
things you actually have to
you have no choice then designing a
structure test everything you need
because you have to make it fast and so
this also as the responsibility
you know the single responsibility
concept
um to um you know count the drop demands
count the total number of events count
if there have been preemptions
contest reaches this kind of things drop
demands happen because maybe the ring
buffer is not fast enough
you remember when i said 5 million
ciscos
maybe at 5 million cisco's events are
starting getting dropped so there's no
memory
free in the ring buffer to put them
and at that point
cisco's are not yet
ready to be uh used by
by your application because well you
recycle pointer
first second thing you
go to the pointer to see what's inside
there's memory and then you look
and there's only the name of the cisco
and some other
um you know some other data that you
don't understand
so we had to make a mechanism that's
called fillers
that basically goes to every cisco you
know when i said
do this for five millions of cisco and
it takes with
defensive functions cisco get arguments
deprecated
because there's another way yet
it takes the registers and transforms
that information
to a string or to you know
in this case their information was not
there so it just prints out
not available and
and then if there have been success the
cisco isn't reached
still in the same data structure so you
have to do this for every cisco
two times because there's the enter and
the exit
and nothing i just wanted to share this
with you all because
it's been painful and at some point
you go to people you talk with others
you find out that there's ebpf you find
out that people are very upset
about having to compile their current
module all the times
and you decide to do this with ebpf
again
and it turns out that it's a much much
nicer experience
there is no uh ring buffer involved at
all
because ebpf doesn't allow you you know
to advise and
you know move memory from current space
to user space because
the purpose of it being safe will be
totally you know
it will be totally useless but it has
a set of concepts that allow you to do
that in fancy ways
that are called maps
and in this case libscap which was the
library that before we just
read in the file descriptor loads
an vpf program to kernel space and says
the kernel a kernel takes this object
that i compiled for you
and i can say it's yes and then the kind
of says
oh yes i like this and then the current
says okay
i will send you data and you know
all this conversation was the abba
verifier
which basically make sure that you don't
mess up with the kernel
and at that point data
flows to libscap through ebpf maps
and guess what we had to do to do the
fillers
we had to tell this is very very nice
we had to tell to lipscap to actually
send
ebpf programs in the map
for the kernel to load them at runtime
when they are
needed okay
i mean you have to see the code it's
very funny
and and these make sure that
again every cisco is matched to the
right argument
all the blob data becomes you know um
strings and you have
i mean if you look at the chi mod cisco
you don't want
uh the you know excitation
representation of the the permission you
want to see
uh you want to see these two
zero seven seven seven or do you want
you want to see
the actual name of the constant like uh
you want to see sue id right
and to come back to lipscap just to
to explain better uh what this does
it basically maintains the control loop
through the current module and to the
bpf map because
when you read from that file you know
it's a device
so you continue you have to read right
because
you need to consume it or you lose it
and when you do a security software you
cannot lose data
right you cannot just i'm not reading it
for a while so that
and you know attacker very very very
happy but you're not doing that
so it has the responsibility to do that
and we had to actually do a library that
does that because the
attack surface of that library alone
would have to be
very very small it would have to be just
some lines of code
because at that point since
that you know does the enrichment you
know to the next slide
as a lot of you know code that talks
with content runtimes and
you know other parts that you know might
be compromised
and this also does a very nice thing
which is the scap format which is a file
that you basically can write and read
it's a format
so you can avoid when you need to test
uh
dealing with cisco you can avoid to have
a real kernel you can just
write and read from this file
and then again since that's the
container on time metadata
and i said this is in c plus plus so we
basically had to rewrite the client for
every
container at time nice and um
coordinates metadata and filtering
and this is essentially what falco is uh
well it's much more than this because if
this will be the project will not exist
but it's just a main with a while loop
that has an event called scenes payment
here and every time
uh there's that we go to the next
iteration the pointer is
reset and sent to the next event
and then the falco engine applies the
rules the falco rules to this event
to match and there was a trait
and if you want to see
a falco rule
you still okay to see yes
this is how it looks like so you have
the rule name
it's very it's very fancy uh yamo
no one loves the piano oh my gosh
and that's the description of the rule
and then there's a condition
so in this case
we let me find the very easy one
i don't want one with the macro because
if not i have to explain the macro
okay okay this is a perfect condition so
this in this case
um we have a macro which can we can use
you know to avoid repeating writing
to avoid repeating to write the same
thing and it matches to the event type
exactly so whenever someone executes a
process
with exactly c school
with direction to the left so
when the cisco starts executing it will
actually match and go to the next
condition
so that's why we needed to do all this
crazy stuff
another important thing when you deal
with cisco's
and when you deal with having to
bring them to user space that was one of
the mistakes we've been doing
we've been doing earlier was to actually
send all the cisco
that was the initial point of my
presentation you don't actually have to
you just send the ciscos that match the
conditions
so what we did at some point was to take
some parts of the filtering mechanism
and bring them as close as possible to
kernel space
so that we could actually just take out
the cisco that we needed
with the arguments that we need okay
because maybe there are five million
ciscos but we are interested in opens
of this file
and to summarize you really want to do
an bpf probe when you
do a project that does something like
this because
implementing your own current module is
never a good idea
and having very well-defined boundaries
and interfaces
is always a good idea because
you can
[Music]
you can work on something that you
and that's very well defined again like
as
i said the skap format is very useful
because you can use that format even to
send data to
another server in your infrastructure
so it's it's very easier to you know
make
anything on top of that like a user
interface like wi-sharp right
wireshark basically use the pickup
format i could make
a wireshark like interface for the scap
format for example
and if you're interested in learning
more
because 25 million i guess it's not
enough
and also i speak very slowly you can
join the community
or go to the website or
find me on my email or don't do anything
because you are not interested
and thanks
we might have time for one or two
questions if they will not be too far
hello
scream hello uh
what is the performance impact on
running falcon on your machine
okay that's the first question and the
second question is if uh
something matched the filter if there is
any way to have an action to take place
right away
instead of a simple output something
about happening okay can i
start with a second question uh the
second question was
uh there's any way to do an action when
something happens
like you know doing uh prevention
um like c linux or something like that
well with custom code and there's not
actually falco is not a framework to
design
uh you know prevention mechanism it's
just detection
so it will tell you when something
happens it's
in you know in that kind of uh segment
of security software where
it only tells you hey there's someone
poking you you know
mining uh some bitcoins on your machine
but it doesn't actually stop the miner
from happening
it will send those data to uh you know
uh a server like you know collection
mechanism that
you use and with those information
you can actually take action like it
either manually or with a script or
whatever you want
and the first question was what's the
performance impact of running falcon
machine
uh the performance impacts are very
different based on the rules you apply
uh on most of the machines that
i personally use because operators
project i don't
actually have you know myself uh
production machines but
you know the user said and what i've
been noticing
in the issue and in the community calls
was that it was around one or two
percent
of the cpu usage we are almost
out of the time so if you've got some
other questions please uh talk
to orange
[Applause]