welcome everyone
i am abigail garner and joining me is
elon barr
we are with least authority based in
berlin we have a
team that is across 19 time zones
leased authority is committed to
building and supporting the development
of i'm not miked
i mean the mic is for the the live
but i'll speak up um lease authority
is committed to building and supporting
the development of usable technology
solutions
and ethical business practices
one moment
and ethical business practices that
support
uh the privacy as a fundamental human
right
and secure solutions for everyone
yeah so this project is supported by
open technology fund and it is looking
at
file sharing and storage for human
rights organizations
we're looking to make this process more
secure for human rights organizations
this is using tahoe laughs a
secure file system that is open source
also the tools being used for this
integrated with tahoe laughs
are grid sync magic folders and
magic wormhole we'll have links to those
at the end
the four partner organizations that are
human rights organizations that's been
really key to our research
are based in mexico nigeria india
and argentina uh what we
we work with them in throughout this
progress
process it's going to be about 18 months
in total
and it was important for us in our
criteria is to look at organizations
that had a human rights
track record they were also they also
had expressed a need for secure file
storage and sharing
and that they also had the capacity in
terms of time and staff to participate
in a long-term project
and finally we wanted to make sure that
it had the
global diversity for to represent
different parts of different regions
so why human rights organizations when
we focus on human rights organizations
we're looking at
groups that have very sensitive data
things that have identities
even if it's not names it may be people
in locations or
experiences that really tie that data to
a particular person
and we're talking about things like
witness testimonies
films photos so a lot of things that
would be
high risk if they were found also if
they were
found by people that should not be
seeing them
also in terms of the threat model their
risks are very high we're talking about
things like
harm to your to your body or threats to
yourself
or your family members and situations
like detention
or um or interrogation
they also these organizations because
they're doing such
work that is pressing and often
under stressful situations they have
limited resource and time
to learn new tools so if we can make
these tools more usable for them
they're more likely to adopt them and
then we also as we make them more usable
for
human rights organizations we're making
them more usable
for everyone and finally this is aligned
with
lease authority's mission to participate
in in within the internet freedom space
and human rights
thanks abigail i hope i'll speak loud
and clear enough for everyone to hear me
also on the back
okay thanks so what do you want to learn
as part of the research that we did for
this project
so we did the research as part of two
phases and i'll tell you about both
phases so in the first phase
the goal for the research was to find
out what the file sharing what the file
storage needs are of human rights
organizations
so we did that research by first
selecting human rights organizations and
abigail spoken to that just a second ago
and then we shared a survey with them
that they filled out to explain
what they're doing at the moment when
they want to share files or store files
and we followed up with foundational
interviews basically where we had a
chance to talk to them more in depth
about the things that they feel that's
in the survey that was the first phase
in the first phase we discovered that
the sharing use case was the one that we
probably wanted to focus on for the
remainder of the project
and i'll tell you a little bit more
about how we came to that but just to
share
what the second phase looked like and
the second phase were actually still in
but the research that we've done so far
basically focused on first describing
those file usage as far storage and file
sharing
needs of human rights to organizations a
bit more in depth and also focusing more
on collaboration
and secondly to do a usability study of
one of the open source tools that we
work with at abigail mentioned gridsync
and gridsync
is the graphical user interface of tahoe
labs
so we did more foundational interviews
with these organizations and an
additional organization
and then we did a moderated usability
test which means that we
had the organizations and the people
that we tested with
run through some tasks using gridsync so
that we can see
how usable the program is at the moment
is actually something that it can work
with
is it easy to use etc so what did we
learn as part of this research
in the first phase as i mentioned we did
mostly needs finding and we won't have
time to share everything that we learned
so we'll just share some highlights
we learned that organizations have
different file storage and sharing needs
well this may sound self-evident but
it's not as self-evidence may seem
and it's important for us to keep that
in mind because human rights
organizations comes in many
shapes forms colors and everything they
do many different things
they have different use cases and that
means that there's also generally not
like a one size fits all for the work
that they do
one thing that was interesting in that
sense that we learned about the
different ways that they choose the
tools that they work with
there are many different factors that
fed into this choice and so for example
when human rights organizations choose a
tool to work with
security practices matter and security
threats that they face
abgil talked about the threat modeling
that they need to do to understand what
kind of threats they're facing from whom
etc
and it also leads to different kind of
security practices so some organizations
may fear that their laptops will be
stolen from their office
and instead they put things in the safe
or they might fear that their absolute
will get stolen when they go into the
street because they might get mugged
and so they don't take laptops into the
street or they might fear surveillance
of their digital equipment so they
might fear that if they send an email
that there will be
something intercepted and it also
changes the kind of tools that they
choose
other factors that contribute to this
choice of tools are the file size of
particular thing that they want to
share does it fit into an email or not
do they need to share it through some
different means like we transfer or
dropbox
whether they need to collaborate with
other organizations as part of it
how easy specific tools to use the
privacy features of particular
tools or the reputation that they have
whether to
costs or whether it's free or how much
it would cost
and lastly the choice of the partners
that they work with
i'll tell you a little bit about that
one um now
so the partners of human rights
organizations so the other organizations
human rights organizations work with
they have a large role
to play when organizations choose what
tools they can use
human rights organizations tend to not
work in isolation they're usually part
of networks they collaborate they do
campaigns together they do research
together
and that leads to the fact that when
they use a tool they often look to their
partners to understand what tools their
partners are using
and when they have a sense for what
tools the partners are using they might
affect the tool
the tools that they can choose or vice
versa when they think oh we want to use
this tool then they consider well
actually i'm not sure if this part
organization could work with that or
would work with that so we might need to
reconsider
and also some organizations actively
give advice to other organizations for
what tools to use
so there was an interesting thing for us
to find out about so how this partner or
partner organizations of these human
rights organizations
play such a key role another thing we
learned is that collaboration is really
an important use case
so oftentimes it's not about extending a
file to another party
it is often about working together in
specific documents
so that was really a thing that struck
us as part of this research
so some of the recommendations that we
came uh out of this research with were
that we wanted to focus on the
collaboration
sharing use cases and we figured well
within the scope of what we can do
within this project we can't go to let's
say real-time collaboration new
real-time editing together but we can do
asynchronous editing
and we can look at things like version
control which really matter when you
collaborate together on something
we thought we can figure that we can
also improve the sharing workflow
of the tools that we work with and
overall just improve the ease of use of
the tools
yep absolutely yeah so the second phase
of research
we decided to focus on sharing
collaboration and also to do this
usability study that we mentioned before
so just one thing that we wanted to
highlight from this version control
uh finding that we learned as part of
the second phase is that
version control is especially important
when collaborating so when people are
working by themselves in a particular
file
being able to go into earlier versions
etc seem to be less critical as when
people are working together on the file
we identified four needs in that context
one is
the need to be able to restore earlier
versions of the document or a file or to
view earlier versions
two would be to view track changes three
would be to see
when changes were made and four to see
who has made changes
i also want to share just a few
highlights from the usability study that
we did with gridsync
this is the user interface of gridsync
so this is the file storage and file
sharing tool that we use with tahoe labs
so we asked the organization that we
worked with as part of the test to
see if they can share this real cat
folder
with a recipient just want to ask people
in the audience
how would you do that if you see this
interface and you want to share the real
cat folder
what would you do any idea
sorry you would drag and drop okay
right click on folder sorry
okay so right click on folder or on the
three dot menu
so sorry click on the white
okay uh on the invite you said yes
gotcha so uh we learned that when we
asked this question that
this was actually not something that was
very intuitive to people and so this
important task that we had for people to
share something with
others seem not to be as easy as um
it should be so basically the way it
works now is that people can indeed
click on invites and then click on
enter invite code that's our create
invite code
or they can indeed right click or click
on the three dots
and then choose sync with device and
create invite code but even if people
reach that stage it wasn't necessarily
clear to them that yes this is the path
for them to follow this is the most
effective way and yes now they're
certain that they're doing the thing
that they're seeking to do
something that did work well as part of
the research that people seem to
understand that this sharing use case
was something where
people sync a folder together so it's
not something that you share
in one direction but once you share
something with another person
then the other person can also make
changes to that folder and also then
what happens
with that folder on your own device so
some of the recommendations we came out
of this research method to focus on
version control on
previous versions when chains were made
who made changes
to improve things in the sharing
workflow to make sure that the user
intent
is reflected in the way people can
access the interface and also provide
more guidance in some areas
and also we actually need to do more
user testing as part of
the outcomes on particular aspects of
i will hand it over to abigail
since a key part of this research has
been working with our or
our partner organizations we wanted to
share
some information we'd like to pass on if
you're thinking about working with human
rights organizations in this situation
um we had about four months scheduled to
find these
four partners that would commit with
with us for this um
for for this project and we actually it
took we underestimated how much time we
would need for that it took us about
seven months
and that has to do with um some
suspicion around what we're doing
building that trust and um and some
some of the no's that we heard were
because they actually had bad
experiences with other development
projects so there's also some learning
to happen there
and we um we ended up we've now extended
our project a bit in order to do that
but the way that we did our outreach was
we went to the internet freedom space
and the human rights space
introduced people it got introduced to
people and then they introduced us to
people but that took
quite a while longer than we anticipated
it's really important that we compensate
these individuals as the professionals
and the um the experts that they are
so keep that in mind they're not going
to do this work for free they already
have enough on their plate
so make sure that you work that into
your budget and be upfront with them
about what incentives
you can offer so that you're really not
wasting their time if it's not going to
work in
in their plan what we were able to do
with this project is
invite them to meet us in person at a
conference that they would be attending
anyway
so internet freedom festival or rights
con
they would be there and we would cover
their travel expenses and their hotel
and other related expenses
in exchange for two to four hours of
meeting with us during that time
defining the expectation the clear
expectations and commitment
really helps the organizations get a
sense of what you're asking for
that there are no surprises so we
developed a memorandum of understanding
an mou
that really told them which activities
we were doing
how many hours each of them would take
the maximum time over this
over this project is 32 hours
and we also made it clear that this was
a non-binding
non-binding agreement not even a
contract that was important because of
the suspicion that there may
they may somehow be legally liable for
something along the way or kind of
if they need to drop out at some point
they can do that without consequences
we had uh we faced challenges with low
bandwidth and other
connectivity limitations we did some of
our user testing
uh remotely and there were specific
challenges to that
one of them of course is when they're
showing they're sharing their screen
with us
we um can't see their faces um so we
they
would talk through what they're doing
and we could glean from that
and from what was on the screen but um
but they're the those
problems that come up that you kind of
work through you see how they
work around them and how and it informs
our work more on a positive note it
informs our work in being aware of the
real
um challenges and circumstances uh that
that human rights organizations are
dealing with in the field
and finally to be aware that their
threat modeling may not
fit your framework of what is safe and
what is private
so keep that in mind every time you
include them in discussing
your project whatever it is check back
with them
it also um that builds trust and it also
um
keeps them engaged with the project
because for example they know where it
foster
and they know they each one of these
organizations consented to have their
names in the slides with the
understanding that that would also be
online
so we continue to do that in every time
that we
mention them so um
don't presume that it's that it's okay
with them until you've checked
right now we have discussed our findings
with our team including the developers
and
that is currently underway for for
making those
changes and then we will go back to the
organizations again and do more user
testing
at that point we will work with them in
deployment and that will inform
how we um how we do documentation for
uh for broader deployment in the future
and those are our um the tools the open
source tools that we're using as well as
our
website and a blog post specifically
about this project
what questions are there
what file storage and sharing tools that
they use
a wide variety for different purposes
and so
in some cases they're just sending an
email in some cases
um they want they make sure that they're
sending encrypted email
there are other situations where the
they don't even want it to be anywhere
except on their computer and the other
person's computer and so
they are walking a usb to that
that other organization um i mean
because so many of these
organizations work with with others um
and then depending on
google drive is a big one and um and
also very
um popular because their partners
are also working and so if they need it
they see it as some uh someone said
um we just need to get the work done and
so sometimes
assessing safety over convenience that's
constantly the dance
for them um
what else does that come from
crypt pads yeah cryptpad was a big one
for
um but one of the feedback about that is
the
formatting is not there the way they'd
like it in collaboration
i'm sorry again
how many people are using our tool right
now
with the human rights organizations they
have not they have not
deployed it yet so they are they've just
participated in the user testing so far
what was their feedback
the feedback on gridsync and what we
showed them there
yeah so many of them said that well this
is actually something that
worked quite easily and yes we can work
with this
and at the same time as we did the test
that was not always
as evident right so this is part of the
lesson that
organizations or people when they use
something and they go
through the motions and they've learned
how it works and okay yes
i can use this this is fine this is
workable but at the same time to get to
that process
actually there are a lot of stumbling
blocks and so there are all sorts of
things that
we learned from there that oh actually
this is not so self-evident or this is
not
as clear as it should be for people to
use it without any
any barrier
any other questions you mentioned
so as part of the agreement that we have
with with these organizations they've
agreed that
um if they want to that they can deploy
the tool that we will offer them
and so that is something that we're
looking forward to do in the next
few months and so we have to see exactly
how that will be
if there's something they can work with
if they also have the facilities to work
with that
server space and all these kind of
things but generally there is a
willingness and interest to to use that
yes
any other questions please
how it works technically on the hosting
side
so as part of the this particular
project it seems like we
will not provide the hosting ourselves
but that we will help them with
organizing hosting for themselves so
they can actually use their own servers
for that so some of these organizations
use their own servers and they're used
to using their own servers so we can
help them deploy tower labs in such a
context
or did you just by chance
we had a statement of what we were doing
that improved the more we learned when
we heard people's resistance or
misunderstanding of what we were trying
to do
so we had a statement of that plan and
then we distributed that
to various mailing lists and um
and through other people's personal
networks that's how that worked
um you mentioned that for some
organizations they'd already been
burned and in that case didn't want to
collaborate to explore it further
did they also explain how or why and
did you try to explain
why your solution is better or workable
yeah i can speak to that the question is
um what um when organizations would talk
about their resistance
and their the negative experiences they
had with other development projects
um i i can speak to it very generally to
say that they would put a lot of
work and effort into their feedback and
and then
the response of the people that were
developing the tool was not necessarily
oh that that they didn't give a reason
for why it was wrong
only flippant response is like yeah
we're not going to do that
or um that's not the one of the quotes
was that's not sexy
so they're kind of like putting this
heartfelt
effort into sharing what their risks are
and sharing what their experiences are
and say here's what we need
and then developers saying yeah you
maybe you need that but we're not going
to do that
thanks very much
you