so guys this will be a bit of a bumpy
ride today
um these slides were almost finished an
hour ago
and we had 20 minutes to talk together
five as well
he will be on one on the slides you'll
recognize him in a bit
he knows i've shown it a few minutes ago
yeah
he was not well he was happy and not
happy so yeah um the sites were only
finished a few
of an hour ago max and we had 20 minutes
to go over them last night when they
were still in an unfinished state
because of all the
stuff we had to do so it will be a bit
of a bumpy ride and i have
a bit of an idea of the structure these
guys i have no idea of the structure
anymore
and i don't know um whether the
transitions will be okay or not we will
see
so over there is geriani can start
hi i'm uh i've been part of the fosum
organization for
16 years now i've taken up a role in the
video team
five-ish years ago when we tried to come
up with a new solution to our streaming
as you've seen
our video history has been a bumpy ride
so far
um but in the last couple of years we've
managed to get it to work quite well
and well this what you're about to see
um
the boxes you see in the back well
that's up here in the front are
mostly the reason for that we'll give a
brief overview of
how we got all of that to work um and
then
we'll tell you about our future plans
mark
introduce yourself well uh i'm mark i've
been
i'm too old to remember uh i'm too old
i've been in on the fosdem team and yeah
i started playing with
video together with kyrie i think
uh yeah but i remember you running the
aw
building in 2010. no yeah i had a core
boot
and and and then and you were running
the building yeah so we first
started chatting yeah 2010 yeah so i'm
look for
mostly known as libvi mostly known for
graphics drivers such as while mode
setting
the free ati driver called radeon hd
which was actual c code
lima then xunxi
flashrom for ati graphics cards that
sort of thing
i've been running a div room here since
2006 with a few hiatuses
in between i think at this point with
philip the switch stopping with the
embedded devroom i'm the oldest
room manager around
yeah so a few years ago we didn't have
enough talks
in 2016 there weren't enough talks for
the exhaustive rooms so i went
decided for another hiatus and then i
helped these guys out with a bit of
video
which was interesting and then i slowly
got more and more dragged into the whole
thing
so you all know this fosdem is indeed
insane so nobody does
what these guys are doing or i only do a
small part but these guys they're core
organizers and they're
they have no time and they don't sleep
much in the weeks before the event and
you can't reach them anymore on the days
themselves and if you see them they will
they're always running
um so what the numbers you see here
we're now at 29 parallel tracks last
year we're in 28.
nobody does that i think we're three
times as large as the next larger on the
planet
something like that of the 835 talks
accepted
in penta there were about 1800
proposals so more than half got refused
and we're the only people that are
streaming this out live
and 29 live streams
nobody does that nobody does that even
if it's only 720p nobody does that
and you'll be surprised about the budget
um
we won't say any numbers but you will
probably spend more on public
transportation going back to the inner
city and
uh back and forth two times or four
times
then you falls and spins for every
visitor pretty much
so it is this is quite insane um it's
all either
beer event it's probably a bit of money
of the food trucks
there's a few there's big sponsors but
they're also limited in the amount the
money that they can give so that it
stays a proper grassroots project and
that it
it doesn't change its nature at all and
one of the mantras is small changes
every year tiny changes tiny teens don't
change anything big like
one dev room or uh small changes to hdmi
kitty
well that is exactly one mistake that we
made at one point um is when we scaled
up from five rooms to 21 rooms
don't do that it doesn't work when was
that um
i think that was 2014 oh for video for
video yeah not not for the whole
difference
so don't do that that idea
yeah for me it was amazing before that
it was always michael larabel
from furonic sitting in front with a hd
usb webcam
there was like one dev room in the h
building where there's only one door
no windows no ventilation no nothing and
it would just sit there for two days
straight and then
it's insane so all this stuff is quite
amazing
so this is our setup is working
those boxes well they're they're wooden
boxes you'll see a picture oh we forgot
i forgot to bring you one of the boxes
upstairs
well yeah there's no changing that
anymore um there's a picture of a box
in there as well so the speaker's laptop
is all the way on the
uh is there a curse being there that's
the speaker's laptop in this
image this is the slides box which is a
bit special it goes out to a projector
the audio is going straight into the
camera
and this then uh feeds it in over hdmi
audio over the camera
into another speaker into another slides
box and this all gets combined in a
switch and then goes out to the fossil
network and you can see the cable
running over there
to the back and it goes here into in at
least in this building it goes here into
the
um the ulb network and then it's into a
video vlan
and the guy who was setting up the audio
earlier is sitting downstairs
watching a big monitor and this year we
have three guys watching monitors right
so that's already a big change i didn't
do your suggestion to the slides because
well this one laptop is quite cool and
there's only a small machine in between
doing the actual streaming right so
there's downstairs there's a few
laptops that there will be a slide about
this you don't know the structure
yet right this is a bit of a surprise
for you guys and
if you've ever talked here or if you've
been running a dev room then you know
that since a few years a few minutes
after talk is finished
you get an email and you get to be you
get told that you can review your
talk and you can say the start in the
end and then minutes later
if there's nothing going wrong the
network is okay this will be published
already
and it's all being streamed live and the
publishing is already
where is it belnet and a few other sites
probably have about 10 million
we have about 10 mirrors that hold our
content so
we upload it to our master server and
then the mirrors
just sync sync from there using rsync
that's nothing
magic and we use a redirection service
that's mirror bits actually
um to redirect you to the closest or you
know most useful mirror for you
so everything becomes a so as soon as
the dock is reviewed it will be
available to
viewers within the next half an hour or
so
so next few slides will give you a bit
of an idea of the insanity and
the scale of the current setup and most
of the insanity we will keep
we'll just fix this one thing and take
one of the biggest issues
so this laptop is a laptop downstairs
and there's a few more of those it has
friends
mark well yeah we first attempted to
recycle some old servers uh they were
more efficient as like
space heaters basically we had like
five or six of them in a garage and like
it was in the middle of winter and like
it
got pretty hot in there with just trying
to do
like eight or nine streams
and then they fell over dumped into
kernel bugs
so and we were on the time pressure uh
for the first time we were like trying
to do this software setup ourselves so
i said like hey i had this laptop that i
had this
voctomic stuff like that we used to to
do the
mixing on um uh i i tested with it
and it seemed to work like let's just
try with a laptop and see if it can
stably well yeah
do the encoding and mixing etc in a
stable way
you have network you have a power supply
ups basic keyboards dirt cheap so we buy
a bunch of these before the conference
about 50 and we well we get rid of them
after the conference
during the conference during the
conference yeah people buy them right
and then they were sold in out in like
one hour one hour yeah
so did you make money or did you just
break even or did you lose a tiny bit
so um we don't make money on the wall we
we make a couple of dollars
um on the on the laptops but so we buy
them in bulk
um and we sell vouchers at the
info desk um well i did that yesterday
um they
i sold 38 because i had reservations for
a couple of others and we keep a few
ourselves
for use under the year and they were
gone in about an hour so
um we sold all of these for 150 euros a
piece which is approximately the price
we paid for them
there are lenovo x250s this year this
year but we started off with
x220s a couple of years back and we
repeat the same cycle every time so
this costs us nothing at all and we get
to
well we have them from october
approximately so it gives us time to set
them up test them all
and use them at the event and at no cost
actually
so this is underneath the big
uh the chairs of the big room downstairs
to the network room so you first pass
some
um really smelly sewage pipes
and then you get to a warm room and
there's lots of humming going on and
that's where they are standing
so on the other side of this there is
actually a few server racks and i think
a few
of us machines are always in there all
year long right
so we rent most of the other gear like
the cameras are rented the microphones
are rented and the stands are rented and
there's a
big mess every year trying to get the
inventory of that done trying to get
them tested and then
finding out that this year a few hdmi
connectors were broken on the
cameras and the microphones were broken
this is always fun
but yeah this is the slide pile they
come from holland
somewhere they fill up half a t5
transporter
so that's quite a big pile now this is
only 35 of our boxes
um in the fosdem office there's usually
58 lined up but there's a 3d
printer on this side of it and then on
the other side
there are just more boxes and the only
picture i
got was from this is from ghosty that i
got and the other side was all blurred
and
i have one picture with you in it but
showing you from your better side so i
was not using that slide
you were just looking in a box at this
point so no we're not using that slide
so they're all packed up in flight cases
these are this is the exact
coffin that is over there and these
things
get quite quite heavy and we have to
drag them from
one floor up from the fosdem office all
the way down every
thursday before fosdem and tomorrow
evening we will have to carry them all
up
all together with all the boxes that we
have at all the kit which is also about
between 80 and 100 boxes that we have
like this big
and these things you need four people to
get those up the stairs or down the
stairs as well so they're they're quite
bulky and quite heavy so we have
several of them this is a photo taken
yesterday morning so
six and a half of these boxes and in
every building usually one box travels
off
and that's sometimes also where the
video people will live for the weekend
when they check streams and make sure
that the cameras keep on running
so this is one of the video boxes you've
probably seen them everywhere already we
are now currently using two in the back
because we're testing a
open source hardware kit it's open
source hardware right yes
we're testing an open source hardware
camera and our usual camera so we now
have
two um camera boxes there are two
different ones there's one for slides
there's one for camera
we'll get to that in a bit the axiom
people are right next to it by the way
these guys are doing something really
cool it's a 4k camera which is
completely open source hardware so it's
not cheap but you're working on it but
but next this year you guys should have
a talk about this in this exact room
let's do that yeah
and invite the guys who do the full hd
version as well so there's two different
boxes
this is what they're and next year you
should bring 30 cameras maybe
for free just a suggestion
so yeah mark you used to double with 3d
printers for a bit so you
did all the you did all the case work
for this and you thought it was
going to be fancy and all 3d the whole
um laser cut stuff
yeah and then you started screwing them
together and then you noticed that maybe
for 58 boxes this is not the best idea
so this was a lot of work for somebody
you got something
yeah okay i outsourced it yeah outsource
it and the connectors in front are also
mighty expensive i think all the
connectors per bucks are more than what
the our box will be in future so pretty
much yeah
this is this nurturing stuff it's like
that's on the lower end of 100 euros
just
just the connectors yeah it's just
anyway so you've all walked in here
you've seen the franken box that i've
built over the last month with parts
that i scrounged from the office like a
month ago
and yeah if i would just leave the slide
at this and you would have learned
nothing
because all you see is cables so i've
done slanting slightly fancy so
where the signal from the laptop first
comes in is an hdmi active splitter
it's one of those cheap chinese things
that you bought
100 from immediately or yeah we have
about 100 of them
this is not very smart because the first
hdmi connection that it sees is also the
monitor identification data that it
keeps and feeds on
so this is always a bit of a gamble now
from here
it goes to the projector and it
goes to the scaler and i have a slide
about this in a bit
because this is a very important and
also blocking item for us
from the scaler it goes to a hardware
h.264 encoder there's also a slide about
this
one and from there it goes to banana pie
with a status display in front
and a very cheap at this point very old
artist that's enough to store the data
for the whole weekend
from there it goes to a five port
gigabit switch
and from there it goes either to the
front box or wherever we find network
and then it goes into the fosdem vlan
video vlan and then it goes from there
right
exactly um maybe just to give you an
idea of what one of these boxes costs
um the total price for it all of this
what you saw until now
um is about 650 700 euros
of which the bulk is actually the hd64
encoder which is which goes for about
400 euros
so just to give you an idea of what one
of these costs
so and this is a standard atx power
supply we have the power good signal
of course tied to 5 volts so it's always
on
second it sees power just flip the
switch is flipped then it's on
and then we have five volt connectors
and one twelve
fault connector for the h.264 encoder
which is quite hard yeah we standardized
on those so we could use the atx
so no inline vaults no nothing you know
nothing else yeah nothing special
so this is one of our biggest blocking
items at this point and
we've been using these since 2014 as
well
so it's in anything to 720p hdmi
so we have vga we have hdmi but it can
be full hd right but we use it for 720p
because we do a 720p for everything
which is good enough
it used to be dirt cheap chinese shanzai
hardware that is like yeah but no
questionable in some ways but stable
yeah uh but it's almost impossible to
get
any more so 2015 and it's chinese so
it's there one moment and it's gone the
next um
and well there you can go and have a
look at it later because i didn't manage
to fill
so the big gap over here is where
another um one of the shots from here
should go and it's
i didn't have time to put it in today so
there's already too many pictures
in this whole thing yeah this box grabs
hdmi and outputs
a scale a skilled version of it so
actually it can grab
exactly it normalizes it can grab vga
hdmi or composites
and it outputs hdmi in a normalized
resolution to capture that
right yes so we'll get to that okay
because the same company manufacturers
also
yeah we know but i think we're not sure
whether it's the same cpu being running
there we haven't tried to look i don't
think many people have this scaler
people have been the people have been
working with the other devices the
hdmi to ethernet version people have
been reverse engineering that i'm using
exactly but we don't think it's the same
hardware actually because this
chip um the markings are layers lasered
off
and which yeah and it has uart
but it's encrypted so if you can break
it it would actually help um yeah not
for us anymore hopefully in the year but
yeah
anyway so then the black magic gate
susic 4 encoder the most expensive thing
in there
the most hot thing in there and the most
awkward to use
um yeah black box um luckily it was
reverse engineered already before
you guys started with it because i
wasn't there yet at that time so at
least with the video stuff
so if you look at the slides of it on
you can click on the link and see the
work that timo
and you all know the stuff from the
broadcom driver and a few other
wi-fi and other drivers that you have to
go and extract the firmware
and upload it and then it's even then
it's very picky about the resolutions it
takes because the resolution i need for
our test hardware is also not working on
that
thing so yeah so we came into the
project at the point where
like into the first and video project at
the point where we already had this
hardware
and we wanted to get something as close
to free and open
as we could possibly do so the first
thing we did was like
well look for just extracting the
firmware and running with it
well just throwing a binary blob but it
was the best we could do
but at least with a mainline kernel and
and stuff like that
so yeah so the next thing for me as a
song c developer as
one of the founders of songs is the
biggest eyesore in the whole thing
and i've been complaining each and every
time the first time i saw it i was like
why did you do this but these guys were
not responsible because
otherwise we would have chosen something
very obvious somebody who talked an hour
ago it's faith and of course oli mix
is what we should have done but it was
all set in stone back then already we
have to have like 60 70 of these devices
laying around so yeah
so yeah any reason to not use this magic
board that they do
for linuxcom australia and for some of
the
unconferences so so we are
in active communication with like
almost all these people like the depconf
people in particular
um there's several
it's expensive
it's difficult to deploy on such a
massive scale because it needs to be
well it needs to be tended to like a
little child
uh yeah i i'm sorry but like
yeah no i never used it i just read
about it and was always curious to try
it but i ended up with that
hdmi to internet grabber because it
costs like
20 times less than that exactly
of course then you're right to use it
okay so um one of the reasons why we
made so many compromises on so many
things that we picked out is ease and
speed of deployment
so we get to the venue well we have the
venue available from noon on friday
and by the evening all 30 rooms must be
working um and we were pretty good this
year like 1700 we were done
exactly so um speed and efficiency and
predictability
um is what we're looking for and that's
why we made a lot of compromises
yeah yeah i i want to stress that like
i really admire the work that goes into
this
fpga based stuff like that mitro and and
other people are
uh i know i know uh are doing
so like definitely it's a really really
good thing what they are doing but our
use case
is a tiny bit special with the focus on
fast deployment massive scale deployment
and and a very very very low budget
so yeah so yeah this gets this runs the
bmd tools from teemo
talks to the h264 encoder and uploads
the forum firmware and this and that
um it streams over its gigabit ethernet
port which is
more usually are there any all winter
820 devices without gigabit
does anybody do that you do that okay
nobody nobody does that or okay
and then we use setup for local backup
because at one point we
we lost some videos because some disc
was gone somewhere
a few years ago so it's being stored in
multiple locations offsite on site and
in the box itself
we used an sd card for the file system
at this point we displayed the status
it's this black thing you saw in front
of the
of the box that's a status display we
will talk about it later a bit and it
controls the scalar
which is probably the most interesting
hack of the last few years but we'll get
that in a bit
and since last year we are running
mainline ubuntu and mainline kernel
because paul kochiarkowski because of
all the work of the sunset community
and we threw paul kotchalkowski in lcd
and he implemented that for us he
was our hardware enablement developer
manager the last two years and we miss
him and we hope that he comes back
next year because we missed it
yeah so this is gary's
special feature all you
right so the tape that for for for
correctness the tape is all me
that's here um here he has created a 3d
printed usb holder
for this little thing up there and it
goes into the usb socket that you see up
there it's
genius but the real genius comes now
right so um in the first year that we
were using the boxes
one of the things that really frustrated
me was
controlling the scaler so you need to
input some settings so that it will
output the right resolution and it will
actually use hdmi input instead of vga
input etc etc
the scalar being inside the box is hard
to reach
i mean it has basically two control
interfaces it's got four buttons on the
front
hardware buttons and it's got an ir
receiver so first i thought well
you know probably the best way to
approach this is to solder something
to the buttons and then make something
to control the buttons via the gpio pins
of the
banana pi but then that would involve
on top of opening all the boxes that
would require a lot of soldering
um i would have i would have to take out
all of the scalers do the soldering do
the wiring et cetera et cetera
so it would not be fun exactly it
wouldn't be fun
so i thought of one or two years of a
more
stupid way of approaching this
and i was thinking maybe i could do
something with the ir receiver on the
board
now one thing about the banana pie is it
has
it also has an ir receiver but it's not
got an ir transmitter
so that was a bit annoying first i
thought that
well maybe i could use usb and you know
control and ir
transmitter that way something something
but that would
require you know getting ir transmitters
etc etc
i wasn't really looking forward to that
so i thought a bit further
and figured that an ir signal
is actually just a waveform now
what on the banana pi could emit a
waveform
easily without you know too much
fuss so i
built an ir receiver that goes into the
audio in
of my laptop and i captured and
all of the ir signals that were emitted
by the remote control
my actual remote control you were going
through the menus of the road
control exactly and i captured the
waveforms um in just plain wave files
um i edit them a bit so that i had the
proper signals audacity to the risk
exactly i used audacity for that um and
then i had a couple of wav files
that i could play on my computer they
would make funny sounds if i played them
through my speakers
but if i attached an ir transmitter to
my audio
out port so to my audio plug audio audio
out jack
on my laptop the ir transmitter would
actually
emit right pulses and i could control
the scaler
using my sound card in my laptop
and so i opened up all the boxes
install the an ir leds right in front of
the ir receiver
um using um just a
3.5 millimeter check going to the banana
pi
um and now we can remote control the
scaler just by playing some wav files
from the banana pie
and you can you can cycle i can cycle
through the entire menu of the
lankan device just from the banana pie
and i can see the output on the stream
so yeah with a bit of a delay but yeah
with a bit of a delay so it's not
perfect
but instead of opening all the boxes and
using a screwdriver to punch
all the buttons in the right way i can
now do it remotely so
i was happy so one of the big issues we
have at the boxes
is this double scaling that we're doing
so
this is why speakers normally get told
to do
4x3 because our scalers are being set by
our waveforms to
do 4x3 conversions so if your laptop is
running
uh 16 by nine then you'll have this
first letter box effect of the
of the uh what do you want to say kitty
it's not entirely true so our scalars
are actually set to
um so the the output that goes to the
encoder is actually 720p
and it will um right exactly
so the problem is um it's a bit
complicated to explain
so um imagine
you have a 43 projector so a projector
protecting a forgery image which this
one isn't
um and remember what you said at the
beginning that the edid
transmitted to the laptop of the speaker
is the first one the splitter picks up
you will probably see the the projector
there
so your your laptop will see a 4-3
projector and use and you know adapt its
resolution to that
and imagine that you have made 69 slides
because you thought that this was a
modern time and we would all use 69 you
were wrong
um so now you have
69 slides that you made outputted on a
4-3 resolution
and then sent into the box now on our
end
we want 720p so our scalar
will convert your 43 signal which has
already two black borders added by your
laptop here yeah so that's the
second one and it will add two borders
on the side again
so now we have a double letterbox effect
so if you see on a stream that there's
lots of black borders around it
that is the reason why that is and it's
a bit silly
but it is the way it is i we can't
change it in this design
so every november there is a video
hackathon going on
in the living offices where all the
boxes are usually living most of the
year
and last year we started chatting a bit
we had both seen this
adafruit adapter that is built
for hdmi to lcd conversion so that you
could use an hdmi connection for
raspberry pi for instance because the
raspberry pi doesn't have that much else
and then drive an lcd with that well
what is coming out of that is a parallel
signal it's parallel rgb
with two sinks and a display enable and
maybe a backlight enable
but this is usually also a signal that
you can take in
on a on any soc that has like a camera
interface that is a bit wider than
anything else
and this is how i got thinking just
november 2018 about maybe we can do
something else
what if we feed this directly into the
soc so in that case we will be able to
drive this projector directly
and do all sorts of fancy things get rid
of all the all the
borders we can provide our own ed ideas
so
that edid so that everybody uses the
exact same resolution
if we get an onboard h264 encoder then
we have that problem solved as well
if we then use open source hardware like
for instance all the mx stuff
then we have open source hardware
mainline support comes with that
and we can make it small and cheap
and we get all our wishes granted so
that was the state last year last year
we had a few chats here i had a chat
with
svetan with fazer with you guys about we
should do this we should do this
and the lucky thing was that on monday
morning every year
um me and egbert i can do a bonus go for
the
we've been thrown out of the hotel let's
have breakfast
and i started explaining what we have
been talking about all weekend and uber
his face lighted up and said well
i work for the darmstadt university i do
electronics there
uh i could prototype this for you i
could design this for you because this
was the only thing that we couldn't
solve
before that because drivers and stuff
that's what i usually do and i could
try to marshall in other people from the
sunshine project but who has said
i could do that and ue is actually here
and he's been designing our board so
please
put your hands together for uber
so he solved the last question we had
then and
ever since then it's just can the
hardware do it and can we get the right
resolution so
design resolution is 720p because
while we don't need that much more we
could maybe do a full hd
but 720p is bad enough and people are
already abusing this many pixels that
they have
because not every person develops slides
that can be read in the back of the room
so the slc is naturally an alt albino
because it's probably one of the most
open source flindy chips out there even
though all winter isn't always being
that open source friendly it's one of
the chips with the fewest restrictions
no drm
stuff there's almost no binary blobs
around anymore but most of you will know
that
if you're in this room we ended up
choosing the olympic slime 2 but there
will be a separate slide about that
and we first thought about the tfp 401
module from
texas instruments which has a module
from adafruit
but the issue with that is that it's
actually a dvi to
parallel decoder so no idea so no audio
and we thought that we could maybe use a
splitter or something and then use one
of those
hdmi to i2s decoders i2s is the the
digital sound that philips developed
ages ago but it turns out that
these are just abusing the cable of hdmi
and doing nothing else
so we looked a bit further and then we
found the adv 7611 from analog devices
and we had a chat at
embedded world as well with some analog
devices got in there and
apparently analog devices is one of the
most open source friendly
uh makers of these sort of chips this as
an all-time
display driver developer that wasn't the
case in the
early 2000s so that things have changed
there
now the second we or we found out that
we wanted
to use this chip google turned up
something something quite interesting oh
yeah me and my funny slides so this is
where the plan got together
so the line two is what we're using of
course
um is sitting right here in front you
all sound just now
luckily it exposed almost all the pins
on its
tiny connectors which are a bit
difficult to work with
but we're also very stable so when you
when you have the daughter board
attached to this this will never ever
come loose on itself
so it has it's a bit of a disadvantage
and it's a massive advantage at the same
time
uh and we only had to change the
um back display enable signal for the
lcd
with something else so that we could
have full 24 bit rgb capture on
on the lime 2. so this is the board that
we're designing our first generation
hardware around
so when i googled for the adv 67611
we found this and this happened and it
also wasn't the sanctity main list just
at a time where i was no longer doing
that much songs
so in the second half of 2014 is when i
went down there a bit
these guys here are cutting her here
pitch and javier lucas were designing
pretty much what we were trying to
do as well they were still using a lime
and they were having issues with getting
the signal right
but that's something for slightly later
in this talk and
they ended up kind of losing steam they
had other things in their lives
happening and it kind of died down
but the second i sent them an email i
got an email back and a week later we
had
their test chips that they got from
analog devices and we have one of their
boards as well which
is in my backpack down there because i
wasn't prepared enough
so we have this here as well this is the
exact board that i photographed this
morning at some point they will get this
back but
this is how friendly they are and we
will be reusing their open source
hardware design for our future designs
as well
we will just adapt it to our own needs
so the work they've done
we will continue with that and we will
finish it
so our plan low costs
the hardware is not so yeah um you can
all read
and i like to i just had to put the
world chuggable in there it's just
let's go for a breakfast it's just
that's where we want to go we want to
have it break sized
we want to be able to send people um to
every building over the whole campus
with a backpack with at least two
devices in there and that all the rooms
have two devices as well
so that people are no longer running
with one of the two we have two spare
boxes and thanks to this one three spare
boxes
and the rest is being spread around and
if something breaks then there is one
guy
running with one of those boxes all
across the campus so
that is usually not a nice thing to have
it's not easy taking
some of these into your hand luggage on
the plane you know
so this is our this would already be big
for what we we won't have
so if it's already this size we would be
very happy but it would
go a lot smaller than that and then it's
just two in a backpack and then send off
a video guy and
we don't have to physically see them
again the whole day
anymore let me just talk on iris i don't
like the screwdrivers and the
cables and the clippers and whatever
you need to fix these things when when
something gets loose inside either
and if there's that many boxes if
there's that many boxes spread around
then you just have enough in your
backpack
then there's no more worries you just
swap one for the other
so the big advantage and as a display
driver guy is that we can drive the
projector correctly
so this thing is what is what i
photographed this morning when it was
still dark outside
um it's the only the only box doing it
in the whole of fusdom
that actually when there's no cable
attached it will actually do it properly
otherwise it's the scalar saying that i
have no signal
so we can use the native resolution keep
the aspect ratio as it is and we can do
a very interesting
things because um we have so many
display layers going on here that this
is now just a png
are shown on one layer but we can make
it all dynamic
so that it could show the next stock is
coming up it's going to be that
we could for instance down here we could
show this many minutes left so that the
speaker can immediately see it or the
time's up
if zombies attack then we can also put
it on there
uh or stuff like fosdem's over fuzz them
is over everybody leave or clean up
and we can all control that remotely so
it will solve at least the projector
side of things as well
and make this whole thing a whole lot
nicer to look for
then we get full control over mpeg-4
encoding
yeah we're not tied to aac because the
ccc guys
they're probably in here as well there
they want to move to something else in
acc
we don't care the hardware encoder does
h.264 whatever it's packaged in it
doesn't care
that's something that we do through
probably ffmpeg or something like that
but we're far away from the well a bit
away from that still
so there's another display thing that's
going on on this side you see what's
happening
on for every of those of the standard
fasdon boxes let me just use the cursor
if you want to wake up um this is all
dynamic it changes every second
basically as fast as the ffmpeg process
on the on the banana
pie can grab a frame from the live
stream i'm gonna render it to a png
on the cpu and then show it on the
on the screen so it's dynamic and it
updates every
five ish seconds maybe so when it's when
it doesn't have an ip connection i will
show it
as well on this side this is just me
showing off what we can do with our
future project because all of this is
just a png to show off what's going on
the all winner display engine has a dark
background
so black it has a background color then
it has a
40 opacity um
real time full rgb 720p
um rendering at 60 frames per second
this is actually eating quite a lot of
memory boundary because we're scaling
down and we're trashing the cache all
the time but this is real time
this is 60 frames per second instead of
one per second
and these things are just a png and this
is also uh two pngs being shown there
so there's four layers happening there
already and we can do a lot more so we
could draw individual lines
in individual bits of frame buffer and
then show them which will make it a lot
more
faster and we are using so little cpu
with this we're not doing anything with
it it's basically like a few percent
so the last one is the last one we will
solve for our first generation hardware
is that we in this room it's okay
because we only have one microphone
and the microphone is attached to the
camera if you have
a handheld microphone it will have
another receiver as well
and then they have to be mixed together
which they usually do in front
in front because then they can drive the
speakers that are in there
are in the bigger rooms and then there
is a big xlr cable going all the way
back
just taking the exact same route as the
ethernet cable
and it's always a bit of fun and games
dragging these xlr cables across the
campus and then putting them in each and
every room and we want to get rid of
that in time as well
so if we can get the latency down then
we might be able to
have the box in the back also taken two
microphone channels
and then send it to the front and send
it out over the over the speakers as
well
if we can get the latency down but wait
and see if we ever get there
well we will get there but when we ever
get there so this is the board that
so last may we had a meeting in
frankfurt which is kind of halfway for
all of us
so it was us to me and uber lives just
one
what 20 kilometers away or something
like that and then we chatted a bit of
what we are really going to
do and while we are going to now how
we're going to attack this
and in the end we decided to go back to
the adafruit tfp401 module the dvi
decoder as something that would give us
hardware quickly
that i could start developing the
software for this
um so uber designed this in the space of
what a week and a half or so
it's just a connector there's a few
resistors in there and then
one and then one voltage shifter for vga
probably but we're not
using the vga yet no i think it's
totally passive
totally passive okay so you had some
space left that's why you added the jtag
adapter
um i first tried to use the
um the csi0 connection it's not me
csi it's the it's a chinese version of
it so it's still old-school parallel
it's called cmos sensor interface thank
you
all winner and this was a dead end so i
spent three weeks trying to get that to
work
and then cleaning up the register tables
and then thinking no i'm not going to
use that lit
it's just 12 registers i've dealt with a
few more let's just write it from
scratch and see where we are
i will at some point have to feed this
back to the existing csi driver
but i needed to have this thing working
faster that we verify what we're doing
it also has an lcd connector we have the
vga connector we have vga out for free
so why not just implement that as well
one thing that hasn't happened yet
nobody has read in the software for that
maybe something for the future as well
not that important
the lime 2 provides the hdmi output
the adafruit adapter oh in case let's
move to the next slide
it's this bit on the side and this is
what we've been running all weekend
now you can tell that we've been
in this room yeah only in this room
there's only one setup that we have we
have seven of these boards
seven of these set setups adapt uh
implemented there's
two in leuven oh you have one i have
two and then fazil and marian have one
each as well
so we are running this and this thing is
very stupid you can't talk twist
the dvi uh decoder and it doesn't deal
well with
quarter megahertz resolutions dot clock
resolutions and you can tell because
the first four pixels up there are a bit
late
and our capture engine is a bit weird
it doesn't have a display enable it
needs to be told when the syncs
happen and it needs to know this many
pulses
after the sync horizontal or vertical
happens is when we start capturing
and because this module is a bit stupid
the first line is always messed up
i've had this running for a full day
capturing full hd
at 60 frames per second i think it was
like 14 terabytes of data
that it tested with a special
overlays that i developed that i could
figure out here and you know the other
corners where all the pixels were
correct there and we lost
400 pixels always the first pixel up
there
over millions of
of frames so if we over a
flat cable like this as well so if we
move to the adv
which we can tell to boost the signal as
well
if we have this all on the same board we
will not lose a single pixel
on full hd resolution the issue we do
have is that the all wear 820 is
pretty limited in memory and bus
bandwidth and we run into that mainly
because we're
using the scalar badly on the status
screen but
yeah so the upcoming design we will
reuse
the work that the heroes and gabriel did
and add our own connectors to that so
the lcd connector we want to keep
because status is very important
vga is nice to have and we've mostly
implemented it already
in hardware it's an easy thing to do vga
okay um software it will be a bit more
work and we will also have
to built the audio breakout connector
so this is the whole pipeline we're
using now
one and other interesting thing about
the csi1 engine so the capture engine is
that it doesn't do
proper rgb as we know it
it does this planar so we have a
separate plane for
each channel so a separate bit of memory
for red a separate bit of memory for
green and separate
memory for blue nobody does that i think
yesterday somebody said
or it was daniel or something who said
amigas used to do it but
amigos were a few years ago so what
okay so v4l linux doesn't know about it
and drm doesn't know about it either
one interesting thing is that no display
engine usually can handle that
but if you have y u v you have color
space conversion and you have a matrix
three by three
if you put a unity matrix in there you
have the exact same result
so that's what we do there um then i've
been having tons of fun in games with
the
with the display engine at what we've
been driving the status lcd
this poor status lcd for three months at
150 more
four hertz because the clocks of this
pipeline and this pipeline ended up
being tied together
and one changed and then ruined the
clock for the other
and so i've been fixing that sort of
stuff i've been adding
overlays more overlays than um kms can
handle
kms has a because it was originally
planes for kms were originally made for
intel
and at the time when sandy bridge
happened
and at the time of sandy bridge they had
finally gotten to the stage where we can
do it all in the 3d engine and we have
like one or two overlays left
or three something like that very very
little
back in that day i was i was actually
consulting for you for a bit
and i had to go and get 2011 i had to go
and get an
older epc to be able to get an older
display engine where i could play with
planes a bit more to implement one
version of hardware composer that
fell off victoria said in the meantime
but yeah
each of these display pipelines supports
overlays and kms supports 32 in total
for the whole driver so we have four
base layers we have a hardware cursor we
have a background color and we have
sprites which are not scalable are a
single color format but it's like 2k
on 2k and then it's just a memory
bandwidth issue and then we can place
all sorts of display games now for the
encode pipeline since we have this
really weird
color format um we have to put tie a few
engines together
so the g2d part is the one that will
converge from
r8 g8b8 to nv12
which is half resolution so 12 bits it's
a yv420
in case anybody knows that sort of stuff
or wants to know that sort of stuff
in between that is always a part of the
the encode engine that's the media isp
and it can't handle the resolution what
it can do is do thumbnailing
so it will take one picture and then
rescale it i haven't gotten it to work
yet for any scaling
but that's what we hopefully can get to
work and can
make use for our status display that
we're no longer trashing the bus
and the h264 encode i have been doing a
bit of archaeology and by this time it
was already almost
october november i got jens kuska from
the linux team
his old code from 2014 and all the
various forks that removed this
copyright and remove those commits i got
them all figured out and did a bit of
archaeology because i like those guys
and this is how open source actually
should work uh
and in the end i moved all the code from
user space into the kernel
and we are hitting with the display with
the bus being trashed
um for a 40 second file we require 20
seconds to do real-time encoding at
seven up to do encoding at 720p so we're
twice real time if we stop trashing the
bus we are four times real time
so we have space left to maybe if we
stop trashing the bus
bus to do do one atp but i can't promise
this at this point
but all of these things have been
verified so it's time to move on all
these engines
the fact that the capture could do this
resolution with with a parallel
connection the fact that the
um the mpeg encoder could do the h264
encoder could do this
all of this were still unknowns and
we've all tested it and it's been all
been working
pretty well so we are moving forward
slowly
so the work done i think i meant
went over most of the things already now
there's a tool that
is written specifically for this using
kms and v4 linux it's
now heavily threaded which will change
but it's just keeping all the buffers in
flight
and we have so many things happening on
overlays
we have all the data coming in and going
to different places
that i don't think anybody in this
planet will ever be able to
write a g-stream or pipeline for that we
can't debug standard g-striper pipelines
this one will be something special no so
this will probably be a custom tool that
does all sorts of stuff that is very
specific for conferences but which will
show
anybody else who wants to play with it
to how to do this
also this tool is being built up at the
same time that the drivers are being
built up and
verified so these things are growing
together which is why it is what it is
yeah so high memory bandwidth is our
biggest problem
so what we're going to do is now i need
to go test the adm hdmi active signal so
at this point
whenever there's no frames coming in for
because my code is that bad
the threading code if it doesn't see
frames then
it waits for 160 of a frame and if it
doesn't see a few frames
then it will say oh let's show this
other image the one that you see when
the when the speaker unplugs
and this is six months of work to have
this one feature here that's that's a
nice thing right so six months of work
for that
no so i need to verify i2s coming from
the adv
from the hdmi decoder and
verify the audio and then uber can go
and
finish the design of the actual board
and start prototyping it and getting it
made
and then there's a few other bits and
bobs that i need to go to there's a lot
of work ahead still
but everything is looking as it
will work everything that we've wanted
it to do
it has done so far and it's just a
matter of just doing it and we
are doing it so the future is then
with the external audio connectors that
we will have is that we will have
balanced audio
for xlrs that we can use the standard
microphones and this and then plug this
directly
we will need to have phantom power for
that which is going to be a bit of an
issue to go from five volts to that but
that's what uber can work on after he's
done
with the first thing one other thing we
want to do is the a separate
switch that we have oh apparently time's
up
okay um yeah then let's have the next
talker so the deployments very quickly
this is how we're gonna deploy this year
we're gonna we still haven't talked to
the froscom guys we've been too busy
maybe we should have done that before
yeah yeah but the ccc guys are doing
most of frostcon and the dev rooms are
not being recorded and we
will take try to take that over and test
our hardware then we will do open fest
because
that's already always involved with and
then in a year from now there is
this this conference that nobody heard
of that we might want to roll this out
and by the way the dates you saw there
are not confirmed so don't book anything
no it's just it just
it just me guessing and here's some urls
so that it's in the slides and
question time i'm really sorry but this
will have to go outside