my
slsr from the beginning my name is deb
goodkin i'm the
executive director of the freebsd
foundation and i'm here
to represent the freebsc project and i
talked about
freebsd and it's it's sort of similar to
benny's talk
introduction of freebsd but i also try
to incorporate
things for people who are already
involved in the community too
and so so if you are a contributor
already
some things might be new some things
might you already
know so i i try to make it so
it was uh informative and welcome
welcoming talk to um
people from all areas and the talk that
i'm giving now is a talk i typically
give
to people at like linux conferences and
other open source conferences
around the world so
we will get started here so my goal
today is to show the long history
and i know benny um so actually i'm sort
of assuming a lot of people in here
um was here for the previous talk but
i but also i know a lot of people laugh
so there's probably a lot of new people
in here
so first i want to start before i go
over the goals of my talk is to find out
so who is new to bsd in general
so good that's a good number so that's
awesome and who
and um and who in here uses linux
okay so almost everyone in here raised
their hand
so so that's okay so my goal here is to
um is to share um information and our
history
about freebsd in particular and i'm
going to talk about why people use it
what freebsd is
and why you should use it and maybe
hopefully
contribute to our project and then
lastly i'm going to highlight
what we as the foundation and project
what we've been doing around the world
and in
advocating for the project
so i'll start with free what is freebsd
since there's a lot of people in here
who are new to the bsds
and um and so i assume that's also
previously
so so i put i use this slide
and not to be mean to tux because i
think tux is really cute
and um but it's really a lot of people
um
do you still think that free bc is a
linux distribution
and so i use this to make a point that
that it's not it's totally separate now
and and it came from a different place
and so
i'm going to highlight that but i
want to share those slides here too
right and this is recent i mean this was
i think
opensource.com which is uh it's
basically a
website that's hosted by red hat and
uh and they were doing this poll and um
and so this is another reason why people
get confused that
you know i mean if i were new to unix
and linux
and you know any of any of the unix-like
type of operating systems i would just
think that freebsd was another
distribution
and so what's that i know i wonder well
we could probably find out
and so and i did read in the comments
too on here that
one of the reasons why they did this it
was because
they wanted to include freebsd but what
they really should have done was what's
your favorite
unix-like operating system and i think
that would have been
better for at least for us well and i
think for
for people in the world so freebsd i
look at freebsd
the previously world as three different
components
and so on on the top there you have the
actual
open or the open source operating system
it's
the binary that you download off the
freebsd.org website onto your computer
and you run it
the middle one there is the actual
project and there are some people here
from the community
but the project is made up of thousands
of contributors
and then the last one is the foundation
and that's what i run
and represent and um and we are a 501c3
which is
us it's a
designation within our government and
how we file taxes and what it means
basically is we're a public charity
and we are for the public good and so
our whole focus
is to support the project and the
community so we're not a trade
association which is what the linux
foundation is
we're actually here for the community
for the project
and and to support them so it is freebsd
i mean it's when the oldest largest most
successful
open source projects in the world and
we've been around we'll be celebrating
our 27th
anniversary in june and it's a complete
operating system so when you think of
so i so i will compare previously with
with linux just because that's what most
people are familiar with
but linux when you talk about linux it's
the kernel and so then you have
all all these distributions that's why
you have this whole list of
distributions
and that puts the whole operating system
together so when you're running your
computer
you're not just running linux you have
to have that whole
uh user and lend the tools documentation
all that kind of stuff so freebsd is all
of that this is very
cohesive coherent operating system we
support over 33
actually i think the number the number
increases every day
we may be at 35 000 third-party uh
packages which really means that when
you're using it as your desktop and
you want to access the internet you
could have a browser that you can
install in a
word processor and whatever software
that you want to use
almost anything is supported
like i said we have over a thousand
contributors or thousands we have
uh 400 between 400 and 500
active source committers and we run on
many platforms
and and so it's hardware as well as as
cloud
platforms and uh and there's millions of
deployments out there
so i saw this from uh uh someone from
netflix gave a talk last year at the
main track actually it was really good
and um and so i actually stole his
abridged uh
version of where freebsd came from
because i really liked it but i added
nice graphics to mine
and uh but it's really a tnt unix
started in 1969
and um and so you may have you may be
familiar
with the anniversary that was celebrated
i think it was last november
in um new jersey where unix was created
and then the bsd started um
from that it was a t
actually if you heard warren erlash's
talk yesterday
um or if you didn't i would recommend
watching the video
of it he gave a talk in the main track
on the early enx's
it was really interesting so
so that's available as well as i believe
mad dog
john hall is giving a talk a keynote
later today on
he's like the google of unix and
computing he's pretty he's amazing
so uh so i would recommend both both
those talks
and uh but the bsd is berkeley software
distribution
and um and so so unix was licensed to a
few universities and berkeley was one of
them
they come came up with berkeley unix
it's also referred to
berkeley software distribution or
berkeley research
unix there's various names of it and and
that's where a team of people actually
worked on
improving it and and it became the
platform for freebsd and netbsd
and so this is a little visual
of the timeline see if i can get it to
play
where so i just talked about how enx
started in 69
and then um you know the c language
was developed there to make it more
portable
and and then different versions of these
bsd some of the research and features
that were added
to it i'm not going to go over each one
because for me really what i care about
is in 1993 freebsd
starting and that's also when that bsc
started
so let's see if i can stop this but we
have a great timeline on our
website and when i say our website it's
the freebsdfoundation.org
website and it was it was fun to put
together
so let me start again because i just
let's see here
i'd show from here yeah
what's happened wait here we go yeah
a little technical difficulty here um
so it's starting there and i believe i
need to go here
so i know this is
actually this is nice because everyone's
pretty close on so i like to use this
because it really shows
the lineage of freebsd it shows
unix at the top and how it branched into
a lot of proprietary closed source
type of operating systems i mean when i
graduated
college which was a few years ago i used
ibm aix
and so it was sort of in the prehistoric
days and
um and we and so that's what we used at
ibm and it was actually before pcs came
out
yeah but hp had their version and
various companies like those large
corporations they had their version of
unix
and but if you see if you look here on
your left
and so here i zoom in a little bit more
so what i'm trying to show here
is the lineage of freebsd and how it
descended from the berkeley unix
which descended from the original unix
that was developed by ken thompson in 69
and and then i included i have an arrow
there
on the left of of linux and how
i mean it didn't just magically appear
but he did base it on he didn't model it
after unix but um but it
didn't descend from that from that
years of development and when you look
at the people who
worked on bsd at berkeley they were
they were university students they were
mostly phd students
some of the people bill joy if you don't
know who he is i mean he's one of the
co-founders of sun
and he oversaw the bsd project
and so you had um these years of
development at berkeley
of these college students so if their
phd students are probably
like in their early 20s and so then when
freebsd
started a decade later then you
actually we still had a lot of those
people continuing to support and develop
on it
so the difference in age when you look
at when linux started versus when
freebsd continued or started that you
actually had 10 years difference in
the age of the developers and so you had
sort of a more mature group of people
who were developing that
and you could look at that in you know
two different ways you could say well it
was young
and you know maybe it's more innovative
it's but it's
you know but i'm just trying to
highlight what the differences were
in the um the people who are part of
that
so who uses freebsd so i mean when i
tell people
that yeah you're probably using freebsd
they're always surprised because
a lot most people haven't heard of
freebsd before but what i did here
these aren't the only companies that use
freebsd
what we try to do is choose marquee
companies or recognizable companies that
you're familiar with that use freebsd
so most likely you use freebsd i mean if
you have an iphone
uh you know mac os and ios were
developed from
freebsd they still follow for the
the command line they actually come to
our conferences still
netflix is a big known company that uses
freebsd
for the high performance they they get
on the streaming so
when you're watching a netflix video
you know tv show whatever that's all
streaming
on freebsd servers trivago
the playstation and i understand the 5.2
will be freebsd
so i won't go through all these bullets
but
but really you know the the main reason
why
people why users use previously and and
it will be different between like a
individual user like us in this room
versus like a corporation
a corporation like say sony's a good
example
why they may use freebies uh because of
licensing and so we do follow the bse
license
and so linux's gpl previously is bsd
and so it's a permissive license which
means you can take
the code and you can make your own
changes and you don't have to give it
back to the community and it's a
philosophy that
the community believes in that they are
happy
that someone else is using their code so
they don't feel the need that
they need to get recognition for it and
but there's also companies that use it
for the same reason but that
they actually upstream almost all their
changes so netflix actually
is a really good example of a company
that does that
and and i would highly recommend
watching uh
jonathan looney's talk from fosdem last
year it was in the main track
and he talked about how netflix follows
the
developer current branch of freebsd
and and how they successfully do that
so it was a really popular and well
received talk
and then just the fact that it's a
cohesive operating system and then just
this
history of development too is another
reason
why why people like to use freebsd
users like us then we'll use it because
of
um yes stability and reliability
actually that's why
companies will use it too but also for
the community
so we're also known as a very friendly
and welcoming community too
and the documentation we're known for
excellent documentation so
when you're installing freebsd and i'm
actually going through this process
right now so i have freebsd on here
i run it on a virtual machine and but i
also have another a new
laptop that i have at home so sitting
and waiting for me to install freebsd
and since i don't do this a lot
i can search for help on when i run into
issues there's also a really good
community that i can reach out to and
get questions
answered so how the project
works so first i'll start off with uh
since we descended from berkeley they
had a whole
model that they followed on development
since it was a
fairly large software development effort
on their part and how they
control everything and so we still
follow that model
and it's so so the first thing that i
include is just the fact that so
so i work for the freebsc foundation and
then we have the freebsd project and
actually in the next slide i think
i have a better um graphic of this but
we
we are a separate organization so we
don't run
previously the project we can't tell
them
what to do or have any control our whole
purpose
is to support them and so if there's any
critical needs
any holes in the project then if we have
the funding we step in
and and help fill those needs we have a
core team
actually when the core team member is
he's not in this room right now but he's
we do have a free bsd table and uh
let's see what room oh one of the
buildings
in h i think okay
yeah so it's the main building where
when you go in and
and they had the files done t-shirts and
all that kind of stuff so we're there
and um and so bendick represents the
core
team and that's actually um elected
every two years we're coming out for
elections
and i believe may and anyone who's a
committer has a vote
and um and then it's a mentoring system
to get your commitment so if so for
example
i'm doing documentation and so i submit
patches for changes
and so eventually someone will recognize
that and then they'll offer me
a mentorship and then hopefully i'll get
my commitment that way
i just need a little more time to do
that and it's very collaborative
so this is my version of org chart for
the project so it's nothing official
and really didn't have room for all the
the functional teams but basically we
have these functional teams
and it's a great way to sort of organize
how things
are supported within the project and it
also allows people who
are interested in different areas to get
involved in those areas that they're
interested in so
say for example if you're interested in
security then you
and you have background then you can be
part of the security team we have
release and ports and so we have various
different
type of functional teams that make up
the project
and then the way i did it was sort of
you know a top-down approach where you
have the core team
and the core team is basically like i
view them as like the
the board of directors of the project
and so
they oversee it but they also don't have
control you can
i mean as a developer you can work on
what you're interested in working on
and that's philosophy of the project and
the core team steps in to help
with um you know sometimes it's
administration
and sometimes it's you know developer
relationships but they're sort of like
those managers that you
go to and so i just talked about the
core team
and and that's actually a list of
what what they work on and so what i'm
trying to point out here is that we
don't have one person who oversees the
whole project
and has the year or an a what goes in or
how things are run
so it is definitely democratically run
and i like to show this graph so we did
this graph back in
so about a half a year ago and and what
i'm trying to
highlight here is the age distribution
of our and this is actually the
committers and not all the thousands of
contributors we have and
showing not only are we diverse as far
as countries and cultures represented
but also age so we are getting
new people involved in the project and
and probably more importantly getting
younger people involved too
because they're the ones who are going
to continue the one
the age near the end of that graph
a lot of those are actually people
who've been with the with previously
and bsd since the beginning which is
really
cool because we have new people who are
joining
and we love working with them and we
have these
older more experienced people who are
part of the project and know the history
and and they're so welcoming that
they love talking to the younger people
and and helping them
along with the project and so it's
really neat to see
so how the releases work um
so it's basically the so we follow this
the principle of least astonishment
and it's basically things work don't
don't change them
and don't don't break things that
already work
and um and also across major releases
so when you when we have a new release
then
it's gonna you know i don't know
99 that you know confidence that it will
work that
you won't have to um back out
that um that update so we have two types
of releases major
and the uh point releases and so right
now where we're at
is the next major release will be 13.0
uh there isn't a schedule for that yet
but i i would guess
the end of the year early next year it's
every couple years
uh where there's a release schedule for
12.2
to come out and i believe 11.4
and and so we also have these sort of
policies
the rules of not breaking the avis and
apis
and then like i mentioned earlier with
netflix we have the
the two different uh branches and so we
call
current also referred to as a developer
branch and then the stable branch
and so like so for example on my
computer that i'm
installing for bsd i'm actually using
the current branch so it's the latest
and greatest version of freebsd
and what what we do is we we as a
project provide what's called a snapshot
and so every week those are run and so
that's the image
that all i downloaded on my system
but if you're you know if you but if you
want a more stable
not the development branch then we have
the stable branch too that a lot of
people use so like if i
if we do we hold workshops at
universities and in various places
and and we'll always use the stable
branch for that
so how you can or how you contribute to
the project there's very
many ways you can contribute like i said
i write documentation
i don't write code throw my background
so my background
isn't operating systems even though i've
been working with them now for almost 15
years
i'm trying to learn as much as i can but
my background is i was a firmware
engineer for many years for storage
devices
which is so different than operating
systems so
that's why i i could get back into
writing code but i choose not to and i'm
doing because i'm
already running in the foundation so it
would be difficult
but it's easy to get started
contributing and some of the suggestions
that we have would be one would be is
work on
documentation so you could translate or
improve the documentation
um you could there's many ports like i
was saying there's over 33
000 and so we always need ports
maintainers
and uh you could just go through the
peerless and and pick a
you know a problem out there that you
can fix and submit a patch for
and so yes so earlier i talked about why
people or why users use freebc this is a
list of
why companies will use freebsd
and um and really if someone asks me i
would say the two top reasons really
so the license and um and then cfs
and especially for uh data centers
uh people who really want that um
you know that reliability that they use
cfs and it's been supported in freebsd
for a very long time
and all these places where freebsd
stands out
and and the one thing that we don't have
on here that we are working on
is support on the laptop and so that's
always an issue especially with people
like us
that we want um
wasn't sure if that was like a fire
alarm
[Laughter]
so um and that so that's an area that we
are
working on it's a hard area to support
because you have so
many different technologies and then you
get new one new generations
technology cpus and um
everything and so we're but we as a
foundation actually are working on
trying to support
some of the newer hardware so more
people can get freebsd running on their
laptops
i am highlighting some of the kernel
features here i'm not going to go
through each one
it's basically a list of the a typical
kernel that has to
work in this day the user one features
are more
um what what
i think sets us apart as far as making
it
a coherent system that our user land
is developed and tested and integrated
with the kernel
from our uh from our community so it's
one group of people
that are working on all of this and so
it's very consistent
coherent and integrated
some of the other features were known
about so like i said
zfs and uh and we're very active in the
opencfs
project d-trace which was brought over
from sun
back in i think it was about 2005.
it's a dynamic tracing tool
jails i mean we really came out with the
first containerization and actually
there are
projects that are working to um
you know product size that a little bit
better
beehive actually i just came from
australia for linux coffee u
and when the original beehive developers
gave a talk there and he's getting
involved in the project again it was
originally developed for netapp
and then they open sourced it and so
so that's been a very successful feature
and the tcp were still used as reference
platform even though that was originally
developed in
bsd and capsicum actually is getting
um a little more um publicity
and it's very recent well they've been
working on this for years and it's
coming out of the university of
cambridge and they're working with arm
on a recently announced project that arm
is integrating the instruction set into
a version a cpu version that will be
on what's called the morella board and
they'll be very secure
and they have millions of
pounds funding for this project and
freebsd
has been working on this for i think
they've been working for five years
so it's very promising for
you know secure platform um
maybe iot area and um
and but a great collaborative effort
with previously
and arm so
i'll talk a little bit about the freebsd
foundation so you understand who we are
and we are celebrating our 20th
anniversary
this year we're going to celebrate it
all year but we were founded
in march 2000 we are based in boulder
colorado
uh that's where that's where i am based
and
um but we are a distributed organization
we're very
we're very small i have i haven't
counted recently but i think i have six
to eight employees and we have interns
too so that's why
uh but we have an office up in canada
too
in the waterloo area and so we have a
lot of development going on up there
and then we have a board of eight board
members and we do have
um benedict who's down at the table he's
also
on our board we are 100 funded by
donations so we're not a membership
organization and so we do reach out to
companies
and ask them to help uh help fund our
efforts
and and so we're constantly doing that
if your company is using freebsd and
benefiting then
i would ask if you could either connect
me with the right people
or ask your company to to
help us with our funding more money we
get the more
software development that we could do as
well as advocacy for the project
so this list i know so i don't know you
might be able to read this so what i try
to do with this and this is
where the freebsd around the world comes
from so we
went we participated 38 conferences
in 21 countries this was all last year
and the whole reason is to raise
awareness about freebsd
and so at a minimum people understand
what freebsd
is and hopefully you spark an
interest in people trying freebsd and
hopefully either becoming a user
or contributing back to the project
and so you can see here basically i went
in order so i didn't go by country
or anything and this doesn't include
bsd conferences or just conferences that
we sponsor around the world
but one thing i do want to point out
here is that um
like open source summit uh we did give
freebsd talk
at both of them the north america and
the european one and
if you don't know open source summit is
a linux foundation
conference used to be called linuxcon
and so
it's really important that we include
our voice in these
open source conferences and that's what
we're doing
and so um so
i actually included a list of sort of
like
the key conferences that we're going to
be at or
that are happening this year i mean as
far as conferences we're going to be at
it's we have a really long list like
that one earlier
but if you're interested in getting
involved and
or finding out more about freebsd the we
have three
major bsd conferences that i have listed
up here
as well as other conferences that we're
at
so people so this slide really is for
people who are part of the community
already or people who
who want to get involved and who want to
help us advocate for freebsd
and so what because i wasn't sure
what who all was going to be in my talk
and so
with this slide i was hoping to convince
people to go out there so
to come to conferences like this
actually this is one of
our best represented conference i think
because we have
well we had rodrigo who he organizes
this room
and a lot of people from the community
come and if you go to our table you'll
see that
not only are there usually like four
people behind the stand
but there's actually a group of us in
front of it and and it's just it because
there's so many of us we can't all stand
behind it and so it's
so it's a great conference for us so to
so to go to a conference
go to a linux conference and my slides
are available to share to introduce
people to freebsd and or go to a meet up
or run a meet up or go to university and
these are all things that we're doing
it's just that the foundation is very
small we can't
get to all these places and you can
install
you could hold it installfest which
basically means
that you go to something you go to a
meet up and everyone brings their little
laptop you install
virtualbox or some vm install freebsd
and that's just the basic and now you
can start playing with freebsd and learn
about it
and i have resources actually on the
right of that slide
is a list of a lot of the resources that
we do provide from flyers to stickers
someone was asking me earlier about
could they get the
like pedia for the stickers and and so
we do have people who run their
their local events and they print their
own or have their own
stickers made so this slide i like to
use
for when i go to like a linux conference
for people who are new to freebsd
and i love this graphic i don't know who
did it and i wish i did because i'll
probably
someday get in trouble for using it but
but it's showing us working together and
um and so why should we work together
it's um i mean first so say you're in
here
and you're just learning about freebsd
and you have no interest in
in switching but you're linux i know sys
admin
this way i mean it's so important just
to have that knowledge
understand how other operating systems
work
and it'll just make you better at what
you do because you may say
i hate how they do all of the stuff so
i'm going to do
you know my whatever my development my
work
better and that's that is how you
improve things
so we really could learn from each other
whether it's successes or failures
and um and we do have different coding
methodologies and philosophies and so
understanding the reasons for both
and so i do know people who contribute
especially developers who contribute to
freebsd
companies like google and facebook try
to hire them which is really bad for us
but because they don't usually
contribute anymore but
it's it is a good way to get really good
training
and um and they have we just have a good
reputation for
producing uh very good software
developers and that's why that happens
our code base is smaller and so it's a
great reference
platform so for learning about open
or learning about operating systems uh
it's
so you so i mean so we have uh if you
just compare the two kernels so we have
about
uh five and a half million lines of code
and
uh linux is 35 or more million lines of
code
so right there you can see like well if
i just want to look at source code
i'd probably and you know that they're
both good then i would choose a smaller
one because it's going to be easier
to find what you're interested in or
what you're looking
you know to find what you're looking for
uh previously
if you look at the whole operating
system it's about 17 million lines of
code
so and uh distribute
linux distribution i don't i can't even
tell you how many lines of code because
they're all going to be different too
but it just gives you an idea that it's
a great place to learn about operating
systems it's
if you're interested in becoming a
system programmer or
to improve your system programming
skills then it's a great way to do that
with
freebsd and i had that quote because
this was one i found
when i was just reading uh i forgot what
where i was reading this at but
i thought this was a really good point
that this person said that they became a
better linux system
by learning about freebsd so i think
that that's really important
and so why i contribute to freebsd and i
know i like
i could actually make like probably a
book on this and that's why i try to
squeeze as much as i can because
here is why i'm trying to convince
people to contribute to freebsd
but it is a very inclusive and welcoming
uh
community i was so we had a developer
summit on friday and there's a
contributor and i can't remember how
many years she's been involved in
the project i just met her for the first
time here
and she submitted a patch and she
so she tweeted it i just submitted my
first patch to
freebsd and everyone's like reply you
know commenting like congratulations and
all this stuff
which is great because then it makes you
want to contribute more
as well as also people are there
reviewing and giving you constructive
feedback too
so we're assuming people aren't perfect
when you know when they start
contributing
like i said it's a great way to learn
about operating systems and because of
the size of the
project since it is smaller it's it's
easier to make a more
notable contribution so we've had like
some of our interns i mean they've
become sort of the like main people like
on risk five
is a really good example of one of my
interns
and um and so it is it's much easier to
to stand out or to become an expert in a
particular area that you're interested
in
and get involved and like i said earlier
some of those
original people like kirk mccusick he's
one of the original
bsd developers and from berkeley
and he's on my board and he's still very
involved in the project i mean you go to
a conference and he's there
and he's there talking to people and
he's not uh you know
uh i mean you don't have to line up talk
to him he's
just very approachable and very friendly
too
and um and then the fact that it's
democratically run too
that that makes a difference is first
getting your contributions accepted
so what i would recommend is if you're
interested in trying out freebsd
just to try it and there's many ways of
doing that from
like i have it like i was saying that i
have virtualbox that's typically how we
do it with a workshop
but you could actually get an account on
azure
aws they have free accounts for new
people
and a digital ocean actually is another
one that's really good
and or or we also have how-to guides on
our web
our website so the freebsdfoundation.org
website
does have how-to guides and so if you
want to just install freebsd like i'm
doing on my other computer
then we have a guide for that and then
this last one i think the slide will
disappear
but this is some of the main resources
that i use and most people will use for
getting more information about freebsd
and but there's a lot more information
it's really you know just google for
freebsd and you can get what you
hopefully what you want to
know about freebsd and there's also a
good facebook
group there too but there's forums email
lists there's
many different ways to engage with the
community
so i have one minute left which i timed
it perfectly so i wouldn't get too many
questions but
no i'm kidding but um but if you do have
questions
um i'll take questions now but the other
thing too is we do have that table
i'll be down there but also we do have
developers down there who so if you have
real
you know specific or you know technical
questions
that they should be able to answer those
for you so anything
in this last 53 seconds that i have
so who's gonna try freebsd now
that's awesome okay okay that's great
okay well that's all i have thank you so
much