uh
thank you for coming i forget how many
of these we've done
so far um is there anyone
not enough too many um
so it's been really good watching you
know the community evolve over the years
and people getting together and sharing
ideas and learning from each other
um i would like to call attention to the
new radio conference
in charlotte in september of this year
charlotte
charlotte uh north carolina and the u.s
charlotte is a major airport you should
be able to get direct flights from
london and
frankfurt at least and a couple other
places
and it's always a very good conference
we have the
european gnu radio days which i would
love to go to
except you've scheduled it on top of the
embedded linux conference in the us
come on in we're just doing the
procedurals we have stickers
please take stickers the guys don't want
to carry them home
we have a speaker gift of pluto
thanks robin and we will also
be able to give some out to people who
ask very good questions so during the
talk
think of good questions to ask and if
the
jury awards you a pluto that's what will
happen
and with that is there anything else
so we'll stick to the schedule we have
to stick to the schedule because the
video recordings are done by time slices
so if you end early your next talk will
start on time
and your talks cannot run over and we'll
do like a five minute gap
in between to change the room the room
will probably fill up and it will get
very crowded and very hot
and there will probably be a line so if
you haven't been before
getting in and out can be a problem if
you need
food we can probably send a runner for
one occasionally
and if you need mate we can do the same
so last week we had a hack fest at um
east deck in the netherlands outside of
leiden
organized by andre here and
that was a very nice experience a very
nice facility and there was a wonderful
cat
and with that we'll let andre explain
what we got done
all right thanks philip uh yeah as
philip said my name is andre
i'm a uh isa employee by day and a gun
radio officer by night
and i had the wonderful pleasure of
inviting people
to my workplace three days before fosdem
to
have a little heck fest sit together and
hack on radio and related projects
and uh right oh
i'm wait that's the wrong slides i have
to go here
right uh so the slides are also already
online you can visit this link and
actually if i switch the slides here it
will also switch on your laptop then so
it's kind of convenient for you
i had other slides before already
assembled at the hack first
but then i left my laptop at home so i
had to
yesterday at night i reassembled
everything i could
uh remember ah yeah 2 am something like
that
so uh sorry if i forgot anything we did
at the hackfest we have a lot of people
that were
there so correct me if i'm wrong
somewhere
um all right some facts so
it was three days we had meeting rooms
from the 28th until the 30s
we had food and convenient
traveling from the next big city we in
total we had 14 participants
including me and six of those were
actually going radio officers so that
was a good turnout i think from the
grand radio project folks
and we also had a space cat on site
which helped
improve the productivity of everyone
attending
and also at this point i want to thank
my section and my division at
isa aztec for letting me invite everyone
and book the meeting rooms and yeah have
this wonderful event
so basically this is how hackfest
looks like it's a bit blurry but uh
yeah we don't need much we just need a
meeting room we just need convenient
uh like support for food and drinks and
then
basically some reason to go to a place
for example like fosdem so if you
live or if you have something in
brussels for next year
i think we will be happy to arrange
something
right there's the space cat that we
visited and
had some quality time with it
and it's actually a real staff so it has
a badge
and it can go in and out of the facility
so no problem there
so what kind of topics we're working on
so
we had one group that was basically
dedicated three days
working on the scheduler and the runtime
and it was
uh had some high profile members so
marcus mueller was there bastian russell
and some other grenadier core developers
who
actually started from scratch and
made some progress on that then we had a
group dedicated to grand radio 3 8
out of 3 module porting and also
coming up with a way how to create a
binary package feed for out of the
modules
because right now we have pi bombs and
you have to compile everything from
stores and it's
not super convenient for every end user
we currently have out there
and then we also at the last day we had
some
smaller group that looked at cmf and how
to improve the ecosystem
in regard with regard to cmf
so the schedule and runtime so the first
day
the group had a brainstorming session
and basically assembled
two page documents something like that
with thoughts and basically all the
collected lessons learned everything
how to write it correctly
and the second and third day they
basically spent uh
implementing a first proof of concept
and uh it's actually already a public
git git repo which can be accessed at
this url
right um then for the ignorant three
eight out of three module porting
we uh had some
[Music]
features that were implemented for siege
oh no no this was
great uh yep so uh zack did
had some effort actually implementing
the
qt guy in osmocom fft so i don't know
i think a lot of you know osmocom ft and
it previously used the wx
gui i think in greater three seven and
now it's will hopefully soon after
the pull requests or patches get merged
support
qt and so with that they're also going
to radio 3 8
which is a nice effort so some more
plots from osmocom fft how it looks
with cute also
nicolas made an effort to actually have
one extra column in sigrin which
displays the supported versions so
if you have an out of three module you
can write in your manifest file
which versions you support and we will
automatically display this in sigrin now
and also if you have a logo and
we click on one of the pages here you
can
have your logo shown there so that's
some small fixes but
it's a quality of life improvement for
the packages
so also if someone wants to port some
modules from 37238 you can just
you can just look at the list and pick
one of your favorite modules that are
not yet ported
yeah and for the automatic package
feed for the order of three modules i
was basically
looking at that with several other
people how to
do it the most efficient way and
the most efficient way will be probably
to add more metadata to the pi bombs
recipes
then have a automatic let's say
templating script which then templates
my
ubuntu or debian source package files
and then we can feed it through some ci
pipeline
which i spent a bit writing the
templates and
it does also get the repo which is
already public but i forgot to put a
link here
and hopefully soon i will be able to
progress on this
in a efficient manner
right uh and then on sick mf tooling uh
yeah we want to implement and support as
many external tools or tools around the
negan radio ecosystem with cmf
and yeah one part of that is for example
to have
one library or header only library for c
plus plus which
has a good packaging
in downstream packages so i looked at
that and posted the pull request to the
deepsea
lip cmf repo which improves the cmake
and hopefully i get some reviews and
get this code merged after the hack fest
yeah also schneider did some effort to
actually implement cmf in or look at his
old code to implement sigmf in in
spectrum so
if you have a cmf annotated file you can
load it in a spectrum and
then have like these annotations
displayed inside of your
spectrum yeah
right also at hackfest we do fun
activities and
being at the european space research and
technology center
it has some upsides so we can for
example
watch 3d cgi and real footage of the
high
of the iss so basically a nice
image movie of us floating through the
iss
and also learning a lot about
microgravity and why we actually do some
space research
and also visiting the concurrent design
facility at
aztec and learning on about how to
actually do
spacecraft design in the early stages to
get something into space
so conclusions we have some real
progress
actual code of greater runtime in
scheduler
thanks to the folks working hard and not
for three days
we have some packages i actually forgot
some packages that got three eight
updates
because yeah the slides were done
tonight
um and some more interest in cmf and
maybe we get some more tooling done soon
there's an idea to actually have a
g-stock
also working on that maybe some some
student in this room or
from outside this room wants to work on
that as well
and yeah thanks for your attention and
just join the next hack fest and i don't
know when we will have the next hackfest
so
we are very welcome to suggestions and
also if there's
some conference or some other event in
proximity and there's like three days
before that we can have a meeting room
for 20 people or 10 depending on the
location
just come come up chat with us and
we might be able to have another one
yeah that's about all i have
right now
you