yes sir so hi everyone uh
thank you for coming uh this session is
an amendment because the previous
speaker
is unable to to come to attend fosdem
she sent her uh yeah notice but
unfortunately she won't be here the
session would have been
uh bridge the physical world currently
native on raspberry pi
uh but instead it will be from swagger
to cutting via gradle
uh if you leave the room please um
pay attention to the chair because it's
really noisy
and and yeah let's get it started so my
name is nicola corti
i work as infrastructure engineer that
means android infrastructure engineer
that means that i basically
work on libraries framework tools for an
android engineer i mostly
develop in kotlin when possible but i
also
have to deal a lot with java um
yeah if you probably know me you know
that i'm more like a dog person rather
than a cat person
and why this is important this is
important because
i don't have a dog at the moment i will
actually would love to get one at a
certain point i'm actually really in
love with
corgis so i thought that maybe you can
help me
get one pet actually
a corgi so what happens next is that
yeah i could actually go
to to the pet store a pet store that's
wagered
and then they tell me that i can't
just call get slash pets
because that's not valid
so today we're going to talk about
swagger and open api
uh so swagger and open apis are both
tools to define
in a machine and human readable way
the apis for your backend services
so there is a little bit of confusion
between open api and swagger
if you go on the website they will tell
you that open api is actually the
specification
while swagger is all the tooling around
it
in the community it's more like
connected to the fact that open api is
related to the open api specification
version 3 while swagger is whatever is
is related to then to the specification
version 2.
so today we're going to mostly focus on
swagger that means version 2.
what's the cool part of this if you
don't know swagger
quick question how many here are
actually working
our projects that have swagger apis
and not everyone so uh the cool part of
this is that they're actually
this is actually a tool to define your
apis with just
json or yaml file like one or more
and the cool part is that is actually as
i said before
machine readable so you can build
infrastructure around it
and tools so let's make an example
and the example i'm going to make is
actually the pet store the pet store is
the equivalent of
hello world but for the api so it's like
a minimal set
of endpoints that represents the
basically feature set
of this api specification tool
so we start with a yaml file we define a
version as i said we're gonna work with
swagger2
and we have an info block so inside the
infoblock there it's like a little
preamble where you can like specify
what this vlogger file is going to be
about so in this case the description
the version of this spec file so 100 in
this case
a title swagger pet store you can
provide
further information like a contact email
or
a license then
uh you can define a host in this case we
are going to be reachable a pet stores
wager io
a base path like equiliba slash v2 as a
base path for all of your endpoints and
the supported schemes like http or https
that's all part of like the introductory
part of this pack
uh but let's let's go further and let's
actually define
like how our spec will look like so
usually within this fact you will have
to define two set of things
endpoints and models like objects
so let's start with the definitions here
you define your models and
we start by defining what is a pet we
can say that a pet is actually an object
and has a set of properties specifically
an id
and we can say the use of type integer
format in 64
and the name there is a string and
define
our reality obviously also complex types
are supported for example i could have a
photo urls there is actually an array
and the items of their a are of type
string so i will receive like a list of
urls
i can specify which properties are
required to make these definitions
meaningful in this case i could say that
name and photo urls are actually
required so they should be there
i can have even more complex types for
example status
and if i don't want the status to just
be a string i could
say i could provide a description and i
could say that this is actually an enum
so i could restrict the set of possible
values
to available and sold only and the real
power of swagger is that i could
actually
define more than one model so i could
say that
a pet has also a category but a category
is a reference
to another definition like in this case
let's zoom back category is again an
object
as some properties again an id
of type integer format in 64 and a name
of type string
so this is like a basic definition of
two
two models but let's go to the to the
core part of the spec like
we would love to have some some
endpoints so we go back to our
yaml file at the top level we define our
paths property
and we begin enumerating our endpoints
so the first one is path pad id
sorry pat pat id and we can say that on
this endpoint we support the get
operation and we need to provide summary
and description like
uh find a path by id and what it does it
returns a single path
uh this context is also really useful to
provide an operation id
an operation id is a string
representation
of this combination of endpoint and http
verb
so in this case we will write get pat by
a d and it's also
at full because it's just characters
there are no crazy symbols
and slashes in between we will see why
we need it
and here we define what our endpoint is
doing so for example is
returning an application json and has
some parameters
like one there is pad id and is inside
the path
is actually the one that is before
between curly braces
and we can provide description like all
those descriptions are actually optional
you don't need to provide all of them
but obviously if you provide it you will
have better space easier to maintain
and we can say it is actually required
like you need to provide that
[Music]
parameter and specify the type integer
and the format in 64. so the last thing
that we need to define here is actually
what this endpoint will produce
so we have the responses block so we can
say that for
200 so for the successful uh
response we are going to produce so the
description is successful operation
and for 404 the description is but not
found because there is no pad in the
our database whatsoever uh we still
haven't connected this endpoint with a
definition that we provided before
so inside the 200 we can also provide a
schema
and this will mean that the the body
will uh
will have this this schema that we
provide now definitions
path so this is basically how we connect
this endpoint to the to the object with
just defined so as i said before the the
power of swag is that it comes with
some tools uh that are really are really
helpful
first of all swagger ui it's it's
basically um
sort of like a web server that shows you
a
web representation of your spec and you
can actually
uh navigate through your endpoints and
see the
the description of every endpoint and
also
really useful the the swagger editor
this is really similar to the
uh to swagger eye there is the one on
the right but on the left you can
actually
see the spec file and edit them and see
in real time how things are changing
so out of these we will uh we actually
discovered that we can't call get
pat corgi because that parameter should
be of type m
so we'd rather call get pat 42 or
something like that
so as i said swagger comes with a lot of
tools
and one tools that is also available is
swagger cogen
and that is the one we're going to talk
about we're going to talk about today so
swagger coding is
yeah again open source is available on
on github and it's basically a tool that
allows to generate
code out of your swagger spec files uh
it's available on swagger dash api slash
swagger cogen
on github it's actually really active
over there so i really invite you to
take a look
uh to give you like a super fast
introduction to the project it's
basically composed by
two parts there is the generator code
so the the code that is responsible of
reading the spec file like analyzing
it and then there are like a set of
templates file that will be populated
with the value that are parsed by the
generator
so there are actually a lot of templates
that are already available online
and you can use them as as an
inspiration you can start from that but
it might not fit
your needs and also it swagger coding
comes
by default as a command line tool so
ideally you should call it like
java dash jar and the jar of zarger code
and then pass everything
in there are some plugins to to plug it
in some build system but as an android
developer
uh i don't find it really um like
it doesn't really fit my workflow and
then this
is like why we will like we end up
i ended up developing something
something different this is
the list of templates that are already
available
there are templates for server like you
can generate your server stops
but there are also a lot of templates
for clients so
uh yeah gold java rust whatsoever there
is actually
kotlin also but the java one
there are multiples specifically there
is okay http retrofit 1x and retrofit
2x but there is nothing for coupling
like there's just
plain cotton i don't know if that got
updated recently but
that might not fit what what is your
actual stack
and this is how like a template looks
like it's actually a mustache file
so if you're not used to that it's
something like this
so you have like a lot of tags and this
text will be populated by property and
you have
some really limited
computational logic so for example here
we are saying like if like the tag
with a hashtag means if there is a
description
print those characters like slash as
there is casters because it's
javadoc and then print the description
and then
close this context so it's like
it's not really handy to work with those
template files you
might have to do some tricks and that's
why
uh i ended up developing this tool
called swagger gradle cogen
so it's it's open source is on apache 2
license uh it's available on github
so i developed this as part of uh like
when i was in my former company so you
will find it on the yelp org
but i'm actually i'm not working there
anymore but i'm still like
uh heavily contributing over there
and i find a project really interesting
so yeah that's that's the reason why
it's there
and what is actually swagger gradle
coding is actually a gradle plugin
that fits a bit better inside a
classical like
android or kotlin library build system
and as some feature is actually input
output aware
that means that um the gradle plugin is
able to understand if you change your
spec
and will rebuild stuff if needed or not
while a common line interface will just
like you know
redo all the the building every time as
a simpler api for the developer
so zwarkie kojon the the original
swagger code
is extremely powerful but has a lot of
properties and the majority like
a lot of them are actually not needed
for android engineers
so we like i sort of like uh hide
a lot of them under like a simpler api
to use so the idea is just like plug and
play
plug this plug-in and you will be ready
with your code in a couple of minutes
and the second important thing is that
this tool is opinionated
like this tool is built around uh the
one that i consider
probably the most common android
developer stack
there is cuddling rx java 2 or curtains
retrofit moshi uh so retrofit for rest
abstraction mashi for json parsing and
treating abp for dates um this might not
fit your needs like
if if you don't use marshy this tool
will not work for you
but nowadays i think this is like the
most popular android libraries out there
so the templates inside the project will
use
this uh so let's let's go back to our
vloggers pack this one pat and category
and let's see what the generated code
will look like more or less
so uh category so yeah obviously this
would be represented by a class
uh we are in kotlin so why not using a
data class it comes with a lot of nd
functions out of the box
and there would be two properties id and
name
from the format we can like infer the
type so it will be
a id of type long name of type string
there are both optional they are not
required so
we can mark the type as optional and we
can actually initialize them
as null so
obviously as i said um everything works
with moshi
so class classes will be annotated with
json so that the parser is like more
resilient and knows where to put
everything and this is basically how um
yeah how your class will look like
if you are uh like a good developer
and you like have uh descriptions in
your swagger
file as i suggested before you will also
have it
uh populated in your kdog annotations uh
that is really really handy because when
you check documentations and you have
all those
classes you immediately see what those
properties are doing directly from your
swagger specs
let's go on the on the more complex one
like pat
again a data class everything already
annotated there are a couple of things
to notice here
uh so for example the name was required
so
we can set the type as non-nullable
string
and we don't need to we can't initialize
it to now so you need to provide a name
you can't create this class otherwise uh
the photo urls in the swaggers
in the vargas pack we mentioned that is
an array and on kotlin we convert it to
a list because it's either easier to
to to deal with and
again we have a category so the
generator is
correctly linking this property called
category to the class that we previously
defined and again we have a enum
this enum is generated as an inline
sorry as a
inner enum and yeah it's available there
and again everything is annotated
and again provide augmentation strings
it would be helpful for you like you
will have it there
then let's go to the to the end point so
get pat
pat pat's id so
as i said we generate retrofit
interfaces
so there will be a default api with a
function
called getpat by id this is where the
operation id comes handy because
we need a unique name to identify this
operation
and we we got it from the spec
and then we uh provide all the
parameters
so in this case there is only one is
called para id is long
and is annotated with the retrofit to
annotation at path
so this will end up in the path and
again also we have to annotate
the function with our at get annotation
and the proper
url there is one thing that is missing
here
is the return type this is where the rx
java
2 wiring happens so in this case if you
use the rx java 2
template this will generate a normal
function that
returns a single of a path if you
instead
switch to use keratins this will
generate a suspending function that
returns just a bet and if you
use retrofit 2.7 i think it will
work correctly so you will have like the
asynchronous pattern that you prefer
there is a header called x operation id
this is like a header that we wanted to
add like on every request
and is basically a way to pass over the
operation id but you can change it if
you want just like edit the
template and then yeah again
you will have the documentation of your
endpoint over there
if you provide it and this is basically
how the final class will look like with
all the
imports the package and italy will
compile
so how you use this plugin there are
some use cases like you can it's a
greater plugin so you can plug it to
whatever is a is a gradle
module basically if you have like just
just a
app module like you don't do
modularization at all you have a super
small app
you can just plug it there and specify
where you want your generated code
to end up and that will work but if you
have
modularization maybe you want to have a
pure kotlin module that contains this
code
or a library an android library project
that contains
again the code all the modules and api
and if you are in a bigger org or you
want a more structured approach
or what i really suggest is to integrate
these within your ci system
um so let's see how you can like
configure
the plugin and now you can integrate it
in your in your ci so
you define the class path dependency for
the plugin
uh communal code gen plugin the latest
version is 130
and then you need to you need to provide
this generate swagger block
and over there all the properties that
are needed for the generation
so specifically the the there is only
one
required property that you need to
provide and is the swag
the swagger spec file like this plugin
is not a wizard like if you don't
provide a spec file
nothing will actually work so
then the output directory and other
properties like
uh which platform you want to use the
package name
and other stuff so this this plugin
will basically do just one thing to your
build system will
offer you one extra task
that you need to call we not do auto
magic this task is called generate
swagger
and the fact that we don't modify the
build system is actually intentional we
leave
this like my idea was to leave this duty
to the developer like it's up to you to
decide if you want to hook
everything within your normal build and
rebuild every time or not
so what you can do you can say for
example pre-build depends on
and you get this generate a swagger task
in that case
what will happen is that there is this
this is like a random assemble build
and you have this pre-built
gradle task where you can hook
everything there
that needs to be executed before
the build starts so you could say like
hey before building
just call this generate swagger generate
all the code and then actually
build my app and now let's see how you
can actually
generate your code inside a ci
and i have like a sort of a small
pipeline
to generate your code and what are the
benefits
so i assume you have your swagger
specified somewhere
ideally in a git repo or somewhere else
you'd need to have some sort of a
webhook mechanism
to trigger a ci build so you will invoke
your jenkins travis gitlab ci
whatsoever tool you want and
ideally you you need to have like a
skeleton project
you can take one uh that is inside the
apple in the samples
folder or you can craft your own so
what's what's the idea behind this this
skeleton project
this skeleton project will uh like erci
will be responsible of fetching
the sp the updated spec file inside
this skeleton project calling generate
swagger
like calling gradle generates wagger so
all the code will be generated
then you can actually run tests like
the power of these is that you can have
integration tests
that test your generated code against
like a mocked environment or some
environment that
runs your swagger spec implementation so
like
you test that what what you generated is
actually working
once the tests are green you can
assemble so you have like an archive and
yeah so you have like a basically a aar
or a jar based on what you want to to
build
and then once that is ready you just
call publish and that it's on you if you
want to put it like
on a private maven repository
or on something public uh like if you're
maintaining
public apis like i don't know apis for
weather
services whatever you could actually
have a pipeline that generates
like uh an android sdk implementation of
that
that it's rebuilt every time that you
change the swagger spec
so at the end of the day who is
consuming those generated code will end
up having something like this like
implementation
com corgi samples generated api and the
version
and the the power of this is first that
you have versioning like you have a
strict versioning system to go back in
the history and knowing
which version of the generated code
is what like this is
swagger spec file generated this r and
those are the
files that are inside so you can
actually go back in time
and yeah basically the power is that you
have this
bundle with all of your retrofit apis
and the data classes
so and again the fact that you consume
this as a third-party library basically
is that it's read-only so if you are in
a bigger org or
you're in a bigger project and you want
to enforce that those
files are like the same they don't
change
like people can't actually touch them
this is like
uh a great way to enforce that your
network model
and your network interfaces are actually
one by one
with the swagger spec file so
uh yeah that's that's all i want to
spend a couple of minutes actually
talking about
challenges and future like a little bit
of road map like what's
what's coming next so challenges
when generating code you have to shift a
little bit your perspective
um i actually invite you to read one
blog post from jay corton that is called
changing the mindset
when doing code generation but if you
search j corten code generation you will
find it
is actually really interesting and there
are some
um some scenarios or problems that arise
only when you're actually generating
code
not when you're writing it normally
the first one this is actually not only
for code generation but encoderation is
it's really dangerous
it's it's breaking changes like
or changes they're actually breaking the
implementation of your app
let's see an example let's say you have
a get pet by a d
and point with two strings name and
surname
okay and then for some reason like you
change
something in i don't know israelis pac
file or the implementation of the
generator
and you happen to invert the order of
those two parameters
what will happen is that uh this this
code
is both binary and source compatible
on the user side so people will just
bump the library will
get other code and on on the on the call
site is just get pet by the string comma
string
so nothing nothing will happen but
actually
you're passing the name as a surname and
vice versa
and this could be problematic if instead
of having name and surname you actually
have username and password
so that is a problem and what i suggest
for scenarios like these is actually
having like
um static analysis tools uh
kotlin has a great feature called name
parameters that prevents
this kind of situation so you could say
like get pet by d
surname equal whatever expression
variable that represents the surname
and name equal and that will um like
protect
you against this kind of changes so just
like a detect rule that detects
whenever you use a generated call code
and then like raise a warning if you're
not using name parameters
another problem is defining names so in
swagger you can actually define models
in line
like you can have models inside models
inside other models
and those models don't have a name it's
like an anonymous inner class in java
it's like anonymous
so but the generator needs to generate
classes for that
and needs a name and you might end up
with classes that are like
id to session info for customized result
map to use their ui interaction map
that's not cool like if you use
import as like if you have big names you
can save yourself using import
name of the class as network model and
you sort of save yourself
but this is this is still a class and
you will find it when you like
type in your autocompletion so pay
attention make sure that
every model has a proper name
uh and then accessing the raw response
like
what happens if you want to access a
response header
like i would do that like in retrofit
what you need to do is wrap the response
type inside our
a result or a response object but
this is coming from a template like if i
change it for one
endpoint i would change it for all the
endpoints and if i have like i don't
know 1 000 m points
uh yeah that's going to be complicated
so
this is still an open challenge ideally
one thing could be
to uh like this is unsolved sort of
uh ideally one idea could be to see if
in the swaggers pack you have a response
header and if it's defined there
then change like offer to uh
only for that end point access the raw
response
and yeah those are like some challenges
that i faced
and then like i have here the guy over
there with the red t-shirt there is
another top contributor of this project
and i wanted to discuss a little bit
like what's coming next like what are
the challenges
what are we working on um yeah so
january 21st this year so like a couple
of
days ago we just released version 130
and that offers support for cutting
curtains that was actually
requested a lot like very like i had a
draft pr
for curtins and a lot of people wrote
like hey i need this now like please
ship it and yeah we just didn't wanted
to like mess up
with the project so we had to like do a
little bit of refactoring but now it's
live
so you can use it so there will be a
version 1 4
coming soon like months probably i don't
know
yeah there will be support for moshi
cogen so
right now this project is using uh mashi
um kotlin that uses the kotlin json
adapter factory
they're inside uses cotton reflect so
uses a reflection
it's really heavy for the up size and
it's really heavy at run
time like creating like parsing stuff
around so there would be mushy code and
support
uh it will be like it will not be a
breaking change
uh but at a certain point like there
will be a truex version at
some time this year ideally uh and
we want to drop support from mashikalen
like we want to have everything on
on massive cogen because it's just
it's just better like we prefer this
approach
then another important thing there is a
hot topic is
models inheritance so what happens if
you have
a model like swagger allows you to say
that you have a pet
as a model and you have a cat and a dog
as a model so and you have like a
discriminator field
that comes through the wire so you will
have like type and if it's a dog there
will be the properties of a dog and if
it's a cat
they will be the properties of a cat
yeah so
in our case we decided to use data
classes
that don't play well with inheritance
so um yeah we are working on a solution
like specifically samuel is working on
that it's working on a solution to
have like a classier key with
higher classes they are not data classes
and lower classes there are actually
like the the sun
like the leaf of these three are
actually data classes
uh this will come we are still
discussing on implementation
you're actually more than welcome
because a lot of the discussion happens
online
like on pull requests yeah and we're
looking for contributors
and that's all thank you very much
and i'm happy to get questions
if there are i know
awesome thank you
you