hello guys
please find a seat and then we can start
with the next
talk the last one for the history so the
end of history of this
for stem will be presented by
liam proven he is working with zuzer
and he's working with unix since 1988 so
he knows quite some history
and he's a technical writer so please
enjoy
generation gaps with liam proven
have fun
wow thank you very much
um so hello good afternoon thank you for
coming to my talk
um my plan today is to commit heresy
i want to murder some deeply loved ideas
especially some beloved of the open
source community and the unix community
if you're not okay with that then good
because you might actually you know find
it interesting
um i'm going to talk about stuff that
you probably already know but i will
talk about
things that you maybe don't know that
you know
there are things that we don't talk
about in the history
and the development of open source unix
software in general
um i'm here to tell you that these
things
are although true not
good things that they are toxic things
harmful things
things that are holding us back you
might find it all a bit difficult and
you might find it ridiculous
so i'm going to start quite slowly
you you know the cartoon before i had to
go and get a job i worked in biology
and everybody misunderstands evolution
they think that it's a progress of
getting more complicated and getting
better and more sophisticated and that
is not at all how
evolution works evolution is random and
chaotic and
sometimes stuff gets weird
um so computers have been around for
about 75 years now
and in that 75 years a lot of people
have spent a lot of time
arguing about generations of computers
um well i have a slightly different take
on that
the general belief is that each
generation of computers is better than
the generation before
that it's obviously faster that it's got
more storage it can do more
actually that's not true many times in
the history and development of computing
the new generation has been worse than
the generation that went before
we have not always been adding new
features
adding new capabilities actually the big
generation transitions have been when we
take them away
when we make new computers that are
inferior to the computers that went
before
i touched on some of this a couple of
years ago in a talk that some of you
might have seen
um so i'm going to give you some
examples um
here is one of the first programmable
digital computers that's eniac it
was an american computer partly funded
by the
department of defense as so much was um
these things were huge
and they were very expensive because
they were hand built
out of individual valves and so on um
they had just one type of storage and
not very much of it just
a few dozen words in the very first
cases bytes were invented later
um they could only hold one program at a
time which were written
by hand in machine code on a piece of
paper and then
entered into the computer one bit at a
time so
easy to manage they got a little bit
bigger they got a bit more sophisticated
and they got more memory
and some very slow offline storage
things like punch tape
paper tape uh punched cards this made
programs
and data quicker to load but the
computer was still
something where the workload was managed
not by anything on the computer but by
people it was a people problem to get
somebody in get their software on the
computer run it
results printed and out as quickly as
possible
and everything was hand written in
machine code so every time you got a new
computer you had to rewrite everything
then roughly at the end of the
50s came a huge distinction
this is an ibm 701 and standing next to
it is future president ronald reagan
um the image is from ibm um
the thing about the early mainframe
computers
that distinguished them from the
computers that went before was not that
they had more storage although they did
it was that they had two types of
storage
one type was stored at first on
little tiny magnetized rings directly
mapped into the processor's address bus
now we call that ram the other type of
storage
was much bigger and much slower and
much more expensive this
is i believe the university college
london i'm not certain that is a five
megabyte hard disk being delivered
um if you have to ask how much it cost
you couldn't afford it
um the difference here
was two types of storage this is what
was called secondary storage
so some of the storage is in the
processor's memory bus
some of the process much more some of
the storage much more of it
is on a device like that and it's
accessed not by the memory bus but by a
controller
the processor has to go and say to the
controller right i need this block
and it the controller goes and fetches
it off the
huge hard disk with mechanical parts
moving and puts it into a block of
memory and you can work on it and then
you can write it back
this two-level distinction primary
storage
and secondary storage is very very
important and we don't talk about it
much
anymore and
the problem is that
it's so implicit virtually every
computer
in about the last 60 65 years has had
this split we all know it's there we've
taken it as red we take it as a given
that you have memory and you have discs
and you move stuff between them
this is absolutely built into the
structure of virtually
all software in the world today
it enabled a whole new generation of
technology it enabled things like
compilers where you have one program
that reads another program
does something to it to produce a third
program that you can run
that created cobol and fortran and
made a market for computers very much
bigger this
the stretch pioneering machine a
complete commercial failure
first super scalar computer the first
computer with eight bit bytes
the first computer with pipelining
remarkable machine
they sold about six of them for roughly
half the cost of building it
but again once you've got compilers
you've got high-level languages you
rewrite everything all over again
then the next leap was not really a
technical leap
the next leap was a commercial leap it
was a marketing leap
again ibm invention at the time
early 60s ibm sold multiple ranges of
computers
they sold things like the 701 and the
1401 and the 60 30.
all totally different different number
of bits per word
different operating systems different
programming languages totally
incompatible
ibm had a very clever idea in the 60s
and they invented the ibm system 360.
this is the smallest model of ibm system
360.
this is basically a single user personal
computer that can just barely struggle
through one programming
language at a time the
idea of system 360 was they could sell a
whole range of different computers and
they could all run the same software
not the same operating system they
offered lots of different operating
systems for
the s 360. it was a huge success
it made them a great deal of money they
continued to add
and enhance the system 360 for years it
became the system 370
and now it's called z series and the
direct descendant of this computer
if you bought an air ticket like me to
come to fosdem your ticket was booked
through the descendant of that computer
running compatible software
if you paid for it with a credit card
your money went through a bank account
that was controlled by the offspring of
one of these
again it's like evolution
we complex multicellular mammals
evolved from simpler organisms which
ultimately evolved from bacteria
the bacteria are still there underneath
there's more of them than us there are
more species of them than us there is
more of them by mass
there's more of them by individuals it
doesn't go away nothing goes away
but what's interesting about these is
they contributed very little
to the next generation of computers
because the next generation of computers
suddenly started to get smaller
and cheaper because of transistors
because of integrated circuits
this the first machine units was written
on this is a pdp-7 it might have been
even the
the same one in the slide earlier
this only cost 72 000 pounds sorry
dollars
a department could afford to buy one of
these they were shared at most by just a
few people as opposed to a mainframe
which occupied a floor of a building and
was shared by an entire company
this was in virtually every way
worse than a mainframe they were
smaller they were stupider they were
slower
they had less memory they had fewer
instructions
mainframes had wonderful fancy smart
terminals
where the software on the terminal could
collect
information from the user filling in a
form and validate it and package it up
and send it over network to the
mainframe these
had a printer with a keyboard on the end
of a serial line
mainframes had fantastic fast clever
storage controllers which could search
and sort and index all their own data
and the mainframe could just send it an
instruction that said find me
all the people whose surname matches
brown
and it just happened they used
a technology called query language for
this there's one you've probably heard
of
sql sql structured query language
originally from ibm
didn't get anything like that on these
they had to manage their own disks
manage their own blocks
but they caught on they sold really well
just a year later this was a smaller
model
only eighteen thousand dollars hundred
and fifty thousand
today approximately they
got cheap enough that now the computer
could sit
and wait for humans to input information
this meant interactive software this
meant all kinds of cool stuff like
text editors from the mainframe you
edited your text and punched it into a
card and no computer needed to be
involved
these smaller cheaper but worse
computers
enabled a huge burst of creativity
now i'm going to do something a little
bit better i would really like everybody
to go and watch
this presentation the future of
programming
and as you can see from the slide dbx
conference july the 9th
1973 dbx's dropbox
um he wasn't really presenting it in
he presented it 40 years later but he
dressed in a
70s outfit complete with a pocket
protector and he presented from
acetate slides put on an ohp
it's a wonderful period piece because he
talks about
what the next 40 years of software would
develop
and none of it happened
you would be amazed at what was invented
on these kind of computers
at the time on big clunky mini computers
they invented you've probably seen the
doug engelbart famous mother of all
demos
if you haven't you should really see
that video conferencing
live video streams multimedia
shared interactive workspaces in the
sixties
invented on many computers
there was a huge variety of them dead
for example the pdp-7 was an 18-bit mini
computer
but the pdp-11 which was the next
machine they ported unix to
was a 16-bit mini computer deck also
offered 12-bit
and 36-bit machines at the same time
and they all ran multiple different
operating systems as well
so this kind of stuff means that
there were lots of obsolete operating
systems you've probably never heard of
so
for example um the dec
pdp 8 ran an operating system called
os 8. it very cleverly managed to encode
file names into i think
four words and the result was
that the file name had a six character
name followed by a dot followed by a
three character extension
i bet everybody here has computer files
called jpg
when it actually stands for jpeg jpeg i
bet you've all dealt with files called
htm instead of html why
because of os 8 running on an rs are
running on a deck
rt sorry running on the deck pdp8
the pdp8 also influenced a later machine
from deck called a p2p 11 which ran a
different operating system called rt11
it expanded the file names very slightly
to 8.3
it also invented commands like copy and
era
and dell and so on dir
this stuff is all pervasive in your
computers now the 32-bit successor to
the pdp-11 was the vax
programs on avax are called exe sound
vaguely familiar
these are all long gone they're all long
dead but their influence is still deeply
rooted in everything we run today
one thing that did come out of those
machines was
the idea flowed back up the price chain
to
interactivity ibm found it really
difficult to do interactivity in their
big mainframe operating systems
in the end they come up with a
workaround they wrote operating systems
that could run
under other operating systems so each
user of the big multitasking mainframe
had
their own single user operating system
talking to their terminal
all multitasking on a totally different
unrelated operating system
it's a hypervisor it's one of the very
few things to make it from mainframes
into many computers and into
computers today because many computers
got swept away by the descendants of
this
this was a five thousand dollar terminal
with two kilobytes of ram but it could
actually run its own software
the company that built it gave a
commission to a small california company
called
intel to design them a single chip intel
failed they couldn't deliver on time so
this machine had its
processor built out of discrete
components but intel did finish that
chip and it became the intel 4004 which
was upgraded to the 808
which became the 8080 which became the
which is you know the ancestor of what
i'm presenting from
so two big shifts around the turning
point from the 60s to the 70s the
computer revolution you all know about
that there's another one
that you might not have met
so the first micro computers
this was the one that started the
microsoft business empire this is amits
altair
it ran microsoft basic their first ever
program
it's composed of separate cards
you could buy it as a kit or you could
buy it ready made
but there's a separate card for the
processor a separate card for the memory
a separate card for the disk controller
and although you could flick switches on
the front and operate it in binary it
was much easier to plug a terminal in
then you could see listings on the
screen and edit them
but in virtually every way worse
than a mini computer it was smaller it
was cheaper it had less storage it was
slower
you have one to yourself there's no
multitasking it doesn't need it there's
no multi-user support
you own it why have multi-user support
so all this technology from the mini
computer era
thrown away not adapted not modified not
respected
if you heard the earlier talk they've
lost all the tapes of the early versions
of unix
nobody thought it was important thrown
away
they kept a couple of things this ran
cpm in later versions which had
os 8 like 8.3 file names and things
but not dil related to it totally
rewritten ground up
then computers got even smaller and even
cheaper and you could give them to kids
as toys
that's a sinclair spectrum in there
that's one of the original rubber key
ones but i at about age 13 put it into a
much nicer keyboard
and i've still got it
first home computer in the uk that you
could afford to buy just about for under
100 pounds as a kit
i played with things like a commodore
pet
my uncle bought a zx81 but i was like 12
and it didn't do graphics it didn't do
color it didn't do sound it was
boring but my spectrum had all of those
things it was great i loved it i still
play with them occasionally
if you know any biology this was the
time of the cambrian explosion
of computers there were hundreds of
different makes and models
a couple of guys involved in the
sinclair zx81 went off and set up
jupiter and made the jupiter ace the
only home computer to use fourth instead
of basic
there were six 502 machines z80 machines
six 809 machines
vast variety no two two-level storage in
these either
you could dump stuff to tape and that
was it
people were so fanatically loyal to
these machines they
loved them they engaged in
advocacy that makes linux distro
advocacy look very tame
and then another generation of computers
came along apple
more or less made the home computer
market in the states with a
1 000 computer the apple ii they
tried to make a 16-bit successor but
it cut into the margins so they
disrupted the market with the
apple lisa 10 000 machine and then they
replaced that with the mac a two and a
half thousand dollar machine
soon everybody copied it lots of new
companies launching
68 000 powered machines with graphical
operating systems
one weird little company in britain
called acorn
tried a 16-bit successor which is almost
totally forgotten it's called the acorn
communicator
it didn't do very well so they junked it
and they
came up with an insane plan to write
their own operating system for their own
microprocessor which they designed from
scratch
the project completely failed and
crashed and burned so a couple of guys
did a
frantic skunk works replacement which
became this
um colorful isn't it um this changed the
whole world
um they sold again millions of these
things
nothing came across from the 8-bits they
were not powerful enough to emulate the
old computers
so all of those millions of hours of r d
were totally thrown away they weren't
good enough they couldn't
run an emulator fast enough to run the
old software so they just didn't bother
they can't read the previous machines
disks they can't run the previous
machine software nothing
nothing works start the whole thing from
scratch
again you keeping count i'm not
so
i said that there was a parallel line of
development that started in the 70s
it's one that doesn't get talked about
much now and i only found out about it
in
research for a project which led to this
talk in my previous talk
um the mini computer makers
shrank their machines and made them
smaller and cheaper until they went from
a row of filing cabinets to one filing
cabinet to
a huge great box that was the size of a
desk to something
like a very fat tower pc that sat next
to your desk
and they invented the single user mini
computer
or workstation um one of the first was
the sun one
which fairly typical machine of its time
the aim in the early days of the
workstation market was a 3m
machine a million bytes of ram
a million instructions per second and a
million pixels on screen
laughably low spec now big deal then um
this is one of the famous influential
ones of course this is a xerox alto
that's the small talk programming
environment it ran
apple went and saw a demo of this and
totally failed to get the point
so they went home and took a machine
that ran
xenix the prototype apple lisa and they
adapted it with a sort of frantic
lash together graphical operating system
it's what kick-started the microcomputer
16-bit micro-evolution
this was actually the first popular
object-oriented programming language
this software was all live and dynamic
and written in the language itself
you could edit the code and change
windows surroundings frames on the fly
there's no compilers here there's no
static binaries it's one huge mass of
live code that you can look at and edit
what happened is mini computers merged
with
one terminal and became a very expensive
but powerful standalone machine they
cost as much as a small house so they
didn't make much market penetration they
really only sold
to research institutions universities
and a few wealthy companies
this is the descendant of another famous
workstation
this is a symbolics lisp machine
this is a later generation list machine
if you look at the window frame in the
menu bar you can see it's running on
macros but this is not an emulator
this is a list machine on a new bus card
fitted inside a mac its memory is
totally separate to the max memory
um another amazing operating system
um symbolics was a hugely important
company in its time symbolics had the
first ever.com domain on the internet
they were that big
again the entire environment written in
a single language
from the apps right down to the
bootloader
lisp famously hard to understand but
famously powerful and capable um
the list machines are indirectly
responsible for both
emacs and the gnu project so you can
arguably blame them
but most of the mini computer
manufacturers persisted with their old
operating systems this is a dec
vacstation 4000
um it's running vax vms with deck
windows on top
um i've got a couple of these one of
them is somewhere in
red hat's office in farnborough and if
anybody's connected with red hat i'd
really like to find that i'd quite like
to have it back please
dec did machines with their own vax
processors they also did machines with
mips processors and later on they
invented their own
risk chip alpha the first 64-bit risk
chip all completely incompatible with
each other
two of them running totally different
operating systems from unrelated unix
families
absolutely normal cross-compatibility
was not a thing nobody thought about it
so you know at the same time as micros
were getting
colorful graphics and fancy stereo sound
and
rich windowing environments the
workstations were having all that stuff
but they also had
built-in email built-in internet access
all these kind of wonderful facilities
in the 80s before the internet
let's go before the web
computers just sort of quietly faded
away
but these are the offspring so now
coming up to the end of the 80s the
start of the 90s
there's still about a half a dozen main
families of
incompatible computer which
make up most of the market for both home
computers and business computers
um another revolution
is coming another generation switch is
coming
32-bit processors were becoming
affordable
they were cheap enough to start to put
into home computers
into ordinary desktop business computers
and that's when something happened that
had never happened before in the history
of computing
something very weird it led to the birth
of a new god
and in my opinion it's a dark
and malignant trickster god
it looked like a helpful friend it
wasn't
this is called backwards compatibility
the 32-bit chips didn't seem like a very
big deal for all the people making
gui powered pc comp computers
commodore atari apple their computers
just got a little bit faster
got a bit more memory great but the
very primitive little operating systems
that
today look tiny and svelt
and elegant they look they weren't
they still provoke huge nostalgia
in a certain type of middle-aged geek um
they couldn't be adapted to the new
capabilities of the newer chips
but the intel ones were a bit different
the intel 32-bit chip the first one the
386 came out in 1987 but it was fully
32-bit needed 32-bit memory on a 32-bit
motherboard and it was just too
expensive for most people
it was the later 386 sx with a 16-bit
bus
and 16-bit memory that made them cheap
and affordable
do you recognize this operating system
incidentally this is a very early beta
of what became windows 95
you can see that they really didn't
quite have the taskbar
idea and so on worked out in the
beginning um
the 386 had a secret feature feature
that is now
almost forgotten it is no longer present
in 64-bit
x86 chips a 386 can not only pretend to
be
the old early 816-bit 8088 processor
it can pretend to be several of them at
once
this was an absolute killer feature this
meant that once
microsoft adopted windows to three it
adapted windows to 386 chips
the new windows 3 could run dos apps
in a window multitask them and actually
run them better than on dos
you could copy and paste you could run
several of them side by side
you could run a spreadsheet because
we're talking about pcs
save the figures load them into a
graphing program and do a nice
chart because most spreadsheets couldn't
do that on the era of dos
um this was a huge change
and it made them a lot of money and it
meant that as 32-bit caught on
it allowed the pc to catch up
with all of the proprietary graphical
machines
it got all those things that only the 68
000 owners had before
they got multitasking they got a nice
graphical interface
they got color and sound and video
and all this kind of cool stuff
so this was a new era but
it was very hard to adapt
ibm microsoft and apple struggled
massively around this time
ibm had a project called os2
some of you might have seen that um
os2 was very clever it was a
focused ground-up rewrite and
replacement for dos
but ibm targeted the 286 chip which
couldn't do the multitasking
of dos apps feature it doomed the os
apple apple did an awful lot of flailing
around about this time
um i'll get back to that but microsoft
did something very interesting they took
a long-term view
they ran two side-by-side operating
system projects
one project took the fairly
shabby 16-bit gui that they had from the
80s and enhanced it
the other project was much more
interesting they started with the
cpu independent version of os2 which was
called os 2 version 3.
it ran on intel's attempt to make a
wrist chip which was code named the n10
so this project was code named os2nt um
it was barely a sketch of an operating
system at the time
so they went to digital and they poached
digital's programming lead
and his team dave cutler they gave them
os2 3 and said
finish it make it work um well os2
n10 became os2nt which became windows nt
and you may not use it but you all know
it
um it looks like windows
it's nothing like windows underneath nt
it looks very much like digital vms
because it's written mostly by the same
team
the data storage structures the way it
handles interrupts and
ioqs and everything are all borrowed
very directly
from vms
it looks like a descendant of the
80s desktop pc but actually
it's really a descendant of a 1970s mini
computer os
apple well apple flailed around bless
them they really tried
um they tried to work with ibm
on a totally new object-oriented
operating system
it failed they tried to rewrite their
proprietary operating system to deliver
true multitasking and so on
it failed they did a port of linux
running on top of the
micro kernel to their power pc max
it failed pretty much um they did a
radical pocket computer with the acorn
processor in it
within a lisp-based operating system it
did make it to market
failed um so in the end they gave up and
they bought a workstation company and
this
is what resulted they bought next of
course and
they went to unix like all the other
workstation makers
but the next programmers when apple
bought them put in a virtual machine and
in the virtual machine they ran an
entire copy of the old apple operating
system
to give backwards compatibility the new
god you've got to have it if you don't
have it
your computer's not worth having
so
the year 2000
variety the diversity of the 20th
century
has gone it's dead even microsoft's
weird hybrid
16-stroke 32-bit line is dead
it's left two types of computer
both are written in c
both are based on a very mini computer
like core design with
little walled off memory partitions with
compiled applications running in them
calling operating system facilities by a
rigorously defined api
often with visible c like properties
even if you're using a different
compiled language
the two families are of course unix and
windows nt and basically everything else
is gone
now i i rather like this this is from a
great little article about one of my
favorite obscure operating systems
oberon
um a family tree of graphical operating
systems so doug engelbart the mother of
all demos
inspired the guys at xerox and xerox had
a visitor from the
uh eth in zurich professor niklaus fiert
the inventor of pascal he saw the
small talk system and he went wow this
is cool but they didn't have the budget
for such high-end kit
so he went back to zurich and he wrote
his own operating system in modular two
which he
really ought to have called pascal to if
he had better marketing skills
um and he called it the lilith and then
he did
another successor operating system
called oberon
meanwhile the xerox park project
completely failed to be usefully
commercialized never sold but it
inspired the lisa which inspired the mac
which inspired mac os 10
and all graphical unixes
and it also inspired windows nt um
so here we are today we have
two operating system families one is
descended from
a deck operating system from the 70s
which is descended from a deck operating
system in the 60s
and the other is inspired by a
third-party
deck mini computer operating system from
the 60s how's that for diversity
what happened well in the 50s mainframes
advanced they got better and better and
better
every time a new generation of
mainframes came they added facilities
they invented some clever stuff but they
didn't move on
because there comes a point when your
project is so big and
you can't usefully enhance it it does
everything you can think of and it works
meanwhile over in the micro side of
things and the mini computer side of
things we kept on getting generations of
computers with less storage and less
hardware facilities than the previous
generation
but cheaper and because they were
cheaper they sold lots of them
and that meant everything had to be
rewritten
every 10 or 15 years for the entire
history of computing
we have thrown the entire thing away and
rewritten it from scratch
until about 1993 to 1994
1993 the release of the first version of
windows called
nt windows nt called 3.1 for licensing
reasons
and 1994 linux
version 1.0 um why
linux well this is sco open server six
this was
mainly sold as a server there's a clue
in the name the full function version
was one thousand four hundred dollars
for a single user license
ain't nobody can afford that on x86
boxes so we just rewrote the whole thing
but all of the developments that
happened on the workstations all the
developments that had happened in unix r
d oberon also inspired the unix guys to
create the successity unix which i think
should be called unix 2 but was actually
called plan 9 from bell labs
it's window manager is directly inspired
by oberon
its editor is directly inspired by
oberon it's unix with true built-in
kubernetes in the kernel basically
processors can be mobile
processors can move across the network
to any compatible machine
subject to privileges and so on went
nowhere
what happened well what we had was good
enough
in the 90s instead of throwing away all
the 80s stuff and starting again
instead of moving forward we moved
backwards
we went back 25 years we took
sophisticated operating systems from
1970s mini computers
and we updated them and adapted them to
modern hardware
and that's where we've stayed since then
we've taken some of the nice 80s stuff
we've got nice colorful gooeys on top
we've added touch control to those guise
this is a unix computer with
two-level store in my pocket
i bet everybody here has got a computer
in their pocket some of you have
probably got several
but it was good enough we didn't throw
everything away we didn't burn it down
we just kept going
so now you have two choices
you can go with 40 years of accumulated
baggage
from the ibm pc there's windows 1
or you can choose unix and have 50 years
of accumulated baggage yay
that is gnome one incidentally um
that's your choice why well because it's
good enough we all know it
it works well we've fixed most of the
bugs now
it'll do it does the job there haven't
been any big technical shake-ups since
those 32-bit pcs
these mini computer operating systems
could handle 8-bit computers 9-bit
computers 12-bit computers 16-bit
computers 18-bit computers
and 38-bit computers 64-bit no problem
as the previous speaker said minix unix
was running on multi-processor computers
in the 70s multi-core processors no
problem
so that's where we are
i'm sorry this is a cruel example this
is 50 years of baggage
we are well half of us anyway are still
using
basically the first ever interactive
screen editor
i started using this in 1988 i still
hate it with a passion
but just in case i tried telling emacs
and i hate that with a passion as well
so you know
um um i use a
i use a graphical thing called oxygen
for my job um
i hate it too but um we haven't really
moved forward
we now have computers based on 70s
worktation technology
all of the advances since the beginning
of the 1970s and
into the 1980s there was some wonderful
stuff out there
amazing dynamic programming languages to
construct rich internet capable guise
lisp small talk they still exist
they're niche programming languages now
operating systems and forget about it
there were new radical unix-based
operating systems like plan nine and its
successor inferno these are both really
worth your time to have a look at
inferno didn't just take the network
transparency of plan nine it gave you
processor transparency as well it
embedded a virtual machine into the
kernel
but not like the jvm which it went up
against this was a
register based virtual machine it's much
easier to optimize
all modern processors are register based
because you can optimize them
the jvm is stack based all the stack
based computers have gone away
um there were c plus plus operating
systems in the 90s
i personally used to use scion computers
with epoc32 which became symbian which
powered all the early mobile
smartphones gone away um there was bos
the nearly new apple operating system
they'd be totally dead now if they
bought it
it's gone away buried inside access inc
in japan there's haiku which is lovely
and i like haiku a lot but it is not
small fast and elegant like bs was
software went backwards as the hardware
went forwards
all the major revolutions in computing
that have defined the generations
have been defined when the hardware got
worse not better
every time we have had to adopt a new
generation of computers
mini computers then 8-bit micros then
all-in-one 8-bit micros then 16-bit
micros
everything was thrown away and destroyed
and we started again it was
normal it was just what you did but you
started again with new better languages
and new better ideas
and in about mid 90s that crashed to a
halt and we haven't done it since
because the hardware hasn't got worse
since the mid 90s
we are stuck now with multi-gigabyte
operating systems with tens of millions
of lines of code in dozens of languages
that no one human being can understand
anymore
and we can't substantially improve them
anymore because they're so big and so
complicated we just don't really
understand them so now we're developing
things like container technology which i
document for a living
which understands that they'll fail all
the time and detects when they fail and
restarts them in a quick and efficient
manner
software is culture and our culture has
been stultifying
for 25 years when 25 years ago it
reached back another 25 years
we need a new generation of worse
computers
we need simpler computers we need to
take something away
i propose next slide please
oh yeah seminal paper you should
absolutely all read this
c is not a low level language your
computer is not a first pdp 11.
excellent paper um
so we took the radical guise of the 80s
in their marvellous object-oriented
dynamic languages and we reint
re-implemented them with statically
compiled manually memory managed
languages with weak typing
and um yeah they're shiny and
everybody's got distracted by the shiny
this might might save us
it's a very big if these are
a pair of intel optane
nvdimms i maintain the
section in the suse enterprise linux
documentation relating to supporting
these devices
um i got the job because i was the only
person who'd heard of an nvdimm on the
team
um probably shouldn't have disclosed
that should i um
this is a big shift if it happens it's
not going to be
risk 5 it's not going to be an
out-of-the-box mill processor it's not
going to be
processors at all it's going to be
storage this
is kind of like flash memory
it's much much better than flash memory
it's orders of magnitude faster
it can be rewritten orders of magnitude
more times
um it's also substantially cheaper than
ram you can
buy it as a very high speed pcie
ssd but you can also buy it as a dim and
stick it straight into the dim sockets
on your server motherboard
it's not like an ssd it's not pretending
to be a disk drive it's memory
right in the processor's memory map
except whatever you write there just
stays there you can pull the plug
when you put the plug back in the
contents of memory are exactly as they
were
now it's true this has a finite lifespan
it's many millions of rewrites in the
current early versions and there are
multiple companies working on
non-volatile memory if you ran one
little loop counting to a million in a
block of this ram it would burn out the
ram
so probably you're going to have some
ordinary ram in there as well but you
can partition the workspace
you can have a computer based on this
you don't need disk drives anymore
and if you don't need disk drives you
don't need disk controllers
if you don't need disk controllers you
don't need the whole concept of a file
system
which is a way of finding blocks of
secondary storage
finding the right one and loading it
into ram that is now an obsolete concept
we go back to the 40s with machines with
magnetic non-volatile memory
the whole distinction between primary
and secondary storage can just go away
you don't boot the operating system you
turn off the computer when you turn it
back on it's still there in memory
just picks up where it left off you
don't install an operating system
you boot the thing off the network when
it's new and there's the operating
system in memory and it just stays there
until you upgrade it
why bother with disk files there's no
files anymore you don't need files
everything's just a block of memory you
just need some system every operating
system there has ever been
has systems for managing and allocating
their memory and deciding what's in
where and keeping track of it this is
not new technology
this is old technology but
this is simpler this stuff is way
cheaper
than ram at the moment it's more
expensive than flash but i think in a
few years it's going to replace flash
and then the whole idea of the ssd goes
away this will be
the rest of my notes thing um
simpler and because it's simpler
it'll be cheaper and every major
generation of worse computers has been
driven by the fact that they're cheaper
because that's all the manufacturers
really care about is not clever software
it's how
much profit margin there is
my um iphone is three years old now i
bought it second hand and
uh battery's second battery is nearly
dead now
i'm probably going to replace it with
another chinese android phone because i
can get a much better one
for 100 pounds cheaper is what drives
everything
i think we don't need better computers
we don't need more processor cores we
don't need better gpus i mean we're
going to get them anyway
you know what we need we need worse
computers
we need an inferior generation of
simpler machines
that lack major facilities that we take
for granted these days
that make us tear everything down set
fire to it and start again
it sounds ridiculous because you've all
been worshiping the god of backwards
compatibility
for 25 years but actually that's done a
massive amount of harm to the whole
world of computing
it's time to start over it's time to
burn the whole thing down
and reboot it and that's it thank you
very much
thank you
thank you yeah proven for this talk i
think it was very fascinating over
all this history um we have time for one
question so please
keep seated if there is one question
and wait for it we are just nearly done
is there a question
if you have a question just wait for me
or i don't see a quest
ah there's one question
there's some contact details if you want
to tell me i'm completely wrong
afterward hi liam
question given that we have
40 years or 50 years
where on earth do you think the the
operating system
iconoclasm is going to come from
to actually make use rather than
reinventing another wheel
in software with of this new hardware so
the question was where will this
operating system iconoclasm come from i
think the open source community is
ideally positioned to do this
because it's going to be risky which is
something businesses are very averse to
um every important new generation of
computer when it came out was a toy
it wasn't serious it wasn't something
you did big serious work with
it was a toy that you played around with
and you know what ms-dos was a toy when
it was launched cpm was a toy
linux was a toy and i quote i think it
won't be big and serious like gnu we
should start playing around
those of us who don't need to risk our
company budget on it
and start playing around there are open
source versions of small talk and list
which are ideal for this there's oberon
out there it's open source
there's plan nine there's materials to
draw on
but start again re-implement it play
around come up with toys who has the
most
cool new toy to program with
next question yeah i think that's a good
good end for this talk and a good
motivation to do something
so um thank you again for the talk for
everybody else
[Applause]
you