i work with geo server which we're going
to be talking about today
geotools which is a data access library
does a lot of rendering does a lot of
that
geo for geospatial jts topology suite
which is the rocket science
of the geospatial uh community this is
the library that does all the geometries
without geometry and uh and being able
to compare
shapes we wouldn't have an open source
gis industry at all
um i just help out with that project i'm
not one of the rocket scientists
um i work on a couple other projects
imogen and
and udig i also volunteer with the
community
so i volunteer with the osgo foundation
i just wrapped up my second tour as osgo
director
i serve on the incubation committee
helping
new project teams not to be embarrassing
on the internet
i'm also the geotools project officer i
also help out with the marketing team
because without users a lot of our open
source projects would get very lonely
i also do some volunteer work with the
eclipse foundation
now there's several popular geoserver
talks
we do an annual kind of team update a
tour of what's new
this is great for folks that already use
geoserver
we do a geoserver feature frenzy this is
all the stuff that's cool and exciting
and kind of the headline features
that we wouldn't normally get to talk
about every year
and we also do one called geoserver
ecosystem where we
show a lot of the crazy systems that
people have set her up
worldwide and that's very inspirational
it gives
folks a chance to see what what's
possible
there's a problem with all of these
talks every time i i help out with one
of them
i get a question so what does geo server
actually do
and so that's what this talk is about
so let me start with what geoserver is
for
geoserver has a vision right on the top
of our homepage geoserver is an open
source server
for sharing geospatial data we're really
passionate about sharing data
the project was founded out of like a
community project in new york to like
help the community map all the trees in
their neighborhood
we're here because we want people to be
able to share a map and
we don't want you to stop just at
sharing a map we want you to share the
data behind the map
and it's not enough just to share the
data we want to support editing
we want to make sure those community
members can actually edit the data
not just consume it blindly
so this is the foundation principle of
how
our software project was formed our
approach
how we're trying to address this design
for interoperability
we actually take that pretty seriously
to publish data from
any major data source using open
standards so i just want to unpack that
a bit
geoserver doesn't want to lock you in
we're not a vendor
we want you to share your data with as
many folks as
possible and to that end geo server is
kind of
open-ended it can be considered a
framework where we gradually plug
more and more protocols in over time so
once you set up your geoserver
and you're publishing your data as you
upgrade you can reach more and more
clients
we also don't want you to have to like
import your data into geoserver
it hangs out in the middle if you're one
of these organizations that
has like oracle as a as a
data policy well you're going to be able
to use geoserver to take the data out of
oracle
and share it with the open community
if you are in the cloud and have like um
geomesa or mongodb you'll be able to
take
geoserver and have and use it as a front
end so people can access all your cloud
data
and we do start with the industry
standards it's the opposite
of a not invented here syndrome if we
have to invent something
in isolation chances are we're taking
the wrong approach
we're always looking for folks to
collaborate with
so most people come to geo server just
wanting to publish a map
so each data set in geo server speak
is a layer of content you can actually
gather those layers into a group
and arrange them in order to like make a
little base map or something
there's also a small little layer
preview that you can use to like test
things out locally
geoserver in this case is the rendering
engine so it's producing maps
for clients on the web desktop mobile
etc
we've got more than one approach
remember it's just the concept of
publishing a layer
you might publish it as a map where
people can zoom and pan around and do
ad-hoc queries
you might publish an entire tile set of
data for like mobile clients
the result of publishing a map doesn't
always look like an image
like it doesn't have to be a png svg and
kml output
um they're little vector formats that
include
baked in styling information on how
they're supposed to be drawn
you can also have extensions for
geoserver that get it to generate out
pdfs
and one i personally like is vector
tiles which are pre-processed
um little vector data sets uh and
they're pre-processed for client-side
rendering
i'm just gonna breathe there everyone's
looking stunned
how am i doing so far there's a question
i'll try i guess i should have got some
water
the next thing we can do is vector data
publishing so in the spirit of open
we're really
wanting to set ourselves up to share the
data behind the map
and we've got interfaces that support
queries and a whole wide range of
different out formats
from json to kml to zip shapefiles if
that's what you like to work with
who likes zip shape files
wow this is a developer conference
i was just at a qgis user meeting and uh
yeah
they're they're in the middle of the
transition from shape files to
geopackage and
there's terror
we also support vector editing so we
really want to make sure those community
members can get a hold of and interact
with the data
we did make sure editing is off by
default but we only did that
recently so if you've been using
geoserver for years
check your settings you might be letting
anybody on the internet edit your
information
we also do provide direct raster access
now
keep in mind for the vector and the and
the raster access
geoserver is not providing you an
interactive experience that's up to a
client like qgis on the desktop
or open layers or leaflet in a web
mapping environment
okay so you get a general purpose of
what geoserver is for
who here owns data they want to share
a couple people that's great
so geo server configuration
when you use launch geo server there's
this little welcome screen
and it's it's a little web configuration
app
that you can use to configure and
publish your different data products
i need to stop at this point and say
this is not
geoserver this is just a little tool to
configure
the real services the real web services
are over here on the right hand side
the different service capabilities and
endpoints which
clients use to programmatically access
the data
yep so if you're going into production
you probably want to configure your you
know your apache
or something to hide these configuration
screens there's no reason to share that
with the public
my examples use natural earth so
i'm going to walk through how geoserver
is set up
to begin with your data is collected
into individual workspaces
these are like folders which you can use
to organize
content there's a few little tweaks i
got to talk about here
each workspace is considered a distinct
xml namespace
for all of those little formats that
really like xml because
the 1990s were fun and they had good
music
the workspace also has a little name
that's used in a prefix when we're
talking to the individual layers
so we can go through we can hit new
workspace fill in a little bit of
information
and we've got a new empty workspace to
to work with there
advanced thing to talk about each
workspace
can be its own distinct web service so
if you're supporting
dozens of teams you might want to set up
a workspace for each team
next we get into data sources so data
sources is
geoserver being connected to a directory
of shape files
or you know two terabytes of
geotiffs in a folder or
a cloud service or a database um
the data store name is internal to
geoserver that doesn't show up
on any of the protocols that way you can
change
what service you're using behind a layer
and no one
none of the clients have to know so we
can go through we can
uh add a new data store in this case i'm
pointing it to a directory of shapefiles
so my connection parameters aren't very
interesting it's just a single
path on my server and it's the same
thing here when i'm publishing
a geotiff i'm pointing to a single path
on the file system
i should have had an example here
working with a database
so pausing workspace
inside the workspace we've got various
different data sources which we're using
to connect
to the information that's already there
in our organization
uh for vector layers um geosurface
publishing information is distinct
layers
we've got a little uh we've got several
things you need to check when you
when you publish you want to make sure
your layer has a name
and a title the name is actually machine
readable and it's used on
all the protocols and urls and the title
is human readable
we also really need to make sure that
the spatial reference system
and the bounds are correct if we don't
have that information correct clients
won't be able to draw
our data in the right spot each protocol
is going to use a different term for how
they publish the information
sometimes a layer will be called a layer
sometimes it'll be called a feature type
sometimes it's a coverage or a grid
coverage or a tile set
it really just depends on what protocol
the client is using
so in this case i'm going to the culture
data store i
set up before i'm choosing one of the
shape files for my directory of
shapefiles
and i'm hitting publish to start out
with i'm filling in the name
and the and the title and i'm sure
nobody can read that
and then i'm going through here and
double checking the bounds
and the bounding box and in this case
i'm generating those
by having it look at the data set
same thing for a raster data layer i can
go through and publish a raster
geotiffs only have one data product
inside of them
but if i'm working with something like
netcdf i might have to pick and choose
which data product inside the netcdf
bundle i want to publish
okay so next up i've got a layer group
so
the most common use for a layer group is
to bundle up several layers together
in order to draw a base map the layers
are listed in draw order
you can also use layer groups to kind of
construct a table of content structure
so like a series of folders to organize
your your data
so i can go to layer group add a new
layer
provide a name and a title and then i
need to go down to the layer section and
add my layers in order
and that's the order they're going to be
drawn in so my raster data
i want to draw first and then my vector
data
and if i had point data i draw that on
top and that's really unintuitive for me
so this mistake of getting things in the
wrong order is that one of the most
common
geoserver kind of learning troubles
after we've got our layers we can go
ahead and calculate the bounds and the
coordinate
reference system it's hard to do that
before we have content
which is why we added the layers first
okay take a break how's that working for
people
going too fast can people hear me
a couple people good
next i want to talk about styling
geosaver has a bad reputation with
styling the
styling engine the drawing engine we use
from geotools is
really super powerful but
geoserver out of the box uh supports a
format called sld or style layer
descriptor
which is all done in xml but here's the
secret
nobody wanted you to write that by hand
um we really want you to use a tool like
qgis
or geostyler or any of the other tools
to generate your sld
and we've started to see extensions
developed where people have
human readable css or yaml
style definitions which makes geoserver
a lot more accessible to people
so we really recommend if you're a human
you
write your style in something intended
for humans
there's built-in styles uh provided
one thing that's interesting is each
workspace has a style folder
and that's where you're going to store
any icons or fonts that you want to use
for your cartography
so i can add a new style in this case
i'm
adding it to my workspace i'm calling it
map color 9
and i'm choosing the ysld format
which someone very carefully thought of
as a joke but it's a yaml
version of s the sld concept
so i can hit generate
the geoserver style editor lets you look
at a layer preview as you're
updating your style so i'm going to go
ahead and switch over to the preview tab
and have a look i'm going to fill in a
little snippet of yaml here where i'm
going to recode map color 9 from one to
a color from two to a color and so on so
this is a very
well it's more human readable than than
xml
so this is a little bit more
approachable
here's what that looks like and then
finally
i can go over to the publishing tab and
i can associate this style
with my state province shape layer i
published earlier
and here's what that looks like
so it's my hope that we've managed to
introduce
four concepts workspace which is a
folder to organize your things
data stores which are used to connect
you to the data in your organization
layers which is where you published
individual data products and styles
where your
where you're choosing how you want those
drawn
okay just checking time
i'm not too bad for time so i've got a
great question how does it work
who here is programmed in java before
okay how many people have used spring
okay so geo server is a spring based
application
it didn't used to be uh geo server used
to be done in a system called
struts i think is that a system i'm
trying to forget it it was terrible
um the other interesting framework we
use
is one called wicket has anyone used
wicket before
it's a ui framework which only a java
developer could love
the reason we like it is because it's
modular
and geoserver is a very fiercely modular
application
we really want all our extensions and
community modules to be distinct
so people can have the code and their
code can also include
user interface contributions um we've
got a little
so the web administration is done with
wicked and open layers and so on
our rest api uh we transitioned from
wrestlet
over to spring model view controller a
few years ago
the core geoserver application is
creatively called dispatcher
so that's the thing that takes in
requests and
uh dispatches it off to the appropriate
service like
wms or wcs or so on
we actually have an embedded an entirely
otherwise innocent application called
geoweb cache
you can actually download geo web cache
and install it
on your own it's a perfectly good kind
of tile proxy thing written in java
but in this case we're using it as a
library
underneath the covers geoserver has a
catalog which is where we store
all our configuration we also have a
data directory
where we were storing all those files
and fonts and icons
and the resource pool represents our
live connections to all the different
data sources
i just wanted to bring these ones up
because when we look into advanced
deployments of geoserver people will
take these components
and plug in alternates
under the covers we use spring geotools
and an image processing library called
java advanced imaging
and that's what this slide says
okay so we've got a lot of effort put
into g
into keeping geoserver modular the
formal modules we have are called
extensions
so these are actually part of geoserver
they're released as
part every time we make a release they
have the same version number
the only reason they're an extension
isn't is not because they're not good
it's because we want to keep geoserver
as small as possible
and have you only install the things you
use
so oracle is an example of connecting to
a new
data type we also have entire other
services like web processing service
that you could install and geo server
would you know
learn to speak uh and manage entirely
new set of uh
challenges um collect into cloud
things like geo mesa or mongodb
we also have a really robust security
model so there's a
an extension called geofence where it
rips out the geoserver security system
and puts in a really sophisticated one
where you can limit editing to just a
geofence
area and one of my personal favorite
extensions is one that does vector tiles
we also have a scary kind of
demilitarized zone
called community modules this dates from
when we were hosted in
in subversion and so it was easier to
give people a little community play area
in order to support grad students and so
on
over time we've actually found that
consultants are working here
so they are doing some work in public
for their customers but they haven't yet
met our
our requirements for documentation and
quality assurance
so if you see a community module it's an
opportunity to pick up the code yourself
or to see who's interested in supporting
it it's very much as a use
very much use at your own risk
so examples of community modules here's
one which
backs all of the catalog and data
directory onto a
onto a blob store and that's really nice
if you're in amazon web services
you can store all of your configuration
in rws
and cluster for example backup and
restore
pick up all of your configuration from
test and deploy it into production
map ml sap hana all kinds of stuff
so just to wrap up we've got a project
steering committee
we're part of the osgo foundation so
they've reviewed our processes
we try and keep things open and fair
we do have a strong history of
collaboration this
project has seen many entire companies
come and go so
it was started by open planning project
i don't know 2002 or something like that
the initial core team of companies was
open planning project
geosolutions refractions research
we've seen government departments come
in and take part
so we try and keep our event we try and
keep our steering committee with a mix
of skills and backgrounds okay so
try it out there's binary there's a web
archive
um we don't have any windows or mac
installers right now
our build server had some vandalism last
year and we haven't restored those
docker there's a bazillion docker images
out there but nothing official
and there's a few companies that are
willing to offer you hosting
thanks
sure if you don't have questions i have
questions for you so speak up
yep
so moving features
i'm not sure we do offer animations and
lots of our raster support is temporal
based and
a lot of our featured data sets can have
a time component
but i don't think there's anything
specific for oh what do you call it like
um
i can't like bearings and so on
okay
yeah i'm not aware of any r d right now
i do know one of the community modules
is working on the ogc apis for example
those community modules are often where
a lot of
like ogc test bed work takes place not
all of it sees the light of day
yeah sir
weirdos um yes maybe we should talk
about stuff
right i'm just wondering do you know
geocyan
no okay that's a geology format
and cyro spent like 10 million
teaching geo server how to do all that
stuff right so just ask questions
right
i understand one cottage industry for
consultants
is writing a data store to read abnormal
things
so geo server can make them consumable
by others
maybe we should talk after it seems like
a challenge
there was someone over here sir what
city are you based out of
that's a great question i'm really
jet-lagged so i think i'm gradually
moving east
i think i'm probably at halifax now
no i'm i'm out of vancouver island
um so go to vancouver fall in the ocean
go a little bit further
so victoria bc but you mentioned it's a
netherlands-based company it is they're
in a little village called benacom
oh okay yeah
i just joined them so i i know nothing
okay
okay the footprint
yeah the memories oh um it's actually
not as scary as you would expect so it's
been
it's been designed from the ground up to
stream
so it never loads the data into memory
it's always streaming the features past
the image processing um engine in
particular is really good
using a on-demand processing
i can't remember the right raster
buzzword for it for that
so i i've certainly run geoservers in
like 256 mags
i've seen people throw lots of memory at
it and have no effect
so it really depends on your data set
how much memory would
help you does that
help i don't know
okay there's versions of geo server that
have been set up
as little spring boot applications for
cloud
i'm not sure i do you recommend them
anyone's done any packaging
there's a reason why not that java
advanced imaging thing
is not open source it's a sun binary
something or other license
i actually got oracle to donate the code
to me actually this
guy did so i'm trying to rescue that bit
of code
but i didn't get into the java dev room
i'm here with you so
it might take longer yeah
you