exporter
so exactly thank you hello everybody
we have plenty of time i submitted this
as a lightning talk and was allocated an
hour so
um if you have questions or comments or
anything please feel free to
to interrupt me and
does anybody use prometheus already
or it's new for everybody a few people
okay you've heard of it
great we got a
prometheus exporter in freebc 12. so
somebody in the freebsd world at least
knows and uses prometheus apart from me
so this was a few months ago i
i wrote an exporter to to make
disk utilization metrics available to
prometheus
from freebsd and i was
encouraged to to come here and talk
about it i did a blog post about it and
was encouraged to come here and tell you
so
uh since
many people probably don't know
prometheus i'll start out by talking a
little bit about
what it is and what it does and why it's
awesome
and then the concept of exporters and
then
we'll get to gstat and the actual
exporter that i wrote for that
i also have a graffana dashboard to
actually visualize the data connected
and if everything works and my internet
connection keeps working then
i have a live demo of some servers at my
workplace
using this so it's always nice to see
some actual real data
but i'm not making any promises because
my connection has been flagging so let's
see when we get to it live demos always
as you know a bit tricky sometimes so
my name is thomas rasmussen i'm called
twigling
on the internet i'm
born and live in copenhagen in denmark
and i do system architecture
build and administer freebsd servers
i do some programming as well and was
recently laid off
with three months with salary so i'm
just going to fuss them and
relaxing and enjoying myself at the
moment and looking for something else to
do
i run a dns service called uncensored
dns for 10 years now
11 years which is before
google dns and before all the other
public recursive dns server services
i started this as an alternative to the
isp sensor
often censored isp dns servers
and it's been running since i also help
organize bonheck which is an annual
danish hacker camp i highly recommend
going it is a great time it's a week
with temps and laptops and hacking
around with all kinds of fun things
and i have a bunch of minor
open source projects on github
i use freebsd exclusively on servers
i've used this since
5.2.1 i think was my my first installed
server
and on my laptops i run something called
cubes os which is an
awesome operating system i wish it was
freebsd based but it's a
fedora and scent based it's the concept
is you have
different virtual machines for different
contexts so i have one for work and one
for
playing with the bond hack stuff and
they can really disposable browsers
for for surfing so the vm just
disappears so if you
happen to click something bad then just
nothing really happens
so awesome concept so
i'm here to talk about this g-stat
exporter
this is actually the first time i've
been in the psd room there's never been
room but
one of the perks of being a speaker is
that you have to let me in
so um i wrote this tweet
and someone picked up on it and uh and
recommended i come to uh
to fuss them and talk about it and here
we are so
prometheus and in their own words it's
an open source monitoring system
dimensional data model flexible query
language efficient time series database
and that is pretty much it it is very
the whole ecosystem around it is very
unixy in that that they do
one thing and they do it well prometheus
in itself
is is a time series database
it really doesn't do anything except
collect metrics and stick them in a time
series database
and then have it has an api to make them
available to graphene for example so you
can pull the data back out
it doesn't do alerting it has something
that's something called alert manager
which
from the same team but it's a separate
separate piece of software
separate configuration file and stuff
which handles
alerting and alert dependencies
and which teams should get what alert
and patient duty support and all that
stuff
monitoring has often i think been many
years been
it's been a bit of a like there was a
void left when nagi has kind of
stopped being modern and i've been i've
been using sapix and a few other things
but nothing has really been
it's like they try to do too much
somehow it's a big job both to
gather the data and visualize it and do
alerting and everything and i haven't
really been happy with anything
and i think you know like the first time
you tried zfs and thought this is what a
file system should have been like all
along where have you been all my life
this is
how i feel about monitoring with
prometheus it is an excellent
system so
it is based on they call it dimensional
time series data
it means that your metrics can have
labels
they call it so if you have a metric
called http requests
total for example for a web server then
and you get a number when you when you
scrape the data so you had 100 requests
then that data can be can have multiple
dimensions and that can have labels to
say
what the path of the request was or what
the http status code was
so you can ask to get only the http
404 requests for example and then make a
graph of those on your
in your graphana this is incredibly
powerful it's actually a
relatively simple concept but it
enriches the data
greatly prometheus and alert manager and
all the
accompanying software has all written
and go it was
started at the soundcloud some years ago
it's been
open source since 2015 and there's no
company that owns it now it's a regular
open source project with
many contributors and a great community
a great ise channel and stuff so if you
have
questions they're very happy to help
so this is the the diagram of the
ecosystem from their website
um central to the whole thing is the pro
media server it's a
time series database and it stores
the matrix of course on some sort of
disk storage
it's a pull model prometheus that's one
of the things that
some people have to get used to which
means that prometheus connects
to the stuff it's monitoring and pulls
the metrics over http
various ways around that if you
absolutely cannot do it like that but
but that is the
idea for example the freebsd system
exporter that came and
arrived in freebies g12 is supposed to
be run
in and the inaudib
connects to it and pulls out the metrics
so and that that's what the the
exporters make available
they open an http endpoint and
it's just a plain text key value list of
lines i'll
have examples later
there's something called push gateway
that if you have a job that runs for an
hour and then has some metrics to submit
at the end of that
you can use push gateway for that it has
a very
um extensive service discovery system so
if you are
aws kubernetes user or you use one of
the many many cloud services available
there's probably a discovery service
discovery thing available for it
at work i i worked on a
worked in an isp until i got laid off
we used the file service discovery thing
and just exported a list of customers
and ip addresses and that was
automatically ingested by prometheus so
when we add a new customer in our
central provisioning system it
automatically shows up and
starts pulling the data from it
and to
to talk to prometheus and and
query the data get it out they
invented something called prom cool it
is
what doesn't really have anything to do
with sql it is a
custom query language specifically for
this and that will be examples of this
later and it is a very powerful
and easy to use language
and like i said alert manager is a
separate component so when
when you add some
threshold or something you want to be
alerted on in prometheus
it pushes an alert to alert manager an
alert manager handles
all the nitty-gritty with who's on
vacation now and who has the duty and
who does what
so all that complexity is separate from
prometheus
okay so we generally speak
of black box and white box monitoring
black box monitoring is when you
ping your whatever or just
poke something from the outside check if
it's listening on port 80 or
whatever you might do white box
monitoring is when the
the thing being monitored is kind of in
the game
so so for example uh
the freebsd systems alex powder is a
good example or
an exporter for yeah for gstat data for
example
means you're kind of inside the system
exposing the metrics to the outside
and that's a much better way to do it
than blackbox monitoring
it has support for that as well if if
you need to
like we do at work ping seven thousand
customers every five seconds then
you do that with uh something called
black box exporter but
but mostly and primarily it is white box
monitoring it is
supposed to be used uh
with uh with the exporters built into
whatever you are monitoring
so if you have a system like our
provisioning system at work it's easy to
for example
export metrics for the queue length for
provisioning the customers
the router needs to be the switch ports
need to be configured and there's
sometimes a queue
if there's many changes at once and it's
very easy when you're
in the code to export this metric and
just
do a slash prometheus or slash matrix
endpoint in your in your system and
export it it's over http like i said
and it is designed to to handle
everything you can throw at it
you don't shouldn't be picky you should
instrument all parts of your system uh
anything that might someday make sense
and even if you think it doesn't because
sometimes these
subtle little changes in whatever can it
turn out to be
to be important and then it's very nice
to have the history it is
it is very efficient it is designed to
handle hundreds of thousands of metrics
and on a single
single server commodity hardware
it doesn't do it has a little bit of you
can when you're exploring the data in
the prometheus web interface it can draw
a simple crude graph but it's not meant
for graphing it's
meant to be used with gravina or
something else but i highly recommend
it is excellent integrated into graphata
there's client libraries in many
languages the g-static port i wrote is
written in python and you start out with
these
10 lines or something from the
prometheus example client and you just
add
name define your metrics saying we have
a in g stat we have a
disk i o busy present message metric or
whatever and
and you know feed data into them and it
takes care of listening on the on http
and and serving the data up in the in
the right order and it's uh
it is easy to use and they have of
course in go and many other languages
client libraries so it is easy to get
started
riding your own exporter
so it um it is like i said very
efficient
they say about three and a half pipes
per data point
and it is remarkably efficient when
pulling in data
we went to we replaced our cyborgs
installation which was
thrashing the discs using a postgres as
a back-end
i love postgres i don't love cervix but
it was a decent setup but it was i mean
we could barely
handle polling them once per minute
the five eight thousand customers or
however much we had back then
and when we switched to prometheus we're
polling them once every five seconds
we're doing additional metrics besides
what we did with cybex and the server is
bought now it's not doing nothing
so we went from absolutely threshing the
drives to
the server being almost idle it is
amazingly
efficient if you go beyond what one
server can handle
it supports sharding and federation so
you can have many prometheus servers
working together
and it does that very very well and the
alert manager as well
supports high availability stuff so you
can send an alert to any number of alert
manager instances and only one of them
will
actually alert you at
work the prometheus
installation i was managing this had
about 750 000 time series
and about 13 and a half thousand per
second metrics put into the database and
that's small in prometheus terms that's
a
not an issue at all you can do that on a
laptop or on whatever
it's a in a jail all my stuff runs in
sales
and you can easily have like one for
each team it's not like
managing an elk instance or something
like that where you have to
you can just wave up a new if you if you
want one for
the network team and one for the
operations team or whatever you can
easily do that um
okay so the query language
from ql uh i brought a few few examples
and it's easy to look up
it has
a page or two and then your if you
understand basic uh
basic statistics and math then then it
should be easy to use
first things first http requests total
is the example metric we're using here
so that's a that's that was the
internet connection that stopped working
um so that just returns the metric http
request total
if for example i want the metric but
only if the job label
is api server and the handler is slave
apis less comments
then i put it in the curly brackets and
it only returns
the number of http requests that had
those
those labels you can also
return return arrangements you get you
get all the values for given for for
example for a five minute
interval uh if you need that uh you can
use regular expressions for the labels
and um and you can do
fuzzy matching and stuff for the uh for
the label values as well
i use those labels a lot in the g-stat
exporter to save stuff like the disks
serial numbers and stuff we'll get to
that later
um a bit more advanced it has it has
some keywords to do
uh for example uh it can calculate uh
the rate over five minutes
uh for for this metric or even do
a quantile uh 95th
percentile is used a lot when
when charging for bandwidth and hosting
operations and stuff like that or
wherever you need to to use it
and it is it is very flexible
it can also show uh the you can query
the
the alert the number of alerts firing in
the system and when when the
installation grows
that's the sort of stuff you want on
your front page of your graffana
instance you can have
zero or five alerts or whatever
okay so
prometheus connects to an exporter and
gets
fed metrics and ingests them and these
metrics are exported by by exporters
machine metrics like like the normal
metrics like
ram and and i o and network traffic and
stuff like that
are exported by something called node
exporter which we have in ports
and it works well but on freebsc it
doesn't have a
disk utilization metrics that has thus
on linux
of course but but not on previously
which is why i started out because when
you're troubleshooting stuff on a
database server or something it's very
nice to have metrics for for disk
utilization
there's exporters for every type of
software you can almost imagine it it is
uh there's
hundreds of them uh
each is allocated a port on this list
you just go to the wiki and allocator
port and
for the gstat exporter i got port 92
something
something but but that's a good list and
you can search for freebsd on it and
find a few others that
there's a jail exporter which is very
nice that somebody made
that uses rctl to get iops and memory
use and stuff for
for jails and then exports it in a in a
way so
prometheus can ingest it so you can get
graphs to say how much
ram each jail is using and how many iops
and stuff that is very nice if you're
using jails for
yeah if you're using jails at all
okay so you know i guess you all know
g-step
it looks like this it is a top
style thing that shows
the the geom devices and the
read and write operations by default you
can show
deletes and other stuff as well um
i actually have no wait i don't because
i'm not online
okay so this is g stat and these these
are the numbers i was interested in
getting into a graph
and um uh that's why we're here today
um there's a c
flag for for g-step that makes it output
in csv mode it's called in the man page
instead of
the top style display
and unfortunately
a bit of a complaint would be that it
it it when you enable
c it also enables endless mode so it
keeps running you can't just make it
output values once and exit so that's uh
that should probably be added because
usually in
exporters when prometheus connects you
scrape the data and then you return it
but
i've had to keep it running endlessly
the g-stat and just streaming the output
from it into the
collector
also if g-stat could somehow export the
counters
it bases the the top display on
so these are you know the difference
between counters and gauges
uh and and we lose a bit of precision
because i'm reading the g-step values as
counters it shows me how much
there's an update frequency in g-step so
every five seconds or every one second
or something
and and stuff that happens in between
let's say every five seconds
is kind of lost and if you had the
counters instead prometheus would be
able to
it doesn't matter if you read every five
or
ten seconds then you would get all the
information and
i'm not a c person but looking at the
code it looks like it is counters
when it comes out of the kernel and and
somewhere it is
converted to the to the human-friendly
display that we see in z-stat
okay so with the with with g-step we
really have
everything we need with the c-mode we
have everything we need to write in a
write-in exporter um
like i said the client library
prometheus client libraries is easy to
get started with
the g-stat exporter is 240 lines
it sounds like more than this because
it's formatted
with these code beautifying tools and
they are
very generous with the new lines so
um it's on github and yeah port 9248
is uh it's a g static portal it's not a
they don't add them to services files
everywhere because they're so
dynamic and there's so many of them but
but they do have the uh
the page on their website or the wiki on
github to
to keep track of which ports are used by
what
okay so running the exporter locally
and and grabbing for
da zero and grabbing for right this is
the
output for for the g-stat exporter you
see it's just a plain text and this is
just
fetch outputting to uh to std out so
it's a it's a plain sex response and
it's just
lines of metric name and then
labels and then finally a space and then
a number
which is the actual value for that
metric with that combination of labels
for that specific time
as you can see i've stuffed all the the
info i can get from
geom what's it called geom
identifier or something there's a geom
command that can return
rpm and all these neat metrics so i can
get
yeah for example this exercise and rpm
and the serial number for the disks and
the size which is very nice because as
we will see later in grafena it uh
it makes it easy to to filter for
example and show only the nvme drives
only the spinning drives or
only the 12 terabyte drives or whatever
you need
okay so as i said it doesn't visualize
stuff but
by itself but the the uh the integration
superfan is really good
it can uh once you add the prometheus
instance as a data source in graffana
when you start typing a metric name it
autocompletes it and
it it really works very very well
and you can filter dashboard by label
values and i'll show you what i mean by
that
later but that for example means that i
can easily in graffana
just select one disk if i'm if i'm
suspecting that one disk is
foggy or select only the 5400 ipm drives
across all servers if i
should for some reason have the need for
that
i published the dashboard at at the
gravana
dashboard publishing place and
and if you don't know gravana i highly
recommend it it is hope
it is uh it's very easy to make it makes
pretty graphs for you
like you don't have to decide on colors
and stuff it uses colors that look
well together and uh and generally just
works extremely well
okay i'm gonna need to uh fix my
internet connection so
talk about yourself for 30 seconds while
i get this
[Music]
okay
just work for the love of sorry
yes i would if i could it's a long and
boring
explanation why it doesn't work but
and usually the phone just works but of
course right now it doesn't
is
yeah thanks guys but it's not gonna work
really
this is great advertisement for linux
it really isn't
i'm glad i want that this might happen
ahead of time
yes
okay so maybe we skip the live demo
since it's not working i'm sorry about
that
um
i'll talk a bit more and then try again
in a few minutes when it's had time to
recover
uh i do have some uh
some screenshots in the beginning that i
can go back to but uh
oh yeah thanks um it was a pretty quick
project i did it in a day
uh saturday in the morning investigating
how i would do it and then i wrote the
code during the day and in the evening i
did the dashboard and
then i wrote a blog post and posted it
so it was that
in the scope of the day you can you can
write an exporter for something
including
doing a nice dashboard and making
everything work
if gsat gets support for for outputting
just a line and the next hitting i'll
probably change the way it calls g-step
so it doesn't keep it running
perpetually but just
cause it when it is scraped
and maybe good airflex to
support if there's an effort
gstat can show consumers as well as
producers
in the gm stack and
and some people might need this for
reasons i can't really
the graph hana dashboard needs some fine
tuning
[Music]
and if anybody wants to oh off
if anybody want feels like helping with
that then then you're very very welcome
um i'm gonna get this one quick
final attempt
well i have it i have it open
fortunately so we can show you
some of the things i was talking about
the labels
i add to the
hey the labels i added to the metrics
can be used in graffana to make this
nice
little table in the top that shows this
is uh
in the top we have the
the uh the filters that ravana take
makes it possible to to filter by label
values so this shows
server names and this shows the
different geoms
and the different disk sizes we have
and section sizes and rpm and stuff and
this is where would for example
i didn't know we still had a 5400 rpm
drive but after i installed this
then i got a bit better overview of the
entire
and it's a it's a nice way to see for
example serial number if you know a disk
is performing poorly you can easily see
the serial number and ask your
on site hands to to fix it
another than that there's sections for
each each of the
metrics geom exports so there's a
latency graph
for read write and delete latency and
there's a bandwidth section for of
course it can't
trust me there's bandwidth graphs behind
if i was online
and there's an eye up session section
and
i'm a queue in the cube that depth this
is showing 30 days
i've had this running for a few months
since i wrote it and
one of the fun things is that if you've
if you've ran a very large set of s
pools you probably know that
the scrubbing can take almost forever
to uh to complete which means that many
uh
people with loud pools end up doing like
a nightly scrub
that just poses it runs it through the
night and poses it in the day in the
working hours
and that's a fun uh this is the pc
present and the scrubs are these uh this
is 30 days so you can see we scrub all
weekend
and then every night and then all
weekend and every night
um so it's a it's a fun pattern to
have to observe and we found we found a
bad disk in one of the servers using
this
i can't find the data now of course but
uh
it works really well to to get an
overview of the
of the disk utilization and
that's actually that's all i wanted so
so that's very nice
any questions we have plenty of time yes
uh my ocd screams at me that the media
size should be just
a number without the string yeah but
it's uh
exported directly from the uh
[Music]
the string that the geom info exports so
i could cut it off and then tell
graffana that it's a byte value and it
would
humanize it for me um you're right
that would be that would be easy uh
graffana knows
like it knows units so this this graph
i've told it that this is a number of
seconds and then
it shows auto scales the the y-axis to
show that this is uh
milliseconds of course not seconds
fortunately so and it understands like
megabytes per second and stuff like that
so
[Music]
it is very lovely to work with
yes have you had any trouble with
prometheus or graphana because you're on
previously instead of linux like things
looking for systemd
or stuff like that apart from it not
exporting disk utilization
no oh right the question was
have i had any problems running a
grafana or prometheus on freebsd
because it's previously and not linux
and no
apart from the the node exporter that's
the
thing that exports exposes system
metrics like memory and disk io and
stuff like that apart from it not
exporting disk io and not export
exporting a set of s data then
no everything works very well the ports
work perfectly and
they are updated timely and run run very
well
the latest version that the upcoming
version of node exporter does have
freebsd zfs support and
i'm very much looking forward to that
and combined with this then you can get
a great
impression of how your storage is doing
yeah yes i
have questions in a bit disjoint topics
the first one is
you were touching keywords like alerting
and federation
and this kind of stuff so my questions
about
these servers what you were scraping yes
they were only scraping endpoints
or they were scraped and processed at
the same site
or you had one central from ethio server
and then
scraping all the endpoints yes one
central server that
that connects out to you could you
configure it
tell it which targets to scrape and then
it just sucks up
all the metrics that that that are
available at that
endpoint
the delay or the latency
no i mean you would think but no it just
really works very well um it's it's a
bit of a radical
both the the pull model and the the idea
that it
like that it does describe as it
connects so if reviews doesn't connect
for a while then
there's no data collected but it really
works very very well and and turns out
that it doesn't matter too much as long
as you use counters it wouldn't matter
for g-stat
exporter because you would lose the
precision
if you reboot your previous server then
you would lose the five minutes or
whatever it takes
but if you have counters available then
uh then you don't
because it doesn't matter if if medius
is gone for a while it'll
figure out how to uh
what's the word i'm looking for
yeah exactly uh it'll it'll smooth it
out uh yeah
so and no it works very well and people
are doing some
like the big uh hosting operators um
i do have some like they have 500
prometheus servers doing
uh millions and millions of data points
per second some crazy big instances so
for my users
with 100 servers or something i know
it's a it's always nice to
to have to know that it can handle way
more than you need
but this also means that you had one
central server so you had to maintain
your alerts
on one server right so these
or the alert conditions had to be
written on one server
well the alert manager can is a separate
jail i mean it could
it could be a separate server if you
want it yeah i mean
yeah a different question yeah in
the intro of your talk you mentioned
that
you take care of this born hack camp
yes what's the topic is this
yeah it is stuff like this
it is infosec it is also hardware
open source and really broad if you uh
if you've been to the german ccc camp or
the dutch
big hacker camps it is very much
inspired by those
so it is kind of reminds a little bit of
first time except that people live in
tents and
there's not as many people of course
about 400 people i think this year and
it's slowly growing it's the fifth year
this time so
and it's an annual event and it's
getting traction it's a lovely little
event
so um
any more questions
and some yes you seem to have a good
experience with promoters
absolutely did you try
this computing stack telegraph and
i've used no not really i've
i haven't used it enough to uh to i've
not set it up i've only uh briefly been
exposed to it when somebody else had
configured it so i
i don't know enough but
you know how you can sometimes sense
that something has momentum like a
project
like every i think everywhere i look
prometheus exporters are popping up like
natively inside
whatever nginx or whatever suddenly has
a way to explore and and that tells me
that uh
you know i'm not the only one who feels
that this is the
the right approach and uh and that's
very nice because i think uh
i think we have been i've been looking
for something nice
for monitoring for years and years i've
never been really
really happy even back when nagios was
the thing to run
i've never really been very happy with
it i think everybody really
kind of loved to hate it or yeah so i am
so
so happy that finally something and it
also i mean the aesthetics are also very
important because even though
technically it's the same number as if
it's an arctic graph or a pretty graph
but it just
still makes a difference it's nicer to
work with
i have one response to that
uh so just looking at uh influx while
it's
nice to work with in at least some
aspects
uh probability use has much much more
advanced math
available like for example in influx
it's not possible in a single query to
get
uh for example you get the return codes
of http requests
in influx it's not possible to get
what proportion of requests were
say errors it's possible in graphite
it's possible in
prometheus it's not possible in influx
growth
sure any more questions
i have a quick question because i'm
rarely surrounded by a lot of freebsd
people so
i just
oh damn i went offline oh and i can't
even show it
okay well the question though the
problem is you know uh the jail exporter
i was talking about
which measure which uses rctl to export
jail metrics and then then you can do
graphs for for example memory use inside
the tail
so i i use that of course because i use
jails for all my stuff
and it's very nice to see if the disk is
being trashed
you can easily see which jail is causing
this
postgres doing an auto vacuum or what's
going on
rctl counts shared memory
twice in jails or as many times i have
what i have in this tab that i can
switch over to because i'm offline
i have two jails on this server it has a
20 128 gigabytes of ram
i have two postgres jails and rctl
tells me that one jail is using about
130 gigs and the other jail is using 80
gigs
which is about 200 gigs and there's 40
more jails on it so clearly
something is is wrong and i've been able
to track down as much as
it is i don't know what the fix is but
it's absolutely misreporting
memory use in jails and since
if i have 100 postgres workers and each
of them is using
two gigabytes of ram then and most of it
is shared
what you want rctl to export is how much
memory would be freed if i shut the gel
down
i don't care if 100 workers is using two
gigabytes you shouldn't report 200
gigabytes memory use
does anybody know is this just a bug or
is this
not possible what i'm asking for or i
mean
between jails are you even able to tell
not between jails
but between 100 postgres workers in the
same jail for example
and then each of those they have access
to the same shared memory space and it's
been counted 100 times because
there's 100 workers so it tells me that
one jail is using 140 gigs of ram on 128
gig server
which clearly is not true
i wonder how it would look like if it
was running outside of jail
if it would be reported the same way uh
it would but we can
talk about it later after i just
it's been bugging me because uh i
finally got some nice gel graphs and
the memory usage is just way way off
i was like what the hell is wrong how
can it be using 300 gigabytes of ram
when it has
128 and our ctl exports the v memory use
as well and that's
of course a high number and higher than
the it's 1.2 terabytes of memory rv
memory i think
but but the memory use should be we
agreed that it should be
however much would be freed if the jail
was shut down right
otherwise what's the point of reporting
i mean you see my you see what i mean
okay i think our ray open pr
and write to a mailing list and see if i
can uh
i think i can catch somebody's attention
with that but the other one that
the jade exporter is really awesome and
stuff like iops
and that works very well so you can see
which
jail is trashing a disk or or using a
lot of cpu
i think that's it for me we're done
with a quarter quarter of an hour to
spare so
you can use that time to for
self-reflection and the self-improvement
and thanks for having me and i hope you
enjoyed foster and my talk and
yeah thank you