thank you
thank you guys for having me i hope you
guys are having a good foster
um my name is mohammed osama and i'll be
presenting gun rock which is our graph
processing library
built on gpus using cuda
i'm a phd student at university of
california
working with professor john owens and i
flew
more than i think 14 hours to give this
talk
so let's hope it goes all uh so this is
a link to the talk if
you if you guys are interested in
downloading it and following along i'll
give you a second to like take a picture
or something
all right so just a second
um so why use gpus for graph processing
um i didn't feel the need to actually
sort of
uh give a motivation of why graphs are
important because obviously you guys are
in this dev room
so maybe you care about graphs but
why how can you use gpus to sort of do
graph processing better or faster
and how did we manage to do it well so
graphs are everywhere gpus are nowadays
everywhere as well your phones your
laptops everything now has a gpu in it
graphs require fast processing it its
need within the memory and the compute
that you'd require
to do some graph analytics gpus sort of
give that powerful
memory bandwidth and computation
together so it goes
really well hand in hand graphs are
becoming very very large
there's billions and billions of edges
and now in graphs nowadays within
facebook and twitter
um and yeah there's there's a need to
process a really really really large
data sets
gpus however are not good at that we
have a very limited amount of memory
32 gigabyte i think is the most in an
nvidia
v100 um and i'll talk about how we
handle some of that some of those issues
um there's some irregular
data access patterns within graphs which
makes load balancing quite
hard and a very really difficult problem
to solve
so writing high performance graph
analytics and graph algorithms
uh really require you to get load
balancing right
and that's really hard to do on gpus
using cuda
so we show um a way to solve that as
well
so what is gun rock a gun rock is a gpu
based
graph processing library like i already
said which aims for performance
state you can write state-of-the-art
graph algorithms using our library
it also aims for generality so it covers
a broad range of
graph algorithms and i'll give you a
list of algorithms that we have already
implemented and
ways that you can implement your own
graph algorithm
so problems that you're interested in so
programmability which is really cool
because you can implement your own graph
algorithms and then extend it to
go from a single gpu to a multi gpu
environment pretty easily using gunrock
scalability so once again one of the
problems was the how much memory you
have available within
a gpu is super limited but the graphs
are really large so there has to be a
way
to sort of scale that and still see the
performance that you'd need from a gpu
to sort of start off where can you find
gun rock gun rock is hosted on github
for i think over three years now
it's an open source project has a lot of
commits a lot of contributors
and really active and a lot of graduate
students that work on it too
so this is the link right here to the
gun rocks website where we have our docs
and link to the github page and all that
stuff
uh some of the open source sort of
project workflow stuff
we managed two branches on the main
repository the master branch and the dev
branch
master branch is where all the releases
happen the dev branch
is where we push all the our development
work a lot of it is done within forks of
individual people
individual graduate students and then it
eventually gets merged into dev branch
and which eventually sort of trickles up
to
the to a release in in a master branch
it's hosted using apache 2.0 license
we also provide code coverage using code
cover i o
central integration using jenkins
and lots of documentation using a slate
documentation
for api and oxygen also for api and some
of the
performance results and stuff are hosted
on slate so you can check that out as
well
um we have unit testing using google
test which is really cool
um and if you are interested in
or you have any questions please give
please
post a github issue or if you want to
contribute
create a pull request there's someone
there there will be someone that will
review it or give you
feedback on it and will be able to
respond really quickly on that on that
as well using github
we prefer github over emails um
so everything related to gun rock is
open source and online
there's no hidden development at all
even our roadmap is online so you can go
and check that out if you're interested
in seeing
what kind of research problems that
we're trying to solve in future
or working on right now or the kind of
graph algorithms that we aim to write
and some of the interesting hive stuff
as well is um
all on there um
yeah so i talked about a lot of
contributors bunch of commits
um and uh and
gun rock is also part of the nvidia gpu
accelerated libraries
um and also it's being worked into being
integrated into the nvidia rapids
framework which is a python framework
that allows you to do
uh data science and stuff so under uh
underneath the hood it will use gun rock
and some other graph frameworks provided
by nvidia
so let's actually see how everything
works um
i i heard some people hint towards sort
of different graphics
programming models there exist and graph
abstractions that you can use
uh gunrock relies on the data centric
abstraction so vertex centric
abstraction is another name for it
and it uses both synchronous programming
models so what is
what does those two words actually mean
um so when i say data centric we have
notion of a frontier where a frontier is
just a group of vertices
or edges so if you have your entire
graph you just create
a frontier using a subset of those nodes
or maybe an entire graph gets put into a
frontier
and then you process your whatever
algorithm you're trying to write on this
frontier you don't have the notion of
the entire graph anymore so everything
works on a on a frontier moving forward
you um have parallel operators this is
what you use to actually do
work on that frontier um we have some of
our parallel operators but you're free
to write your own
as well these are really high-performant
cuda implementations this is where all
the engineering goes into
so some of the examples i have on the
left side are advanced
filter for intersection neighborhood use
and a lot more
so an example would be advanced where
advance will take a frontier an
input frontier and then it will generate
new frontier by visiting all the
neighbors
so in the in the action of visiting the
uh
the neighbors you have access to all of
the neighbors
off the of a given node or something and
then you can perform
all sorts of different operations on
that node and i'll give an example a
concrete example of where advance is
used
filter as the name suggests it just
filters stuff out so you have an
input frontier and you use some
condition to filter some vertices out
and you have a resulting frontier that's
smaller than maybe
the input frontier that you put in and a
lot for a lot of
documentation is available for available
for all the other
operators that there are and there's
some that i don't mention here as well
so what is the bulk synchronous
programming side of things
um so the operators in themselves are
highly parallel and they run on gpu
and how you write algorithms is you
couple these
operators together in sort of a bulk
synchronous way so this is one operator
you might have
another one after that another one after
that and so on and then you run this
in this in a serial loop so you perform
this in a serial loop so after
every operation operator runs there's a
synchronization call
and that synchronize synchronizes the
entire data flow and sort of
makes that knowledge available to every
uh processing unit
or whatever you want to call a cuda core
too
and then all of this runs in a serial
loop until your algorithm converges
so these are the kind of algorithms that
we currently support there's
some that are being worked on and um
so we have some of the traditional
algorithms like connected component
breadth breadth first search page rank
is somewhere in there too
ssp is there to single source shortest
path and there
then there we also have some more
complicated
um applications which require other
algorithms to work so
graph trend filtering is one of them
which requires max flow as is one of its
components to really perform the whole
application
um another one is shared nearest
neighbor which is a clustering algorithm
that requires k nearest neighbors
which is somewhere in here for it to
work
so there's some really concrete real
world examples
and some textbook algorithms that you
can use to couple those together
or you can couple different operators to
get together to write your own graph
algorithm
all working on in parallel on the gpu
um i also have an example application
i tried to sort of simplify this code as
much as i could
but i'll go and quickly explain what
each of those line means
so the first step to implement any
algorithm in gun rock will be to
actually implement the
lambdas of the lambda functions of the
uh operator that that you're going to
write so what lambdas
see these are c plus plus lambdas the
entire library is written in c
plus plus uh and cuda so what lambdas
allow you to do
is have the generality of like doing
anything within a function so it's
basically a user defined function
say you wanted to do a traditional
advanced operator in gun rock
but you also wanted to attach some sort
of notion to it
some sort of um some sort of like
computation attached to it uh in this
example in a single source shortest path
the algorithm is quite simple you have a
single source and you want to find
the shortest path to all the other nodes
in the graph so you cue a frontier with
that single node
and then you basically do in advance so
that's why you need the advanced
operator you visit its neighbors and
then you visit the neighbors neighbors
and you build this frontier of neighbors
and neighbors and neighbors
over multiple iterations and then you
calculate
the shortest distance to that node given
a source node so you take the distance
of the source node that's the first line
so
auto distance equals distance of the
vertex id the work the source that
you're working on
plus the weight of the edge id so the
weight on the edge uh going to a
neighbor or uh yeah going to a neighbor
um
and then you find the minimum between
that and the existing distance that was
in the source node and if it is the
minimum the predecessor is set
to the neighbor node and you move on if
a shortest distance is found you'll need
some way of removing that vertex
from the frontier otherwise the
algorithm won't terminate because the
frontier is
is completely full and you keep doing it
so it will be an infinite loop
so you need some way of removing nodes
that are already
that already found their shortest
neighbors so that's what a filter lambda
does
it's basically saying if it's still
valid um
keep keep it in the frontier otherwise
remove it remove it from the frontier
so lambdas are are great abstraction to
basically
allow users to write their own
computation within this
and you can imagine using the same
operators with different lambdas
to implement a different algorithm
entirely one of the recent ones that i
did was graph coloring
where i used uh four lambda or you can
even use a filter for that
and graph coloring requires is basic
is basically a problem where you want to
color
different nodes with different colors if
they share an
edge um and you can write that all
within
a filter operator but with a different
lambda and all of those examples are
online for you to see
so once you've written the lambdas down
once you have actually expressed your
algorithm
you launch it and this is just
a while loop while the frontier is not
empty keep running
keep running the advance operator with
the advanced
operator uh lambda and the filter
operator lambda so you provide the
lambdas and you keep running it
until the algorithm converges until the
printer filter
frontier is empty um
and that's basically all i have um these
are
some of the uh grants that we have that
allow us to do this amazing research and
i thank you guys for listening
um left a few a lot of time for
questions i think
okay thanks
yeah so um on the web so
uh the question was do we have any
benchmark where we compare our results
to
other stuff that's being done um yes
they we have online we have a
web page of evaluation where we compare
against different graph frameworks and
uh on some of the famous data sets and
one of the recent
uh performance evaluation that i've
performed run
runs over 74 different data sets which
includes
anywhere from like the twitter data sets
social networks road networks
uh some of the structured data sets the
rgd the randomly generated graphs
so anything you can imagine in sort of
the graph analytics world we have
a data set for that and a test for that
yeah
yeah yes how do you know the graph
so that's a good question so we uh use
okay uh how do we load the graph so
we have we take matrix market format as
an input
um and then we have underlying graph
representations which
are the common ones like csr compressed
sparse row
csc which is compressed parse column
coordinate format
c-o-o um and we also have a graph
representation which you can plug your
own graph representation in
and then define that under our graph
data struct
and we'll be good to use that going
forward yeah so currently we support
three
and there's some work being done by
rapids folk at nvidia to support
uh the i think uh the apache arrow
format within
uh gun rock and within their framework
as well
so the frontier itself when it's built
it's exact
so you know what you put into the
frontier to start off with
but when you do operations like advance
there's
a policies that lets you determine is it
uh
is it an approximate deduplication or a
complete
deduplication where you'd remove any
duplicate neighbors that you found in
parallel
or you might want to keep them for
certain algorithms where it doesn't
matter
which will perform much faster because
you don't have to do a synchronization
and a deduplication of some sort uh so
there's support for both
so you can do approximate frontier
handling or something or you could go
aggressive and
do exact yes have you found any
algorithm any functions for which
the gpu is slower than the cpu uh one of
the ones is actually max flow
so graph trend filtering is uses max
flow and max flow we found that there's
a cpu algorithm that
that just maps so much better and it's
not transferable to a gpu environment
it's not parallelizable
so the ones we the one we use i think
it's the admins carp or
push relabel max flow and
it just doesn't do as well as we'd want
it to be but there's
a student working on some research and
developing a maxwell algorithm for that
but that's one example that comes to
mind
so yes
because it's like you have to spend you
have to
right so the question is about low
memory uh availability within
gpus and you obviously need like a
high-end v100 to get the maximum 32 gigs
so what we also have is support for
unified
virtual memory which is a cuda uvm
driver that allows you to manage
memory through cpu by page faulting
so your graph will essentially you load
as much as you can
on the gpu and the rest of it is page
faulted as needed
but you can imagine that will have a
huge performance penalty
depending on how many page faults there
are and how you're doing them
um there's also a multi-gpu environment
so you could buy maybe cheap cards
and use the multi-gpu aspect of gun rock
which is sort of hidden away from the
user which allows you to
do the same algorithm in a multi-gp
environment with now more
more memory available but obviously
you'll have to spend money on buying
more gps for that
i have a question yes you showed the
sssp example
um and you use these uh the values the
input values for the lambda to store the
result distances and the weights
yes what are the constraints on those
data structures can i
basically pick a generic value or is it
so that can be anything that can be
literally anything so c
plus plus lambda allows you to capture
any of the variables that you'd like
uh so that those square brackets are the
actual capture
where you can capture the data you're
working with so if it's an array it can
be a float or
double or int or whatever and it's
all the entire gunrock library is
templated so it supports
any of the data types that you'd like or
you'd want to do
um the i forgot to mention the sort of
parentheses there with the dot
dot it's uh i sort of simplified that
for the slide but
it's the signature of the lambda that
stays the same no matter what
uh so it's basically copy pasted from
the api which provides you
access to the vertex id and the edge id
because that's how you get those
yeah yes any more questions
what about graphic bearings i saw that
you have glass
uh so i'm not the person that's working
on graph embeddings
but you can have any sort of
data struct or struct attached to node
labels or edge labels and then you pass
it in in the same way and capture it
within the lambda
and you should be able to uh
you should be able to work on it that's
my 20 minutes okay let's
thank the speaker
you