okay
sorry for the uh technical hitch there
um
right i'm uh i was supposed to be doing
this talk with uh
a colleague who works with g on jfr um
unfortunately he wasn't able to come so
i'm going to cover the
material he's provided for the talk this
is a talk about
our attempts to add some new
functionality to
growl vm so
what i'll do is i'll start by providing
some background what grall is just to
give an overview of how it works and
the the the what we're actually trying
to achieve talk about the things we
wanted to do
um explain how that went some of the
problems that we had
uh what we actually succeeded in doing
some of the things we learned from the
process
and i suspect we probably won't have
time for questions but i'd be happy to
talk
with them outside so um
growl is not just one thing it's
actually a whole series of components
all written in java
at the core of that is a compiler which
is used for various different purposes
it can function as a jit compiler as an
ahead of time compiler
there's an interpreter framework for
called truffle which can be used to
provide support for a whole lot of
interpreted languages that these
because the compiler can then optimize
by compiling
there's a native image generator that
can take a java
program and finds a closed world of all
the code that's uh
called the program and will generate a
small executable from that code
that can run independent from open jdk
doesn't need a jvm
because it's got its own little jvm
inside there called substrate
which replicates all the functionality
you need from open jdk to run a small
native java image as a self-contained
binary you can also generate shared
libraries with it as well
it's just a binary with multiple entry
points essentially
so what grail looks like at the core of
it all is this compiler
and you can use it at open jdk as a jit
compiler so
if you were to plug it in by the jvmci
compiler plugin interface
uh um openjdk will create some compiler
threads and start handing methods to it
to compile and get compiled code
back and that will be used as the
compiled code from jdk
in order to do that it has a front end
which passes by code and generates a
graph structure
there's a the usual high middle and low
tiers that massage that graph
into a shape that you can spit code out
and a back end that generates code
buffers and there they are you've got
compiled methods
a slightly different configuration of
the compiler most specifically with a
very different backend for linking in a
different way
can be used in in the ahead of time
compilation for java and open jdk
and that can be used to populate the
class data sharing segment
application class data sharing with
pre-defined methods so we need bootstrap
you've already got compiled code for
java runtime methods or application
methods
so the same compiler has been repurposed
by reconfiguring
all the the the the components in the
compiler
another use for it from truffle um
truffle allows you to build interpreters
that parse a language and there's
various truffle language implementations
and execute by walking the abstract
syntax tree for the
parsed language program the uh
truffle interpreter framework knows how
to take a node in that graph
that syntax tree and maybe some of its
sub nodes
push the graph straight into the
compiler bypassing any byte code
parsing front end because you've already
got um you've got a different
representation of the program
it pushes it through the the stages in
the compiler
out pops code at the back end and you
can install that as an execute method
for the
interpreted language to call directly
rather than interpreting the graph
running on open jdk you can also use it
in native images
where you've compiled things the native
compiler and the grail compiler can run
inside a self-contained binary
as part of a program running uh some
truffle language
the native image generator itself makes
two uses of
the compiler you start from a method
in a particular class or a set of entry
methods for a library
and it takes that uh method and the
class is associated with with jvmci
descriptions of them
eats the bytecode and instead of
compiling it out of machine code in the
first pass it
analyzes the method and at the bottom of
the transformation stage in the graph
processing
comes um and a transform method and a
list of methods that
and types that that method refers to
they're put into a pool into a universe
which built is built up recursively
processed
finding all the references from classes
to other classes methods to other
methods
until you build up a closed world of all
the code that can be reached from the
initial entry points
you can then take all the type
information you've derived and the
methods that you've found and compile
them
to a completely self-contained
executable image
that has a closed world model you found
all the code you could reach
from that entry point for that library
or that application
it's not quite as simple as that because
this closed world executable image
is at some point when you call into the
jdk runtime
methods is going to expect to call out
and have a jvm under there
under normal operation have opened jdk
and of course this program has to run
its own without open jk
and it can't reuse all the jvm
functionality from jdk because that
expects to do class loading
and keep track of classes and it's all
meant to be compiled into the image
self-contained
so what this translation process that
the first stage does is it also
substitutes
invocations of jdk runtime code at
certain cut points
and side steps them into substrate which
provides an equivalent thing
that will do the same sort of job as
open jdk in this delivered image with
limited shared library
um it used to be that all the
functionality that was provided to
emulate open the opengdk vm
was implemented as java code that became
a bit of a burden when they realized
they would have to keep
porting that for 11 and all the later
releases so from a lot of the native
code that's implemented c
code in native libraries like the zip
library
the libnet code that's been put in and
linked underneath the substrate image
and it's used directly to avoid having
to maintain so much
java code but substrate obviously has to
emulate some of the things that normally
go on inside
the vm code and provide an alternative
because you've got a different model for
execution
so there's this set of things that were
the term
started arriving a few years back and we
were looking at this about two and a
half years ago and thought well
the arm port isn't really properly
supported it's the sort of second-class
citizen so our first idea was
we'd do some work to help make the arm
back end
be on a par with x86 and our goal there
was architecture parity
more recently we've been interested in
the native image generation because of
our middleware product caucus
so we looked at adding jfr support um
into the substrate and vm
and into the app the native application
all the monitoring capabilities you have
open jdk
are not currently present in these
native generated images
and really for usability users are going
to need to understand what's going on
in the application and also have some
way of identifying things when it goes
wrong
so jfr was what we decided we want to
port oracle already have plans to have
that in their enterprise edition of
grail we wanted to add it as a community
feature
and that's really critical we think for
usability
for the community edition the open
source edition um
with uh debug info for for debuggers
this is a different story
um a program that runs on opengdk if you
get a native
compil a native image compiled version
of it and in any way
diverges from open jdk behavior that'll
be because the compiler has compiled
code into this heavily optimized
uh executable program that is doing the
wrong thing
so you've got to be able to work what
happens if everything like that should
arise
so we've wanted to put debug info in
that would allow you to take the
executable image
and refer back execution the
instructions there to the original java
source code
in a debugger like gdb or in visual
studio
so you could actually deal with that
problem should it ever arise and
understand what's gone wrong
and then go and fix growl probably so
this is more a supportability goal
so um for the uh the answer 64 code what
we wanted to do was just add very basic
stuff two and a half years ago there was
very minimal things like um
addressing there were no displacements
embedded in in addressing it was they're
actually
loaded as independent values into
registers but there's no pre-fetching
things like merging an abstract shift
and a mask operation and using one of
the bit
bit fetch instructions in arm that we
wanted optimizations like that
and the most important was using load
acquire store release for volatile
operations rather than having memory
barriers for efficiency
so there was a lot of stuff that really
just wasn't there we needed to put in
um with jfr we really just wanted to get
jrfr working so we wanted this a lower
overhead profiling mechanic method uh
mechanism because it's really critical
um we needed to have um as many of the
vm events we wanted the equivalent sorts
of things that made sense
to come out of the substrate vm so you
can see what the virtual machine and the
native runtime code is doing
we'd also want to have support for user
events um
and we'd also like if there's something
about the way substrate works there
doesn't
isn't really a correlative open jdk we
were thinking of adding new events for
that
we mostly just wanted to reuse the
existing code as much as possible so
we'd have to reinvent the wheel
the debug support we had a fairly simple
set of capabilities we thought would be
enough to debug problems
uh breakpoints by by method name
breakpoints by file and line number
the ability to step when you reach a
breakpoint line by line
stepping into a rover functions back
traces
we'd like to print objects field by
field if we can and we'd like to use
path expressions to
the reference through objects and pick
values out using a
as a field axis so on so that's the sort
of capability we really wanted to add
um so what happened
what were the things we encountered we
did that well um
with the arm code two and a half years
ago we started this it's actually
still ongoing we've been slowly adding
things we've met in real problems
because of the complexity of the
compiler
um it was very difficult to get things
into the code base
but actually there were problems with
the development process and where that
was organized
and there was also problems with our
understanding of where grahl was going
what the
the road map was for growl um
i'll talk quite a bit about the capacity
because this is really quite important
any compiler is going to be complex
you've got
usually a high middle and low tier of
transformation stages in
in a graph model and um
so there's a whole load of different uh
uh uh operations happen in in various
stages some of them are itchative some
of them are nested
understanding what happens with where
the flow of controllers is really quite
difficult thing to do
and you're massaging a graph and
transforming its shape all the time
so um nodes come and go so aligning the
life cycles of the graph
and the life cycles of the phases is
always a problem when you have a very
deep node hierarchy you may have a phase
that operates on a generic node type
but which actual types of node does it
really operate on
same views a lot of interfaces so these
are generic problems but the
the problems that are the problems that
growl faces but i think it's
particularly difficult with growl
because of questions of scale
but there's also the configurability
issue
growl is used by many clients for many
different purposes
so all those phases that apply in each
suite and all the different back ends
are different for different uses and
that makes it
that means there's a lot of possible
combinations of choices of what might be
going on in the gra
in the graph transformation process
particularly they also use a plug-in
model which allows you to take a
particular
method operation or a family of method
operations or a particular
code operation and to have some special
handy viral plug-in
and each each uh different client plugs
in different
phases to these different operations
there's another indirection makers of
where things happen
annotations are used on the code to
guide these operations to guide
how the phases operate how the plugins
operate so you need to understand how
the
annotations actually side affect this
and what makes it really complicated is
that
some of the annotations are defined in
substrate classes and they affect the
way that jdk classes are modified and
compiled
there's an indirect mechanism so you can
see there's lots of hooks and lots of
indirections that
make the complexity of this really
really difficult to follow
and a lot of the configuration is done
with a layered hierarchical
uh overriding model so you have a a
basic
uh suite provider that provides the
phases you have a hotspot
for suite provider and then you have an
aot hotspot suite provider so there are
these
not everything's in one place it's
distributed so it's really really very
complex
some of the numbers involved there are
150 subclasses of class phase this is a
thing that does a single graph
transformation
there are 200 different types of graph
node in in the code base
access which is an interface that's used
to encapsulate all the memory nodes has
21 different types of read or write
nodes
or in one case a read write node um the
graph builder plug-in that does special
case side effecting for particular
transformations
200 different uh graph builder plugins
nine different types of plugins doing
different types of transformations
and there are 200 annotations that
direct these operations these
transformation operations in different
different paths and of course the other
problem we had was when when we started
this
the arm port was relatively new so there
were problems with the code and the
shifting code base
um uh the arm64 code was the least
stable part of the compiler
but actually there were problems with
some of the generic code so when we
tried to
fix what we thought were back-end
problems in the r64 port and improve
code quality we actually ran up against
things that were problems in generic
code that didn't quite do what was
needed so
there were generic fixes needed we
weren't in a position to do that
um and actually um that that generic
code was also still in flux a bit at
that point it's got better synths and
we've managed to make some of the
generic changes
but um it really meant that we had to
either rework things or withdraw some of
things because they were just too
fragile
but the really biggest problem was the
development process
um the growl engineers that stage were
working on their own on their own repo
with their own management system and
they put up a github repo with pr's for
us to try and push things in
but they were really focused somewhere
else and they weren't ready to be
receiving things from us they weren't
even really looking at what we were
doing because they were actually looking
internally to their own group so getting
them to actually be prepared and
understand the implications of trying to
build a community and to work with that
was actually quite a long
a long slow process um it it didn't help
also that the final testing stage this
is an old story of over jdk was done
behind the scenes
in oracle and so when we put changes in
did get them through
we sometimes get a cryptic message
something had gone wrong but we couldn't
see what had gone wrong
because we couldn't see the tests and we
couldn't see what changes oracle putting
into the
uh into the code base it might have
broken our tests until they eventually
came forward
into their shadow reaper we could see so
it was really done at a distance it was
quite hard
sorry did i just yeah um the other the
other problem was that um
where what this product was and where it
was going was quite difficult for us to
see growler's got a very long history
relates back to maxine
i think before that jikes this idea of
java and java and
all the sort of generalizations that
graham was doing all these capable
capabilities
was think we gradually began to
understand it wasn't just a jit compiler
and an aot compiler
it was actually not just an interpreter
framework it had all these other uses as
well
and um part of that was us not really
knowing enough about it and not reading
the right things we just went in to do a
job and fix some code
part of it i think was that the the map
that oracle labs had for the product was
not clear anyway they had different
ideas about what they would do with
growl
what would be the key thing that would
be his key value proposition and so on
so there was it wasn't all our fault but
it was uh that was in
to a great degree our problem but there
was no public road map it wasn't really
because it was a
a private project that was trying to
become an open source project and none
of the things were in place there
um with jfo our support there were josh
had real problems understanding he had
to go through much the same learning
process i had with a compiler with
substrate vm
understand some of the limits of how it
operates um
he was trying to link in jfr code
there's native code and there's real
issues with linking things in
this substitution mechanic replaces
things meant you could think this thing
was going to happen because that's the
way it works in the
in the jdk runtime but actually it's
different in substrate
and just putting the whole thing
together required a lot of understanding
and of course be
since it was more new than to compile
even though we did this more recently
it was still a bit of a moving target
one of the things that you have to
really deal with is the fact that
um you can't use reflection and you
can't load close
load classes dynamically so you've got
to make sure that any class you want the
image
is notified to the growl um code
analysis the points to analysis
so that it will get linked in and
compiled in ahead ahead of time
so you've got to actually go about
getting code that uses relies on these
features to work in a different way
and you have to understand how to do
that and similarly jay and i you can't
just load a library and have native
methods
there's a registration mechanism for
registering uh foreign code
um that was actually quite um tricky to
do
um and this actually changed part way
through as
i said all the java code was replaced
with callouts to the java libraries
so lib libnet lib zip and so on the one
library that wasn't included was lib jvm
and of course the jfr code that we
wanted to use
is in lib jvm so josh is still working
on getting that
factored out and actually linking that
as as a separate static library
um and that means the other
authenticator would have been rewriting
it all in java and that's really not an
interactive proposition
so that's been the biggest stumbling
block that hasn't resolved yet
um as i said if you're if you you're
looking at the way that the um the
jdk runtime code works josh was looking
at system load library trying to get a
library loaded
to get some foreign code in and system
load library never got called because
they'd cut above that point
so he spent a long time trying to work
out why his code wasn't being run
and eventually found this out um
the um there's another thing that that
substrate does for optimization you can
generate in the native image that you
produce
you can populate pre-populated heap with
static
class field data including objects that
are computed at build time
or else you can run class initializers
at runtime
now you've got to get those two things
consistent across all the classes that
might be side affected by
computing and evaluate something at the
bill in the build time context versus
what you might
generate if you compute things in the
runtime context you get those wrong you
get these really subtle bugs so that was
another thing that was really hard
to decide what should be initialized at
build time what should be initialized at
runtime and whether any existing
decisions that were made about that
might snooker you so josh spent a lot of
time working through that
so he's had a really difficult time of
it actually um
and again this code was in flux there
were things changing but particularly
the library the way that the jni and the
library stuff was changed really
meant you had to redo a whole lot of
work the debuggings
work is something i've done much more
recently than josh and it's been
probably the easiest thing but i think
by this stage we understand a lot more
um it's actually also a relatively
self-contained thing which is
if you've got code in your code base or
types in your your type base for this
analysis universe
how do you tell a debugger about it so
um
that one of the problems we had was to
put this in a way that doesn't upset the
upstream implementation that already
exists
so that's one of the constraints we're
going to have to go through in the
review process
the biggest technical challenge is
making sure that the the stuff that
writes the object file doesn't have to
know about
all the other uh types that the in in in
the compiler and the heap management
code and so on
so that there's only one one sort of
constraint and that just was defining
single interfaces to allow these things
to happen but that was
decoupled fairly easily um i haven't
looked yet at making this a
an optional feature using all the sort
of mechanisms grail uses for
enabling features i'm assuming that's
going to come out of the review process
i hope so
but it's been pretty successful so with
the jit we did get some very basic
things in about two years ago
we had another little round about 18
months ago and got a little bit more in
in the last year uh roland westerlin has
managed to make some generic changes
with the grail compiler
team and actually um arm have also
contributed some of the
instruction reduction optimizations
quite a lot of stuff there so
we have had quite a lot of success
eventually it just took several goes to
get there
josh is still really struggling getting
a working prototype
in a native image he's got the event
stuff worked out he understands what he
needs to do
we can run that in fullback mode when it
runs on opportunity and that we know
it's going to work but he's still going
to deal with the library linkage problem
so
we'll probably be a few more weeks
before we get anywhere having something
that's a working prototype
that we can then polish up and submit so
that's still a work in progress there
unfortunately
the debug stuff i actually um two weeks
ago submitted a
a pull request with the first three
features
it so we now have for linux and gdb we
have
working break points working um line
stepping and working back traces
and the type stuff is the next thing i'm
going to add in that's just gone in for
review
and um uh we've had i got just two days
ago
um a nice big set of review comments
from paul burger which is really good so
oracle were really helpful with this
they um they actually gave us a whole
lot of hints and
some which i'd already found which i
haven't when we we raised this as an
issue
and they've actually they've actually
been very cooperative about getting this
into the product so that's been really
quite heartening and i think this will
probably go in in the next two or three
weeks i'll have the core
debug functionality and then i'll work
on round two next
um the process has got better the oracle
engineers
and in labs are much more aware of our
existence i mean we've been bombarding
them in a way with lots pull requests
not just us
but the caucus team and many other users
of growl but a lot of them have risen to
that and started working with the
community more um
they're still working on their own repo
that's the problem but they are more
aware and they're more responsive
they've always been helpful it's just
the time this response has been
the biggest problem they're now much
quicker and we know who people are and
that really helps
and they know who we are as well we had
a committers workshop we met them
we made some good contacts so that's
really helped in terms of us actually uh
just getting things to happen because it
just makes a difference if you've
met face to face and you know people
it's just a fact of the world
um the planning process we understand a
lot more where growlers come from and
that was particularly helped by think
talking to the growl developers and they
they also we also have more idea of
where the products going and how we can
now fit our work in
um and the committee's workshop was
actually very helpful in getting all
that to happen
and we've got a we've got an agreement
that the open jdk team
and our middleware team who are working
on caucus will regularly review and some
of the other
people contributing outside of red hat
as well will regularly review things of
the growl team we're trying to just
improve the process
and and and make sure we plan things
we've been actually given
ownership of the issues for some of the
compiler issues and
for the debug info and i'm assuming that
in the longer term we'll get that with
the jfr
issue as well so we now actually have
responsible for the ability to negotiate
all that with the community
and seeing it through your view so
there's been a certain devolution of
ownership and responsibility as well
which i see is one of the most positive
things that's happened just in the last
last week that happened so i think
hopefully
just to wrap up um we had a lot of
problems
there are still some structural problems
we've learned a lot by doing all this
and
we've also i think we've helped educate
the oracle lab stream about how to work
with the community and how to build up a
community and benefit from having
community input
um the project is now i think
stabilizing a lot more it's
oracle are clear where they're going or
the labs are clear where they're going
with this
and i think we know where we need to go
with it to to keep the
functionality we need in the community
and so i'm hoping that this is going to
be an up and up
rather than um something that gets
stymied or stagnated here so i'm
quite optimistic about this at the
moment so
how's that doing time for questions no
not really all right well i'll take them
offline
i'm sure andrew would be happy to answer
any and all of your questions
on the corridor track
[Applause]