are more
coming from the performance side and now
we have a developer coming into
performance so that's it's super
interesting i think and she will talk
about fonts
yeah so go away
carry away i'm sorry you want me to go
away
no go ahead i'm sorry
[Applause]
hello everyone how are you doing are you
excited to be here i'm excited to talk
to you about fonts
my name is sia caramelagos it's a very
long greek name actually that's not even
all of my name but um
i am a web developer and performance
engineer i
like front end i end up still having to
do full stack sadly but
um it's all right i live in new orleans
this is me at mardi gras so
but that's enough about me you're not
here for me i'm also a
google developer expert in web
technologies and i come more from the
industry side
so i um i
teach at conferences i teach workshops
on performance but i also actually build
web applications and web really is my
bread and butter
these are the slides um at bitly font
dash perf lower case
you can find these slides so you don't
have to scramble to copy anything down
or take screenshots they are deployed in
the web so all these links are clickable
um yeah you ready to get started
so i want to pull the audience really
quick um
how many of you are super passionate
about web performance and you're like a
wonk you're like really into like this
the weeds and the tech
there's a lot of you here um how many of
you
are you think performance is great and
you love it
um but you're you know a developer and
you're still learning and you're in that
process
yay there's lots of you and um
how many of you are curious but not yet
convinced that performance is important
okay and then the rest of you
why are you here
[Laughter]
but it's good to know i like to know my
audience because i'm going to adjust
this a little bit
um i don't think we need this section
because i think most of you care about
performance
so we're just going to jump right in but
what about typography because i'm
talking about fonts here so i'm just
going to take a
super quick side thing and talk about
typography
so typography is what language looks
like
it communicates content is king like the
words are king
but typography still makes a difference
and if you don't understand that let's
look at these few slides
so think to yourself what does this
evoke in you
i'm going to go back and forth that's
just one word hello
oops wrong way
versus this what are these do these
things evoke different feelings
in you maybe this one's like
it's more out there it's friendlier it's
open it's trustworthy as a slab font
the next one is maybe a little quieter
but it's also all cats so it's a little
confusing is it yelling at me but it's
italicized so
um i know most of you are not americans
um
but these fonts this is all the same
word right new york
new york new york i feel like i should
have started singing the song
but um but each of these evokes a
different feeling in me
because i'm also it's like brand
recognition so it's like
associated with the publications that
they are from or the sports teams they
are used for
so typography is still important
but what like when we talk about fonts
in action
in the web and typography what annoys
you i like to be interactive so i want
you to shout things at me
what is something that annoys you about
fonts and performance in the web
they are slow when they're slow right
what else
special characters yes
and like what else about swapping fonts
there's something that really annoys me
what oh the flash but also like
especially when it like
moves everything and you're like oh my
god i was halfway down this article and
i have no idea where i am anymore right
like that's annoying
so i'm a web developer but i'm also very
concerned about user experience which is
why
i love performance because i want the
users to be happy when they visit a page
and not feel like
it's annoying so let's jump right into
case studies
first i'm going to talk about web fonts
so like google fonts how many of you use
google fonts or something similar yeah
we all love them yay
um so web fonts um
they're hosted on fast and reliable cdns
they also have optimized variants i
don't know if you know this but for
example with google fonts i think open
sounds has at least 30 something
different variants
that optimize based on um a user's
browser
so because i don't know if you know but
this is the joy of web development
browser differences right
so like safari is not going to render
fonts in the same way that
chrome does so this can be a little
annoying so it's nice when you use these
cdn's because they can you know
they can actually serve a more optimized
font for that user's browser
this this should be an air quote
opportunity for shared caching
we'll get back to that in a little bit
but we now have control over um foot and
fight a flash of unstylotex and flash of
invisible text and we'll talk about that
a little later
what are the downsides there's a minimum
of two separate requests
i'll talk about why we're going to jump
right into that
you can't use resource hints if you
don't know what those are it's all right
i'll tell you what they are
and it can't take advantage of h2
multiplexing
if the server can even prioritize it
right and luckily right after my talk
robin's going to dive deep into a lot of
h2 issues and other things
so i know the font's a little small on
this our screen's a little small
but this is a network profile i'm
assuming most of you have seen a network
profile
and if not you know it's okay we'll
learn here um
so what's in this first line what's the
first line always anyways
what what file is that it's like the
page right
um the second file uh you can't read it
i'll just read it to you it says
style.css
right so what do you think that is
stylesheet yeah i know it's a trick
question
not um the third line
it says fonts.googleapis.com
css what is that
it's that call it's that it's what you
copy paste from google fonts
into either the head or into your style
sheet right
but what kind of file is that
it's a css file right it's not the
actual font
the css file does have you ever opened
it and looked at it it does all the font
face decorations
and then after that it calls out to
fetch the fonts
um so what do you think those last two
lines are
the fonts does this look efficient to
you
what's going on here why what does
anyone notice like a big glaring
issue of um what's going on here and
why i might have made this slower than
it needs to be
so we have remember index the css my
font css
and then the fonts that's the order so
what's going on there
yeah sorry sorry camera
what's why is this starting here after
the css
because i called it from my css have you
ever actually i'm going to break all
these rules
about the video sorry um
i am calling the font from your style
sheet because you know it gives you
those two options
um sometimes it's easier to do this like
maybe you're working with a framework or
a tool and it's easier to drop your font
call in your css
but you're paying a performance price
so what's one way we can fix that what's
one way that we can
make it start loading right away
put it in the head of the html um
so when we put it in the head of the
html this is what happens so we've
we scooched it over some we don't have
to wait for the the css to be
downloaded and the csm css some created
and um then call our
finally our css for our fonts we can put
it in the head and it will start
downloading that font css style sheet
right away
but what but there's more things we can
do here to make this faster right
what do you notice about you can't read
this but
it says fonts.googleapis.com and then
the actual font lines say fonts.g
static you can't see the rest of this
but it's dot com and then there's a long
hash for the font
so what's happening here
yeah but didn't we just make a call to
to google they're on two different
domains
so the style sheet and the fonts are on
two different domains
so what do we have to do
yeah oh yeah we'll talk about the font
hints but um
so the browser has to start up a
connection to that separate domain but
it won't do that until it knows that it
has to reach out to that domain
um so we have this wasted time again
from doing this connection we know we're
going to do this connection but we don't
know
until after that style sheet is
downloaded and the css song is created
so that it knows
so resource hints are our friends um
we're going to focus on these middle
three um this is a nice little handy
thing i got from um one of addy awesome
andy's tweets he's a
he was a performance engineer at google
i think he's on a different team now
but he has some great stuff um so
pre-connect preload and prefetch are
really fun um
resource hints uh we'll talk about dns
prefetch also but first we'll talk about
the others
so what pre-connect does is it can
warm up a connection for you it can do
all the steps of warming up that
connection for you
and just have it waiting for you in the
background but there's a time limit on
it
so if you don't think that you're going
to access
a domain until later what you can do is
instead do dns prefetch and it just does
a dns part so at least it negotiates
that time
but a pre-connect will do the rest of
the connection as well but it has
it's time sensitive um preload
what preload does is um
it tells the browser oh hey i know i'm
going to need this file
soon download it now so normally
browsers are smart they're not going to
download a file until they know it's
necessary when we're talking about fonts
and similar
so it's not going to pull it down until
it knows that you have the matching
characters
and that you're using the font on that
page based on the css
but preload says hey i'm going to just
go ahead and download it now
because i know i'm going to need it
later even though you don't know it yet
prefetch lets you uh
put things in your cache for future use
we're not going to talk about that in
here but just
so you know
so what can we do actually conveniently
on this slide
that code snippet is exactly what you
would use with google fonts
so what it says that is i want you to
warm up the connection to
fonts.gststatic.com
now and so if we just put that in on the
head of our html with our call to our
style sheet
then that connection will start to warm
up and you can see it down here
you know it's kind of just like on its
own hanging out here
before the actual fonts are downloaded
so you just copy that line directly in
there and that does a pre-connect
and so now we've made our site faster
by just doing these little kind of
tricks like the code isn't significantly
different but you can actually
make a pretty good chunk of savings just
right there
let's talk about self-hosted fonts so
these are fonts that you host
you know on your domain
so you might call them in your head like
this um
preferably in your head because then you
know you don't have the same problem as
before when we call it from our css
so this is my waterfall what's on the
first line
the page itself right the second line is
mystal.css
that's also where i have my font face
declarations
and then what's going on with those last
two lines it's the fonts right
but like what was one of those hints do
you remember what i said earlier
there's a hint that can say oh hey
hey browser preconnect is for the
connection
we've already this is our domain so we
don't need to do any extra connections
preload so what we oh sorry forgot the
mic was there
so what we can do is we can say hey
browser
i'm definitely going to use this font i
want you to
download it earlier so i don't have this
longer time of waiting
um because you know what else is
happening what happens
while that font is downloading but it's
not yet loaded
what does the page look like
it depends on your font display settings
but it's either going to be
invisible or it's going to be a
different font
until that loads yeah
i call it food but other people say fout
[Laughter]
good thing we're not talking about uh
content
um so what we can do is we can preload
and the only thing i've added to these
lines here
is this rel equals preload
and then what can happen now on
supported browsers
is that those files will be downloaded
right away
any file i put link rail preload on
there so
with great power comes what
great responsibility if you watched any
superhero movie
um and so we don't want to abuse this
right
we only want to do this when we're
actually going to use they're definitely
going to use the file on that page
because we don't want to abuse
our users data plans and also i suspect
is it the next slide i suspect that's
why this has happened i don't know does
anyone know anyone on the firefox team
so on firefox preload used to be
supported and now it's not supported
it's like behind a flag so um i would
really
be curious if anyone on the firefox name
please uh oh my
twitter handle is the green greek um
please
let me know what happened there um my
guess is because
maybe they are concerned about the users
and kind of people abusing these
privileges
so um make sure that you don't abuse
this privilege but it will work in all
the other modern browsers
so um remember when i said when i said
uh
shared caching of popular fonts they
used to say like you know if you're
using open sans or roboto don't
uh just
do it directly from google fonts oh
don't ever try to just copy the hash
of the um of the font itself there's a
hash
so don't try to copy that whole url
because those are changed often and
they'll just disappear so you never want
to do that but shared cache is going
away
so now you can contemplate whether it
might be a good idea to download the
font and serve it locally even if it is
a google font you'll lose some of the
other benefits like the variants and
stuff like that
but um because of double key caching and
i don't know if anyone's going to talk
about this later
but shared cash is not really
a benefit anymore let's talk about font
rendering
so remember when i said white and fruit
or fout um floyd is on this page i know
it's a little hard to see
um this is i have a screenshot of
performance happening
that's what's over here on the right
hand side
and this is the page itself if you look
at the page itself you can see there are
actual words in my navbar
but if you could see this
screenshot better the
projector's a little bit dark there's no
words
in my nav bar there's no words in my
button
it's annoying right that's a flash of
invisible text does anyone know why
that's happening
this is this was using google fonts does
anyone know why
that was happening
yeah yeah so the default for
google fonts on their font display
property was display swap
so that means that it's going to show
the fallback font
for up to three seconds and then it
finally will switch to the web font
um so
it won't i'm sorry it will block it it
won't show anything at
all and um for three seconds and then it
will show the fallback and then it will
show the web font
and so this was annoying right like you
couldn't you had no control over this
before but now you have control
um with the google fonts api and now by
default it has this part of the url in
it
if you just add and display equal swap
you will get um display swap and what
display swap does is instead
of um making it invisible
it will show the fallback font until the
font web font is loaded
and we're going to kind of see a little
bit of this in action in a minute
so that's really cool if you have legacy
apps that use google fonts
you can make you can make them use
display swap if you want all you have to
do is add that last part of the url
you don't have to like go in and like
re-copy your urls you just add the
um the query at the end
so that's not playing
so flash of unstyled text right
that's this change here that's annoying
right
um some i mean sometimes it's more
annoying than others
if we think about what's happening here
i mean this might vary by user
i feel like we used to match fonts based
more on
style but if i'm for example reading
a blog post or an article the thing
that's going to annoy me more is layout
shift
so once that font comes in if i'm on a
totally different paragraph when it
comes in
for me as a user that's going to annoy
me so for me
i reckon i um i guess
recognize the intent of this quote the
style doesn't matter so much
as it has to flow the same way and so
there's some great tools that we can use
like um font style matcher uh and i'm
gonna actually go to
this um and so what you can do
is you let me zoom in so you can see
this a little bit better
um you can put it automatically has
google fonts available here but you can
also upload your own font so i've
uploaded this font and i'm going to tell
you more about that font
and what my fallback font used to be was
ariel
so if i go down here you can see them
overlapped
we can use a different color for each
font so ariel's red now
and then you can see an action like the
shift that happens
um so i have this this is actually a
variable font i'm going to talk about
that in a minute
so we can see what happens and what we
can do is we can adjust properties
for example like font size arial if you
look here it just it's a little bit
smaller so i could like bump up the font
size and i could basically provide an
entire fallback font
and change things um change which one is
used based
use on javascript i prefer not to do
javascript so what i did is
i put in some other website fonts in
here and i found that
um verdana i actually don't know how to
pronounce that for donna
i put that one in and it matched a lot
faster
but you can actually get super close on
some fonts and then maybe you realize
you don't actually need
your web font but um but at least here
my um the size of the font the line
height
and the wet the letter spacing really
closely matches so it makes a really
great fallback font for me because i
don't want the extra javascript on the
page just to load a separate
um font style as well
so that's a great tool to keep in your
back pocket for
having to deal with the swapping fonts
how many of you have used variable fonts
before i figured i would go into this a
little bit because they're fun and new
and so um and they also present some
challenges for performance
so we are going to we don't have slides
for this we're just going to do this
i started playing with this variable
font called recursive they have a really
cool website
um and it's a highly flexible new
variable font what i should do
is go to firefox when was the last time
you used firefox devtools
yesterday okay somebody actually hears
me so um
i do use okay that's fine
um i do use chrome mostly for
performance
but um firefox has
you know what helps what to do before
your talk
get on the wi-fi
it helps actually i think it might be
hold on
yay all right um so if i go
into then
inspect my element actually did i
inspect that one
i was just doing it randomly let me
inspect
what's really cool about firefox
devtools is they have this whole
fonts panel over here i wonder if i can
zoom in that so if you look here
we're going to play this is so you can
see what this particular
variable font will do i mean you can
play with standard things like size
and uh line height which is kind of cool
and
letter spacing oh that's terrible
but it also has all these special things
that are just for this particular
variable font
so what does this variable font do right
now it's
on um not monospace but this font
actually can be mono space as well
so i like to use my blog as my
playground and so i'm using this
variable font so i can use oh this is my
coding font too
and then you know and my body text is
going to be
that and then um it's called casual but
i call it sassy versus not sassy
right now that i think that's sassy
here's not sassy
and then here's sassy aka casual
um weight so look at that it's like a
smooth transition
i can like choose any weight in there
that's pretty cool so instead of like
downloading you know you have to
download your 700 weight your 800 weight
like if you want heavy bold
or you're lightweight um you could
theoretically just have all your weights
in one variable font
and then slant like italics there's
actually slant and italic are two
different things
um italic actually changes um
slant features as well so firefox that's
one lesson from
this firefox infecting inspecting fonts
are really great actually
css grid and other inspect element
things are really cool there
um so that's a variable font an intro to
a variable font um
but um
how how many how many kilobytes do you
think are loaded when you do like a
regular font
has anyone like looked at that how many
kilobytes you use
yeah so i feel like um you know like per
per style that you use because it might
be like it's like 400 weight
regular would be maybe 15 to 20
kilobytes or
up to 30 it depends on really the font
or in uh what subsets you're using like
is this just
you know latin text or is it others um
and so so maybe you have like
maybe let's say you have four of those
because you're doing maybe you have two
different fonts and you have two
different ways
that's conservative that's like 80
kilobytes maybe so
my basic english subset was 130
kilobytes
because it's a variable font like i said
this is my blog so i get to play with
things it's okay if they're a little bit
bigger
so what happened was the designer came
out with a new version the font designer
came out with a new version and he
wanted me to deploy it but it was like
400 kilobytes and i was like
are you a performance engineer i don't
think i should do that
so we started playing with performance
more so if we have things like variable
fonts what are some other things we
could do
perhaps do you have any ideas i mean i
don't know if we have this all correct
but
what do you think we can do there's
another thing i haven't spoken about
here
with fonts that you can do yeah
yeah so subsetting well we can subset
based on character codes um do you know
about this
inside your font i don't know if you've
played in font display properties
we're all developers most of us are
developers in here right so it's like
we don't often play or learn all the css
things that maybe we should
um but uh let me zoom in a little i was
going to show you the difference with um
for donna but it's fine so what we did
is we made more subsets
and so most of my website is in basic
english characters
and so um you can put a unicode range in
your
um font face declarations and it knows
to use this font for this unicode range
and this is the only one that i preload
now
i don't preload the rest and then the
others will only ever load if they're
used on a page
so um like i have um
yeah so like some diacritics and some
other things some symbols
and extended fonts and then a special
font just for my first name because i
made it the super heavyweight
so um that's that's the path we chose
there's also
tools you can do to subset your fonts if
you want really aggressive subsetting um
it's actually called sub font i think i
have a link to it in the back of this
but if you want to look at sub fonting
not just for variable fonts for any
fonts you can look at this tool called
cell font
i forgot the developer who wrote it but
it kind of gives you a whole
set of tools for setting up your fonts
in a more performant way
so yeah what's really cool about preload
which i forgot to mention because i
wanted to show it to you live
is that often what
happens is we can beat the rendering
path remember what preload does
it auto it automatically we put in our
head that we're going to
use this font and i want you to pre-load
it i want you to load it now so what we
can often do
is the only what happened there when i
reload it did you see that
i should slow it down there's only
one thing that happened there that you
could visually see right oh
not slow orbic so it did that but on a
faster connection
what can often happen is we actually
skip that fallback time
i do have a display swap on my name
because it's
brand it's branded so like branded
things you might want to keep swap
because you don't want to see the
ugly font on your brand um but yeah
so if i go to firefox right which
doesn't do
preload
i need to disable the cache
this one has a much bigger layout shift
all right
so more more resources mentioned i do
have a short article it's a little bit
data now but it still works if you want
to learn how to
self-host your google fonts there's a
little tool you can use in there and the
steps involved
um also when you're looking at things
like um
i didn't mention this in this talk
specifically but you can
pull your data into can i use like if
you use google analytics you can pull in
that data
and you can see like you know for my
particular users is this feature going
to be supported
like for example preload um
most of my users for one um client
are on um safari so it's supported
thank goodness um and then subfont that
tool i mentioned
which you can use for any type of font
so thanks
thanks for coming to my talk again the
slides are at bitly font perf
and um writing resources more
co.codes you can get find me at the
green greek
we will um
i guess we'll take a few questions i
prefer offline questions though
so feel free to come up to me later i'll
be in this room for the rest of the
web thing so in the breaks and then also
afterwards if you want to you know reach
out to me and go out there you can also
dm me on twitter
um or just us or at me
it's up to you but thanks for thanks for
coming to my talk thank you
you