so we're gonna
anyone who's been to one of my homebrew
talks before we'll know there's a lot of
hand raising that has to go on
so i'm sorry so who is who's heard of
homebrew before
now very good who uses homebrew
hopefully you have heard of it if you
use it uh who's submitted a pr to
homebrew
anyone submitted a pr to hombre which
was closed and rejected by me
note the majority of the people with
their hands up are homebrew maintainers
so that's
that's fine um great who likes putting
their hand up
way very fun all right so
my deeper there we go uh if you want to
talk to me about anything in this talk
easiest way is either twitter or my
personal email which is on github and my
website and stuff like that
i come here with two hats on generally
i'm not going to talk too much about
anything github related today but that's
my
day job they pay my bills they pay for
me to be here thank you very much github
i've been there about six years and i'm
working on github sponsors now
if you find any of that stuff
interesting then feel free to like
just grab me hopefully not physically
during fosdem and
talk to me about it and we can have
interesting conversations
and similarly about homebrew do you want
to talk about stuff like that
right so this talk i'm going to talk
about features and funding in homebrew
these two things are completely related
they're definitely not just two blog
posts i wrote that are jammed together
to make a normal size talk
so who likes features in software
if you haven't put your hand up i'm a
little bit concerned uh particularly new
features are generally nice i like it
when
i get to work on new features and i like
it when i release new features that
other people like
which is very exciting but a lot of the
time new features
are not very good when i first released
them because
i socket coding so
the problem with homebrew pre 1.0
is homebrew there's a lot of design
decisions that are made that
might look smart but are generally made
just because
me or one of my predecessors are
extremely lazy because
that's how it is one of the nice things
about being a software engineer for a
living and doing open source i'm sure a
lot of you can relate to this
is the pain of knowing how what you
would actually do if you had time to do
things the right
way which i don't have time to do
because i have now two small children
and they don't tend to allow me as much
time as my
paid overlords i get up to to do things
like write as many tests as i would like
etc etc
so one of the things you probably may or
may not know
with homebrew is it uses git and github
pretty heavily
so when you are doing updates of the
package repository or updates of the
package manager itself
that's just doing a git pull from github
essentially so
before homebrew 1.0 when you ran brew
update
or eventually when that became automated
for you then
effectively that's just doing a git
fetch checking what the latest version
is on github
and pulling that down for the package
manager itself
and for all packages now this is quite
good
when you want to just have everyone
running the same thing all the time
but it's not good if you like new
features that are not broken because it
makes it quite hard
to have subsets of users that you roll
features out to
when they are not quite ready yet so now
as of we're now a homebrew two point
whatever
most people will now end up
when they run brew update on a stable
tag
instead so we now tag things in the
repository so when you run brew update
the main package manager itself not the
packages we don't have any plans to do
that
but the package manager itself you will
kind of jump between tags if you are
most people
but if you are some special people then
you will get
effectively the same workflow as before
you will be on whatever the tip is of
the master branch
and whatever the latest commits are so
that means if i push some
pr or new commits or whatever it may be
then you will get them almost
immediately
now you you may wonder am i
some people or am i most people right
i'll tell you later but
ponder that question for now the way
more software generally works
for doing betas and handling kind of
features that maybe aren't quite ready
yet or just
big refactors that might maybe aren't
quite ready at is they might
pop up some little box asking people if
you want to use the beta or not
or in shorthand do you like bugs
or if you want to be a little bit more
philosophical do you hate yourself
personally i find almost any software i
use on a day-to-day basis that asks me
if i want to use the beta channel i
never do
because like the general fact is because
i'm using software i generally want it
to work
and when it doesn't work i definitely
get very annoyed
another problem i found is because i've
been working from home from 10 years
i'm not really used to like working in
an office environment so
now when software doesn't work the way i
want it to work my reactions are
increasingly
ridiculous loud and violent towards my
computer
so i don't really know that beta
software is good for
me or the structural directory of my
house at this point
on homebrew we do things a little bit
differently that basically the
fundamental question
with homebrew instead of asking yourself
you know
do i hate myself enough to try this new
software it's really about
do i hate you and the answer is no
of course i don't well obviously i do
still hate
some people around homebrew a little bit
probably no one in this room there's
enough people blocked on the homebrew
github organization that
you know that probably indicates a
little bit but
i mean to be serious though why do i
hate you
enough to make you some people
why do i hate you enough to make you sit
on the
on the master branch when you could be
on a lovely nice stable tag that's a lot
more tested
well so if you end up grouped in that
little group
i happen to think you're a little bit
special i happen to think you're curious
there's something about you that makes
you a little bit different from
the average person in the world and
i think you're probably a bit more
likely to be helpful and
that's a weird thing for me to have
maybe attributed about you without
knowing anything else about you
so how do i identify these things
well in homebrew we have the concept if
you look in the man page
we group our commands by we have
commands and we have developer commands
so a homebrew command might be the
normal way that you would use homebrew
with something like brew install wgap
most people are using these when they
invoke homebrew when they
work with it this is how most people's
entry point to homebrew is through these
but then we also have things called
developer commands which are what you
use if you want to contribute to
homebrew if you want to
be a homebrew maintainer if you want to
submit a pull request you're going to
make some changes
even just like locally for yourself then
you're going to run one of these
developer commands
so the fun fact is we track
not externally but we track on your
local machine
whether you've ever run a developer
command or not and 99.9
of people never have and point one
percent of people have
so 99.9 of people get
the stable branch i realize now i flip
these the wrong way around but oh well
uh 99.9 percent of people get the stable
branch and 0.1 percent of people get the
master branch
so again why would we do this this is
maybe a little bit weird
so this was based on experience over the
years of kind of observing how these
different groups of users tend to file
issues
so people who've never run development
commands
you tend to get issues that look a
little bit more like this
those of you who are maintainers of any
software would know
the dreaded phrase it doesn't work it's
generally not
super helpful in figuring out exactly
what the problem is
and what the changes are that need to be
made to do things to be fair though
i'm not blaming these people because
again with tools like homebrew despite
being
i guess sustainably a developer tool
it's now increasingly used by
a lot of people who are may not be
developers
at all maybe following some guide online
whatever it may be
and they're not familiar with the kind
of
open source free software bug reporting
way of doing things they don't know that
you need reproducible instructions etc
etc
but as a result since we kind of made
this move
people who only have run developer
commands tend to make bug reports that
look a little bit more like this
or quite a lot of the time i would say
50 of the time when it's a bug that's
affected them directly and is a
relatively simple fix instead you get
something like this which is very nice
this is generally when this is explained
i find
89 of people go oh that's interesting
whatever and
10 of people get very upset and don't
like this idea
that we are deciding for them
effectively whether they get the
unstable stuff or not
if you are one of those people then you
can set this in your environment
homebrew update to tag that basically
says even if you run a developer command
or anything like that you always want to
be on the stable branch so
don't trick you into ending up on the
master branch inadvertently
if you're the opposite and you're just
excited to get out there and find some
bugs
then you can set homebrew developer
equals one that will go
and that does a few more things that
will partly make sure you're always on
the master branch but then there's a few
things that are
warnings or don't print warnings um
but that will then turn into errors and
stuff like that which would be useful
for you to help
us fix generally if you want to set this
though the i would say the high level
for a command like for a flag like this
is
i'm prepared to submit pull requests to
fix things that i encounter
if that does not feel like you then feel
free to
not set that so
sometimes we get situations where we are
working on new features
where that like split between
master and stable tags is not quite
enough
so again a lot of stuff we do we will go
and
make a new change whatever it may be and
then we do a new release
of the package manager itself maybe once
a week or so
and then once things kind of get into
that stable tag then they'll get rolled
out to everyone i normally kind of
you know if we roll out something a bit
more dramatic then we'll give it a
couple of days before we do a release to
make sure that kind of
any of those beta testers have been able
to kind of potentially pick up on that
file an issue file a pr whatever it may
be and also like the homework
maintainers themselves because again
we're all on the
beta channel effectively but sometimes
that's not enough sometimes you need
something which
is going to last a bit longer that may
need toggled on and off for individual
machines or individual people or
whatever it may be
so for that we use feature vlogs who's
familiar with the concept of kind of
feature flagging
okay like some people might everyone
so again back to the feature problem of
you know we might want people to try our
new features but
often they are completely broken when we
first make them particularly with stuff
like homebrew there's some stuff where
if we want to change the way the
compilation process works for example
it's not feasible for me to test 4 000
packages on my machine
before i roll that out to everyone um
but at the same time i don't want to
just rule that out to everyone
and break their stuff so again do i hate
you
not yet because i want to try and make
sure this stuff is a little bit more
refined
before it ends up being with you so
generally
the way we do that is similar i guess
before
the way basically everything is
controlled in homebrew is through
environment variables
because we don't have a configuration
file we just decided this is the way we
like to do things
so we let users set environment rails
for these particular cases so generally
in the first case if i'm rolling out
something that i suspect is really
broken
then the first person to set that will
be me i will set that on my personal
machine
because i'm using homebrew for like work
stuff and i'll basically wait to see
what breaks internally in the code
obviously we're checking for the
presence of that variable
and then we can do like slightly
different logic internally whether you
have that flag set or not
then if we want to go a little bit more
advanced than that we can check if
hundred developer is set so that's gonna
basically group in all of the home room
maintainers and anyone who manually sets
that flag
for which i don't think there are a
whole number of people but again that's
sort of the group who've opted in to
receiving more warnings and problems and
stuff like that
then if you we want to not just put
something in
the master branch or stable tag we can
check that's the
equivalent variable that's set for us
for people who have run a developer
command at some point
and then at that point then it generally
ends up in the stable branch
so the the flow through these things is
generally
the first person testing a new feature
that i makes at least is going to be me
then it's going to be our ci system we
might initiate black globally so we can
see that
across all the packages then various
maintainers will enable it
then the people in the beta channel and
then everyone else
so hopefully then we end up with new
features that are not completely broken
so a brief side tangent for an employer
plug
so that's one of the things about github
that i kind of stole this idea from
from them obviously people have been
doing feature flagging before github but
they do the stuff generally very heavily
internally as well
so almost anything i work on a github is
going to be used by
feature flagged at least if it's some
new feature or some
big change in behavior it's going to
feature fly to just me first
then my team then the employees at
github and then
sometimes we have stuff if it's very
relevant to open source maintainers
we'll flag in like people in a kind of
set
maintainers community we have and then
we've started doing more like beta
opt-ins and things like that
and then we roll out everyone
so the next part of this talk there's
not really a great segue but i'll try
and make one up anyway
so talking about funding so
again we there's a lot of talk about
feature development and open source kind
of getting better and better and stuff
like that
and it's been in the last few years i
don't know how many of you
picked up on this a lot of talk about
like oh no it's open source broken
because you're starting to see big
companies who make
things you know like maybe maybe you
make some sort of thing that's maybe a
bit like a database but even better
and you want to write a bunch of codes
over the years to make this
amazing not quite a database but almost
like a database really really good
and you want to release it under an open
source license and have lots and lots of
people use it
but the problem is you can't get anyone
to give you any money
so you basically go
and maybe see if you can convince people
to pay you for the open source project
and no one really does and stuff like
that so
you're asking yourself well how can i
make new feature development okay i'll
make a company around my open source
product
and then you because you're making open
source
no one's going to pay you directly for
your thing but maybe if you go to some
people who can help people with stuff
like this
then they can generally you know throw
some money at you
and then that might help your company to
grow over the years and things like that
and then but the problem is eventually
you get to a point where your company is
making me making some money but they're
still not profitable and whatever it may
be
and then you you hit a bit of a wall
where you realize like oh there's all
these big kind of cloud providers who
are not in our opinion giving us the
fair share that we're due
and then as a result you go and
re-license all your stuff to non-open
source licenses
you then say that that is open source
software still and try and make package
managers pack your stuff anyway
and just keep telling everyone that it's
open source even though it's not anymore
and then go around telling people oh
open source funding is broken so
is open source funding broken though in
my opinion open source companies are
broken it doesn't really work
to have vcs fund massive organizations
who are going to go
and then just change their licenses five
years later
but in short i don't really care about
this problem and neither should you
because i think the problems that bigger
organizations who might make open source
databases and then change their licenses
a few years later to other things not
that i would name any names
the types of problems these types of
organizations have i think are
completely irrelevant to the open source
ecosystem as a whole
because actually at the end of the day
what does your project need money for
probably it does not need money for a
shiny office
it does not need money for a tesla in
your drive it does not need money for
a whatever other things venture
capitalist
money injections to your organization
give you so
if you want your tesla you're gonna have
to figure out another way of doing it
but
if the problems you are having which
means that your project needs money
are things like you need places to host
your binaries and that actually needs to
be paid for
or you need some sort of cloudy thing to
run some services in and that has bills
that needs to be paid
or in our case you need a ci system that
actually tests all your packages
but none of the kind of cloud-coasted ci
systems is anywhere near the scale
or provide the infrastructure that you
need then
you're going to need to get some money
somehow from somewhere
so homebrew found ourselves in this
situation in 2013
we didn't have any ci back then it
wasn't
as much of a thing certainly back then
travis
ci wasn't supporting mac builds and
stuff like that so
there was basically nothing that looked
like it was going to be an option for us
really to do
so we wanted to get some money and the
way you got money off random people on
the internet you didn't know in 2013 was
kickstarter
so we launched kickstarter we got enough
money
to buy ourselves some computer hardware
and then we installed that and kind of
ran that for a good few years and that
was fine
unfortunately we had a few problems with
this right so
partly having physical hardware means
that
some sort of humans are going to have to
manually deal with that normally the
humans who are physically closest to the
hardware
which was me and that sucks when that
person is you
all the time secondly we had leftover
money from the kickstarter that we
wanted to do stuff with at some point
and we
feel kind of we are obligated to do
something with at that point but that
was
again in a bank account in the uk in
pounds
and i was the only maintainer in the uk
so again that was non-ideal as well
and this stuff is all sounding very bus
factory of one so
i was trying to go and shopping for
other solutions so
in 2016 we kind of started talking with
the software freedom conservancy
after looking at various other kind of
software foundations and thinking that
was
the route homebrew was going to kind of
start to go down in order to kind of
have some
basically more bus factor around our
finances and stuff like that so
that provides us with a legal entity so
that entity could be the thing that owns
things like physical hardware rather
than any individual
it provides us with a 501c3 which is in
the us
the shorthand for an organization that
can receive uh donations and then people
can claim that back in their tax return
and like companies like stuff like that
for donations as well because it makes
it basically
more valuable for them to give you money
and again with it being 2016 we had like
a paypal account that we could get money
sent to us relatively easy for and
donations and the bank account if people
want to go like in physically wire
transfer
stuff so companies generally prefer this
route though so this was a little bit
more handy
but the problem with this model of
having
like get just celestine donations and
getting them
is it's not very stable you know you
might get a nice
and we've got some big like one-off
anonymous 10 000
donations from big organizations or
whatever it may be and that's really
cool and really helpful but that doesn't
particularly if with the stuff i
mentioned before if you're paying a
monthly fee for something
you don't want big lump payments you
want you would happily take lower
payments which are rolling on month over
month of
the month so in 2017
we moved to that way of asking people
for money on the internet which is
patreon
and that worked for us relatively well
we started to get a little bit of kind
of monthly income and things like that
but again you still have that problem of
how do you actually solicit
for people to give you a bit more money
so we started off by just putting it in
our readme and saying
yo we could do with some money for x y
and zed
please give it to us that didn't really
work very well like again we got
drugs and drabs but most people are not
checking that section of the readme to
see stuff like that
then 2018 we have like uh i think 10 000
followers on twitter or whatever at this
point
so we pushed on twitter kind of asking
and then we saw a little bit of an
uptick there
but the really impactful thing to our uh
funding in 2019 was we added a little
message to the application itself and to
the installer
so when you first install homebrew
or when we roll out really things which
we think are important to users such as
stuff like analytics
we display a little one-time message we
check that you have a tty which is
basically our way of
more or less seeing while you're not
running this within some other script
and you're probably going to actually
see this message and we do like a
console beep and stuff like that
so we've done that previously for kind
of analytics to let people know that
this is a thing we're doing and how to
opt out
so we thought hey we could do this as a
one-time message people will only see
this once per machine
or when they install a new machine
to solicit some donations more or less
just saying okay would you like to
donate to the project and then
that's what happened here-ish so
that that made a really so this was when
we saw it started i guess just before
and had just the donation stuff in the
readme again picking up slowly over
time big jump there when we started
asking on twitter
and then the jump when we added the
little mag message was
fairly ridiculous so and since then
we've been sitting fairly
sort of statically on between two and a
half and three thousand dollars a month
which is pretty great um and then as of
2019 we've added kind of gab sponsors
which is
like plug plug that's something i work
on at work so that's a nice other way
for us to kind of
get funds organizations are still in
beta for that
so we were kind of one of the early
organizations to get into that but again
within the next few months that should
be open to all
organizations um but again that's a way
that we've been able to get monthly
income through
uh the github platform and that's like a
few hundred dollars a month at the
moment as well
so with that combined we have kind of
two and a half to three thousand dollars
a month which
actually now gives us enough money to
partly have maintainers fly here and we
have a
our annual general meeting for the
second time on monday
and partly to start actually paying for
hardware and things like that that we
need to run the project effectively
and we've done this without selling user
data which is again things which
we've been accused of doing in the past
people worry about stuff like that with
analytics but it's something that we
wouldn't ever consider
we've done it without asking people to
donate again and again and again
like again i i kind of i don't
mind when programs i use do that because
i feel like that's within their right
but you do have to wonder like if
someone has said no thanks i don't want
to donate like three
or four times how likely they are in the
fifth sixth or seventh time to
decide to donate and not just get really
annoyed we've done that without having a
sort of like homebrew pro edition some
special version of homebrew with
features limited which are not open
source so people need to pay for or
whatever
and surprisingly we've done it without
anyone really accusing us of selling out
and we've not had any backlash as far as
i can tell
to our donations and our funding stuff
this may will both be partly because
we my advice maybe to other projects
would be we effectively don't
really make any promises on what you
will get
for donating to homebrew and what the
money will be spent on except the fact
that
you know we're part of a software
foundation and this isn't going to be
like none of the money has gone in any
maintainers pockets
individually or directly or anything
like that and before that would happen
there would be a very
formal process of contracting and stuff
like that so basically
although we can't promise you what your
money would be spent on if you donated
to homebrew
we can say that it will be used to kind
of for the project's mission and not
just
to buy me a tesla so with that
i think we can say that homebrew is
still quite good and
things seem to be going better for the
project as a result of doing this
funding changes
so thank you very much and do we have
time for questions
you