hi everyone uh my name is greg
i am a i'm a hardware engineer from
lowrisk
uh previously i've worked at arm on
a-class processors on memory systems and
on broadcom and gpus and it's really
great to finally be working on some open
source hardware
which is what we do at lowrisk so today
i'm going to talk about ibex
which is our our cpu core it's a
microcontroller class cpu core
uh two-stage pipeline very simple uh
32-bit
u-mode m-mode pnp um supports
uh emc and imc um we've wrote this in
system verilog and it came to us
from the pulp team uh zurich which i'm
sure many of you are familiar with um
and where it was known as zero risky and
we have picked it up and we've developed
it from there and we've done a lot of
work into improving the rtl
uh and really um doing a lot of
verification on it
and so it's being developed by lowrisk
which is the company i work for
we are a not-for-profit company uh we
work on open source silicon so we use
collaborative engineering we work with
various organizations
to build open source hardware designs
and a notable use of ibex is in our
recently announced open title project
that you may have heard
of which is an open source silicon root
of trust and we hope there's going to be
many
many more things it's going to be used
in
so today's talk is about improving the
performance of ibex
so here what i'm really talking about is
i'm trying to reduce the total number of
cycles i've spent executing
um some benchmarks so in this particular
uh
talk i'm talking about core mark and
then bench core mark because well
everyone talks about call mark numbers
and then bench because it's this nice
new interesting open source benchmarking
suite
um and i felt it had a great range of
stuff to run
and i thought it was a useful thing to
look at
you do have to be careful when you're
working with benchmarks um you've got to
be careful you're not just optimizing
for the benchmark only
so you need to it's very useful to
analyze what's going on with a benchmark
and use that as a guide as to things
that you can then do
you then need to take a step back and
think is this actually generally useful
or am i just making
specifically core mark quicker
and i would say that the improvements
i've mentioned here are going to be
configurable options in ibex
so you're going to be able to choose
having between a smaller or simpler ibex
core or you can have a faster core that
will be a
bit bit bigger and a little bit more
complex
so the trial system that we are running
these simulations on is simulating ibex
verilator we've just got a dual ported
memory containing code and data with a
single cycle access latency
i feel this is a fair analog of a best
case real system
obviously you can get other systems that
aren't going to have quite this setup
and thus aren't going to perform as well
so how do we go about working out what's
going wrong with our performance
you can uh you don't have to do all i
didn't do anything complicated
literally uh run some benchmarks trace
the simulation open up the tracing gtk
wave and just start having a look around
what you're doing here is you're just
trying to look at it identify
interesting behaviors
that you can then poke into more and
then determine if they're actually
causing you performance issues
so it's not a quantitative analysis but
it's just a quick and easy way to get an
idea of what may be going wrong so
i run cormark in uh on on our verilater
simulation
and i open it up in gtk wave and i have
a poke around
and here's a couple of things that i
found so the first thing
is having a look at how is this example
here which is a conditional branch
so you can see the instruction down in
the bottom there
it's a branch of not equal and this
particular condition is passing
so the thing i have in the red circle
there is the first cycle of us executing
this branch
we've pulled the two operands out of the
register file
we're seeing and lo and behold they are
not equal
so our result there is a positive so we
are going to branch
but before we can branch we have to work
out where we're going to so in the next
cycle
we use the alu again to calculate the
branch target so we're reusing that
resource
first a computer condition and then to
do an addition
and then finally we branch so this has
taken
a total of three cycles and
during this time in these in the sec in
the second two cycles the processor is
stored because we stay in the same
pipeline stage while this is happening
so if we could improve this somehow then
we can speed up
our execution
next thing we can look at is uh here
loads
and again we end up stalling on every
single load and the reason for this is
again our two-stage pipeline
in the first cycle we request the data
we have one cycle access latency so in
the next cycle we get it back
but we need to wait a cycle for us to
get to get that data back so we end up
stalling the pipeline again
and we actually have the same behavior
on stores the reason for this is we wait
for a response from the store to tell us
if there's an error
for example if we accessed a
non-existent address
uh so we end up stalling for at least
one cycle on stores as well
so we've got these stall cycles around
branches loads and stores which
you know clearly isn't particularly good
for performance
so we're going to actually do some
quantitative analysis now we're going to
use the performance counters to actually
um
see what's going on and dig in to some
of the uh
and try and determine how much this is
actually impacting our performance
so we've just identified um two three
interesting behaviors that are probably
slowing us down
let's see what the actual effect is so
run we run our simulation
uh across a variety of benchmarks using
these performance counters
and we get some results that tell us how
much time we're spending stored
so this first graph here on the bottom
uh axis on the x-axis
you can see the various benchmarks on
the far left is cormark
on the far right is a geometric mean of
all of these numbers
and in the middle is the m bench
benchmarking suite
and what we have here is the percentage
of total cycles spent
calculating the branch target so if we
go back
here that second red circle there this
is the total number of cycles percentage
of total cycles we're basically spending
doing that red circle
uh sorry that red circle
and you can see um on average around
about four percent of our time is spent
doing this so if we could remove this
cycle we could um
increase uh reduce the number of cycles
that we spend doing these benchmarks by
around about four percent
and different benchmarks have different
amounts of branching which is
you know unsurprising we can do a
similar thing for the memory
um note that the uh the y-axis has
changed in scale so we're at um
but otherwise very similar graphs this
is a percentage of cycles that we've
spent waiting for a memory response
whether that's the data coming back
or the response from the uh on a store
from the memory system
um and this is a significantly bigger
chunk of time
you can see on average that's around
about 15 percent
and then different benchmarks have
different amounts of memory activity so
fairly uh spread about how much
performance you can potentially save by
reducing the number of cycles you spend
hanging around for memory
so we've identified these things it
definitely seems to be slowing down
these benchmarks we can go
is this you know if we improve these
things are we just improving benchmarks
are we just are we improving other
things but i think it's pretty safe to
say
everything is going to use branches and
memory accesses so yes this is generally
useful and yes this is a major thing
that is slowing down the ibex core right
now
so we need to improve things
so the first thing we're going to do to
improve our branch performance
is to introduce a new alu a branch
target alu
so on the right hand side here i have a
diagram of the
ibex pipeline very simplified we've got
our two stages we have our instruction
fetch so that grabs the instruction out
of memory
and then we have decode and execute
introduction moves into there and it
sits there
and um until it is done until it is
finished and written back to the
register file
so if we want to remove this stall cycle
around computing branch targets all we
need to do is just add in the second aou
so rather than spending
two cycles using this main lu twice
we are going to use the main alu to
compute the condition decide whether or
not we're bouncing and at the same time
perform the addition that's going to
work out where we're branching to
we increase the area of the core a
little bit because we're adding in some
extra logic but we're getting a four we
reckon we're going to get around about a
four percent performance going out of it
so this is probably a good idea
so we do this nice straightforward
but there's other things we need to
consider that's the implementation so
the physical
impact of these changes we're going to
add some logic so it's going to add some
area
it's also going to alter the timing so
what frequency we can run the processor
core at
so i built an experimental synthesis
flow using uh yosis
open source synthesis tool if you're not
familiar with it um and i did timing
analysis with opensta
i pulled um the 45 nanometer nand gate
library that you can get out of the open
road repository
and i use this to generate some uh
implementation numbers
i would caution that things like yosis
and the nand gate 45 nanometer library
um are you know aren't going to achieve
the best numbers compared to what you
could potentially do with commercial
tools and libraries
so this flow is not here to say here's
the best numbers we can get out of ibex
for frequency and area etc
but it is very useful to see relative
changes as we make these
as we make these improvements and then
see where our air as a timing pressure
are
see what chains of logic are slowing
down our frequency
and thus work out where we can improve
things
so here are the results of implementing
the branch target aou i've just put the
core mark results in but um
you'll see some m bench results later
and court mark per megahertz well that's
gone up by about four and a half percent
which is what we expected
great area has increased a little bit
but not too much
great the problem here is we've just
lost some frequency so our f max
the maximum frequency that our core can
run at have gone down by 13
so actually this means overall we
haven't necessarily increased
performance because if we're running at
maximum frequency
our maximum frequency has just gone down
so the our call mark per megahertz has
gone up but overall we end up with a
lower core mark result we end up with a
slower core
so can we do anything about this this is
kind of disappointing we have this nice
little simple change but
which seemed obvious but actually we
started going slower
so we need to dig into the
implementation and try and work out
what's going wrong
now yosis allows you to do this it's got
some nice tools for selecting out logic
and examining paths and things
and it produces these wonderful diagrams
which you can spend a very long time
staring at
obviously it's not particularly easy to
just pick out of something like this so
this is a graph of some of the
uh logic inside the ibex core as
produced by the yoast synthesis tool
you can't immediately go aha it's this
line here
but you can with some knowledge of the
design spend some time examining this
have a bit of a think about it and work
out what's going on which is what i've
done
so here's a far simpler diagram which
actually explains what we've messed up
so what's happening here for people who
aren't familiar with
uh synthesis and logic implementation
the the thing that's slow that sets the
maximum frequency in your design is
based around the the length
of the longest chain of logic in your
designs you have a whole bunch of logic
gates
all connected together and the longer
the longer those chains get the longer
it takes for a signal to propagate down
and the slower your clock can run
and so what we have here i've got this
grey line which is the longest path in
our design
so we start with the instructions and
that's instruction we've just read out
of the instruction fetch stage in the
previous cycle
which we are executing we have a decoder
which is a blob of logic which is
working out
what we're going to do it's going to set
up the controls for for this this
instruction
this then feeds into the main alu which
is going to compute our results for us
and then on the right hand side here
i've got what i've labeled the pc mux
selection logic
so what this is doing is choosing where
our next pc is going to be which then
feeds into that
insta adder o on the right hand side
there
that is the address we're next fetching
from instruction memory
and so it's actually quite complicated
to decide this because there's quite a
few things going on
you might be branching you might just be
going to the next instruction there
might be an exception there might be an
interrupt
we actually have a prefetch buffer which
is trying to fetch ahead
which is also affecting the instruction
address so this pc mux selection
actually has quite a lot of things to
decide so it's a reasonably complex blob
of logic
and what we've done here is previously
if we were going to branch
um we're going to spend two cycles over
it and so the first cycle
main lu is going to compute the
condition it is then going to remember
whether or not we passed the condition
the next
cycle the main ao is going to compute
the branch target
and what's going to happen is it's going
to come out the alu it's going to come
up this dotted line here
and into this mux and then out to give
us the next instruction fetch address
we have just removed this dotted line
because we now have this advanced target
alu
and we've introduced this new line here
this is the condition
coming out of the main alu and it feeds
into the pc mux selection logic
so what we've done is we've taken what
was the longest path in the design
namely this dotted line here
and we've added just a little bit of
extra stuff onto it because we've now
put the pc much selection logic in there
because of our
because we're no longer saving the
condition we're using it immediately
and this has slowed us down
so how do we make ourselves faster well
we need to have a look at some of the
blobs and try and work out what it is we
can improve the main alu there's
probably not much we can do about that
you implement the best ad you can and
there you go it's as fast as it's going
to be
what we can probably do though is look
at how we're setting up the operands for
the main alu so we've got these red
lines coming in here these are the
control lines which are selecting what
operands we're doing
so what we're going to try and do is
make those main aou
operands turn up earlier so the main alu
result
comes earlier and the problem here
that's causing these things to be quite
late is because of the decoder this
is a big complicated blob of logic it
basically controls the entire design
it is trying to work out what the
instruction is doing we need to make it
go quicker
so there's a few things i need to fix to
do this sadly i've only got time to
discuss one of them
and this is this instruction flop fan
out
so this thing here which is what i just
called the instruction flop
connects to an awful lot of logic all
kinds of gates
and so in order for it to physically
drive all these gates it needs a bunch
of buffering to push that signal out
everywhere
and this slows it down quite a bit so if
we could somehow reduce that if we could
reduce that fan out we can speed up
our design and so what we do is we just
make a copy of our instruction flop we
now have two of them
and then we split out the decoder so it
looks a replicated version of the
instruction
and then it uses that purely to decide
the alu operand select and then the
operation
and then the d then d code for
everything else comes from the other
register
and in doing this we um make these
red lines appear earlier in our cycle so
all of this returns earlier and we help
fix the path
and as i said there are some other
things we need to do but i have not got
the time to discuss
so after doing this plus some extra
improvements i've now got a better
implementation
area has actually gone down a bit i
think that's because i've reduced the
amount of buffering in the design due to
duplicating that register
sadly i still haven't recovered the
frequency though
now i'm not too worried about this um
for a few reasons one the tools i'm
using yosis and abc the optimizer it
uses
don't actually take timing oh sorry i
owe timing constraints into account
so what we're the path we've got here is
an output um path
and there's a constraint on it saying
how early it needs to appear
you can't actually feed this into yoast
so it can't really really target the
optimization at it so i think if i had
some other tools that were capable of
doing this
i could probably optimize this path a
lot better and i could hopefully
make the rest of this problem go away
and then the other thing is this is a
microcontroller you're not necessarily
wanting it to run it at the maximum
possible frequency
but it is important that we're trying to
maintain
we don't just keep adding things that
keep slowing it down and slowing it down
so overall probably a pretty good
optimization for someone who really
wants to run ibex at the maximum
frequency they can maybe want to turn it
off but they can do that because it's a
configurable option
second thing i've done um was add a
third pipeline stage to ibex
now this is actually quite i've made
this look very simple this is actually
quite a complex thing to do it's just
one of those things don't really have
time to dig into it but what we've done
here
is now an instruction goes into decode
and execute
it computes its result then the next
cycle it sits into this right back stage
here
and then it writes itself back to the
register file so this gives us an extra
cycle
to wait for the result to turn up for
memory or for the response to the store
so we lose a store cycle out of loads
and stores
and so this is going to help solve our
uh our store problems around memory
and as i've said this is quite a comp
reasonably complicated thing to do i
just don't have time to really talk into
all the details about what is going on
and then when i implement that um area
goes up as you might expect but we've
got about a again on core mark
we've got about a 20 improvement in call
mark per megahertz so
notable area cost but it's outweighed by
our performance gains
f max has basically stood still so this
is the right backstage along with that
new branch target alu so it hasn't
really affected it
it's still those branch target aou
changes that are dominating our timing
and keeping us at that f max that we
have
so nice complicated graph same thing
you've seen before
benchmarks on the bottom car core mark
on the far left
geometric average on the far right m
bench suite in the middle
and you can see and then it shows you
our total speed up and the combination
of where
what the branch target aou has done for
us and what the right back has done for
us on top of that
and overall our geometric mean there is
21.3
so i think that's a really quite
significant gain in performance
for seven percent area which seems like
a pretty good deal to me
obviously it doesn't affect all
benchmarks equally not all benchmarks
are
memory or branch bound i think some of
these benchmarks in particular using say
a lot of multiplies
so that is what's slowing you down now
and there we go um quick whistle stop
tour for some of the performance
improvements i did
if you would like to find out more you
can check out our ibex repository here
on
on our github uh the work i've just been
discussing not all of it is yet in the
main repository
um so i put up a special uh ibex fosdem
branch of my own ibex fork you can go
take a look at if you want to uh
recreate my results or play around with
what i've done you can also check out
lois on the lowest website
we're now we're currently hiring so if
you're interested in working open
silicon uh
powering both software and hardware
positions do get in touch and if you
have any questions about this work or
anything else then feel free to
get in touch and drop me an email okay
well thank you very much