okay thank you everyone
next talk aderin is going to tell us
about
psychic custom transformers all right
sorry it's not mike
okay thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
hello everybody um i'm adrian i work at
anaconda
and um i want to cycle land maintainers
um
today i'm gonna talk about how to write
your own estimator um
before i start i need to know how many
people
have used scikit-learn
okay cool so i don't need to focus too
much on the background
it's good for the rest of us who are not
familiar with it it's a statistical
machine learning library it doesn't that
means that it does cover all the
old-school stuff the support vector
machines random forest k-means and
whatnot
it does not include the deep learning
ones it doesn't cover
gpu acceleration um just not in this
scope
that said um what are the when we look
at the library
wanna what are the main or some of the
main components of the library before we
start writing our own estimator we need
to understand that
we have estimators the estimators are
either transformers
in which case they take some data they
transform that they spit it out
or their predictors they are classifiers
or regressors
then we have scorers these models we
need to know how they perform
uh so we have different scores to
measure their performance in different
ways
then we have meta estimators the meta
estimators take
an estimator and they do something with
it um
two two of them two of the important
ones and relevant ones to this talk
are a pipeline which allows you
to have a set of transformers and then
if you
will at the end a predictor you have
your classifier at the end
and then you have your transformers
before that and then it lets you
treat that whole pipeline as one single
estimator
and then you have grid stitch which is
easier to explain
with a little example the usual pipeline
we have our data we need to we need to
pre-process and prepare the data
uh to give that to our classifier in the
case of a classification
so in this case i have two steps to
prepare the data
and then i feed that uh to an
sgd classifier but each of these steps
usually have some hyper parameters that
you can tune if
it if it's a transformer that um if it
if it's doing
um principal component analysis like how
many components do you want to return
that number are you doing k-means that k
if you're uh if you're regularizing what
is the regularization parameter um
how do you do that that's your parameter
set
and then that set defines your your
space
and now you want to search in that space
and find
the best point for your data
um glitters does that for you you pass
it your estimator and your parameter
space and it does this edge
okay if you want to use a different
score than the default one you can also
pass that
so with all that flexibility why why
would we want to write our own estimator
um
there are a couple of cases one is that
scikit-learn doesn't
have all the algorithms out there it
does have the classical ones
but it's not really possible for us to
include everything
so if you if if you fancy a new
algorithm it's probably not there
or if you are a researcher who would
like to implement their own
and work on their own method you
probably want to write your own
and then see how it works um in
combination with the other methods and
transformers out there
or my favorite example is if you're
doing ethics um doing ethics and like
virus mitigation and detection are not
in the scope of psychic land
um so if you if you want to work on that
then you would have to write your own
cycle and compatible ones and like
mitigate your bias we also don't include
things that are
extremely specific to certain use cases
if you need to do something that applies
only to your data
you probably need to write that and it's
not going to be included in the library
um another use case is writing meta
estimators if you want to do
something before or after every time you
call an estimator you can easily write a
method estimator wrap around your
estimators
and then do logging or auditing or
whatnot
so what's the basic api what does it
look like um
estimators um expose fit to train on the
data
predict if they're doing classification
or regression transform
if they're a transformer and score if
they're a predictor you need to know
how they perform when i look at
people's people's codes trying to write
their own estimators it
it looks as if they watched this talk or
equivalent of this talk and they stopped
here
so please don't um
so if if i want to write uh this this is
like this this estimator is not really
doing anything fancy just
it's just to show how you could write it
what are the components that you need
the main one
or okay before that one thing it is it
is a it is a very opinionated api
and it has its own design i know
probably half of us in this room
may not agree with that design but
that's what it is so that's not
the discussion we can talk about later
we do composition that means that if
you're writing an estimator
you are you have to have base estimator
if you're writing a classifier is
classified mixing
and then depending on what you do you
would need different mixings regressor
mixing
uh meta estimator mixing and a bunch of
other ones
we have a bunch of really nice methods
to do input validation
you really don't need to write your own
input validation you need to you don't
need to check if
if the input is a non-parallel or not um
all of that is there
and then my classifier is going to wrap
around on svc
you know in a very poor way
then so things to note here uh i have my
init
and in the in it i i accept my met my
hyper parameters
and the only thing i do is that i store
them i store them in public attributes
and i do
no validation that is important all the
validation
goes into fit in fit i do input
and if needed i do validation i'm up
on my parameters if two if two
parameters are not compatible and i need
to check
like only one of them is set this is
where i do that
and then here i'm just um storing my
trained
svc in an estimator with a trailing
underscore and that's again important
the convention is that attributes are
attributes they're public
if there's a trailing underscore it is
set in fit
if it's a leading underscore it's
private and
backward compatibility is not guaranteed
then i have predict um i check if i'm
fitted
if yes then i check my input and then i
delegate to my estimators pretty
so what did i use there
one of them was check is fitted it
checks if there is any attribute with an
uh with a with a with a trailing
underscore you can you can
tune the behavior chakra is a is a
really long and important one
it does return an empire uh unless you
say you
do explicitly want to support sparse
arrays in which case it doesn't convert
this particular to a dense array
and if it's a pandas data frame it
converts that
to numpy so if you if you want to for
example
check your like get your feature names
before from your
pandas data frame you do that before
passing it to check area
and then check x y does the same thing
plus doing some extra validation on y
now that we have it how can we be sure
that it is now
compatible the compatibility is usually
checked through our common tests we have
check estimator
it does a whole bunch of tests and we
recently added this decorator
parameters with checks you put that on
top of your
pi test test and then it does all the
tests individually and you can easily
check and debug what went wrong for
example when i was writing this one
i forgot to set the classes attribute
which is needed if you're a classifier
and then a complaint and then i go back
and set it
now that we have it then it's easy it
you can use it the way that you
you would use before um i have a bunch
of data
i can fit on my data i can get my score
i can put that in a pipeline here i have
a select kb
best and then my classifier and then
i can even pass that to a grid search
i feed my grits edge and then if i check
my best estimator
i see that my classifier this is the
hyper parameter selected by the grid
stitch
so what are the some what are some of
the conventions um i pretty much
mentioned
all of them except um the one that the
parameter is passed to fit
the one that you see usually in in the
existing encyclone api
is sample weights uh but you
you could pass other stuff you could
pass groups you could do
um in like when we have in the context
of um
um bias detection and fairness we
usually have our protected attributes
that are not
a part of the data like gender zip code
race all of that
all of that you can pass to fit as a fit
parameter the convention is that
everything that you've
passed as a fit parameter should be
sample aligned if you have feature
attributes
probably don't pass it there if you have
something that you could pass as an init
from do that there
and it's important because if you do
pass things that are sample aligned the
grid search when it does the
uh the folding and um the cross
validation
it does slice these parameters these
like extra parameters for you
and then pass that with your data to the
fit prompt
to the feed function
then um so this is these are the usual
ones but not all estimators follow all
of that
and um either other meta estimators or
some of the tests
need to know that so that's why we
recently introduced
uh estimator tags um they're still
experimental
as in we may change them without
prior notice like they don't go through
the usual deprecation cycles
but they're pretty useful um you can
tell the other meta estimator or the
test what kind of
input types you allow do you support
multi-output do you do
accept nouns and then if you want to
change any other defaults
you can do that by having a more tags
attribute
so what are we doing now this is
this is like how it works now but we are
we're adding a bunch of stuff to the api
and um uh they're useful but that means
that um you would also need to
to add or change your your api a little
bit
one of them the first one that is coming
in uh which hopefully will be there in
the next release
our end features in and end features out
we want to be able to inspect the models
and know how many features went in
and for a transformer how many features
are coming out
that's the first step and um it like it
helps a lot uh for us also to clean up
the code
but it also helps to understand what's
going on in a pipeline
the the step after that is that we want
to have feature names
um if usually if i have data which is
not just a numerical
block if i have a pandas data frame with
a bunch of feature names and i have a
pipeline
i would like to follow in my pipeline
how my features are going through
if i have a bunch of transformers at the
end if i have a classifier i want to
know what went into my classifier
if i have a linear model and then i want
to inspect my coefficients of the linear
model i want to know
which feature was it that now it has a
high coefficient there
so for that we would have right now the
api allows you to have get feature names
that you return the feature names uh but
it becomes ambiguous
or like is that the input feature names
or is that the output feature name
sometimes it's not um clear to define
what it was so we're deprecating that
and we're going to have feature names in
feature names are pretty clear
and that means that if you pass a pandas
data frame you would extract the feature
names for you
and then at the end you will have all of
that propagated in the pipeline
the next one that i'm really excited
about is
data properties sample proper sample
props feature props and data props
um sample weights is an example um
gender that i mentioned is another
example the issue there
is that right now in a pipeline if i
have a pipeline and i want to pass that
to
a fit i have to say okay pass this one
to the fit of that step of the pipeline
and then if i want to pass the same
sample ways to under the fit i need to
copy that and say well
also pass that to this one and if i have
a meta estimator
i don't know if the meta estimator
should pass that through
or not maybe i have to duplicate that
and pass the one that is used by the
meta estimator and pass another one that
is used by the one
handled by the meta estimator so it's
really not clean the idea here
is that i could have a really nice
routing and
um every set the pipeline every meta
estimator would know
what needs to be passed to what's to
which step and not just fit also score
and predict if you if you
if you need to pass other features other
other properties to them
then you should be able to pass them
that requires changing the the api a
little bit
um and then there are some prototypes
and hopefully they will go forward and
we'll have them uh
soon
but that's that's not all of it um they
i i only showed you
uh like a really really simple one and
um
for example here i could if i if i
really
wanted to write a clean estimator if i
am wrapping around an estimator
i may be a classifier but i'm also a
meta estimator
which means that i shouldn't have to
care about
which hyper parameters are there the
user should be able to pass it
an estimator and then i should be able
to know what the parameters are
you don't have to do that yourself you
can use the meta estimator mixing
and all of that you can see um in the
like in the in the points that i give
here
um this one this documentation um covers
most of the stuff i talked about
uh this file the base that pile uh has
everything other than the except the
methyl similar ones there are other
mixings that you probably could use
um and then the meta estimator one and
then the validation. has it has it has a
lot more utility functions that you
could use
thanks i'll take questions now
[Applause]
we have time for lots of questions
so this estimator can work with like
tensorflow
data structures and other from keras
like hazard
interoperability or just for basic data
structures
if i have a data and like tensor flows
that that distributed structure can it
like
can i just insert it in this estimator
from scikit-learn or it will work
it will require some kind of other
conversions
in the in the way so if if i understand
the question is a question
that if you could put a for example a
pi torch model as an estimator here or
yes yeah or something like that yes
yeah so so the um the idea is that um
they don't
so the default api of any of those
libraries doesn't follow
this api but usually what happens is
that they have an sklearn wrapper
so you could i don't remember which one
has it where
but for example if i see pytorch dot
escalant then i know that that's where i
can find
my cycle and compatible estimators and
then those estimators
they wrap around their own estimators
but they expose an api which is
compatible here
therefore you could take that and then
plug it in a pipeline here
okay so principally it can it can yeah
no it does people do that
okay thank you
don't be shy raise your hand and if i
don't see
crazy tire
nothing okay thank you
[Applause]