hello i'm
drew uh fastini this is my first fosdem
i've been watching uh videos for many
years uh so this is my first time
actually
getting here so i'm excited to be here
um
actually i'm from chicago but i moved to
berlin uh this past year um
so i'm in the area now um i'm part of
the beaglewater dark foundation we make
small
single board computers most popularly
known as the beaglebone
also part of the open source hardware
association um
this is a group that we have a open
source hardware certification program
um and i mentioned berlin if you are in
the area
in a couple weeks we have the berlin
embedded linux meetup
so if you're around we'd love to have
you stop by that
and then on march 13th in new york city
um
the open source hardware association we
organized an annual
uh conference called the open harbor
summit so if you're able to this will be
on march 13th
um in new york city
um and since i mentioned open source
hardware just want to give a brief
introduction of what that is so it's
hardware whose design
is made publicly available so that
anyone can study modify
distribute make and sell the hardware
help sell the design or hardware based
on the design
um so for electronics which is mostly
what i do um that would be the schemat
you'd be sharing the schematics the
board layout
in the editable source file so if you're
using a program like keycad you'd share
your
board file in your schematic file and
then also the bill materials
and one of the best practices if you
want to do this is to make sure that the
bill materials
you have the components are available in
a small quantity
so like with beaglebone we make sure
that all the components are available in
quantity of one from distributors
and the reason for oh i also gave a talk
at ccc recently that i go more into
depth about like open source hardware
um from the different licensing and also
some of the different
open source hardware boards that run
linux so if you're interested in that
you can check out my
363c talk um but
going back to the open source hardware
why would you do this i would say the
main reason to do it is you want to
enable other people to collaborate on
your hardware project
so by sharing your schematics and your
board layouts and editable format you
can
get people to contribute back changes to
your project and
if you make the components available if
you choose components that are available
through distribution people can actually
build your project
so um i'm very excited right now about
risk 5
which is a um open instruction set um so
what's an instruction set so probably
many of you have heard of x86 or arm
these are um instruction sets which is
essentially
the standard for uh what tasks a
processor can do at a low level the
instructions that the processor can
execute um though with both x86 from
intel and amd
and um the arm instruction sets they're
all proprietary
so if we want to make like an open
source chip we need to have an open
source instruction set so
risk five um i think it's about ten
years ago now it was started by a group
at berkeley that was doing uh computer
architecture research so
risk five is a free and open instruction
set um i believe it's licensed under
creative commons the standard is so
anyone can take that instruction set and
implement it
um there's a couple great talks if you
want to get more in depth on risk five
one is from david patterson who's one of
the people that originally um started
risk back in the early 80s
and then also chris asanovich who's the
professor at berkeley that was
leading the risk five team
um and he does this talk at um probably
like every six months at these risk five
conferences so
it's always kind of changing because
it's uh there's a lot of development
going on so
if you ever want to check out like deep
dive into what the current state of
affairs is
with risk five is they do the state of
the union probably like every six months
um so one of the things about roots five
was the idea was to make it a modular
isa
that you could um be extensible so
to make it last for something that's
going to be valid a decade from now
two decades from now they want it to be
something where they're planning for the
future so there's 32-bit
64-bit and there's also 128-bit um
version of the ris 5 instruction set so
the idea being that you know once we
have petabytes of memory we'll
we'll still be able to address all that
memory um
yeah so going back to the project
beginning i guess in 2011
um all the way up to now we we have um a
bunch of different companies that are
involved now
um and
the ecosystem is probably the most
important thing the software ecosystem
so
it's fine to have an instruction set but
it's not worth
it's not that valuable if you don't have
support in compilers and tools and
operating systems
so their support in gcc llvm
linux kernel pre-rtos now zephyr so
pretty much everything that you need
to have a system that you can develop
and
build and put into production
so this kind of gives you a bit of a um
bit of an insight into the instruction
set so it actually is a very small
base so the base of the isa is just the
32-bit integer so that's all the bases
for risk five so
you can write software for this base isa
32-bit integer
uh and you'll be able to run that on a
in the future we have some like
10 core 128-bit risk 5 processor it'll
still be able to run this base isa which
is frozen
um but then there's lots of extensions
so this is the risk 5 32-bit integer
um and then there's a bunch of
extensions as well
so david pearson gave this talk and in
his pocket there
is what is called the green card so i
guess back in the day when people were
um
programming um machines with like you
know
terminals and teletypes and stuff like
that they would have these um cards that
showed all the instructions for the um
for the cpu so this is the risk five
equivalent of the green card
so you can see here this is just the
instructions for the base isa which is
the 32-bit integer
um and it's maybe like 20 30
instructions um
and then this is for all the current
extensions so we have
32-bit 64-bit 128-bit and then there's
like a
multiply and divide different versions
of
floating-point um compressed
instructions so
even putting all that together it's
still not still not that much it's not
overwhelming and it's
architected so that you can um just
choose the extensions that you need
for your use case
so um it was started at berkeley at a
team at berkeley
they now transitioned it where it's
being organized by
something called the risk fi foundation
so the standard
lives at risk5.org
they also have been growing a lot so i
think they have over 400 members now
which is companies and universities
you can also become an individual member
as well of the foundation
and one of the reasons to join for
companies and universities is they can
join these working groups where they're
setting these new extensions like one of
the things i think is in the works right
now is
vector extensions so in hypervisors and
so
these sorts of things are adding to the
base isa you can join the foundation and
get involved with
shaping those and companies like nvidia
is using the risc-5 as kind of like a
management controller they replace their
own
proprietary isa in their graphics card
not the gpu but
something that helps manage um the the
device
and then western digital is probably one
of the most heavily involved companies
and
they're replacing all the controllers in
their drives um to be based on risk five
um so in in the future nvidia and
western digital and other companies will
be shipping
millions of devices every year um with
risk five
processors in it um one of the things
companies companies can get when they do
this is
they don't have to pay licensing fees
for proprietary isas and proprietary
implementations
but more than that they get the freedom
to um
implement it as they want like i think
with arm you have to have an
architecture license if you want to
do substantial changes to the micro
architecture which i think only a few
companies have like
qualcomm and apple everyone else like
with beaglebone we use ti
um parts and i think ti just licenses
a specific core uh from arm so if you
want to
make more changes to like the micro
architecture you oftentimes can't do
that whereas with risk five you're free
to do that there's also a lot of open
source implementation so
boom and rocket from berkeley and uh
pulp is out of eth zurich
and swerve which i think is the western
digital one so there's a lot of open
source implementations also yesterday
there was a talk from uh
open piton um out of princeton um they
also have this uh
kind of one-to-many uh core design
capable of running linux um called open
pitons so
there's a lot of existing projects out
there that people can leverage
and there's this event i guess it used
to be called the risk five workshop i
think now it's called the risk five
summit but
these things happen like every six
months so if you're wondering what's the
latest and greatest that's happening
with risk five is you can
you can go to ris5.org and they just put
up the proceedings and the videos from
the one that they had in december
uh in california so if you go to the
risk five youtube channel
um there's tons and tons of talks on
there i think one of the one of the main
ways i've been able to kind of find out
what's happening in this
community is watching a lot of these
videos
so one of the other things i find
interesting is um
kind of the global sense of risk five um
and
one point is that the risk fight
foundation was based in the us they're
now moving to switzerland
and part of that is to be free of
political implications
um nations like india and i think also
pakistan have declared that risk five is
going to be their national architecture
and i think that
a lot of countries want to have more
control
over technology want to have more
sovereign control over process
architecture processor architecture so
um you know in this past year we saw the
us
prevent the us current presidential
administration prevent
u.s companies from doing business with
huawei and and
back at the beginning of last year it
was also uncertain if arm would be able
to do business with huawei
they ended up deciding it was okay
because arm's a uk-based technology
but you know i'm sure a lot of chinese
companies don't want to be
don't want to be in the position of not
being able to license
the cores that they need from arms so i
think there's a
lot of motivation for companies in
china and other nations to have more
control over the
processor technology and i think like
the
the biggest uptake in risk five
foundation
membership has come from china recently
uh i tried to kind of give an overview
the overview of this in a recent issue
of hackspace magazine
um just it's a short column but um if
you're just trying to get a sense of
what's going on risk five it's a
hopefully a good way to
in like a few minutes get up to speed
so the first time i saw a risk 5 chip
was
the open v which was a microcontroller
from a
group in colombia colombian university
they call themselves onship i think the
university's uis
but this was a 32-bit microcontroller
and it was a completely open source
implementation um they also did analog
which
was kind of unique about their project
is they're interested in the analog
peripherals
one of the other organizations that i've
been watching for a few years now is low
risk
so low risk is a not-for-profit
organization out of the uk
um and i like that their mission
statement when they started was they
wanted to create a
system on chip completely open source
that you could use to build a single
board computer
some of the people that started low risk
had been involved in raspberry pi so i
was really excited like ooh we'd get
like a
fully open source uh single birth
computer
most recently they've been working with
google on the security project called
open titan
but you can um
you can try out um their soc and run
linux on it so
there's a version 0.7 of the low risk
release right now and you can get a fpga
development board for
less than three hundred dollars and you
can actually run like a
little graphical uh linux environment on
it so
if you follow this tutorial i just found
out about this like on like two days ago
from someone here at fosdem so
i'm eager to go try this out myself um
so that's kind of like their long-term
vision i think is to have a you know an
soc that's produced in volume that you
could use to run
um linux on um alex bradbury is one of
the people involved in low risk and he
gave an interesting talk about
the ecosystem for operating systems in
the
tool support around it last year in the
summer
so one of the i'm so i'm part of the
open source hardware association
and kind of i would say the equivalent
to that to some degree is the
free and open source silicon initiative
for chip design so
they're a great organization they
organize several events throughout the
year so they have
or conf which happens every year here in
europe
which is stands for open risk conference
but there's a lot of risk five content
there now as well
um they started doing an event in the
u.s called latch up so last year was in
portland
and this april um it's going to be at
mit
and the us in last past year they also
did a week a week of open source
hardware uh
at eth zurich um so
they're a great place to find out like
what's going on with uh
beyond just risk five as well but with
um open source chip design
and they now run a website called libre
cores um which you might have firmly
heard of
as open core so this is kind of the
successor to that
the idea is to aggregate together um
processor design
so you know if you need to get a
controller for
spi or you need to find like a usb
controller you could potentially go on
libre course so they're trying to set up
a way for you to
have a place to go to if you want to
share your um
chip design ip and if you're looking for
something
you could potentially go on there and
find it
so some of the people that were at
berkeley that um created the
risk 5 isa originally went on to start a
company called sci-5
which some of you might have heard of i
think it was maybe two or three years
ago now they launched this
microcontroller called the
fe310 so this is kind of an arduino form
factor board that has the fe310 in it
so this is nice um it's interesting but
i really want to have a system i can run
linux on
so i was really excited here at fosdem
two years ago i think it was um that
palmer um
unveiled the sci-fi unleashed which is
their
64-bit um a quad-core 64-bit
um linux soc so there's a board called
the hi-five unleashed which is a pretty
exciting board
um it's open hardware um it is
unfortunately a thousand dollars because
they only made
a thousand of them i believe the idea
with this was to be something for like
early access for developers um so this
is one option that a lot of people are
using um that have access to it for
doing like
bring up of distros and tools and things
like that so
it's probably the highest performance
risk 5 board you can get right now
but it is expensive and only available
in limited quantities
so um fedora actually has a risk five um
a port as uh right now um and they've
been using
the uh unleash board um to
bring it up and also uh qamu so there
was this talk back in december at the
risk 5 summit
from one of the people involved in here
is them running
a gnome on the siphon of unleashed board
which requires a lot of hardware which
is probably not something
you would probably want to set up if you
weren't one of these companies that's
bringing up um you know something like
fedora but
um here's a you know an image of what it
might look like in a few years if you um
have a risk five system and you're
running a linux desktom on it um
so the sci-fi solution with the
unleash board in this fpga board that
does the graphics is quite expensive so
the thing that's much more accessible to
everyone is qemu so
you can with just your computer that you
have right now your x86 computer
um you can download qmu
and the fedora image you can run it on
your computer um which is the way a lot
of the work is being
done right now for people that are um
bringing up
risk five tool chains and distros and
things like that
so here's an example of booting the
fedora risk five so
if you have the sci-fi board then this
is the flow but not that many people do
so most people are just working with um
qemu so if you
want to get started right now you don't
have any hardware qemu with
fedora is one way to do it there is also
debian so debian also has a port
for risk five uh 64-bit as well so
you can either grab debian or fedora and
go ahead and start running it on your
system with um
qemu
now there is a microcontroller
or smaller processor from a company
called kendrite so
this is a really cheap um processor it's
a
dual core 64bit it's 400 megahertz
with eight megabytes of sram which is
pretty decent for like a microcontroller
and you can get like dev boards from a
bunch of places seed studio has one for
so like a really inexpensive risk 5
development board
now can you run linux on it so there's a
person at western digital
um damien who's been hacking away at it
and there's a couple of linux kernel
hackers that have been working on it
um with somewhat limited success so
damien gave a talk back at
linux plumbers in september um about
trying to run it so
one of the issues with this kendrick
chip is that um
it technically has an mmu but it's not
the right type of mmu so
you have to run it with with mmus and
memory management units so normally on
your computer
in most things that are running linux
you have a memory management unit and
if you don't have that you have to
kind of take a path that's atypical
so you need to have no mu support in
your libraries and linux and stuff like
that
linux now has that capability um in it
to run as m mode so with risk five
there's machine mode
in supervisor mode so machine mode is
just like we're just running with a
unified memory um view not with uh like
virtual memory and user space and kernel
space so
um right now
um they're still kind of hacking away on
it but if they're able to get it working
or if you're interested yourself you can
you can check out um
uh here's some links
so here's a screenshot of them booting
linux on that cyped board that's 13
but it only kind of gets to this point
um basically logging into busybox
um and one of the reasons is is without
item mmu you need um
i think it's ft pick support uh which is
an an arm way of dealing with the fact
that you don't have um
virtual memory um so
basically it's work in progress if
they're able to progress it farther
then we can probably start running risk
five on
really inexpensive sub twenty dollar
boards
um and playing around with it it only
has a megabyte of memory though so
how useful will it be i'm not sure but
for now qmu is probably the
the way to go um however coming up
in uh this year uh is three
processors that i'm i'm kind of excited
about from having watched some of these
uh
talks at the risk five summit so andy's
has a
processor that's coming out um that's
supposed to be linux capable
they're saying q1 of 2020 um microchip
firmly micro semi they have kind of what
would be the equivalent to the xilinx
zinc so this is going to be a
fpga with a hard risk 5 core
and that's called the polar fire soc and
i think they're talking about
second half of 2020 um and then the one
i'm most excited about
uh which i saw one of my friends tweet
about um at the risk five summit was
nxp is working with this organization
called the open hardware group
to produce a risk 5 imx style
soc so if you've heard of like the
freescale imx6 or imx8 they're pretty
popular for embedded linux systems
you see them in a lot of different
boards so i think the idea here is
something that has the peripherals that
you normally have an imx system
with a risk 5 core instead of a arm core
so this is supposed to be second half of
i think they announced it would be like
clocked at 1.5 gigahertz so
pretty hot pretty high performance
supposed to have a
gpu so if it's one of those levante gpus
that we have
the aetna viv open source drivers for
then i think this would be really
exciting
there's no information on pricing yet
but like this might be something that we
could actually build like an affordable
single bird computer with that would run
linux
yeah so by the way in these slides
there's links to all these different
articles if you want to check them out
um so one of the things i would love to
do is
um get a group of people together that
want to help
make a cheap linux capable
open source hardware board i think we
kind of have to wait for a chip like
this to come out
so if you're interested in get in touch
with me however we don't necessarily
have to wait for these socs because
there are also fpgas which is what i
have here so
this is a fpga um it's actually a badge
with an fpga on it and it can actually
run linux on risk five
um however this is not gonna be the same
performance as this
so with the fpgas we're talking about
maybe 50 megahertz 100 megahertz maybe
200 megahertz
so not the same performance that we have
in a soc so
one of the reasons i'm very excited
about fpgas now like i learned them in
school
a long time ago and it was all
proprietary ides and windows and i had
to run a vm and i didn't like it
we now have open source tools for
working with fpgas which is really
exciting so
um back at hackaday super conference
which this badge is from uh
prison from sci-fi megan wax gave an
interesting talk about
overview of risk five and fpgas so this
is another thing i recommend checking
out
um if you aren't familiar with an fpga
is it's a field programmable gateway so
it's basically a chip that has a bunch
of
gates in it um like for example this one
has 45 000 gates
and we can take those gates and
reconfigure them to implement whatever
digital logic we want
including a processor core so like this
one
has a um soft risk five processor that's
the
the fabric that c of gates has been
configured to be a
processor uh and then
the thing for me that has made this more
exciting is the fact that we now have
free and open source software tools to
do the synthesis and the place in route
and load it onto the fpga so this
started a few years ago
with a group of people most notably
claire wolf that
started building these tools for a
lattice fpga called the ice 40.
it's kind of a modest fpga um but
it was the first one that had like a
free and open source tool chain for it
and now
that referred to as generally as project
ice storm
and then this is actually an ecp 5 fpga
so it's much more capable
it can do things like hdmi um higher
throughput things like usb 3 i believe
as well
um so this was enabled by the work from
david shaw
um so one of the things they have to do
with both the ice 40
and the ecp 5 is document the bit stream
so that work was done in project trellis
so we can now use the ecp 5 with these
free software tools and hopefully
soon some xilinx parts as well so xilinx
is like
kind of the market leader in fpgas
and if we want to have higher performing
parts
the sorts of things we probably need if
we want to have like a more usable
lending system in a soft core
then the xylex parts are going to be
probably the best way to do that
so i'm told in the next couple months
you might be able to
use one of these xilinx boards with uh
the free and open source tools
um if you can find him tim
ansel is here at fosdem he's he's
pushing hard to try
and get um these tools working with
xilinx so um
he always has the latest information he
gave a talk at uh hackaday supercon back
in november
uh where it's kind of the status of
where this is all at
so this board i'm quite excited about is
called the orange crab
um it's from a person in australia greg
deville
it's a completely open source hardware
design um and he's managed to put
um the ecp5 fpg on there along with 120
128 megabytes of ddr memory um so it's a
nice little small board
that's uh actually can run linux quite
nicely we were
at the kiosk communication congress and
someone was like hey you should run
linux on it
and then like a few hours later greg and
tim hacking together they got they
brought up linux on it so
and i think linux boots in like 17
seconds on it so it's actually
um not too bad i'm i'm hoping that greg
will
do a crowdfunding campaign at some point
this year for it because
i think this would be a nice board for
people to get started with
there's also a board from a hackerspace
in croatia called the radiona
this one has sdram though so it's not
quite as
capable as the orange crab but this one
will be coming out
soon from crowd supply i think in the
next month or two
you'd be able to go and back this
campaign on crowd supply
and then david shaw who did the work on
project trellis which enabled us to use
these tool chains with the ecp five
he created this like ultimate board um i
think mostly for his own development
needs but this has like a
gigabyte of ddr memory ethernet pci all
these all these things on there
this is not available it's something you
can buy you can build one if you want i
think it's
probably a couple thousand dollars if
you want to build one but
if you're looking for like a high-end um
board for doing uh
using the ecp five free software tool
chain then this is probably the the
highest end one
one of the things i thought was
interesting was uh someone posted on
twitter um
that uh what does it look like when we
configure our fpga to be a linux capable
core so
we can see here like this is like the
mac review of the place and route
utility um
called next pnr so this is what it looks
like when we've configured all the gates
to implement a
risk 5 processor that's capable of
running linux
so this is the badge from the hackaday
super conference
it kind of isn't a game boy style form
factor
i think the primary intended thing was
for people to program
games and little graphics on it and walk
around with like your name in flames or
like tetris and things like that
so there was a graphics engine and see
that you could um write games on there's
tutorials about how to do this but
there was some of us at super con that
wanted to run linux on it so we were
like oh that's cool it can do all these
graphics but
let's see if it can boot linux um so
one of the issues with this was it only
had a hundred it only had 16 megabytes
of
uh sram it's not just it's external sram
over spi so it's quad
quad spy sram which it's not really that
great for um trying to run linux so
we banged our hands against it for for
like the first day
and didn't have any success um
and then uh turned out that someone had
showed up to super con
having already designed a dram add-in
board so
we were like oh we i think we really
need dram if we want to boot linux
and jacob was there and he's like oh i
designed this before i came
okay that's what we need so uh he had a
board here with
32 megabytes of sdram and that proved to
be um
enough for us to be able to get linux
running on it
so that one of the other things of this
badge was the idea was you'd have
cartridges so this is uh
one of the cartridges um there's other
ones like for
pmod connectors and different
peripherals so ideas you know
you could give someone a cartridge and
they plug it into their badge so
this one you plug it in and you get 32
megabytes of dram
uh so but how did we actually get a
system on chip into the fpga that was
capable of running linux
uh and the way we in in like a day
pretty much so
the way we did that was with lidex which
is a pretty interesting project um that
is leverages me gen which is a python
based language for doing chip design so
if you've heard of verilog or vhdl these
are hardware description languages that
people use to design
hardware that goes into chips or into
fpgas
so instead of using verilog or
vhdl you actually program in python so
it's python code that actually is
describing the hardware describing the
logic inside of the chip and then that
can be synthe
that produces something that goes into
the synth into the sense of synthesis
tool
so it allows us to basically do chip
design in python
which proved to be i think pretty
powerful because we were able to
um pretty quickly iterate on this and
bang away and get it working
lidex is kind of a combination of a few
things so there's mijan which is the
domain specific language based on python
and i'll show you a little a few
snippets of me jen in a bit so you get a
flavor for what it looks like
um and the other part of lidex is these
um ip blocks
so there's like a dram controller
ethernet controller pci express
controller sata
there's a few other ones there so these
are ip that you can go and grab
and tie together to build a system on
chip
for your fpga uh and then the thing
specifically that we use is this project
called lidax on linux
so this takes a risc-v cpu called the
vex risk
um which is a 32-bit um risk 5
cpu that's kind of designed to fit well
into an fpga
so they take that and they take some of
this um these ip like the like dram
controller
internet controller and it puts it all
together into an soc that you can load
into your fpga
so this is um linux booting on the um
vex risk uh risk five processor inside
of that uh
linux on uh vex linux on lidex festuris
uh
um yeah it's hard to say linux on lidex
risk v uh soc um
which we still don't have the display
working so yeah it's like
to me this was very exciting i guess
some people like graphics on the display
video games and stuff is more exciting
but we were very excited when we got uh
to see linux boot um over the the uart
um so after we got back from super con
you know we were hacking away trying to
get work on one person's laptop and then
i got home and i built the board
and then i was like okay i want to get
set up and it took a bit to like figure
out okay what is all the different stuff
that we changed when we were at the
conference
uh finally did that so there is now
upstream support in linux on lidex for
this hackaday badge
um which you know only people that are
at the conference has the badge but if
you want to
have a sense of what it is like to add a
new board to linux on litex
you can uh take a look at these pull
requests um
also just to give you a flavor for what
the um
uh lidex in in using uh me gen which is
python looks like so
this is uh basically the file that
defines the board so
the hackaday badge has badge and then
this is basically defining the different
pins that we have on the badge and how
they map to
uh signals inside of the fpga so you
know whereas you might otherwise do this
stuff in verilog or vhdl here we're
doing it in python
and we have the nice object-orientedness
of python where we can
import things in inherent classes and
things like that
um and then this is also just kind of
gives you gives you a
another sense of what's going on here so
we can you know we import things like
the
light x clocks and the light x
ram um and then we can basically kind of
just tell it the parameters that we have
for our thing
uh hopefully i have a screenshot in
it for for it as well uh
yeah so like we had to add our dram
module because it wasn't already in
there so we're using a
32 megabyte sdram module wasn't already
in lidex so
we just extended what was already there
and added a new class
where we say okay here's our timing so
you know from the data sheet
had to figure out the banks and the rows
and then basically the timing and then
it kind of uses all the existing
infrastructure inside of like dram so
kind of made it a minimal amount of
effort to have to bring up
a new dram chip uh
and then this is how we like add the
board into the build system
so um thing here is like it's pretty
basic if you look at some of the other
ones they have like many many many
different things that
is in the base soc so our soc right now
only does serial right now i'm trying
to get it to add in flash as well but so
it's a pretty basic uh
lidex on linux um soc um so we just have
serial there and then here is how we
actually load the um
the gateway which is produced out of our
um when we do the synthesis
so we just use dfu util which allows us
to load the gateway over usb into the
badge
so if you take a look at the linux on
lidax you can see what some of the other
boards look like some of them have a lot
more capabilities than
than this one and then
it was running really slow it would take
like 300 seconds to boot
which is annoying um so i hope this was
like a great like github moment or open
source
development moment uh where i was like
oh it's going really slow and i opened
up a
issue on the github repo and then like
that same day um
enjoy digital uh florent who's the
person behind lidex
goes by enjoy digital and he posted an
improvement and it
was going 10 times faster so i thought
that was a pretty good uh
pretty good open up git hip issue and
also it boots in 27 seconds instead of
300 seconds
also when i was doing this i discovered
this cool thing called ascii cinema
which maybe some of you have used before
but it allows you to record your
terminal
which was really useful so like i wanted
to show it was happening when the badge
was booting up so i would
run ascii terminal and record it and
then i could post the link in the github
issue
and you could see what was happening and
also
you know sometimes this doesn't boot
when i want to show people stuff
because the batteries are dead so i can
always just link people to the ascii
sending
video
and what specifically what he did was
interesting so and kind of shows you the
power of i think the
the me gen and the object-oriented
nature of of using python is
um one of the one of the optimizations
was it was having to go
to memory too often um because it's just
an 8-bit wide memory so
we were having all these expensive
memory accesses and it was slowing
things down so
he just made the l2 cache 128 bit and
that speeded it up tremendously
um and that might not be like a good
optimization for everyone so it's
something that you can play around with
and
and optimize it for your use case and i
played around with this number a few
times
putting up the 256 it shaved off like a
couple more seconds so
to me it was quite powerful i can just
go in there and change these values and
go and load it up and see how long it
takes and see if that improved it or not
so that's pretty much it um i can
hopefully show you what it looks like in
the terminal so
this is uh we're hooked over review art
here and um
what lightx does right now is it just
runs busybox
which if anyone's interested i think
would be interesting to do something
more
like maybe a debian bootstrap or
something like that so
um it's an area of active development
the other thing too is there's drivers
for the linux kernel like uart and
um the other peripherals that we have in
there um so if you're interested in
in those sorts of things if you check
out lidex on linux there's a lot of
opportunities for people to get involved
so let's log in to our system here so we
have uh
linux running on a risk 5 processor and
fpga
using all open source tools which is
pretty fun i think so
if anyone has any questions i'd be happy
to take them
yeah so i'll do this first and
then that one yeah it's absolutely
fantastic thank you i mean i too have
been waiting
since i was at uni to be able to play
with this stuff i started out with
the black ice mx um phonologies yeah
yeah um and i've got zephyr going on top
of saxon so
i need to have a slide for that yeah so
cool uh
yeah so you know and again totally open
down to the gates so
i want to be able to put together
securable iot solutions that are just
completely open
in this way yeah so the next step is is
to try to follow
you know what you're doing here putting
linux onto these boards yeah um
which is very exciting and i i've you
know taken down some of the
examples of boards to get going with and
in commercial terms
if we're trying to manufacture boards um
obviously we can go out and get asics
it's really exciting to see that nxp are
coming out with the risk five yeah
we do a lot of work with that um talking
to my colleague who does the hardware
side of things
he's a bit sniffy about all this you
know because he says well fpgas they're
expensive you know how do we make this
stuff cheap how do we make it viable
i really want to see completely custom
calls with standard soft cores in them
and then some custom magic to do
acceleration and sort of build our own
open cores in that way
i've heard that there's libra silicon
which is a project yeah
kind of small scale basic manufacturing
yeah and i'm wondering if you know
anything about the economics of how this
is going to be possible
to drive down costs like open silicon
cores that we can put together
yeah so the question was about um
open silicon and the idea of pushing
this down and getting things
manufactured for cheaper
um so i learned some more int about that
yesterday i think um
there was a uh a talk or actually i ran
into the person that
does a thing called chips for makers
where he's trying to produce his own
soc um and he's trying to push down the
cost by like grouping things together
so there's the chips from makers i also
saw some of the libre silicon stuff so
there's a group actually called libre
silicon
um and they're trying to have
like an open source fab technique so
they i think they're working in a fab in
hong kong trying to like
bring down the cross so uh there's the
libra silicon people and they're also
trying to create like these cell
libraries
i think the downside to that is it's a
pretty old
technology process so
the one thing i have heard of that may
maybe will help at least in terms of not
having to pay for software tools is
yesterday in the open piton talk
um in the cad tools room they were
talking about
having a chip eda tools that are open
source now so there's a project called
open roads
um out of i think uc san diego
and they're creating like an open source
tool flow for doing chip design
um so at least maybe that'll eliminate
some of the cost of having to pay for
these expensive proprietary tools
um though i think
most of that is still going through tsmc
so
the library silicon people always i know
they're trying to like do their own
fab technology um but it is like older
processes um so yeah
and the other thing too just i should
mention is sax so i was talking a lot
about light x on linux there's another
project called saxon sock
s-a-x-o-n-s-o-c
um so that's another option for running
uh risk five
linux on risk five and fpgas as well
yeah so what can you tell us about the
open source hardware summit badge
uh i have the pcb somewhere so this is
sadly not linux
we're using a nordic microcontroller but
it's going to be a wristwatch
style form factor badge so we were
inspired by the
badge from camp this year at kiosk
communications camp called the cardio
um so the idea is a wristwatch form
factor badge running circuit python
yes not risk five but um uh hopefully
people have fun with that uh
yes yes so if people are interested in
risk 5 microcontrollers there's a
company called giga devices that has a
really inexpensive
um risk 5 microcontroller so i think
it's like kilobytes of memory so you're
not going to run like linux on it but
you could run a real-time operating
system on it and they're they're quite
cheap
and they think uh did they also have the
as they match the stm peripherals or
okay so they also have the sdm 32
peripherals so basically the things
you're used to on sdm 32 but with a risk
5 core as well
from giga devices
just want to point out and right now for
my job i play around with the ecp 5 a
bit
so like the evil board you get one for
80 euros like the easy
ecp 5 eva board and also
like an interesting alternative for dram
it would be like hyper ram
it's just a dram with a
interfaces with 13 io pins
so you have it's kind of like option spi
or something
so the the hyper ram would be at least
better than the uh quads 5
uh sram dram or your ddr memory that
takes
up like 60 70 ios yeah it's quite easy
to implement
and it goes like up to 330
megabits uh bandwidth okay
for protocol for reading and writing
because it's not in the same lines they
do i o
so how how would hyper ram compare to uh
ddr memory
okay cool yeah and what was the board
that was eighty dollars
that board okay from lattice
modules that you can buy from some
manufacturers so that might be
the option to put something together for
yeah yeah so maybe with this lattice
uh board from lattice with the hyper ram
we could maybe get linux on lidex
working with it or something like that
if you don't get one of those yeah
yes yeah cool
all right cool all right thank you
you