his
leadership integrity compassion and
dynamism played a huge role
in sustaining and building the zen
project community
lars's foresight was invaluable he had a
clear view of trends
and any future difficulties he was
highly respected by those who knew him
if lars said something was important it
would be done
on a personal level lars was frank open
funny and generally great to be around
he will be
deeply missed i'd also like to read out
a short
tribute from george dunlap one of my
last colleagues
lars invested a lot of personal energy
in the success of the zen project
lars had a gift for communicating across
boundaries
once he wrote some slides to train one
of our participant companies
on how to effectively engage in open
source
he sent them to our team for feedback
and almost all we could say
is wow these slides are amazing
his work on effective communication
guidelines part of the code of conduct
currently in the
zen project approval process distill
down a decade
of work of open source experience
i expect them to become a useful
resource for many open source projects
he was a tireless peacekeeper who tried
to listen and give everyone
and help everyone understand one another
bridging gaps
and giving feedback george says i could
trust lars's sense of what would be
politically wise or unwise to say
far more than my own i'll miss the way
that lars always panic the week before
the submission deadline for zen summit
because so few talks have been submitted
we always ended up with more talks than
we could accept
i'll miss him hearing him say that
somebody or something is driving me nuts
or him
explain oh but you see this is how this
works
so uh thank you um maybe there are some
other people here want to say something
to
me yeah
yes i guess i just wanted to add that um
uh okay i guess i may just wanted to add
that um
doing this for lars here at fosdem in
particular
is very weird and very sad
because fosdem i mean i was um
i'm a former colleague of arts we were
colleagues at citrix until i was working
for surgery myself
then i changed job and
fosdem was one of the event where since
i was working for
from home so frozen was one of the
events where we see each other
and it was
i remember it very well that it was
because of lars
that some nine or ten years ago
the same project actually started to uh
invest
in fosdem and push to have a boost who
she pushed us
developers to submit thoughts to the dev
room
come stay at the booth and interact with
the fosdem crowd and actually staying
there at the booth with him was really
quite an experience and so it's
particularly
i don't know touch into remembering here
and yeah also as a personal level he was
a very good friend
he helped me again at a personal level
without it being necessary
only because he just it was
like how it is and so yeah i will
miss him very very much
well then it's really hard to find the
right words because
uh in fact last helped me to make my
first
talk at fosdem back maybe in 2013
and he was a great somehow mentor but
also
someone able to to push you to do stuff
uh
if if he thinks that matters then he
will have his support
and also he helped us to integrate
the linux foundation recently and that's
because he decided to to do that that
was possible
and without him uh all the projects
i started won't be there today so uh
and on a personal level uh it's also
really sad because
he was really a nice guy also a friend
and well at this time i'm happy to
to to have shared some moments with
wells last because it was really
really fun and i remember his love
yeah and well it's it's a bit hard to to
express all the feelings
but anyway uh um i i think um
it's the right time to say goodbye
goodbye and
farewell
[Applause]
you