yeah i'm richard
uh limits distribution engineer at souza
which is like the most generic job title
anywhere it's like you know
human planet earth um
and yeah i'm gonna be talking about some
of the stuff i'm not going to be talking
about a distribution for like my first
time of first time ever instead i'm
talking about a nice
library living underneath but starting
with that
who is responsible for the for the
configuration of a machine
once it's deployed you know
not leonard pottering although you know
if you want to point fingers you can
you know you know is it the distribution
is it the upstream
um who actually don't get a mention here
um or or is it the user
um you know from speaking from a
distribution perspective
you know i i honestly believe you know
distributions have a hand in making sure
the configuration
of the operating system once it's
deployed is right and sensible you know
we we
should be making sure the defaults are
sensible and good out of the xbox
experience you know
secure you know whatever sensible means
really i mean it's you know open to
interpretation different distributions
have different interpretations
and of course different upstreams have
different interpretations too
um and you know sometimes we don't agree
with what upstream have decided of the
defaults
but also upstreams always do interesting
new stuff and that interesting new stuff
often requires new configuration
parameters to be set or you know the
sensible defaults change and somehow we
need to get that to our users
but at the same time you know some users
believe
the mix is about choice or at least
there's definitely the choice they have
to you know potentially ruin their
system
you know and they want to configure
their configuration the way they want it
um and that means you know potentially
having
unsensible choices or at least you know
weird ones that make no sense to us
and they're not necessarily going to be
paying attention to all of the stuff
going on in the distribution
in those upstreams so they're not
necessarily going to know that this
default needs
changing this new feature has some nice
new flag you know just like the system
detox we knew
we just had with all those wonderful
different flags you can put into your
system do unit files
you know that you know right now if a
lot of services a lot of demons you know
that's
a bit of a mindset and sort of the
typical
classical problem is you know
distributions
put up got a package we've got some
service called food there's a conflict
file in epc
the user edits that and sets it up the
way they like it and then a new version
of who comes along
and we want to change the you know we
want to change the defaults we want to
introduce the new parameters
you know or we you know there's been
some horrific cve and we desperately
have to make sure that there isn't that
setting
set by default and whatever happens
there's some
you know horrific or semi-horrific
explosion there is no
perfect solution to this problem at the
moment no matter how we look at it
you know you can notify users on wikis
and stuff but they don't read it and it
doesn't work
you know or if you're trying to find a
technical solution you know most of us
as packages
try something like some fancy post
script where we're you know
editing with said and just praying we've
got our regular expressions right
and then we get it wrong and the users
scream and file bugs saying the distro
broke our conflict
um more conservatively you know certain
packaging tools
are you know especially rpm and sort of
arch you know we have these sort of
nice helpers where you know we can in
the packaging tool
back up the user config install our new
user config
and you know leave their old config as
an rpm save file
and then the user doesn't bother
noticing that and they file a bug saying
you know the distro broke our config
or we flip it the other way around and
we're paranoid and
never touch the user's configuration and
we put our new settings in an rpm new
file
and then nobody ever looks at it and
then they file a bug and we just turn
around and say sorry your setup isn't
supported
um yeah it doesn't work at all at the
moment
it's it's the hell we've all been living
doing destroys for so long
and the hell's getting worse um because
you know
this lovely new trend of atomic
distributions like with open season
micros
where this problem gets even more
complicated because like in micro
s we have a read only root file system
you know a user can't modify that root
fs once it's there
but we want them to be able to modify
etc because you know they need to be
able to change the settings
um so but when we need some way of
atomically delivering those new
configuration settings that we
need on there without messing around
with that conflict so
you know it yeah it has all of the
issues plus more because
we yeah we can't just mess around on the
root file system
like we used to and
when we were dealing with some of these
issues that cropped up with what we're
doing in micros
you know we realized there's there's one
really configuration heavy service
sitting on all of our micros machines
which
doesn't give us any problems at all and
it's wonderful and life is great
and it's systemd it kind of shocked me a
little bit when i realized it but yeah
you know system d solves this problem
really really nicely you know it has
this lovely structure of everything's a
unit file
and those unit files live in one of two
places
you know the distribution config is
meant to live in usr lib system d system
and that's where all your unit files
live your timers your services blah blah
blah blah
and then for your user config every
change they make
is in etc systemd system and then the
two worlds are separated
and we don't have to worry about that
you know we don't touch etc system d
system we just touch usr
and all is good it gets even better
because with systemd services you also
have
this concept of drop-ins well like a per
service basis you get a
you know food.service.d folder and you
can put little drop-in configuration
files in there
those drop-in configuration files can
individually
override individual lines or parameters
of the the other config file elsewhere
so you know
and it's even that is layered so you can
have you know
usr drop-ins and etc drop-ins and system
v figures out what the right priority is
and applies the right one
which is like what we're using with like
kubernetes now you know you've got
you know container runtimes and
kubernetes and
all these other distro dependent stuff
and they all want to modify
each of the services so us you know in
our on and open to the cubic at least
you know our usr lib drop-ins you know
we have drop-ins after drop-ins after
drop-ins
and then users can put their own
drop-ins in and then you eventually get
the right config at the end
so it's great when you've got the sort
of multiple layering
um and we realized well this is cool for
you know systemd services why can't we
do it for like everything else
um which of course you know is gonna
need some work so let's try and make it
easy for people
um and so uh pascal an apprentice
at uh souza last year this like this
entire project is like not even a year
old
um uh yes that basically started writing
a c library to kind of
first as an experiment does he can we
even do this
and then like all good experiments it's
got completely out of hand
um for basically providing to anybody
using this library
api calls and functions to be able to
be able to do the same kind of
configuration layer in their services in
their applications
um it's an mit license so you can use it
for everything
and the two main use cases are literally
you know both
layering sort of an entire config file
like the typical system
d service thing of usr versus etc
or if you really want to be fancy during
sort of
foo dot d and and yeah drop ins and
layering those two things
on top of each other like i said not
even a year old
so not even if this is its first frost
time it could ever be at because it was
26th of april last year we started it um
um but yeah we're using it in plenty
places it's not magic
you know start with start with the
negative you know
you need to modify software to have lib
ecom support
you know we're not magically taking over
other bits of services
and in its current form it only supports
sort of any style configuration files
where
you've got a group you've got a key with
a value you've got another key with the
value
um it's flexible in the sense of you
know you can have whatever delimiter
and white spaces you you want um but you
know we
at the moment we're only working with
these kind of configuration files which
which
form this structure i'm not going to
give like detailed code examples
and you know the api list is getting
longer and longer but at its core is
sort of
eight or so core api calls which kind of
do all of the work
ecom for read file reads a configuration
file
takes all those key values and you know
dumps them in a key file for
use elsewhere in the application reader
basically does that
so but for multiple configuration files
in a directory so you know that's what
you would use for the kind of
food.service.d equivalent
there's a function for enumerating the
groups in there which you know can be
handy when you're looking for that one
config file nested
the one config nested in one group
somewhere down the line
get the keys and then we have a whole
bunch of
get value of various types that you can
you know grab your strings and
make sure it's all type saying and grab
grab your right long intent
get the the correct value of the correct
type you expect as you go along
um that's all the reading on the writing
side of things
thanks um we've got a bunch of
setters for doing the same in reverse so
you can
set your configuration back in there
we've got a tool for merging files you
can actually just yeah two stroke files
merge everything together
job done and all of those api calls are
up
stable versions you know we're not going
to break them at all
we promise write file on the other hand
for writing out this to a configuration
file
we've got people using it but it's it's
not yet stable it's
it's you know because you know we're not
entirely happy with how it's writing or
handling things like
the file already being open already
being edited
um but it's there if you want to write
the file back at the desk
in open season land like i say this is
all kind of gone out of hand but in a
fun
exciting way um open souza is moving
towards
using usr for all of its district
conflict that's the goal
it's going to take years but we're
moving in that direction
as fast as we can so we want etc to be
considered
user data and you know treated with the
same reverence and avoidance as
slash home or slash slv you know we
don't want to be messing in our users
sad but that's
etc should be theirs we don't want our
packages touching it
we don't want our scripts touching it we
don't want to be responsible for
breaking anything anymore
um so you know in the case of like
systemd it's already using usr but for
the
the stuff that doesn't we're now
starting to use usr etc
and basically moving our configuration
to that
in the case of le become the b cop
doesn't care about these locations
it's all variables so you know you could
use it how you want to put it where you
want
so this can handle you know user lib
whatever
or use etc whatever it doesn't matter
but
for us we're finding it's easier to move
things along to that because it's
a one-to-one mapping of user etc
whatever to edc whatever
makes makes the logic a bit simpler for
us
there's a number of examples where we've
already got applications moving across
to it
like pam pam upstream has lib ecom
support since
three or four months ago i think now um
so
if in open source we've already packaged
up with this um
so user etc pam d has all of your pam
configs
then user config can be an etc pam d
both get passed at one time and etc
values always fun
nice simple done
the same for shadow also update is also
upstream
which of course they're also using pam
so it also has their conflict in pam d
so it's fun that when they're all
sharing the same thing and
using the same library but you've also
got login devs and i just realized the
type
that's meant to be user etc login depth
but yeah the login desks are stored
there etc login deaths
you know can be overridden by users the
etc values always run that's all done at
one time
and all of the youtube linux stuff this
is not yet upstream i think it's
submitted but there's some
discussions about our patch but we've
patched it in opensuse so all of the
sue login remote et cetera and opensuse
are using this and
using it exactly the same way but
there's exceptions so reboot manager
which is the
the tool in micro os which basically
uh detects when there is an update
pending well there has been an update
applied and there is therefore a reboot
pending and required to be done
that configuration is really simple
there's like it's one group there's like
four parameters it it
there's no point doing all this
complicated nesting and layering
so in that case you've just got a nice
simple straightforward config file
and you can put another nice simple
straightforward config file in etc
and we just merge both of them at one
time and we we use that
unstable write file to just dump it in
etc reboot manager conf
and so all the logic in the code for
actually reading the configuration file
hasn't changed at all we're still
reading the same config file but yeah
libby comp is doing a little bit of
magic before that
to move things along um
and yeah we want as many other projects
to start adopting this using it in their
own way we haven't
yet uh done this where you know you must
follow a certain sort of system d like
or or
you know pam like approach well you know
you have to use the same topic you know
we realize upstreams have their own way
of you know upstream applications that
have their way of doing configuration we
want to make this as easy as possible to
fit in
so you've got the primitives here where
you can take libby conf
make our life easier and make your life
easier hopefully
but you don't have to rewrite your
entire logic of you know how you're
consuming your configuration in your
application
we are thinking of adding more high
level api calls for
people who just want to make things even
simpler for them in the long run
but before that oh
we have some yeah concrete plans
you know passing config files is hard
and you know our password isn't perfect
so i've been looking at using a thanks a
much more established configuration file
parser um as
you know instead of writing our own and
constantly tweaking our own
um so august is on our radar um i have
some patches that are roughly working
and you know i'm slowly
patching it into all of the api calls um
it does a very good job technically
speaking you know it's very
it's very reliable it handles far more
variations of configuration files than
just any
it also handles those ini files more
gracefully especially those weird ones
with weird delimiters and weird white
space walls and all that stuff yeah
august has figured that all out already
the downside is though
you know it does make the dependency
tree for
for libby coffee you know a little bit
heavier than just the nice simple c
library that you can plop on and
put into everything um and the code is
getting a little bit more complex
so this this isn't certain i want to
kind of
get feedback from anyone here and see if
there's any other options out there
or help doing this you know if people
think this is a great idea
um but yeah it's a sort of work in
progress and
the direction we'd like to go because we
realized that just doing any files
is is somewhat limiting for this idea um
and
dominic is dominic here nope dominic
another one of my apprentices he's
working on
uh ecom for tool which is a basically
aimed to be sort of a generic helper
tool
for the idea being you know an
application's
started using libby conf that now means
you've got configuration files in usr
configuration files and etc
how does the user know what parameters
are actually being applied when
how the e-commerce sort of generic help
of you know
taking that default logic you know you
so you know like ideas like yeah eat
control pam d what your config is
done you know give a list out there and
a bit like system cto
with like system cto edits you know be
able to edit the config and it'll
put the right snippets in the right
place and make your life a little bit
easier
um this is just the beginning if people
like this idea you know there's obvious
things we
you know we could do to improve you know
different file paths have been
being the one that i've already
mentioned but also language bindings not
everything is written in c
um so sadly um especially when it comes
to go
um but yes if people want go if people
want private and if people want us you
know this you know
this needs to be something used in as
many places as we can
you know we're not just gonna start here
stay here
but we can't do everything alone so you
know if you like this idea
the code is open it's mit contributions
are welcome
changes are welcome features are welcome
um you know please help enjoy start
using it
start putting it in your distro that's
why i'm here basically
um and with that i think i've managed to
squeeze this into
20 minutes or so so there is just a bit
of type of questions at the end
yes sir the first one you had
was something like that yeah
this is the whole idea that it reads all
the files and all the drop-ins and does
the
magic behind the scene or yeah so so
why is the read file just a read a
singular file yeah
um that's because there are definitely
cases where you just have one config
file
for the cases where you have multiple in
a directory that's why we have the
readers config
the reader's api call and readers just
you know reads the directory
and read files all of the contents of
that directory does the programmer
have to go through i understand the idea
is that the user and there's the etc and
then the drop-downs
[Music]
the application developer who is
patching libby com support into that
application has to do that
so the user doesn't but you know libby
conf is there to be consumed
yeah so at the moment yes you know we
are planning on adding
you know higher level api calls which
you know have opinionated views on how
you do that matching and merging which
will make their life easier you know
that's
you know oh wait after this
under user etc
and there's something under abc4 and i
have to order
and yeah but
like the the reboot manager example is
kind of like in my simple one you know
it's one config file so you know the
config file now lives in two places you
merge it
it's yeah not everybody has complicated
stuff like pam
yeah absolutely yeah
yeah we will look at that thank you cool
yep
do you handle uh most conflicts
um no we do not handle merge conflicts
you know so the moment with with the
covenant calls we have
you know the you know we've got you know
with that merge files for example you
know you're declaring one is going to
override the other so
you know by how you order it and you
know there's no there's no magic there
um so for the more complicated stuff you
know you could use those primitives to
do fancy stuff
with with handling mode conflicts but
yeah
no um is there a standardized and simple
way to
display all the physical files
there's no standardized and simple way
of displaying the config the all the
config files you know that's kind of
what
the uh ecom cto or ecomfort tool sorry
we was called you compute a week ago
uh ecom tool is looking at doing it sort
of giving us giving you a sort of
standard way of doing that
yes
i have a feeling that it doesn't really
make sense
to port libby com systemd to use libby
conf you know they're doing it fine
but we wouldn't really have anything
there yeah another question about it
no this is this is all completely fresh
no no reason code no
sorry just repeat the question the
question was yeah um uh
did we reuse any assistant code with us
at the moment it's just it's just etf
yeah it's
a bit basic at the moment yeah it's a
bit naive at the moment we admit that
uh most of them are in this slide i
think i might have missed one or two but
you know this is kind of
kind of where we are after a year so so
the question was how many upstreams have
we patched um
um so the most of them have been
like the the question was what do they
think um
most of it has been like surprisingly
wow this is cool great merchant done
like
like so youtube linux has been like the
only one where there's been sort of
questions feedback like improvements
juggling around
there has to be like here's a patch find
done in
um of course in the case of ruby manager
you know we are the upstream so
that yeah we cheated but
yeah next question yes
um how would the distribution ship a
change to the default in the case of
like movie manager we were writing it
out
yeah we wouldn't um you know it's you
know it's
in the case of ruby management because
we're the upstream as well we know we're
like
probably never going to do that and if
we do let the conflict feel simple
enough so
we'll still hack around it the
old-fashioned way
which you know it's a rod for our own
back you know we'll do it properly one
time
um but you know in that case it's mainly
for adding new configuration files
because reboot manager is
is you know in a kind of similar state
of development relatively new moving
relatively quickly so
they're just using libreconf makes our
life way easier for adding that new
thing
out to existing systems um plus also
with reboot manager being like a really
like
that's definitely something where you
don't want to mess with what the user's
already decided
you know they've got their policy for
how they want their system rebooting and
that like those core parameters are
basically that right now
so the chances are even if we change the
default we're not going to change the
default time your system is booting
you've picked it you're running it you
know it's it's done dusted
you would you would hate us if you
suddenly your machine's not gonna be
rooting at the long time you prevent
tooling every distribution to move to
like this system
in the way that you compare what the
distribution will provide how the user
modified
and then to move like only the diff to
the
user stuff and the system yeah default
yeah so the question is do we provide
any uh any tooling to kind of help
people move to this
this approach um we don't e-commerce
will do some of that for users
because you know you'll have that there
where e-computer will be showing this is
coming from
the the distro usr this is this is what
you've got in etc
so this is what the the runtime uses um
we could look at you know adding that or
working on that for making sort of the
transition easier
but we have found because we're going to
this you know every upstream app is is
different
they've implemented their configuration
differently they're consuming it
differently across
their entire code base and we're not
trying to
force everybody to doing everything
exactly the same way you know so this is
sort of trying to be that middle ground
if it's flexible enough that you can
patch it in
so your comfort could be split and
layered but you don't have to
you know don't have to do everything
exactly the same way
time's up i'm sorry but we'll be outside
so we can catch you later thank you very
[Applause]
much