so um
can everybody hear me great um
my name is julius varuva i am software
engineer at red hat
and i'm going to talk about a ring
and how we integrated it in chemo
so uh first we're going to discuss iring
ap
and uh how cool is it and what's new
inside
and then something about
kimu and
what's inside
so this is iopath
in virtual machine we can see that a lot
of stuff is going on
um so io pass from user space
uh to kernel and you need to choose some
uh asynchronous io there
and then um it connected
to chemo using um
with your blog driver and
then
we can finally pass through our io
request
to kernel so what's now existing in kimo
we can use uh linux io
but it's not really good because it's
not true as in
we can use thread pulls we can use nvme
passthrough which works well great but
it's not migratable
and spdk is hard to manage and
um so what we can do
we now we know that
we have this path um from kimo user
space to hardware
and we can now improve it because we we
have a
new iou ring api
instead of existing linux ion
what is the taiyo ring it is a new
truly asynchronous interface which
which was created for blog devices but
now it's it can do everything it can uh
just a good interface to pass
pass messages to the kernel as in an
asynchronous way
so uh you can pass network
also and do other syscalls for example
and you can change six syscalls for
example if you have
asynchronous open and in a synchronous
read
you can make that uh read will
go after open and
this all way will be asynchronous so
that's cool
and it's part of linux 5.0 or that's one
um so it's new so uh if we use it in
chemo we need to
make sure that we're on the newest
kernel
what's inside a urine um
if you remember in linux io we have
events and we have
we submitted um into a single queue
and now we have two separate queue for
submission and completion
and their memory they are shared between
user space and kernel
so you can use it directly you don't
need to enter kernel that
and you can use asynchronous flash which
is not available in linux io
and because of that we needed to
switch back in chemo to
synchronous flash and this work that
doesn't work good
so for my to remind you submission is
when
[Music]
it's from user space to hardware and
completion is backwards
so basically a ring is three system
calls
it's iron setup
when you can manage we can you choose
different regimes
and you can um all from
submission sites or completion sites
you form your submission
queue and form your completion queue
and do enter this call
what cool is that you submit
submit requests simultaneously with
fetching completion cues so you don't
need
two syscalls for that and
a great feature is a file descriptor
register so you don't need to
do i've got and have put on
each submission and completion
so just register a set of files and then
refer to
indexing index and array
and you can register first
this is not a great improvement but
since we in such
heavy workloads such improvements helps
how fast is it well
it is quite good it is better than linux
io but not
entirely great
so uh you can see information with
which i test i use uh feel
and nvme ssm
so if iu ring is so cool um
then let's integrate in key mode and
that's how uh stefan heinrich came up
with our twitchy idea
and our mentor our sri mata implemented
it
and basic function is actually merged
upstream
and it will be in chemo50
with some problem existed yeah
how we integrated it we use the same
that's
linux io actually implemented uh
we have chemo event loop it's based on
io context
um we just add
io context in the pool and use file
descriptor
to pull completion check and so this is
how we can
submit requests segment submits requests
with enter
and check completion on irq
we also have a use libya ring
and i can recommend
much uh to use it because it's really
helpful
uh it's easy to use but now we are tied
to
libyan versions
launching is very simple you just remove
your you you put
instead of your native or thread are you
uring
and this is how it works it works with
uh
i o direct and cache too so we can do it
yes and you can see that
even without extra features
it can do good you can take a look at
base
what we can do next we can uh implement
some registration
so uh when we have
our io in um
in chemo um if if we know that it is
entered from
different uh file descriptor we just
register it
and that's how we can save some time
um yes it is improved a little
it doesn't really help much but
one thing of it it is really helpful
when it comes to submission polling
what is the mission polling you need you
can
run a kernel thread to wait for
submissions
uh you need to wake up it with a special
syscall
but if you have a heavy workload you
don't kernel um
kernel thread just don't sleep you don't
need to wake up with
so it's really helpful and
of course when we uh submit when we
pull submissions from kernel threads we
always uh check of these and
that's how objective registration helps
yes and now we submit requests
without syscall and get completions on
irq
you see that we don't have
any syscalls at all if you have a very
heavy workload
what can we do next uh we can pull
completions
from from uh to site we can you
we can do user space completions um this
is a feature
in chemo itself instead of uh
using ipol uh we can do
we can do manual polling sometimes and
it could be good but it doesn't it just
doesn't work
the feature in
the future in uh iring itself is
completion polling
we just we just paul um
we just submit um cisco i don't enter
and it's busy waiting it is just
falling completions and we're just
waiting for it
and
you can see that it uses extra cpu but
this is the fastest way so we
we have a threads that pull submissions
we have
we are pulling completions and
we don't have any extra
context change
yeah it's not implemented this is uh
this is what we need to do
yes what we need to do is
merge submission polling
and file registration it is implemented
but it needs to be merged
we need to implement file buffer
registration and io poll it is difficult
with iopo
takes some time and we can probably
switch
to our ring as default io if it's simple
but if it's supported by the kernel as
we know it's
needs to be it's it's a
decently recent kernel yes and
the final idea that was
that was suggested uh is switching main
pool to irene
so um you know that we use
um linux io context
in in key main pool we can switch it to
our urine context
but this is this is a lot of work
i'm not sure if if we can gain some
performance of it
but we can try and take a look
yeah uh i guess that's it that's a quick
presentation
[Applause]
any questions yeah so the way i
understand
iou ring it basically is a more linda
specific
way of implementing details right
different protocol different things
you have good like that less less curvy
restrictions but it basically is
right i mean
like i was wondering could we literally
just expose iou into the gas
with a couple of restrictions so that
they can directly issue calls
i'm not sure if it's possible it's
really
um yeah so the question was uh
it's not really a question
we have big hosts and a urine is some
sort of
big host but from the kernel side can we
take this to the chemo directly
to the guest sorry to the guests
directly
so well it's not supported
uh in linux
sorry
well probably we can god well
i don't have you have something to add
um yeah so today today it's not
possible to do that but there is someone
who's working
to see if that helps yeah so the
question was about v
host and um uh it would be possible
to expose the the the rings that julia
described to the guest
and there is someone who's working on it
so we'll see they'll send patches and
we'll see what happens
any more questions
no okay thank you
thank you
you