hello everyone I guess I can start now
at a 1405 so my name is Chi Kang I'm a
software engineer at Red Hat primarily
on Mission Control and flight recorder
and along with me he's not actually here
is Marcus art director of engineering at
datavac he's the lead of Mission Control
originally we were planning to do a talk
together but unfortunately couldn't make
it
however a lot of content here is
contributed from Marcus so I've included
him so yeah today James G and J F are
kind of in brackets 20/20 vision
looking ahead so on the agenda I'll just
give a brief introduction to JMC and JFR
what they are and I'll talk about
development updates in the past year too
as well as the roadmap for the coming
year I guess and then a nice demo of
Mission Control in the cloud so yet
James T and J far for those of you who
have haven't heard of it before J far is
the JDK flight recorder it's events
based JVM tech for production time
profiling and diagnostics while JM c
stands for JDK Mission Control and it's
a desktop application for jerax browsing
as well as JFR visualization and
analysis so JDK flight recorder it's a
low overhead recording its compact
subscribing data in the JFR file format
it's extensible and you can kind of
think of it as analogous to a fly
recorder in an airplane
Mission Control again desktop
application provides two main features
you can connect to JVMs and browse gmx
related data and then more importantly
though it has a huge amount of tools for
visualization and analysis of the flight
recording files so JDK Mission Control
really depends heavily
GFI the third thing along with that
though is JMC project does have core
libraries for parsing and analyzing JFR
data and they are available for
third-party use so if you're looking at
using JDK flight recorder and you want
to analyze or visualize in ways that JMC
doesn't currently have you can easily
develop your own tools using the core
libraries yeah so looking at the tool
chain for flight quarter in general
there's three main parts first is
controlling JFR you can do that through
CLI Poggio jmx etc so you can start and
stop flight recordings of a JVM
application you can ask it to be dumped
on exit you can set the max memory size
that JFR is going to take etc then you
can add data to JFR so there's API for
that
JMC provides an agent that I'll go touch
upon briefly for a dynamic injection of
jeffer events and then of course you can
have your own integrations as well so
JFR does come with a lot of pre-built
information inside the JVM itself but
for an application you may have specific
application data that you want to also
record and you can use the flight
recorder system that's in the JVM to do
that and then at the end of the day of
course the whole reason we're doing this
is to use the data to find problems in
our in our application to try to solve
performance bottlenecks etc so that's
where Mission Control comes in there's
also a GFI utility tool that's provided
by the JDK that you can use on command
line and then you can also build your
own third-party applications to analyze
letter equipments so if we just look at
a general workflow you run your JVM with
JFR enabled various configuration
options that will output a JFR file that
you will need to store somewhere
probably not in the production system
and then eventually you get that jr4
file maybe on to your local desktop and
you analyze the data with Mission
Control or with other tools
so you have mini demo just quickly
showing Mission Control in use so on the
command line I've started Mission
Control from the github repo targeting
JK 11 that opens up this interface so
it's desktop application on the left
side we have our JVM browser so
currently on my laptop
the only ajv I'm running is Mission
Control itself we open up up we can
connect to the ambient server so this
shows live data of various basic things
CPU usage cheat memory etc has triggers
so you could trigger like if CPU usage
goes too high I want a flight recording
dumps things like that so it's it's got
some neat tools in there you could
diagnose the command but of course the
most interesting part is I think the
flight recorder section so over here we
can see that for Mission Control it's
already having it already has a
continuous recording which started as
soon as the JVM launched so if I double
click that I can choose to dump the last
5 minutes for example this outputs a JFR
file and then we get to all of the the
tools that JMC comes with for analyzing
that data so just to cover a few the
automated analysis results is pretty
neat so it will analyze all of the
events in the JFR file and there are
specific rules that are written to read
specific events to try and score them
and provide useful info and on maybe
there's an issue here that you should
look at it cetera so that's being
constantly developed there's various
pages here like the threads you can look
at all the threads that are that we're
running and their states over time it's
pretty neat there's a huge amount of
pages I won't go through all of them but
that's basically Mission Control yeah
demoed so development updates before I
go into this hopefully you've all heard
Oracle open source Mission Control and
flight recorder about two years ago now
I think in 2018 may ish timeline and so
that's even the reason why I'm here
working on Mission Control on flight
recorder so since that time one of the
biggest updates last 2 months ago maybe
now I don't know what time flies is the
jamesy project is now on github via
SCARA so the contribution process can be
started with a simple pull request which
is pretty neat there's a lot of tools
and BOTS around there too so the
development process of Mission Control
is very much open from the floor but
going into actual development updates so
Oracle did open source Mission Control
in 2018 and then in June of 2019 which
is now last year the very first open
source release of JMC was tagged 7.0 and
then following that in December which is
last month or 2 months ago it's February
now 7.1 data was tagged so if anyone's
wondering what happened to Mission
Control after open surah Oracle open
source it it is continue it is it does
have an active community we are
developing new features for it and are
looking to improve it in into the future
as well so some of the features in 7.1
doto are more optimizations of the rules
so the automated analysis that I showed
a little earlier it does have some
issues when dealing with multiple
gigabyte sized
JFR files trying to get to analyze all
the events etc like that so that's an
ongoing thing actually the J overflow of
you so there is a view that JMC comes
with for heap dump analysis that's
converted from using Java effects to SWT
now so you no longer need to also have
Java
tax on your system to use that and then
we also have two new views on the flame
graph which is pretty cool actually and
then each chart histogram so yeah of
course there's a huge number of bug
fixes and stuff like that as you'll see
um just to try it oh I just realized I
probably should a click present so it's
full screen but anyways so a project
commits since the initial open-sourcing
to 7.0 they were actually 128 commits
7.0 to 7.1 399 and the github project
itself when I created this slide had 238
commits so it's definitely actively
being worked on and there's a lot of
features we want we want to add as well
distribution wise adopt open JDK has
provided binaries for download actually
for the time being these are snapshot
versions so the latest in the repository
and I have heard from the developers
there that they are going to do release
binaries as well in the future
Oracle of course does have binaries as
well as long as it clips update site
unfortunately they have yet to do the
7.1 dot or release but hopefully you'll
see that into the next few months and
then Red Hat has rpms for fedora and rel
so if you are using for Doral you can
DNF where young install those yeah and
then there are a few other distributions
like Azul has their mission control but
basically they're at the moment all the
same which i think is good yeah so a
quick slide on contributing the
repository is on github there's a
mailing list we have slack which is
pretty active then our bug tracker is
the the JDK open JDK JIRA instance and
as well a little plug for Marcus's JMC
tutorial if you are looking to learn how
to use JMC to analyze various problems
Marcus did procreate
a quite decent set of problems like
dealing with memory leaks or hot methods
etc and how you would see that using JFR
and using GMC so you can always try that
out
so yeah moving on to the road map what's
up in the future before I talk about J
and C's road map there is one thing I do
want to share regarding JFR and so
Arkell did open-source GFR and JMC for
open JDK 11 plus but the community it
has worked on putting GFR into open JDK
8 and so the CSR was finalized and
closed in December the remaining to do
is just to merge it into mainline and
Mario actually started the thread for
that in January a week ago maybe so yeah
once that's accepted we're gonna see JFR
in open JDK 8 which will be awesome so
yeah back to JMC though the road map is
Mission Control 8 so this is our early
access splash screen but it's going to
be a major release so there will be
breaking changes if anyone uses the core
API for example and it's going to target
open JDK 15 so 15 releases if there's no
delays in September 2020 and so you will
see JMC 8 a few months afterwards as we
make sure that it actually works on open
JDK 15 so what are what's what are we
adding to 8/3 keep things here James C
agent rules update and then core library
updates I'll go into each of these
so the JMC agent is actually a quite
neat tool it's for dynamic insertion of
JRR events at runtime so as I said
earlier you can extend your own events
into the JFR system but that does
requires like writing annotations etc in
the code and then obviously recompiling
redeploying so the of course you can do
bike
instrumentation with other tools to do
this as well but the JMC agent will be
designed ground up for insertion of GFR
events at runtime so if you wanted to
modify your application without having
to rewrite the code we recompile
redeploy you can do that it's optimized
for the job so hopefully we will see
that as part of the JMC distribution in
a thought oh yeah and technically the
code is already in upstream repository
and it's being developed on there so if
if you are interested there are a lot of
open issues for that too and then rules
2.0
again mainly the automated analysis
section there's going to be improvements
for performance there's going to be a
redesign of the rules in general so that
they can be reused the idea from the
developer was like you could use rule
rule a results and rule B and those can
be used in rule C etc and build up rules
in a more organized fashion than than
what they are now and there'll be more
typed information in the rule itself so
that you we can more easily visualize
the rule results and then for whatever
reason some of them have HTML and
they're not gonna have that in the
future and then going into the core API
so this is the API that JMC also
provides to third-party applications
mainly to do with reading in JFR files
managing the flight recorder system of
JVMs or discovering jaebeum's in general
so a lot of these features are extremely
useful for third-party applications and
and JMC 8 we're going to be updating it
to use JDK 8 language features and
previously it was 7 so this isn't to do
with compatibility between JFR and your
open JDK version this is just the actual
code of the API will compile on 8 plus
and run on 8 plus because we're going to
be using JDK 8 language features and
more thing
from the application will be moved into
core to be reused by third-party
applications because they are useful
yeah and so some more features in terms
of I guess the visual aspect of JMC
we're gonna have new sectors
visualizations we're gonna have
improvements to the thread graph the
flame graph is already being updated as
we speak but there's gonna be a large
amount of improvements there and then
this is something Marcus has like a
prototype for on his own repo but
visualizations of stack traces with
various graphing tools so the image is
just an example of method profile events
in a graph format so yeah moving on to
the demo portion JFR management in
openshift with container JFR so before i
jump into the demo i do want to give a
little bit of context so this is like a
huge diagram explaining how the demo is
set up and what's going on which i will
show again but the basis behind this is
this new project called container JFR
that my team's been working on it's
under the github org alright CMC team
and the whole idea is just to make it
easier for users to control flight
recorder on JVMs that are in containers
whether it's docker kubernetes openshift
etc so the features are pretty simple
you can start and stop recordings you
can archive recording so you can
download them you can view automated
analysis immediately without opening
your desktop application you can view
events available for the specific JVM
and this is all able to be manipulated
via web UI or command-line tool and then
we also are looking into various
integrations with things like griffin o
of Prometheus etc but those are more
like experimental so they might
disappear so but the idea is all this
stuff you can do now but doing it with
je viens and containers or je viens
running on orchestration platforms like
openshift is not necessarily the
the easiest thing to set up and the idea
here is running this project alongside
your your deployment you can do that
without any extra work so jiff container
jeffires made up of four core components
each of them are their own repository
there's the main container GFI which
contains the management service
including the API for kubernetes and
OpenShift there's the core which has
core libraries for JFR management so the
idea here is technically if you wanted
to write your own stuff you could extend
off our core library which contains like
useful features for dealing with likes
for example JVM discovery in openshift
or kubernetes or something there's a web
front-end just to give a web UI to
easily do things and then there's
operator project so I'm not sure how
familiar everyone is with how kubernetes
and openshift work but they have this
operator concept to help deployment of
things and so we do provide an operator
where it's basically becomes like a
one-click operation you click subscribe
and then everything is started and
automatic automated and managed by
OpenShift
or kubernetes and then along with that
we there's the side project JFR
datasource and it provides a data source
for graph ana for JFR files so if you
have a JFR file you can you can upload
it into this data source and then you
could view any time series or related
data in Griffin ah and then finally for
the demo
there is also an incorporation of Iger
which is end-to-end distributed tracing
for your applications so if you're
deploying like four or five different
micro services that are HTTP based and
they're requesting across networks to
each other you can build a map of what's
happening using distributed tracing so
yeah going back to the diagram the setup
is basically this micro service called
the robot shop which consists of an
order service a customer service and a
factory service so users can
come in and request an order for a robot
that goes into the order service which
tells the factory that it needs to build
a robot and then tells the customer
service that they have a customer who
needs like the database to be updated
with their order etc and so eventually a
robot gets built and then gets sent back
to the user and so these are three
different Java applications that are
running basically HTTP servers there
that are going to be deployed in
openshift and then on the side we have a
Jager operator below which manages an
instance of Jager and the services are
all and implemented to to work with
Jager for distributed tracing so they'll
be sending traces to to the Jager
instance as well we'll have the
container JFR operator deployed so
there's one of those per project and
that will manage a single container JFR
instance which contains the web UI
container JFR the data source and
Agrafena instance and that will be able
to connect to any of the applications
that are running for retrieving flight
recordings from them so you'll see as
well
it's more of an implementation detail
but the operator will be running flight
recorder instances resources per
application in the project which is used
for management purposes it's not too
important so yeah we can jump into the
demo so there is a portion that's
internet related but the Internet's of
its body so I might skip it oh yeah in
the project I created in in openshift
cluster on my local machine I called it
Fossum 2020 if we go into the operators
I've installed the Jaeger operator as
well as a container JFR operator and
then the Jaeger operator itself installs
the elasticsearch off
though I don't technically use it if we
look at the deployments I have a
container for operator Jaeger fantastic
search and the Seeger instance so when
it comes to to setting up container
Jerry fired the basics behind it is you
install the operator through through the
operator hub and then once you've
installed it you you simply go into the
project that you want an instance of and
you click create instance and then you
hit in the spec minimal either true or
false
so that will decide if you want to
deploy the web UI and related tools or
not so if you want the web UI you put in
minimum or false and then you just hit
create and then from there everything
else is is automatically set up by the
system and and you're done
so once you have that up and running I
already have an instance called
container tray fire and I just created
the example instance but if we go into
our route section this stuff it's
automatically created so there are
exposed HTTP endpoints for container JFR
so I can visit that now so this one just
opens up our working problem
work-in-progress web UI and so this is
where you can through UI look at the JVM
s that are running in this openshift
project so going back to the cluster if
we look at the deployment coffee this is
actually where I've deployed the robot
shop with poorly named means so RCS is
the customer service our FS is factory
service and RLS is the order service so
these are the deployments that
correspond to the micro services I
showed earlier so here we can connect to
the target je viens at the moment it
basically just shows their their
hostname and then the port so down below
here is the RCS
it's the IRFs sports and our OS ports
for the micro services so on these
applications I have exposed for our GM X
connections 1991 so for example in this
RCS 1991 I can connect to it and then
the basic UI is you can create
recordings can set a snapshot time what
events the name etc and then once you
have a recording for example this one
which is continuously running you can
view a summary which will load the
automated analysis reports in the in the
web UI you can choose to download it you
can save it into the archive which works
with persistent persistent storage for
open shift and then that's basically
getting your JFR files outs out of your
out of your cluster ok so as far as the
demo is concerned we have three micro
services that are running and I'm gonna
submit an order to them from my local
machine so I have this load application
I'm just gonna run yeah so the load
application will target those three
services which expose HTTP routes
hopefully this works and so you can see
here it's it has pretty extensive
logging but in general it's ordering
three robots to be created and then
delivered to the user so if we go back
here we can open up
Jagr and see we do have this services
and their traces so like you can find
that and then with distributed tracing
we'd get a overlook of exactly what
occurred in the HTTP
work so request was made to order
validated user and then there's three
build robot requests so it built a robot
three times and there's pickup etc as
well we can go into dependencies and
look at the directed Silla graph and
just see in our setup of services when
the request came in the order service
made 10 requests the factory service and
also one request the customer service so
it just shows you the connections
between your your micro services and
then back to the trace so given a trace
there is quite a bit of information you
can see for example here in the creating
chastity it was of type T 800 and it
took 469 milliseconds to do that whereas
when it was creating this Wally robot it
took 670 milliseconds and then you can
see across a whole request how long it
took to point four seconds here at three
seconds etc so you do get a neat
overview of what's going on at a little
higher level in your application but
when you when you're trying to diagnose
issues or potential performance problems
you do need a little more and that's
where in combination with something like
JFR you can solve a lot so in this
scenario with this is obviously a dummy
project there are a few problems coded
into it for example in the creating
chassis x' you can see here when i was
creating the wally robot for whatever
reason it took 670 milliseconds whereas
when I was doing coffee it was only 272
it's a huge difference if you know a
little bit about your own application
maybe this is an unexpected result these
two robots should take a similar amount
of time so from here though you can't
get much more than than the information
it shows right like so why did it take
more time and that's where I'm gonna go
in now with JFR so this was in
factory service so I'm gonna get a
recording of that back to the web UI I'm
going to target the factory service
it says port it has a continuous
recording enabled so I'm just going to
download that to my system so with with
your click it's now on my own machine
and then going back to Mission Control
now I can open that up real quickly in
the Downloads factory service dachi FR
so yeah on the get go for the factory
servers there isn't too much and
automated announce results unfortunately
so you do have to go digging a little
deeper so one thing I can look at in
this case I know it's the creating
jassi's and in this process when it
creates a robot it uses a thread pool
system so I can look at the that the set
of threads in this case the factory line
and see what's going on so if I then
zoom in to that I can see here the
execution of these threads and what they
were stated their state was so actually
in my demo
I sent the request quite a while ago so
some of the information isn't around and
the reason for that is it's a continuous
recording which I've set to only keep
128 megabytes of space so the recording
won't contain events from the lifetime
of the JVM if it's lasting for a long
time but that's a configuration option
but in any case we can still see some
interesting information here we're in
the scope of building a robot a huge
portion of time was spent blocked and so
there's obviously a concurrency problem
here going on because I can make
hopefully decent assumption that it was
blocked because of something else like
the other factory line
right because this so the blue is it's
it's sleeping and then here it's blocked
and then this is I think active but so
if I actually click into the block
section go and look at the stack trace
portion I can see that in its block
states
oops down here it was in the paint robot
which was then in in in the logger so I
have a little bit of code now that I can
go back to my project code and say maybe
I'll go look into this logging of ok
robot or logging of create jassi's and
see what's happening there so if I go
and open up my code editor now and the
project so I'm just gonna search me
chassis so in the chassis code there is
a span dollar for tracing purposes and
then there's a logger call right here
and then the sleep it's supposed to
simulate building each a sees which is
supposed to be constant time so um
because the the secretary showed that it
was sleeping in logger I'm I'm gonna
check the logger out now coño logger
Java will see that Marcus decided to
make this synchronized static void
message which is terrible for logging
purposes because we have for factory
lines that are trying to make robots and
they're gonna all hit the slogging
synchronize thing and get blocked so
we'd have to work that out so this is
just a quick example of how you can take
distributed tracing and JFR together to
get a deeper look at problems in your in
your code yeah and so going back to the
open shift set up just for some clarity
in terms of your JVM application
apart from deploying container JFR the
only thing you now need to do for JVM
application
in a container is exposed a connection
for container to fire in this case we do
support IgM X so if we look at our
deployment configs and the environment
variables we'll see there's a Java op
section that I set up and in this Java
ops I'm going to make it bigger yeah
okay that was too big I exposed
9091 obviously on a non production
system without authentication and then
these are the settings for flight
recorder to be continuous so yeah in
general territory far the idea is to
make getting JFR files out of je viens
and containers as easy as possible and
yeah the other neat thing to hear while
in there is just for example in an
orchestration system there's concept of
internal external networks so normally
when you do a JMX connection you want it
to be secure because if you're opening a
port in in the system than anyone could
maybe exercise and do something
malicious but with internal external
networks the port is actually in the set
up I have only on an internal OpenShift
network so only OpenShift services with
the correct privileges are able to
access it so you get the security there
for free so theoretically this stuff
isn't exposed as long as open Chiffre
with their code correctly yeah so going
back to the slides here
again that was the demo demo for JFR
management and open shipping container
and finally I'd like to end off again
with contributing to J and C we have a
repo meaning it cetera we're pretty
active there's a huge amount of issues
in a variety of areas so you can work on
and yeah thank you so I guess I have
some time if anyone has questions uh
sure in the center so that's something
oh yeah so the question was if the GMC
core libraries will ever be published on
maven central so that one actually
became a little complicated because
Oracle had plans to publish it into Sona
type and so they started the process and
they got the permissions and the admin
rights and then they stopped and I don't
know where they went but they have the
admin rights to the name for the core
libraries and everything so we have to
discuss that but in general we do want
them to be on mute and central so people
can easily get them into their maven
projects for the time being adopt open
JDK actually publishes to a a repository
the core libraries so you can pull that
from your maven projects you just need
to add an external repo yeah
any other questions sure back
thanks Andrew thank you um regarding the
container JFR what's the deployment
model like is it like a sight card
that's injected into every JVM and since
it sees no is it like a Damon's head or
so how does this scale I mean just okay
yeah so the question was what's the
deployment method of container JFR and
how it interacts the JVM s that it's
trying to monitor it is not a agent it's
not an agent that you inject into the
JVM itself or into the the pod that's
running the JVM it at the moment solely
relies on connection protocols for
example our gmx or JD p to connect to je
viens that are running so the general
process is for an application developer
you deploy your JVM you expose our gmx
and then you're done container JFR runs
on the side as long as it has access to
the same network it will see that a 9091
port is exposed and then be able to
connect to it and go from there so so
the discovery at the moment is is pretty
dumb it discovers it tries to discover
everything but we we're trying to
fine-tune it for example you could add
an environment variable or something
this is specific to kubernetes or
openshift but to specify that this is a
JVM that's exposing a connection for you
and then so will connect directly bad
but
yeah so Prometheus is Apple based system
so compared to Prometheus Oh so the
question here was how does this compare
to prometheus is discovery protocol and
so Prometheus for those that don't know
works on a primarily pull based system
where the aged the running application
exposes a base basic web service that
prometheus connects to and poles from
repeatedly and how Prometheus discovers
these is through service tags and things
like that so we will have a similar
system for kubernetes and OpenShift
where you can apply it in an open ship
for example they have this concept of
labels which you can apply to an
application deployment and then we can
read those labels and and see that oh
that's far label so we should check that
out but otherwise at the moment the
discovery protocol is within the
OpenShift networking system or
kubernetes networking system where we as
a deployment in the same project have
access to the network and we can see all
of the things running on that network
and so we don't actually need your
application to specify anything
technically what's that help any other
questions yeah I think you should
probably take those outside we need to
have time to turn around the room for
the next speaker thank you very much
[Applause]
you