hey
thanks everybody uh thank you for coming
i'm gonna do something a little
different this year in the past i've
done a lot of uh
state of the union with keycad this year
i'm just going to ask if you want to
keep track what's going on with key cad
go out and look at the version 6 road
map
works in progress now so we've been
working on that i want to talk a little
bit about
i've been kind of musing in my mind
about
how key cad's role has helped the open
hardware movement and
where we're going with that in order to
do that we've got to go all the way back
to the beginning of the open source
heart
software movement and see how that
progressed and i think what you'll
notice is for i look around i don't see
a lot of people in this room older than
i am
so there's probably a lot of you won't
remember
some of us you know where we started
with the open source software movement
you're going to see a lot of
similarities in the open source hardware
movement
even though it's much much earlier stage
of that so
in the beginning before there was
anything that resembled a personal
computer people worked on mainframes and
everybody sat
terminals and it was connected the
mainframe and the only time you worked
on software was
when you were connected to that
mainframe so software development back
then was the only people that worked on
software
software collaboratively were people who
either worked for the government
uh universities or large large
corporations like ibm so
but it was pretty obvious even back then
in the very early days of computing that
software copyrights were coming so the
big companies lobbied the major
uh governments in in 1964 cop software
copyrights were recognized in the us and
pretty much everybody else
follow the rest of the world followed
suit pretty quickly okay
so there was kind of a lull there while
they were still sorting out
the microprocessor world so the small
8-bit micros
that were in design between the early
60s
into the early to mid 70s it took a
while so
there wasn't really any software
development open to the what you would
call the general public
right by the end of the 70s the pc was
starting to
take root so these startup companies of
uh
apple and the ibm at least their pc in
this area right
so early really early in this movement
only only enthusiasts went out and
bought computers for personal use right
nobody else had them they weren't on
everybody's desktop
everybody's now they're in everybody's
pocket so
there was a lot of sharing of code early
on people would say hey look at this
thing i made and
they'd there would be like these
conferences like this where
got you know people who were writing
software for computers would meet up and
share ideas
but it didn't last very long because
this grew so fast that people realized
that well there's money
there's not just money to be making made
selling software for mainframes there's
money to be made for selling software on
personal computers um
so the that rushered in the dark ages
basically
once the sharing stopped all the
licenses went proprietary there was
there was
no longer any concept of open source
software at all
um they were restrictive proprietary
you've we've all seen those licenses
before
they've been around for you know decades
early on even commercial software
quality was not
what it is i mean today i thought if
you've never used
if you're never part of this and having
to live with because you lived with this
because
software distribution was by me some
media hard media like
there was no internet it was either a
floppy disk or some other
you know that was how software got
distributed
so bugs persisted until you upgraded to
the next version right so you had to buy
the next version upgrade to get the bugs
fixed but then there was always some new
bugs
that came with the new features right
some of the things that also happened
during this time that was not
very nice was work working applications
were purposely broken for competitive
advantage
i won't call anybody out but if you know
the history of that you know who did
do did those kinds of things and
basically if you were a user a software
user like
like i was during this time you kind of
felt like you kind of felt like
that you were just an afterthought you
know it didn't feel like they had your
best interest at heart
so what happened is a large group of
professional programmers were kind of
getting frustrated
with this whole idea of proprietary
software
and so in 1980
the bsd released the first what we now
know what we now know as the first
truly open source license right and mit
followed uh
not long after that um in the mid 80s
so most of this was done at the
university level most of the
open source software was done by uh
educators and
and um their the staff right
but there was a couple of big time
projects during this period that were
um because because of the permission of
permissiveness of these licenses
they were the pro there were two
projects that comes
to mind bsd sockets and kerb ross and
they were hijacked
and then you know the point of those two
projects was to
unify things right we were going to
bring everybody together right well they
were
broken for competitive advantage and so
a group group of people realized that
these licenses were
not necessarily the spirit of these
licenses
was always to to make your code freely
available but it didn't
specify that so later in the 80s
the new project was formed and they
released the first
version of the gpl right and so that
opened up the
the foundation so the gnu project worked
on all the core tools compilers
librarians they basically
had clean room versions of all the unix
tools that
people had used in back in the days
right
and what helped what helped um spur that
was
the internet right the early internet
even the good old dial up days of 19.2 k
and your your phone line would scream at
you when you you know you logged on to
it
it was a way for people to collaborate
and things started to grow pretty
quickly at this point
okay so now things were so we still lack
the kernel so in 1991 some guy from
finland created a kernel under the
under the gpl2 okay
and that that really spurred development
things really took off at this point so
within a couple of years by the mid 90s
there were
probably a dozen packaged distros of
of linux so you had red hat and debian
and mandrake and
susie and so there was a whole bunch of
them so you didn't even need to
do any compiling anymore you could
download install and and
run linux and this is when i got in
i'm sorry just i'd like to move around
this is this is when i started getting
involved in key
in in open source development and at the
same time
right around this same time there's some
guy a professor
named jean-pierre scherra that worked at
a university in
france started working on a project
called keycad okay so
that's how old key keycad goes back to
the very very you know just when
the whole open source thing was really
starting to take off
what really changed the tide was
high-speed internet access once
high-speed internet
net access became readily available the
effective cost of distributing the
software went to zero
right so now open source was really
development was kind of in full swing at
this point
um by the late 2000s
the small form factor devices and
smartphone industry
it was everywhere now you could you
couldn't hardly use a device without
touching open source software you may
not have known that you were using it
but you were using it
so at this point floss won
you know we basically it's there's not
any
debate here about whether or not floss
was the dominant
development model for software right
but also during this time we started to
see hardware design tools
um key cad projects start when even
though it was always public it was never
really publicly developed and we
that that was happened in the in the
late 2000s group groups of people
started actually working on key cad to
collaborate and improve it
okay
so also during this time
there was some move so now we had some
tools and they weren't
super powerful compared to the
commercial hardware development tools
but we had them
so we were starting to see some growth
in
the idea of open hardware because people
wanted
the same arguments for open source
software you could almost make for open
source heart or open hardware
you know it's freely available you can
learn you can extend it
there's lots of good reasons to do that
right
so what happened here was
the cern released their open hardware
license in 2011 and they also
joined the keycad project because one of
their thing one of their mandates is is
their
intellectual property is part they want
to be public and they realize that if
they were going to use a proprietary
piece of software
well how open was it it technically
their hardware designs were open
practically
less so okay so that's why they joined
and
started to help make key cad functional
so
during this time that it's it's pretty
obvious from some of the talks that open
source design tools are
increasing in power usability um
in some cases they're um
approaching a lot of commercial products
so as you see there's an interesting
thing here that
recently board vendors have been
supporting key cad board files directly
you don't have to go through the
processing step
of you know generating gerbers and the
old the way we've done it for
you know 40 years now so obviously we're
having some influence there
in in in the hardware space because
people would otherwise because if
there wasn't enough reason to do so they
wouldn't so that's
that's kind of where we are at the the
moment so
what also happened at the same time
which was really interesting and i
honestly didn't see that one coming was
risk 5 development so we now have
an open in the last few years risk 5
has been implemented by quite a few
people so this is an open
um taped out part and a design for
people to build upon
right that i think that's the i don't
think you can undercut the significance
of how important that is because
you know we're getting open heart we're
getting open boards and open electronic
circuits designs but
we really don't there's still things we
don't know about our electronics right
that's all hidden from us and if you
like in
the past the hardware was always kind of
approached as well it's a black box
you just have to trust that it works but
given the last few years like
with things like spectre and meltdown we
now know that our black boxes might have
problems
and so one of the things i'd like to see
happen is dye level development tools
start to be
opened and moved moved in and moved into
like
key cad for development so now
i'm not naive enough to believe that the
hardware will quite be the same way as
the software because
obviously the cost will never be zero
for hardware there's always going to be
some cost
involved but well one of the questions i
have is
well will the will the stack from top to
bottom ever be fully open
and i i don't see the reason why it
can't be i mean there was going to be
resistance just like there was
resistance to open source software back
in
when it was developed so so
the only thing that's left is is will
the cost of that
determine how the rate of um open
open hardware and you can see like it's
we've all so you think about 1980 as the
first open source
license software license that was 40
years ago
we're there right it's only been nine
years since we've had an open hardware
license a true open hardware license
that
where will we be in 30 more years from
now in the same time frame
will the entire stack be open i hope so
because and i think
key cad plays a prominent role in that
as we'll continue to try to
increase the the debt the breadth of
things you can do it with open tools
over time and uh that's one of our goals
so whenever you can use an open design
use it it sends a message to
the people who aren't open that you
would you prefer open because that's
what happened with the open source
software
basically the message was if we can use
open and it suits our needs well that's
where we're going to go
and so peop vendors notice that kind of
you know
when their business starts going away so
if you can use open please do
okay now i a lot of things if for those
of you who don't follow the project
closely
this is just a quick uh year in review
since last
um fosdem right after fosm last year we
released 5.1 this the stable release
i got hired to work full-time on key cad
yay
well that's a that's there's another
side of that story um
we had the first ever key cad conference
in chicago
in april last year and if you didn't
make that you missed a great con
a great conference probably one of the
best i've ever been to so
if you have a chance to make it this
year i highly recommend you you make it
and i'll talk a little bit more about
that later um
key cad services corporation was formed
this year one of the dings against key
cad was well i can't get paid support
for key cad well now you can there's
commercial so if you're if you're if
you're a corporate user and you just got
to pick up a phone
and call somebody you can do that now
there's and in the in the fair in
fairness of
open disclos or disclosure i work for
key cad source
it was it was formed by seth and i
thankfully he invited me to
be part of that and in october with the
company that
promised me that we were going to make
t-cad flag
dropped me so so boo
so that didn't last long enough to get
anything significant done
really it was a kind of a bummer um the
other thing that happened in november of
last year we joined the linux foundation
and now what that means is we have a
two-prong
uh set up for um donations
the the cern donations will continue as
they always have but one of the reasons
we joined linux foundation is cern has
pretty strict rules about how we can
spend that money so really for software
development
the linux foundation allows us to do
things like expense
pay our developers to go give talks so
that's the linux foundation gives us a
lot more flexibility how we spend our
money it's not
just software development so if you are
interested in donating to links through
the linux foundation
you can just find the links there and in
the
my presentation so i joined tcad
services in december
we also moved another big thing that
happened we moved from
launch pad to gitlab at least just the
source for now eventually
we're going to try to migrate the whole
project there because there's a bunch of
stuff at github
right now but i'm really happy this move
has worked out really well i'm surprised
how easy it was and how much
will really i think it's going to help
development our workflow just a lot
better
um yesterday we had the first ever new
kick head
developers meeting so there was about
what 10
15 people who aren't regular key cad
developers
and three of us three of the lead
development team were there and we
worked
we introduced them to the code base and
helped them work through some pet bugs
that they were
interested in fixing so that's
significant because it's always nice to
be able to
you know bring in new talent into the
project and you know because the keycard
code base is pretty intimidating so it's
not
it's not something that you'd probably
want to take up on your own
now a couple announcements keycon 2020.
if you missed last year's you definitely
want to make this year's it's going to
be at cern in geneva switzerland
from september 11th through september
13th the tickets haven't gone on sale
yet but keep an eye on either the blog
post on the keycad website
or you can go i have the link right now
it's just it's just a
placeholder image file there's no
information
but i suspect the tickets will probably
go pretty quickly to this one so if you
if you're
if you're in europe in in september and
going to going to cern to to talk about
all things key cad sounds interesting to
you
please please come to that conference um
the other thing is happening is monday
and tuesday and wednesday of next week
uh the folks at eisler and i'm going to
butcher this
did i say it right
okay we're going up the the
there's quite a few members of the lead
development team here we're going to go
up for a hackathon for three days and
work on key cad so it's we get a chance
to
it's rare when we all get a chance to
sit down and work together it's usually
email and that whole process is less
than
ideal um so and just an announcement
about we've already
i put an initial goal i had no idea what
to really put down so i put 40k down for
one year at
linux foundation we're already about a
third of the way there since
november so the donations are good i
thank you for
all the time and so just what i always
it always i always say thank you to the
development team because
i get to stand up here and people know
my name by the fact that i'm the project
leader but
i'm just one guy of many it's a big team
of people
that writes write source code develop
libraries documentation
translations package builders the whole
nine yard
i mean there's probably what 50 80
people
combined it takes the tool you know
contributing their own little
in their own little special way to make
the project work
i always thank to say thanks to our
donors it's
it keeps key cad um going and it and it
helps
it attracts interest to um other people
who
might be interested in developing kicad
it definitely is a plus
we we i always say thanks for that um
thank you for your interest in key cad
um we're going to continue to do our
best to get to provide the best possible
electronics design application that we
can
and i i don't see us slowing down
anytime soon it's just going to keep
growing and growing and growing it's
getting it's getting more feature rich
it's getting more impressive every year
the things you
can do with keycap these days are your
there's very few limits
i mean it's not a it's not a stripped
down four-layer
board layout package it's a 27-layer
800-pin fpga monster board layout one of
one of our users who's like our
performance test guy because he's got
some incredibly complex designs
so kikai can handle something like that
you're probably not there's i don't know
too many people doing board designs that
are more complex than that
and a special thanks to seth in javier's
absence seth stepped up and did the dev
room so
thanks to seth for stepping up and and
helping out there so
thank you
all right remember
us sitting in this bar in april and jeff
was totally excited about all that stuff
and
now i'm well yeah there are some
questions in my mind whether
[Music]
if you mean the relationship between
between myself and jeff know it wasn't
that it was
i mean i i'm not i'm not at liberty to
talk about it
because it's not it's i signed an nda
so i can't talk about anything with
company wise
but it was not my decision it was
it was based on other other factors
you could probably guess if you were
there that night you could probably
guess what happened so
i'm just going to leave it at that
please say something about version 6. i
knew somebody was going to ask him
they say something about version six
that's not really a question but we'll
i'll say something about version six um
things are starting to roll into the
master branch now
i'm working on the new file formats for
the symbol libraries and the schematic
and so that should be done here
hopefully not too distant future
because there's a lot of features new
features that kind of
sit on top of that but uh there's a lot
of work going on there's
some configuration work that's going to
change we're going to start
one of the things i heard somebody
earlier complain about that you know
that when you know that we we used to
say we currently save like some of the
the uh the visibility states of the
layers in the board file so when you
change them even though you didn't
change the board the board
file changes we're ripping all that out
we're taking that out so that
that'll be a separate config file so we
got somebody working on that
um so there's a lot of things happening
i mean it's
key features curved traces
groups and rooms uh whatever
yep pad stacks we have a map we have a
layer manager now that you
that's already done that's been in there
for a while that you can you know set
layer color
you can set the the all the definitions
of
um between layers so there's a layer
stack up editor now you can you can
assign it a color or
a silkscreen color mask color uh the
thickness between each each um copper
layer
so yeah there's uh there's that what
else are we working on anybody what am i
missing guys
well 2581 export will be in there um
somebody's actually working on an altium
importer right whether that'll be ready
for
whether that'll be ready for six or nine
i i can't say but i mean it's
sitting right there where is here
is he oh oh there he is ah yeah so
who knows you know um
i'm sorry the bus apology stuff that's
that's all right
john's bus work oh yeah that's right the
there's um
there's real time net list management so
the net list will be updated real time
as you make
changes so that was done yeah sorry
sorry john um but yeah it's nice because
we have the bus unfolding now that
if it's a feature if you you know you
create a like a
data bus or an address a complex bus
using the you know standard
text definition you you can go and break
out when you
right click you can break out the bus
each net and it'll automatically connect
it's pretty slick
so some new stuff going on there's some
people who want to work on um
orthogonal uh dragging
uh with for the schematic editor so that
you know the wires stay nice square
you know right angle lines instead of
when you drag now you get
you got to break them yourself and you
know make them square again
so yeah there's a lot i mean there's
lots of things going on right now i
you know i know i know somebody's got to
go the next question is going to be when
and
i would say i would say
given the current rate i'm hoping we're
like in a
feature freeze in beta around
kikon we'll have a better idea at keycon
but i'm hoping we'll be close to that
so that maybe by the end of the year
we're close to a 6.0
release oh yeah yeah so
i just wanted to pick up on the analogy
you're making for the software side
so one of the things that helped open
source software
is it was an easy way for large
companies to come up to monetize the
cost of some of the big things they were
maintaining
ibm hp and whatever else
i can see that's kind of happening on
the harbor side for a lot of things
like board design and so on where i'm
having a hard time figuring that is for
the
silicon manufacturers so the fabs
themselves i don't see how open hardware
commoditizes their costs and i was
wondering
well i there's actually um i know now
there's actually people
working on trying to get an open an open
pdk
so that's work in progress i
those are things that i'm not at liberty
to talk about but i know people are
trying
to to do that and i i think of like i
said i think event
it's it's the one it's kind of the one
domino theory if you can just get
that one even if it's not perfect and
even if it's
but it's you know it it meets the needs
of a large enough group of people
every people who want open will start to
merge that way and people will see their
you know other customers will or other
you know
fab guys will see their business going
elsewhere and it's kind of how the open
source worked you know it was
there was there was a first
implementation and people started to go
that way and no somebody noticed hey
where are all these guys going
right so i suspect that like i said i
don't i don't i'm not naive enough to
believe that it's quite the same as
software because like i said
the internet makes software cost zero
there's
never going to be a zero cost hardware
solution
is the money spent on the commercial
support anyway
less effective on code development
the question the question the question
is is um
when um so for key cad services
corporation if somebody pays
for a feature or a specific fix
does that affect it does it affect the
development it only affects
the it only affects the order in which
things get done
normally i have like a progression of
things i'm working on so as long as
nothing gets in
the way of that that's kind of how i go
but if somebody comes to me and pays is
pulling to pay me and say i want this
done first
well i'm not going to say no you know it
just i just i slip slot that in and then
everything else
but but but a lot of times it's a
feature that
it all gets it all gets go it all goes
back into key cad proper right so it
gets merged into the main
key cad master branch so i there there's
i don't see a downside to it i really i
just don't see a downside it's not like
we're
just making those features for like one
person and we're hiding it because you
can't do that
the key cad code bases excuse me gpl3 so
we're
kind of tied to that
what do you think is the biggest thing
what do i think the biggest thing
holding back key cad development
um oh that's a good question
a lot of it's just time you know people
were most of us
up until recently are very part-timers
you know when you have a full-time job
and family and
you know you want to have at least
something that resembles a life
you know which i didn't for a long time
um uh my wife was here she'd tell you
that uh
so i mean i i think that's just you know
what it boils down to is
is if we can get back into the way ways
some way to monetize it so we can pay
people to work
spent spend more time just working on
key cad instead of working
on it in their spare time so so
actually development pace has real has
picked up in the last couple years we
have
we've at most of the lead development
team
seems to be able to find enough time to
spend to get that get worked on
so i mean obviously it's all it'd always
be nicer if you could do it faster but
it's actually pretty it's moving along
pretty good right now
any other questions maybe uh two more
questions
yep yeah there's always a trade-off
between um
ease of use and user experience versus
the full capabilities of what you know a
professional user using cadence or
somebody might need
what's your philosophy on that how do
you make that trade-off because you
don't want to make fixing
you can't make cadence the question
the question is is trade-offs between
usability and complexity um
there's always trade-offs we try to keep
the core features
that you would use to do simple board
layouts fairly straightforward in keycad
a lot of the times if you don't need to
use any of the advanced features
you're not necessarily exposed to them
so like say you would need to do
uh matched length tracing you tuned
to length tracing right there's there's
some configuration you have to do there
you can't get out
you can't get away from that because
otherwise
there are things there's parametric
things you have to set up and there's no
way to avoid the
complexity of doing that but if you're
just doing simple two-layer
trace boards and fill in some zones that
stuff's all
fairly straightforward i i can't imagine
you know like
just to do simple board design layouts
the key cat is like
so complex that you can't wrap your head
around it it just
it's fairly straightforward
one more question
quite recently there was quite a lot of
like
transitions made in the coal base like
uh
for some time in the whole version i
guess
there were some changes in how the
libraries are stored
changes in well we could have chosen
different
ways the thing is rendered and depending
on that we have different features
so are all those kind of things already
some well to be super quick
the question was it's the problem with
the symbol libraries which has always
been a problem since the original design
of key cat
and the answer that is yes these were
the problem is is to get from where we
wanted
where we were to where we want to go
there was a couple of intermediate
transitions
and they were somewhat painful because
one of the things we always had a bug in
the old library look up
that was based on the library ordering
so if you had two symbols
or identical symbol names in two
different libraries
what mattered was the library ordering
so if you then
that was a if you picked the library
from one the one you thought
you got and you had the library ordering
wrong you got the other symbol
and that was the problem so that yeah
the table where you map it to a table
now they're all hard to find they're
absolute there's no relative to
the the symbols are and so there's a we
had to get from there
to there the next in version six the
symbols will actually be embedded in the
schematic like the footprints are in the
board
so you you won't need any cache library
anymore you'll just pick the schematic
up and take it with you and
every now you won't you may not be able
to if you don't have the symbols on your
the other machine you won't be able to
update the symbols that are in the board
with the latest versions of the symbols
in the library but
you'll still have those you'll still be
able to work on the schematic open it
it'll be completely portable that's all
part of the new file format stuff that
i'm working on
thank you
awful yeah
i gotta go