um
okay next up we're gonna have um jeff
frederick was gonna be talking to us
about
kubernetes on factory raspberry pi's
okay so um it's it's something
to be a kind of educating fun
and try to motivate you to try the same
experience
um there's a demo i have a bunch of
raspberry which are going to make some
light at some point
uh it's to tell me that i have to start
the demo
uh because basically this is going to
build a network i don't
and i'm going to this this is basically
to uh
it is the o2 of a tomcat demo i've been
doing at from apachecon
explaining uh how we can do
session sharing using
the kubernetes cloud in tomcat
so um i'm john furrier i'm working for
red hat
you can find me under this email
nearly everywhere on on twitter
on slideshare the slides are already
available on slideshare so
if you don't see the small things and
you see it better on your laptop you can
just
go there so um
here i have my kubernetes
cloud made of raspberries basically
i have one box here
which is going to provide a wi-fi to the
others
and i have a master running here
and two nodes which at some point should
make some light
actually both of them are making some
light so
these have created a network on which i
have to connect to start the remove
which of course going to take a while to
start
so um i have to that's the first thing
when you
you show how to do a demo usually the
first thing you screw is like
what you know that network or something
like that so
this demo is basically to uh to show you
that you can easily have
kubernetes uh running
so that you can use it uh with some
space
with very little space you can have
offline demo
of your application that you have
prepared for kubernetes
so at some point i should get network
hopefully
it's trying to connect to the first and
then fail with
okay i need two seconds okay
so i'm i'm connecting on this box and
i'm going to uh
tell master to start to master
and to start the two nodes
so i'm i'm starting it and then i will
explain with the
how it goes because it it requires some
time to stop
so it's going to ping the node and then
it's going to start the stuff so
i'll go back to the presentation while
it's starting
so what what i'm doing here is basically
i'll take it
a bit uh the hard way um i'm using a
fedora distribution uh on raspberry 4.
uh the raspberry ford is not yet
supported by the linux kernel i mean the
base canal so you have to use the
raspberry pi uh specific fork
of the linux scanner uh it needs to be
cross compiled so you can it's quite
easy on the laptop
uh you have to install the arm 64
cross compilation tool and unbuild your
kernel
you have to build it for raspberry 4 and
you have also to add some stuff
that fedora is requiring uh
like uh to have the same way working for
s linux and you have some parameters
also to set uh for kubernetes
uh this is in you can find it in the in
my your under my url there
there's not so much stuff there so to
build
uh you just tell that you want to build
this config
you uh that is building the
configuration files
and then uh you make mac image modules
and
and then you will have uh the kernel and
the modules and some
some other file you need then you need
to prepare sd card
uh basically it's easy i have
raspberry pi sd card there where i have
installed the stuff
and i can normally show what is inside
you will see
so um this is it's a bit small but
it's readable now okay so basically uh
this is uh this is my uh my car this is
the uh the boot this is a
uh dos or fat uh that is going to be
read by the uh
uh by the bootstrap uh of the raspberry
the bootstrap of the raspberry is done
by the uh
uh graphic card or the vod.com card
which is going to read this
uh load the kernel uh in memory and
uh tell the kernel that it needs to run
on the arm 64
version and then and then start it up
which is
uh what is has been done
and um uh you have the uh
the root partition uh of the raspberry i
have used very big
card because uh i also want to run
openshift on it and it's a
it's i was you can do it with us uh
32 without problems and you probably
could use a smaller one but the smaller
sd card that does not worth it
so back to the presentation so you have
seen the
starting is running in background
um the first the next problem i have is
like basically um
i have to set up the the wi-fi uh
to do this uh you have you have to wait
you can either copy the fire at the
right place
uh in the raspberry pi it's it's doable
it well it's easy
uh i i'm not going to explain it because
uh i've done it the other way
uh which is basically i'm just
connecting my raspberry pi
uh to my router at home uh
and i make a nmap uh find out that it's
a raspberry
uh i have uh previously uh copied to it
uh raspberry is starting ssh
and has my case on it so basically i
just have to ssh to it as root
and then install what is needed so
basically i'm going to they get the
configuration for the raspberry 4 uh
i'm going to install some tools to do
and then i'm going to configure the
wi-fi uh
fedora 31 has a some funny channel
feature
which is a mac address randomization so
that i have to edit the file that's
never because otherwise i have some
problem to find my raspberry
um the description of what is running
there what is running on the infra
if you look you will find a raspberry pi
network here
uh raspberry tree i guess
you can guess the password easily from
uh my facebook
friends and information uh and
uh in my other demo i'll let everyone
connect to it to play with it but
we won't have time for that um and
so the explanation of how to set up this
box uh is
uh on on my blog uh you can have a look
to it
uh um i can show more stuff on it uh
after the presentation like open it and
show you what uh you need inside
uh because basically uh it's it's going
to make to run kubernetes
without uh an internet connection so i'm
i need a
real-time clock i need uh the hcp and
dns to have
all those things running so all this is
explained in my blog if you want to try
it
uh just go there and have fun
the next problem i had is like of course
i need to build uh
arm 64 images uh
the cool thing is like uh m64 images
there's a lot that are available
uh i have tried it with santos
7 and the
alpine kernel the alpine kernel the
alpine linux is good because it's quite
small
basically what i did is like uh i
use this raspberry and and install
docker on it
and java maven i'm doing cat stuff it's
obvious
so basically i've i have built uh
these things uh a small note like
i was doing the same on my laptop to
make sure that i understand
everything thank you uh and then uh
basically uh
you need to take care of multi-platform
if you want to use the same image name
otherwise the first time you start the
stuff on the raspberry is going to take
like it's a wrong image so you must make
sure
you have the right to use the manifest
tool in order that docker is able
uh to put in the um in the docker of the
right information so
basically you have the information that
uh this image is uh for arm this image
is for
a s 390 this image is a for
arm 64 and so on so basically it is this
i won't jump in the detail uh you use
the docker build
uh you tell him which arch you are and
then the important thing is in this
file that you have done under the the
demo
yaml file
on the master you have to so this is
basically what was what is running in
background
um you you are basically i've run this
demo several times so i have to clean it
i have to play a little with ep table uh
i have to remove the swap because
otherwise qb admin does not want to
start
uh and then i
i need a kubernetes network i have
choose a wave to do that
you you have a lot of others but this
was the
this is the first one i tried and it
worked so
i stay on this one
i'm open to suggestions i can do tries
it's very easy like it's it's my own
it's my own kubernetes so i can do what
i want we can try it
i can try other stuff and so basically
then i'm going to uh
do whatever you would do if you use
kubernetes uh
i will basically copy the configuration
to my local configuration
so i can run on uh this guy but i can
have done that on my laptop i can run
the command on the kubernetes things so
basically
to install the network is going to
something like qbctl
apply minus f and the name of the of the
file
um i have a local copy of the uh
of the of the of the plugin in my
repository but
it's just uh we get from the original
one
on each node uh well you have to do a
kind of same thing
you're just going to join your
kubernetes cluster basically you have a
command to do that
uh you just uh qb admin
cluster uh token create it's uh
going to give you uh the token and if
you say
uh print on command it will just
basically tell you which command you
have to run
on the node uh to
to make this node join your kubernetes
cluster
and once once everything is done you can
make a qbcl get node to see the nodes
that are running we are going to try it
so here it could be ctl
get nodes
and you see i have the nodes running
uh green is also obviously the one which
is displaying in green the
blue is the one displaying in them
in uh the blue is the one that's playing
in blue and master
is this one which is hidden there with
no color
so it had been started uh while we were
explaining the stuff
so so i have my
i have my kubernetes running uh let's
try to have some fun there
so so the next one i want to do
uh is basically a move from a tomcat
cluster
to a kubernetes cluster of stormcats
so basically i have one problem i'm
going to i'm jumping
quite fast i hope everyone knows what
is wep and http so basically i have one
problem uh
the protocol does not have a the http
1.1 does not have a
transaction as a persistent connection
so basically you need a cookie to carry
this information
and if you are in a cluster basically
you're going to create a cookie and
you're going to store the information of
the user
on the server and you associate it with
one cookie in this case it's the session
id so basically
i what i'm going to need is like
basically i need to replicate the
session information between the
the the two nodes here because of course
i can't
i can't i can't be sure on which top cat
the in the things isn't going to
to arrive so uh this is the uh
things so how the tomcat cluster is
working we choose multicast
uh we don't have multicast in kubernetes
for the moment
uh so basically uh you have to wait you
have to i
this guy has to discover this guy so
uh you can use the kubernetes api to do
that this is very easy
uh it's it's the internal things it's
like uh
this is like you make a get uh well you
need to
need to be encrypted and all that stuff
but this is a decrypted version of
it the date is wrong because basically
it was a try without
the uh the clock working uh
and you can see that he's going to tell
some information like
where it's running um especially what i
want to know it's the point
the pod ip which is the the ip inside
the kubernetes network
so basically that with this i'm going to
be able to find
uh from this guy where is this guy at
which ip it is so i can
exchange the session information so when
i will run my small
application on my http i will basically
be able
to to arrive on the right tomcat and
on one tomcat but i will have the right
session information on both
so basically i don't care on which one
i'm arriving because i've been
exchanging the
session information
qbp is a it's a bit tricky because you
need some permissions
so in this case it's not a big problem
but if you're running a real
on a real cloud you won't have those
permissions uh you will not
ask your administrator so that he gave
it to you
so there's another way to discover the
net they also know this is
just uh basically uh winami
uh qb ping you can look for it uh it has
been invented by the uh
infinity span guys so basically uh yeah
you just make a
uh ns lookup so basically well this is
uh
this is openshift example uh it works
the same way
uh well the command is a bit different
uh so basically you make a ns lookup uh
on your namespace and then you're going
to find the tomcat this is the way
the this guy is going to discover this
guy and this guy is going to discover
this guy
so in the in my demo in the next page
i'm going to uh to see i'm going to i
have
http running here uh this httpd
is going to be able to find uh the
different uh
load balancer uh in uh
in i i need to start the demo otherwise
i will run out of time
i will run out of time now okay
so
so we are basically i'm i'm i'm in my
kubernetes uh
clown and i'm i'm starting uh
my boats um and uh
you can see basically what did i do it
create a namespace
put it set on internet space uh then
it's it start uh it's up the tomcat
uh pods uh and
create a different service we create one
service which is a dns service so that
the ns lookup will work on both of these
and then i have the two tomcat which are
starting which at some point
some points are going to be up hopefully
so one is running the author is not yet
ready
okay at some point they're going to be
so what time what you do in the what you
do in um
uh in kubernetes it's like basically
you're going to have a
uh one kubernetes proxy on each
of those running is knowing uh the other
node so basically
what we do is like we you can connect on
any of
of of those members of the uh of your uh
of your cloud uh with the right port
so to access to the service so basically
to create my
uh to make my httpd which is running
here
distributing the the load between the uh
the two tomcat i don't care i'm going to
tell him
like any of those member of my cloud
is able to do uh the routing this this
is uh kubernetes which does the routing
for me
uh what i like to mention is like um you
need a docker registry local registry uh
is running on this box and it's very
easy it's a sample command
uh you you start a docker registry
docker run
on the port uh you have to be a bit
careful so that kubernetes does not
complain because it
it's a demo so it's unsecure uh one
minute it's unsecured by
on purpose uh you pull the image and
then the things
have been running so now my demo should
be ready
so normally uh i could join my httpd
then and then this is the tomcat running
and when i refresh a bunch of time it
should be
the counter should be increasing and it
should be moving from one node to the
other
and set it so basically uh i have i've
proven that
my tomcat software is working and then
the session is shared between the two
uh uh nodes which which are running
there and
chair between the two ports it's the
same if i would run 10 port if i scale
up as i have only
two nodes i can i will have uh for if i
scale to three i will have a two-tone
cut running on this one maybe or
two-tone category on this one and one on
the other
and i guess i'm out of time
yes
[Applause]
if you have questions you can come to me
after