so
hello everybody welcome to my talk about
libre pcb
um maybe first a quick question who
knows already
libre pcb okay maybe
a third and so i was here
uh two years ago um with my
talk introduction to libre pcb
and now i want to give a short update
what's
happening with libre pcb so
for those who don't already know
libre pcb is a free open open source edi
suite
it runs on linux windows and mac and
yet development started already in 2013
and there is a slow but continuous
progress
um and what happened since my last talk
in 2018
in november 2018 there was
our first official stable release
0.1.0 and
after that every few months a new
release was
published and i don't like to
mention every feature implemented in
this time
but just want to focus on some specific
features
and one of these features is the library
editor rule check
probably every hardware designer knows
the problem
you create a package or a symbol
in your library editor then you add it
to your design to your pcb or whatever
and then you realize oh no
designator label for forgotten in the
library editor or oh no
silk screen is overlapping with the pad
or something like that
and then i ask myself why do we have
a design rule check in the board editor
but no
rule check in the library editor because
a lot of
issues you can already catch in the
library editor actually
so in libre pcb we implemented
a pretty simple actually check
with a few rules defined and if you
violate some of these rules you get for
example the
big scary yellow warning there is
something really wrong
with your item you have created and
in the right bottom corner you have a
list
of messages and what's wrong
with this element so you can already fix
it in the library editor
and you're happy when you add it to your
board
and another thing is the liver pcb cli
actually for most users not that
important but
i asked myself in software development
we today we use continuous integration
static code analysis
pull requests for code reviews and so on
but for pcb tools we
for libraries or projects probably
almost nobody uses such tools for
example on github
and continuous integration so
but what's what's needed to make this
possible
we need a cli so you can run checks
automatically on continuous integration
and for example we have a cli which is
able to check libraries
and if they are valid and yeah more
checks
will be added in future and
in for the base libraries of libre pcb
uh those are uh hosted on github we use
github actions to
run these checks so if a pull requests
a pull request adds an issue to the
library
the ci will fail
the same we have for projects and so you
can
use the cli or continuous integration to
run the cli to
check your project if there are directly
for example electrical rule check issues
and um if you want you can also automate
the generation of care profiles boom
export and so on
and actually probably the most important
user of this tool is azler
because now you can upload your libre
pcb project
directly to azler.net if you want to
order
your pcb and aisler runs our cli
to generate the gerber files so you
don't have to generate them
locally on your computer and
the best thing is of course for every
order of a liver pcb project
azler makes a donation to libre pcb so
you can support
libre pcb by ordering your pcbs at azler
um how to get started
with libre pcb um we have
a lot of binaries or packages available
for example for windows for
various linux distributions for arch
linux for nyx os
even for open pandora if someone knows
this thing it's an
arm processor inside and libre pcb runs
pretty nice there
and of course for mac os and bsd
so now i want to give a short demo
to see lever pcb in action
and so let's start libre pcb
if you when you start liver pcb the very
first time
um you get the short wizard which
just asks for for a path where to store
your libraries and so on
just click through you're ready
then the control panel says you don't
have any library installed so it's not
pretty
not very useful yet the tool so you can
just open the library manager
which fetches the library list from
our api server and so
this tool is also able to update your
already installed library
so you can just say oh i want the base
library
let's install that one it downloads the
library from the internet
and installs the library you see already
the
the warning disappeared because now you
have libraries
and yeah we can check what's inside this
library
and the library is scanned in the
background
because there are many files so it takes
a few seconds to
create the index and now
we have the the library elements
download
we just downloaded symbols
packages whatever okay
so now what's a typical use case you
also need a your own local library
so let's create one for example because
some transistor is missing in the other
libraries
then you just need a device for example
so let's add the device
and whatever
and it asks for choosing a component
which we want to implement so let's say
it's a mosfet
and channel and which package you want
to use
maybe to 220.
these library elements the package and
the component is
contained in the base library we just
downloaded
okay so now you have the device and you
only
need to create the pin map basically
open the data sheet assign package pad
one to
drain to to gate
and source maybe and the pad is
unconnected maybe
okay so now we have a warning because we
didn't assign
this device to a category and the cool
thing is
this warning has a a lot of warnings
have a fix button so you can
or even a help button which gives some
context what's
wrong and many warnings have a fix
button and in this case
it opens the category chooser and so you
can assign
a category what else and
or title k title is not
title case because the f is lowercase
can just fix check uppercase finished
no warnings okay so
now we have our library elements ready
so let's create a new project
okay and we start with the schematic
with for example the schematic frame
and of course we want to add our um
our mosfet i added it to the
i don't know where i added it but we can
find it
um
oh here it is under discrete transistors
mosfet and channel here it is
okay so let's add this one
maybe a resistor what else
let's just connect them
something very useful
[Laughter]
that's our schematic so let's switch to
the board editor
and the board editor says we have two
unplaced devices
so let's place them and you can choose
your exact
device here so maybe
[Music]
smd whatever
and our mosfet we just created in the
library
and the cool thing is we didn't
create the package because someone else
already created it for our mosfet
and this package contains multiple
footprint so we can just switch to a
different mounting variant for example
um yeah so let's create some traces
maybe something very simple
okay
now we want to create gerber files and
fabrication data there you can make
some settings but defaults are fine so
let's just generate it
open the directory and we have gerber
files here let's open it
with the gear view and here we are
so simple piece we made in a few minutes
and that's actually the main goal of
libre pcb it should be
easy to create pcbs you don't have to
spend hours and hours and hours
just to know the tool and it's
that easy yeah um
what's the current status of the project
um
basically everything is um working nice
so far so you can
create your pcbs there are already a lot
of pcbs created with libre pcb and order
it
the main issue currently is the board
editor which
needs a lot of usability improvements
and
a lot of features are still missing
and so the priority for the next steps
um highest pro priorities uh add the
missing features like
custom paired shape blind buried wires
slotted holes pads and so on and
improved the board editor to yeah
to be much more powerful also clipboard
cut copy paste
is not available yet in the schematic
and port editors
and of course extending the port
libraries
requires quite some effort
um and priority two is
adding part management for mpns
assembly variants 3d models
is not implemented yet mcat
export hierarchical sheets and so on
and you see many things are still
missing but for
at least for simpler pcbs it's
pretty usable
and yeah if you want to
contribute i would be happy there are
several ways to contribute to libre pcb
just check out the website or the github
repository
yeah that's it
so questions please why did you decide
to make a new project instead of
contributing
very good question i have a slide for
that
[Laughter]
yeah the question was why not
contributing to kitkat and
instead creating a new software and
basically the main reasons are i think
the
underlying a lot of the underlying
concepts are
pretty different so i think i have
different opinions
how an eda tool should work and should
be designed
and usually you as a as a contributor
you can't
completely change the the mindset or the
opinions
of a different project and
the the other thing is um changing
if you uh make it happen to change
fundamental
things it's very hard to keep the
backwards compatibility to
older kiket or whatever projects and so
on
and users wouldn't be happy if
if they can't migrate to the new
software version
and it's much easier to create a new
tool then you don't have legacy things
you don't
have to provide migration paths to
crappy file format or whatever and
the other thing is the target audience
and the priorities is quite different
i think and kitkat is very
feature rich it's professional great
it's very flexible you can basically do
everything with that tool and that's not
the primary goal of libre pcb libre pcb
focus on usability
and intuitive user interface so you can
get started with liverp very quickly
and also portability stability
and the files i would like to put files
uh
projects and so on on the version
control and
this is also a goal of libre pcb2 and
yeah to make it possible much better
than with other tools
when you're working behind the corporate
firewall
applications aren't allowed to access
the internet network
and is it possible to update your
libraries
for a browser um
the question is when working behind
corporate firewalls is it possible
to get the libraries through the browser
because applications are blocked um i
mean
basically the library manager of libre
pcb
just downloads a zip file in the
background and extracts it to a
directory
you can get the zip file directly on
github
you can clone it with git it's no
problem
you just can't use the library manager
in that case
the question was can we import kitkat
files
no at the moment there is no kickhead
import at all
there is a very simple eagle library
import but it's a standalone application
not
integrated into libre pcb yet
yeah how many active contributors on the
project or is it mainly
just you so the question was how many
active contributors we have
i think on if you watch on github i
think it's
20 or 30 contributors or something like
that
but the the main part of libre pcb is
actually implemented by
myself so the contributions are
rather small usually
but then to manage it to change it and
to
keep it updated so could you uh give
some
more overview of how this could be
achieving
libra pcb i mean there's no part of
creating pcb but then
changing something how for example the
libraries
if they change and i download them
will i won't i have any problems with
that i had
some bad experiences with that
um
so i'm not sure how to
so let me summarize the question uh how
do how do you focus
on version control yeah can you repeat
that
yeah how we focus on version control
um of libre pcb projects and libraries
so basically um
the most important thing i think is that
files should not contain any crap for
example which changes everything you
open the project
close it and files are changed that's
horrible for version control
and thus in libre pcb and
we strictly separate information which
needs to be checked in
because it is important for the project
or for the libraries
and information which is not that
important
for example which layer is visible or
hidden
or what zoom level you have and so on
that's not
part of the repository in the end that's
stored only locally
so you don't have um changes you you
don't want
in the in the git log basically thank
you