please
turn off your mobile phones
hello yeah okay okay
let me introduce you michael mix and his
talk is
libreoffice turns 10 and what's next
police after michael finished his
presentation uh
don't run away and wait until uh
question session
end thank you michael
thank you very much excellent so you
know
i'd love to encourage you to all move
closer and enjoy the
the proximity of being next to each
other in this this lovely
tutorial but perhaps not this time
anyway
um so say this is what i'm going to talk
about so i won't
uh tell you about that um here we go
so 10 years 10 years or 20 years
amusingly uh libreoffice has been uh
growing in in
conjunction with fosdem for 20 years and
so we're very just thrilled
to be able to celebrate our 10th or 20th
depending how you look at it
or 35th anniversary at the same time
that fosdem is so
just fantastic and um yeah
was it i'm sorry 45 35 it's a long time
1985.
yeah 35 years i'm saying marker buddhist
a wonderful guy a teenager working in
his garage
you have to be careful about garages you
know don't go in
you may come out with an office suite
you know um
so so he releases this and at this stage
in um
this this time it's really just a word
processor star writer
but it gets the dibs you know it beats
microsoft office by you know nearly five
years
so that's so that's all good this is the
93 version
and uh just a word processor and you
need to understand the world at this
time
um all sorts of interesting things are
happening
uh so a spreadsheet was created which
was called quattro pro
i don't know if you know why um but
lotus created something called one two
three
and so borland created something called
four um
which was you know it was a friendly
time um and we lived in a diverse
industry not dominated by one monopoly
which was fantastic um and at this point
uh lotus was suing borland about the
structure sequence and organization of
uh menu so you know not nothing like
today obviously
um and and anyway so these are some
great quotes from philip khan the ball
and
co-founder you know prehistoric anything
20 years old and over
i don't know if any of you are over 20
but i am and uh it's good to it's good
to know that the facelift isn't going to
do it you know
um but but philly was particularly
interested
and a good exemplar of the the
excitement at the time about
revolutionary programming language
change
you know object orientation would make
everything wonderful
everything would be 10 times quicker and
and more beautiful
you know we would develop so amazingly
rapidly
software would become easy to read easy
to to handle
um it was absolutely amazing and
philippe told
so many people this you even get the new
york times
explaining um you know this this radical
new uh innovation you know so here are
some great great quotes from him
um creating the initial objects is
difficult
uh especially for programmers and so you
can you can see some of the pascal
programmers that came into open office
in the time or star office
and did the one big class approach you
know yeah
sure it's obj orientated why not one
class with a thousand methods that does
does everything but ultimately the
payoff will be faster
less costly development of new programs
and updates wonderful
mr gates has an interesting quote in the
same article if it's so great
why are their products so late well i
think that's uh that's a really great
question
um careful of panaceas anyway back at
this time marco is is
is i guess uh in this era of excitement
around objected
programming and so he creates a visual
class libraries a new way of creating
toolkits
that will make applications trivial to
write um
and so well he tries to sell this
toolkit but the demo apps
it turns out are the thing that most
interests people you know he creates
these office apps and and actually in
the end he then ends up refactoring uh
and creating these these uh office
productivity suite
out of his uh his visual class library
project which is brilliant i think these
days they call this a pivot
um you know there's a posh term for it
but absolutely brilliant
so he he went back to the the office
business he created star office three
which completely rewrote this so he even
ran on os2 which is fantastic and spark
and yeah directly competed with windows
on the office 95 as it were
and this is the code we're built on
today it's uh it's still the skeleton
of of that some of that design
and why is that interesting well it
turns out that object orientation is not
a panacea
and it's it's a different way of
arranging your code and your data and
that's good you know there are many
benefits to it but
the problem is when you sit down and you
design your object hierarchy based on
what you see
you don't necessarily get a very good
design so you see
cells in spreadsheets so well that has
to be an object everything i can see
should have an object
you know yeah yeah that's not
necessarily a good idea
you know small talk popularize this
approach i guess you know every integer
should be an object
um but well anyway um say paragraphs
tables should be objects um the problem
is that this really screws up change
tracking
um so it was really very well understood
how to create good
office suites uh back in the day when
these decisions were made
and almost none of these insights were
taken into account
another cool thing about object
orientation of course is encapsulation
of information
so wouldn't it be nice if your file
format just serialized all these objects
and they stored their internal state
and all would be well oh dear
well roll on 20 years and some of those
initial object
hierarchy decisions turn out not to have
been the best ones
and the problem is when your file format
is essentially a serialization of your
object hierarchy
you have a real problem so what was done
was copying and pasting the whole office
suite
at the point that it could generate xml
files into a duplicate office suite
which we call the bin filter
and this kept the old object hierarchy
loaded your file saved it as a
as odf reloaded it as odf into the main
office suite and we finally managed to
get rid of this
you know like uh five years ago which is
which is quite good going
and this then freed us up to you know
undo some of these these stupid things
so spreadsheets for example
you know massive refactorings of the
core there totally restructured the data
a cell is not an object it's it's a set
of you know
complex uh data structures that describe
styles and formatting and
um you know and if it's got a number in
it if you have a column full of doubles
it is a root a contiguous span of
doubles if you want to sum them
you can do ssc optimize some you can
parallelize this you can deal with the
data in a meaningful way
and that's simply not possible with the
object approach um
and similarly writer you know the
problems of trying to do change tracking
with tables and
all of these different objects just
incredibly
problematic incredibly problematic and
so michael stahl for tip has been doing
some great great work there
shipping now too to try and turn this
into a view state so previously when you
pressed
when you pressed a key um it would
actually mutate the model
to what it thought it should be and then
put the key in and then mutate it
again um so if you weren't showing
change checking it would actually
literally edit all of your redlining in
and out of the document every keystroke
which is kind of uncool um anyway
so so open office so how did this happen
well
um this is the heady days of floss being
the panacea you know
open source will fix everything it's
fantastic and i i'm a big free software
lover myself so
you know but you know i think larry
ellison says you know open source is
going to kill proprietary software you
know um
you know the mini computer will kill the
mainframe
you know larry who's not a man i
approve of generally but but he says you
know he's been in this industry a long
time and watching the mainframe die
is like watching a glacier melt you know
even with global warming it's
it's going slowly you know there's still
still there anyway but
so so you know floss our mission is to
drive floss and make it uh rule the
worlds
but uh we need to think about ways to
speed that up
so yeah so anyway somebody start a
vision for less than the cost of the
licenses it was paying
uh reputedly and uh market is then a vp
of whatever and he opens sources star
office which is absolutely fantastic
and a really good a good thing to do i
mean so he did this talking to miguel
and nats who were doing a lot of gnome
stuff at ximen
are working on evolution male client
stuff and so actually some kind of
compromise whereby
gnome kind of de-emphasized its office
suite and they
got rid of their male clients and life
was happy we all
worked together in a glorious new world
unfortunately
in terms of attracting developers um the
guy who wrote the build instructions for
open office was a non-developer who
apparently hadn't done the job
um you know he just cargo culted some
rumors he'd heard from from here and
there
and when they came to attracting
developers you know the the the goal of
a dependency graph of open office was to
terrify you
uh rather than to try and teach you
anything it seems you know um so
actually it's not really that difficult
you know i mean like get this complexity
there's eight million lines of code
but it's not it's not the madness that
you can try and make it
look like if you really if you really go
for it
another fun thing about openoffice was
the development process
so so inside the team of you know i
don't know 100 developers there was a
great
development methodology which was this
um you could do something
fun you know in your base library uh you
could rename a method
for no apparent reason or or or change
the order of parameters or
or something like that and then you
would simply send an email to all of
your colleagues saying
well i did this please go and fix your
code
um before moving on to doing another
similar you know
thing and and and the problem with this
of course is that
you know the code never actually builds
of course you commit your code as well
right so
your code goes in your and everyone else
has to um
to try and catch up and um
yeah unfortunately platform and api
churn rapidly
overwhelms the ability of any anyone to
do actually anything up here because
it's all
breaking down there and yes of course
there's a panacea to fix that just
rewrite it all in another language and
then you know
um so the build tree was in a permanent
state of brokenness
i mean so they had release engineers
whose job was effectively to branch the
tree
every two weeks or as soon as they could
actually build it it usually took
that sort of time and and then they
would try and include all the fixes that
would actually make it build
and at the end of this they would do you
know many a day or two of building on
cpu time
and then they give everyone binaries
that they could build on top of for
their next
extravaganza of api change and
an improvement i'm saying so one of the
corollaries of this is the top commit
count people in the world if you look in
olo
are the release engineers that merged
everyone else's patches they they're
just
you know they're just outstanding um
see just to to reflect on this this
sounds like a ridiculous situation where
the people who maintain the platform
can rabidly change it and break everyone
that works on top of it
that's a mad way to develop software
isn't it
well welcome to linux fantastic
you know everybody in the base system
has brilliant ideas for improving uh
things at the bottom
um and the great news is that everybody
that builds on top of them gets to live
with this
and uh you know so let me encourage you
to keep your apis stable
and your apis stable and to to live
with the pain um because although
removing the
threaded the option of having threaded
users of your tool kit
seems like a nice cleanup that removes
20 or 30 lines
out of gtk just to pick an example
it totally screws libreoffice and
everyone ever wrote a macro potentially
so you know it might be nice to see this
nixon hello see the suffering you
inflict on others before you uh you know
do it i guess so anyway it took me a
month to get my first build i'm
obviously an idiot
um but um with with a whole lid of fixes
which i quickly upstreamed i managed to
get it to build
and you know you could then update it
and then it would break again
completely for weeks and there was never
anything that you could actually be sure
would actually work
so i created this thing called oo build
and based on frederick crozat's work and
suddenly
all the linux distributions used it
fantastic
and the good news was that you know a
day into your build of wall clock time
it was at least not intended to fail you
know like like
at least someone else had built it and
thought it should work um
which is kind of kind of good you know
build times have improved but we're
still
you know an hour a minimum and so
there's some serious strains there i
mean at the time i visited a conference
in the uk
and everywhere i went i found
frustration uh you know there were
people with holding up
placards like this and you know don't
mandate
incredibly burdensome process just to
fix uh simple
simple things i don't force people to
have a team that they have to join with
a
a product owner and a spec writer and a
ux designer and a qa person
why not just you know let things
actually uh
carry on um try and avoid the
bugs uh you know piling up and uh yes
actually fix some will be would be be
nice um contributor agreements well when
do you think fedora dropped the
requirement for a contributor agreement
that assigned copyright to a wonderful
company
uh red hat right um so you know don't
don't keep people out of the project uh
when you we don't need to
um it's very difficult if you're the
majority contributor not you know to to
include otherwise but uh libreoffice of
course you know
try try to fix this and then there's
just the cultural problems you know i
don't know if you know
people who are like this you know every
solution has a problem
uh that means you can't even think of
doing it and uh it gets a bit much after
a while
and and yeah i don't want to
mischaracterize the the starter vision
the really
you know many of these burdensome
process things were not just for the
community they were just like corporate
culture projected outside
and there were some real heroes there
that went so tried to make the community
a fun place to be
by doing the burdensome process
themselves
and they're just absolutely fantastic so
uh you know but it was
serious cultural uh problems here
uh so libra office well here we go so
during the libreoffice conference
uh in in budapest at the open office
conference uh we we managed to bundle
everyone else in the conference off on a
boat
on the river and had you been on the
boat you would have noticed that these
people weren't there they were at a
separate restaurant
a plotting uh and so by september the
second
we'd come up with a plan and had a nice
meal to boot
um and interestingly almost all of these
people are still involved in the project
today
which is fantastic some of the most
full-time staff or almost all of them
are still doing wonderful things
it's a testament how fun uh this can be
um but yeah so you see we had a we had a
good we had a good time there
and uh in less than a month we would
have released uh libreoffice
and of course um at this point you need
to call in all your favors when you're
starting a new risky
a risky project uh there are a lot of
people you've met at fosdem and
elsewhere
and programmed with that you have to go
and uh encourage to do something risky
um so so this was the the management
stack in red hat and this was susan
these are two main
external contributors to
uh and here's one of the i will i
anonymize the company that was having
having uh problems because frankly both
of them were you know it was really much
after you no no after you you know this
little thing is this going to be a
success
how can we tell when i'm when i'm you
know this guy at the top
and to be fair these these are really
cool guys you'll never have well maybe
you've not heard of many of these people
probably uh probably you should do um
but
you know the problem was that we'll do
it if google does
you know we we we want something to uh
you know
it's about exactly you know we had pr
agencies lined up corporate backing
you know and then red hat and caesar you
know backed back this extraordinarily uh
helpfully so
10 days to launch i sent an email like
this um
uh to chris christa boehner and uh
jeremy anderson who's he's here which is
cool
at google saying you know quick
we need help uh please can you give us a
double rainy
rainbows and ponies uh you know uh sort
of thing or just
any kind of vague commitment that we can
use to uh to bounce this along
the bit the perhaps you missed here is
that much of the plotting was done
entirely without any
any backup and then you go and ask for
it uh you know when it's all on the edge
of course something real happening there
well ten days to launch i think this is
a good sign you know
um so yes seven days before launch
they come up trumps you know so uh so
yeah google is proud to be a supporter
of the document foundation which doesn't
exist yet
and it's run by a whole load of kids
right you know and participate in the
project
you know a resounding a resounding
endorsement
uh bingo unlocked everything so in terms
of getting people to line up and sign up
um this is this is uh just absolutely
wonderful and so you know i i think
yeah google play perhaps an unsung but
uh extraordinarily helpful
a process of getting everybody on side
of doing that some kind of due diligence
over a beer you know in a community room
somewhere and making it making it fly
so yeah then we didn't have a logo well
so christoph noack is an awesome guy he
was one of the
early plotters as you can see and we
were playing around
with lots of different legos my friend
larry ewing uh
created tux actually a programmer um
not really a a designer he drew the tux
logo and then he wanted to draw the
simian logo
after we'd spent a fortune on outsourced
design agencies to try and make a logo
all of which sucked
and he's like oh i just you know like
anyway so it turns out
kristoff created this yeah
help me improve i'm not experiencing
graphics design you know
i know some but actually if you look at
wikipedia and you look at the logo
article
i think someone's got a sense of humor
there this is the example of the
minimalist
logo and ibm is next to it and you know
what can you do
it's it's it's a pretty cool and
visually distinct brand
and then of course you know we needed
build so everyone's panickingly creating
builds
uh synchronizing them to our mirror
brain network so we can cope with the
download
uh bandwidth so uh peter pummell created
that and was involved with this
getting the infrastructure set up the
git repository with a website in it late
at night craziness blah blah
bingo the 28th here it is
and so we have you know obvious liberal
office you know navel red hat
and lots of other people then come in
you know richard stallman and mark
shuttleworth
the osi simon is of course still
involved with the libreoffice
name neo office br office and beer if
it's interesting because it shared
uh it had a powerful brand in in latin
america and all of those guys could move
across
straight away to to us and so our very
first release looked like that and
hopefully you can see
some degree of brand continuity let's
say uh
from the initial initial release so so
then there was a whole load of work
you know like it was amazing loads of
people arrived
and actually before i talk about that i
just want to talk about how we
structured the community
so my experience of working in free
software has not been prior to
libreoffice
has not been one free of conflict let's
say um
it was it was routinely my experience
that not only would there be four or
five
duplicate approaches to anything say
window managers and gnome
you know like written in every
conceivable language list c plus blast
has
whatever um but they would actually
fight each other quite viciously for
for user share mind share market share
and they would not talk to each other
either they'd certainly not tell them
what they were going to do
in the future you know i mean disclose
any anything and so so
actually it's like cats fighting in a
bag almost
almost everywhere and and this is pretty
depressing and it sometimes got personal
you know oh don't talk to him he's the
bad guy oh yeah you
wanna watch and all these coalitions
would be built
and then the mailing list would arrive
and they'd fight tooth and nail on the
mailing list as well
i i speak from experience as one who
used to fight tooth and nail on mailing
list
anyway if you if you read all of the
literature on conflict resolution
using email to resolve conflicts is a
reliable way of making everything worse
okay like this is this is kind of easy
you know this is they tell you something
like this is the first day in hr
and yeah so so it's absolutely
ridiculous and of course giving control
and ownership and like this
maintainership where you own something
and it can be taken from you
and you you know you've got to fight to
hold on to it and so on
ah yeah it was absolutely nonsense so we
from the very beginning had
phone calls of the engineering steering
committee
in whom everyone was peers they were all
the right people
all the people doing the work of course
if you have a respected expert in calc
and someone who works somewhere totally
different telling them what to do
everyone's going to give them a pretty
hard stare right like i mean
you need to respect experts but yeah
no one owns owns modules but of course
this is a bit of a problem for people
that don't speak english like i do
and so what we do is we transcribe live
transcribe the meetings so as people
speak it's written down
so everyone can follow and uh get
involved
and so in at least the technical sphere
there have been as far as i'm aware no
instances of conflict
no significant duplications of anything
and everybody has worked
uh reasonably happily together so yeah
it's it's just a blissful experience
libreoffice if you want to work in a
project where it's fun
and there's not massive conflict uh come
and see us anyway
so what do we do well gnu make we made
the make the build system easy to use
uh we fixed a whole load of coverity
defects uh we did systematic crash load
testing
interestingly we were always told that
we were the dirty hackers that didn't
know what they were doing and they were
the professional developers with our eye
teams and
you know process and so on um but you
know we just just
fixed so much junk in the in the code
base
over time i mean it's even fully
translated now the code base um
unit testing from not existing at all to
you know starting to be you know quite
significant
automated performance regression testing
running in valgrind
this is this is a cache grind is a
wonderful tool
and it's wonderful for one reason which
is that over over years of development
where nothing changed this line is flat
completely flat there's no jitter so you
can see from commit to commit you didn't
cause a regression even a small one
proper crash reporting fixing that code
quality improvement we threw every tool
at it we could find
pretty much and people were willing to
fund probably the best is oss fuzz
google's thing they're using afl and
clang but
just lots of other stuff and what you
discover is that as soon as you
introduce a new tool okay verity say
there's a massive burst of fixing and
then it tails off
and so you think oh we're brilliant
we've fixed everything and then you
introduce another one it finds a
different set of problems and we fix
those
so so here's the active commit account
um so it's it's a bit dodgy before
we use git but you can see various
historic things here so sun
sun was bought by oracle at this point
so you can see
the the things happen there cesar
decides to exit
uh a libre office and does it
beautifully cleanly
and you can see it tapers slightly but
they they then spin out calabra
and put some staff in there and some
funding to to create the company i
i run which is great at sib comes out of
caesar a bit and starts to do some stuff
this
screen line uh you can see uh yeah um so
you can see all sorts of things there
you can also see oracle disappearing
bingo suddenly gone and you can also see
the magnitude you know that we we
managed to recover the project
and keep it alive uh despite the the
sudden loss of staff
native languages yeah like 145 used
languages four and a half thousand plus
users doing translation fantastic work
there thank you for all
uh who do that and of course you would
regularly meet up fosdem was uh yeah
just wonderful
you know fosdem you know the support of
the open source community made this
made this fun you know it was nice to
come and talk and tell you the stories
of what we were doing uh give you usb
keys with the code on it
help you get started get people's first
hacks done you know plug the thing into
the laptop transfer it get their first
commit in
and so on at some stage i went around
collecting scalps leonard pottering has
a commit in it you know uh
greg kh you know we have we have a
number of number of people
who who uh you know so come and see me
if you want to get your first first
commitment we'll find something uh
something for you
um and of course you know conferences
are all over the place uh you know
the first one we were not good at taking
pictures as you can see but we got
better and better
and you know lots and lots of people
over the years
uh working on this susicon is next oh it
works again
excellent and then i'm just going to
flick through these
[Music]
i'm going to flick through these very
very quickly um
aha vba yes so i'm going to flick
through these quickly and i'm not going
to tell you anything about them because
the purpose of these features
is not the features but anyway a g
streamer auto shapes making smart
artwork nicely
ranges on text comments massive rtf
improvements
docx annotations cmis integration xml
importing conditional formatting icons
everything stock option pricing
android remotes beautiful android
remotes ios remote controls libra logo
for education improved image scaling
all sorts of left to right fixes for our
arabic and
israeli friends templates prettier
previews
widget layout so you can dynamically
size and adapt for language and make the
ui look pretty
reworking every user interface dialog
all you know 800
900 700 of them plus to use a proper
layout language
and native platform widgets using the
toolkit css animations beautiful stuff
unity integration good name three
integration personas to make it pretty
new trend lines character borders sifu
you know new icon themes everywhere
start screens making it look pretty
windows integration you know
policy management group management
lockdown a firebird so you can rid
ourselves of the last java pieces
of ultra fast calculation using your
hardware
prettier branding selling t-shirts
everywhere
formula wizards you can you can go to
our booth i'm sure and get one of these
a multi-threading support actually using
the rest of your hardware that's not
used
improve statistics better impress a
sidebar you know prettification and so
on
are better transitions much better
impress a view
3d transitions of all kinds of beautiful
things
yes we even have some bugs as well so
you know
but getting the high priority
regressions down to almost almost
nothing
and getting our regressions flat um
liberating your documents so
you know odf obviously helps you
liberate your documents if you can
already load them and
transfer to that but you know there's
all these old people word pro word
perfect abby word keynote uh the next
keynote format apple keeps changing its
formats in incompatible undocumented
ways
a vizio uh you know more better vizio
microsoft publisher
absolutely loads of these things out
there right i mean i gave up in 2016.
oh cloud stuff i'm so connecting to
cloud things alfresco integration
groupware integration for our online uh
version of libreoffice
uh colab nexcloud own cloud pydio
roof matamos well so why do i show you
all these things
because all of these things represent
years man decades
tens of man decades of work okay
twenties a man thirties of man decades
of work
and one of the problems we have as
engineers is that we think if we make
the software
better uh they will come you know
uh if you build the better mousetrap
people will buy it
and i still believe that you know if you
look at how i invest my own personal
money
you know it's in software development my
time is isn't some of them but actually
here's the tragedy it took five years
so most of the features i just showed
you there were already in
libreoffice and yet still more people
were downloading
something that fundamentally hasn't
changed in any
any feature function way since it was
launched
so this is the open office a trend line
right
and i i google cannot lie you know this
is uh this is
hard data from from you know loads and
loads of searches
and so actually all that branding that
we built in the first 10 years of
openoffice
took a huge amount of effort to turn
into
you know something positive and open and
uh you know community driven and so on
that actually works and get our brands
the point where people can see it
and that's a little bit concerning it's
a bit concerning
um and and we still have 250 000
downloads a week of something that is a
museum
of office productivity um which is a
great shame
it's disappointing users i mean it's
fair enough to to have museums i mean
it's good it's good i mean i love to
visit them it's it's interesting
but it disappoints users and it gives
them a bad image of
what free software can do and the
dynamism and excitement
that's possible there and so i think
there's two things there this is pretty
shameful and it should be fixed and
we've tried really hard to do that
but but also that the brand is really
important branding really matters
the equity you're putting into that name
you know and i still my friends still
say open office by mistake from time to
time it's one of those cognitive slips
that you know
that just sort of happens um and it's a
shame so it's very easy to think it's
about the code
about the features but actually branding
trademark
ecosystem investment almost more
important
uh i it's sad to say it but economics
drives
almost everything so you can see the
graph here of commands companies are
doing
nearly three-quarters of the commits in
libreoffice and they're awesome we love
all of our ecosystem
but yeah that's pretty frightening
they're of course mentoring
much of the rest of the quarter as well
right
so how do you do that and one of the
problems is the libreoffice has a brand
and that brand drives people to
a non-profit foundation which is which
is wonderful
but how can you then encourage people to
invest in that how can you give them a
stake in that and a viable business
i currently something like point one two
percent of people that hit the
libreoffice web page
even discover there are professional
services around it
okay so almost all of them donate
something and download which is which is
great
um but yeah how can you build that
thriving eq system such that this
this graph begins to be slightly similar
to this graph
or at least a closer and as you see
we're making progress i think it's gone
up from
point zero five percent to point one two
percent in the last year so there you go
anyway people are downloading it the
good news is we have you know i don't
know a million
eight hundred thousand uh downloads a
week which is which is encouraging
uh and certainly you know in the right
ballpark and going upwards uh which we
like although
heavily seasonal and and of course
interestingly
i mean it's a business product that
people use so they at the weekend it
drops off
and at christmas um yeah donations seem
to be going in the right direction
um and one this is a huge strength we're
just so grateful to our
64 000 donors who each gave
you know eight bucks each or whatever uh
to help us run
the foundation 12 12 bucks feature
whatever it is um
that's really cool absolutely cool so
here we are i'm supposed to invade on
the future and this is the very risky
part
uh you know who knows um i'm convinced
the future is a rocket ship you know so
so there we go
um but but who can predict the future
here so you can listen to your users and
see what they want
here's a here's a selection everything
is going to move to the web and go
online
everything else will be totally totally
ignored it'll all be in the browser
the next quote is from the same person
oh it's just
so cool i can download the app and run
it natively on my chromebook
i wish we could fix the bugs in that
you're like really
interesting and these are not this is a
strategy you know strategy
people to sense why respect their view
right um i want to collaborate on my
mobile phone you know
so phone's obviously the future um i
want to be able to load edit docs
offline you know
um i want to be able to use the
in-network when there is no network you
know all this all those sort of other
things
um it seems clear to me that the the
obvious solution is um
is to create a uh an artificial
intelligence of stunning subtlety and
you know conversational brilliance that
can see
what we should be doing at every point
uh so if you'd like to help join us and
and do that that's uh that's that's
great um
the other great way i have a predicting
the future is is telling you what's
already done
and just pending release so there's a
whole load of cool stuff in calibre
online it allows collaborative editing
of documents
on your premise you own it digital
sovereignty
uh no control to anyone else so nice
sidebar stuff coming here on the right
to make the ui richer things that no one
else does
transitions animations and so on uh well
um
just just you know prettiness coming
editing master pages
for your presentation online you know i
don't think anyone else does this
it's too advanced a feature managing
conditional formats
rich dialogues to do that prettier ui
formula wizards uh you know just cool
color correcting your images in your in
your documents and so on
a better handle for resizing for
spreadsheet stuff
url pop-ups and so on and of course the
mobile mobile version 2
has had a completely new one-handed
ui rework so this is um you can download
this as collabora online mobile beta
and it's improving very rapidly it looks
familiar to people i hope
but again you can do cool things in
there you can't do actually we're just
taking the sidebar and wrapping this and
re
redoing that as native javascript
widgets um so you can uh
you can get lots of cool functionality
there
ios versions for for tablets and of
course that they work on android too
um so so that's i think partly the
future um
more mobile more online more
more richness but all reusing that same
core code base that's got
you know 35 years of awesome work
underneath it
underpinning that and you know some
really good functionality
so we'd love people to get involved we
have easy hacks
we've paid a lot of technical debt down
but there's lots more to do
if you love javascript after you've seen
your doctor
uh you can come come and help us you
know it's a it's
yeah it's a challenging and exciting
language but we have plenty of
javascript that needs
these uh doing c plus plus ux design
there's all sorts of things whatever
your skills are
we would love to work with you come and
talk to me um user experience i think is
one of the things that we really need to
be working on more
it's one of those never quite done
things but there are still loads of
paper cuts there there is a ux team that
meet
they have things they'd love to do
they're specified they have lush
artwork for it but they just need a
couple of programmers to help them
do the simple typing to make this work
and then of course when you change the
ui the documentation needs updating
so i think i'm almost in time
so i think that's pretty much the story
of uh libreoffice open office maybe a
bit about star office
the star of his times i was not there
you know i i'm afraid i
i only joined at the very end of star
office and talked to the open office
people
so i could be there at the launch and
help this uh this gnome
uh open office compromise but we did
what we had to uh to make the code base
survive
um yeah and just the sheer number of
people that did things there is
way exceeds my ability to write all
their names down
in the taxi while i was coming here um
which is when i finished much of the
slides um but
thank you thank you for all of the work
from those people are there
i think a key a key thing is that our
digital sovereignty is really important
um you know if you look at china china
collects your data in order to control
you
uh and to oppress you probably or to
maintain
social stability uh with them with the
with the right people at the top
uh is the perhaps a positive
construction um
america of course uh gathers your data
to sell you things
uh so you know a different uh different
different way of looking at data
and of course the european union has a
chance to pass you know have a different
path
uh where we you know we help drive and
teach the world about the importance of
guarding your
and controlling your not only your
software but also your data keeping it
on your premise
uh controlling yourself and and we
really enable that
you know and i am excited it's not just
us of course we do the office
collaborative piece but i've shown you
some of the integrations we have the
partners
there are great great tools and products
let me encourage you to work on those
and help
move people towards protecting
themselves their sovereignty
and arguably their society in the long
run so we need your help
come and help us make it better there's
some challenging fulfilling work i
i love it i'm still doing it uh you know
10 10 years in 20 years in and it's it's
it's cool
um really we'd love to to have that and
beyond that we rely on your support you
know maybe you never contributed
anything to libreoffice but we we love
the fact that you tell your friends
about it
uh that you help us with our branding
problem that you you keep us alive and
you you turn up and listen to this sort
of nonsense so thank you
thank you for your support we strongly
appreciate it
and yeah and you'll be very good
so if we can have a few questions i
think we have you have plenty of time to
get to the next talk
that is the first thing to say i have
finished ridiculously early there's 20
minutes
you know and then something else will
happen so you can rest and relax
we have a question or ask questions you
know that's that's
fantastic oh well get some water
well thanks michael for a great talk i
would like to hear
maybe a little bit more about the
certification
are the document foundation happy with
the current state of the certification
would you like to see
more certifications exam and maybe
partner up with linux professional
institute so you can take them
both together i don't know cool
so i think we discovered earlier the
acoustics are not wonderful in here for
questions but i think you said you want
more certification
and linux professional institute
certification exams and so on
we'd love that anyone that can help
contribute is good
our certification currently is primarily
focused on professionals
to help grow our ecosystem and get more
companies and individuals to contribute
to and improve the project
um so end user certification is not what
we're doing really um but we'd love
other people to do that
talk to italo he's here and he runs or
loaf rebecca
see i go to your booth and chat to them
if you have good ideas and you can help
we'd love it good good idea what's up
hi i'm alex first many thanks for for
for the
libreoffice students like it's great uh
i'm still like i have
two questions one the first one is do
you
um still have uh um
trouble with the lack of documentation
for microsoft's
format like that the new one that the
newer ones
and their support ability uh that's uh
the first thing and the second thing is
uh
who what do you see is your like
greatest
competition is like is it like still
microsoft office
or uh the the google uh documents
uh ecosystem or is that an opportunity
to grow
yeah so good two good questions the
first was about open xml and
documentation and interoperability
so i think i think our interoperability
is outstanding and improving
um i don't think there's any other code
base that does as well as we do in terms
of allowing you to view and understand
and edit those documents
um you know look these are very old code
bases
microsoft calls it source code legacy
rich
and i think that's a positive framing um
the documentation is pretty good it's
usually not the documentation it's the
problem it's the time
spent to implement the feature because
it's no good
if you don't have the feature you can't
interoperate terribly easily
so that was that and then in terms of
your other question which was
competition uh who's our competition
well i hope
people are aware of uh who who are who's
out there uh producing
a software but um i think you know
clearly microsoft is is the big beast in
the room
you know in terms of the the desktop
product um in terms of the online
product
um i think you know there are all sorts
of marketing niches you know digital
sovereignty is a great niche to be in
people who care about having their data
under control you know lawyers
professional you know professionals in
all sorts of spheres medicine and so on
you don't don't want to be handing out
your data to someone
someone else uh so so i think there's
some great niches there and yeah
obviously we compete with everyone that
makes an office suite
um but you know i'm excited about what's
going on sir
uh hi do you sorry
uh do you ever work with uh the
developers of open office or neo office
do you talk with them or
collaborate they're friends of mine well
to some degree like
the neo-office people i think still
exist i i don't
i haven't talked to patrick and ed for a
long time um
but our mac mac builds are now pretty
capable uh you know so
so they're cool and yeah of course we
talked to the open office people to try
and resolve the uh you know
uh the divide whenever we can um
yeah i mean you know what can you do you
know i i think there are all sorts of
really positive stories we can tell
if we can encourage the users to use
something that's better
so yeah i mean like this yeah
so come and see me if you if you're
involved with apache and have good ideas
good question one more two more
any questions so far
[Music]
anything at all well in which case
you've been extremely good
and well behaved thank you so much have
a great day
you