Thanks hi old I'm Anastasia Stannis my
talk is about light with hypervisors in
the cloud above the aides I'm going to
talk about our work in our team we are a
youngest and me we're doing research in
hypervisors and and the low level parts
of the stack we are almost seven people
most of the things here you can ping us
right there in front you can think of
any time to grab a coffee or a beer
we're working on on the lower level
parts of the stock
meaning with hypervisors with containers
with antenna runtimes with storage with
uni kernels and we're also working on
accessing hardware accelerators from
within VMs or containers or unique
animals we're based in the UK in Greece
and in Spain so this talk is about how
we should handle the hypervisor layers
and that and the virtualization layers
in general at the edge so people are
using micro services based approaches
they're using platform as a service
software as a service function of the
service that several staff and they have
been using hypervisors or sandbox
environments or hybrid approaches on on
this level so we have been working on on
this kind of stuff and trying to
understand which is best for its
solution for its for the workloads that
people are running we will present a
minimal light with vm m which interfaces
directly
with a VM and some of the work that we
did to port the Firecracker on on a
Raspberry Pi so as as I mentioned people
are using containers sandboxes micro
vm's micro via MEMS all unique kernels
were not sure about that and we we have
seen that the community has introduced
some lower overhead via MEMS that can
host these approaches people are using
containers and unique Amazon containers
they're using sandbox environments like
that they're using second to actually
contain a specific workload within a
specific enclaved
they're using KVM to isolate workloads
there's work on solar 5 that the former
UK event you given stuff there's
firecracker this rusty and mam or cross
VM all that stuff but if we if we try to
run this kind of stuff on on a low power
device on a Raspberry Pi on a on an
Nvidia objection board we're getting
issues there seems to be a lot of of
contention in these kind of boards
additionally these boards are built to
have extra hardware to be able to
accelerate specific applications like NP
use or GPUs specifically to handle ML
workloads and and stuff like that so if
we try to run a VM on on this kind of
devices where we will probably end up
with either Zen or or TV M so the I'm an
Amazon guy so foolish
I've been working with them for quite
some time so I'm a more biased on their
approach so Zen is is a bare-metal
hypervisor and we are men there is no
mode treaties between the the monitor
and the hypervisor actually JVM is a is
Apache it's it's actually support for
the hardware extensions using a an
emulator in in user space there have
been approaches where people have been
not have been optimizing the the DMM
worth came alight with cross VM with
rusty I'm with firecracker with solo 5
stuff with the HVT tender at least so we
think that on one part KVM is really
useful in in terms of the hardware of
the of the interface for the hardware
extensions for VMs so it's it's easy to
debug it's easier to debug on Zen
because it's the the most of most of the
vmm is in the user space linux has all
the available device drivers to be
handled by by the system so there's no
custom porting there on the other hand
then has the VM and the hypervisor on
the same context so it's it's a bit
faster in terms of spawning a guest of
handling the memory of the guest and the
hardware extensions for for the memory
management but we need a driver domain
to handle device drivers to act to
interface with the external world of the
nodes that's a figure of how how kayvyun
handles the VM running
so there are device drivers in the Linux
kernel there's the network and
look stuck there are the functions that
KVM offers to to provide this kind of
isolation through the hardware
extensions there's a VM M running in
user space on the on the left side that
handles all the binary loading for the
VM OS to run some of the memory
management all the PV drivers and the
the exit handler for the VM when when a
privileged instruction needs to be
executed and on the right side is the
non route mode where the VM is running
so on on a VM enter there's the this the
streets from route mode to normal mode
at least on the x86 architecture the
application is running or in in user
space there's a runtime there are the
drivers to interface with the monitor so
it switches to kennel space on non earth
mode then the PV drivers communicate
with the PV drivers of of the monitor
there's another world switch there with
an exit with a with a VM exit and then
there's another there is another mode
treats to KVM to handle all the all the
hardware specific stuff I mean like in
the in them in the network occasionally
or in in the block case so all these
paths seem a bit they they seem to
produce a lot of overhead when handling
IO in in the same case the good thing is
that there's no there's no redundant
mode switch but still we need a helper
driver domain to be able to handle
device access so actually there is an
extra mode street and the next are world
treats
so we have been trying to understand
which are the overheads when running
stuff at low power devices and to do
that we we explored several lightweight
hypervisors and we we executed them on a
number of low-power devices are based
and on x86 so we we used a lot of tools
from from the community we used the the
RAM Ranjini kernel we used the Mira's OS
unique Ehrmann we run Redis and nginx
and the DNS example on on solar 5 on the
on the KVM tender of Scylla 5 which is
solar 5 hv t on firecracker on on chemo
and while sulfide worked out of the box
on on a Raspberry Pi the it's it's the
first thing that that we tried we tried
to run firecracker but it didn't work
because there's no geek support for for
the geek v2 version of of the interrupt
controller solar 5 actually works
because there's no interrupt handling so
we we run this simple unit kernel
[Music]
example so we with the blue bars we see
Khemu we have the client running on in
on the same host and the VM running on
kaymu on a on a CD core so the blue
lines show the the chemo results these
are requests per second so higher is
better and the red lines show salah
fiber hv t there is some kind of
improvement but still we think that it's
not enough so we we wanted to try how
firecracker would respond to this
to the set up firecracker is a huge
space monitor written in rust AWS Amazon
introduced it there was already support
for armed devices so what we had to do
was to just port gig v2 support we
managed to drop stirring this effort
which is good so far cracker now
supports I Raspberry Pi 4 and we run the
same experiment we see that that
firecracker behaves a bit like chemo and
solar 5 is still a better than than
those two approaches but still we we
think that there is a space for
improvement in this space so so actually
we we say that that very the
requirements for a for a work load to be
running on on such a low power device
should be that we need a driver for the
hardware extensions we need access to
the hardware so an interface a device
driver for the hardware we need to
define the ABI for the workload to be
running will it be a unique kernel Linux
something else and we need that a VM and
we and we need some kind of software to
be able to access and interface with the
hardware extensions and to handle via
mentor and VM exits so on
we think that KVM is fine it's it's a
great example for for the driver for
most platforms we think that the Linux
kernel is the most used thing
so we have drivers for almost every
device available regarding the the
binary interface were experimenting with
solo 5 we want to try micro VM the the
the firecracker approach or even the
Linux API and for the vmm we introduce
our own monitor so kV mm is actually a v
mm ramming in the linux kernel it
handles a VM enters and the VM exits
just the same way as km o or solo 5/8 VT
and it it interfaces with network and
block stock directly in the kernel so
this is an equivalent figure how off of
how a VM is running this is all in in
internal space so there is no mode
switch on on the VM exit and on via
Mentors
there is nothing that would interrupt
the execution the VM is running on the
under eye on on the right part of the of
the graph and the PV drivers are
interfacing with the vm m in the linux
kernel so there's only a root mode to do
non-root world suites
it's it's working progress so we're
working on that we have support for x86
and arm we are able to run sulla 5
applications and everything that support
that runs on top of solo 5 so we can run
rampant greenie kernels meritorious unit
craft recently we have tried to
integrate noci compatible runtime we
forked the work that the nabla
containers thing have done so it's as
easy as running dhakkir on with our
runtime
and specific image so we run the same
experiment with Redis that's up I should
mention that these results are on on x86
so we we can see that there is
improvement compared to eme on
firecracker and also improvement
compared to the generic solo 5 approach
regarding latency we have run a micro
benchmark ring for further for the
round-trip latency handling on x86 and
own arm we see that that k vm m is so
this is time so lower is better we can
see that k vm m outperforms all other
approaches and and the same stands for
forearm for for the arm case we run dot
America thus vim 3 board we could do a
small demo for showcasing our approach I
have a screencast
I have a Korean custom luxury of kind of
zoom can you see I'm not sure how to
zoom on that so the whole point let me
let me just skip that I'll just say what
what the demo is about so we login into
a into an Nvidia jets on nano board and
we actually run we execute doctor run
and and the container image with our
runtime and we we see that we if we
point a DNS client to this IP address
that that the runtime has given us we
see that zones are being resolved as
they should so it's actually showcasing
our vmm on an unarmed device let me go
back I think okay let me conclude so
we've shown with some TV mm which is a
minimal virtual machine monitor residing
in the Linux kernel we currently support
the sole of five ABI and we're planning
to have a pre-alpha release sometime
next month our next steps are to support
more ABI so we would like to try running
something more let's say extending our
our ability to run more applications we
would like to study the the container
integration there's some work we have
been doing some work on in
eating container storage and uni Kendall
storage and bridging the gap actually
when we run clinical containers as when
we run eunuch analyst as pass containers
and also we would like to try some of
the of recent approach by the community
like VM forking or pre allocation of of
V CPUs to be able to handle to to have
instant respond times I would like to
mention that this project is partially
funded by horizon 2020 projects and also
I would like to take the opportunity to
invite you to submit a paper in our
workshop on I see this year it's in June
21 25th and the deadline is April 5th
thanks very much
you can also feel free to check out our
blog blog cloud canvas.net or our github
[Music]
so so the question is if we were using
the host why are we better than than the
game or the Firecracker alternative so
we are using the host that's one thing
that the second thing is that for these
kind of benchmarks we are in on on a
Layton sees analytics side so because
it's not helping with latency at all it
should I'm not sure okay we can shut
about the flying but I I think that in
the in the V host case if the message
size is large then you do get the same
result if if the message size is small I
think you get an exit
back then because you waited for too
long for the Packer to come in sure sure
sure but sure yes and just to be clear
we're doing the exact same thing as
solar fiber came before the exit and the
our how they are handling there's a
hyper coal we you wake up in the monitor
and you do the the send message we
receive my certificates for the network
and actually we have been thinking that
we don't have to use having avatar your
approach or the solo 5 approach which
which just poles we could use something
which is more elegant and tailored to
our approach I mean if you if you are
already in the kernel then we don't have
to do anything complicated like iron
rings or you could just forward requests
from the guests to the network or to
storage so it's what you always want
optimized for in nvm worlds to not have
exits because any exit is always slow
it's always going to be through the slow
path whatever you do if you can somehow
avoid to do accept is exactly what all
of the modern interfaces are about like
the V host or i/o Ewing or everybody
who's like if even the smart NICs do the
same thing right the whole point is to
not ever exit the VM at all if you're
doing UI oh yes you might end up
sacrificing a core but again especially
on edge devices you have in order cores
just lying around basically you could
dedicate one of those just to to keep
handling you IO in the background if we
could integrate with what I'd suggest
earlier with IO Ewing or maybe just
prove Rijos - to do the polling for you
on behalf of you you might literally get
to the same performance numbers as
bi-metal most likely yeah could be
issue is that we need to exit to ensure
isolation in this kind of case so no I
disagree and we don't we don't need to
exit - into if you need to exit you need
to make sure you have only access to the
data you actually need to from from the
the polling side but that doesn't have
to be the same entity as like the vmm it
can be defined either way um I don't
think this is the like we don't have the
time to to go through this in detail so
let's take this offline and then okay
[Applause]