hey everyone good evening
hey yay we've managed that because this
is the last session
the last talk say uh lightning talks um
we got um
this many uh volunteers here i'm very
glad to report
um so more or less all slots are filled
we're not probably not going to run this
until the very last second otherwise we
will get
kicked out violently so i thought
everybody got
eight minutes and then we will um 30
seconds before i will stand up and then
at eight minutes we will
friendly cut the people off with a round
of applause
and we start with olivier
thank you starson uh good night
everybody
i'm going to present the current
status of the help editor
okay so basically what we have is this
uh editor is
made for editing the xml
and
we we
i need my computer well okay
let's let's let's go base what we have
is
is essentially um this editor we can
open and choose a file of uh
uh of help to open i don't have any file
in this local computer so i can't
pick one you can also save it okay
but you also can start a document from
scratch
and we have set all these menus
to make some xml blocks so that it makes
it
easier for us to edit
the contents of a file or to create a
new file
this case here i will start a new hxp
document it asks me just because i'm
going to clean
uh the editor and then i will have to
i will add some new things so i say okay
and it starts giving me
this xml which is exactly the start the
uh
the initial uh content of our next of an
help file you have the meta we have the
the help document we have all the tags
this editor here is code mirror
okay and with this code mirror we have
implemented not only the edition
but also several add-ons so i can
display use for example
the full screen editing we have a search
and replace
feature we have
auto complete tags everything is
available for
making easy to edit
for example here i start my
my editing here in the body
if i want to add something i just click
here
for example and i want to make a title
so
i'm going to type whatever thing here
and then just a moment
then i select it here
and i format as a paragraph
or for example a heading such as
h1 it immediately
surrounds my my text by the proper
tag and it adds a specific
identification which uh is unique
inside the file so something that is
very cumbersome for
whoever edits the
help files in in libreoffice is to find
a new string for your unique
identification
and when i'm done i can
he come here with the tools and asked to
render the page
and okay
so we have resolution issues here
well it's it should have rendered the
page on the left
yeah we have a resolution issue here uh
it uh
the result of this page is displayed
here
and you can see exactly what you
are typing unfortunately it's not
working here
i don't okay
okay so here well yes
so here is the render page sorry it
should have been on the
on the on the right but then you have
your title here
and i have also implemented the
possibility to make a choice
uh you those who knows uh who edits
help files knows that there is
difference between the systems
and also difference between the modules
it's surrounded by this switching line
or switch tag that we use
and here is so here in the results
we have also other debug info
okay and also we have implemented
some uh some checkings
for example i want to check if the file
is
and it's
it makes the validation so first of all
checks if the xml is correct so you have
open a tag and you have also closed the
tag
check with the xml document type
definition
to be to see if the dtd is correct and
also
check if there is a duplicate id in in
the file
okay so before you submit your your file
you can
run these checks and it will guarantee
that your phone
will be correct for the help the help
okay we have implemented other
other niceties such as
in the dock heating for example just to
come back here
uh if i want to introduce a heading
sorry
where i am here where is my mouth
well i lost the mouse not sure where i
am
yes it's on the other side
no
yes it's close it's bounded here i can i
can't use it so
um
okay so here we here we are
so we we we can for example introduce
this chunk of of xml which is the
dock heading
and it will introduce here
lots of i'm sorry
[Applause]
lots of uh a section
id the bookmarks the heading
the paragraph with the a help everything
is already there
and with some uh placeholders
so that you can easily feel with the
content okay
um also so base what we have is
the bookmarks several bookmarks you can
fill the sections uh generic sections
the section that is the related topics
the how to get
divisions that are for basic code and
python codes we have some
templates for tables if i
click and add a table here
for example it it will generate
all the table for me
okay with all the structure and then i
feel the content of the table
and we plan to
one minute 30 seconds and we plan to
implement
uh not only to generate a patch
to be submitted to garrett and also
eventually to load the files directly
from
the master branch and
some uh help uh pages the
hhp reference uh that explained
okay yes so
you could have
hello my name is kisha and i'm libra
office developer and i'm working
in collaboration i will talk about the
improvic libreoffice in interrupt
operability in libreoffice and
when we want to open a o xml
based document in libreoffice sometimes
we
can have some problems and to solve
them and first if
we have a bug report first reproduce to
we need report the bug
and second we simplify the
back document because we need to focus
on the problematic part and
we should do it step by step and
check it after every step the box still
there and if it's possible
we can we should create a bug from
scratch
and after uh
we should try it back in all the
libreoffice versions
if there is no bug in other and older
versions in its regression
and we can use git bisect
to find guilty commits
the and the documents
all the odt and docx pptx
and these all uh documents it's
zip compressed device and when we open
it
in unzip and we can use read
xml files and
we can pick some clues from that xml
files
and the files
are unreadable but an examined
tool is corrects the
indentations
[Music]
if if it's possible to create
a correct document and we can encompa
and compare a problem and problematic
and non
problematic files
to solve the bug the mod is
a great tool for this compression and
it has a nice vigilation and it allows
us
and compared the directories and after
that
when we pick up all the clues
and we should grab on the source code
and debug and try to fix it
i want to give an example and that i
sold before
in this back report we have a document
when we save in libreoffice and open
again we missed
three digits after the comma
in the chart level and
while i saw solving
first i reproduced back i saw
the bug i see i saw the bug is there
the simple the document was uh
enough simple and i tried
it with all the libreoffice but back
back was there and it is not
it was not a regression and four
i examine the
chart label in chart level properties in
microsoft office and i saw the person
the checkbox is checked
i looked for the corresponding feature
in libreoffice and i found it
and i i debug it
to learn how it works and after
i unzipped the file and
i found a suspected attack
here the non-format format code
when i compare them
before and after the file
saving the file i saw the format code
missing in buggy file and
i read the related xml
specs and learn
what that tags it does
and i gripped and debug
var the external export
code and i found it and
and i have at the format called
attributes
in the new format okay attack
and i saw this all about is
picking some true key words
to graph in libreoffice the other part
is
your code reading skills and debug
skills
that's the patch that i
sent and that's all thank you
[Applause]
do we need this thing
okay
hello test test
okay i'm svante schubert pleased to meet
you
while he's looking up i'm i'm going to
give you a disruption warning now a 10
minute disruption warning i wasn't sure
if it's three minutes or four or
five minutes so i only got 10 slides i
would have taken more
so um while he's trying to find
yeah just found scrambled should be
possible
windows i believe oh no few
sorry
great hello
so this could be libreoffice and i hope
it won't become libreoffice
so i give now fair enough a very
short disruption warning disruptive in
the sense of
just second do i use this one yeah um in
um disrupt this feature i have in mind
like in nokia
one of the leaders i love my nokia
phones i was was very proud of my nokia
phones
but then the smartphone came and they
were gone right so
i'm proud to be here with libreoffice
and i don't want that it happens again
so what kind of disruption might happen
there so
we have in the tdf um a new toolkit more
or less new it started with sun at
the beginning of 2000s and we put all
the java source code we have to
manipulate odf
documents and it went from
apache now to ddf and was forked by
um by the open exchange
for their back end and i merged it back
and soon you see there's a snapshot one
zero zero this feature will be
integrated and this is all wait a minute
how can i do this
okay just a second try to
oh yeah it is wonderful all right so
that's very simple
so are we doing now it's just a green
box here
not a black box because open source so
we drop in the text document and it
becomes
um totally equivalent sequence of user
changes so
we're entering now the real move changes
here and you can merge new changes back
why we're doing this
because we don't wanna as a software
developer zip our source code
repositories and then send them to other
developers
um if we share our work all we want to
do we want to
dispatch commits this changes so we are
able to merge them back
but it's impossible we have zipped xml
and these are like repositories
and we need to come down to changes to
really do collaboration
like in asynchronous offline
collaboration where we can
um where we can work together in a more
comfortable way
and this is becoming actually a feature
and i'm going to document now i'm just
documenting this all the way to doing
now
so in the end i would love to
standardize even the changes so not only
the full zip
repository is being changed but there's
some odf change
and you see um it doesn't matter how we
serialize it it's
the user knowledge of these things the
entities when i phone you about my
change and it's gonna call you
hey by the way in the third paragraph
the second letter please delete it okay
if you if you follow my mom she doesn't
know anything on odf or so but but she's
sitting in a from libra office and you
tell her there's the table there's the
image then there's a paragraph and this
paragraph
go to number um now make the third
character the fifth police bolt
and that's the way we we go to the
semantic level with stable
and we are going to standardize these
semantic entities and set them around
so in the end we do a fine collaboration
here so
why is it cool what can we do now so we
are first extended
we know as long as sending repositories
we're going to send changes right
so we might be as github we can say
there's some famous author now having
his book outside and he doesn't want to
get copies because it's a very huge book
but you can send a gif
sorry a github pull request saying oh by
the way this
1 000 countable thing that's being a
paragraph there's a typo please delete
it and you can take just to take a look
at this tiny thing and change and you
can say oh
cool i merge it there's no bad jokes in
this uh
copy he might receive so it's very easy
and very comfortable
and of course um version systems like
git currently there are only
line based and uh there's only binary
file but if we go to abstract semantic
level
then we we can say um what are the
difference between two
versions of this uh contract for
instance and somebody say
okay we just return these changes we
just defined and you say oh
um and the third there's a new third
paragraph and the fifth one we've
deleted
okay so we can come to a new level
of um collaboration and handling with
documents right
and i think one of the most powerful
things is that
these changes already exist among
multiple not only odf applications but
in html there are paragraphs as well and
there's bold italic and
tables and they do the same operations
like insert a row into the column
and you can even load an odf document a
full feature document in a vi
in text document emacs by simply saying
every line
is a paragraph and there's text and we
just receive
from all these changes um these changes
that are
about paragraphs and tables and align
reorder the positions
to addition in the editor doing uh
additions
and then we merge these changes back and
filling all these features that are
where are known earlier back in so we
are merging changes back and not
like we always do with the floppy disk
load everything safely thing
so when you ever edit it with
libreoffice word
a very huge document and you make a
small change and say oh i better save i
don't want to lose it then
waiting everything everything is being
saved doesn't matter it doesn't have to
do
because all you have to do now is to
save only the change
or just to merge it back so it's
becoming much much more faster
and if we all got copies of documents
and you give me back your changes or
a single change i don't have to look at
all the documents and pass them
i just take the changes each one and put
them together yes compare these changes
so the the merge is no longer dependent
on the on the size of the document but
the amount of changes
all right so
and so we have a different level of
interability and um
we'll see how it's going to um and why
we are in danger
because it's very hard to implement in
the libreoffice um
people are not customers not demanding
it because it's they don't aware that
that's possible and it's very hard
uh i heard from developers to imple
implement it in a way that's being um
that you see something like i asked
michael stahl what he needs
and he said i need a time machine
because the design
what was chosen the 80th was totally
different from floppities no internet
to the current days were always the
internet and we're collaborating with
ourselves all the time
and so if
there's no danger yet right there's only
this tiny back-end tool not front-end
nobody is aware of this feature maybe
you are but
um no user knows it but if others taking
this up
and building let's say like cak 8.5
which have changes in their model
by design losing this to using this to
load and
edit um office documents
with odf and embracing git then it's
becoming very very powerful and then we
are in a danger
so what i'm suggesting here is
that we are no sorry that was an old
slide
we are we are we are really implementing
it right we
and if we are not doing it then i think
the document foundation
if should take care of and
it's not for me because i'm not actually
coding in libreoffice
but i think it's important that we have
this in our
view okay thank you for listening
hdmi is on
yep
now my talk is about bin bags
not really um but the foster organizers
came in before so sorry for a bit of
disturbance during your talk but they
said if we have any rubbish
left uh we need to collect it together
so if you've got anything you don't want
to take with you tonight
we'll just put it all in the bin bag
here yeah close the windows and
because you know i think they're all
working voluntary and they're doing the
best they can so
we'll leave that there now um one of the
biggest problems we have
in an open source project is um
crediting contributors
and making them feel um uh
showing that we're really grateful for
everything they do obviously we can
invite them to conferences
uh we can send them stickers and small
merchandise and gifts like that as well
but what are some other ways
how can we say thank you and make them
feel really
um appreciated and one way is with open
badges that some of you
may have heard of before so this is the
super short description open badges
verifiable portable digital badges with
embedded metadata about skills and
achievements so these are
png images with metadata inside
to um show what somebody has done why
they are awesome
uh as well um the fedora project uses
them i'll show you in a second
um good way to show appreciation to
contributors and
it's hosted it's its own open source
project here's how
fedora does it so these are all
people in the fedora project active all
their usernames
and when they hit a certain milestone
when they've done something
they get a badge they have lots of
automated systems set up for this as
well
and they they make it into a sort of
friendly competition between people in
the community
so if you've done 150
git commits or wiki edits or 150 some
things you get a certain batch
as well so and then they show who's
leading in the week who's leading in the
month they gather all the information
from all the different activity in the
fedora project
and then they give these badges now you
can decide you can define
what these levels are what these
thresholds are it can be for the first
time somebody commits
actually gets their patch committed to
the libreoffice source code tree they
get a batch
as well you know cool we can decide all
that as well
so slightly boring technical stuff but
the badges
are defined by json files as well so
just involves
poking around in those three files the
issuer which
in this case is us libreoffice the
document foundation the badge class that
defines the type of award we want to
give so maybe for 100 wiki edits
or for 10 code commits a thousand
questions
answered on ask libreoffice our user
assistant website for instance
and then this json file that's very
specific for the person who gets
the uh gets the badge so here's an
example
again not super exciting but just so you
can see
this is who gets the badge this is
when it was issued but this is very
important as well this um
this is super important this verified
thing because
when we issue a badge and if somebody
wants to show off that they have a
really nice badge from the document
foundation that they've
written 20 code patches or answered 500
questions
with this it can be verified that we
issued the badge
so it's not just somebody has opened a
png image in a hex editor and poked all
this data inside
and this isn't this is good when people
really want to show off their badges for
future um work opportunities as well
so to say i've got a i've contributed a
lot to a big project like libreoffice
and i want to show that i want to put it
on my linkedin profile or
social media it's not just a little
cutesy thing that they're given but
actually like
this is real stuff that the libreoffice
project has shown they appreciate what
i'm doing and i've contributed enough so
we have a couple of badge designs thanks
to our community as well
um i quite like this one personally
because i think it's quite quirky and
fun
but if again if people want to show them
off on their on their linkedin profiles
and they really want to use it to to
further their job opportunities
then something like this may be better
so we'll have a bit of a discussion
in the design community maybe use both
let's see
but we have this working the tooling is
set up
as well um so the plan is now let's go
ahead and do it so
after in the next few days after
fostering we can start giving badges to
people
for their work we can thanks to
gillem and the infrastructure team as
well we can get lots of statistics from
different services and tools in the
project
so we can run commands to see who has
answered 500 questions on ask
libreoffice who has made
500 wiki commits whatever code commits
as well i think even
bug reports this there are a few other
things we can do gather the data
my plan is to initially give badges to
people personally so to generate a badge
and then email somebody
and say with a personal thanks for for
your contributions
um so to start off a bit smaller but
with a
sort of customized message the way the
fedora guys do it which is cool
is it's all done automatically in this
nice system
maybe we can go to that as well we can
aggregate lots of data and issue the
badges
automatically but i think at the start i
want to send them to people and say
thanks a lot you know we really
appreciate it here's something it's not
just a nice
shiny png image but this has data that
you can then show to a potential
employer um yep so that's the plan
um do it personally for now and then
automate it later
um then maybe some of you will be
receiving badges from me soon as well
so and then you can open them up in a
hex editor and check that they're real
that's the back and i think that's it
yep was that eight minutes
okay uh it shouldn't be like a new
design.org but hub
uh slash badges slash
whatever which redirects
okay sure yeah we're just using new
design at the moment for testing
purposes
that's a good point i'll make a note for
when we implement it live yeah thanks
okay
most probably it won't but we'll see
so um let me just introduce myself
um i have a fancy
app here and a fancy device
and i would like to show you what we did
in the last couple of months
so my name is nicholas i work for ad
finishes with
free and open source service provider
and i will become a deputy
board of directors for the dtf soon
you can also follow me on twitter where
i use the
nexlore twitter
name so what you can see here now is
libroff is more or less running on um
natively on an ipad um i would like to
explain a little bit what we did here so
this is not
um online so i can actually disable
wi-fi
and everything will work as it should
so the app is um using the same code
base as
libreoffice online does and it's also
the same as we
we are using on android and candy showed
it
this afternoon as well and i would like
to show you a couple of um
things that we can do with the app so if
you open the app what you actually see
is the
the native ios file manager and i
prepared a couple of
files just to show you um a couple of
easy things so let's start with the text
document
there you can see that it's
more or less the same uh use user
interface as we have in in online
but we have some um things that you can
do
um using the native functions that are
your sprite so for example i can use the
emoji keyboard to add some emojis
or um i can copy and paste
pictures from from the browser for
example so if i have
this little animal here oh okay yeah so
the browser is offline
now as well but um let's just connect
to the wi-fi again um i can copy and
paste pictures um from other
applications to to the app as well
um we can use um things
with the finger so you cannot see that i
touch the screen by them if i want to
resize
the table i can actually do that with
with my finger i can also
just tap on one of the gray areas around
the table to select things and make them
bold for example
we also have quite big handles around
the picture to just resize them with the
finger you can also
rotate them and you also have the
sidebar for example um
which you already know from from the
desktop version
um and there you can also see that we
have
quite big widgets to just
use them with the finger as well
what i also especially like is if we use
the spreadsheet component you can
actually
use the hardware keyboard that was not
possible
until i think ios 13 or something
so now if you um want to select the cell
range you can do it with the handles as
well but sometimes you just want to use
the keyboard so you can just use
the usual um shortcuts like shift and
then
um just use the arrow keys on the
keyboard as well
same also works for formulas so if you
start to write the formula
and then you can use the um
the hardware keys to actually select the
range as well
and do things like that you can also
just then
select the range of cells insert
a diagram and
these things will also update so if i
just use a
much bigger number here you will see
that
the diagram will change and um
this all works natively or like you
don't need an internet connection
and we can also have a look at
the empress part so um there's a
slide deck that i prepared and
of course we can can edit things here
um change text and then
start the slideshow navigate to
those slides have um charts
here as well and then
you can um edit everything as you would
expect
um there of course are still a number of
things that don't work
um it's still work in progress um but i
think the
next um release the 4.2 release
should bring quite a bit of um
these nice new features one thing that i
also would like to show is the dialogues
the native dialogues
that you should know from from
libreoffice they look a bit
like ios native dialogues with those
green
switches and um yeah
things that are big enough to actually
use with the finger
so that's more or less what i would like
to show you can
download it from the store from the
apple store i have it somewhere open
it's
um right now
you can use the colabora build and
i would like like to censor thanks also
the the developers from collabora
for their support for the heavy invest
they uh did
and um it's fair to um give them a
uh shorter plows or pay them a beer
later on so
if you use collaborative office the
search term you should find
the version right now it's 4.1 that you
can find but i think you should
get 4.2 through test flight and also as
a final building
in a couple of weeks i hope that's it
thank you very much
any questions
[Applause]
[Music]
no questions good thank you
okay so it's me so i'm cheating a little
bit so it's um what i'm talking about
it's not going to be
um about um libreoffice for a change
um but it's about something that i care
a lot about which is a digital workflows
so i was hacking a bit
with boobly on something that
many of you might know which is
poplar and ocular which is some
one of the more
more popular pdf viewers on
on free operating systems
so since this is uh not a native linux
i'm just gonna
play some um screencasts i must say
uh i was doing so the problem um that um
rises obviously these days is that you
that you want to sign
um documents digitally not not printed
out and
paper and then scan it again so that
that's a feature that's broadly missing
except for libreoffice so libreoffice
can do that
but there might be documents that you're
not generating in libreoffice so what
you're going to do
um so well this document is generated
now in libreoffice um but
um what i'll show you now in a moment
while i'm trying to save that down
is that so that there's two patches um
two merch requests one for poplar that's
more or less
building on something that someone did
four years ago
which started that and then um i took
quite a bit of code
from libreoffice um that was done i
think but
with this crowdfunding from this uh
willem talks project i've got this
partis pardess extension so that's like
time stamping authority
and other nice nice things and put that
into poplar which is um the the let's
say the low level pdf
reader and renderer and then added
as a bit of ui on top um which no no
that's not me that was bubbly but i was
kind of
just doing the finishing touches in the
last
few weeks um so while this is
building i wonder if i can just forward
that it's getting a bit boring
um
so yeah let me let me just ramble on so
right so um actually i think i skipped
too far
um so that's the um the actual document
that was signed already
unfortunately i can't
there's no key frames there so it always
has to oh yeah
there we go so that's the the generated
document with the
signature stamp and the party's
stamp of approval there in libreoffice
i should probably scroll back a bit
further
so that you can actually see that it's
ocular doing that
and then the workflow is essentially
like like an um
um and an acrobat or other so you just
um
yeah you you open some you draw some
rectangle
okay there we go so that's the document
you pre you bump the sign button
you draw a rectangle where you want to
put the signature
um you select your your certificate
you sign it eventually i will do that
there
right so
that pulls the like like libreoffice as
well pulls that out of the
nss defaulting to firefox configurable
keystore
and then eventually
select that yes come on
okay and then saves that and reloads
that and
um it's all down
okay so this is um right now this is in
review
the idea really is um to have um
with pure open source to have the
complete
set of tools that you need for a fully
digital workflow
where you don't need any proprietary
software anymore you don't need to go
and and have clumsy workarounds or worse
printed to paper so
and yes there it is okay i bought you
enough
um let's pause that for the moment any
comments questions
you have a bit of time
great thanks
so
this
you don't see anything
so
um
all right uh you've seen a lot of very
professional called uh
talks in this lightning talk session and
even one with the linkedin linked
in the early days of libreoffice it was
a little bit more cowboy so who
who knows what will happen if i press
return here
right it takes some time but uh
after that my slow ssd should find that
uh this hasn't been optimized from 1989
till
libreoffice 6-0 and there was a talk by
mikhail style
are we optimized yet and since then we
are optimized
so it was only 20 years
so trigger warning drugs
what number do you expect to come out of
that
it's not one line so it's
if you want to see an especially
interesting one
maybe look at that one
i'm not doing this to protect the guilty
who knows what will we find with this
yeah that was i think it was in when
libra offers started and
it's still in
who's german here
okay so let's let's quickly see this one
for
you guys and if you want to make a
german very happy you can ask them to
explain the joke
to you
all right and finally
uh i also want to like this whole talk
is essentially be careful
it never forgets um
the last one we also have storytelling
the guilty are smiling they know what's
coming
we also know we also have storytellers
in the project
um i really love this
uh source code comment and with that
thank you and uh let's have a nice
little round of uh
fun tonight thanks
um