okay
uh hello everyone uh welcome to the
decision
uh my name is batwan i'm a high school
student from turkey
and in this session i'm going to talk
about llvm and python
uh this talk is specific to python and
uh
the approaches taken by uh python's jit
compilers using elevm
but there are some good points that can
be used in
compiling dynamic language style vmware
uh so we are going to start with uh
c python's workflow and pipeline uh
you may see this irrelevant but uh most
of the applications use
this workflows pipes to
generate ir ldmir and jit compile
then we are going to see a dynamic
nature of c python
like why you shouldn't trust user code
and why can't we can easily
convert python to llvm or other
representations then we are going to see
some
projects that are not currently
under development and dead because of
some reasons
uh the first one is unladen swallow it's
a google sponsored fork of c python
uh which is
which tried to bring llvm into python's
core
but then google lost its interest
google's clients lost
its interest so uh
it's that then there is pipe to llvm and
pile album pythagorean was an old
project
uh by indie developer and it is
retrieved as pi alvian
and the both are that right arm it's the
edit compiler for python 2.
and piston keystone is relatively new
project
it is sponsored by dropbox but then
dropbox switched
performance critical code to other
languages such as go
and it is also that there are some
current projects like number
uh number is a jit compiler for
uh numpy python mathematical uh
oriented code which uses llvm light at
the back end
and alvian knight is a python binding
style lvm
which offers a great api and
it offers a way to access jit execution
engine of llvm
and in the future part we are going to
see how we can uh
implement and develop a jit compiler for
python
in two ways one is converting python's
ast into the
llvm wire and one is convert python's
bad code to llvmr
uh we are going to start to see python's
workflow
uh c python takes your source and uh
generates tokens from it tokens are
individual parts
and they have no relations then
the c python's partial takes the tokens
and constructs a concrete syntax tree
uh which has relationships but it is
hard to work on
and then uh it shifts uh all of the
irrelevant information from that
concrete syntax three
and constructs an uh asd
and then uh through the ac it constructs
a control flow graph like structure
there are no real control flow graphs
in c python uh and uh
but there's some structure that like
control flow guard and it generates
bytecode
from the ast and that structure and then
it executes that bytecode
uh in python's virtual machine uh
the code the astn bytecode is suitable
for coordination
but the other parts aren't uh and let's
see
them in details uh the tokenization
starts with reading your python file
like
it should be a dot power that py file or
the standard
input that doesn't matter python reads
the file decodes
its contents in the encoding you have
specified
or utf-8 and it tokenizes it with
certain patterns like that patterns uh
depends on the context
it knows how to split a dot b it has an
individual
meaning by its own it has an individual
meaning by its own
but it doesn't split 1.1 because 1.1 is
a flawed
but you can use tokens to generate a
machine code because there are no
relationships
no blocks no nothing uh it's pretty rare
format
like this is a
okay can i highlight this yeah uh
this is some tokens like one is number
operator is plus uh i know you can't see
it
because of highlight yeah uh the number
uh this is oneplus one
but you can generate code from this
because there are no relationships
then there is a parser parser is a
program that takes that generates tokens
and uses rules to construct a tree
like structure concrete and congress
next three
spread complex uh because there's
uh irrelevant information such as white
space
or parenthesis uh
there are relationships but the blocks
aren't suitable for direct code
generation
and python's parser interface is
deprecated and will be removed
so python advocates the work on in ast
level
ast is the abstract version of that
concrete syntax tree
there are nodes that are defined in a
stl
format the fierce asl format which are
easy to work on
like uh when you pass a function it says
this is the return this is the
function's name
this is the annotations of the functions
code uh etc etc
python says uh you can manipulate this
or generate your code from ast i give
you some interfaces some helper
functions
but don't use the parser because it's so
rough
and it keeps only relevant information
for generating code
like it doesn't keep any white space or
comments
it keeps line no information for syntax
errors
uh for highlighting like where this
syntax error happened
uh this is an example of
pythons not visiting interface
like you can whenever python sees a
constant note
it will call the visit console handler
whenever it sees a
name node it will call the name handler
so you can generate
uh intermediate representation here
then after that asc step python will
construct
code objects code objects that contains
bytecode
and some information uh scored objects
uh
is going to execute under c python's
virtual machine uh
which is a stack based virtual machine
that works like
uh you push something you pop something
with the instructions
the instructions are formats like uh
there's opcode
and apart operation arguments
uh and there are some extra sequences
like if you use a load const opcode you
specify
argument as an index of call cons
data structure so it will make the
python faster
unfortunately there are no uh direct
interface to assemble bytecode in python
itself
the interface assemble are ast in python
but there are interfaces for
disassembling bytecode objects
which we can use in jit compiling the
functions body
uh just an example uh
function that takes x as an input and
compares if
x is greater than four returns power of
two etcetera etcetera
and when we disassemble this we see
instructions like this the first one is
a loadfest
uh it lost a local variable from the
argument
uh spec uh and they are format like this
uh there's uh this is jump target change
thing uh python stack base virtual
machine operates like
this it checks if x x is greater than
four
if not it pops directly here uh
if it is a uh it is true it runs this
place
so this is a jump target from the
from that return power of three line
yeah this was the workflow of c python
let's see why we can't directly trust
the user code
uh because we won't
give the types of the arguments or any
kind of name
they are all dynamic and it will make
our job
harder user can even change buildings
like
user can change lamp function or they
can even uh put handlers
inside of class definitions like when
you define a class python load something
called build class
which is a uh helper function and when
you change
build class from the built-ins module
whenever
someone defines a class in python your
function gets called
and this makes things even even more
harder and uh compared to other
languages
in python everything is miserable unless
you say otherwise
yeah let's see some attempts from the
past that tried to
integrate llvm with the uh python itself
online swallow uh it's a google
sponsored fork of c python that
tried to make a jit compiler for c
python itself
its name comes from monty python show uh
it has to make python faster
it's a fork of c python and they plan to
eventually merge this into the python
score
but then uh there are some side effects
which
prevent this it was sponsored by google
and then google lost its entirety
because
this was a fork and deployment was hard
google
hasn't any performance critical code in
python
and google's clients uh don't want to
allocate
money and time for this it's features
it's made python 2.5 times faster
on single thread python code it's single
thread it
they didn't solve the global interpreter
log problem
in python if you have a cpu bound code
it can run it runs one thread at a one
time
it it doesn't matter if you have
fortress it runs one thread
because of some reference counting
issues uh and
uh on ladies follow didn't solve it uh
but
uh it's uh make pastor my python faster
2.5 times
in single thread code their aim was five
times
but there are some problems about
reaching the name
they didn't break any part of the code
because they were already based on
c pythons itself so every c extension
run as usual
they analyzed python code before running
it
so they know if you change the lamp
function or not
uh so that they make some assumptions
performance on
this and some data collectors run time
like what fun
x function gets if if x function gets
always integers
uh they said uh okay generate a uh
intermediate representation
based on that fact but if it gets a
string
there's a guard which prevents it uh
these assumptions false
it converts bytecode it operates in the
bytecode level
instead of ast which is their choice
there is a hot threshold in unladen
swallow uh
so uh there's a cost of making one
a function compared to llvm so if a
function called
uh so many times and they know so many
about it uh
they compile to llvm and
before that compilation they collect uh
data about that function
uh help of the data
they know uh this uh they know if there
is a if
a branch never executed they just cut
out it
or if they know all arguments are
integer they
optimize for that but
ensuring that everything works as same
even the
arguments changed
they put guards which has caused
if mispredictions happen
and they worked with linking llvm into
the python binary
there are some cons bad sides of this
one is memory usage the memory usage
increased up to eight times
it's not always eight times but the
most part of it eight times
this is one of the cards of llvm and
other libraries
the increased network usage and if you
keep
different versions of same code in the
memory it will increase
by default so they keep the native code
they keep the bytecode they hit the asd
so memory is increased and there are
some optimizer
structures they try to optimize python
bytecode
before sending to llvm so they create
some structure
which gives pythons internal knowledge
but they have they caused uh
there are some console startup time
uh static linking again uh
and uh when you want to compile a python
function to lvm you need to initialize
llvm
and c plus plus initialize take some
time
and there are some overtops here on time
routines uh
binary size increased as usual because
you linked the llvm
uh why don't they reach the 2.5 times
they reach 2.5 times but not five times
uh because when they was working this
project was from
2009 llvm isn't that good at
just name compilation and they had some
issues
with that and llvms
uh digital doesn't work well with gdb
if you are developing a c extension in
python you probably want to debug it
with gdb
on set files and use all profile
and llvm's gt code didn't work well
so they allocate some time to fix this
but they lost some gain in performance
this project lasted one year and then we
will lose this
interest if the project continues uh
in my opinion they can reach the five
times goal easily on some quotes
uh some eleven points about this uh they
initially selected llvm because they
they don't want to generate assembly
code on every machine target
allowing was easy
the optimizations of coordination was
great but in 2009
it isn't directly suitable for gt inc
and cost of operations compiling was so
heavy
uh and
without calling sub runtime data it is
hard to optimize
they was collecting and they was
collecting after
learning this so they spent some time to
do this without collecting runtime data
the next project is pi alavian
which is a compiler for subset of python
that specializes in
machine learning uh algorithms and
computations
uh in python mathematical code gets
executed
slowly because of there's overlap of
dynamic
things if you compile this to llvm you
get
so much uh gain and they try to do this
uh their features are they are as fast
as
c code in some cases that compile with
clang
they only work for a subset of python uh
if your function doesn't fit that
subject they directly return your
python function if it fits they'll turn
a wrapper around the digit codes
they don't want they don't collect
runtime data but they do static type
inference and
symbol table generation python is a
symbol table which you can use
that comes with standard library but it
doesn't give you an anything about types
so you need to create your own symbol
table which records types and inverse
types which could be uh cool
uh they use something called lvmpi which
is a library airport library
around llvms api c plus plus api
they use python asd model inst of
bytecode which is
more suitable in my opinions
they try to convert the function body
and if
they see something that can become they
raise an error
and if they catch that error their they
return normal function
if they don't see that error they just
return the
function and they invert types
let's see piston piston uh is a jit
compiler
and the runtime for python 2 it's
runtime most based on c pythons
so they have some gain on that
they use something called tracing jits
and they specialize on web applications
especially dropbox they manage to run
jungle food test suites as far as i
remember
their features as their 95 percent
faster than c python in the latest
release
in 2017
they have c api support because of c
paths runtime
and uh in a big codebase you can run
piston with little changes
over the general code base they have
more than
three executors llvm is the highest
level and there's
egypt and there is a ast interpreter
so if your function
gets called gets
called less they interpret the functions
ast
if it is called more than 25 times they
get with uh
digits and if it's called more than one
thousand times they
they eat it with llvm
they have a select control flow graphs
and
as the interpreter two jits tracing and
they use something called inline caching
and rewriting of functions body
and c python based runtime so there are
some projects
uh from current dates uh
number number is up to date project that
uses llvm to jit
it's a jit compiler it's specialized in
uh
numpy and python functions it knows how
to boot sharpness to
is assembly level and gets
best performance such a subset
and it works only for only with type
inference if it knows
what types it gets uh it directly jits
if it does it doesn't know uh it
records runtime data uh it's used with
simple python decorative
you just add something uh at top of the
function
called legit and number automatically
handles
everything else uh it supports nvidia
kudo and amd rock experimentally
it's almost as fast as c in some cases
which is pretty good
uh it works like this it takes python
source
uh it uses bytecode to generate ir
and then it converts that by code to
their own specialized
intermediate representation they made
some assumptions based on type inference
and they generate llvm ir and jits
afterwards
there is some different modes in lvm
and number one is no python mode no
python mod means this object never gets
python objects uh it always gets
integers and
other atomic types so
if you use it you get more performance
uh
changes uh lmr and it optimizes the
alarm light
has an interface lvm and uh you can
optimize the barcode
it binds to it functions in the future
we are going to see how we can
write our llvm compiler
this is the r target function uh
it takes a and b and it uses python's
annotation feature which we don't handle
with type inference
you need to specify the types
we are going to use ast electron knight
the same library that number uses
and annotations this is the function
we will have a compiler if we can
convert the functions buddy we will
convert
if we can't we will return the normal
function so it will work
in a subset of python uh it's a basic
compiler
it will get it will try to get function
source code if it can't it will return
normal function
uh and if it can it will pass the source
code into the ast
and it will try to
traverse that ast using not visitor
class
python's asd returned if any error
happens during that traversing
it will return normal function so if
something doesn't fit our
subset we will raise the compiler and
if this part catches that error it will
return the function
uh this is the ast of that function it
starts with a function definition
there is a argument part there is a body
part
uh the quarter part and return
annotation
uh the module is the highest level of
any ast and we are going to generate an
llvm module from the python's ast
and set to uh soft mode and generic list
is a function that
traverses the body of given node so we
will give the body a module
and it will uh traverse every node
that lives under the module this is the
function
if you want to recall the functions
first of all we will remove the
decorator
that is used to jit our code so
it won't be infinite loop
then we are going to uh generate an
argument spec from that
uh there is a cast algorithm function
which is just checks the annotation and
converts and aladdin wire and then we
are going to get the return type
so we can convert an element function
type from that
it takes return type and the values of
arguments
uh then we are going to use that
function type to generate an
llvm function which will live under
uh the module we have created it will
take the
function type and if it will have the
name of the node
then we are going to append the basic
block uh
which we can use that afterwards to get
a builder
in that basic block so we are going to
traverse the
node's body one by one and use that
builder to build
our expressions the first expression is
constants
element types doesn't directly fit to
python mass
so we need to convert it python's
integer doesn't have
a specific bit length so we are going to
use 32
for default and we are going to use
float for our floor type not double
uh this is the cast album function
if the given type is integer we are
going to return lrams in type
if the float we are going to return
floor type and if
the type we don't is something we don't
know we will raise the compiler
uh this is the part that constructs uh
intermediate representation
llvm's constant with the type of the
ir and the value of the nodes
there's the argument access part we will
visit the name nodes and if we can fetch
the argument from the
given functions type spec we will fetch
it
and return the value if we can't we will
raise a compiler because it's something
global
or we don't know there is binary
operations
we will try to get the operator from the
builder object
if we can we will raise a compiler
because
some operator we don't know and then we
will return the left side and right side
under that operator
uh the repair operation is pretty simple
we will just
call red method of builder and return
the
given value which is going to be binary
operation
so we wrote a basic compiler with a
compile class method a compiler
uh if it doesn't fit subset and visitors
for module function return binary
operation name and constant
uh the funny part is creating an
execution engine
we will create a default ripple target
that's configured llvm and create a
target machine
uh in the creating target machine you
can specify the optimization level or
anything you want
then we will create the execution engine
which
takes a bootstrapping assembly we don't
have anything to bootstrap
and our machine and we will return the
machine engine
this is the exiting part we will create
the engine
with the with this method and then
parse the our module and verify it if
it's ability
uh intimate representation or not then
we will
add that module to end our engine we'll
finalize and
run the static constructors and then we
will get the function
as a c types function
uh pointer so
at the end we will uh fetch that
functions pointer
and cast it to c type c function python
offers a way to uh
access uh c functions with c types so
there's a
c type c func type which takes a typeset
and the type spec is
given here and we will cast the function
pointers to that
we did this with asmr ast
so we can we did this uh same thing
with barcode yes uh we will have
something like this to decorate our
function
uh and we will have that same part
uh we will keep a stack of the functions
barcode because python's visual machine
is by
stack based so we will uh with the
obscures by one by one
if the opcode is something we know uh we
will add
the stack if we don't know
we will break the for loop understand
the normal function
uh loading names is simple uh if we see
a
lot uh bad code we will return the
uh given arguments to stack
if we see a load cost we will cast it to
llvm
and append the stack if we see a binary
operation we will pop two things from
the stack
and create an operation from it and if
we see a return value we will return
this is the whole code to
construct that ir yeah this is it
thank you for listening is there any
questions
[Applause]
no okay
okay um
can you make explicit what makes your
opposition different
uh what are the things that are
different
in your approach to the
okay you are asking uh what are things
different in my jit compilers
other than the projects i saw i
presented
okay i need to go to the outline to uh
list other function
uh other projects okay this will
okay uh there was four projects online
swallow was using bytecode
the bytecode i am using in the second
approach
so our latest values approach and my
approach is
almost same uh pi aladdin uses asd
and in my first approach i used ast to
use that same approach piston and number
also uses
bytecode so mine isn't different than
others but i pre i try to simplify the
process of there in my examples
in both ways okay
typing issue is a real issue and it
seems to me that
your approach you're delegating that to
the user
yeah so that's actually a very big
difference compared to
the other approach you are not taking
care of type insurance which makes
things
much easier but
when you annotate a variable with it it
means
python int which is actually begins yeah
and you are casting them to 32 bits
which is a totally different word yeah i
mentioned that
types doesn't directly fit the python
type so
for the sake of easily i
casted it to 32-bit integer but
in a real world application it would be
nonsense to cast thirty two bit int
or you could for instance using c types
can
exhibit two bits
well python's typing doesn't uh allow to
specify integers uh there's literals but
there are nothing to specify the length
of bit length of the integer
in type annotations so it would be hard
to use to
define that
how much
my compilers get around to 20
speed because i don't do any
optimizations
any extra thing i just convert the
direct python to llvmr
and it gets 20 persons speed up
what stops you from doing optimization
why are you not
doing running the optimizer because
for the sake of presentation i want to
keep everything simple
okay
as you're using type annotations you
don't need a jit at all
you could do that statically you just
take the function
and perform your static compilation
and then under the binary
into your python barcode and that's okay
so
why would you use a jit in your
situation where
you only use static information you are
asking why i am using cheats
when there is already defined type
annotations i can just convert to
functions by the ahead of time
population
because in the approach taken by like
unleaded swallow uh they recurred the
runtime data
i want to keep that in the my slides but
it doesn't fit
so i have a project called swinging head
which takes the exact thing
like online as well and of course
runtime data so you are right
in this way uh it would make sense to
not running jit but uh if you are going
to record the runtime data
or do other things you need to use git
any more questions um
when are you using the bytecode one
versus the ast based
to me ast is much more simpler to work
on
because you don't need to extra boost
dropping code python offers an interface
to access it
but i want to show how only the solo and
piston worked so i an example to
bite god you say it does
the future you see using the ist by this
one as the future
one of the shortcomings presented by the
piston
piston broker was that
most of the python code is actually just
glue
calling native functions that's true for
sustana library but that's also true for
party package like numpy and it presents
a very strong barrier to the optimizer
unless so did you take that into account
or when you see the
a native function you're just calling it
the python way and
getting back the results uh you are
asking if i am optimizing
native functions with bootstrappingsd
number does that
but my jit compiler doesn't do that
okay thank you okay
you