all right hi everyone i will just
skip the introduction because you see my
name and you uh
might have seen me before uh i would
like to start with a bit of a disclaimer
so i will be speaking about a very
specific company
which is intel at this part um
this here is not about blaming anyone
it's not about you know
saying or pointing out that something is
very very bad anywhere
uh this is really just about getting a
clue
of uh what we can understand from
previous work
or what i have personally looked into to
understand what the intel management
engine is and what it's doing
or what it can do um yes now i might
have some errors in here
there will be a link to my github
repository later where you can also find
all the slides so you can just file
issues you know
or make pull requests which is even
easier
so we'll just start with a hopefully
brief introduction this time i already
gave a similar talk at
c3 last year like a month ago with uh
very bad timing actually so i'm very
sorry for that
uh i will therefore skip some of the
parts
ahead in there um then i will uh speak
about the perspective from the open
source size
side about creating firmware and working
uh with what we already have from
vendors
and then i will um give you some
motivation
uh why you should maybe look into what i
looked into
uh i will start with how it actually
started for me
and then i will give you lots of hints
of directions where you could go
um yeah in the end i will also come up
with a brief conclusion hopefully i will
make it there
um so for the introduction part um
you all might have already played around
a bit with microcontrollers like the
arduino stuff and everything
and when people ask me about firmware
they want a very
brief explanation of what it actually is
well i pond them to that
and i tell them that actually what you
have in your laptop today
is very much the very same thing as just
playing with arduino
except that you have like 20 arduinos in
here okay
and of course they all are connected
together so you have kind of
these i know 20 or more chips in your
laptop
or also if you work on servers or
whatever machines
uh it's still the very same thing just
with some minor
differences okay um
there are some components which are
actually critical to the entire thing
uh that starts with what we know
sometimes as the south bridge
or more general the chipset uh which
kind of
connects everything nowadays uh intel
calls it the platform controller hub now
because that's where all the controllers
are coming together
there are two variants actually so
sometimes you have
all the cpu cores also in the very same
sock like in this example here in the
picture
uh sometimes it's two separate chips i
will come to that later
but besides that there is two things
which
actually seem like they have a lot of
power
and probably they shouldn't so that's
why we take a closer look here
one of them is the embedded controller
which
on your laptop is for regulating like
[Music]
battery management for example when you
connect your charger you will see
an led actually light up and that even
works without running an operating
system
why is that because there is an embedded
controller actually doing that
right of course you could also do that
just in hardware directly yeah but there
is
much more to it and this controller can
also be connected to your keyboard and
mouse
sometimes it's even a dedicated chip it
can be connected to your tpm
or a fingerprint sensor or whatever and
also basically to everything else
there is also related work but more on
that later
on servers you have a very similar thing
which is called the bmc
which you can use for like power cycling
or uh you know provisioning from outside
uh but usually that's on a different
network interface
and then there is something which is the
well management engine which is also
kind of similar to that
and that's what we're focusing on today
but first i would like to uh give a very
very brief perspective
on the open source firmware side of
things
starting with the list of projects so we
have
projects you already heard about here
there is the
cardboard project which you can use for
initializing your hardware
for example this laptop here is also
running cardboard now
uh like many other devices you might
find at this event or people also ask us
and they want a flash call boot on their
device so that can already uh
take uh control of a lot of the laptop
okay then there is the linux boot
project which can be used as a payload
we already heard
about the head project which is also a
kind of the linux boot approach so you
have a linux kernel
and then you have some tools which are
running on that kernel
to then actually kick off your operating
system okay
uh there is the url project uh also very
similar
uh it has its own tool right so it's uh
well similar in the approach then we
have four embedded controllers
from google for all the chromebooks open
source firmware actually
and the same thing as currently being
done at system76
uh there is repositories online you can
find them on github
parts are in gitlab.com yeah you will
find it
actually the slides are also online and
you can just click through all the links
so
uh all of uh what i'm listing somewhere
is actually
uh links behind it so yeah just follow
them
for the baseboard management controllers
on servers
we also have open source projects there
is open bmc and there is ubmc
also very similar actually to the links
boot approach so you also have a linux
kernel
and just some tools which are then
running on that kernel
to actually control the system
okay so look let's look at the intel x86
platforms a bit
um so i mentioned sometimes you have
everything in one sock sometimes you
actually have two separate chips
uh people are well if if you look back
some years ago we were used to knowing
something called a cpu
there is something today which is very
very similar to that
which you can see in this picture it's
called the core processor now
um there's slightly more than just a cpu
in that uh you can also see that it's
also connected to other devices like
your graphic card
graphics card for example so that's
where it's actually doing a bit more
than really just processing so yeah
it has relationships and this is really
just
a very very high level overview
let's take a closer look at one platform
which is the denverton platform
that's one of the few images actually
where i could find a direct reference to
the management engine
which is what we're looking at now uh
here in the
upper right corner we have a cursor here
no anyway so in the upper right corner
of this image
you see two engines managed one of them
mentioned one of them is the management
engine
one of them is called innovation engine
so what is it the management engine as
we know it today
is basically just a microcontroller so
you can imagine something like arduino
uh it's an ad51 instruction set
there have been multiple hardware
versions over the time
i think this is now currently the third
generation
so it's not changing very much
but there is still lots of difference
among the implementations around
it it actually started with something
that was called the
active management technology and that
still exists today
so the first idea was to have something
very very similar to a baseboard
management controller
but it's still part of the entire thing
so it's not on a dedicated chip
uh or well it's um actually integrated
into everything
and it doesn't have its own nick you can
still use
the very one nic so the network
interface controller that you also use
for other services
right so um sometimes people ask me like
hey
what is this management actually uh what
is the engine
is it dangerous does it really do
everything that i heard about
uh because there was um references about
web servers running in there
which is not untrue uh and there is
rumors about it being capable of
actually wiping your entire laptop from
outside
which is also not completely untrue
so what's actually the case is there is
multiple versions of it for multiple
purposes
and if you buy like your whatever acer
laptop or something
for like a few hundred euros then it's
not very likely that you have those
features in there
because they are not designed for
consumers okay
more on that later so
um now there's uh a bit
more that was actually put in the
management engine
and that's why today it's actually
called csme
okay so cs for converged
security and management engine
i will briefly mention those security
features as well
but first uh let's look at the
innovation engine i've only found it in
this very one picture i just showed you
uh from what i have been told uh hp
enterprise is actually using it for some
purposes
and it's kind of really just a
one-to-one copy of the management engine
which is why i'm mentioning this so we
can just monitor what's happening over
time and see
you know if they still exist side by
side
or if they diverge over time but yeah
this is
where it's starting now
but first let's look about how let's
look at how the entire platform works
together
so i just explained that we have lots of
chips in our laptops
and one of them is actually the
management engine
so it's actually part of one of your
socks
what is it doing when you power up uh
when you power on your laptop
there is a rom in that chip it's usually
very very tiny
and that's also true for uh yeah many
microcontrollers actually
they have something called a mask chrome
or a bootrom so that's what's running
initially
and it's quite common that you then load
another image
into ram which comes from somewhere else
to then
keep running and do more things than
really just the boot part
that's called rbe here so rbe is the
first phase which is just uh
after boot up
it's like a rom boot extension or
something like that
um then there is bob the bring up phase
which is supposed to launch the entire
platform
so you should know that the management
engine is also
well connected to all the other parts
we just heard about some core boot
information so
or also uh general firmware information
for the host
which is also connected to lots of
devices and needs to initialize stuff
so it's basically like you have multiple
chips
and multiple firmware images which are
all doing some initialization here and
there
and they do not necessarily uh know
about each other okay so that's where
sometimes potentially bugs come from uh
i see some nodding in the room
so yeah if you keep looking into
firmware you might come across this also
um well and then eventually there is uh
an operating system running in the
management engine
but not in every version of the
management engine in some versions of
the firmware of the management engine
this is really not necessary because you
don't really need it like for example uh
i as a consumer i don't provision my
laptop at home from my
whatever server you know i just run my
one operating system there and i'm okay
with that
it's not like i need to wipe it from
outside or you know
have some fresh images coming in i know
i just take some install medium from a
usb stick or something
well if all that is done the cpu reset
vector is actually triggered from
what i know it can be slightly different
on some platforms
some people thought it might be that the
cpu is just on hold all the time and
then released at this point now the cpu
can start it can load uh
microcode updates and it can just keep
uh
running the entire boot process like
what we know from uh
all the other firmware initialization we
just heard about like what core boot is
doing or
what your vendor's uefi is doing
and then side by side with that there is
another chip
which is also somewhere integrated the
power management controller
it also gets for more updates actually
from the management engine part
from what i looked at it can be that it
also differs a bit on platforms but
yeah i mean if you want to look more
into it you might figure out differences
and then there is the embedded
controller which is really just running
side by side in a way
but it's also still connected to
everything so you have to also be able
to talk to the embedded controller chip
so if for example if you look at the
kobrik uh project's
source code then you will also find
references like hey here we're talking
to the embedded controller
for example to read out some sensors
so you know if the laptop is overheating
so maybe you need to scale on the cpu or
something like that
okay
all right and then at some point you
come across this um
you might find this sticker on your
laptop uh it says something about core
i7 that sounds like the regular
marketing stuff you hear
ninth generation so you know a bit like
was
you know made in 2018 17 19 i don't know
which exact year it is
um and then there is this thing called v
pro
and that's where i came across when i
was looking at the management
engine stuff so what is it
it's actually kind of an umbrella
marketing term it does not refer to very
specific features but it may include
like
a lot of features part of that is
today also the active management
technology which
started at some point in time it can
also contain security features
so the problem is just
we don't have very much information on
that there is the ark it's
like an archive on intel's website where
you can read a lot about cpus like what
their
exact features are if they have like
integrated graphics
uh whatever um
i know certain features no so not all
the cpus are the same
uh but when it comes to vpro it does not
speak
about support like hardware support it
speaks about eligibility
so not every chip is actually eligible
for this what does that mean
it does not mean that the hardware is
not able to do this
so we had some discussions very recently
actually so
thank you now sitting here
discovered that this boot guard feature
that you might have heard about
is actually still usable in some of
those chips
which are not officially eligible
okay so boot guard is one of those
security features i just mentioned
uh it's able to lock your firmware down
so that you can only boot images
which uh you know they should have
certain signatures checksums or
something like that
so you know what you're booting is
actually okay now usually that comes
from your vendor not from yourself
so you would have to trust your vendor
now
there's other features like software
software guard extensions
uh and the txt stuff that also nine
elements are
elements cyber security is working on
so here's a long list about um what this
uh all of this management engine
technology is actually about
um and there is interfaces for it so
you also need to have some part in your
firmware and you also have to have some
part in your operating system to
actually talk to this right
so that's implemented in the linux
kernel for example you can look at the
source code
in the firmware there is something
called mebx
so when you boot your laptop you may
also be allowed to talk to it if you
have the corporate version
of the management engine
here's a small timeline it's not
necessarily accurate
but this is uh what i kind of came up
with after i read
from igor koscinski he also spoke a lot
about me and reverse
engineering yeah but i recommend looking
at the slide in detail
when you have some time version 12
of the management engine was released
quite a while ago there is
some public documentation about it not
very much but at least some
but recently well actually just at
curious communication congress
we found a laptop which also has version
but that's not in the archives anywhere
so far
at least i haven't found anything so it
kind of stops at version 12
which allows you to deactivate this
management technology
yeah so that's maybe for corporate
versions where you may need
to disable this to secure your platforms
more
so these are the variants i know so far
which i have found
there's the consumer version the
corporate version some people refer to a
slim version i don't really know where
it's found
there is a server platform version and
there is no something
which we're now looking into the
ignition variant
and that was my motivation to actually
look into this whole stuff
so in the edk ii mailing list uh
there was something popping up which is
an ignition firmware binary
and which uh well comes with a brief uh
um variable a brief explanation which
basically says like yeah this is a very
minimal thing
it's designed for this in this chips or
a platform
yeah so if we now take this and the fsp
the firmware support package which we
also heard about
then now we could actually uh kind of
bake a full image to have formula for a
laptop
uh well without all the reverse
engineering which we might not be
allowed to do
uh but you know still all the glue code
around it and then have some other
critical
critical parts actually open source
so let's follow along um here is the
license for it it explicitly
disallows decompilation disassembly
you know everything which would give us
really a direct clue
so uh this is also briefly mentioned
in some other references which i put
here
like for example the fsp training
there is a slide saying well intel knows
there's lots of firmware engineers out
there
it doesn't really directly say that but
it looks like they don't really want to
disclose all the information
so as a workaround they provide the
binaries
in the white paper they are saying that
binaries are actually quite good
because you know that's kind of the
middle ground we can meet
um as long as it works as desired
which is not necessarily always the case
so if you work with core boot you might
sometimes came across issues somewhere
especially if you don't have much
documentation
this is also where dexter's law applies
you might have heard about that one
which says that only proprietary vendors
actually won proprietary firmware
right so i as a consumer i would never
say hey i want some software from you
but please
make it close for us make me never look
into it or something
you know nobody would ever say that
and that's what the issue when we're
talking about security
attackers don't play by those routes
right so if there is some shady people
sitting somewhere in a dark corner and
they want to hack your laptop
they do not care about that right but
we're on the other side we
actually want to secure our laptops and
now we have this problem we can't really
look into it very much
so we cannot really investigate our
attack model here right
but we can take some first steps there
is previous work there is some analysis
tools
there has been some reverse engineering
so i put all the references here
and now we'll tell you a bit about
some attacks which actually resulted
from
some reverse engineering so for example
there was the planner volt attack
this is what some shady people in the
dark corner could have come up with
nobody would have noticed because you
were never allowed to look into the
stuff right i think everybody heard
about this
uh if not look into uh the stuff it's
just plundervault
search for it you will find it
which uh well brings us to this question
can we actually trust the vendors
um i have very uh briefly wanted to come
up with something like a definition of
trust which is
well inherently complicated uh i just
sum it up so there is uh
for me uh two kinds of trust there is
something which is actually earned and
there is something called blind trust so
blind trust is
basically like the uh well this will
this will be our right model
you know um so my question is always
why do i have to disclose what like when
i bake cookies i will have to tell you
if it contains nuts because
some people may be allergic but if i
provide you with hardware
i don't have to disclose anything
basically
yeah so security actually has many
dimensions you know we have heard about
these security issues
there's something which is called this
responsible disclosure
and also coordinate disclosure that's
the model that
the um researchers are using and also
well uh most of the companies are using
so they don't publish information
upfront you know they will
take it offline they will have their
internal discussions at some point there
will
be information released hopefully
now inter researchers actually just
wrote about this
they agreed that we need a common
taxonomy to actually talk about those
things so you know that we don't
misunderstand each other
this is here my security perspective
actually some people also agreed to that
that we need to be able to audit our
stuff if we cannot audit something we
can entrust it and therefore
you know no audit no trust
so here's a brief introduction to
firmware analysis
i like to look at firmware this way it's
a bit like emulating firmware but you
know
uh it's really just uh reading the raw
bytes which you have in your firmware
image
you can do this uh with uh very nice
tools like xsd
xxd and less right so that gives you
this
uh this is uh how the
me firmware is actually partitioned so
it's really just very very simple data
structures
from all the tools i already mentioned
before
you can come to these conclusions
it's very just simple right it's really
just listings like these regions are
here and there
yeah there is different sorts of entries
in the firmware you will
figure it out if you look further into
it so i'm just listing those here for
reference
and unfortunately i'm almost out of time
once again so i will just
skip through some of this stuff
and of course come talk to me because
i'm really interested in exchanging more
about this
if you can read x86 instructions of
course
you can just look at the raw bytes
because this is not decompiling or
disassembly it's really just reading
right
um yeah time's up now
uh so just uh for a very brief
conclusion uh all firmware has to be
open source for security that's what i
propose
uh some people agree and to fully on
your own hardware
we actually have to do something about
this uh here's a lots of projects where
we have open source stuff
yeah and that's where i'm ending here
i would like to uh well actually thank
all those projects uh which are also
present here
and also my hacker spaces unfortunately
there is no time for questions so this
slide is for
uh people watching the recording so you
have the reference thank you
[Applause]