i am madish
i'm presenting maddix the lack of
imagination today we have to choose the
name
but maddix is a toolkit that
allows people to install free open
source application on a new
server without the need of having
technical skills or make
a big investment the idea came
from my experience with xnet which i am
co-founder
and this is an activist group which
operates in in things related with
digital democracy
uh privacy protection whistleblower
protection and so on so
working with other activist
organizations we were surprised to see
how many people
were using services provided by
big corporation and they were creating
actions
and sharing sensitive information for
example with
google groups or stuff like that and
these people normally
most most of them were aware that this
was not the best practice
but they had no alternative they said i
i have no says that mean
i have no money to pay one what can i do
and we have no answer for that
actually so this is what we did
build this answer the approach
to be this tool was very clear to us
we didn't want to be to create a service
to offer a service we wanted to offer a
solution
that will empower users and transfer the
responsibility of their data as well as
the application to them so we
do not run a service with our cis admin
that
manage their data yeah okay encrypt
whatever you want but it would be on our
our responsibility and so we didn't want
to reproduce that
so we decided that this tool must
run on own service of people that can
have at their home or which with
whatever
uh internet hosting provider
uh so uh
this graph i why did i show you this you
say it's this crazy
because this is at least a complete list
of company owned by
alphabet and it's incomplete for two
reasons because in the same wikipedia
they say
that it's incomplete and because it
didn't fit in my screenshot
i made some to make it fit but i
couldn't get it all
so the thing is uh
if somebody needs a email in
make the decision to switch or their
their organization from gmail for
example
to another email provider uh which
option they have
they could for example use protonmail we
have just seen
but on my opinion the the model is not
that different i mean you still trust
that people from protomail
respect privacy and care about that we
say okay
i mean i'm not discussing that but it's
just a
technical design right or to turn on
that so what happened if
tutanota tomorrow belongs to the to that
list
we don't we have the same problem we
have not solved the base problem
that's why we decided that the the email
server must run on people machine not
on our uh common email server
and the image is important this is the
graph
the first one is the gmail users and the
blue bar refers to younger people so it
also
uh it shows that there is a tendency of
young people
to use these tools and it's normal
because it works
it has a sex interface and you have
a lot of other services once you set up
a gmail account
and you can have it set up in a minute
of course
so the alternative if you don't want to
transfer
this responsibility from jimmy to
another external or more friendly
uh privacy friendly company
the only alternative you have is to run
the email server yourself and this is
a guide that you can follow and when you
get at the end this is to install
postpiece
door record without that and when you
fire get at the end
this is the result and from here you can
start
creating your first email account and
this is not sexy at all
so uh many people will end up here
and so of course this is pain right so
this is the ideology all i mean the the
idea that
was with us all the time when developing
this tool we so if there is not only the
email
server of course there are other tools
for
there are a lot but uh next cloud on
cloud
only office online library office online
uh a lot
a rocket chat vpn so people can from a
graphical interface that we have
developed
and which is installed on on server
when you start using mavic's uh with
this graphic from this graphical
interface you just select
the application you want you push the
install button that
is over there and the the
installation process starts
from the same graphical interface you
can also manage other things
you can get a look at how the how your
system is
you can create users give them access
you can create vpn accounts you can
create virtual hosts for your domain
and all the typical things you need in a
server so but how does it work so
you can think about maddix as the recipe
of a repository sorry of recipes
that people can download and apply on
their
own server uh this
now i i will show a slide that you would
say oh
no yes this is these are the technology
we use but
some of you in the hall may you know
that antiball and pocket are not really
privacy friendly tools but we changed
the way we implemented them so
for opennet nebula we only use that in
case we also provide
hosting to set up a virtual machine but
if you want to use
amazon we don't use open level you
you give us you provide the server
yourself
so the first okay it's a part so
ansible we just use it at the beginning
to set up the first
very basic installation so
we do not uh offer
using maddix in servers that are
already the previous configuration
because it would be a mess for us
to calculate all the possible panoramas
we prefer to
go on developing rather than
solve different scenarios so
once ansible basically what does is
install
the puppet client people could say no i
want to do that my own
okay but i mean we have all the
all automatized why not so and we
could one day make an image that people
can
install or but we go slow because
because we are a small project anyway
so then puppets once you have
the puppet install you run a forced
puppet agent this is how it's
called it's called and the puppet agent
talk
to this repository and ask
him in it her i don't know to download
the the basic uh and to configure the
the base of the system which includes
the graphical interface the
ldap uh directory and
mysql and all the base yes based
packages
so puppet normally is
not good for this purpose to to to build
autonomous and and privacy
oriented tool because puppet normally
needs to know
all the secrets about the machine that
is talking with with it
i mean to install for example a mysql
server
puppet needs to know which to provide
which
password will be used as a root password
for the mysql server
and normally puppet stores this
information on the master server
and this was something that we didn't
want
so what we do we solve this problem in a
very silly simple way but it works it
works like a sham so we cheat the puppet
master
so that it is using fake templates
with fake values that are common for all
installation
and upon the installation is always
terminated
the machine locally generates its own
secrets
and overwrites these secrets with
the one that was used by puppets and
that way
we not only i mean there are two
two benefits of this way of working one
is that under security point of view we
don't
store in the same place a lot of secrets
of people which we don't want it would
be
quite uh quite a mess for us
and second users can apply own
configurations
and puppet wouldn't then overwrite
this personal configuration in a normal
environment puppet
would do that right so
um then it's
great but then a lot of people who are
an organization who are actually in high
risk area
started using maddix because it was
useful for them they could
have in infinite
vpn account without asking anyone it was
very agile for them
and so suddenly we get concerned about
the security because we took
care about that but you know so we
asked somebody external
externally to make a security outlet
which
we did with uh open uh radically open
security
and the thing is that from this security
audit
the result was that there were a lot of
recommendation
that we are now in the face of
implementing
in order to ensure the security of all
the system
and this represents for us a big
challenge
because uh we have to translate
all these concepts to the graphical
interface
we don't want people to avoid using
this security indoor enforcement because
they are too complicated so we are
making an effort we are not
expert in ux so we are making an effort
we will
need help on that and also because for
example
the security audit says that we just
show a low tls version 1.2
and we know that there are people using
medics that have
old browsers that do not support that
they may have problems so
it would we put transformatics in
something
impossible to use not working you know
so
we decided to leave this decision to use
so now we are implementing
all views all interfaces related with
these
issues these security issues
and um so uh
maddix you can use once install the
application you want
and not use it anymore you cannot talk
with the
with the server you can actually
uninstall
the puppet or whatever but
what we do we also provide updates
because
one system once it runs you need to to
maintain it
and so we publish periodically new
releases in which typical we have bug
fixes
security enforcement new application
updates for
existing previous applications so
the important thing on that is that this
graphical interface
is not running any comment
it's just an interface from where
all the from where user inserts
uh data which are written from this
interface which is a jungle
uh based in jungle and bright in the
eldar
so then there is the crown
who is reading this eldar and if
it finds that something must be done
because there is
a status who changes so the puppet is
triggered
otherwise no
for example these are some
custom models we have developed we also
use some
models from the puppet forge and these
are
models that run locally on the machines
so not
every time the client needs to talk with
the master
there are for example uh when creating a
new
uh a new a new domain and you need to
create the virtual host this is
something that
the machine can carry out locally on
their own
using these puppet models yes so
what what it happens is that if a new
domain is added
the uh the domains module
turns into a locket status so the cron
read that
and perform all the necessary tasks in
order to create the virtual host the
little encrypt certificate
the web root folder and all that
so we are
always working on on this tool
we have a lot of time working on this
tool
and we are now planning to add
new tools such as moodle
then also we want to add something for
online forms which are not pretty sure
which is the best solution if you can
have
el pas on that but basically the the
decision
uh to to add a new feature is from the
feedback we receive from people that are
using that
so uh but yes we want to
add the kanban that there is nothing
right now for that
uh and there is
you have to think that medics can can
run
on a very small machine we use very
little docker just for the application
that had only docker support
with with a dockerized image support and
all the other stuff are integrated and
we just use
debian because we it's easier for us
to just give support to one operating
system
and and of course people
have root access to their machine it's
their own machine
uh they have access they everything is
written in the log
we didn't publish the the server side
because it's just a puppet with
with the models we use and most of them
we publish the one we have developed
but the other one are from the puppet
porch directly
so also that all the sources are
downloaded directly from
if you if you download another mysql
server it's downloaded directly from
with debian from the source so yes we
would like to make a better
documentation not all the infrastructure
we will do but you know we are
always uh behind the the
timetable but this is our intention
and i think it's all i hope you have
understood what we do
and thank you very much
thank you very much there's a lot of
time for questions does anyone have a
question
i would like to ask you are aware of
you know horse and cloudren and cloud
yes
yes the difference is that you know
horse clothes
yes the other one is i tell you um
hi the one that the guy went to work
with
cloudflare you know how is that custom
yes i know what i do what are the
differences
yes before starting we
load it because if this solution already
exists
why repeat ourselves so the difference
with cloudron is that
on cloudron if you install on your own
another application and then you
update the classroom it will override
all your
custom things they say that on their
website
so it was not useful for us because it
was just
for us it was it but x is the tool that
avoid repeating
boring tasks such as installing you know
but
people need to have the freedom to then
make
the customization of their own system so
this was not useful for us
samsung sandstorm for something
is more complicated for users if you
want to set up a website and make it
accessible
with the domain some configuration and
you still need have
to have some skills in order to install
them
run it and so on and among these three
you know hosts is the one
we love more we think it's great
yesterday we were talking with people
from the project
and the thing is that in this case also
uh
people need to somehow
have a scissors name capable to make
some little maintenance on the one hand
on the other hand we saw that the their
interface
yes is running scripts directly and we
thought that
under a security point of view it was
not a good decision we wanted something
that
uh avoided that could mark this
difference in this separation
and on the other hand these systems
allow us to also provide service service
as a cis admin
i i refer to bigger organizations
and provide them a very customized
uh configuration for the server
because for example we can we could
create a
template just for them if we want you
know so and we do actually we do we
give maintenance and and support to
bigger organization
and they ask us for example of a future
that
it only works for them you know so we
don't we just can work
that way also with bigger organization
and but we have
systematized all the this admin
work which is borrowing and repeating
and
so on any more
questions we still have time
uh would it be possible to um
install it on a like my own machine that
i have running in my basement
your own pc yeah yes you could
but think it's a server environment
and the with local
installation the problem is the ip if
you're changing ip
think that you have for example uh let's
encrypt
uh certificate generated but then if you
change that fee everything could break
you know so okay you could but
take into account this thing about ips
for example to
install the rocket chart you need a
a long domain or subdomain the process
automatically creates the virtual host
so
if your isp change your ip
your mavic server is up or you
won't work anymore
but yes it can work you can for example
the site
then you make some configuration in the
site to work to use it just in a land
and so it could work
how do you do major upgrade major
upgrade oof
we did from jesse to to stretch
and in this we need to a little bit
communicate with the user it's not just
the button
but that what we did was
uh button in which users send us
um like a report because so we see if
they had
made some uh installed other
applications
you know to see if the if their system
has some application that we are not in
is not included in the upgrade for
example
then we have automatized
part of this process but we
every machine that we have that we did
their grade from jesse to stretch
we said to people come to drc write this
comment
do that i mean we you know we had to
communicate because it's a major agree
we tell them do a backup before
everything so this is a little bit
more complicated we could not get just
one click
but because we prefer also that we
prefer to have a conversation with them
be sure that they have a backup
and sit like that because we don't
provide the cap to people
then we are going to implement encrypted
backups so we will also maybe find a way
to solve that but see the moment we do
not provide the cap
sorry here in the in the gitlab there
are some
pre-stretched stretch manifest that you
can get a look of what they do
that is the preparation to go to from
majestic to stretch you can read them
and did you automate also the
installation configuration of uh
things like a fail to ban or climb up
uh stuff like that so we have
this a spam assessing for example
something that user can install until
now we
for everybody is level three but we will
add the option to increase or reduce
this level
and for pay to ban also the
configuration see now
is the default and it's for ssh
savile apache code and so on
but i mean now is already it's included
by defaulting on all servers
not a package that people can decide to
have or not
this is mandatory in this case
but yes we would like to add the the
opportunity to you know to change the
for example we will need to pull the
opportunity to
unban ip from this cultural panel
because a lot of people
for example when configuring the
thunderbirds
yes they make errors and so they get
funds from their job
you know so we would like to add a
customization for that
hello how do you decide which apps
are included in the library of apps
how does it work we started because we
needed this tool so we started putting
the tool the apps we needed and to end
the community we were working with
and then some other that we didn't think
of
uh were requested by people that were
already using medics
and so when we saw that it was not just
only one person but
more than once so we decided okay they
all write this
app is useful so if somebody uh
request that uh would be great to have
this application and it's not really a
crazy
thing that is we we had it
and you said you're going to add new
apps in the future
yes and the future is six months because
we want to add moodle and we want to add
we were thinking about the line survey
you know to
create online form but it's not really
so much easier to use for i mean it's
the interface on my opinion
is not so clean so we are digging and
investigating
why uh why not
which alternative could there be for
that if you know
some we would love to to to
check more okay thank you very much
[Applause]