okay
so hi my name is pedro
i'm a designer during my free time
i enjoy to travel to meet folks like you
but also regarding design arts
i also when i do have a little time
i conduct some kind of workshops
regarding ux design but as well graphic
design
at the beautiful city of prague czech
republic
i'm also a happy camper at collabora
and today i intend you to show i intend
to show you how easy it can be
to customize collabora online you know
without tricks and without coding
and this type of thing so any designer
should be able to do it or even any
business owner right um
so talking about customization
there is great advantages regarding
customizations
not only because it allows you to
customize
customize it according to your needs or
even your personal taste
it can be just that and that's fine
so for that we will be probably working
with
xml css and svg um
nothing too complex um
so uh we can divide um
we can divide the the theme in two
pieces if you will
the widgets um that
you know includes um dialogue sidebar
etc and all the controls
and the overall theme so basically the
rest right
tollbars icons drop down menus
um going through uh widgets
so uh widgets are customizable
that's why i'm talking and starting with
them
they actually use this new extended
instance
of native widget framework and i really
recommend you
um to either after um
or when you have time to watch the the
talk from tomasz where he talks a little
bit about these intricacies
um of how this was implemented
uh but for now um let's just say that um
it draws the interface depending on the
definition
or to be honest a set of definitions um
that are um included in one file and
we'll see that
uh later on um it allows
multiple customizations right so
multiple definitions
which in turn means multiple themes
um this is really cool
we can now have a theme depending on
an environment um and big
thanks for athenis for this yes
um now it's really cool that you know we
open calebra in
on an ipad and without doing nothing it
just
knows that it's an ios device
and it just serves you with the right
thing
with the ios like components and we'll
see this
later on sorry for the bullets i also
don't like it that much
but we will see more pictures um
[Music]
let's let him take a peach
perfect um you know and this in return
gives you the opportunity to forces
going from for instance the
no yes going from a purplish
theme um where you see
not only colors but even components are
from this theme to something
uh versus more bright where the accent
color is actually blue
and even the the controls per se
completely change you see
here
this is great and especially when you
can
serve it uh depending on the theme as we
discussed earlier so you see the the the
components change completely
now i'm going to show you an example of
how
you do that right step by step
so imagine you want to tweak
a particular dialogue a particular
component of a dialog
it could be it couldn't be easier right
so you go to your instd
directory inside of your core
and here you will find in this subfolder
online
this xml file yeah it couldn't be more
semantic right
a file it as definition is called
definition
and inside you will see a bunch of sub
tags
now let's discuss one by one the style
tag in a simple way
it deals with colors right highlight
font colors so even without
messing too much around too many svgs
etc
you can just tweak the overall aesthetic
just by changing those values
next we have settings
at set and settings you can set um
values of things that are not particular
particularly from a specific control per
se
but um generally for instance
margins uh tabs alignment right and we
know that there is
some dialogues with all with quite the
number of tabs
so you can control that
the default font size etc
and now we reach to our first
control let's simplify this
so we can divide this in three parts
so first we need to say which type of
control we are talking about right
here let's let's talk about our little
radio button then
you will say okay this control
will have this size using the part tag
and inside of this part tag you will
have a bunch of states
now each of this state
is actually not an individual state but
a combination of states
right so as you see here um i'm saying
hey
um please define that
when the when the radio button is
enabled not pressed and checked
use this svg right and you see that
all the other states are actually a
combination of states
you see uh these allows you to have
many intermediary states right not just
the on off
disable enable um which is really
awesome
because if you play your svgs right
um you can achieve uh some inter
interesting uh aesthetic results so
uh for instance here when it goes uh
basically you are talking about when the
radio uh button is on and it's pressed
and we kinda i'm not sure if you see it
with the video project but we are
already dimming out
uh our little inner circle so it almost
gives this
even though there is an animation it
gives the essence and gives this visual
cue
to the user and that's cool
um now yeah we here we have uh yes
it shouldn't be like this yeah sorry for
the rending issue
uh maybe the resolution um
[Music]
and exactly we have many states as we
say like
of course uh more than one state can be
catch
right more than one state can be active
um
but just the first one will be
understood and rendered
um yeah that's why it's important for
this order
the order you you you set your um
states but of course you can always play
with it right you can
you set some definitions you play you
you you change some svgs
it's quite easy the svgs used
it would be located in parallel with
your xml file so
there is actually no structure folder
complexity here
now that being said it doesn't
it doesn't make much sense to customize
your widgets
and then forget the rest right
everything should be
uh one identity one visual identity
and i'm happy to say that it's should be
still
you know easy easy to set up and easy to
act
um even if you are just play with it
so in here uh inside of your online
directory
uh inside of this sub folder
you will find many css many javascript
files so my word of advice
would be to don't try to uh
change or hack every single file because
then you will have many
loose pieces right and harder for you
even
even if it's just personally even if
you're just playing with it it'll be
harder for you to maintain
and then you fix some css rule in one
file and then you find out that in the
other file is
yeah so and that's why you can just use
this file
branding.css and
of course if any uh images are
referenced there or you want to add
any extra image you can just drop them
here
right um
before the all these you need to get
collaborate
or development version of it right
and be sure this is quite important that
the code
brand package it's on your machine right
just to check um and then
hopefully you will see what we see here
right now uh
these are this has a couple of
advantages right
uh you have just one place where your
all these customizations go
one file one folder that's it
but what if and we sometimes receive
some these emails where if you
uh went really happy with our
customizations and suddenly you want to
have many
variants of your own customizations
suddenly you want to have your own
personal set of customizations
your little themes if you will
it will be a little bit troublesome to
just uh
you know have it like branding
underscore
copy one and then you know and then if
you want to change you need to rename
um so uh
for it um you should just
we have here a potato and for for for
this case
you should either you know
refrain to have these multiple files and
just have this css file
and everything is there so for instance
if you want to
um if you want to change the the
currency symbol
imagine uh you have a specific
requirement
from your customers or even at your home
someone really likes potatoes right and
for them potatoes means currency
and that's how they see it so you should
be as easy
as a potato to just replace the svg with
your svg
and making sure that this is over this
folder
and then it should be um you know
easy peasy right it will just redraw and
you will have a potato as your format
a currency symbol um
[Music]
so at the end this gives you a great
flexibility because it's really up to
you
uh like it doesn't matter your method it
doesn't matter how
how you do it locally at the end you
just need to be sure that you update
that css
you drop it there right that
images are located here and that's it
right now could you improve this
workflow
and again i reiterate
you are free you know to choose whatever
method you want
what you what you might start to
think is that okay wait what if i divide
the css file in
multiple css files that have my own
customizations and i can play with it
like i used again recommend
don't do that because then it means that
you will alter your
lowly flat directory so it will not be
this pristine directory anymore suddenly
you'll have many things happening there
so for instance if there is an update or
something you will have again these
loose pieces
um and then you might think okay but i
will maybe i can change the classes
in the html no don't do that it will be
really messy
so maybe if you really want
to have a more organized structure of
your own
locally i mean apart from collaboration
so you have your own things
and then uh wherever you want you just
want to
okay now i want to have it from my own
customizations and i want to drop it to
collaborate and everything works if you
want that
maybe uh we can talk about
repo preprocessor right and this css
preprocessor
it allows you um to compile i think yes
it allows you to compile from a script
scripting language
to css um
and this yes adds a layer of complexity
but it also and we will
for this example we'll take says um
and there is there is many as you see
but will for this example will takes us
these are these suddenly allows you to
work with variables
functions uh what they call mixings um
this translated means that you can avoid
repetition
because you can have variables and you
can have for instance even the in this
example where we are talking about
vendor-specific proprieties for instance
when you want to transform an element in
css
or other example and you need to use
more uh
these vendors specific either for for
that browser or that browser
you can add these in one place and reuse
the code right so you don't
need to have this redundancy all over
the place
um yes plus it will still allow you to
debug directly
directly on a browser as you have been
doing with css
you just need to be sure that you have
the source maps on
um and source maps are nothing more than
little files that tell the browser hey
this css came from this uh uh
scripting file that happens to be a sas
file
and this even allows you to edit the the
sas file directly
and you can then use these links to just
to be sure
if they are enabled or set up correctly
in your preferred
browser um
how you'd go about to install it there
is
many ways and using many different
technologies
so it's again great level of flexibility
it's really up to you and even all these
we are discussing
now it's even not needed it's if you are
happy with just css
just you know do your own customizations
just drop it in that directory we spoke
about it
and that's it you know no more work
um but if if you want more com more more
level of
granular um level of organization
you might want to install it over
your preferred implementation
again a word of advice this is the
primary implementation which means that
performance fixes and even new features
always appear first on dart
and then it's up to the communities on
the other implementations if they appear
or not or even with some
small tweaks different tweaks um
now this is how you could structure it
uh you know locally
right so again the big advantage is that
it doesn't affect your lowly flat
directory so your online
uh folder structure is still pristine
you know no no no probability of
problems there
um and here is how you could uh uh
structure right so
you could for instance uh divide it in
in components
your own of course here i went crazy i
i'm just to
give an example that you can really go
granular and you can really
have a lot of customizations as much as
you want
and then you'll have for instance a base
file
where all your theme specific variables
will be right and then this little guy
actually our main guy would uh
do the breach of all these files and say
if there is a rule that comes from one
of this file
and uses a specific theme you guys say
okay give me this
this this this color from this specific
theme and we'll probably
read from this variables file and we'll
see this in a minute so
so you don't need to worry and finally
to run
would be for instance just one line um
and there is quite interesting uh flags
here
but the the advantage here is that you
can automate this process right you can
run this in on a terminal and actually
many
um editors even have
some plugins that if you really don't
want to even
can avoid the terminal and run this on
the background
and it will be watching al always your
file
and you see even even your own customer
custom uh structure is in your
local folder it can automatically deploy
to the directory we spoke about it
so tien is doing the same right it's
just uh rewriting that file
and then there is cool things like you
can choose a compressed style for
you know a smaller file etc
but enough of bullets
let's see an example or second example
actually
so you see here and i try to be a little
bit brief and talk just a small detail
because i think then it's clear to
follow through
so you see we have here we are talking
about
about drop down menus uh different
accent colors for instance even here
we have a normal font height certainly
here
we have bold how you'd go about
if we want to reference this different
set of customizations
easy so following that structure
we'll just go to our toolbar up file
with set normally as we do for instance
in css
but instead of keep keeping uh
hemi hammering down all the rules here
and probably
if we want if we have like two three set
of customization
we will have these times two times three
who knows
so instead of these we say okay no no
just go
and dr and and ask this little fellow
our base
file where we have all these theme
specific variables etc and
get the values from there
on that side this could be an
implementation where we have just the
two set of of of rules
and said okay so if this variable is set
to this use this if
it's set to our your theme two which is
extremely semantic variable
value you'd use this and certainly have
these
two different set of customizations and
this is just one way to go about it of
course if you
if you read the previous uh slide there
is
there is many methods you can go about
it right you can even have
a theme many themes for each specific
file right it's up to you again a
greater level of
flexibility but just to make it simple
i use like this i think it's easy to
follow um
you know and at the end the goal here is
to make it yours
right either for your own personal taste
or if you have a specific need for as we
saw
previously if you want to have a
currency uh
format icon that is not a coin but it's
a potato no problem you can just switch
it
and have it there so it's really up to
you and this is just
a couple of examples how you know the
variety you can get from these simple
steps
yes thank you i hope it was not too fast
and not too slow
yes sir and sorry for i know you were
waiting here
long time but i was waiting for everyone
to calm down before starting
tell me tom i'm trying to figure out
the separation between the rendering on
the server side
which is done in java i believe and
the rendering on the client side because
where is the rendering done
with the css files is that done on the
server as well then
wait uh it depends because i go back a
little bit
okay or
yes like if we are talking about widgets
it's different
right uh because as you notice
we are actually not using uh css inside
when we are defining these
objects right so
uh and i hope we have time uh i skipped
that because i i thought we wouldn't
have time for that but for instance
um uh these there is many of these
components they are svgs
right so for instance when we go here to
our definitions
you see there are svgs right now we have
two types of svgs
on one side we have the svgs regarding
the controls
right and they are they end up to be
rendered as a bitmap
then we have other svgs the svgs that um
they are mutable they are changing right
for instance an svg
for instance for our
um i don't know drop down menu or
you know they change um with
so they're actually render rendered
via draw comments right so there is a
difference there
but if you are talking about like if you
are talking about
the overall thing so not the widgets per
se but overall theme
uh then uh the
the coolness of these is that you can
have it you can have online
running you can you can even use the
web tools on a browser uh go to that
branding.css
change it or even arnold delete the
whole thing and paste
whatever you want and you will see in
real time uh the changes appearing
yeah so it depending on what you are
talking about
it's slightly on this particular screen
that you can see here
like what is rendered on the server what
is on the right side is rendered from
the browser
yeah what parts of the right side are
rendered
everything is not wide
[Laughter]
everything that is
the thing that you can you can do in the
css
so all the icons you can do in css all
the
all the menus you can do in css all the
status bar you can do it in css okay so
but
the big one thing uh that's the document
so like normally there will be some text
and stuff that is not
that is rendered on the server so you're
gonna find it so
that's where the separation was yes okay
yes but
then you can see these dialogues there
and these are
the servers
it's awesome to have candy in the room
as well what the presentation so
i'm not sure anymore how liberals is
calling
the slides it's the same way so again
the document
but once you start the presentation
it's you next it's you next
i don't know sorry
oh it's okay i don't need applause no no