hi
i'm julian apparently it's time to start
now so um let's start
um yeah so um this is me
um i actually work for mozilla um i
should perhaps point this out
great great company to work for um
so that they say for talks there's
guidelines for talks and one thing you
should never do
at the start of a talk is apologize for
how bad your slides are or how badly
organized you are
or how repetitious the slides are so
anyway i apologize for
um how repetitious my slides are
especially the first few
and i also apologize for your hardened
compiler nuts in the room that
i might say some stuff which you already
know
anyway um with no further ado let me
proceed so this is about memcheck
valverin's the most commonly used tool
and it basically runs your program
and as i'm sure you're mostly aware does
two different
sets of checks um one of which is it
checks whether you're reading and
writing
memory in the correct or allowable
places and that's
pretty simple to figure out so
i'm not talking about that the other
thing it does is
it checks whether you are doing branches
and also
making addresses and stuff like this
based on undefined data
because that's actually dangerous that
may cause your program to crash or
misbehave in general and that is a
relatively
a difficult problem by comparison so
that's what i'm talking about today
one of the things we tried to do with
memcheck is always to have a very low
false positive rate
so when it says there is a problem here
you're almost certain that there really
is a problem here
um and that i think that's important for
developer productivity
so um you know 2005 15 years ago
everything was under control with the
false positives no problem there
ten years later we have these compilers
clangs
gcc and probably the intel compiler and
everybody else being
much more aggressive about optimizing
and
there was an increasing number of false
positive
undefined value checks being reported
so we had to come up with a bunch of
tricks
or techniques to deal with these
so as a summary of the rest of the talk
i'll talk a little bit about some
definedness tracking examples and like i
say i apologize for repeating myself
from the
talk two years ago then i'll talk about
the core problem today which is that
compilers actually
generate branches on undefined values in
some
some circumstances strange how it sounds
and i'll show you what my my solution to
this was
so first some some basic stuff
so memcheck is actually going to track
the entire state of your process with a
whole
shadow state that means all the
registers and all the memory
each bit of state there has another
bit of another bit which tracks the
definedness of
the corresponding bit in the real
program
and although it's not important we have
one to mean undefined and zero to mean
defined
it actually generates faster faster
instrumentation code
when when the program does some basic
operation like adds two numbers
um memcheck does a kind of a shadow
computation on the side
which corresponds to it and i write it
with these hashes
or pound signs and so uh it's going to
take
you know the dividedness bits for x and
they're defined in this bits of y
and trying to compute what they define
in this state for the
resulting you know add added value
is and mostly it just allows defined in
this
it just follows definingness through the
program but
and that only works until you get to
some particular places where you really
have to report an error if there's
something undefined so
those places are basically when you do a
conditional branch
that's the case that's important today
it also checks for um undefined values
in
in addresses because that's obviously
bad loading from on
unknown addresses um and if you want to
read more about
the gory details there's this paper
which you can
basically explain to it's a bit old but
you get the general idea from that
so some simple example well very simple
examples
well how would we even do this
so how would you how would you come up
with the
analysis which tracks undefined values
so one thing we can say is that for
every operation
every arithmetic operation we know that
we in principle you could implement it
using
and or not or it's actually you know
nand and nor
in real implementations but it doesn't
doesn't matter
and we know for
all of these three fundamental
operations exactly what the defined in
this
propagation is so here i really wish i
was taller right
so in particular for not we can see that
we
you take if you put an undefined bit
then you're going to get a resulting
undefined bit
and for and well if you
and one with an undefined bit you're
going to get an undefined bit which is
not surprising
but the important thing to know about
and is that if you and
zero with an undefined bit then you get
zero so it actually
removes undefined industry in the system
and intuitively we kind of know that
because we spend all day long you know
writing bit mask you know and
you've pulled this value out of memory
and and out the bits you don't want to
see all the bits that are
kind of undefined
so we could actually in fact in
principle
derive the um exact defining this
behavior for all sorts of operations
like comparisons and subtractions and
whatever
from these three rules um i would say
that exclusive or is a bit of a
an exception but that's out of the
picture
uh being practiced as completely
infeasible so um
impeacably expensive so we're gonna do
some cheap approximations which i'll
show you in the next slide
and the reason the cheap approximations
work most of the time
is because i think it's actually really
hard for humans to reason about
arithmetic operations
on a mixture of defined and undefined
bits
so and that includes compiler writers
so especially compiler writers over here
maybe
so that means that they don't actually
happen very often
or they happen only in very limited set
of scenarios
so here's a good example this is integer
edition
and i have this running example where
i'm adding one zero undefined zero to
zero zero zero one and there's three
potential options we could take here the
simplest is just to say if any
input bit is undefined then the whole
output is undefined
so that's what the first first line
shows you
but this is actually completely useless
in practice
because what we will often do is pull
out
from memory so do a 64-bit load of which
we
actually only care about the lower 16
bits and then add
another 16 bit value onto the the 64 bit
value we just pulled out
and we just don't care about the top 48
bits we only care about the lower 16
bits
so this is no good because in that kind
of scenario
it would say the whole thing is
undefined but that's not true
so then the next best step is to say
well
we know that undefined at this in
addition only propagates leftwards
up the word uh you know to more
significant bits
because addition only depends on the
bits
to the right of myself so to speak
that makes sense so in this case we
would
say that these two bits produce this one
that's fine
and then we have a undefined value so
from there upwards it's all undefined
that sounds um reasonable but there's a
problem which is that um
clang and i think gcc probably are
cleverer than that
and they know that a single and a
defined zero will stop
leftward propagation and they actually
sometimes
rely on this so in this example
we have a zero plus
undefined is going to produce an
undefined bit
but there's no carry out of that to the
next position up
so these two bits remain
defined in the output and
memcheck will instrument additions
accordingly
and generate um you know x86 code to
actually
uh implement those that instrumentation
so you have the cost of like roughly
three five
and ten instructions this in particular
is kind of expensive to do so
i try and avoid it where possible
right so yes we're trying to um
we're in the game of choosing
approximations um from real world
experience
and i really really wish i was taller
here
for the uh for the case of adding and
subtracting
um in general you nowadays you have to
do
the most expensive analyses because
sometimes clang will set a bit in a word
by
adding uh
it adds just a word with only one bit
set
so it can use an lea instruction and
save a register or some stuff like that
i don't know
um but the problem is that's actually
really expensive and most edition
doesn't need that
most addition is actually for computing
address for computing addresses
so memtech will try and make some local
analysis to see which
editions are used only for computing
addresses and do a cheaper
instrumentation
for and and all we've seen that um there
are these important cases with ending
with zero
and oring with one produces a defined
result and that's a really important we
use that all the time for kind of shift
to shift and mask style operations
for integer equality again
we have the situation now where
compilers will
routinely generate comparisons where
part of the
integer comparisons integer equality
where part of the inputs are undefined
and that's actually okay
providing that you can find at some bit
index in the two words
two bits one of which is one and one of
which is zero and they're both defined
because that means that the whole
comparison says
no they're not the same
it takes a bit of thinking about but
it's true
and so for example um gcc will sometimes
do comparisons on
um a structure with two elements which
will fit in a single word
by pulling both both out into a single
register and then comparing
even if one part is undefined and shifts
are tracked exactly because shifts are
really easy to track
exactly everything else is approximated
so basically we say that any
input undefined values produce a
completely output undefined output value
and that's fine but you notice also
there are
many many examples many ways which it's
inexact and could easily
be confused so it doesn't know that
multiplying an undefined value by zero
produces a defined value but again
nobody really uses that in practice and
here's another example i just came
across the other day this is
quite subtle if we have some number x
and we're doing an
unsigned greater than or equal to
of a bit pattern which ends in a
sequence of zeros
then it's only the bits that correspond
bits in x that correspond to that part
which actually define the result
so the lower four bits of x can be
undefined here
here can be undefined and you still get
the defined result
so this is really subtle because if that
was for example
greater than rather than greater than or
equal to then that's not true
and probably if that was a sign
comparison that is also not true
so anyway it was all fine no problem
until this happened
and we started to see this i mean in
various places but
because of where i work i started to see
this in the firefox um or the
gecko source tree a lot about five years
ago
so here's a typical example we get we
want to basically
call compute something which is going to
do some kind of operation
and possibly write the result of the
operation
in the address that you've provided
and it also is going to return some kind
of flag indicating in
success or failure this is very very
common
in gecko code where you say you know do
this and if you get an
error then if you don't have an error
then do the next thing
and we were seeing complaints on the you
know the the tester
anything why is this this is really
strange because the code is actually
correct
and once you look at the disassembly
it's clear that it's actually switched
the order of the compare the compiler
has switched the order of the comparison
around
so it's actually checking the result
value before
it's checking this is it okay actually
okay value
and you think well that's like that
can't be right
but actually it is right if
this if this is actually kind of hard to
get your head around but
in general using the c lazy
and semantics you can actually switch an
a
and b around like that if you can prove
that
this is always false whenever that's
undefined
so if that's undefined then you're
guaranteed that this is always false
so the whole thing is false
and it's really scary and don't ask me
why gcc and clang
do this i just do this that's all i care
about
there's another actually um condition
here which is also b must not have any
side effects because you're executing it
speculatively so it can't do any stalls
or i guess things that would cause a
visible
change of behavior but again
it seems to be correct unfortunately
so so okay the both the program is
correct
and the compiler is correct i should
maybe say the reason it can
and do this i think is because it
analyzes compute something i assume it's
some kind of inter-procedural analysis
which from which it knows that
how does this go whenever result
is not written to then the return value
of the function is
false i can't think of another way that
that can be correct
you see the other thing that can write
your results is compute something
yeah i mean i'm guessing and it kind of
doesn't matter
anyway so nevertheless the whole thing
is correct so why is memcheck reporting
errors well the answer to that is real
simple
and i apologize here to the compiler
crew
um basically the problem is that memphis
unit of analysis is a basic block which
is just a straight line
piece of code which usually ends in a
conditional branch
and it that is the scope of the analysis
and it assumes that every conditional
branch is important
which always used to be true up until
this happened
so this kind of structure here becomes
essentially four basic blocks and
in the transform case we're doing
compute something doing a comparison
here
and so it says well this is undefined so
i'm going to complain and then
here's the sort of the fix up comparison
which makes it harmless
and you know you wind up here when you
would have got there anyway
so that's bad
so i wasn't really sure what to do
yeah the problem is essentially mem tech
can't see over
multiple basic blocks and that that
assumption is deeply wired into the
architecture of the all of valgrind
that is essentially a basic block at a
time jet
and an instrumentation system
so what was i going to do well i wasn't
really sure there seemed to be some
really complex thing you could do here
where
it's like yeah we can wait till we come
back to the point where the
flows come back together which is the
immediate post dominator of the branch
and then if the machine state is not
changed in
and it's like no way that's way too
complex i can never make that work
and even if i did it was going to be way
too slow
so it's like i don't have a solution to
that and i did a talk here two years ago
which basically said i don't have a
solution to this problem
so summer 2018 i was kind of depressed
because i thought it was like
well this is the end of the road for
memcheck it's like memcheck defeated by
optimizing compilers after 15 years of
you know 15 years of valiantly
struggling against optimizations
and then it was winter and winter sucks
i don't like winter march so i was
still depressed and then this
summer i think in my garden and i'm
thinking that's funny
i'm sure i already solved this problem
once
yeah this is actually the same
deal as for and where and the zero and
undefined produces
your defined result the problem is that
the and has been
separated out over multiple basic blocks
so
um that value pure value flow
instrumentation
uh doesn't it doesn't kick in and
won't remove the error so it's like
all right what we need to do is recover
or reconstruct the end
and thought well how the hell am i going
to do that
so here's the plan right it's actually
a real simple plan in principle
if if we see a basic block which is
essentially what you would get from
compiling an and
a a a two-armed condition like this
right then we're gonna transform it into
this which is has a single condition
here so it requires doing more analysis
in the front-end
front-end pipeline of valve so
in particular we need to see this
structure where you have this you know
first condition and the second condition
and they both you know in both cases the
false side leads to one place
and the true side leads to another place
that's
idiomatic translation
um and so we're going and then we
basically going to merge these two big
blocks
giving that block but um
so uh maybe i can point with this
actually
so hey what
oh what a brilliant idea sorry
yeah yeah good good no seriously i
hadn't thought of that
so uh we have uh now this combined c1
and c2 which is a value and
and we can just do our accurate
instrumentation and it's fine
but we do have to be a little bit
careful because this
b which is arbitrary computation
we now have to make conditional
uh so that b is not executed if
c one was false right so that's the
function that you keep having to fix
mark
this is is something is guardable or
something that keeps failing
right um so
yeah so that was the plan
so the question is how how am i going to
implement this
and in particular i didn't want to do
this on a per architecture basis because
we support five architectures
or maybe six if you think that arm 32
and 64 are basically different
architectures and their branch
instructions are all different
and you know it would be complete pain
in the ass to do that
so my plan was to do the obvious thing
and kind of lean on valgrind's
intermediate representation
infrastructure into which everything is
translated into
um so we're gonna you know have the
translate these blocks into ir just like
before
but when you come to when you've done
that
then we will um pass that through the ir
optimizer
here which is also something we've done
before which
basically normalizes greatly reduces the
amount of
the difference in representation that
there can be
and then we'll do the traditional
compiler idiom of patent match to see if
we have a
idiom that we want to transform and then
do the transformation
so it does that when it comes to the end
of a basic block it simplifies it
figures out what the two branch targets
are and then starts analyzing both
targets so you have sort of
you go two levels down the tree to see
if you can find
um one of these and style idioms
and i was a bit concerned about this
because this
you know the jit in valgrind is actually
limiting limits performance especially
when you start
start a large program you might have to
jit
like a half a million basic blocks
before anything actually happens like
that's true for firefox for example this
is going to slow down the jit well
that's actually true but the
thing that gets you out of that is it's
not going to slow down the jit much
because most of the reason
most of the reason that the jit is slow
is um to do with back end costs
so for a start after the memcheck has
inserted instrumentation into the ir is
about
several times larger and then the cost
of that
across from that is largely in register
allocation downstream
and this game is all in the front end
where there's relatively small amount of
um code to deal with so the front end
costs dominate so in practice it seems
to me okay
i should point out as well i've only
talked about and
here but the same mechanism logically
handles or
because in fact you know an or
expression is just going to be compiled
into the same
um style of tree as an ant expression
it's just that
you know the conditions are swapped
around via de morgan's law
so it naturally handles that
um and that's pretty much the end of the
story
so memtec lives to ride another day
which i
kind of thought it wouldn't at one point
um i've tested this on
on firefox and you know with clang minus
o2 and gcc minus o2 which is a pretty
strident you know pretty strict hard
test
because it's really big and does all
sorts of weird weird
and we get zero false positives at least
of this kind there are still
false positives when you pass undefined
memory to system calls but that's a
different
different problem and because it's all
done at the ir level is basically
naturally
available for all architectures of
valkyrie supports except
unfortunately s390 is crashing so i need
to talk to you about this
uh for reasons i couldn't figure out and
also mips is crashing
so i've disabled it in the tree for now
we can just turn it back on it's a
little
if death i don't know i don't think we
have a missed maintainer in the room
right
no oh good it's in tree now
seems to work and
we have to ship it in 3 16 which will
happen as soon as
i get my act together
i think that's all i wanted to say
[Applause]
so are there any questions
okay no questions that's usually bad
because it either means nobody
understood you or nobody believed you
so let me start from the back first yeah
yeah so is there any other thing that is
a huge false positive
like next on the list
the question thank you is the question
is are there any other false positives
that i need to deal with that are next
on the list
not really the only other serious bunch
source of false positives now is the
case where you
programs take a structure and send it to
like the right
system call or you know send it on a
network socket or whatever
and that structure has some alignment
padding holes which are uninitialized
memcheck has no way to know what part of
the structure
should actually be defined and what is a
padding hole so it just
complains that you're sending
uninitialized data out of the process
and there's nothing that can be done
about that
so there just i wanted to say thank you
because
uh several weeks ago i came across
exactly this false positive french i
also wondered why it happened
i don't know why yeah and yeah i have a
question maybe
it's not maybe you're not just right
but did you look at sanitizers
do they have a similar diagnostic and
what they do about the same problem
the question is did i look at other
sanitizers like asan you mean and
msan well i didn't look at msan and
asan doesn't actually do define it as
tracking anyway so
it doesn't it wouldn't tell me anything
i should also point out
another reason why this is important at
least in the mozilla context is because
um in the c plus world you can often
actually at least work around these
kinds of problems by giving you know
dummy initializations to variables
but in rust um you you can't do that
because
um everything is sort of initialized
anyway and there's no place where you
can
add extra initializations so we were
seeing russ code which would show false
positives and there's nothing you could
do about that
hi first congrats on fixing this problem
and maybe see the question about do you
envision
that you may need in the future to like
go
up a level deeper in your analysis like
you go one level deep uh
and transform one another do you see the
case that
you could see like two levels and yeah
keep fighting with the files
so the question is um as i presented it
this only deals with one level of and
which basically means two level two
going two levels deep in the tree
do i envisage that it needs to go deeper
um well the question is the answer is to
that i already solved that because
it's not exactly what i said what it
does is it has a block
and then if the block ends in the
conditional branch then it
chases the conditional branch and if
if it finds the and idiom which it can
fold it pushes that ir back to the end
of the block and then re-analyzes it
so in fact it can it would be able to
deal with you know
ands with three things
chained together if you had to do that
providing that the
speculatively evaluated stuff now can
actually be conditionalized
so in practice it seems to work fairly
well even at just
two levels yeah
there was a question at the back hi um
you mentioned that you handle shifts
completely do you handle shifts with
undefined
uh you know distance of shifting
yeah um that that i think that is
oh sorry yes yes the question is um i
said i have
uh handle shifts exactly does that
include um when the shift amount is
undefined
uh yes it is the if the shift amount is
undefined then there is
the entire result of the shift is
undefined
so this is called pessimistic casting in
the paper
yeah you're right we could be more but i
mean who's actually ever going to shift
by an amount which is partially
undefined and
going to get expected a result that they
can understand
yeah any more questions
last chance okay thank you very much