so
the next presentation will be with
jordan which will
talk about more than one tool for
collaborating on writing the tiki cms
so hello everybody so this is not about
one specific product contrary to the
others
it's about uh sharing our experience
from the tiki the technique cms group
where software community
about well producing collaborative tools
and also collaborating and what we use
among ourselves the reason i'm here is
because
well i've been really interested in open
source and internet
since uh a very long time i discovered
tiki and i immediately
felt part of the tk community
and since uh 2011 i
professionally uh work
for the tk well as a tiki consultant
so that's not the main topic there's
more here on the link if you're really
interested in my
in me um so uh what am i
uh what does our viewpoint
come from the tiki community i'm talking
about
produces some open source software which
is over one million
lines of code we do major releases every
eight months
every free uh release is a long-term
support version which is supported
about five years the project started
uh nearly 20 years ago by luis
algiris and he stayed
some years and he left the project
afterwards he's not among us anywhere
anymore
so the so that community it's
it's community-managed open development
software it is not
led by any single company
we have a
number of us who are consultants
manage for hire but we all have our own
customers it's not uh there's no central
point
it's not a company which manages
anything
so uh there's no single company as i
said there's no benevolent dictator
there's not even the
initial offer so um
communication is the only thing that
keeps us together
so it's really crucial we without
communication there's just no community
and yeah and we're very open
uh the way we work it's we're really
open anyone can contribute
that's what um version
person control systems are for the wiki
way of writing software
you want to add it if it's really bad
and causes problem it can always be
rolled back
um so obviously
i guess everybody knows the sentence
eat your own dog food which means that
you're never going to convince anyone to
use your software if you're not using it
yourself and the second reason why you
have to
use it as much as possible is that yeah
how that's
that's how you improve it that's how you
see what people do
with it when you are among those people
and then we improve it we add things we
fix it that's great um
just about tiki the special thing about
tiki it's it's
all inbuilt so at least among the
community we never have to
argue about which plugin we're going to
use there's no
many plugins that all the features are
there they're active
or they're not active we can use
whatever we like
so we use the forums as such
in order to communicate as well as
forums are for we also have wiki pages
and documents
which means which we use a lot because
that's where we have our documentation
for users
on one side we have technical
documentation on another one
we also have to discuss marketing stuff
which
we as an open source company are not
really great at but we try to um
and we share promotional information you
know for
for making t-shirts or stuff like that
they're all set and don't know
downloadable
all those websites have a are federated
there's the single login etc it works
well
people use that um
it's really it's well as usual the
documentation for user is a bit
late usually but it gets done
um we have uh some
what we call a tracker which is really a
database because
it started as a bug tracker and then it
expanded
uh that's where we share uh
well that's where people report bugs and
also
ask for new features that really works
fine because
we can discuss them we can fix them
we know how what remains to be done
etc we also have
articles feature that's for that's
mostly for communication when we have a
new release someone
gets an article and we share it on
social media
and all that um we have a blog feature
which is rather underused
it's used by the
by the assistance administrators team
the people who manage our infrastructure
there is a
there is some kind of a wiki page
structure
and restricted documents and the
restricted blog and the blog is there
because
it's less powerful than articles and all
we want about this
is to do a operation report
so you need a title you need to say when
it was done and you need to describe
what was done so that the other
assistant means
know what has been done and they can
look at how it was done so they can get
an inspiration
and all that no need for anything
more complicated than that that's why we
use the blog for that
we have comments comments uh can
be linked to any of the above so
you might wonder why we need comments
when for example and anyone can edit the
wiki pages
by anyone i didn't mention it yeah
anyone can register
create an account and you know and
contributes there's no
real problem uh sometimes we get
spammers this way and we just roll
everything back that's
it's a wiki um so the comments are
for discussing a document well some
stuff like the wishes tracker are
commented that's obvious but the wiki
pages is
uh the issue you have with wiki pages is
that everybody can contribute on some
topic
like a technical topic etc but people
are polite
so they add their opinion they never
remove anything
from anyone else so it's they might
prefer to comment
rather than change the content because
they are not so sure
etc that's why well both are needed
um we also kind of it's kind of a
way of communication yeah we we've used
tiki to
let people provide added information
about
about themselves or about why they are
in the community or
or what they look like in a photo when
they register
and another technical feature which
is of course uh really important is that
when you have an account you can decide
you can set watches on what you're
interested in so that you get
email when something happens because
you're not going back every day on the
site
so yeah so that's basically
everything tiki provides for us i'm not
saying it's not working
i mean we use it we like it we improve
it
uh but there's more uh we also have
historic tools
we use that because i told you it's
nearly 20 years
old projects sourcefuls was really
fashionable at one time i tell you
before they got technical and ethical
issues so we still have
used that for two things first the
subversion rapper which is
being migrated to gitlab but it's still
going to stay here because we have
those long term support versions which
we promise people that
they will get upgrades for five years
so it will switch to being read-only but
still available so that
people can upgrade their website and
get the newest security fixes and bug
fixes
and they provide mailing lists which uh
which we use actually so we have a
developers maintenance which
is very successful that's basically
where we discuss what we want to do
etc it's even the one when we say okay
we i want to start this
and here is the here is the wiki page
uh about it but still that's how we get
the information
so that works fine so of course there's
this issue
that those mailing lists um
people complain that yeah but if you're
not registered
on the maintenance uh you don't get the
information
etc but we have that feature that we can
synchronize it with a forum i told you
about the forum one of the forums has
the same content you can
it shows up in the forum when you're
mail and you can answer in the mailing
list and we get it in the
uh answer in the forum we're getting a
mailing list we have another one for
users
uh total failure because
uh people will just ask on the
developers mailing as they get better
answers for more knowledgeable people
and yeah yeah
we have an uh mailing need so it just
gives
all the comments everything that changes
in the code and
we can review it we have that if that's
where excel people actually use it and
they answer there
in order to comment on discuss uh that
shouldn't be this way or
yeah that's useful uh
historic non-social tools yeah we we are
on irc
and uh some of us like that it worked
well
we have zero maintenance about that uh
only issue three years ago i think they
had a massive
dose yeah they were had trouble so we
use it
much less it works better again but you
know
and that's how we have frequent debates
about why
what's best
nothing is best i mean
the people who go on the forums are not
the same people who answer questions on
irc
it's just it just spreads the knowledge
yeah so yeah xmpp also is a great
so another thing that's really important
is uh the tiki fest
uh tiki fest is when people who don't
usually meet
meet like uh you know there's four of
them uh some of us are here or
some of the us came some days before
and we meet it's
not a technical issue it's just really
important to do that because
once you know the people you can go back
to sending them
emails and uh
it just it's just easier because you
know what the person will understand how
you communicate
it's just simpler and also you can ask
questions like
why are they in in the project you know
are they really
are they full time are they just curious
are they
it's yeah another non-technical
thing to keep in mind uh yeah tiki fests
are
kind of expensive so we also do online
meetings
and
and it's been mentioned one of the great
thing about
open source software is don't hesitate
to reach to other projects for
collaborations
they're open we had a collaboration with
big blue button
so that got us integration you are
logged in on the tiki site
for the meetings and then you click and
you get in the big blue button room and
you have your own name
and if you didn't register it shows
guest
we get our um we do that for monthly
roundtable meetings
which started as webinars but it's not
really presentations it
one hour uh very short topics
you know like hey next month
there's them who's coming and one hour
of
presentations anyone has some new things
to present to
how it's done and new features are
usually
easier to present on the on a way on a
webinar because then it's usually
someone else who will have to write the
user documentation we are mostly
volunteers on that you know
tiki admin group meetings oh i didn't
mention that
we have um we have an association which
as i said as you may have figured out
the community created the association
the association did not
create the community it's for holding
the copyright
to the name and dealing with server
and stuff so they meet every three
months
um we've also we really like jitsumit
also
we've been in contact with them but
there was no real reason
for doing any collaboration because it
just works and for our time
big blue button had took a long time
before they switched from flash to html5
so
now we and we were not really happy and
we were really happy to have an
uh an alternative so yeah no big blue
button runs fine and
yeah and it still is recorded on our
servers which is cool because jitsimi
doesn't have that you we could record
that but i think it goes to google we
obviously don't like that we i mean
i'm happy for them that they have that
option is clearly the thing to do but we
don't want to use it
other ways of collaborating is that tiki
is part of wiki switch
which is a project about providing
all the needs of a small company
only with open source staff so we get in
touch with
people or other products and we get
contacts with some of those other
projects that's how we have that
xmpp thing which competes with irc
because it's
it is more modern you know and um
we have people we getting in touch with
goose especially about having that
opened fire server converse gs which
gives you
gives us a web mail a web-based
interface to the xmpp which you can
get on wiki suite.chats
and the pade is an app which is also
a browser-based but it has its own
window
um that's that gets us because i think
xmpp as a protocol has a lot of things
for its federated it has
everything uh but the focus i
think personally is the clients
right now for for more
use of it um think thing is also part of
it so
we use it to spread backups and all that
and yes so the message again
is yes uh we discovered that even though
we provide
collaboration tools uh
a good thing is to have a lot of them
and also
some we have for historical reason and
we want to change etc it's not the same
ones
as 10 years ago it changes so we want to
change also we also have plans
i told you we are not going to stay on
subversion
not even on salesforce but that takes
time
for change management's reasons we want
to really improve
our email the mail integration
capability we have
shift integration gmap in
in tiki and in tk21 which is the one we
just
branched yesterday uh
we have caldaven dev
and as usual now that we have them
they we will improve our way of using
them
as a summary um how does it work
generally speaking for us when we want
to know
where we want to go and make plans the
things that work
great because at some point you have to
make a decision
uh the tiki fest when does enough of us
and the other others on online at the
end of this
decision just and say okay we all kind
of agree that
that's what we do we have the
development
meaning is because everybody's on it
basically so
you know what's going on it's a nice
place for and it's and it is recorded we
have
we have all of that um wiki pages are
also
great when we don't want when we don't
know what where we want to go and we
want more feedback the wish tracker is
also one of those ways
that new stuff pop up because people ask
for them
and we do them or not um
and there are those monthly roundtable
meetings
the tag is a tiki admin group which
also gets things for plans and when we
want to discuss how we do things
uh well there's a lot of discussion
about
comments which were done and people just
start a thread about that or again the
dev tiki or
wiki pages just okay how do we do that
which is basically so
did i leave time for questions so
then any questions about or unclear so
uh if i understand correctly so in the
tiki community you have kind of a
limited amount of developers of
development workforce so how do you
manage to basically provide new features
to the project
while still supporting some of the
features that you support as part of the
kind of backup compatibility strategy or
long-term support strategy so one of the
reasons
we are really happy with the way a tiki
community works is that
a lot of us do that as paid
consultants and that means we have our
customers oh the question was
we have limited development force how do
we
spread the word the the work and decide
on
support old stuff and add new stuff
um part of
our job is it's
very powerful software it gets really
complicated
people like to have a consultant do it
for them because they have another work
they're good at
which they want to focus on and um
so but they have complex needs
so basically it's you it's often if that
ticket has
90 percent of what they want and one of
us
they they pay one of us to add the 10
percent and we
recontribute that 10 percent to the
community
so that's how we get the new things as
for
maintaining maintaining the old things
well whoever uses the
old things will complain that
broken on upgrade they also uh yeah they
also
want upgrades because okay we we stay
five years is not that long
they come back they won the new version
they said i don't
thanks for the new stuff but i like the
old one and
you just broke it it seems or it could
be better
and so there's no yeah central point
where people decide you will do this
you will do this it's if nobody uses
something
then nobody will touch it it's and after
a while we say
okay this is deprecated
any other question
you