okay so
hello everyone um i'm aniket pradhan am
i audible over there
it's fine yeah cool so i'm aniket
pradhan and today i'll be talking about
nero fedora and how we can
use i mean like about neuro fedora what
it is and what's the aim and motive
behind it and
what's what's the purpose of like
actually having a neuro fedora
thing over here so i guess like everyone
would be aware of fedora what fedora is
so fedora is just another another
operating system based on linux
just like debian or ubuntu
so nero fedora is a group that's main
purpose is to provide new
neuroscience packages neuroscience
software
in fedora so before we dig into
dig deeper into nato fedora let's just
start about like
how do we do our research in
neuroscience in the neuroscience
community
so the research pipeline basically
so i mean as you can see in the diagram
it's actually a simplified diagram but
it's
actually quite complex process so i mean
it's the general
overflow i mean like we go from uh data
analysis
to uh theory and then we have like
uh modeling our neurosci our near
any neuroscience structure and then we
have our experiments and stuff
like more most of these works nowadays
are being
conducted through the use of computer
software and computer tools
so like there are many there are many
tools
like for experimental we have like eeg
monitoring and stuff and like we have ct
machines we have mri
for data analysis we have statistical uh
machine learning libraries
and data analysis like numpy cipher i
mean like python libraries i mean
and then we have theory and uh modeling
uh
softwares there are there are all kinds
of simulators
so i mean like there's a list of like
all kinds of
all kinds of tools and software that you
we use to like uh produce and reproduce
information in the uh research domain
that's
like we need softwares for visualization
academic writing like
logic and um i don't know any other sort
of
logic but yeah we have non-academic
writing like blogging
and uh yeah we do we use software for
podcasting and stuff and
so on so forth okay so uh
what do we mean by free and open signs
okay
so i mean like free and open like
everyone should be able to
like have the freedom to share read or
make amendments and modify to your
scientific material
right like that's the definition of
first everyone should have access the
should have freedom to access and study
what you are actually working on
right so okay let's move on forward
so over here it's about it's uh
it's a paper uh by p gleeson uh about
a commitment to open science and
neuroscience it's basically its main
motive is to solve the reproducibility
crisis that we have like we are unable
to reproduce the data or
the results i mean like that's very
important if you are publishing some
papers or
your results on on to the public
so like what can be the benefits of
having open source codes
i mean like it can first of all solve
the reproducibility crisis
like people can reuse that code and then
build upon their new
tools and software on it and the
publication or the code becomes an
adword for each other
i mean like you go to a publication
people will look at your code you go to
the code people look at your publication
and then
you can go on forth with developing new
stuff
so neuro fedora why so i mean like
the neuroscience community is full of i
mean the scientific community is full of
people from different domains i mean not
everyone over here
is a software developer right i mean
that most of most people are biologists
or some
data analysts or some not everyone is a
software developer
not everyone has the required experience
right so
only a small proportion of the
scientists
or the actual people working on research
are trained software developers so they
work on the software
and they create uh they create uh
they are basically developers of the
software too they create us
they create a tool that can be used for
by the end users
but the main problem here is that the
developer may not provide like proper
instruction on
how to use the tool i mean he may not
provide documentation
and there are some people the end user
and like
the the end users they're not not
necessarily they are not necessarily
trained software developers
so they might not have the required
knowledge
they may not have the required knowledge
or the
experience to build and use the tool
directly
and over here the end users may not
always provide the feedback
on how good the tool is if it's working
correctly or not
so if you are a developer i mean a
neuroscience a tool developer
then like we often face many of such
problems like
there's often a single developer a
single professor a single professor
who's working on a single
uh or a small team who's working on a
single uh development tool
so and like given how interdisciplinary
in the neuroscience community is
most researchers are not entrained and
development so
i mean like we have limited maintenance
or short lived projects because once a
research event started research work is
done like
people no longer contribute to it and
they have limited access to hardware
limited code quality
and like based on all these uh evidences
like software using
research is not always of the best
quality may not always be of the best
quality
so i mean like it may or may not mean
the development standards that
people in the programming domain have
like the proper developers
who are trained in software programming
and all so
and they have complex dependency chains
there can be some dependency loops as
well
but like how can how can a developer
solve that so
that's the problem in the software in
the research domain right now
but for the end users like uh
many of the end users they waste time
and effort to install
your the when whenever they waste time
in installing a particular tool
they have to go through the particular
tools dependencies and then resolve the
dependencies first and then get the tool
right they lack the required skill of
programming
usually i mean like not always but yeah
they have a hard time setting up and
using the software they rarely send bug
reports upstream
and they do not check for tests i mean
like they do not run the test with
so how do they ensure the correctness of
the working program i mean
uh testing the correctness of a program
is very important in the res in the
research domain and that
academic domain that's to ensure your
uh your final papers correctness
and many of the end users are unaware of
the help for developmental tools
like many of many many end users do not
know that there
exists a library to analyze your
dicom files and everything but instead
they do it manually so
that's what that's where neuro fedora or
this red
distributions come in so what basically
distributions do
is that they take the code from the
developer and then they package it in a
neat and nice way
and then provided it to the end user so
the distributions like fedora or debian
they act as
a liaison between the user and the
developers they provide
the feedback and report bugs to the
developer as well
and it basically simplifies in
your installation and your usage of
any software tool that is being packaged
so i mean like
distribution selected where they have a
good advantage at being over here
they have high-end servers they have
like multiples multiple mirrors running
across the globe
and they have you have the
infrastructure and they're like firm
packaging guidelines
follow the best practices we always run
the test suits and we
before a tool this package it goes
through a heavy-duty review process
so i mean like the tool is properly
tested and then
it is provided to the end users
and we constantly work on community
development we learn from
one another and we are we always provide
help to the users
so that's where we come in
so neuro fedora what it is it's
a group of people who are aiming to
package your neuroscience tools
and software for the fedora operating
system
so our primary goal is to provide a
ready-to-use integrated force
platform for neuroscientists right so we
aim to create
a spin or a lab image of your fedora
and provide it to the users in fact we
have created one
and we will i will share it to you in
the next few slides
and our secondary and the secondary
goals is to provide
improve the standards of packaging and
maintaining the tools
help users develop help users develop
the software development skills
that are required for when you are
creating a tool or when you are using it
and
make neuroscience accessible to
non-specialists
right so our neurofed with our current
metrics we just turned a year old in
september 2019
we have like 20 volunteers 16 packages
and only five who has from a
neuroscience background
so most of us are just acting as
packages while those five are actually
guiding us on how to
package and how to review stuff
we have five designers and newcomers as
well so
sorry so
about software we have like 135 tools we
have packaged for fedora right now
uh we have like the neuron simulator the
nest simulator genesis brian moves
and we are uh we have like multiple
uh packages in queue as well we have
around like 180 packages in queue
like or something sorry
sorry yeah so we have like 180 packages
in queue
that are being that are in process of
being packaged
and stuff so we have near mlight and
simulators of that kind as well so
i guess that's it this is the current
slide i mean
you can search us on google and you can
search we have a mailing list over here
as well we have an irc channel a
telegram channel as well
our documentation is present at neuro
dot fedoraproject.org
we have a blog as well please do have a
look at
it that's it for me so um any questions
uh people may have regarding neurofedora
over here
yes
is going please trying to upstream as
many of those packages into the main
fedora repository
can you please read the question um
uh i mean like uh all the packages that
we are creating right now
okay so okay yeah so uh
the question is uh if we are creating a
separate uh repository for fedora
uh this upstream is separate from the
federal repository right
so uh the upstream is separate from our
federal repository i mean we create we
are creating our
and we are creating our own uh packages
and they are getting stored in the
fedora servers the upstream is separate
from it we just
take the release turbo or the release
zip from the upstream and then use it as
our
uh source code and then we package it in
a lightweight nice way and then we
provide it to the end users
so it's all separate right
please as a follow-up question um how
would you describe the help or
the how does the fedora team core
welcomes like packaging coming from the
scientific background
uh coming from the scientific world yeah
so uh his question is uh what does the
fedora core team think of
the packages coming from the scientific
world so
um i don't have any views of that what
the core team
thinks of the fedora core teams thing
but we as a group
think that each and every like
uh software can like can be up from many
any domain like either be it scientific
or
video or multimedia so
that's our perspective that uh we want
neuroscience packages in fedora so we
formed a group
we want like neuroscience packages and
the fedora the community is very
welcoming the co
the core team they actually support us
for
including the packages in fedora sorry
for i have a bathroom right now
uh-huh anyone any questions anymore any
further questions
okay i guess that's it