so i just want to start off view three
love it i love you three i've been doing
uh
well actually view three but just view
overall i've been doing the last three
years
and it's really really good framework
that i've been using i really want to
talk more about it
and let you guys know about view three
coming up
there one thing i like about view three
is it's really easy to pick up
i bring in some grads into the company
sometimes
and i have they have a very easy time
kind of picking it up again they don't
have javascript experience
but they're able to kind of pick up um
based on the structure of you
um how it kind of works
um ujs has been kind of around
the last uh six years so it's like uh
2013 was the first version like uh
0.6 and it's been going since then and
view 3
is supposed to be released this quarter
but it's been held back at the moment uh
there
so state of view just to give you an
update on it
i was hoping by this talk when i
submitted this talk that
vue was three was supposed to be
released in the end of uh 2019
so i thought by the time this came
around i would have all everything done
for you
and showing you all the new features and
there
and like pro code examples of it so
unfortunately it's still an
alpha stage at the moment now i have a
kind of
i guess that there's view amsterdam in
three weeks they might release there i
don't know for certain
but it's something that i think is there
so it's still an alpha release
and planned for q1 they said when they
upd
when they kind of missed it they kind of
said q1 so and then most of the rfcs are
closed for comments at the moment
so um
as well with the with it not being
finished the only kind of
version of it that's available at the
moment is the kind of like the cdn
version so we import it into your html
and then you can kind of use the kind of
javascript there what we normally do
when we're programming in my company
is we use the kind of compiler the
vue.js compiler
so we have our dot view files and then
we compile it that's not ready because
the view loader
that understands that schema of that
file is not ready
so again the examples you see in the
view repository
is just uh ones from when they import
the kind of the cdn link
so it wouldn't be a thing without
showing like how popular view is
again it's not the most popular but i
think it's kind of gaining traction
um how you kind of measure popularity
and kind of
frameworks is kind of like up to
yourselves but i kind of picked it by
like
npm downloads so as you can see up here
is the green one
is that we react obviously the most
popular one
but then you see down here is um
view so reviews kind of come behind
behind react
and then you have like angular amber
source
and backbone so i think views kind of
get more and more popular
again i think it's the ease of use of it
again graduates can kind of pick it up
senior maybe infrastructure people that
never did javascript before i've seen
pick it up very quickly like
so i thought that's what i kind of like
about it
um these are the kind of new features
there's more than this that they've
introduced and these are the ones i'm
going to kind of go over
there um
so one thing about the these kind of
features and stuff you don't see
is it's a smaller code base now so
they've released
the way they've kind of done it is they
made it about 10 kilobytes now so it
used to be around 20 kilobytes the core
and they've kind of like
brought it down a bit there um there's
better typescript support which i won't
go over here
as well other features there there is
kind of like time slice and support
static tree uh host hosting and
you know optimized slot generation so
those are those other kind of um
features but we'll kind of go through
these ones here to kind of show you
hardcore the core what i found through
like
investigating this and going through the
rfcs is really what they've kind of done
is they've brought in some plug-ins into
the core of ujs
so that's the ones i'm going to go over
and then some of them they've just they
were never plug-ins before
and they've added them as new features
so you can think of it
some of the features that are in view
three you can actually do in view two at
the moment
and then when view three comes out it
should be like an easy upgrade
so i never say easy well you never say
easy because there's always going to be
some kind of problem but it should be
like
easy enough to do like so
that's i'll show you some of those as
well so just for
anybody actually one thing i forgot to
do how many vgs
developers are here i just kind of want
to know
say 50 60 60 okay that's good okay
lisa's getting more popular i've got to
ask that in the popularity a bit there
so just for the the guys that are not
vue.js developers
this what i love about it is the
structure of it so this is a single file
component
and you've got three sections for a
template which all the html goes to the
script
where all your kind of javascript goes
and your styling again when i show the
grads or maybe the senior
infrastructure team how to kind of
develop that's what i show them and they
can understand it pretty quick
do you know so this is a very basic one
of this
and here you have in your data section
your reactivity
so you have a thing called greeting and
the greeting will appear there and
that's your one web component
again it's very very simple for them to
understand
so this is like what i was talking about
earlier a compile time
file so vue.js has to use webpack to
convert it
into html and javascript files then
afterwards so this is not what's going
to appear on your kind of
application it's going to compile it for
you and this is not what's ready in
vue.js3 at the moment to take in the new
features that it's done
so
okay so one of the big ones that they're
one of the big features that came in and
there's a lot of controversy over it i
think people kind of got the wrong of
the stick straight away
is do you know the way there was the
optional api
now this is competition api again you
can either use one or the other and
view js3 it doesn't really matter um but
i would start
to use composition api for more bigger
components again we'll go
through that but um
it just really helps our kind of code
reusability and we kind of show that
so just again for the people that don't
maybe know vue.js here these are all the
kind of options
so this is the option based api and you
have these different sections you have
like the
the prop section the data the method the
computed components watch and mounted
and these are all the kind of things
this is really good really structured
grads understand this you know people
that haven't done javascript before they
can kind of go oh i need to do a new
method i do in the method section i need
to do a computer property i do in the
computer property section
only issue with this with this structure
as your um
components get bigger and bigger it cut
it's harder to maintain
and it's harder to reuse some features
you might have in it
so you might have a method in here that
looks after the greeting
and you have a message here and they
kind of work hand in hand say
when you want to use that in another
component you can't extract both of them
with the options api
so you can extract this into like the
method into a javascript file but then
the other kind of the reactive data
stuff
it doesn't follow it or if you're
watching the
the data property there that doesn't
follow it either you can't extract it
down that's the kind of issue
that they had and i've seen in my own
kind of programming and own products
that we make
like some components i can't bring down
far enough and there might be pairing
components really
and the composition api is kind of going
to solve that
again with some of these features you're
kind of like i kind of knew about the
problem but then there's a solution
you're like actually that's a solution
okay
so and it's really it's about
like maintaining that's all i want in
the products is about maintaining
and readability making that high quality
look
so the composition api again i just took
this from
view skills which is quite a good
resource you've seen before
that there was the different sections
export default and there was the
different sections in the options api
and now here you just have one method
called setup
and in setup you can define any of your
different
um your different functions that you
want to use
so you can kind of like what you do is
you import reactive or compute it
and you say actually i just want to do
the um
reactive bit and i want to do my method
and i want to return that so it's
available
in the template again the thing is about
this
is like you define what you want and you
return what you want then
big thing about this as well is this can
all be an object from like line
uh 12 to kind of uh 19 you can put that
in a separate javascript file then
so you're kind of like having you're
monitoring your state of the account
you're also updating the account in one
javascript file so you can export it
or have it imported from a javascript
file into your
um component and then you can use any
other component
so all the kind of properties are
following each other the computer and
the watch so that's kind of that makes
it a bit
uh easier to maintain
you can also reuse that kind of pattern
over and over again
now the only issue i find with this and
the thing we have with the options api
nice and structured nice nicely done
grads can kind of and senior engineers
can kind of understand it quickly
and implement it and you can kind of do
your code reviews work quite good
with this you can do whatever you want
anywhere you want
again within your own company or within
your code you have to come up some
pattern
that somebody doesn't just put a method
up here
and then compute it and then another
method and then reactive properties at
the end
you know you can kind of really create
unstructured
patterns then so with great power comes
great responsibility on yourselves to
kind of do that
and that's what i see it may be a
problem in the future with it
just to show you the difference um that
it's it's really the same it's just
another way of doing it
again you can either use composition or
optional
api there so again we have here we have
money and delta and they're reactive
and we get the the um
those functions from view so exactly as
well so the one thing i couldn't do
um with the view at three code base is
get composition working
so i imported it from view two again you
can get composition in your view to
application at the moment so this is
just my work around for now
so what i can do is i can have
reactivity money in delta and i can
that's it kind of maps to the options
api there
i can also do computed which then maps
to the computer kind of uh
function in the options api again
they're all kind of following the thing
so it's the same kind of thing it's just
a different way in a different pattern
of doing it
the only thing is i can export this this
section here
to here to a javascript file and call
that a feature
and then import it into my component and
then all i have to do
is return that object
and then it's part of the html then i
can use that kind of functions in html
so again just with this as well just to
explain it with the composition api
everything you define you have to return
so i have delta
money there are two reactive properties
i have to return them to be reactive in
the html
and then formatted money is a computer
property and then add as a method which
i'll use in my html
so i have to return them at the end and
they're part of the setup and that's all
i have to do
then
so that's the kind of composition how
they kind of map to each other i think
it's quite powerful i think it's going
to be a lot of reusability available
on it okay this is another feature does
anybody
has anybody pay portal does anybody know
portal is
okay about half the correct okay so
portal is like you have a gun you shoot
the wall yeah
and then it creates like um a portal and
you shoot the gun at another wall
and it creates a kind of connection
between them yeah so i can jump in that
portal and i can peer up there
so sometimes you might want that in your
in your dom yeah
you want to want to define something
when i'm coding in a certain section in
the dom or a web component
but when it renders i want it somewhere
else in the dom do you know that kind of
way so i'll bring it through kind of
idea again this is useful for kind of
pop-ups and modals
and notifications where they're kind of
like nearly at the end of the body
sometimes because you don't want them
interfering with the rest of the dom
so but really when you're maintaining it
you don't want to be going up and down
going okay
this is the button that enables the
modal but then i have to go to the
bottom page to kind of look at that code
but this allows you to kind of co-locate
the information when you're programming
but when it's kind of uh
executing then it uh renders somewhere
else so i'll just show you a quick
example here is a card class
and here i have like a button and when i
click the button
this section appears there
so that's fine it's just a v show when v
show just
toggles the display css attribute to
kind of none and show
so that's all it does but i don't want
this class
user class here interfering with my
with my like little section here it
might have stuff
the css that i don't want to have it but
what i really do want is i want this
section here
located next to the button because i
want the grads to understand
this button and this is connected but
really what i have to do
and if this is a modal kind of if i had
a class called modal
they might interfere with each other or
this class might interfere with it then
so i would have to move it out of here
and to the end of the body then
so that's what portal does it says i can
define it here
and this is the kind of idea is i can
define it in this nested kind of
component
when i'm programming so and what i'm
saying is a target
and when it's running it actually
appears somewhere else in the dom so i
could say here when i'm programming
this is the portal and this is how
javascript or the vue.js knows
it's wrapped in a portal element and
then when it's
uh running it will actually it's
probably what it's doing is a very
simple like
um find and replace so it's going
find me all the portals and then i'll
replace them wherever they say pop-up
target
so you have to have that so that's like
your portal like i shoot up the wall
that's my target um that's my source
and then i want to move this to where
the target is at the end of the room so
that's the kind of way it's doing it
again i never had that kind of
i did have that problem but i didn't
realize it until this again this is
available in vue.js too through
the uh viewportal um api but now it's
part of the core
and when i was looking through the code
this is part of the
code already so you can see there's
three different types we would go
through
there so again this is just showing you
that i can co-locate them now so the
problem i had two slides ago
i had a button but i want to say this
button
enables this kind of um say modal or
or a show and then it will actually
wherever i have to
put an id pop-up target it will appear
there in the rendered
html so that's what it's kind of solving
so yeah so it's kind of um
it's a handy feature i think as well so
keeping co-locating getting more
maintainable
and people understand that okay this
button and this is the code that it
activates
and then when it's rendering you don't
care because it's just for the
rendering somewhere else again you can
use it for other things
uh especially there like so so that's
the kind of portal feature
suspense is another one that's in court
that's part of the core now
it used to be in view two i would use a
thing called view weight
plug-in so the view weight is like do
you know when i fetch information
i want a loading kind of bar sitting
there now they've brought that into the
core so it's part of the default thing
and this is a type that it understands
vgs3
so all i'm just saying here is this
template as soon as it's uh
ready then display this component here
so it's just kind of like
uh when you're doing a fetch say when
the fetch is finished
then say fetch finished and then it will
display that and it's just a handy thing
to do your loading again react has
brought that into their core as well
with that render triggered this is a
really handy thing
so render trigger is part of the life
cycle now of web component
so this is a web component for vue.js
and you have these uh different
lifecycle methods
and now it's render triggered so render
triggered when it triggers something
to have to kind of render again it will
run this function and you can kind of
put like
debugging information or you can put
debugger there and say
actually you render it again why did it
you can kind of investigate it
again you can look at kind of
performance improvements there again
that wasn't available
in view two
fragments fragments is a handy one as
well i haven't
had a use for at the moment
but the thing is with view is in your
template section here
which is kind of figured out is you need
one root node
or one root element so you have a view
instance and one root
element you have to have that connection
sometimes
just for sake you might have a wrapper
node around our wrapper element around
your code
just because you will complain about it
if you have like
just these three elements here input
span p and you don't have fragments
around it view will say you don't have a
root element
you need to create one now sometimes you
just might create one just to have it
um just to make it um
happy there so one thing is you can do
is you can wrap fragment around it again
fragment is a type that view understands
now in view three
again i had to use the view fragment
again it was a plug-in
and you can import it and that's how it
kind of
is useful then so again this could be
stuff for like
the parent wants to be the wrap around
three three like um
elements so you don't want to have to do
the wrapping yourself
in this web component just for the sake
of it so as soon as this compiles it
gets rid of fragment
that doesn't appear in your html or any
divs or any anything there like so
so this is the kind of output of
fragment as well how it actually
monitors
which elements are together within the
fragment is it has a fragment id so
that's how you know so we had three
in the last one over here so this
we had three elements we had input span
and
that represented all those three
elements and then that's
the output so that's how fragments kind
of monitoring uh
how they're connected together usually
what have they noticed is
it would have a div around them and
that's how it knows it together
and it would have an id on that div so
that's a kind of workaround then for it
another change as well is v model
changes
so v model changes is we have a parent
here
called settings that's a component and
then we have a set in cards which is a
child of
settings parent so what i want to show
you is how we would do that
in view two is we would have you can't
maybe can't see it
is we would have one v model to do the
username
and then we would have two props to do
email and
location um there
so then we would input that in and
on this side then we have for the v
model we'd have to have a prop called
value so v model
um has to when you do v model you have
to have a value in your custom
component there so then you would have
to say i actually need more information
that has to be reactive
and two-way binding so you have to
create props and then you have to create
emitters then or events so here
i have to do props and i have to call
one of them value as well
so that's the only thing and then i have
to look after this so again it's a bit
verbose
but then avenue kind of seen that people
wanted actual multiple
v model properties now you can name them
you could say v model.username or
colon username v model email a v model
location
and now they'll come in as actual props
username
email location again and all you have to
do though
is you have to omit a update and the
name of the prop
and again it will look after it and
it'll be reactive again it's nicer code
and it's more maintainable there another
thing they've introduced as well is
custom modifiers so in view two you have
custom modifiers like trim
for your input so you want to make sure
it takes out the space
or you might have lazy or um
or a number so they kind of like modify
the information when it's emitted up
straight away so now that you couldn't
do it in view two but now you can do
your own
uh modifier so you can kind of go dot
reverse
and that's all that is a prop and you
say if top reverse is true
then when i admit the information i'll
actually reverse the information
beforehand
again it's just a boolean for you so
that's the kind of information
another thing as well i haven't really
used it myself is there's a new custom
directive api
that's how you do directives in view two
now it's kind of following the way the
lifecycle of an actual component in view
three and view two so again you have in
your component and a normal one
is before mounted before update that's
that life cycle
in view three but it was a bit confusing
here so i think evan you had thought
why don't we make component directed the
same kind of life cycles they're the
same names and people understand it from
a web component
i haven't used it yet but it's something
like i think this makes it easier for
people to
understand that
one other thing as well that's changed
and it might i haven't kind of tried it
out yet because i don't have the
compiler to kind of change
dot view files to outputs is
view reactivity so how view reactive
works
in view two is you have
a data or you have a thing called touch
like a
reactive element called or property
called touch
when you create that it uses a thing
called object.define
property to get a setter and get her on
it and in the setter
it would kind of weave in its own code
to say when this is set
notify people that are interested in
when this changes
and this is the watcher the watchers
kind of always kind of gets notified
that's that watcher section
once it's kind of the setter is like you
change that
value of the touch property to something
else the watcher will be
run and the watcher will say if you're
watching this
then re-render so we'll call the render
function again and that's how it kind of
re-renders the stuff
so how it's changed in view three and
you shouldn't see it really
um is it's using the es6 proxy before it
was used in define
define properties so again one thing you
should see and i can't deny it
uh our claim is true is you see
and performance improvement that's what
they're saying i can't deny a
thing so that's one thing you might just
by upgrading to view three see a
performance improvement then
so other things just if you want to see
the code base it's there i'm running
that time
view amsterdam is in three weeks if you
want to go to it official view
podcast by view mastery there if you
want to keep up to date that's how i
keep it
and that's all the questions i have
there okay