so hello everyone my name is Alex I'm
from professional services at on the
office and today I would like to share
with you our experience in building
connectors connectors that allow to edit
and collaborate on the documents within
any content management applications so
first briefly I will try to explain you
what is on the office and what we do on
the office is a powerful solution for
editing your documents your spreadsheets
and your presentations office open XML
has been chosen as a co-op format to
ensure compatibility with almost 90% of
all existing documents in the world and
to avoid any issues by converting the
files only office can be deployed on any
any platform so we have a single engine
for web for desktop and fare for mobile
applications so and that guarantees
seamless switch from offline to online
and vice versa
we selected JavaScript as one of the
most universal languages so we use note
8's on the server-side and what's very
important on the office is already
integrated in more than 20 well-known
platforms and in more than 100 web
services worldwide on the office is
available as different packages so as
dr. container snap Universal server
cloud on Amazon limits and many others
and of course our source code is
available on github
now why only office our first task is to
create
very very powerful engine for processing
the documents and here you can see the
list of the points which are very
important for our team only office
provides comprehensive tool set
organized in a tabbed interface so here
you are able to use different features
like standard features table of contents
content controls bookmarks and many many
other features and what's very important
javascript allows you to enhance
additional features to the editors using
our API and our plugins only office
plugins are applications that allow to
add some functionality to only office
editors we divide all plugins in the
visual that just add some buttons maybe
some menus to the interface then non
visual plugins that open some dialogue
some context menu
we do have system plugins that just
works in the background we have non
system plugins that can be started by
clicking on a button and of course we
have all le objects that allow you to
insert some information into the
document itself we already have few
plugins and our users are using these
plugins to translate texts to use
services like citation generations to
use web chats like telegram in the
document editors interface to use
reference services like Mandalay and
Zotero and many many other features are
supported when you use our API so right
now different developers worldwide are
experimenting with our API using
plugins only office editors are based on
html5 canvas and that has had lots of
advantages so html5 canvas uses its own
internal tools for rendering the
document so every single element can be
rendered down to the last pixel and that
allows to use only office in any browser
on any device it's very important and
what's also very important and that's
one of our key points our client-side
performance talking about client-side
performance we talked about advanced
sharing permissions there are few
standard sharing permissions like view
or edit but we also do support
additional like commenting like filling
forms like track changes like modifying
filter and of course of course
restricting downloading and printing is
also available but you may say ok we
were able to use that feature in any any
web editor but when we talk about
advanced permissions we also talk about
core editing so for example here you can
see a document and three different
persons these three persons are working
on the same document the first is
editing that table the second one is
using track changes mode and the third
one just adding some commands to the
document but what is the most important
thing
nobody is disturbed here and that's only
possible when we move the processing to
the client side
one more example a simple action like
undo your last move can be a very hard
job if you work in co-editing mode so
only office allows you to use undo
feature without affecting your
co-authors on the office has its own
lists of the actions mapped to every
user in the document so you are able to
use your undo without affecting any any
other users so and now about security
that's crucial question for everyone who
works on the documents online what we
did on the server side we use JSON web
token so we are able to sign or requests
between storage storage document server
and your client we also have additional
features for configuring the cache of
the server and we also guarantee that no
user data is stored on the server we
also do support additional security
features like watermarking like secure
phone feeling that's when for example
you have access to some area in the
document and nobody else has the taxes
so we also have end-to-end decryption in
our desktop editors when working with
our only office portals now a little bit
about performance if you need let's say
1,000 simultaneous connections
you only need a single server with 8
cores and 32 gigs of memory just because
you need your server only when opening a
document and when closing it that's all
between these two points you don't need
your server anymore and more if you need
more power so you are able to run only
office cluster with all dependencies in
a
tributed manor we have our open API that
allows you to add some additional
features or to integrate our editors
into almost any document management
system for example the first one
document builder document builder is a
core of document editors you are able to
create documents using javascript you
are able to convert your documents to
any other formats so it's a PDF so you
are able to create your documents from
your database using some templates and
my favorite portion you are able to add
different features to only office
editors basing on your use cases on your
experience for example if you need to
mention some user in your document
editor so you are able to do the
following document editors will connect
to your database will request the list
with all users in your database so then
you are able to select every single user
then our our editors will inform your
system and you will notify user that he
was mentioned so that's all you need to
do next one content controls that's one
of the most important plugins I think 3
out of 10 developers use that plugin I
will try to to make a small example how
it works so let's say you work on a
document the document is stored
somewhere in your cloud maybe on your
server in your storage but the document
has an area that area called content
control takes the data from another
storage from your private database or
some other storage and what's the most
important thing you met you may not even
have access to remove or to edit that
interns control and even more you're
able to share the document with anyone
who won't be able to see the content of
that area so that's one of the most
simplest features once again there are
lots of features available when using
our API version history just left panel
with all actions all actions and here we
don't talk about track changes now just
usual editing you just need to save some
metadata to your storage when you save a
new document then when opening the
document you take that metadata file and
open it that's all you need to do to
display that version history panel one
more thing using drag-and-drop you are
able to work with different iframes
within a single HTML page and you are
able to use drag-and-drop to move some
information from you for example chat to
the document editors interface for
example when you work with Firefox
that's okay but chrome doesn't allow to
move such information so what we did we
just created a small plugin called
external listener that allows you to
catch the information direct from your
chat so our online editors have
beautiful API that allow you to
integrate into almost any any document
management systems we already created
few connectors for next cloud on cloud
sharepoint alfresco and confluence new
connectors for harm hub Liferay just
created but the most important thing
there are lots of developers who created
their own connectors guys from xwiki see
file video exit platform they created
their own connectors for on the office
desktop edit
now briefly explain how it looks like
using connector with next cloud you need
to create some kind of global settings
and user settings when creating a
connector to only office so you may
create server settings using
configuration of your server but we did
admin menu for next cloud and here you
just see few fields
the first one is document editing
service address just address of the only
office document server one thing that
server should be accessible from next
cloud storage and from your client and
of course next cloud storage is also
available for document server for
downloading the files then secret key
very impossible very important field you
are able to sign all requests as I said
so using that secret key then if you are
going to use only office and next cloud
on a single server so you need to use
advanced server settings only if you use
next cloud and on the office on a single
server
what about user settings we have few
additional options you can configure so
some user parameters like restricting
access to editors to certain groups in
next cloud then you can setup default
files default formats that will be
opened with only office editors you also
are able to customize your interface for
example to compact toolbar and you also
are able here to enable watermarking if
that's necessary of course you need to
create some context menus so we did it
for next cloud here you can see two
additional buttons were created for next
cloud we already
did some features for next Cloudant we
have plans to add additional features
for example we already created very
interesting integration point
integration with right menu of next
cloud here you are able to use next
cloud sharing dialogues maybe to
integrate our editors with next cloud
applications like video chat or maybe
for next cloud talk something else so
and we have many many other plans how to
add different additional features to
integration we have our roadmap and in
that roadmap there are the tasks like
creating new industry-specific
connectors but as well we are trying to
add additional features like using Volpe
protocol like locking the file while
editing that's very important when using
next cloud integration so that's that's
one of the of the many many features
that we are going to do so and of course
if you have any questions if you would
like to contribute if you would like to
send some pull requests some issues
you're welcome thanks a lot for your
attention
[Applause]
the question was how many developers we
have so right now we have about 20 maybe
25 guys who are working on the editors
the question was if ODF formats are
supported yes of course of course we do
support office open XML as well as all
their formats so all the T files are
supported we we do support almost all
document formats that we have so the
question is when we work with our
editors we need to convert these files
to office open XML standard then edit it
and then if necessary to save it back
converting to ODT for example so the
question was when we are going to
release a new version with pivot tables
yeah we are going to release it very
soon yeah just I guess a question of few
weeks we have few fewer release
candidates with that feature and our
quality assurance team is working on it
yes you're absolutely right right now we
do support viewing yeah but we do not
support editing as I said just question
of few weeks we are going to release it
question on support in this so I saw
that you when you are in a spreadsheet
you can take a chart you can copy it and
you can put it in now the question was
when we are going to support external
links for elements like charts and like
tables yeah for all the objects so
that's very good question we are working
on the question right now right now we
plan to find some workaround and that's
that's really hard to realize cause yeah
cause we do support our own olá objects
yeah but we plan to do that we know that
that's very interesting and that's very
required feature yeah
the question was how we deal with user
interface changes when working with
different modes like mobile web and
desktop as I said we have a single
engine and we have talking about desktop
editors we have chromium so framework
that allows us to work with desktop as
if you work with web browser so almost
the same for mobile versions so but here
we need to adopt of course mobile
versions for compact displaying the
menus but we don't see any any critical
troubles here so we do it you may try
any more questions thank you
[Applause]