openly always the main thing i'm working
on stack was just
the side project basically that i
started working on because i needed it
for open yo
so in openyao is an funded project by
the european commission at the moment
and the idea behind it is to get an
interoperable geoprocessing
api for the cloud for cloud services
so why do we do that basically at the
moment if you want to geoprocess data
it's often the case that you have either
r python javascript or whatever language
you're using
and then you need to connect to any of
these cloud services they have
all their own apis and specifications
for
how to process data whether it's for
example a data cube or tile based
um whether it's could be like downloaded
as duotif or as
whatever they have all the different
things for billing
and how to store data and stuff like
that
so basically for each of these things
you need a different
a different client you need to learn how
to process the data you need
like basically if you start working with
one of these services you're logged in
because you have learned that and of
course you want to proceed to work with
that
because you learned it and it's always
like a tough time to get
used to something different so what is
what do you think is better is to get
something like this you have
one client our python javascript in our
case what we support at the moment
and then you have a streamlined api in
between
um which then translates the things to
a single um yeah
to a single api basically where you have
a single uh part how you process
like whether for us it's a data cube how
you build things how you download things
and so on and so on so it's basically
like
most of you probably know gdal that's
the thing that translates things between
the
gis programs and the data formats and
that's basically
some kind of gdal for the cloud um i
guess so
um that helps you to make reproducible
uh
research as you can basically
take your application that you wrote or
your algorithm
from one provider to the other so if you
run
things on google earth engine first and
want to know whether that's really true
what they
computed for you then you can take the
code that you wrote in r and just
change the url and some other minor
things for pre-processing
and transform it to code that is running
on for example veto
on the proper vmep or any of the other
cloud processing providers that you are
aware of
in that case it's portable to some
extent and that's
how we think it should be in the future
that you just have a very simple access
to data
in the end and don't need to write
proprietary
workflows in for other cloud providers
so as i said it's a language for
geospatial processing
we have on the one side the api which is
basically the translation
layer between the clients and the server
and
a set of predefined processes which is
basically
trying to make interoperable processes
so that
for example if you compute things on
python in x array and in
r with stars on another package then
processes may slightly differ in regard
how they compute things
and we try to do this like define it on
on a higher level so that you can use
all the same processes for
processing for all the different kinds
of computation software that is in the
background
this is in contrast to stack is focused
on processing and
that was focused on search and discovery
it's open source so all software we
develop here is open source and the
specification as well
we are focusing on data cube so that's a
bit
changed maybe from the traditional gis
workflow where you downloaded
individual tiles and process based on
them and here it's all basically
wrapped into a data cube which you can
process on um
and we support udfs which is a very
um interesting thing because then it
allows you to send your
r or python code that is not like the
processes we have at the moment are very
like
narrow in the sense that for example
that you have don't can use
custom pro libraries for example that
compute some very advanced algorithm
that we don't support at the moment
and in that sense if you need any
specific libraries for example be
fast for some computations then you can
actually run it as udf where you can
basically just
write a script code in python or r and
send it to the server and then it's
executed in the cloud for you
so what is not well it's not another
cloud provider we just specify the api
and
translation layer it's not another
geoprocessing software so we're not
writing the new arcgis or something like
that it's really just the translation
and it's
not very much as the previous
traditional gis workflow so that you
download the data then you have tiles
and
you need to process them and so on it's
all cloud-based so your algorithm is
going to the
data which is stored in large amounts in
the cloud
and then you get the result back and not
the other way around
of course in this part again i can show
this again here
which is basically of course defining a
new standard
and in that sense we could run into the
issue that there are
afterwards 15 competing standards but i
hope it's not
um so the api the translation layer in
between
offers the following functionalities um
of course first it
uh needs to give you the basic
information so it's
uh giving access to discovery things
like for example how the api works what
it supports
the eo data that you can use in this
workflows
that is exposed via stack stack
collections
and stack api and then the processors
which is basically a
yeah just a list of processes that is
supported by the back end
then it supports of course
authentication with open id connect
then you have workflow management for
where you can basically store
your uh own user defined processes so if
you for example
want to make a new algorithm based on
the
predefined processes we have you can
store them as user defined processes
again
and use them as were as as they were
predefined before as
from the back end so it's really
integrated into things and you can pass
around your
algorithms and run them on other
backends or you can pass them to other
users to be reused
then then there's file management where
you can basically upload assets if
there's a geojson file that you need to
pass or something like that or whether
there is uh things that you want to
download all is
handled by a central file management api
of course then there is a processing
service you can either process
synchronous so then you basically send
the things to the server and immediately
or
in a matter of seconds hopefully get a
response back with the result that of
course only works for limited like
extends and data um and for
bigger things you can use batch jobs
where you can basically
uh also send the data to the server and
then wait for whatever time it needs to
process
things and then get back the results to
download it
again as stack catalog with the
appropriate files in it
and the third thing is the web services
so you can basically um
also there is an api to basically host
wms through open eo or wcs or other
services that you want to expose
so we don't redefine things for viewing
and stuff like that but
rely on the standards that are already
there and defined problem mostly from
odc but you can also like expose
non-standardized things like xyz tiles
that are used by openstreetmap for
example
yeah processes are already mentioned
there is a set of predefined processes
like at the moment i think 130 or
something like that
for band mass for loading data into data
cubes
working on data cubes remaining renaming
dimensions adding new values and stuff
like that
you can visit processes.opengo.org to
see the list
and then of course based on the
predefined processes you can
define your own user defined processes
which is internally
just a graph that is basically a
dependency graph with instructions how
to work
on the data and then there is udfs again
which is basically the thing i
talked about before where you can write
your r and python scripts and send it to
the server as part of the other
processes so basically you can
say i use a predefined process and then
load data with it and then
this data gets passed to the udf process
and then you can
further compute it with other processes
we have predefined to say for example
the data
and then you're ready to go and download
we have several clients implemented at
the moment we're tackling javascript
python and r at the moment
which should tackle most of the
geospatial community i guess maybe
there's yulia in the future again as
well but
we'll see we have a browser-based
application as well for
users that are not so much into
programming so that pretty much works
like a
model builder in arcgis or qgis
then we have a qgis implementation where
you can
use it as a plugin and basically start
jobs from
qe gis and download it and show it in
qgis directly
and there is a mobile app that can you
can use as well
this is a screenshot for example from
the web editor
you see these workflows over there at
the top in the middle
then the management stuff is here in the
in the bottom
you see a list of processes collections
you can use you can drag and drop them
into the model builder
and then on the right there is a map
that you can basically use to
view the data i think there is some no2
visualization at the moment on the map
this is how for example an evi
computation would look like
on that is r yes that is r
um it it's pretty easy you just connect
to
the web servers with the url and of
course username password then will be
prompted
then you basically create a data cube
you can load data
in this example it's central to again
you can specify the spatial extent
template extends and bands to be loaded
then that will be loaded into a data
cube then for example in this case we
will reduce the dimension bands
and do some band mouth on the bands in
this case the evi computation
and then reduce the temporal dimension
to b to just give you the minimum
composite
and save the result as geotiff and
then the same you can do with python in
this case
it's looking very similar you can use
the
the functions as if in python like
the the operators here are overloaded
just to be used
um and then they are translated into our
internal representation and sent to the
server
yeah we have several server
implementations already that are
you can reuse um or extend if you want
um there's geopyspark into your trellis
implementation
um there is a google earth
implementation so you can basically run
our scripts already on google earth
engine as well
for free there's a grass gis actinia
implementation you can
go to microstock and at 2pm
to get more about that there's a jrc
earth observation data and processing
platform from the european commission
there is an open stack implementation
there is access to sentinel hub as well
and there is a server implementation for
wcps
which is in the end rasterman
there is a bit of ecosystem we also
developed as for example open the oh hub
which you can go to and
then you get basically a list of
overview which um servers are there
where you can process on you can
basically for example also just pass
your
algorithm that you implemented and then
it tells you and which server you can
run it
gives you information about which data
is available and what it costs and stuff
like that
you can also share there your own
defined processes your udfs and
stuff like that and then there is a
validator of course to check whether the
api implementations are valid it checks
both the
actual just the structure of the api
whether the responses are valid
and then also it checks whether the
results that are processed are valid um
so there is a also a way to check
whether in between the
back ends there is differences that are
coming from processing
um then we have of course when you visit
processes.openmuo.org you see a rendered
list of processes
which is basically rendered through
our dock generator for processors and of
course you can also reuse for
at least for the data discovery part you
can use the stack and ogc api features
ecosystem because the api is completely
um
yeah compliant to that standard and and
that's such
you can use that ecosystem and if you
expose the wms of course you can just
use the wms
clients that you are aware of
the state of openo at the moment is that
all these partners are working on that
and maybe also you in the future
we are currently have released version
1.0 release candidate once so we are
pretty much going into stable mode now
after experimenting a long while
for two years um with what works best
and what doesn't
and um the project ends in the
third quarter of the year so then we can
expect a stable version where you can
really rely on
yeah and that's it for my two talks now
i need some water and
then thank you for listening and i take
your questions
here's some time for questions anyone
can we stack and open yo yes
yeah so regarding maintaining there are
a couple of companies that are basing
their work and
future work of an open eo so eodc for
example and veto
are all already like pushing things
internally so that
their internal users and external users
are using that so
in that sense they need to continue with
that of course
because they have clients that rely on
that
and there's also further projects that
we want to establish based on openyo so
i hope that will make it future proof
regarding user base we have some use
cases that are running at the moment to
really
check whether all that what we did is
working
that is a broad range of things snow
cover analysis
agriculture and stuff like that but
there could be more of course
the thing is like if you start something
new you start to find
people that are really want to hop on a
thing that is not
stable yet so but we are working on that
and it evolves over time
we also have some metrological things in
the future um
with ecwmf plan so
yeah that's the future hope
questions what about licensing and
actually about
is this infrastructure for that
license on my own
so for open yo everything is licensed
under apache 2 license so
that's all open source and you can reuse
it uh
to whatever extent you want um
so feel free to implement something or
do pull request it's all on github
um so that's good uh what was the other
thing
actually i see that
um
as far as i know for most of these
implementations there are docker
containers which you can run
let's start we're working on making
their that more
easy to adopt at the moment most of the
implementers are still
like setting up their own infrastructure
to get things running of course
so in the future there should be more
things like vagrant scripts and stuff
like
that
anybody else if not
well thank you very much thank you