hello everyone
so i thank you for coming i'm with sorry
about all i'm here to present the id4me
project for
open and federated identities
so as soon as we get back to
presentation but
okay so i mean i think
everyone already knows about the online
identities and how
bad they are today but to recap
basically we actually have
uh each of us has an online identity
which is internet-wide
it's the one that is created by the big
advertising tracking platforms because
they know everything about us and they
cross
all different sources of data about us
so
we do have a single online identity but
we don't own it we actually don't even
know
a lot about it on the other hand when we
have to identify so we want to use
multiple services online we are still
stuck by
with having a thousand different
accounts with different passwords and
different
systems for login and and this is really
inconvenient it's insecure because
people use passwords or
then they cannot use them so they write
them down and so it's really a system
that doesn't work
so of course the solution is well known
the solution is a single sign on which
means that you have
some kind of authentication provider
which is the one that verifies your
credentials and so tells
everybody else all the services you want
to log into that you are you
and they should let you in and of course
this result
requires some kind of trusted
authentication provider
and of course the big internet platforms
the over the tops already thought about
this
so in the last two or three years
there's been this proliferation of
forms like this one they are now
everywhere almost on every website
as you see i mean most websites usually
give you these alternatives so you can
either login with facebook or with
google somehow only have facebook or
google
some have a few more and then there's a
tiny link and which is going to
disappear more and more if
you really want you can log in with your
own personal account with your email but
again that's going to disappear and
what's the problem with this the problem
is that this is proprietary not in terms
of protocols but in terms of the
implementation and of the actual service
so this is very convenient it's now
ubiquitous i mean you just click and
you're in you don't have to enter your
data everybody likes it
especially the average user that doesn't
realize the privacy implication of this
but it's really terrible if you think it
is first of all there is no
interoperability
it's fragmented so i mean you have if
they support
facebook you have to use facebook
facebook if they support google you have
to support google
so this leads to concentration because
of course no one will want to support
1000 systems on their
web page login and so the only the big
ones will survive
if you want to support more systems i
mean your website web web admin you
you have to implement each and every of
them separately again and again
and the users in the end don't have a
choice because you can only choose the
ones that are supported by
most websites and in the end this makes
tracking straightforward so the
platforms that already know everything
about us then they have an even easier
way to track us across
the multiple services we use and on the
other hand you get to situations like
this one which was actually funny this
was the recommended hotel for the
ietf or out working group the security
workshop they had and they recommended
all the handle
you choose between eight different
systems to log into your wi-fi
so this was really crazy so it showed
everyone at the itf also that there's a
problem that needs to be sold
so we need some kind of better way of
doing this
so we need openness because we cannot
allow these companies to own our
identities
and we need federation so that everybody
can run their identity and
or at least we can have thousands of
providers and we can have a choice
so of course single sign-on has a lot of
advantages so these are advantages that
you already get with the current system
so of course you only need one set of
credentials because you log
into a single place uh this place can be
made more and more secure because you
just need to implement for example to
factor authentication in the single
place where you login
and you have a way to control your
information as long as the provider lets
you control the information which google
and facebook unfortunately
basically don't and you don't need to
raise i mean in the end this idea of
registering for a website is going to go
away you just have to show your identity
in the same way you mean when you want
to
rent a car you show your identity
documents that's what's going to happen
in front of websites
and but if we succeeded in making this
public and federated there will be
more and more advantages so why cannot
single sign-on work like email
email is being an old-time service where
before all this
mass commercialization and big intense
platforms came email is still federated
which means that you can get your email
address from
whoever you want including running it
yourself and then
everyone can speak with everyone else
and that's how it works and there's no
reason why identities
should not work like that so you could
get your identity from whoever you want
or even run it yourself and then use it
everywhere
and we would just need one account for
everything and you could choose your
provider or you could even
run it yourself and you could possibly
choose one that is not selling you out
and you could also keep your identifier
which is a known problem so i mean you
have to own your own
username in a way otherwise it will
always depend on the company that
supplied you your username and this
so the technical problem is that to have
a federation you need what is called the
discovery mechanism so what's necessary
is that
someone shows you an identifier the
wrong let's say username
and you i mean the website the service
that needs to verify that you are you
needs to know where to go which server
to contact to
to do that and uh actually the the main
protocol that is used today including by
the propriety single sign-ons
for for online single sign-on is open id
connect i guess
people here are mostly i would say i
could be familiar with that
though i mean it has some federation
capabilities but it's never deployed in
a really federated manner so the
federation in the common deployments of
open id connect is that
the same company has 10 different
services and they all
use a centralized login server for login
identity provider
but it's always everything run by the
single company or at most by a group of
companies
and so we need a real federation so we
need to keep these directory of
identities somewhere so that
websites can look them up so where do we
do that and this is what we try to do i
mean the standard openid connect method
relies on web finger so it's a an https
call to the
to a web server running on your identity
provider which is a problem that you
need to have a website running for that
on each and every domain name or
identifier that you want to use
so it's not very handy and it's actually
i mean well
basically very hard to implement for
example for domain name industry for the
hosting industry for the isps because
you would need me
and so and also it requires you to have
a web big a certificate with
lesson clip you can get one for free but
still needs and
of course why not the blockchain there
are i mean i say thousands of identity
projects based on blockchains and it's
fine we have nothing against the
blockchain but we want something that
can actually compete today with the
biggest it is so it must be something
that is already available today
everywhere
it's tested it can scale to mass service
and so on
and everyone can just pick it up and run
it and so in the end
we're going for the dns and i mean the
dns usually
i mean there are people that love it
there are people who hate it but
it has several advantages because in the
end it is an open public standard
there's three implementations everywhere
you can just download one around your
dns server
it's widely available it's tested it
runs for 30 years on a
global scale it keeps the internet up
and so it's it has some kind of
regulation so even if there is some
centralization there's also some
regulation to prevent capture and so
maybe that's not perfect but it's
already there and it works
and so we chose to use the dns for the
namespace because also i mean to to to
have a global
internet scale online identities you
need a global a unique identifier
and of course our own names are not
unique identifiers there's many people
with
the same name over the world and so you
need a global namespace which is also
distributed and federated and
can be delegated and this is the problem
that was already solved with the dns
35 years ago so you can just use dns
names and people are actually familiar
with them
and they are human readable in the end
they are usually strings with dots in
the middle you could even use email
addresses just convert them into a
domain name with a fixed
hashing algorithm and in the end this
would also allow people to just buy a
domain name for a few euros
and become owners of their own
identifier which is another advantage so
then you could just move your identifier
across different providers if you
don't like your current provider anymore
and and so it's also very easy to
realize that the discoveries came to
make a discoveries came over the dns
since again email basically does that
email has the same problem you have an
email address you need to know which
server is
managing it and so there's the mx record
in the dns that tells you
which server is managing it and we did
the same
we're not going for a new resource
record type because that's
hard to get implemented we're just using
a txt record like many other new
protocols
and we there are actually the internet
drafts already there
they are we are not at the moment going
forward with this standardization
because first we want to get
implementations and prove that it works
and so on but but the
drafts are already there they are public
so basically this is what we did
we just chose that i mean you can use
whatever
valid host name even if it doesn't
correspond to an existing server in a
domain that you control so that you can
create records in it
and you can just create a standard
specially used txt record
and which points them to a stringer
which basically tells you where this is
being run
who is the issuer and the claims
provider for your identity in open ide
connect speak
so and so
well the project in itself is basically
this it's just an attempt
not to become yet another identity
provider or group of companies or
entities that compete to provide
identities against everyone else
but it's meant to provide the basic
building technology to allow
everyone to run providers and
interoperate with each other
so the point is that we want to create
basically a set of open
patent-free standards that are there for
everyone to implement the traditional
way like
email is i mean we are an email company
so this is why we believe in this model
and so in the end we do have also a
foundation here in brussels it's a
non-profit
we decided to have one because you need
the place basically to ask companies and
supporters to put money and then spend
it for the project to pay
for example promotion and people to
develop something maybe and
and other expenses so it's not a
controlling entity anyway the standard
is open everyone can implement it
it's more like a place where we can run
additional
activities over that including some i
mean well i will i will come to that
basically the the architecture of the
roles in united for me is
more or less the same as the traditional
openid connect system
except that we decided to break the
traditional identity provider role in
two
partly because i mean among the original
supporters there are several
companies and people from the domain
name industry which i mean that's not
surprising
since we are using the dns and so we we
have a sort of separation that mimics
the domain name registrar and registry
separation so we have
an identity authority which is basically
the registry for identities
and the only thing that it does it
verifies your credentials so enhance
your
authentication and it doesn't get to
actually know your data so i mean
the data and the relationship with you
are kept by your agent
which is the other entity which
basically gives you the service so that
you could even change agent without
changing the authority or you can change
both or you can run both on the same
service you could even have a service
running both roles at the same time
it's entirely free but at least i mean
for
for the attempt to i mean to get to the
real average users which needs to be
built upon an existing industry to have
chance to actually reach
out for people uh then this is i we
thought this is the best
way of organize it and and so in the end
you you
provide your information and manage it
with the agent and then the authority is
the trust anchor is let's say in the
authentication system
that guarantees that i mean the
authentication is being done correctly
and so the login flow is actually pretty
standard if anyone is familiar with
openid connect
so i mean it's a basically it is a
standard definitely connect
login process except that before
starting the entire process you have to
do this dns query so the reliant party
will have to discover who is running
your identity who is managing it and so
the
they will make this dns query and
getting return to the
record and discover which which server
they have to contact to start up the
normal open id connect login process
which then uses
a feature open a d connect which is
called distributed claims so that
the the initial identity provider which
is the authority then redirects
the relying party to the agent with a
signed token so that they can actually
get your personal information
but the the nice thing in this process
that the authority for example can ask
you
actually which data you want to share so
i mean you
you have a set of information but for
the moment it's a basic one but in
theory you could
standardize names and claims for any
kind of information that you would like
to share with websites from your
frequent flyer number to whatever
and then when you log in uh with the
first time you log into a website that
the authority asks you i mean this is
the information they would like to have
about you
and do you agree so do you give consent
and you can choose
for each information field whether you
agree with sharing it or not
and then this is signed and gets to send
to the agent then so that the agent
knows which
data they they actually can share with
with the relying party
and so in this way we are trying to put
back control over data sharing in the
hands of of the user
so that in the end it's the user that
chooses which information gets passed on
to the website
and so on so
as i said that the status is like the
process the project is about a couple of
years old
it was initially promoted by a few
german companies now it's becoming
international there are more
entities signing in profit for profit
and nonprofit
so there's a website there's
specification and there's an api
there are several prototypes test beds
there's actually an id for me based at
the service
which is the unique id dining is the
manager for the
top level domain in germany so they are
the first company that really tries to
release a public service based on this
and this technology and they're
basically about to launch it
and uh we are working on the possibility
of adding a verification layer on top of
this so you can still i mean this the
data in that is what you put in in it so
it's not verified you can use it also
anonymously pseudonymously
you decide you can have many identities
whatever you want but for
certain use cases you might want to have
a third party
validate that you are you and in that
case we are building the extensions to
the standard that would allow
basically a third party to sign an
attestation and so on
and so provide verified identities and
we have now about
30 members in the international
nonprofit here in brussels
so what's coming next if anyone here
will attend the cloudfest
in germany there's going to be a
hackathon project
to develop a completely free server
implementation
we already have a part of it so we want
to finish it and release it
so that it's available to everyone we
already have several authentication
plugins for several languages they are
also free and so on
and so we are as i said we are working
on the verified identities
part so that you can have a stronger
identity and we are discussing the
reputation issue and i want to stress
this because this is a problem that
comes up in any
federated approach and it should not be
underestimated because it is a difficult
project because
in the end if you are google you can say
okay in google i decide which degree of
uh
validity i want to give them the
information i pass to websites and i
people have to trust me in a federated
system like exactly it happens for email
with spam and so on
there could be people that run services
in a bad way
and so you need to have some way to
exchange the reputation information and
be sure that
if someone is telling that this person
is authenticated and designed from
their data they are not just making
everything up at least for certain use
cases so this is the discussion we are
having around
how to manage the reputation of the
operators so this is the website
uh you can go there and there's
everything about the project there's
also the technical part with
documentation links to a github space
and whatever
and that's it so basically thank you and
i'm happy to take questions
yeah hi i have a question so when i'm a
website
and i integrate the login with google
button
for the sso for my users basically the
reason i do that is because i trust
google that
it's doing the authentication correctly
for the user
but if i for example use id for me
i don't know who i'm asking and in
augmented connect i usually
need a client with the identity provider
right so how does that work because they
need to establish some kind of trust
yeah with the
identity provider yeah as i was saying
that this is like the key problem we
we are discussing exactly because i mean
we decided to make
for example the client registration open
and dynamics so you don't need to
ask the identity provider for a key to
start being a reliant party because that
would make
the federation unworkable uh but yeah i
mean
in the end it depends on the airline
party because if you're just uh
i mean a basic website a forum for
obvious or whatever
you don't need any any real certainty
about the data i mean you
people are actually that's a case in
which people should be encouraged to
log in anonymously if they want on the
other hand for some services you might
really want to be sure about their
entire process and in that case possibly
you are the relying party want to put
some barrier
on the on the identity provider that is
being used so i mean
since you cannot know i mean you could
in theory say i will only accept
identities from
these one two three identity providers
but again this is
doesn't scale so what we are thinking is
that we could have some kind of
certification
so that you can get some cryptographic
station that does i mean this provider
has been verified up to this level of
verification
so you can more or less trust that they
are who they are and this other is
completely unknown so it
accept it as your own risk but on the
other hand we don't want to make this
too hard because otherwise you will
rule out the self-hosting of identities
which i think is a pretty important case
i have a question uh the open id connect
uh
process of they have they have a
certification process
uh did you take your services through
that process or did you talk to the
people about certifying your
services yeah i mean you mean the
certification of the implementation yeah
i mean the
uh as i said denis who is the first
company that is launching services
is an open indian foundation member and
they have applied so their
server implementation is being certified
by the openid foundation
and also we have been submitting some of
this this development
for standardization basically in some of
the extensions i mean there are a couple
of extensions that just came out to open
eddie connect in terms of federation and
and they were actually influenced by
some of us participating in the working
groups and
bringing ideas and of course we want to
be aligned so in the end
if of course this is still catching up
so there are no websites are almost
today except maybe for denik and a few
of you
that accepted these identities so this
is the the challenge
if this gains adoption everything i mean
we're going to apply for standardization
of all the parts of the protocol both
are the open id foundation and
the itf my question is
have you thought about integrating with
the decentralized identity
standard that is going to be developed
okay you know another side i mean
we have thought about getting the id
schema for example for id for me so i
mean
i mean some kind of if that's what
you're referring to
there's already the id message for web
so you can write some kind of in dns
it looks kind of similar it's just how
to resolve
so yeah as i said we i mean we haven't
done it yet but we
we have not i mean we could do it we
actually have thought on it
so i mean
um is there any place here at fosdem
where i can find people for an open
exchange to chat with them or you
yeah with me it doesn't sever here
so yeah just grab us later either on
this or any other thing that operator
change is doing so
um have you thought about a use case
where you're not trying to identify a
web application but any other thing that
doesn't have a browser
available sorry i speak loudly because
have you tried about identifying uh
providing the ability to uh identify
outside of the browser
uh yeah i mean yeah we were trying to
for example see whether
this could be used for imap logging for
example all these kind of things
there's not been the focus yet because
of course there's a problem with the
interactivity because openid connect
is an interactive process for them but i
think you could get your token and store
it around when you could find ways
but we have not worked on this yet it's
it's on the list of two things
but if you want to help you're welcome
um have you looked at engaging with web
standards bodies or
web browsers to help standardize this so
you could just have a
new html component to have a federated
login for example
yeah i mean we do not have browsers at
the spot at this point in time
also this is a very european project
originally german now european
there are no basically european browser
makers so we we
yeah okay so so if you're interested
please join
and uh yeah i think that some degree of
support in the browsers would help a lot
uh i we i had a quick chat with mozilla
like
over a year ago the problem is that they
tried persona if you remember it and
then it didn't really work so they are
sort of
wary of these kind of things but this is
how i understood
i was wondering if you can talk a bit
more about the the status of the project
because if i
understand correctly most of the the
components basically are just uh
thin layers in front of id connector
providers
and other data storage so it's just a
matter of writing this uh small
yeah exactly this this was a design
feature so when we decided not to design
everything from scratch
but to try to design something which had
an implementation path which is as
short as possible so yeah for the
relying path it's actually just this dns
call in front of a standalone penalty
connect implementation
then if you want to support some of
these more advanced features
maybe you want to customize at the time
but but basically yeah and also
denix is running the implementation for
the server side and
by using an open id connect server and
just developing a few things on top of
it so yeah
okay okay thank you very much and i'm
here around if you still have questions
of course
please give him a warm round of applause