so
um hello everybody
thanks to join so early
to listen to me that's yeah surprise
first of all who am i my name is luca
pizzamillo i'm an italian guy
working at trivago i'm a freebie is the
enthusiast
i use previously at least for 10 years
now
and i received my port commit bit in
august 2017.
uh what i'm doing usually is trying to
look for new uh use cases for freebsd
i really believe privacy is a very solid
platform and can
run basically everything
specifically in trivago i build packages
customized stuff and so on
a note it's early sunday
i had the ability to provide gadgets yet
socks
so every time you have a question you
receive a socks
so the first time first 10 questions uh
so don't be afraid please speak out
make this presentation more interactive
help me
it's really it's only for me also
so this is for today uh we'll talk a bit
about
jsonport what part is uh something i
presented two years ago
here what is a
service mesh or what i believe the
service mesh is
what is a pot image feature work and
then
your question
the port framework is something i
started uh
more than two years ago actually the
ambitious goal was to
basically was yeah there was there is no
docker we know
on previously at least not natively and
but actually is a really nice pattern
or at least something that is quite easy
to use
but obviously there was actually no
container model
in general so say why don't you try to
do something similar using all the
technologies that
are already available like zfs uh jlpf
finnette ctl cpu set and so on
so i came up with this framework as a
set of
basically a tool that allows you to
manage jails
data sets i would say
pretty easily now at that time was quite
rough
but yeah that was the logo that time so
part comes from
apart that is not the other meaning of
part
someone else suggested
and that was basically the state at the
time
um
and how that fit in here who doesn't
know what
service mesh is or use
wow so you have to i have to explain the
best of my capabilities what a service
mesh is
a server mess in general is an
abstraction um
where a developer you
can submit basically a job or
that would see what what the job is to
this
very big black box cloudy thing
and then the user can just use
the service that is exposed by by this
job
i will go a little bit in detail this is
not like i mean it's similar to
kubernetes but it's
not kubernetes so basically
the developer has a job description
where it specifies
which container to use
and which parts should be exposed
which type of services is that and so on
here we have
a central point in this case the
orchestrator
it received this job description and
they say okay you want these containers
up and running it looks for the in the
worker cluster so we'll basically
transfer the allocate or orchestrate
basically the
execution of these containers to the
workers the workers will download
the container images there will be spawn
basically those new containers
the servers will be up and running and
that is one side of the story
then it is a natural service you have a
service discovery
something a server basically we use
console here
and what the orchestrator does will
register your service here
and say okay now i decided that your
server is running on this machine
exposing
the port i mean it's running on parts
one two three four five whatever
so these information are registered now
here so
um this so the discovery uh the service
discovery will know okay there is this
service with this name that is running
there
and what is also doing is continuously
checking
if the service is up and running so the
health status of this
of this service and this is the
so-called control plane
so now theoretically if you want to
reach the service i mean the
orchestrators decide where the server is
running so you don't know exactly where
it is
so you have to basically interrogate the
the server discovery
uh and this is called i guess the
control path so basically you can so you
can know basically where your services
are running
and you have another element it's called
is a proxy or a layer 7
balancer
this load balancer or this proxy
you can configure it basically to say
okay or when there is a user they want
something uh look for
where this service is running so
basically the the list of the backend
is continually updated uh to know where
all the services are running so oh you
want this service boom i will route
basically all the traffic to the proper
node but they get information here
and every time there is a new service
that is
[Music]
if the same service is replaced so the
old container got destroyed and your new
container is running for instance here
the information is updated in the
service discovery and so
the the proxy can get updated
information and will route the traffic
in a different
direction i hope
i explained myself i'm not really a
super master of this
all elements any question
cool he gets
so to repeat the question uh this
doesn't seem
uh freebies did things to me yet that
of course that is what's the problem
actually those are programs that runs
everywhere they are mainly i guess all
of those are
go programs um
yeah that's actually the point uh how
can we have something
like this on previously and that is the
solution that i'm presenting now
as you see the the real issue is this
container images there is normally
no such solution that has used these
names
[Music]
and exactly that was what is really
needed
uh the features that was really missing
was the ability to deal with
images so creating and downloading
images so you need to create
and export an image you need uh
image registry i mean imitating docker
okay you have to create a docker
container
you need docker hub and then the ability
to download and
then import an image that was the set of
features that
we worked on
but more importantly what is really
different
is the is the paradigm how
you work with those kind of i mean the
workflow is really different
we are used to create js on directly on
the machine and then you'll configure
them and you let them running
and the developer will just you know
just give you
the php code or the java code whatever
is running there
but you are directly managing
js on your final machine uh
so the program here is different someone
is working on the
image creation so in the ejl image
and someone else is deploying it so
the pattern is very very different and
also how uh the set of tool that you
need is different
and it was is an almost unexplored area
i'd say and sorry
i will discuss before the deployment of
the j on the available nodes so
to make that visible and then we'll
discuss about the
how to create an image and all those
things
[Music]
there is already a lot of complexity all
around
i mean a lot of new names new components
things are going there and there
so the first implementation of pot as
basically
a jail was composed by multiple data set
there was the base that was mounted in
read-only and shared with other data
jades and so on uh for this kind of
scenario when you have those moving
parts was too complicated
so i decided okay just go to um one
single
big data fast data set where i put
everything there so it's easier than to
create images uh
how an exporter pass basically
you create a pot basically a jail you
customize it you put
the software that you want you take the
snapshot
and then we just if you send and
compress tool
boom you create an image so basically
what you want inside your
your jail and then you have a file a
file is easy to
move uh to import a part well
uh is the other way around your
uh the question is only the face is used
yes the first is mandatory
[Music]
i don't support other thing if you
uh if you want to use a different
uh please support a patch
that means winter patch and we're happy
to to extend support but
i mean that the whole pod framework is
heavily based on zfs because
uh i have all the nice feature uh
snapshots uh
wrote back and you know everything's
there
i said to import uh a part when you
download the file then you can just
uh end up
uncompressed zfs receive boom you have
the same
basically content somewhere else and
then you can clone the snapshots
[Music]
i use the clone here because if you have
one image
then it's if you this this image is
reduced
imagine an nginx server and you have the
same engineering with different
configuration
it's easier than to clone it and just
change the configuration file then to
antar again and use the first receive so
that's basically
is a slight uh short optimization
question so far other questions
no because it means completely the point
uh
i mean jails is very very
uh light the hive is not that
that light i mean behind makes sense
when you have different operating system
uh that you want to run on previously
host if you have the same operating
system
use jail i mean i want to pro um and
focus on
uh native support it has to be native
it's really faster if you have beehive
you don't have the same
performance because full virtualization
with jail you have a light visualization
so it's just the operating system
right so
i'm waiting for your patch
on that topic um
so why we choose nomad
to try to implement this service mesh uh
dinosaur normally the console are
say fabulously friendly in the sense
that they are already in the package
system so you can just
install nomad and console and run them
up and running
um so console is the service discovery
and nomad is the orchestrator basically
moreover nomad has an internal structure
that allows to add
additional driver and driver is
something
that is basically supporting a different
type of containers so there is a driver
for docker container a driver for
they call it uh this java thing means
that basically
you have a jar turbo and then is
executing the jvm
right away so different types
of containers and what happened here
is why can we not write an additional
driver to let nomad interact with pot
so stephen that i see here
present scholar of mine just developed
the driver i mean try to
create this bridge between nomad and the
pod framework to
interact with js
so the driver is already available you
can install it on your own so it's
i was a mature product but stable enough
and this is the job description
uh i will go through that a little bit
uh this isn't a very
easy example even if it's very long
you have on top the name of the job the
job
is it's a service then you have the
concept of group
because a service can be composed by
different containers so you want to join
them to provide
a service in this case the group is
called example group auto fantasy
and is composed by only one task that is
only engine expo
and here you specify the driver saying
the driver is part
then nomad will look for a worker that
support
part and will able to execute a jail in
that way
i will just jump here this is the the
part that was
strictly part of the driver so basically
you say in the configuration
where to download your image
you say the name of the image the
version
the command is basically is optional but
it's the
the entry point of your jail what is the
first command that's to be executed when
the jail is spawned um
then we have here that's the service
part so that is
all the information that you give to
tonoma to spawn the jail
and this part the service is what to
register
to console
[Music]
the name of the server will be web
example for instance
and then you see this port http for http
here
is mean that the part 80 in the
container
will be mapped with a different part
outside there is an automatical pf
redirection rule that is injected to the
node
and this new information will be
registered in the service so we will see
in console that will
a different port locally the the j
we have an nginx running on port 80 but
then you have a pf rule that make the
redirection
and any console you will discover
basically where uh
this thing is running question so far
yeah so this is
like the pod registry
yeah the pot registry uh there is a
slide later i mean the question was
about
what is this spot registry is a web
server with files
[Music]
there is one slide exactly on that topic
it's complicated
it's all the second part of the uh
what's about that
um it seems easy but it's not easy i
mean
if you think why i'm not using io cage
or
other jail frameworks that are out there
first of all because i can do my own
it's open so you can do whatever you
want now this series it was
it doesn't work there are features i
mean
a container has something different from
a different
normal jail for instance
this comment in
with nginx nginx is not
fork working in background what it means
means that if you use that type of
command with jail
with the jail command line the jail
command line won't return because
the first command is basically executed
by the j
command and it's just keeping your um
still your your shell it's not returning
in jail has this standard assumption
that the command the the exact start of
the command that you gave basically at a
certain point with fork and will return
in this case it's not the case i mean
usually containers are working with
blocking commands so basically they keep
them
engineering spawning and they're serving
directly with traffic period it's not
forking and that it creates a series of
issues um in this case for instance the
potstar
post start hooks are not executed at all
because what the jail common is doing
is just working like create the
container spawn the comments whether
it's over and then executing everything
that is after the post start
the post start is never reached because
the comment is keeping basically is not
returning
and a nice thing that is nice yeah it
took me some time to discover is
um usually those containers are
ephemeral means that if the
process inside the container disappear
the container disappeared itself
uh js are by default persistent so if
there is no processes there the j will
stay and io ch for instance only support
persistent
js
the no persistent parameter is also
applied
by jail start as a poster hook
and it didn't work basically i have to
find some weird way to be able to have
this
no persistent flag applied even when a
comma that doesn't return
last but not least this is not clean up
themselves
you know that there is the post stop
hooks or the pre-stop hooks and so on
if you have a not persistent jail you
mount your
devices you create your rpf rules then
the jail disappear
come on you have to clean up but you
don't have any notification
that the jail disappear or you don't
have any way to register a callback
what you do usually when you call j
minus r that is the j stop
uh is the command that is executing
those hooks so
say okay that comes i have to stop this
j
so i run the hooks i stop the jail and
then i run the other hooks
uh but if he's not persistent the j will
just vanish
and there is no centralized demon
basically that is controlling that what
happened with the js they are just
when is an internal physicist um
operating system structure that just
is like when a process is going away you
don't get any notification
per se we solve this basically
inside nomad if nobody has to control
that the containers are up and running
if it's not running
it's just calling a pot stop and they
clean up basically
uh almost everything
in that way but we don't have
generically a way
to to clean up not persistent j
question so far
it's clear i'm too fast
can you repeat the question can you run
something
um
[Music]
you have to avo the question was if you
can run something that doesn't demonize
you have to change your command line to
avoid that is demonizing
for example you're running
oh no so yeah yes you can run
so the best practice in this world is to
have one process per container
so for instance we have a radius
instance and the exporter that is just
basically
another program is running in a
different container
because if one container dies you just
replace this and you don't replace the
whole service basically there
is a common best practice in this way
technically you can
is suggested not to do it but yeah you
can put more
you can create your own creator and
spawn different stuff the point is that
the last one
shouldn't return
network currently we support
two network configuration
one is the so-called host meaning in
jail jargon is inherit so basically you
are you're using the
the the machine network stack or the
other one is the public bridge
meaning that you have an internal bridge
every jail has a v-net
it's on stack it received one ip
and is exported outside uh there is an
app that is showing everything and
you have redirection rule for every
service that you want to expose
and those are supported both in part and
enormous input we have also other two
network type configuration one is the
private bridge that basically works
exactly like the public bridge so
basically you have one bridge and you
attach your
js there but the public bridge is one
for all of them
with private base you can have a bridge
only for a subset of js so i have three
js i want them isolated
so they you can have delegated bridges
just for
those type of yeah for your work
we want to add this to nomad as well so
it makes sense for us for a group
you have three different uh js you want
them you want you don't want them to be
on the same unique bridge
for many reasons uh currently we have a
small issue
because the driver was at the task level
but
the bridge works at the group level so
it's one
it's one abstraction level above and
apparently on uh nomad 010 there is this
ability to have something at that level
so we have
to figure it out i mean currently is
already working with the public bridge
but if you put i don't know 200 jails
then this bridge will be overloaded and
probably the performance degradation so
this is an area where we want to improve
the last type is alias this is the
typical jail
way on doing things so basically you
assign a static ip
to your jail and that will be an alias
on your network card
in this dynamic cloud environment it
doesn't really
fit well because you have
i mean you can theoretically have this j
that is moving from one note to the
other and this ap will follow
uh but it means that you can only have
one instance of that
of that container you cannot have
multiple uh
i mean this cloudy thing is
designed to provide you horizontal
scalability so if you need more
uh horsepower then you have instead of
three web servers fiber server 10 web
servers
and in this case we are limiting to one
because there is only one ip that you
can assign
so and also when you do
um when you want to spawn
i don't know you want to respawn the
same the same you know there is a new
version of
of the web server so you have to
redeploy your job
well you have to remove the former job
you deploy someone else and then you
have
a small downtime between those two those
two times so
i don't know if it's really something we
want to pursue
um
i'm still undecided
can you use it can you play with it can
you try it
yes there is a lot of
different tools that probably nobody
knows or you don't know
the configuration it can be a little bit
tricky
so um mikhail
kremling yes suggested why why you don't
do
a mini part that is basically mini cube
so kind of an instance that is run
on one note so you can play with it uh
so there is uh there it is
uh mini minipod is basically a service
mesh uh
what do i describe before all these
console normal
traffic components everything this is
running on a single node
so you can install mini pod as a as a
package
uh there is a one script that will
change some configuration file on your
machine and then you can start it and
you have
the same environment on a on your
machine so you can
it's not for production not at all
because you don't have high availability
and for tolerance of course it's running
only on your machine
but anyone can try so if you want to
give us what this is the way
there is
a readme page with destruction how to
install it it's not for production
if it's not clear it really it's not for
production
questions so far
don't be shy i still have five socks
wanna see a demo
you sure
so this is how mini pot looks like i
have mini pot running basically on my
on my laptop and what you have you have
a console running on port 80
8500 you have nomad
one here and you have traffic this is
the front end
actually we won't use it but
it's here so
how it works where it is example
what's that
yeah yeah now i'm
so this is a job description file
[Music]
on many parts you specify a
data center just to know where can we
spawn but the
internal abstraction of abstraction
[Music]
it's that's a very the very hello world
example so basically
just define a service called alofosdem
uh the configuration is nginx i mean the
standard nginx
will be we will see the the standard
page of nginx where to download the
image
which one which version blah blah blah
and the port 80 will be
mapped of top side and that's it that is
the minimum
thing that we need so how it works is do
we just say nomad
run custom awesome.job
come on
[Music]
the command line tool is now speaking
basically with the
with the server say hey this is the job
description
oh the resources
so the question was about the resource
limitation um
yeah i missed that point so basically
i'm using cpu set
so that it's complicated uh
theoretically the resources that you
specify are used by the orchestrator to
understand
if your cluster has the capability to
run
this kind of a job
[Music]
so the cpu is kind of a bogus
megahertz uh so if your machine has
is running on two gigahertz and you say
that your job needs 100 megahertz
is basically okay your machine is two
megahertz and then it's using
like to say five percent something like
that but it's it's bogus somehow and
it's used mainly for
uh for scheduling and orchestrating
memory is i'm using rctl to enforce
memory
but it doesn't work like in c groups
rctl is
try to to limit the amount of memory
used by your jail
but if your jail needs more memory it
won't kill
your your processes
and that is not ideal in general because
then you can have people exploiting that
fat so you can use basically more memory
invading the others uh it had this
neighbor effects so called
one thing that you have to work on is a
om killer so basically trying to monitor
the memory consumption as it's really
not able to
stick to that value you have to kill it
but those are resources there are
with rctl and cpu set basically they are
enforced
um that's it now yeah we have the
submitted the job triggered created blah
blah blah what that means
we just look now at the the ui
here so
we have our first in job one
up and running
[Music]
and you see there was only one instance
it's running where
is running here that is basically where
is reachable
just click on it
and then there is the welcome to nginx
we have the same information here
basically the the service is registered
we will have also some tag
because then you can basically subscribe
to specific service that has this tag
and so on
and what you have here you have also
basically now
console is keeping this information
up to date so you know he knows where
it's running you see there is not
opportunity but this
weird number and then it's performing
continuously
checks so if that disappears that will
be marked as
red and basically you can ask to counsel
okay give me all the services
and give me the service they are in
health and
healthy and not not running so this is
trying to keep this information
always up to date and then you have also
here basically this is traffic
this is the this proxy it receives the
information from console
and it had that here
a new front end called uh
hell of austin because that was the name
of the service and if you basically
occur
with this host header you will be
redirected to the
back end hello foster that this year and
those are
totally dynamic so basically continually
asking console oh there is a new
service he's adding a new front end and
he's adding then a new backend to
service
to serve this
this service i see that i have
i have to i have another demo but
yeah i don't have time to show it
it seems nice seems working
but what is the problem creating the
image is actually an issue i mean what
is the image how can i create it how can
i provision my js
uh we need to provide automation
reproducibility that's a heavy topic for
me
has to be fast the images should be not
gigabytes but reasonably small
the solution should be portable and
usable portability especially because
the current solution is basically flavor
so
when you run a pot create to create a
pot
you can specify flavors that are
basically provision scripts
so you can say okay if you want engine x
boom i have a script that just installed
nginx
i make nginx an example but
and then you can have basically multiple
flavors that do just element
a small set of operations for instance
those
uh there are two flavors out of the box
fpg update and slim
everyday update is running previously
update
before anything so it's because when uh
how it works when you say okay this is
the base 12.1 it's downloaded the biz
dot txz but that doesn't have any uh
patches so you always have to run a
previously update there
and this limb is a work in progress
it tries to reduce the image of the size
of the image
deleting c lang deleting a lot of files
that
if you're running web server you don't
need you don't need gdb
you don't need a lot of things so i'm
just removing
hundreds of megabytes of stuff that in
that scenario you don't really need
two problems first of all
it's not user friendly scripts go and
it's not really user friendly it works
obviously only on freebsd
what is a script that use js
it works only in freebsd web developers
use
they don't use previously period type
i have a favorite they i'm the only one
in chicago we have a thousand people i'm
the only one with previously left off
uh nobody's you i mean nobody few people
use previously on the laptop so
it's it's an issue and the other thing
that is not really nice if you let's say
oh
new version of engine x you have to
recreate everything from from the
scratch so yeah
you keep your flavors there basically
those butterscotch but then you have to
create
everything from from the beginning this
is still an issue
the second one is not that bad
can be better um
what machine estimate again
why you don't imitate docker with docker
machine
so basically if you want to run a docker
container on a mac
uh i mean docker i mean inside docker
there is
linux binaries but they run on the mac
and how it works basically
what you have is and you have to install
docker machine that is installing
a linux kernel in a virtualbox or
in the vm sequentially and it's a
security linux code there
so why can we not do the same
and put machine is this project to
create
basically it works on mac os x and on
linux you will use vagrant to spawn a
previously
vm where you can execute and run your js
it extends all the command available on
path so basically you have two three
commands
more and every command that is not
special
kind of you have park machine possibly i
mean two or three commas
the other are just forwarded to the
freebies dvm and you can have your js
running on
linux more or less so that's it's a
it's an important thing because it's
breaking the barrier so everyone can
theoretically now play with js
you don't need a freebsd installation to
play with js
the second work in progress is post file
this is
we're just looking how it goes so we're
trying to imitate
docker file instead of having that
complicated script that you put there
and there
you can just have this typical run from
whatever
it's experimental uh it's not adding
really or changing the way it's just
translating
this pod file in in a flavor
i mean the flavor is what actually you
are want to run is the same
it's not user friendly so that's
basically a wrapper
where people is more used to to use
[Music]
to create bot images
i would encourage you to to try
if you have some issues he will fix them
uh but it's a working pro so we are
still evaluating
we don't want to create a complete new
format because i don't think it makes a
lot of sense
uh but i mean also docker file is not
the best format ever so
we are kind of puzzled what we can do
what we shouldn't do
registering uh
[Music]
easy it's easy to be server with those
files
you put there so when you do a pot
export you create your image and then
you have those files
you copy them over period
you have to maintain your own registry
basically
i don't want to maintain any registry at
all
i don't like the idea to download
binaries i don't want to maintain
to have the burden uh in terms of
security but
having binaries floating there and there
uh
but i'll be more than happy to have
uh a flavors catalog so you need engine
x okay this is the way to create engine
so you have those scripts already
prepared
uh there's a radio approach similar to
what bastille bsd is doing
they have all this template where you
can just say okay i want to jail with
memcache boom done you don't need really
to understand how
it's already there so there you have a
really
a great approach and maybe i can reuse
those template i don't know how to speak
with the
but still bsd developer
this kind of registry that i showed in
the examples is a visual machine running
somewhere is a
web server with those two files period
it's good for example so you don't have
to create your own and so on
but it's not for production use not at
all basically it's just
something so people can try you can try
it you don't need to create a new image
and so on but it's not docker hub
you cannot upload things it's it's a web
server
it's not for production
wow two minutes three minutes uh we
want to do a lot of things many already
spoken
but i'm running out of time we want to
focus now on
more on image creation because that is
where people can then
use it or at least try to use it because
if you have wow you have your service
mesh but you have nothing to run
doesn't make any sense so it is more or
less
especially with probably have many ideas
but no time to
to do it um
the dualsex support will come i get no
it's not here olivier spoken with him
[Music]
good idea to have ipv6 support currently
everything is uh
on my pb4 uh but we will have ipv6
support to provide dual stack so
your container can cam will speak
ipv6 uh really thank you
to here thank you for listening uh i
welcome
also my contributors i put nickname
because i'm not sure that
they want to be i can write their name
but really thanks
question wow many
almost over but i guess i have time for
many how many questions can i
do you have any ideas about persistent
storage
uh it's relatively easy it's not managed
here basically you can go on the machine
you can mount
data sets or directories inside the
inside the container so
it's up to you what to use but if you
have on a specific node you can pin
basically
a container running on a specific node
where you have a data center persistent
storage there
and then you can mount it uh inside the
inside the gel
is official i didn't show but it's there
and you can define that
container yeah you specify
mount in you can mount in a as i said a
folder or zfs data set
you read only if you have to be read
only only and then you can pin the
the job directly to a specific machine
uh i don't see why not
i use pf i don't know how your cage is
using pf
i only think what it's doing is is using
uh two anchors that i add and that's it
so i
don't really pollute too much uh
and then i have my specific data under
you specify where to put your
route where to create all the data sets
and if it's different then
it should be compatible i never tried it
but
keep me posted last question
so how would you compare that to the uh
what is