so
in the autumn of uh 2008 i started
implementing
mesa's glsl compiler completely from
scratch
we had a glsl compiler but for a whole
bunch of reasons that
i think i've talked about in other talks
at other conferences
it had to go so i did i'd never written
a compiler before i'd taken a compiler's
class at
university but that was it so i did a
couple of months of research and i
started on the project
armed with uh with two books one was
uh steven munchnick's seminal work
uh advanced compiler design and
implementation
now even when i started this project
that book was already
around 10 years old and it was starting
to feel a little bit dated
it had a very small section about ssa as
this is this new thing that people are
starting to play around with
but everything else that was in it was
really detailed explanations of battle
tested
algorithms and all of the algorithms and
data structures in it
were related back to actual production
compilers that people were shipping and
the
problems that people had with them and
things that they had to do to actually
make stuff work so it was
really really solid practical advice
and in fact there's a jit project
started by some folks at red hat
that's using the uh mid
middle um ir from that book
as its basis so people are are still
using this it's still a great
resource the other book that
uh that i had in the other hand uh was a
retargetable c compiler
so the draw of this book this book is uh
by a couple of university researchers
that's primarily about the
lcc compiler uh the draw of this book
was elberg which was a cogenerator
generator system
and burrs the bottom up rewrite system
that they had to implement code
generation in that compiler
so lcc has this tool that that's part of
it
called elberg that basically implements
a domain specific language
for generating code generators where you
have
a set of statements where you have a
pattern of ir
to match a blob of something that looks
a bit like
assembly code to generate and then an
estimate of how much that blob of
assembly
costs
[Music]
this this set of code is then compiled
down into some data and code
that gets built into the compiler and
used by
the burs the the bottom up bottom up
rewrite system to actually
implement the code generator in the in
the compiler
so burs uses two passes
to go over the ir trees
it does a bottom-up pass where it looks
at
progressively larger and larger trees to
kind of come up with
what's what's the least cost way to
implement
this little bit and then kind of grow
that up and it decorates
the tree as it goes up and then it does
a second pass going
top down to actually emit the code
so this has two orthogonal benefits
one is that open coded pattern matching
code
is really really tedious to write and
is super error prone uh
so for example on later intel gpus
we have a flag on the sources of logical
operations that says
take the bitwise inverse of this source
so you can combine
nots with your sources so we can use
that
say with if you see an ir pattern of
not of a and b well you can just
invert a and b and implement an or
instruction instead
so instead of emitting two instructions
you can emit one
to do that in the compiler hand coded
you end up with
this lovely eye chart uh so in order to
fit
this conceptually simple thing of uh
the the code that actually implements it
i'd use a six point font
gut out all the comments and turn it
into this this
disaster
so without the comments if you saw this
code
in the compiler code it's not even
really obvious what it's doing
so because of that we have very very few
sort of clever bits of code generation
like this in our compiler uh this
i think when i implemented this uh
it helped a few thousand shaders in our
shader database by
you know hundreds of instructions a
percent or two in in them
um so when you have things that are hard
to implement and hard to maintain
like they have to have a lot of of
impact or it's just
there's no return on on the investment
so we don't have a lot of that
but we could
so the other thing that attracted us to
having some sort of automatic code
generation is
this is being able to have the
decorations of
how much you think a particular
instruction sequence is going to cost
so that you can uh try to
do more take a little bit more of a
global view
and do um an optimal
uh code output uh
so this is definitely orthogonal to the
the first benefit uh and some other work
has been done on this
that doesn't use a generator a code
generator generator
uh eric anholt has i think one of the
oldest
still open mrs in mesa gitlab since we
switched over to
to get lab for a
thing called noltus in
the driver that he was working on that
that tries to apply some of this so it's
orthogonal but the two things play
together really well
because if you're going to do this
this sort of global optimization it
helps to have a lot of different
patterns so that it can try to find
different
routes through how to through emitting a
large
uh expression tree if you have a bunch
of different ways
of implementing that it gives the
optimizer more freedom to
to pick better things
so
once we started digging into this years
ago
the dream quickly turned into a
nightmare
uh there were so many
tech both practical and technical
problems that we ran into
the first big problem was we'd have to
implement our own domain specific
language
to do the code generator generator we'd
have in order to implement our compiler
we had to implement another compiler uh
and that was a huge problem uh
in mesa because until very recently
we didn't have a way to be able to build
something during
the mesa build that would run on your
build system
to generate other build dependencies uh
just because of the way
the disaster that was mesa's build
system uh so it took
you know almost 12 years before we could
have even done
this and that ended up being a problem
for some other things
like how we wanted to implement the
shading language built-in functions but
that's
that's another story
so it also turns out that
source modifiers are a big deal on gpus
it's we can almost for free be able to
say
that a source in an instruction should
be negated or have its absolute value
taken
or both but that's not really a thing on
cpus
so none of the research or any of the
published work
about how to actually implement a
generator generator
even considers these things and it turns
out they're kind of
a huge hassle but
it's super important for generating
optimal code on
gpus
most of the time uh especially on the
gpus that we
we cared about when we started
implementing this project
things like negation are free but not
always
on i-965 gpus
for example trig functions and some
other complex math
you can't have any kind of source
modifiers on so there's
a lot of things that have to be taken
into consideration of whether you're not
you have to
resolve those those source modifiers
and it isn't even wasn't even universal
which things were free
so on 996.5 absolute value was free
but on 9 15 which was a thing we still
cared about 12 years ago
and our 200 and r300 to kind of
date where this started uh you had to
use
separate instructions for doing absolute
value they didn't have an absolute value
source modifier and if we were
decorating
if we were going to have a bunch of
patterns to implement
all the different possible instructions
we didn't want to have to go through and
decorate every single place all the
combinatorial explosion of
yes you can have absolute value and
negation on both the sources
of an ad and all of the it would have
just made it
way too verbose and would have kind of
defeated the purpose
so kind of going along with source
modifiers there's also
possibility of destination modifiers
which is definitely a thing that doesn't
exist on general purpose cpus
you can have a saturate modifier that
will clamp the result of an operation to
the range zero and one
and on some nvidia gpus there's a
different saturated modifier that clamps
to
plus or minus one
um and we've kind of come
a long way in our compiler design of
in the the compiler stack in mesa since
then and it's
kind of dubious whether or not having
in the ir this the
destination modifier is a special thing
is actually that helpful
and i think probably in the next year
we're going to end up
uh removing that but it's still a thing
that has to be considered
because being able to get that clamping
happens a lot
and being able to get it for free on
instructions
is a big deal
uh so then
on the gpu architectures of the day they
were predominantly vector-based for at
least part of their pipeline
so swizzling was hugely important
um and that's not a thing that even
exists
on cmd architectures right
cmd architectures are just generally
parallel up do the same thing on all the
channels
in their order there's no reordering of
channels except with
some very special instructions that are
that are dedicated just for reordering
swizzles end up being worse than source
modifiers
because source modifiers there's there's
four combinations that you have to worry
about none
negate abs and negative abs
but with swizzles on a vec 4
architecture where you have
four element vectors your your base
there's either 256
or 1296 possible combinations of
swizzles
there there's some architectures that
can not only reorder x y z w
arbitrarily per component but can also
select
constant values of zero and one
and that doesn't even consider having to
deal with right masks
so the whole thing was just
so far out into doing basically compiler
research to figure out how to do these
things
um they was just completely impractical
but that that dream of being able to
write these these concise descriptions
of
when you see this generate this code
was so compelling that we tried several
times
both myself and eric anholt each
of us tried at least twice to come up
with
something that that would do this
but every time you know ran into a
roadblock and just
gave up because we had to ship products
and not
do you know compiler research as much
fun as that might be
um so they say time heals all wounds
and i i don't know if that's true but i
do know
that if you ignore technical problems
long enough
they will probably become irrelevant
so what what what wounds did 10 years
heal
well first of all we don't have to write
a dsl
anymore pretty much everything that
elberg or any of the other code
generator generators that
people had ever come up with pretty much
anything that those
languages needed we can handle with just
python data
right we can make something that look
that we can make data structures that
encapsulate the
match match this do that we can do that
really easily with just uh python data
and in fact neuroopt algebraic
that's already part of mesa is an
existence proof that that
kind of architecture works really really
well there's a couple of things that
it doesn't that neuropt algebraic
doesn't support
uh that might be nice in a generator
generator
uh it doesn't support any kind of
regular expressions or or more complex
pattern matching you just do a static
match this exact pattern and do this
exact thing
and in the do that part it doesn't it's
very limited in what you can put in the
do that part
and there's also it's also a bit lacking
on
being able to put constraints on the
sources
we've over the years we've added a lot
of things to how it can do
constraint matching on parts of the
patterns
but it can't do something like if you
have a match
expression that has say two constants in
it
and you want to say match this pattern
if
this constant is less than the other
constant there's there's no way to do
something like that and there's a bunch
of cases where
where that would be handy
and then also you know vector
architectures are dead that whole
swizzling right masking all that
nonsense just
is irrelevant because all those
architectures
died off uh the last architecture
for intel where we had to use a vector
oriented thing
was haswell which was
years ago at this point broadwell
supported it but didn't require the use
of it and we
we never used that in the the driver
that we shipped um
and there there are still a few
architectures that
have some kind of more traditional sim d
within a register kinds of things like
the uh
there's a handful of four by eight
instructions on
on vc4 that that do operations on
four parallel bytes within a single
32-bit register but
because those look like traditional
cindy they don't have
the the craziness of the swizzling and
right masking
and all that nonsense so they don't we
don't have to worry about those either
they're they're not a problem so
looking at opt algebraic as a dsl
you have a simple pattern to match
is is the first field and these those
can be arbitrary
nested trees you have a
replacement as the next field which are
also
trees and they can each of them have
variables that are just text we have
some convenience names for them
abcd etc uh so you can rewrite the
expressions and then there's a sort of a
global
condition flag that's that's optional
so in this case this will do lowering
uh if the ir has a subtract instruction
but most gpus
don't have a subtract instruction you
just do add of neg
so this does that that sort of lowering
pass
[Music]
so the do that part
of the neuropt algebraic dsl
is always replace the old
tree with this new tree and replacement
is a little bit of a misnomer there
because
nothing gets removed from the the input
string
what happens is it just adds some more
stuff
you have a new result value and all the
old users
all the all the users of the old result
get modified to use the new result
and then we expect that later
optimization passes like dead code
elimination will
will clear out uh any of the
the bits that are that are no longer
needed they'll do the actual deleting
part
the other subtle point here is
parts of the input string might not
match any patterns
that exist in your your giant pattern
file
uh which is actually a good thing and
eventually as you go through the
optimization passes
you'll get to a point where nothing
matches otherwise you'd get stuck
in an infinite optimization loop which
is a bug
that happens occasionally if you have a
series of patterns that sort of fight
with each other
so if you had this pattern and had
another pattern that converted add of
neg to subtract
and they weren't decorated with this
condition they would just keep
undoing each other and so each pass
through
they'd both activate it'd say yes some
their
optimizations happen so keep going
through the loop and you just get stuck
in
in an infinite loop
it is a bug that happens from time to
time
all right so especially after hearing me
talk up neuropt algebraic it
it's probably not hard to guess where
this is going
we can use the this existing
infrastructure
to implement a new match this
do that kind of dsl
but there are some still some some kind
of sticking points
the algebraic optimizations happen while
the ir
is still in a very pure uh ssa form
uh but when we do code generation
we've come out of ssa form and so
there's a lot of assumptions that
are are made by the opt algebraic
framework that don't hold anymore
so for example the uh opt algebraic
can't handle source modifiers in the
matching if it encounters a source
modifier
at any point while it's trying to match
a
pattern versus the actual ir it just
says i
i don't know and gives up um
so what seems to be sufficient for code
generation purposes
uh is to if you encounter
a value and a that same value but with
some source modifiers
is to just treat them as they're
completely unrelated variables
they're not it's not a value and it's
negation it's a value
and a different value and just match the
patterns as though they were
had nothing to do with each other
so it also can't handle having the
destination
saturate modifier so far
i think it is sufficient to only be able
to
have the destination saturate modifier
at the
the base of the match tree so in the
subtract well i guess that is a very
good one because there isn't much of a
tree there so only the
the root of the tree would have could
have
a saturate modifier in it if you
encountered anything during the match
farther down in the tree you say okay it
doesn't match
so far i haven't found any cases during
code generation where it would actually
be beneficial to detect
saturate modifiers at other points
in the tree the couple cases that i came
across where
maybe something clever could be done it
turned out
it was actually better to just implement
an algebraic optimization to
change what the tree was going to look
like
before the tree was in before the ir was
in the state where
you have those as modifiers where they
where saturate is just
an instruction do the optimizations
earlier on
and then later on you don't see that
stuff during code generation
and it it ends up being so much much
simpler
that may change as we come up with with
more clever code generation patterns uh
and if it gets to that we may have to
just stop
using the destination modifiers which
we may end up doing anyway it's it's
still
an open question
so can't opt algebraic
can't handle non-ssa destinations
so after we've come out of ssa mode
if the shader has control flow there's
going to be places where
rights happen to registers and set it to
ssa values
and i don't that that doesn't that's
fine it's it's completely safe to match
the the final thing as writing to a non
ssa value
so the the patch that i reference there
is
it just deletes an assertion out of out
of the matching code is all
and so that's pretty easy but going
along with that
it also can't handle sources that are
non-ssa values
and we have to be able to match those
because
we have to be able to generate code from
that um
i so far i think that it is safe to
match
a non-ssa value in an expression tree
if that ssa value only or that non-ssa
value
pardon me only appears once because the
problem is if you have
the the ssa values are
by by their definition they don't change
non-ssa values if you see two reads of
them that are separated
at all those reads could be reading
different
versions of that value so they might be
different values
so if you had the same thing appearing
multiple times in an expression tree
each of those might be different and so
the tree
doesn't really match um you might be
generating bad code
so for example if you had if you had a
pattern that
matched a plus a and replaced it with a
times two well if those two a's
were non-ssa values they might be
different values so replacing that with
one of them multiplied by two is going
to give you an incorrect result
so i think that it's safe and i have
some results later on that that
helped convince me that it's safe to if
if a non-ssa value
appears only once that it's safe to just
match it and
and go on with life uh the need for
being able to have
non-ssa sources in the trees
poses another problem for the existing
match
in matching engine but i'll get to that
again in a in a couple of slides
[Music]
so it has the existing infrastructure
has
really really limited uh type tracking
so the values themselves in nur
don't have any types they're just a blob
of
bits they only have a type when they're
used by
an instruction and
the instruction dictates what the type
is so we have separate
floating point add an integer add
instructions so if you have the same
values as sources to both those
instructions
in one of those cases that value is
interpreted as floating point
and in the other case it's interpreted
as integer
even though it's the exact same sequence
of bits
[Music]
so where this becomes a problem is for
example
on intel gpus we don't have
a specific instruction to
convert integer to float
what we have is we have a move
instruction and you mark
on the move instruction that its source
is integer
and the destination is float so when you
get into the
the do that part of the patterns
you need to know i'm just emitting a
move instruction
but for this source i need to know what
type it was being
interpreted as in the pattern that got
matched
so there's some additional uh tracking
that needs to happen so that
the values that are used in the the do
that part can get
back connected to where they appeared in
the original
matching tree
so like i mentioned before opt algebraic
doesn't require
that everything in the the input
matches something in the patterns but
if you're generating code everything
that exists in the ir had
better end up as some kind of
instructions in the output or you're
just
like dropping stuff on the floor so it
isn't
a problem per se but it's something that
when you're writing
the code generator descript the machine
description for the code
generator and when you're implementing
the other infrastructure for the
code generator that you have to be aware
of so you can detect
i sent some ir into the matching engine
and it didn't match
anything you need to generate some kind
of an error or
or do something because you
you're about to do something bad
uh and then the other thing that's
that's
kind of a quirk uh it's not really a
problem but is again something that
uh you have to be aware of is in opt
algebraic
the the input language and the output
language are the same but
the whole point of doing code generation
is you're translating from
one thing to a different thing
so what this means in a practical sense
is about
half of the infrastructure that exists
in opt algebraic
is completely unusable for a code
generator the only part that you can
that is actually reusable is the
matching part
the we found a match now let's do
something
isn't isn't any good to you because
we're doing something different and it
turns out that
about 45 of the work of this project
was completely rewriting
all of the uh the infrastructure for
doing the
the do that part of the um
the process
uh so the other difficulty
with non-ssa values that i alluded to
before
uh has to do with the the optimized
matching engine
in opt algebraic so the
algebraic optimization happens a huge
number of times
during the the main optimization loop
and we found that it was a big chunk of
the time
was spent in just doing all of the
matching
so connor abbott wrote a
really really optimized matching engine
that uses a
a modified finite state machine to to
very quickly do
the matching but the way that it
implements this
is it uses the the ssa value numbers
the the the index on each ssa value
as the main key for the entire engine
so if you have to match things that
don't have
ssa value indices like you're stuck
you it just the whole infrastructure
just completely falls apart so we can't
use
any of the super optimized matching
engine
that's okay because
while algebraic optimizations might
happen
hundreds of times while compiling a
shader
code generation happens once so if we
can't if we have to use a slower path
for that
it's a thing that happens once i don't
expect that it's going to be a big deal
okay so the output language
um there is a few goals and requirements
as i was implementing this the first was
i
really wanted the thing that
that a human authors to look as much
like the actual gpu assembly as possible
that's being implemented it as some kind
of python objects but we
i wanted to make it so that when you
looked at it
it looked like you were looking at gpu
assembly because the people who are
going to author
these things and try to debug them and
maintain them
are going to be familiar with that right
that's that's the output that you see
when you're debugging shader compilation
issues
it's the format that's in the hardware
documentation
it's what we get when we look at output
from shader db
runs like that's that's the language
that we work with
so let's make this other thing look like
that just to reduce the the cognitive
burden
of of you know having to
um to understand these these patterns
so this can be challenging because
a lot of the instructions and the way
that register accesses
are encoded and a bunch of other things
about the gpu architectures
are weird and complicated so
getting those to look civilized um
as a bunch of python objects is is
tricky
uh so the other thing that's that's nice
is
you really really want to be able to
represent
as much of the weird quirky bits of the
architecture as possible
you don't necessarily have to get every
weird quirk
but it turns out that
those weird corners of how
a particular gpu works those are the
cases where you're most likely to find
opportunities to generate smarter code
right
[Music]
the way that you can access subparts of
registers or
mix types and instructions or do other
kinds of weird things
like that's where you can generate kind
of kind of clever stuff
so it's beneficial if you can just
represent that
so as i said before
in python you have to be able to also
represent these things
as a list or tree or some kind of
collection of just python objects right
that's the
the whole point of the exercise of not
implementing our own
dsl is we can just reuse python
and then in c right this is going to
somehow generate out c code
we want it to be represented as either
data or code or some combination thereof
and i think ideally if we can generate a
set of
compact data tables to represent the
transformations and
the patterns that that's kind of ideal
when the code generator is hand coded
uh the the existing hand coded one
uh the single generator covers all the
different gpu generations
and that's very practical in that case
but
when you are when you have instead of
a handcrafted code generator when you
have a machine description file
essentially that describes
translation of patterns from the ir to a
set of assembly instructions
it's more natural to have a bunch of
separate files that
just cover a single architecture and so
kind of the thing that naturally flows
from that is to come
to compile each of those machine
descriptions into
its own blob of data so instead of
having
one big chunk of c code you're going to
have a bunch
of pieces of data so having those
you know five or six or seven
giant piles of data be as compact as
possible is
is beneficial
so here's how the
um
the output language looks as the the
list of
of python objects this implements the f
sign instruction for 64-bit floats
and i think that this covers i i picked
this one because
it hits almost everything that
uh that it can that the the output
language can support
uh so the first thing it has is it
declares
a a temporary register because in this
sequence of instructions
it's going to generate a temporary value
and then it has an instruction that's
going to load that temporary register
with the
a double precision float immediate zero
value
it's does a comparison that sets the
not zero conditional modifier flag
uh does another move it does an
and that a an in
a bit wise and instruction that only
uses the
upper 32 bits of the 64-bit destination
and the upper 32 bits of the 64-bit
source
and then it has an or instruction that
is predicated so it only
executes if the compare instruction
actually set the not zero flag
so to pretty much anyone who's familiar
with
the assembly language of this gpu
what this is doing looks pretty obvious
right if you don't know it
if you don't know this gpu assembly
language it's just a pilot
but you're probably also not
authoring or maintaining one of these
machine description files
but it covers pretty much everything
and it does it in a compact concise way
and it's just a bunch of python objects
the instruction
generates an object and then the the
predicate
method modifies that that object
it does things in a pretty uh clean way
i think
uh so what i ended up doing with this
is it the the output of when you run the
the python scripts to convert the code
generator
or convert the parameter the machine
description into c
is it they generate a a couple of tables
of
byte code um there's two separate tables
one is a table of immediate values
because those could be
up to 60 64 bits for each immediate
value
and then a sequence of instructions uh
which
each instruction uh is much smaller i
don't remember if
i managed to get it packed into 16 bits
or 32 bits
um and so the the byte code
each instruction in the byte code does a
very simple thing like
declares an op code and then there's a
separate instruction that declares the
destination with all of the
flags and modifiers that can be on a
destination another one for each of the
sources that also has
all the flags and the
the c code that then converts that
byte code into actual machine code ended
up only being
203 lines uh including
the license header so you know maybe
150 lines of actual c code so it was
very
it's very small and very concise
um i ended up creating
six different machine description files
to cover all the
uh all the various generations of
intel's gpu architectures
and the files were are organized so that
it's really easy to just
do a diff of
one generation's machine description and
the next generations machine description
and you get a very compact output of oh
here's all the stuff that changed from
gen 7 to gen 8. it also makes it really
easy when you need to add
the next generation you just copy the
old one
and go to town making edits on it to add
new features
or remove things that use features that
that got removed or instructions that
don't exist or
or or whatever once i got the first
machine description written cranking out
all the rest of them was
was pretty easy you know it's always the
most work is to to make the first one
so
remember back a whole bunch of slides
there there was the eye chart
so we can now look at what it looks like
to do
all of that that same kind of
optimization but using the machine
description
it's still a lot of stuff but
nowhere near as much i fit it on a slide
in a ten point font
instead of a six point and i didn't have
to delete any of the comments
um but i want to just look at one of the
the sub patterns here so this says
if we have a knot of
a logical instruction and sources that
don't have any source modifiers
we're going to omit a single instruction
that's
the other the other logical instructions
so if we had
an and we're going to emit an or with
all the same sources but we're going to
set the negate flag on this particular
architecture on a logical instruction
if you have an a negate source modifier
it instead does a logical knot
and then all the rest of this is just to
handle
one one sort of annoying quirk that came
out of this
is all of the patterns have to match
for specific bit sizes so there's a lot
of
[Music]
there's a lot of sort of redundant
patterns that
ended up existing in in the machine
descriptions uh so in this case i have
to generate
separate patterns for 8 16 32 and 64
bits
because i had to know what types to
decorate on the sources so it was a
little bit of a hassle
and so that's why this ends up being a
little bit bigger than it
should have to be there there may be
a solution to that i i don't know uh it
didn't end up
affecting that many instructions that i
wanted to generate so it wasn't
it wasn't too bad um
but you know there's there's always
potentially room room for improvement
so you know we're talking about
replacing a pretty major subsystem in
the compiler and whenever you're
replacing a big subsystem with something
new
uh there's there's one important goal
that you really should have in mind that
people don't
talk about a lot and that's minimizing
disruption
right if you're going to replace this if
you're going to replace
some existing code that works with a you
know new
shiny better version that's going to
make some things faster
we'd better make sure that it doesn't
substantially hurt
other things right
and if and if if some things are hurt
you know
you have to at least make sure that it's
it's minimal damage
and that the the pros dramatically
outweigh the cons
so when i ran
just the straight machine descriptions
as as i
authored them without adding any new
optimizations
across our shader database which has
about
50 000 shaders from real applications
there was no change in the generated
code
so that that felt pretty cool um
it i ended up the the
impact on the mesa source was about 1400
lines of deletions
and 4 800 assertion insertions
and a huge chunk of that was just the
machine description files
because there were six of them and each
one averaged about 500 lines
so there's there's some debate about
whether or not we should
extract common bits from the machine
description files
and have them stored in a separate file
that then basically just gets included
i think it's a it's better keeping them
standalone
and where each one is entirely
independent because
as the architectures change
less and less is truly shared across
a large chunk of the architectures so it
kind
of kind of has diminishing returns as as
time goes on
um but i don't know it's it's it's still
a debate to be had uh
so and then i you know towards the end
of the project i added a couple
really simple optimizations that
would have been a hassle to add in the
hand coded
code generator and those helped a few
hundred shaders by
a couple percent um but at this point
almost no work has been done on on
finding
patterns you know new new optimization
patterns and and clever tricks
um but i have a big list of things that
i want to try uh
and i i know that there's just from
having looked at
lots of shader assembly over the years i
know there's a lot of stuff that we can
do
um so future work well wait no
no finishing current work uh there's
still
there's still a couple of the patches
that are that are marked work in
progress
uh the big one is is
like i had mentioned before about
deciding what we want to do about the
the machine description files
keeping them stand alone or or trying to
extract out common parts
and there's a couple of patches in in
the mr that
show what some of that would look like
if we if we pulled out the common parts
um the other thing is there's
still a couple of the patches that i
think
could really benefit from some unit
tests uh
in particular the one that enables
non-ssa
sources uh i i think that that's safe
but i would like to see
i would like to spend some time trying
to come up with some some counter
examples and try to encode those as
unit tests um
so i'm gonna i think i'm running out of
time so i'm gonna try to go through the
the actual future work kind of kind of
quickly
[Music]
so one thing some
instructions can't have source modifiers
some instructions can't have immediate
values as sources
and there's a handful of other
limitations like that
that are currently handled by adding a
bunch of extra patterns
and putting in a bunch of complex stuff
so for example
on the the intel gpus where
the negation source modifier on a
logical instruction
means take the logical knot we have to
if you have a source that that has the
negation source modifier on it we have
to emit
an extra move instruction to sort of
resolve that
negation and i think that it would be
better to encode that a different way
by having a set of patterns that say
if you have an immediate value you can
convert that into something else by
having a move or if you have source
modifiers you can eliminate those source
modifiers by adding a move
and then simply decorating some of those
patterns as
can't be an immediate or can't be
can't have a source modifier and then
having the pattern matching engine
first match the resolve kind of pattern
and then match the other pattern i think
that would end up making things a lot
cleaner
and would help support some of the some
of the other
future work that i think needs to be
done
[Music]
so integrate code generation with cse
so as you're emitting instructions do
the common sub expression elimination at
the same time so you don't
re-emit the same instruction in each
basic block
right now we have a separate cse pass
that will just going and clean that up
but we could just integrate it directly
with the code generation
that by itself doesn't buy you very much
but it does make it much easier to do uh
dynamic uh cost estimation
where if you have a sequence that's
going to match and you know what this
output pattern is
you want to be able to estimate what the
cost is going to be
if you know that well i don't need to
omit these three instructions because
they already exist in this basic block i
can just reuse those values
that's going to give you a completely
different cost estimate than if you had
to emit
all the instructions in the block
and it's really hard uh the reason
that i specifically caught say dynamic
cost estimation
a lot of the existing research about
code generator generators used
static cost estimates but
gpus are complicated like it's really
hard if you have more than
like two instructions in your
replacement pattern it's
hard without any context to be able to
estimate
how much those that's actually going to
cost
so the the cost estimation function it
has to be
dynamic or it's just lies and at that
point like why
why are you doing it um
and then you know finally we get to
great success
of we have cost estimates so then we can
integrate it with something like noltus
or some other
burs or some some existing uh
optimization scheme that tries to pick
the best sequence of instructions
for a given set of of expressions
uh so then i've got a bunch of links to
all the the mrs
and uh the the work at red hat that i
mentioned
uh yeah there's an extra mr in there
that can
contain some uh prerequisite patches for
the actual code generator
generator uh uh
and then the yeah eric's very old noltus
patch series and i think i finished
within time
yay are any questions
yes architecture in such a way that you
could
instead of having like common code all
of them
instead have it for like an older
version and then like
have a newer file and only the things
that i've changed in that version
being right so what i
what i did in there there is a patch in
the the mr
that basically uh
okay so the question was is there a
different way to
architect the the machine descriptions
so that
you basically have common stuff and then
in
newer in the machine descriptions for
newer architectures you just override
other things so what i did is
common parts that i pulled out
i would pull out a common part and i
would make a
separate uh python list for the common
stuff and i would give that list some
name and then in each generation that
was going to reuse that list
i would just concatenate it in with the
other list so i would have
sort of a concatenation of of lists to
pull in the shared the things that could
be shared and then
stuff that couldn't be shared uh was
just listed out in each machine machine
description
that seemed like the cleanest way to do
it um
as just python objects as just a list of
python objects
i don't think that there was a good way
to
override things that were in the list
but i'm i'm definitely not
i'm not the python ninja on the team so
they're there
there may be a way do i have time for
another
one minute left anyone yes in the
your input back and those sources might
appear on different instructions in your
pattern which might be far apart in the
code
maybe there isn't even a point in the
program where both of those sources
actually have the value that you want
at the same time
so the question is if you have multiple
different non-ssa sources
that the value that you want if you have
a
if you have a large enough tree and you
have multiple of those sources that
there might not be a point in the
program flow where
both those values actually exist
maybe that's true and that and that's
why i wanna i mean that's one of the
things that i want to sit down and spend
more time and try to
like find some actual concrete examples
of sort of counter examples um
there were a couple other i mean the
thing that bothered me about this
is you know i i implemented that bit and
i had
that that nagging voice in the back of
my head of are you sure that that's safe
it seems like there's a bunch of holes
here you might fall in
like all right well i have this giant
database of
thousands of shaders and some of them
are really huge
like there's like there's some uh
compute shaders and some games that are
end up generating like 10 000
instructions
and they all just compiled and didn't
explode so i can't find a real workload
that disproves it so it's hard to
yeah and i'm being i'm being told that
my time is up so i'm gonna stop so i
don't get in trouble
you