okay my name is
lionel brush i work in mri so i'm not a
designer i'm not a programmer i'm
actually a
guy who designs a device and make it
work and tries to actually get
the whole things together um i'm working
on a new type of mri device
something that sees new kind of contrast
and can be explored
for for medical applications and i want
to make it open sourced
now mri is not something you can build
in your garage it's some
complex kind of equipment as you can
guess it requires a lot of skills and so
on
so making things like this open source
is quite a challenge
and what i want to try and make is
something like an open source hardware
repository
something you could install on your
computer you would actually be able to
browse project online
if you find something that is
interesting for you you download the
file you have all the blueprints all the
steps needed to actually mark the device
all the skills needed all the
documentation and so on and then you
just follow step by step so basically
the code is the blueprint and the
compiler is yourself
or whatever tools you use to actually
make the device and when the device is
built you have a virtual environment on
your computer that
actually can track what the device does
and so on so that would actually be
quite nice to develop these kind of
ideas but
i'm not a designer i'm not a programmer
so what i would like to have is some
help from a designer or programmer to
give some
inputs about how this could actually
look like not make it
at this stage but to have some realistic
view of how this could look like
technically so that i can apply for
grants and get actually someone hired to
do the job
so if anyone here would be happy to have
a discussion or a chat
tonight or on the beer or whatever i'm
happy to to talk
i leave my email address on the board so
you can contact me
thank you
[Applause]
so you're i'm still
yeah that's my left whole body we have
patients coming there and so on
we have a few prototypes already done
it's working great we have clinical
studies going on and now i want to open
sources
which would be great and i'm not the
only one to do that because there's a
whole community doing this called
open source imaging initiative they are
working on open source mri and
ultrasounds
and also devices they are part of this
but
again we are hardware guys and
any help home design and
or the interface that the mri technician
would be using
the entire thing so basically what we've
done in aberdeen so far has been to
assemble
pcs that were built by suppliers because
it's so difficult to get you know
proper gradients and magnets and so on
these guys in open source initiative are
actually
uh trying to regroup all their
initiatives around open source hardware
that are relevant to mri
they manage to get the whole system
actually from the magnet to the
gradients to the chords to whatever
so lots of pieces are there for a bare
bone scanner at least
so we need a bit more but um and what
we've done in aberdeen is
well integrating all that getting the
software to work getting the images
making the patient studies validating
doing the research on
how we can actually use it what
information it gives that could be
useful for clinicians relating with
the hospital over there that's what
we've done over there yes
so a bit of well yeah go to bed
thank you very much but yeah so again
having someone to help with uh
those apart so all the the technical
thing would be great so yeah
if you want to help or to be part that
would be great
thank you maybe maybe time for someone
[Applause]
else
okay uh who would like to go next
you have some slimes yes i have them
okay
um
[Music]
um should i put this so
okay okay
so hi i'm i'm sophia i'm from the
uva team and the rest of the team is
there
[Laughter]
i want to explain a little bit the
problem we are facing in order
to understand the project so um
we are facing what we all are facing
like mankind is facing these two
problems no surveillance capitalism and
the loss of control of our data so
we wanted to regain this data
and this owner data ownership and
we decided to build a platform to escape
from the corporate consumer cloud
so to do so what is juvia no the the
our project uv is a physical device that
everyone will have
the the everyone that they want we have
in their house
and you can have their
storage email contacts calendar or any
kind of
app that you can download from a
decentralized marketplace
so we wanted
uh as you can access to the device
from anywhere through a secure
connection
a via tour and the intention is
that everything is open transparent
auditable
and easy to use
so this is the tricky part the that
connects with the design
in order to have some something that is
very
easy to use by anyone like our
parents or grandparents uh
we need to make a big effort in design
so we have to develop a design system
we have also to develop the
user interface and the user experience
these are part of the work that we are
now doing
and we also have to develop the hardware
case
appearance so that that are the three
fields in design that
we are working on and that we need help
and your collaboration if you want
uh we have received a funding from the
next generation internet initiative
that is an initiative from the european
commission
we are open to a short-term or long-term
collaborations
so anything that we are open to talk
and in fact i'm curious if anyone has
worked with um like industrial design
or anything like that no
okay and
ah hi so if you want we can talk about
it and i think that's all thank you and
we have stickers
so thank you so much
[Applause]
so is is there software already created
is is there a version people can
yes
uh
um
um we are
we are developing something in order to
test with
um
the first
[Music]
so we are like in the second stage not
not at the beginning
but yes did you ever try to
just do the one frame of the application
not my paper
not yet um
yes
[Applause]
anybody else yeah
so
right yeah yes nice to finally
yeah see you in person i've been trying
to get to this bedroom all day
i don't have slides but is there a web
browser i could do there yeah absolutely
yep there you go
there you go okay so um
so philip is getting his things
together uh don't forget if you're going
to
the pitcher project you can post the job
on
the post on the website
as well just a sort of concise
what it does what you're looking for and
then contacting each other we might have
some
questions over back with you but that's
so my name is philip durbin i come from
harvard university and i just gave a
lightning talk about our project at two
o'clock so you should be able to find
the recording there
um but i thought i'd at least mention
here uh tell a quick story about
dataverse that i told at the open source
design
table which is that we did a big rewrite
of our software about
five years ago or so and it came about
because we
had a usability study done on the
previous generation the first software
so it was called ddn3 we basically
had some students from simmons college
in boston common like look at the
software and gave us a report
and it came back negative like your
software is unusable unfortunately which
led directly to
us saying okay well we need to like it
was like a come to jesus moment
like we need to really decide what are
we going to do and so we did a big
rewrite with a folk we hired a usability
person
and really focused on usability for the
the current generation of the software
and now what we're seeing is i mean this
is not a direct line right but
um if we look at our installations
uh we now have 52 installations around
the world
six continents and i'm not trying to say
it's because exactly of the usability
study
but i really think that the emphasis on
usability has helped a ton
so uh i guess i'm just trying to spread
the word that like tell encourage
projects to like bring in usability
people to study the current state of
affairs and like see if you can
get some traction that way um
i how much time do i have should i wrap
up
i have a totally unrelated project i'm a
dad i have a 13 year old daughter and a
10 year old daughter
and i thought i'd show one other quick
open source project that another dad and
i have been hacking on
are you looking for input in some way
well i don't know we could use a logo
right right now the 10 year old is doing
the the artwork
using that open source tool called
piscol so she made this little bee
and she's doing other stuff but i just
thought i'd just sort of spread like the
word about this idea
anyway um and the idea is that
if you have a 13 year old like me like
these kids are all on their phones you
know they're not you know
they um we would like to get them more
engaged in the community
and and they're trying to raise money
for their class trip and to go see
the boston red sox baseball team go go
play baseball
and they want to go on a cruise in the
harbor as part of the school
uh fundraising effort and so we thought
well what if we put these kids at work
what if they put down the phone
and they could shovel snow they'd get a
lot of snow in boston or or they could
walk dogs
or uh do cat city and that kind of thing
so
my friend of mine and i built this thing
mostly him uh
called helper bees and the idea is that
if you're a member of our community it's
kind of a hyper local thing and you're
like oh i need a dog walker
you you click on dog walking and then
the idea is that
the parent or the neighbor is donating
10 bucks
and getting two dog walks from these 13
year olds
so it's just a way to like give the kids
opportunities like do
a little something and then connect
people so
it's worked out pretty well for for my
daughter where you know it's sort of
introducing her to the world of work a
little bit where she was hired to be a
party helper and she was like oh what do
i wear
you know so it's kind of just get her
thinking about those things this is all
on github also this uh health abuse
thing i just thought i'd
spread the word thank you okay
do you have a presentation no why
or anything okay so i
haven't come prepared him here to
present the project and idea but
hearing about this speech complete
say let's give it a try okay so what do
i have in mind is a bit more challenging
to the system
i don't know if you can you raise a hand
if you're familiar with cryptocurrencies
okay this is a good crowd okay now the
problem in cryptocurrency is mostly the
entry and
exit from fiat to cryptocurrencies and
usually this
is solved for now by exchanges by third
party exchanges which
operate and facilitate you in your
interaction and your
bid execution on their platform the
problem is that
those third party are allowed to censor
you
they reserve the right to disallow you
to
execute transaction and even seize funds
now my solution to this
is to design and conceive unbanked
cryptocurrency atm this is a bit
challenging because
the current existing atms you have the
atm which is calling an api to an
exchange executing the trade according
to what was custom
the customer doing but here you have the
risk that
you as an operator you have to take the
cash from the machine
go to the bank deposit the cash then
wire the money to exchange uh here there
are two third parties which
uh could seize your money first is the
bank who can
simply close your account and say we
don't accept your funds
secondly there's the exchange which
could ask okay how did you get the funds
and
all the aml and kic procedures which is
inconvenient for people who want just
to use the technology so there's like a
bottleneck
through to access this technology due to
relying still relying on the third
parties so my idea is to build the
descent
not decentralized that's i think
misusing the word
uh unbanked uh cryptocurrency atm where
the price would be determined locally by
a local
offer and demand and
people would speculate on the local
transaction on the local demand so the
feeling and the emptying of the atm
wouldn't be
the responsibility of the operator the
operator would have to maintain only
technically like
repair parts replace touchscreen or
something like that
now this is a very old broad overview of
the idea now
in order to launch such a project i
still have a lot of
questions which i don't have to ask this
is a for-profit
oriented project so uh i'm not willing
to invest
funds to pay people to come to work
to employ people but i'm more willing to
find a model to reward dirty
contributors and early participants in
the project
and there are a lot of things to settle
a lot of areas of expertise are
intersected in this project for example
i would mean
first the government structures like uh
the reward the contribution and
the whole model of the project then
there is building the entire project
which is what computer what operating
system
designing the case designing the user
interface
there's a big load of work
i have already some people involved from
the community
which more particularly the more narrow
one
who are interested and contribute with
ideas to this project but due to
personal situation i'm kind of stuck so
if you're interested maybe to
participate in
something like this well i'll drop my
contact details here any questions
thoughts
well usually the more if cost effective
would be to use a bank an exchange
but when you're censored by those those
institutions
cause is not really a reason besides
this you as an operator you have
multiple
the way i view the terminal would be
able to have
three sources of monetization first
maybe internet access people this can be
promoted as
an internet terminal people just browse
the internet and pay either with crypto
either with fiat
it can be used as a net platform like
companies
present ads on the terminal so people
who are
visiting passing by or they give back
they pay for
free access to their website of the
terminal and
the third is practically the
cryptocurrency exchange where the
operator would get a fee from each
transaction from each exchange
and yes now it's supposed to i suppose
to
conceive a model to split the revenue
between developers and contributors and
people who are working
to the project and operators
which country do you wish
it's an open source project which the
idea is anyone can buy build a computer
uh star screen and the bill etc and they
build their own machine
that's that's my idea so i don't want to
target the particular account
is this illegal you're starting on the
premises that something must
be specifically legal in order to do it
so where's
the why
okay so i'm going to uh if you want to
continue
very interesting discussion which i
don't know
[Music]
[Applause]
next uh okay project just because we're
running out of time no you're running
out of the
of the camera camera's recording there
and houston yes
gentlemen prefer to stand off the camera
that's totally fine uh microphone
up here okay
so where's the barriers okay
stick it in your pocket excellent this
one is a bit
cool okay hey hello so i'm tom i work on
ettasync
it's essentially end-to-end encrypt and
sync your contacts calendars and tasks
i know it's a mouthful think something
like icloud or next cloud or
gmail account or google account sorry
but encrypted in a way that the service
provider for example apple cannot access
your data
and so for example whatsapp has
end-to-end encryption so it encrypts
your data in that way
if they're not clear and so how does it
work at the moment so it's been around
for three years now
it's an old project or ish young-ish and
you just on android for example you just
install the app
and then you just start using it as if
it's a normal google account so you
continue using
the calendar app that you love and the
contacts app that you love and all of
that just remains the same
so that sounds as if there's not a lot
of ui and you'd be right
that in on android there isn't a lot but
the
ux and ui issue here is the onboarding
because i had to explain it to you
in 20 seconds or however long and i
think
a lot of users bounce at that stage and
i know from feedback that a lot of users
install it star use like open the app
and they're like wait i can't add
calendars yeah you can't yeah okay
sorry calendar events and the reason is
of course because you should use your
normal
calendaring app but i think the
onboarding i'm missing something
in the way of nudging so i thought for
example about adding a button that lets
you add
an event but then when you click it it
actually says no you should use your
normal app that would be a solution
but i think the problem is that all of
the onboarding flow is not really
i don't know pushing people the right
way at least on android either
we have a web client where we actually
control the
the ui and it's really ugly but that's i
think that's less of a concern
i mean i want to fix that but it's less
of a concern as much as the onboarding
which is really poor across
all platforms so this is something i
would love to get help yeah
and also we're funded by um i mean
supported not really funded by
ngi zero internet i don't know if you're
familiar with them and they just
had a meet up so we partially supported
by them yeah so
cool so it's uh it's a transport
for end-to-end encrypted contacts
you have a contact or a calendar event
on your phone
it goes to wherever it's going to go to
but it's encrypted there
so yeah yes but in in addition to that
it's not just a
transport it also just stores it so
think exactly like icloud
so if you lose your phone you can just
install it again and everything
you can download back as long as you
have the encryption password that's by
the way
another thing if you lose your
encryption password you cannot access
your data and that's another thing when
we kind of like need
part of the onboarding or maybe a bit
later i don't know like five days
in to kind of have a way to make sure
that they know it and they have a backup
of something
i don't know it's a lot of challenges
essentially of bringing encryption to
like wide adoption um yeah i have some
idea
i see that happening also with that with
all the bitcoins and all these things
with apps on your phone that that
initially requires you to re-enter
these private keys on numbers so maybe
only the phrase of that or the start of
the finish
so they force you to copy it so you have
to copy basically
that's actually a really smart idea it's
um yeah i mean but that's exactly the
kind of help i need
so those kind of ideas and that kind of
like workflow that solves those issues
and i'm going to do that i think
like really you know it's really smart
and that's actually the amount of
users that reach out to me like hey i
know you can't help me recover the data
because i lost the thing but can you
help me reset the account yeah
and it's like so so and the
information is stored on anything so
everything is open source you can
self-host if you want but we also offer
on a hosted solution for two dollars
yeah two us a month um so it's not a lot
for the west i think and we also by the
way do fair pricing so if you're like
in india or other low income country we
you know we slash the price fifty
percent
or whatever okay so do you have many
users currently or
so because it's open source i mean the
paid one we have in the thousands
open source you know you look at the
downloads or like of the docker image
and all of that
it can be anything between zero and
twenty thousand more i have no idea but
i mean just
guess completely yeah yeah and also it's
packaged by distros so
i don't know how many downloads there
are there like it's really difficult to
estimate
yeah okay is there any particular place
that people can
go to i don't know that's a good
good point that is a good point yeah so
just
at async.com and but that's more so the
moment at the moment the
the company like the hosting is kind of
pop
in distinction indistinguishable from
the
open source project i mean it's the same
website okay the internet is not working
yeah i mean whatever i've had it all day
like internet is really bad yeah
okay so at async.com at the sync like
this
yeah and yeah and.com yeah and i have
stickers as well actually
i have more yeah i should put more
yeah yeah
yeah i mean we have we have an rsc
channel you can connect
for matrix um we don't have a mailing
list but what else we have we have a few
other things
no and also by the way i'm really it's
not that like i think it's a good idea
to do those things i've done some of
them and i see
that you know the the the ramp up like
so many more users stay or for example i
added one of those
um intercom like but ours is open source
based on xmpp blah blah blah
but anyhow the moment you have that
people actually ask you questions and
they retain more so it's all of those
small things that you think like
it's not going to matter i need to code
more and then you like you do that like
oh my god
spike so i really know the value of it
this one tried to say it's not going to
be one of those kind of like oh leave me
alone
uh kind of kind of communities yeah
okay yeah cool it was really interesting
oh cool and use it yeah use it by the
way even if you're not interested in
helping yeah
great cool thank you
so did you hear the sort of initial yes
i
um hi i'm isthman and i'm actually
pitching for a friend um
who couldn't make it um here's roaming
around stuck in another talk
um the main thing is
so what he created is a um library for
collaborative editing so for google docs
like
um thing and it's really stable now and
it's used by a lot of users
and i myself i'm a heavy user but what
it's completely missing is
awareness so making
um people aware that other people are
using it
so it's it scales to
dozens of users but it's really hard to
follow what is happening for example
there is a um
an example here um so you can type
text well here
um and what we need is
some kind of a design system for
awareness that goes beyond those basic
ideas that
google docs has for example the the
colorful animals on the top
or the the cursors because um
it supports a lot of data types and
things for example drawing
and already hear um the usual
awareness thing so awareness is that you
see that others are what others are
doing
are not working here and we really need
ideas
how we can you know get the information
to the user that some
something happened here made by another
user
so that would be awesome if um yeah we
could
get some help on that there is um
information
on on yjs.dev and there's a getter
there's a discuss
and github issues with contacts
so just to get a realistic idea if i
wanted to
join that and collaborate with you how
would i do that
just go on the website yes.dev and then
scroll down it works on mobile
and then click the drawing tab and start
drawing and then you see
somebody's drawing but you don't see who
is drawing
are you drawing right now
now than this laptop
yeah what the the text should work
i know yeah yeah it's so
you saw that so this magically appeared
but
we don't know who did it okay
yeah some ideas some some design
system that that everybody can just use
and um yeah so we're ready to implement
it but we need ideas
or something with colors and then change
the colors accordingly
also with the text you can use the same
colors name the text to the left corner
with the label okay
oh so so a lot of people are joined up
sorry basically
you generate automatically a new caller
yes you can draw with different colors
yourself
excuse me well this is
this is just a demo so um
you can
yeah but even if a lot of
people are working on google so if
you're collaborating and even 10 people
are working on
at the same time it's really hard to you
need to
to look at the document to see who has
changed what
it's all in javascript
thank you so how do we get in contact
with you um basically on yjs.dev
it's i can't see it here right
so yjs.dev dev and there's a
discuss link github very active
guitar okay yeah
okay thank you very much thank you
[Applause]
so just to remind everybody please don't
forget to
post the job to opensourcedesign.net
jobs um because that's where it will
move
outside of this 20 odd people to
more people okay
anybody else before we yeah
we've got we're a little bit over but
do we have anybody else who's interested
maybe one more
if not that's
you