good afternoon everybody
and sorry for this house and the wrong
format of the slides
i think it happens sometimes and uh
soon enough you'll see that it's not the
only fault here
so
what is lua what is legit and why it
might be interesting or it is
interesting to put
one to the other one first a few words
about myself
and as you've already see i'm not really
a software
developer so i know not so much about
the software and spent last quarter
century
developing hardware where the software
is usually runs on
and here it was a different systems
embedded systems and system
now it's system on modulus and most of
them
are fpga or stock fpga based systems on
modulus
and yes i can write some code on vhdl
but it's again not a software it's
more a description of the low-level
hardware
and the usual problems i have with the
software is not how to develop the
software itself but how to make this
software run on the hardware
and not just on the new hardware but on
the hardware which is
not known to be working yet and recent
development new architectures and soft
core cpus running on the fpga
are not making my life any easier
because now i'm not only
uh i'm not only not sure
that uh some parts of the hardware not
working but
i can be sure that the cpu is also maybe
not quite working right
uh so this uh
talk is about the um initiative project
to
put the lua and specifically lower jit
implementation to the risk five
architecture
but for me as i said it's not
interesting by itself but you
apply it to solve the problems
with the early hardware bringing up and
with diagnostic and debugging this
hardware
unfortunately this projected the
unfortunately for me
it's a very early stage and it's not so
many people involved in it
so please don't be disappoint
disappointed by the end of this talk
that nothing is available and nothing is
working
it's more and lightening talk why it
might be interesting
what approaches do we take what benefits
we will
get if and ever it's done
uh probably in this development room
nobody is
interested to listen once again why risk
five
is good why we should use it or anything
should be ported to it
uh for the application of the hardware
development it's
uh and especially for the soft cpus risk
5 is good because it's free and because
it has modular and extensible approaches
so it's possible to
take the core cpu run some basic
software
if the cpu is or soft core cpu is good
enough and is running and the software
in the state
to bring up this non-working hardware
and non-working cpu
and then you can build upon this solid
foundation
and to add some extensions both to your
hardware infrastructure
and to the cpu itself because i isa
instruction set architecture reserved
some space for the custom instructions
and for the custom extensions of the cpu
architecture
and why it's also important
there are already several hardware
products from
the company i'm working for at the
moment which
do utilize the soft core risk cpu
processors running on the fpga somes
and later this year the uh socket pga
with risk five
cores and system on module
hardware based on this chip are going to
be available so
we need some tools we need some software
to debug it
to demonstrate its operation to test it
in production
oh okay while lower
20 or 30 years ago to bring their
hardware for initial prototype hardware
i've been uh
to exercise the hardware and test it
i've been pretty much happy to
use in a fourth language it's small
compact easy portable to the
new platforms and it provides you an
interactive tool to probe all the
registers to fiddle with your hardware
to see what actually is going wrong with
it
or going right with it
nowadays i think not so many people are
writing any fourth force
even less are using it in production
environment
but uh there seems to be a better also
kind of niche
uh alternative to that that it's um
language it's very small and compact
and it provides you an interactive
environment where you can define new
functions you can touch
all the pieces of your hardware since
it's very compact
plain c code it's very easy to port to
the new architecture
it provides an interface to
c language so if you can access
some parts of your hardware in c just
map some registers and touch them
then it's equally well and easy to be
done from lower from your interactive
shell
and here compare according to
the interpreter language bench
benchmarks lower
i think one of the two on the top
if not the fastest one but uh
usually for those applications it's not
really
critical in any way you're typing on the
keyboard much slower
and this approach with using lower to
bring up hardware and to debug it
has been first tried by muscle firm
something like already eight years ago
to bring up uh the and test the
high-speed serial transceivers
but then it was an ios cpu uh
proprietary intel back then altera
and definitely it's much it would be
much more interesting and sensible now
to do it on the
risc-5 platform just not to be connected
to this particular hardware in
particular
fpga vendor
why luajit lujit is an
implementation of the language with the
just-in-time compiler very efficient
compact fast
even faster than the lower itself but
for me the most attractive if the
not the only most most attractive for
single reason
to try it was that low egypt
it by itself includes a dynamic
assembler
and that allows allows to experiment not
only with
something connected externally to the
cpu block but
uh allows you interactively experiment
with what
is inside the cpu to add some new
instructions and so on
of course it's and for any
real software developer it would be
probably much easier to add support for
new assembly instruction
in their uh binocules llvmgc
here but also things are
way too heavy and even if it would
be possible or if some software
developer would be sitting next to me
and
doing that it still would not be
possible to experiment with those things
interactively on the target
with the logit and its built-in dynamic
assembler
it's possible to write piece of code
with new assembly instructions
you've just introduced in your soft core
cpu and
try them out to experiment with them
also in another second uh
order of importance reasons uh
are that their lower jeep compiler
logit is used in several interesting
projects
in software defined radio much smaller
scale
but also interesting compared to the gnu
radio but uh
still an interesting one and provides
somewhat more consistent and cleaner
environment
let's say lure is 10 times smaller than
python
so lower radio is 10 times smaller than
gnu radio
maybe 100 times smaller but then it's
faster it's cleaner and it gets you
better chances to understand what's
going on really there
toronto database have never ever tried
it
really but what i read about it it's an
fast in memory
uh database and a lower application
server
so for some high grade loaded sites
and enterprise level of applications and
also a nice compact lower power
distribution which includes
the dynamic assembly not only for the
sea preparation but for lower
preparation
so it's just a compact cross platform
lower distribution
also based on utilizing lower jit and
if assume we have an uh lower jet ported
to the risc-5 all those and many other
platforms and applications making use of
legit will be available or easily
available
there are of course some downsides
apparently this
project is not under active development
it's uh prime it it used to be and
mostly and single person development
mike powell and uh it looks like since
2017 he is not actively contributing to
this project
but still taking some pictures and there
were
recent development of the
arm 64 and mips 64 bit ports of low agit
um some of them were presented here
on the first dam few years ago if i'm
not mistaken
but still the future may be uncertain as
with any open source
and free projects
for the specific applications of the
logit it's not uncommon for the
companies
to make forks and just to support the
efforts
in order to contribute to the mainstream
and uh
it was good and bad according to the
mit license the low and low jet code is
under
so and it's somewhat lacking behind
the uh mainstream lower development
which is now it's the version five point
three
uh low agita is stick to 5.1
but it's not the only lower based
project stick to this version so
maybe maybe not what is lower jit
uh itself consists of as i said the most
attractive part for myself
is the dynamic assembler it's an
actually it's a preprocessor written in
lua
itself which takes a mixture of
c and assemble code and generate plain c
code which when compiled and executed
generates a binary so it's a kind of
two or three step cross compiling
environment
and it allows an easy dynamic
relocation of those steps either to
cross compile environment or to the
target
and the lower power distribution logic
distribution low power i've mentioned
earlier
provides the same preprocession not only
for the
c code but for the lower court itself so
you
write the mixture of law and assembly
your target assembly code
pre-process it with dynamic assembler
you get the
uh c olu
executable for see your compile it and
run it follow you just run it on the
interpreter is on target on your cross
development host
and you get the binary for your target
architecture and with lure it's possible
to run
all this flow on the target itself
then the virtual virtual machine which
is a compatible
binary compatible by application binary
interface
and byte code compatible with the
standard lua virtual machine
but it's highly optimized and written on
the
hand optimized assembler and compiled
with a dynamic assembler
and then there is a tracing jit compiler
of course dynamic memory management and
collection
garbage collector and uh there are
various extension
models which are a foreign function
interface the
api for the calling the c functions is
the same
for the standard lower and lower j uh
binary bit operations
which are now a part of lieu of 5.3
but initially they were introduced by
the lower jet itself
and of course there is a floating point
support flow itself supports only a
single
type of the number and it's a floating
point
but uh for most uh embedded mcu applica
mcu class applications so embedded
controller applications
uh you can skip all the floating point
all together and make your life
much much easier
current status is a very short
and disappointing one
yes lure itself can be compiled and run
on the both on the
spike simulator and on the
target hardware i have run it on several
i think two or three different soft core
cpus
on two different fpgas family so there
is a solid
base for tests and reference platform to
compare with
both in terms of the accuracy of
implementation correctness of the
implementation
and in performance git repository fork
changes make file changes to support the
new architecture and build environment
so just the basic initial steps
then the git repository contains the all
the
instructions from the base 32-bit
integer
set not much more than that it's just 48
instructions if i'm not mistaken uh
excel
all the assembly macro assembler stuffs
such as the registers
renaming and hanging immediate
arguments and labels relocation handling
is work in progress so pretty much
nothing is working
and everything else so i would say 95
percent of work
is still in the long long running to-do
list
so if anybody is willing to join it and
contribute to it
then you are more than welcome either to
fork it yourself or to send pages
uh as i said the to-do list is much
longer than
current status list so what remains to
be done
is pretty much everything
no need to repeat that but much more
interesting
where we go from here when it's ready
and when we have
this basic core system is broken
uh and those stuffs are really
interesting unfortunately we have to go
through the reporting and the laborious
efforts before we
there uh risk five foundation
reserves the j extension specification
for
the uh g exactly for the jit campaign
languages
the question is that what languages are
currently heavily
are heavily using the jit compilation
the most heavyweight player i would say
are java and javascript
not sure maybe c sharp and obviously
because behind those languages
those environments there are huge
corporations with a lot of
software hardware developers and some
budget behind
definitely they will try to
shape this risk 5 j extension
through the foundation through their
contribution i'm pretty much sure that
they're
not aware of any efforts but pretty much
sure that there are
efforts to support
jit compilation on risk five for all
those things
but uh so the question is uh who
and in what direction will shape this j
extension of risk five
architecture when foundation starts to
work
on it and having a really small
light weights lower jet implementation
might be an interesting test bench and
it would be great to have it before the
extension itself
is specified so we can see
if and how it compares to it then of
course because
we can change not only the hardware but
the cpu itself
and do it dynamically or almost
dynamically
it would be interesting to experiment
with the different hardware assisted
techniques for the jit compilation to
the detect hot traces because the lower
jet compiler
is analyzing the execution threat of the
virtual machine at run time and compile
the hot
passes in this machine and jit compile
hot passes
and some execution counter performance
counters in the cpu
may be helpful to provide these hardware
systems for the hot trace detection
same goes for the
memory management and the garbage
collection with the hardware systems for
it
then the thing which is really
interesting is the
some custom and target application
specific acceleration development
and in this case uh once again the
dynamic assembler would provide
a very uh comprehensive and useful
test and evaluation test and prototype
platform
because you can just specify the new uh
assembly instruction on the
interactively on the lower level and
have it immediately compiled
and have the binary code compiled in it
and directly on the
target so if not in production
environment and when there is everything
is committed to the silicon
but for the soft core cpus and the
interactive development and debugging
of those functionality that would be
really interesting
and since i've already mentioned that 30
years ago fourth
was language of choice for such
experiments
there is nothing that would prevent to
write another force
on the assembler on the dynamic
assembler of lower jade
and then once we have an interactive
fourth shell it takes just in two or
three
screens to write a new assembler on this
fourth
and it looks like i'm going in the loops
now
so uh thank you
for your attention and if you have
anything to contribute
any questions please feel free to
contact to download to scan
thank you
[Applause]
yes any questions
uh so i'm assuming what was the higher
max i'm working on the raptor jet
the another luggage at four and i'm
wondering if you're aware of
what the other forks are doing at the
moment for example
um in wreckages something that we're
working on right now and as
i also going to talk about tomorrow is
we are porting the
byte code interpreter of lua that's
written in assembly
to see we're almost done with that oh so
that would kind of like save you
supporting the uh yes but for the
uh so the question was if i am aware of
what the
other blue jade forks are doing are
not really much aware of that so i've
seen that
rtrk company if i'm not mistaken the
name
they are supporting uh ports of low g to
mips 64-bit and arm v-8
64-bit architectures toronto
they are mostly targeted on optimizing
the performance
for their database application so they i
think they are providing some
functionality which improves the
in-memory database handling and they've
do
they've done it directly in the load
sheet of
then there was some other one but i
you can talk to me either tomorrow or
yeah later today
i can find the link there and on some
publications
lua vella if ah
okay i'm not uh going to elaborate about
this oh
thank you just starting with that and uh
porting the
virtual machine from the lower jit
virtual machine
to from assembler to see yes of course
that would save a lot of pertinent
efforts that would be much easier to put
it but then
probably for the price of optimization
and performance
maybe maybe not uh specifically for the
floating point as far as i know the
logit is making use of uh
non-tagging not sure how we and david
support it in the airport
so think here i think yeah i'm not only
started late but i finished late
two sorry about that and i think it's in
a break now
oh so something all of us are really
[Music]
needed
you