right
next talk please welcome julian who's
going to tell us about profiling in
python thank you
oh okay so sorry so today i'm gonna talk
about uh production
uh profiling for python so if you don't
know me i'm julian
i worked at deladoc for almost a year
now and i've been doing
free software stuff for like 20 years
now um uh
this is a boring statement let's say
that anything that i say today might
change in the future but i have to say
that to you
so um so first i'm going to talk about
what profiling is and what you need it
uh then i'll talk about uh how we build
a dialogue a profiler for production
system that we use internally that we're
going to
provide to our customers in the future
so the first thing to understand is what
profiling is and what
when you need it uh if you never use
profiling
here's the simple answer that it tries
to to solve
as a sort of question so to solve it's
like if i were to ask you
in a program which function or which
line of code is going to be the most
costly the most
time you're going to spend in your
program running and doing that function
of that line of god
it will be probably pretty hard for you
to guess or to to give me an answer
an accurate answer it's really hard to
know when you run
programs in production which endpoint is
going to
spend a lot of time on the cpu
the one line that is going to look at
the most memory in your programs
you might guess but the more complex
your application is going to be
the more complicated it's going to
answer that question
um so the goal of profiling is to
actually get inside your program and
get all of this data and extract it and
be able to say okay this is a stack
trace what i see most of them this is a
stack trace so what i
talk about stack trace is like all of
the functions that are being called
one after the other and being able to
okay this is
what my program is doing and this is
where i need to optimize it to make it
faster
because this is the end goal is to make
to be able to see what your program is
doing and to make
and to make better decisions about where
to spend your time to optimize it
uh this is typically the kind of output
that you will see if you do profiling on
a python program or any kind of program
for that matter
where you see stack traces and when the
width of the rectangle is like the term
spent on cpu or
allocating memory or anything like that
there are two types of profiling the
first one is deterministic profiling
so if you ever use c profile the python
profiler which is built in
since like a long time in python this is
what it does
um and there's another type
of profiling which is what we're going
to talk about today is like the
statistical
profiling where you do things in a
different way which has its own
perks so deterministic profiling if you
never use c
profile or if you don't know it works
it's pretty easy it actually hooks
itself inside python it says to
see python each time you're going to
call and execute a function
i want you to tell me and i will like
not down the time
it is and when you finish to execute the
function you just call me again and i
will note down the time and then i will
compute the difference between the two
times and i will know that which
this function has run for that many
seconds
so that's pretty cool it's pretty easy
to understand but
it has a few issues which is like
you only know the whole times that means
you know
how much sequence your function has
taken but you don't know what it did
like it was it waiting for io was it
doing cpu stack what is it allocating
memory do you have nuclear you just
know that it's been two seconds exiting
the function
the way it works is that it looks itself
on functions which
is the granularity that you will get
from the output so
if your program is just one giant
function we will have nothing
interesting in terms of information and
if your program is fast enough function
or very small function calling each
other it's going to
have so much overhead that your program
is going to be
10 times or 20 times slower when it runs
so it's pretty hard to use c profile in
production system for that reason
because the most
functions you have in your program the
slower it's going to be
um c profile in particular has this one
problem where
in our case it was an issue where it
exports its data
also in a custom file format which is
something like pcl if i remember
correctly
which is not something that is really
easy to use in any other programming
language
so for all of that those reasons it's
impossible to use something like
deterministic profiling and c profile
in production system you can't afford to
have your web server to run 20 times
slower just because you're doing
profiling
the other way of doing profiling is
different is like you're going to run
your program normally you're not going
to change anything
but every now and then like every 10
millisecond or so you're going to
interrupt your program
and to look at what it's doing right now
so what is going to tell you if you do
that
often enough you're going to have
statistically a good representation of
what your program is doing usually
so it's not like the absolute truth
contrary to contrary to something like c
profile which
really meters every call you're just
going to in that case
statistically over a few hours or a few
days of your program running
going to have a number of samples that's
going to show you
um which number of times you see each
stack trace and you're going to have the
kind of output that i showed you earlier
which is roughly statistically accurate
the upside of doing that is that you can
actually measure a lot of different
things like the wall time but also the
cpu charm which tells you
uh if you spend time just doing i o or
actually using the cpu and doing things
like computing results
it has a very low overhead the way it
works is that it
leaves your program doing what it does
usually and does not try to
rub the functions or interrupt them or
whatever it just
know and then execute something in the
background saying okay what is it doing
right now
and that's it uh you were able uh thanks
to to python that is to go
down to the line of code that is being
executed so you're not just
talking about functions but you're able
to see which line of code in particular
is going to be executed in some
languages not python unfortunately you
can go down to the opcode so the precise
like
operation in the line that's not
possible in python yet
unless you split your code a lot and you
can have like
other things like i'll talk about that
later um see
the report against the exception running
in your program that are being raised
and you're able to
see them and to see the control panel
program um
so what i'm going to talk after is what
we did
at datalog implementing this uh before
doing that i spent a lot of time
uh checking the state of the art all the
dozens of python profiles out there
none of them does that a lot of them
actually focus on
their pooch doing fantasy flame chart or
things like that
which is not something i had to solve i
was only interested into getting the
data and exporting them into a proper
data format
so what i'm going to talk about just now
so the first thing i had to say to the
provider to solve was like how do you
get the cpu
and world time information so the way i
saw that
is in a thread so you run a part the
parallel thread in your python program
that slips most of the time let's say
every 10 milliseconds you wake up
and you're going to use the cis dot
current friend which is like a
private function that has been there
forever and that everybody used so it's
not really private
but what this function returns is a list
a dictionary where the key is a thread
and the value is a
stack trace basically so if you do every
10 milliseconds
regularly you're able to each time see
which stack is being executed
on each thread and you're able to
construct a model where you know
like in real time what your program is
doing every 10 milliseconds
uh when you do that you can actually use
uh so that's only
linux specific for this part a function
that is um
thread get cpu clock id which basically
written you a special clock
and in line which measures the cpu time
but each its thread is consuming so
every 10 milliseconds you will be able
to get a stack trace and
actually associate that stack trace with
a number of nanoseconds or milliseconds
of cpu that has been used by the thread
um so at the end you get a pretty good
representation on each of your threads
what they
would do and how much cpu they used uh
you can actually also get the wall charm
because you can use a regular
clock uh so you get this kind of output
where you have the regular so this is an
example of a python program we're like
uh being profiled for one minute with
four threads that's why you may not see
but there's like a four minutes on the
top root
uh span on the top there's like four
minutes of wall time in total because
you got
four threads running for one minute and
you have the detail of
which function has been called in which
thread and if you have the same data
for the cpu time which is like way less
there's only like three seconds or
five seconds cpu time being used and you
see the output looks like a bit the same
you see the same stack traces
but you see that a lot of the functions
are like weight functions that are just
doing nothing so if you were using
something like c profile you would see a
lot of time being spread in the weight
function
which is not really interesting because
it's just a weight function
where if you take a look at the cpu time
using the data you got for the thread
gcpu
clock id you actually get the number of
nanoseconds being used on the cpu and
you can see here for example the weight
function
we don't see them in the in the charts
below
so otherwise as i was saying it's a way
better
way to do profiling in production system
because it has a very low overhead so
for example on my laptop if i
if i am to a profile a python program
with 10 threads
which are which have each one executing
30 function long stack traces
i can pull and generate 100 samples per
second
for only one percent of cpu so it's
i mean it's already a pretty good um
thing to get and it's it's actually can
get a bit cheaper because the way it
works you sleep every like 10
milliseconds but you can actually
increase that amount of sleeping so if
you want to have less impact of your
performance you can dynamically
adapt uh your sleeping time like i was
saying you
are able to get so you need to do a bit
of c for that
but because it's not exposed in python
but you actually able to get the
profiling
exception information so when you
use a block like try accept and it goes
back to a few functions
before being called you can you can see
that in python it's
equivalent of this dot x info you can
catch that and see the control for your
after program
and you can limit the resources i was i
was saying you can basically sleep
uh more often if you need
right now the only downside that we
don't do c profiling so
if you have psiphon module or c module
uh you are not able to see any
information below the python stack
uh that's something i like to do to
solve it uh in an extra release
um we also do memory profiling so for
memory profiling it's way easier because
uh i would say most of the work has been
done already
in python so there's a python module
since
3.4 which is called trace malloc so what
tracemat does
is that it replaces the malloc function
used by
python to allocate the memory and all
the objects that you use in python
by its own wrapper which allocates the
memory but also
make a trace of the allocation and first
metallic is able to export to you
the information about which line of code
uh allocated a memory and like how many
megabytes and let times
it has been called so it's pretty easy
to get this kind of information without
doing too much work
um the problem with trace malloc is that
it's it wraps and it counts every object
location that you do which makes your
program very slow again
so that's not something you can do on
production system if you have to to
if you have a program but there's a lot
of location and gets four times or ten
times slower just because you are
tracing in the allocation it's a problem
so
the trick here is to also do sampling
and doing statistical aggregation of the
results so
the algorithm is pretty simple like you
sleep most of the time
and once in a while you just wake up
activate or deactivate trace malloc to
get the samples or not of memory
location
if you do that like five percent of the
time it's usually okay you only get five
percent of the allocation being tracked
by um trace malloc but over time if you
do out for a few minutes a few hours
you get a pretty good presentation of
your patterns in your application
so it gives you two results as i was
saying the number of allocations that
each of your function does
and the size so the two charts looks a
bit of the same
but i mean the width is going to change
based on if the allocation is going
to allocate bigger objects or not but
this is the kind of process that you
might get at the end with uh
stack traces and the number of megabytes
that you're going to have
are located so pretty easy again to
debug your program to see
what's costly in terms of memory so
that's only like um the allocation that
you do
not the size of the memory you use but
only the number of times you allocate
memory
it doesn't track like when you create or
if you don't use the object anymore
um so right now the limitation of trace
melodic like one thing is that the
overhead it's really slow
really really slow uh i'm not sure right
now
how fast you you can i mean if you can
improve it to make it faster
there's no frame information so the way
it tracks things it's pretty simple you
don't have any contact information about
which way did their location
so you can't map that to any threats and
it's also limited in the
information reports for the cpu
and wall time before it's pretty easy to
get the function name because it's
reported in the stack uh in that case
trace metallic just gives you
the line number and the file so you
don't know which function or which class
you are actually trying to allocate even
which type of
thing you are locating it is pretty um
light in that regard so that's something
i'd like i'd love to
improve in the future another thing
where we do a bit of profiling is
threading
so usually when you do multi-threading
in python so a lot of people don't do
multi-threading because of the global
lock and
how it makes things slow etc but you
still need some time
to have threads running um
you do um application with a lot of
threads you need to synchronize over
something and usually you use a lock
which is like the most basic
uh object you can get in the threading
world in python
and that lock when you have a lot of
thread strain to acquire it
uh you might have contention and it
might make your program slow
uh there are there's nothing in python
to to
basically to give you one kind of
information about is my thread blocking
because it's trying to acquire a lock or
not
uh is it waiting for too long is it
watching forever
wait what is it what is my contention
issue here yeah it's pretty hard to know
so
the way we solve that is we basically
wrap the
threading.log instances so each time you
create a new lock
you actually get a lock which is not a
real lock i mean it's a real lock but
under the hood we
intercept it to see when your plank is
going to acquire it and when it's going
to release it
that makes it possible to actually get
the information about
how many how much time they spent um
trying to acquire the lock or how much
time they spent acquiring the lock like
being the lord being held by one of the
threats
so you get a lot of information for
example you get the total lock aquarium
wait time
so this is the number of milliseconds
usually not that long
but your program is trying to wait it's
going to wait to acquire that lock
so with this kind of information you're
able to see that you may need more luck
or to
um just put your program different parts
to not use only one lock with several
locks etc
you can get all of this information to
be able to redesign your program which
is
not always easy and possible but
sometimes it is and you get all of that
with the different threads that try to
acquire the different clocks
um so once we build all that
we had to export all the data to use
them
uh which is a its own challenge
so like i was saying c profile has its
own custom format not really interesting
to not useful for us
there is one format which is pretty used
in the world which is a calgarian format
so it comes from the background program
which just profiling for c
um and it has in on text-based uh format
that you can use to export data
the problem is that it's it's text
basically so it's not really like it's
easy to consume but it's not
really efficient in any way and
so that's another good solution for us
like i was saying a lot of python
profiler
then directly export html so
that never gave us any clue on how to
export to something that you can use for
any other program uh until we're from
tproff
so if you don't know pprof it's a lot of
things
the name of the of the profiler that is
in the go programming language
uh it's also the name of the tool they
use to display the data and it has the
name of the format so it's like the same
word for three different things
um so the p prop format is pretty cool
because that's what you can use for if
you do go and go profiling you can
export all of your data in prof format
so it's a format based on protobuf so it
makes it pretty easy to
understand there's a schema with all the
fields documented etc
it's easy to use and protobuf is easy to
use in python too
it's very fast to to serialize so it
would be a shame to be
a i mean to try to be fast gathering all
the data about your python program and
then
being very slow about exporting it so so
that's that's not a problem
the way the people format works is not
going to export everything that you
gather like every sample with every
timestamp
etc it's going to aggregate all of that
so you're going to compute the sum the
average the minimum whatever you need
and export all of that with the stack
traces in your
format at the end and it's pretty space
efficient so there's a pretty simple
model of a string pool where
all your string because you have a lot
of repetition usually like all the
functions you're going to see
are always the same the spectres are
going to be most of the time the same so
all of that is pretty well uh i'd say
organized in the schema
and it's just zipped by default so
pretty fast to generate pretty slow i
probably software they're pretty small
to store
for example on average we use
20 kilobytes of storage to store
one minute of profiling for one python
process so pretty easy to store
even for a few hours or a few days
so prof is also the name of the tool
that you can install pretty easily uh
if you know a bit of a go but it's not
that hard so
it's able to generate this kind of flame
chart
which is on top left where you see all
the stack traces and the width is going
to be either
the size of the location that you do in
memory the time you spend on cpu etc
depending on the status that you
gathered or you can also use
this kind of uh chat on the r with each
rectangle is going to be one function
and everything is going to be connecting
by the number of times they called
each other etc so it's pretty hard to
read when you're not used to it but if
you
i promise if you spend like a few
minutes on it and prof is pretty easy to
gather
and to understand so it's easy to use
it you can open an ep profile with it
being go or python or anything
so what we did uh a data log is uh as an
open source library
which is not yet public just because
like for them is too early but i'm
working on it
uh it's going to be integrated into you
know into our tracer
uh library which is already open source
so the profiling part is going to be
integrated into that and if you want to
use it like you're not using datalog
it's fine because it also supports
exporting the
data to a prof file files
even s so you'll be able to use it
directly
and to export all the design p prop and
use the tool uh
i show uh just uh before
uh so as i said it's not released yet so
if you want to know what literally is uh
you can follow me on twitter or anything
and i'll be able to announce it should
be in a few weeks
no promise but i hope so and that's it
we have four means for questions
okay
you