okay
hello everybody welcome to foster the
lightning talk session
i want to introduce you alexandrio with
um talk about prototyping the internet
of things with
willowdryne studio i hope i
sleep it's close closely okay sue will
give us more introduction to this topic
thank you for stages
thank you so hello everybody my name is
alex
i teach computer science at the
polytechnic university in bucharest
mostly to computer science students and
some computer science track to
non-computer science students
um i'm going to talk about why the dream
studio a project that we started about
five years ago with the purpose of
bringing
prototyping and hardware programming
closer to students
the idea was that everything is going to
run software
actually not only is trying to run not
only that it's going to run software
it's going to be connected to the
internet
so it will not matter in which field
you will work you will have to know some
basics of computer science it's becoming
more and more like mathematics
mathematics is used everywhere
computer science will be used everywhere
so it's automotive robotics
um manufacturing it doesn't matter
the problem is how do you introduce
computer science and how do you help
people that didn't study computer
science
to use it and that that's a challenge um
part of the solution was arduino and is
arduino
um i'm guess everybody is familiar with
this board
but they actually did is take a device
which was rather common
in computer science and engineering and
make it easy to use for everybody
it's easy to connect it has a super
simple programming interface and
everybody can write a program with 10
lines of code and make something blink
so that's great the problem is it's
the device is limited so we're talking
about connectivity and arduino is not
exactly
well well you did for connectivity and
if you go to more
processing arduino again is not the best
solution
so um somebody in the uk came out with
this
which is the raspberry pi i hope
everybody is familiar with it
which is great absolutely great low cost
super well to use for students and for
prototyping
if you can connect the keyboard the
screen and the mouse
so as long as you can do this and use it
as a computer
that's super fine um
now the problem is what happens if the
board is inside the device
if you want to build a robot a car it's
on top of a building
so you want to use it for something more
electronics like
your raspberry pi is not going to be
accessible with the cr screen and the
keyboard
so this becomes increasingly difficult
the steps to program a raspberry pi
which is not
available with the mouse and the
keyboard is
you need to have some networking
knowledge find an ip address
ssh into it use some text
based editor compile it and run it
and if this sounds really easy for
people that
think of this or this it's really
difficult for people that did not study
computer science
or maybe are in fine arts in finance
they need to do a statue for instance
they want to make it interact with you
on facebook it's difficult with
ssh so taking the example of arduino
um we designed a piece of software an
open source software called while dream
studio
which is a one click software
programming for devices
like the raspberry pi just to go through
it
it has a simple interface so the
simplest way is just a text editor where
you can write some code
connect to your device so you hit the
connect button if the device is in your
local network
it will show up here if your device is
remotely
we have a web server which connects you
to the device
um or if you have a serial port and the
serial cable the device will pop up on
one of the serial ports
once you're connected you have a run
button this is all you need to do
so the software while loading studio
takes care of
copying your project to the pi compiling
it if necessary
running it and giving you some feedback
um
this is the basic process on programming
a pi
way easier than ssh ip addresses
logins and so on we tried to translate
the software in
several languages these are the
languages that we support so far
we would love some translators so if you
think this is a cool project it would
really help us if you can submit the
translation
or maybe complete some of the
translations that we have there
um if you want to do a little bit more
we have an advanced
interface where you can have a tree for
your project so you can upload some
files
most of the programming will be done in
one five programs
some people really need more so this is
another option
some people have asked us okay we don't
have a pie how do we do this
so we somehow reversed engineered
fritzing
it was not maintained until half a year
ago
and we are able to load some simple
fritzing designs
and simulate them actually simulate them
we don't simulate electronics we have
some of the apis in javascript so you
can write simple javascript programs
and this simulator will show them up
or we have been asked to do device
emulation so
if your system supports qmo you can
emulate the raspberry pi
one
these are basically some of our users
mostly universities
um it's also toronto public library used
it
a public library in bucharest used it i
think coder dojo used it for some
hackathons
so more or less these are our users
um while it in studio is at the third
version
this is a plugable um system so
we've built it the third time it's
basically a plug-in architecture
um it can be extended really really
easily um
it's fairly documented let's say so
we're looking for contributors
for the moment um we can support
raspberry like
raspberry pi like devices so anything
that runs linux
we can support uh an nxp chip called
rapid iot
as editors we supported monaco google
blockly for python
and we had an industrial project and we
needed opc ua
so we built an opc ua model editor
as languages we have python node.js
shell and the visual programming
language
but it's extensible so adding a language
is just writing another plugin
we have the simulators and emulators we
have a dashboard for graphing
it's mostly for debugging we have a
notebook
so if you know jupiter notebook
it's similar but for using it on the
raspberry pi
and for users that need some more
control we have a shell
so they can shove into their device
um the bottom line is we have a platform
that is super easy to use
at least for beginners um it's not for
writing rocket science programs but it's
super
good for prototyping it's fully gdpr
compliant
um and it's super easy to extend these
are the devices that we support so far
it comes in two flavors you can either
download an application
it's a web application it's an electron
package for windows linux
and mac os or we have a web application
it's exactly the same code base just
built for the browser
and you could use it directly online um
you can use our server
or you can just download the code and
run your own server
so all the data that is stored on the
online version is stored on the local
storage on the browser local storage so
it's
fully gdpr compliant basically the web
server
is just serving a static local
application that runs in your browser
um it's fully open source written in
javascript
actually for electron we license it
under apache to zero license
so um anybody can contribute use it
change it
so on and so forth um we're looking for
contributors so if you like the project
um we are really really happy to talk to
you about contributions
translators that's another thing so
our group speaks about seven languages
together but
we surely need more and um
because we all have day jobs like we
work at university and students
learn at university we are looking for
sponsors
thank you very much this is our website
and that's our github repository
if you have any questions i'll gladly
answer thank you
[Applause]
questions