hi everyone
welcome to this talk my name is john i'm
an open source engineer at packages
and during the next 25 minutes we are
going to talk about the web
in my opinion the web is an amazing
platform
and i think that we can all agree on one
fact is that
it the web has evolved a lot since its
beginning
we went from sending simple text over a
wire
to providing a full experience to the
end user
and i think one key component within the
web that has brought this
experience is javascript
right but so
javascript built in 1985 uh shipped
within the netscape browser was aiming
to provide some dynamism
to the static content of the web but
what we were trying to achieve with
javascript that time it's
a much more much smaller part of what we
are doing with it
now so the way that it was executed at
that time is quite different from the
way it is executed nowadays so
at that time javascript was interpreted
okay
and to take a closer look at what
interpretation is is
for example here we have in the middle
our interpreter
javascript okay and on the right side we
have kind of like the
bare metal machine the cpu on the left
we have a bunch of javascript code lines
calling add functions passing numbers
and when the execution hits the first
line the line is sent
to the interpreter the interpreter does
his job okay
evaluates both parameters their type
what we are trying to achieve
and then output some matching code that
gets directly executed by the cpu
next line sim process again evaluating
both parameters
saying what kind of types they are and
then outputting
some matching code and the thing here
that this mechanism
worked until kind of 2005 when big
javascript apps started to come onto the
scene and one example is
uh google maps which which
uh browser started to hit kind of like a
performance issue with those javascript
apps and why because at the end
doing a simple addition in javascript
is not trivial you have to check
both operands types and regarding their
their regarding the evaluation you you
will output some different
code so you cannot really count on the
language
by itself you have to wait until runtime
so one of the mechanism that
browsers applied to solve this issue
it's a very well-known mechanism which
is called
just in time compilation and if we take
back the same example
we still have both uh items there but
you have a third one a third component
within the system which is the just in
time compiler
okay we take again the same lines first
line is sent to the interpreter
it does the same evaluates interpret it
output some matching code and that's it
second line same process evaluate it
both parameters and then output some
machine code
but this time the interpreter
has monitored the code and the execution
and it has some feedback about the
execution so it
can see that okay we try to execute
twice the same function
passing twice numbers
why don't so it marks that function
as hot and then pass it to the just in
time compiler
to compile it and output some
the same machine code that it was
previously outputted
store it somewhere else somewhere in
memory and
lock that memory region so we cannot
override it
third line comes to execute it and then
there the interpreter say okay i know
this add function it's not the first
time
i just ask the just in time compiler to
com
to compile it and put it somewhere in
memory so
all still are still both parameters
numbers yes okay you can then take the
one that i just compiled it
and directly execute it and if you see
this
here what we have done what the the
engine have done is just that
he made a shortcut for the execution of
a function
and we call that the fast path okay
and that's when javascript gave us his
top speed
and just to show you the difference
between non-jittered code so
non-gta javascript and gta javascript i
just launched an
instance of chrome disabling the
optimization of javascript
and you can see for eight robot denser
it's kind of laggy on the left side
but on the right side it's kind of going
very well you can even i think
i increased until 15 and it's still okay
but then
well we had the performance issue with
javascript
with interpretation we compile it and it
works
pretty well why don't we why do we want
to go further
well the thing is that i didn't tell you
the whole story
if we go back to example and this time
i'm
sending instead of two numbers one
string and one number
the interpreter will try again to say
okay i know this function
i just store it somewhere but
although are still those two parameters
numbers nope so what he's done he's
doing
is that he's going to fall back to
interpretation and
erase the compiled version that he had
yeah super animation
so at the end what's the problem with
javascript well i mean
not the problem i don't wanna offend it
i'm sorry
i'm sorry i didn't what's the thing
what javascript is lacking to be
optimized before execution
well javascript is just lacking
predictability if you take the same
version the same i mean two versions of
the same code one written in c and
another in javascript
you can clearly see that in c the
language provides some hints to the
compiler
so he can optimize code before runtime
when if you look at the javascript side
there's not much going on there
even the number of parameters are not
really
fixed so you can pass more than two if
you want
so if we quickly recap what we learned
here or
no maybe what we have to so we opt
we can optimize javascript and it's cool
and you can have
really good performance with it's no
problem but the thing is that javascript
is not predictable
so the industry browsers
have tried to solve this problem uh
i mean to solve that to fix this and
they try to run
some more predictable code within the
browser and one of the initiatives is
for example
portable native client from google which
was to
to run some some c plus plus
modules within the browsers send boxes
so
it's secured but it didn't really
took off after that multi-lab
came with an idea of just taking a
subset of javascript which was
more predictable um with and they call
it
they called they call it sn.s but
it wasn't enough because it was still
javascript at the end
and in 2015
browsers reunited and tried to come up
with something that they
could agree on to go a step further to
push the limit of the webs
and that's where web assembly came onto
the scene and what is web assembly if we
take
quickly just the the text from the
official page which is quite dense
i'm going to read it so webassembly
abbreviated wasm
is a binary instruction format for stack
based virtual machine
was designed as a portable target for
compilation of high level languages like
c
c plus plus rust enabling deployment on
the web for client and server
application
a lot of things huh we are going to try
to
read it again but step by step so
webassembly aggregate it wasn't
is a binary instruction format so it
just means that it's a set of
instructions
encoded in a binary way so it's quite
efficient to load it
designed as a portable target for
compilation so two things here
um portable it means that webassembly is
not just designed for the web
but it's also designed to run outside
the web on other platforms
and target full compilation means that
you don't have necessary to write
webassembly it's quite low level
you are more kind to you're more likely
to write in
higher level languages like c c
space rust go c sharp java
whatever and you compile to webassembly
so how the process goes simply you take
a bunch of files cc prospects here i
just
okay i mentioned just c and c you
compile it to intermediate
intermediate a representation
it's almost always llvm i will skip the
details about llvm
okay but normally this part is quite
hidden from the developer perspective
okay
and then you compile as a backend
compilation
to a simple dot was in this case it's
the name but
it wasn't module okay and uh with uh
which tool for example one of the
main tools to compile to webassembly is
same script which
first mission mainly mission is to
provide to bring other languages
on the plat on the web so then how do
you consume this simple that wasm
well you fetch the resource i think you
all know this
you fetch the resource and then you just
call the javascript api webassembly apis
that are
nowadays available in all all the
browsers the major browsers
and then you receive um uh you receive
uh
was a module which you can call function
on it
here exported thing and those functions
were originally written in another
language
so what are the goal of webassembly
webassembly wants to be performant
run at nearly native speed after that
webassembly wants to be portable okay so
not only running on on the web but also
running in other platforms
and secure secure by default it's one of
the main concerns
of webassembly being more secure than
javascript
performance well
i might disappoint you but javascript is
not i mean sorry web assembly is not
so much faster somewhere more faster
than
super optimized compiled javascript
at the end they quite run early at
native space
space speed sorry but the thing is that
um javascript
i mean webassembly will more likely to
stay on the fast path
when you have an optimized version of it
while
javascript will kind of de-optimize
easily and falls back to interpretation
and for to illustrate my point here you
have
a multiple just diagram showing multiple
execution of the same code in javascript
and then the same code in webassembly in
blue webassembly is faster okay
but the point here is to show that for
multiple execution of the same code in
javascript you don't have
you cannot predict the performance well
in web assembly is quite
almost the same
also was can be decoded validated and
compiled in a fast
single pass equally with either just in
time or ahead of time compilation
if you check how um javascript is
handled within a browser
you first fetch the whole resource and
then you parse it compile it
and execute it all that in the main
thread
there are some exceptions okay not
everything happens
sometimes in the main thread but that's
kind of the regular way of doing it
but browsers handle webassembly in
another way
so while fetching the packets while
fetching the resource
wasn't modules the browser will
directly compile the bytes dark on the
fly
and when it and when it when it's done
it will execute
on the main thread and the compilation
doesn't happen on the main track so it
does not block
users
just to show you the difference of
performance you have 30
robot dancer here and you can see that
javascript is quite laggy
when you switch the execution to
webassembly
it goes back to normal and you can even
increase the number and i'm going
i'll go there until i think 120
but you will not see the difference
because the screen is too short yeah
okay so portable um at the beginning was
was uh meant the first version of was it
was meant to to to at least
work work on the browser so
the way of execute was was to uh provide
some
gs glue code that when a wasn't module
was trying to do something that the
browser couldn't handle
at least the javascript will handle the
code and
simulate something emulate something for
example calling a file system you cannot
call file
system within the browser so when folks
try to
run wasm outside of the of the browser
what they tried to do is just to run the
existing was a module
outside the browser and um so they were
kind of emulating
gs gs glue code that was emulating a
system interface so it's
not really the well the most optimized
way to do it
so a need of as much as
wasm is a language for a conceptual
virtual machine
it needed a system interface a standard
and standardized system interface for
conceptual operating system
that's when webassembly system interface
came onto the scene
it's just a specification that runs
that that webassembly modules can call
to make some system api is called kind
of it's just an operating system it's
not it's let's say it's kind of like a
posix
way of doing okay so then
the diagram becomes like that you have
the non-browser or browser runtime
that implements wazi and provide expose
some sys system interface api that one
modules can interact with
i wanted to show you one tweet
of uh solomon hacks which is the from
the
founder of uh docker that's that is
saying that if wasn't
was existing in 2008 we wouldn't have
needed to create a docker
that's how important it is it is
webassembly
on the server is the future of computing
a standardized
system interface was the missing link
let's hope wazi
is up to the task also folks from
clever cloud a french company that is i
think here
maybe you have met them uh are running
function as a service in web assembly
directly
on the hype advisor so no operating
system between
the the code and uh the
the hardware okay
webassembly wants to be secure by
default
nowadays when you code uh
it's the the the result set of binaries
is just 20 your that your code and 80
dependencies that you haven't written um
then what happened is that the way that
we execute programs nowadays is just
they execute
within the ambient authority so me as an
admin of my
machine i'm going to uh ask my program
to run and then i'm going to provide
him my whole set of keys the permissions
that he can
so he can run maybe he doesn't need it
but it's okay i just wrote the code so i
know it does it will not
do some malicious things the problem is
that
it also passed the whole set of keys to
their its dependencies okay
and sometimes you have a malicious
dependency
okay so that malicious dependency can
then use
all the rights that you provide to
execute
some malicious code webassembly wants to
execute itself as uh uh capability-based
systems
so it means that i still have this whole
set of keys but when i'm going to run
the whole program i'm not going to pass
all the permissions i'm just going to
pass the permissions that i think my
program needs to perform his task
okay so uh i'm just passing here uh
kind of one key and then this key is
passed to all the other dependencies but
this time the malicious code
is quite blocked and cannot really
perform the malicious task
also one abstraction that the
webassembly wants to provide
is called nanoprocesses so the
the idea here is to execute compelling
modules
wasn't modules in this in the same
uh in the same process so
kind of the result is kind of like that
so you have the whole process which is
like the big
box blue box and then inside you will
have like the first one is
like your main module the one that you
have written and uh
uh it has dependencies to other models
but they all run within kind of in the
same
box it way and they think that they are
alone within the
the memory space the process it's it's
just a software
fault implement uh the isolation
so why uh was
wants to be secure because first it
provides capability-based systems
also it's sandboxed by default okay so
you can run
low-level code in a secure way and also
it nano processes provide a way to um
to communicate between uh different
modules
a lot lot much faster than uh
inter-process communication okay
and the end result is kind of like that
so you write your first uh you write
your main module
in for example russ and then you consume
some dependencies that were originally
written in
other languages like c plus plus go
and so on i mean there are a lot they're
not only these languages huh
um there are a lot of more but voila
so projects
i just took two examples there are a lot
okay but you can check
as you are all javascript developers uh
i wanted to show you ascend script which
is just
it's a subset of typescript that does
not compile to javascript or transpiled
to javascript but
compiles directly to was modules and web
assemblies
okay and because i'm a.net guy
i wanted to show you i'm also the net
guy
i wanted to show you um that you can run
now
uh the clr so the
dotnet with on the browser through
webassembly
and they provide now kind of a framework
which is quite similar
like angular to write front-end
applications
uh in seashore go check this link it's
really interesting
there are a lot of things and that guy
ambasso
i think he's italian and he's doing
a c plus plus front-end library to write
a front-end application that compiles
two web assembly
and it has also provide kind of like gs6
syntax for c plus plus
it's super interesting
the bad code aliens
so big companies reunited
and try to push webassembly and secured
by default web
and they call themselves bad code aliens
they are these are the four
uh founders of the aliens and uh
you see pretty big names and just to
tell you fastly is running
ten percent of the internet and i will
end up my talk with
uh one quote that i think it's can kind
of
resume what i feel about webassembly
is that webassembly is the first fast
multi-language retargetable
and safe intermediate representation
that we have
that we have ever agreed upon as a
community
cto office voila thank you
okay any questions
uh i have a question about not just so
in node.js
you can run uh native sql sql yes of
course and you can run
what do you think is better uh
to run a node.js vasim or simpleplus and
why
it's a question that a lot of folks are
asking um
to be honest i think that uh for now
it's c plus plus
that will continue to be like the major
solution to uh
to provide native performance within
node modules but
at the end it will switch to web
assembly modules uh because
i don't know in my humble opinion i
think it's kind of like the future
of the industry or in this perspective
um but they all both fix
solves your issues which is giving you
performance
and so on hi
um webassembly is a fairly young
language
do you have an overview of the tools and
debugging tools around it because as
it's a binary format
i guess it's a little bit harder to
debug than let's say vanilla javascript
yes okay so uh there are already i think
some
browsers that provide uh debugging tools
uh to work with webassembly modules
uh you have i think within mods uh
mozilla firefox
you can already kind of work with it and
and
the thing is that i didn't mention and
you're right
webassembly has two representation it
has the one that
uh browsers use to uh to execute it
which is the binary format because it's
load efficient and so on
but for human readable it's it's not the
most human readable
format so they also have a text uh
representation which is
webassembly uh text i think what
or something it's called what um
and then you can really clearly see that
it's low level
kind of like an assembly code
uh i have a question about the micro
front end
and how assembly will do in in this in
this architecture
assembly yeah web assembly what we're
saying we're doing which architecture in
the micro front end
the micro front architecture okay
um webassembly
are quite i mean it's composed of
several modules
so if your concern is to say uh
do i have to download the whole module
big big big module to execute it
no you can kind of split it and and in
the in the future you will able to
you will be able to lazy load it so
yeah i think you can already do that now
to be honest because at the end as you
see
as you saw i mean you're just fetching a
resource on the internet and then
you can fetch it whenever you want if
it's
yes i will say yes yes there is no
really they're not competing i mean if
they are loaded into your browser you
can run it
on both sides but maybe you will
struggle a bit to
make them work together but i think it's
completely
feasible of course okay is web assembly
about to access to the gpu okay
so uh this talk that i've done it's
normally
much much larger and i'm covered other
topics
uh one thing that so your question is uh
is it possible to call
some gpu apis from the webassembly
uh right now no because the only thing
that provides uh
that uh that is standardized is wazi
which is kind of like a
system interface to call some uh
the os apis the thing is that uh wazi
wants to extend
itself and so you in the future uh you
would be able to call some specific
domain specific uh low-level apis
can for example gpus okay or you will
be able to call i i don't know something
related to blockchain or whatever so
go check wazi go check out the internet
what it's really they're
they really want to extend themselves
and and they're open to feedback from
the community
thank you so much thank you
[Applause]
he might be available just outside for
questions yes
the exit