hi
um i'm atish i work for also work for
western digital
and uh i'm here to talk about the
booting in risk five
what's current state and what's the road
ahead uh
for the booting flow in disc five and
before
we start um just wanted to get a feel
like
how many of you think like having a
standard booting is
necessary for any platform especially
for risk five
where it's growing right so yeah
my question is still continuing so you
can raise your hands
yes both
good because we do not want a diff so
especially in booting land we don't
different or being unique
doesn't bring value it brings chaos
being standard being boring actually
brings value because
if a user knows how to build a how to
boot a
x86 alarm system he should be able to or
which she should be able to
build a desktop system that's the whole
uh
agenda of the talk is we want to make it
more standard and standard so we want to
follow more open source
as open source as possible and follow
the protocols
or methods that already open source
systems
already uses so is a brief agenda
of the talk that i'll be going through
and
starting the talk so here is a brief
uh most commonly used embedded boot flow
a multi-stage boot flow where you can
have
a different open source and all of them
are
actually open source and that's how all
of the embedded uh
world actually works so you can have a
different combination of it and you can
definitely run it
but that's what the recommended wood
flow is where actually you can go ahead
and
run your software so to start with first
would be your zero state bootloader
which basically does
load the next one gets executed from the
rom that's what whenever the power on
reset that's what get get started
next is the first is bootloader which
basically
uh runs also as a loader loads has the
cash should have the capability to load
all the next stages something like the
next runtime service provider next
uh the real bootloader or for the matter
uh
linux as well but um
given the what software open source
project we're using
it may be doing actually doing that or
may not be doing that
so currently uh in risk five land there
is fsbl which is a
type specific one there is you boot spl
which is the
uh secondary program load from you boot
and then there is core boot
which does that job then there is a
runtime service provider which would
which is the only uh
software piece run actually resident
after linux boot so
when actually linux boots all of those
other pieces
basically overwritten because we don't
need them but we need the runtime
service pro
because that's what the os actually need
anything that needs to communicate
down stream with the firmware that's
where the runtime service provider comes
in
and open spi currently uh provides that
for risk 5
then there is uboot which acts as a last
test bootloader
so lasted bootloader which mostly you
actually see like where you configure
your menu or uh
actually boot linux and uh the other
bootloader so these are the already
upstream available that's why it's
there there is also grub which would
eventually be fit in here
which would also be act as a last stage
bootloader and then
uh currently core boot doesn't
can boot technically you would but
directly just loads linux and then loads
up on sbi
so and then it asks openness way to jump
to linux you put spl
also board loads open space you boot and
then
you can switch to jump to you boot from
opensba and then
get to linux from you boot using your
mmc or
network anything so this basically
summarizes what all
soft open source software projects we
use for boot loading
boot and for booting and then where
the status is is this slide we'll talk
about
what's the current upstream status so
you boot and
core boot status uh has been pretty
pretty solid
uh the recently the youboot spl patches
started uh
landing in so we already have handy
stick patches
we already have qme patches high five
unless patches are already
in the mailing list should be much soon
code boot is pretty good as well both of
them uses
open sbi format dynamic there is new kid
in the block
orbot ran has a talk after my talk which
would be talking about orbot then there
is open sbi
this is the release version and the
stats
you can go to the open space project and
figure out where is the release version
and all currently we are at 0.5
and there is little kernel which is a
bootloader for android
and i recently noticed that they also
have support for
x5 does that mean there will be android
on risk 5
i don't know i'm not claiming anything
whoever has done you can ask them
maybe one day we are all here for risk 5
world domination so
why not so so these
uh now i explained
which all software pieces are there what
software projects are
used in the boot loading and uh what's
the state
so we're pretty much in good step except
uv and grub which will eventually
have some slides at the end but the
other part
uh that we are trying to modify is
so in a in a modern era system there are
multi
every system is a multiprocessor mostly
so
the other part of is how does each cpu
actually enters into different multi
stages and then actually
lands in boots linux so
currently is used as a random booting
when i say random booting all of those
is hard cpus
or risk 5 as favorably called hearts
so hardware threads so actually
randomly jumps into linux and i'll
explain how does it work
so for the future slides yellow box
linux kernel
green box bootloader there is no
relation with
why the color is being chosen it's
because my color scents are really bad
so there is bootloader linux kernel
assuming there are let's say
four hearts in the system and when it
tries to
boot linux all of them jump to linux
together
so since all of them jump together there
has to be arbitration so
one gets chosen to be this uh
the booting heart all other what do they
do they just
keep on waiting until this heart
actually does all the kernel
installation
and actually then wakes up uh actually
configure
the power cp variable so that these are
can proceed
so once it does the kernel installation
it actually goes and sets the stack
pointer for
each cpu and then they go and proceed
so simple enough it keeps the boot code
simple
and nothing really issues with it
is it do you see any issues with it yes
what's the bootloader issue to
initialize some devices so which
which cpu in the blogger initializes
like
the power management ics yes
yeah so what happens is each bootloader
has to now
uh initialize uh all the devices and
then they have to do it for
smp so imagine with one bootloader it's
okay
but imagine there are like multiple boot
loaders so what happens then
let's say i have like two stage
bootloader now now every stage
the same thing will happen every stage
there will be multi-core
then one there will be a lottery there
will be a one core will be going forward
and then waiting
all other course would be waiting so
what happens is let's say
it doesn't matter uh so the stage number
it doesn't matter
it's not corresponding to what actual
stage is for now it's just an
illustration purpose
so let's say first all of them enters
into stage one
or stage two doesn't matter then one
gets chosen
all of them waits again that heart
sends an ipi to wakes them up after it
does all the installation as you said
all the driver installation then all of
them actually
wakes up from an interrupt then all of
them again jumps to the second stage
again one gets chosen it can be any
heart so it doesn't have to be the first
heart
that gets so every stage it can be a
random hat
then that again sends an ipa other are
waiting
it comes out of the ipi then it all of
them together again jumps to linux and
then you know the process how it
uh processes the linux so that's the
problem as we
have more stages this gets complicated
the other issue is now all the hearts
are in linux actively running and there
is no way to
tell there is no way for linux to
actually return the heart to the
uh the bootloader the runtime service
provider
that complicates your cpu hot plug and k
exact
so for k exec what happens is uh it
stops all the hearts
and then one heart boots another kernel
when it boots another kernel all other
hearts if you are managing it in the
kernel
then you have to yes at the same time
you are keeping that kernel resident
code
and also you are booting another kernel
so you have to manage that code and you
have to we make sure that the other
kernel doesn't override the memory
similarly hot plug you have to manage
the hearts in the interrupt
sorry manage the interrupts in kernel
while uh
stopping the hearts and then while
bringing up we have to bring it up
in kernel which is not exactly stopping
the heart because supervisor has still
access to the
those hearts so other alternate approach
uh
to how does the heart boot actually is
uh ordered booting
so most of the other i says other
architectures have already
implemented this this is the standard we
are booting where one heart goes through
all the way to linux
and then it brings up all the hearts one
by one which simplifies cpu hot plug
and k exec uh pretty much because
now in cpu hot block k exec or normal
booting
all of them uses similar approach all of
them
use the not similar exactly same code
path
the former keeps the one heart a
let one heart go and keeps all other
heart and then whenever you need to
start a stop
all of them return to the former and
then it you can start and stop
using some calls which i'll be
explaining later
now uh so how does the order booting
looks like
same uh let's say this bootloader and
linux kernel
there is two stages now the
the first stage uh will have a lottery
because
otherwise you have to assign saying that
this is my boot heart which is
may not be available that heart number
may not be available in a system so
one lottery is okay then that heart gets
chosen as the boot heart
is and all of them actually goes and
wait there
that hat actually goes and proceed to
all of the stages
so it goes to the next stage that
continues to the linux
linux actually does all the installation
then
it now it's ready to bring all the
hearts so it makes a call
to the firmware or to the runtime
service provider
then it receives that call that's when
it sends the ipis
to the hearts actually waiting there
and then all of them heart wakes up and
now
all these stage middle stages which are
not anymore resident in the code so we
do not have to
modify anything related to smp in those
stages
and then all the other hearts know where
to jump to linux it directly jumps and
then starts
running linux so
that's the advantage of ordered booting
and that's how the order booting will
work
now uh another advantage is
let's say you want to add one more stage
the other state doesn't have to do
anything the other stage
you that hat only jumps to instead of
jumping to linux
it just jumps to the next stage it does
whatever
that stays need to do and then it jumps
to linux
and then the entire process remains same
so the question was how do the other
stages do the lottery right
oh because they are not now receiving uh
they're not getting all the hearts all
the hearts are not
available there so it's only one heart
going forward so they do not have to do
lottery
okay so how do we do
the bring up bringing up and
close stopping the hearts from the
firmware with the
new set of sbi calls the i'll not go
through the details
it's available in the spec uh it's
already merged
so and the patches are also available in
the open
open sb and linux kernel patches are
already in the mailing list
so you can take a look and uh give
feedback
i just recently posted so with that
uh ordered booting feature the biggest
issue
we had not biggest but the one of the
issue we had is how do we maintain
backward compatibility
because now you have older software
running doing random booting
with all the boot loaders actually
trying to do the lottery thing
and then with the newer software is not
anymore do not want them to do it
so this is the backward compatibility
table
if you are using open sbi or linux
kernel master you are good you will
obviously get the order booting
if you are using any of the older
version of open sbi
then with or without hsn patches it will
detect that
it does not have the hsm
extension so it will just go back to the
default
random booting same thing if you are
using bbl or any other older
very old open spa which is older than
0.5
it will also fall back to the random
booting but if you are using
master branch of open spi which will
have openness
the hsm patches and you are using linux
kernel without
hsn patches then you will only get one
code because
now the linux kernel thinks that of hsm
extension is supported
but it's actually not implemented linux
kernel basically
is not making those calls so you will
not get smp booting so if you want to
use openspa master
you have to use the linux kernel patches
and it's not current master so there
will be
we are waiting for the spec sba spec to
be merged
uh the replacement extension and 0.2
once that's done
release 0.6 so 0.6 will be without hsn
patches
and anything beyond 0.6 will have hsn
so you should go and pick up the master
of both kernel
and open sbi to have
uh order booting and then cpu hot block
exec which will follow
now the last piece as i uh promised in
the beginning
is uh ufe uh so
thanks to alex uh abner uh the edk2
uh if we already it's almost uh getting
merged
uh there's a talk by leaf uh today
afternoon
that we'll discuss more details on this
uh you would grab support has already
been there
like for a long time the only missing
piece was efi stub
which uh i got it working like a couple
of weeks ago so
it basically puts a efi linux header on
a peak of header on top of linux image
header
so it fakes linux image as a efi
executable to the
uh whatever the your loader so edk2 or
u-boot
so that's how it basically treats it as
a
you can boot linux using uh entire uv
protocol
now with all these features the one
thing we also want to be
like as i said standardization is
important so we also want to
get into the ebb r compliance so as per
uh my understanding ebb r is a
specification that
allows interoperability between
different hardware platforms so once
your hardware platform conforms to
ebbr you know that for sure you have
these many features and this is how you
boot
so as for the technical requirements we
are almost there have to implement
we have to implement the runtime
services few of them and then or
just say that we are not supporting
runtime services but that feature has to
be there
other than that startup protocol and the
startup protocol is basically
all the hearts booting the flow i
explained
and then the former storage which
requires you to be on gpt partition
and we already have gpu you are already
using jupiter patterson
the part i'm not sure and i'm hoping
i'll talk to some folks and get it
clarity
is not technically political
maybe logistics uh because it's hosted
in
um software and the copyright has
unlimited contributors so i'm not sure
whether we
can get into that so i have to
open to discussion how do we get that
work
yes i'm done so there's a so for the
future work we need to upstream the
patches we need to upstream the spec
and then once all those are done
hopefully we can make the vbr compliant
and then do a kxac and cade up
implementation
which would be nice to have all those
features
and help you debugging so i guess i'm
done
yes okay i had a demo but i guess i'm
running out of time so if you want to
see the uv boot
i've been running so you can talk to me
after the talk and you can
i can show you thanks
you