all right then
uh welcome to our first group talk of
the day
uh please welcome with me alex on rook
intro and what's new
thank you um well first of all
if technology works as we want so um i'm
alexander
i'm a devops engineer at claudical i'm
one of the rook maintainers
and well certified kubernetes
administrator
um so before i'm just jumping into the
topics quick
point that you see on the rough outline
on
what i'm going to talk about first part
kubernetes and storage
just a quick point on how is it looking
in kubernetes what's the situation what
is rook
did you well get kind of a bit of uh
an overview on what even what is rook
even
um architecture and then we're going to
dive into the new features
also in the road map for the future and
just as a well last point to throw in
we are looking to graduate the project
soon
so um i'm going to talk about that in a
bit
as well so kubernetes and storage
um in kubernetes if you want storage
uh you're well basically bound to use uh
external storage
meaning well taking on premise with bare
metal as an example
you need to have some sort of storage
already existing
not to name any names but well
there's bigger appliances for storage
you might have
well if you're just on premise that
might be already enough for you
but in general with the storage share
it's not too portable
um meaning that if you go from
on-premise and
you're on the um the uh
multi-cloud hybrid cloud kind of trip
um well your appliance in
in the data center might not be
sufficient for
well your aws or whatever cloud scenario
so um
well as we have it if you haven't if
your appliances in the basement and not
in the aws cloud or
gcp wherever well you need to have
access to the services
um that's not too much of a challenge if
you're just on premise but
well um but it's
it's in general just like a it's not too
portable
unless you are in the same environment
all the time
um for if you're more
less in a cloud environment the problem
with arises
is um well you're kind of locked in
because if you're with aws well
you can use their ebs and their well
their
file system and well s3 and so on at
least s3 is a bit
more open if you will so so that's not
too much of a problem but normal
well classic storage like block and file
system storage
is kind of a burden to have
well switching from environment even
though
as we have in kubernetes storage classes
and such which kind of
are well a bit of an abstraction there
well it's still a bit of a challenge
because if you have a bug
on well on let's say your local
appliance storage and you move it to aws
and you don't have to back there
well there's certain scenarios where
it's simply a bit
more important to have the same storage
from your on-premise or whatever to
full production so now
and another point um well if you're a
big company you probably don't have to
too much as a problem
um you need to have someone that manages
to search
so if you just put some appliance in and
while it runs then
well you might not need to manage it too
much but
still at least it feels a bit weird to
just put in some compliance and yeah it
runs it runs and
it runs till it doesn't run yeah well um
so kind of the question there who's
managing the surge
so that's where we come to what is rook
rook is well a storage operator
the part of the operator part i'm going
to go into that concept a bit further
later on
the part of operator is simply as it
kind of implies
well i'm for example an operator to well
operate well some some crane or
something
it's kind of the same if you think uh
for rook tear it's well operating uh
things like saf hfs and other storage
systems storage software
back ends provide us how you want name
it
and the point with root there is that it
well you have kubernetes oh well fine
put rook on at unfcef for example or hfa
so
it's generally not just about safter
it's
general point of those well
complex storage systems um
making them easy to run in your
kubernetes cluster so
well in containers and yet and the part
of where
well where the rook part with the
operations is coming in is
um it's it's trying to have it as
abstract as possible but with also a
good amount of customizability either
way for the users
where rook takes care of deploying
managing installation configuration all
those hundred steps
and well in the end you create
one two more objects to talk about the
kubernetes part there
and bam ceph cluster in your kubernetes
cluster
ready to be used by the applications
well if you want to bring that to
production it's a bit more to think
about like
what kind of distance on but well kind
of if you think about more on a lower
level
still remains that rook will take care
as good as possible about those points
for storage
software um but well let's kind of step
a bit back there
rook it's open source apache 2.0 license
we are
a project of the cncf we currently
that's also later on i said
we're looking to graduate the project as
um
as other projects like kubernetes
prometheus as well have already done
great shooting from cncf so
we're trying to do that as well um
as we had with the operator part
um to make it easily possible in
kubernetes
we can introduce so-called custom
resource definitions
um those are basically well a
possibility for users
especially more well administrators of
the cluster to extend the kubernetes api
so well for rook looking at saf there we
would for example have a ceph cluster
object
for well other purposes like well
my skill for example you might want to
have like a my skill database or
something object which
um especially looking at
[Music]
well user experience for the developers
if they need a database well go ahead
create your mysql database object and
some operator in the end will take care
of creating all the things needed for
the database it's the same concept there
for rook
the admin hopefully not just all the
users on the cluster
um creates a ceph cluster object
and based on the specifications in that
object
rook will take care of um well for
example for sev
to create osds from the disks in the
servers we'll discover them
and uh well create the um
create the command structures and all
needed uh to for example then tell seth
volume to use those in those disks
based on these specifications um
yeah i already mentioned that it's not
just about ceph
it's also about r storage which well
is yeah well complicated to run
um saf cockroaches be at your fest
uh cassandra nfs yuga by db
um kind of shout out to the yugo by tb
people they just
joined with like version 1.1
um great people and
yeah the idea is to grow that even
further
so it's not just as like seth or
something the idea is that
uh in a broader sense well i have my own
premise for example i create myself
cluster using a rook cef operator and oh
well i need a
i need a well yoga by db and i create it
and just for example tell it to use
as normal kubernetes flow to claim
persistent volume claims as a keyword
there um the storage for example from
the saf cluster because
why not um
so yeah going to the architecture
there's in itself three layers you have
the operator layer
it's well managing the staff it's
configuring it
but the main point to mention it's not
on the data path
so there's no well my one operator part
right now is down so oh
no everything's halting i always stopped
and that's not gonna happen
for storage provisioning thankfully
through the
csi the container storage interface
it's well it's amazing as it's
not just um well for there was something
previously
don't remember like don't um
well it's not too important it's flex
volume
point is with csi it's more like a
common solution for general
storage it has container storage
interface as a name but
it's general interface to more or less
be able to say hey
give me 50 gigs of storage and then on a
node to say hey please mount the storage
for example
uh and that's great as previously we had
written our own flex volume drive line
well it's a pain to maintain such a
driver
so but that's also for it's not just for
the sap
part it's also for hfs for example as
they're also providing
block search and file system search rook
takes care of
setting up the csi driver as good as it
can like there's
definitely some points where well the
admin need to step in to create storage
classes to
maybe well have certain changes certain
security
uh um levels specified in the storage
class or something
but main point is that rook will
normally
uh get you for example edge of cluster
in a state where
you just need to create a storage class
so yeah
so um as previously said for the
operator the operator is not on data
path
so no need to worry about operator
crashing or anything or being
incompatible
um it's just ceph or hfs or cassandra
and so on
there's well yeah um
yeah um i mentioned
uh previously like rook cev operator
and there's even rook hfs operator and
so on the point there is
that it's separate operator it it's not
like yeah i want to use tef
but because i install rook i have the
rook cephalopod hfs and then and so on
operator that's not like it that's the
reason why it's split like that
if you want sev well go for this f
operator if you want let's say
cassandra as an example you use the
cassandra operator so
you have the freedom there to kind of
say what you need and what you want
so yeah well as that we have the rook
operators
that do the management configuration
upgrades and stuff of the software
um from
from as previous as you said with like
the operators
and it's basically the same the operator
is simply
well automating certain actions which
normally a human would need to do or
well maybe even another automation tool
um
like well ansible or something so um
yeah um coming back to the custom
objects
um if you create a sev cluster and say
hey i want to use for example well my
sdb drive or something or maybe my well
you add to add a new disk in that
definition and say well
use my sdc disk as well the rook
operator
will take care based on that and
well we'll see okay the state changed
and act on that will trigger
all the things needed all the
preparation jobs for example for the
osds
and you will hopefully in a few well let
it be a minute
with some sometimes lvm and sound takes
a bit of time
uh at least for the volume part there um
but yeah so in the end operator watching
over everything seeing every state
changed i need to do something
and even kind of like uh health checking
to a certain point
where it's like oh we can't upgrade now
because the status of the
cluster right now says we have data uh
well osd's down or something like that
too many or so so
um there's parts where the operator kind
of tries to throw in a good amount of
knowledge
from a people that run sev cluster or
even well more or less also the
developer
of sev where for example there's like a
um what is called self safe to stop i
think and safe to remove command and
such
and that's parts where rook also tries
to um where we're
more miles moving there and to use the
seven native
parts to um well
[Music]
have the cluster operate as safe as
possibly
um so from the root part
um operator part again which simply is
the kubernetes api there's not
too much magic involved it's just normal
power of kubernetes um
nothing well too special there to say um
i said it's managing upgrades and such
it's trying to do them as
already for like seven sounders well
stateful
if you want um there
see um coming back to your custom resist
definitions
uh so we have those custom resource
and in those the admin specifies what
they want they can
you they can specify one device after
another
they can even if they're well in an aws
environment or
well in a cloud environment in general
they can even specify that
storage should be taken from like the
cloud provider and such through again
like
standard kubernetes methods persistent
volume claims and such
and well just a normal
way of kind of doing it and the object
is basically in the end as kubernetes
wants it it's the state as its desired
so there's not it's the rook operator
will try
as long as possible uh to use the disk
even if it doesn't exist
or well it there's mechanisms in play to
hopefully prevent that but just from a
um just from a kubernetes standpoint
if the object says hey use this disk
it would technically well try forever
because the user wants to decide state
to
use this disk so now
so uh moving on to the new features
you get a you got db joint in 1.1
we already had rook release 1.2 but
well yay new storage back end
um same goes here we are a perfect
example right now for the
crd party custom resources we can define
our own
objects or even well own apis
and the people that create those series
can basically
put in whatever they want and even have
which is pretty powerful about
kubernetes have validation and such in
place
hfs hfs has
been able thanks to giovann issa
i think i'm butchering the name mustafa
um has implemented a multi-home network
that's a big challenge a bit still in
kubernetes
i can tell you at least just from the
general concept there
for the well for the um for projects
such as
multis um if anyone has maybe heard
about multis yet
um the idea is simply to have again
kubernetes native custom resources and
such
uh to be um to easily like be able to
have
multiple interfaces from the node but
even virtual
well overlay networks and such per
application per pod running in your
kubernetes cluster
um he well he didn't just design it he
even implemented it that's great that's
cool to see
um just kind of quick look here for um
again part we just specify a new part of
configuration
in this case i think there's even not
just support for multis but
i can't get the name right now but
indeed one of the other projects that's
allowing custom networking stuff in
kubernetes and easily
um configure those networks to be used
for these
for this edge of this cluster in this
case
um for sev i think
a lot of a lot of people including me
um well have been kind of desperate for
this feature
um partitions
finally at least to kind of uh
bring up what my case is um maybe who
knows hat's not
hosting provider anyone maybe oh well
they have cheap servers and you but you
have two disks most of the time
and there is still almost like four
terabytes eight terabytes or something
back
and if i have my os on one of them i
basically lose the whole disk
because previously i couldn't use a
partition which well i would
100 gigs maybe for the os and the rest
for seth because why not
and finally i think the yeah
since well with the upcoming i'm not
sure if it's already out the 14.28
release though
that is available as a feature to use
um yeah it's it's great to see it's
awesome
so big thanks for everyone that's
contributing helping being on the slag
just
well also thanks for being here um
yeah so for the roadmap
well which just tried to further
stabilize
the custom resource definitions try not
to well
change them too much as we are on a
stable level
for seven hfs for example right now
um we
well we try to use we have well we have
our own code
that does like the watching on the
custom objects and such
um well it's
well there's a bunch of other projects
out there as well
um which kind of offer a more well more
commonly used
um approach to doing that like the
operator sdk
from red hat chorus i think those
two com project slash companies um
so the idea is to well move away from
our own
stuff and get something which well
everybody uses
yeah um as we headed with yoga by db
joining for 1.1 we hope to get
more storage providers on board with
rook
for sev i talked about the multi-home
network stuff for hfs um
well it's soon also coming to seth
in i think let me
in where do you hear it it's planned for
round 1.3
thanks to uh sebastian han again um
yeah let me go back one slide here
um and first have parts the
manager part who knows about the ceph
manager
who knows about the cell manager
dashboard
[Music]
well the idea there is there's a cool
dashboard where everybody is working on
to in general have better integration
with such orchestration tools
like well the deepsea stuff and so on
like the existing
well rook also exists but um but also
for rookside to even also better
integrate it with that
that's uh one of the ideas daniel is
that you
can specify everything you want in the
cef cluster object
um but if you want you can also just log
into the dashboard
see how which disks are available in
each node and then just click click and
say ah well
make them osds or something and well
we want to get there we're not quite
there yet but it's getting better and
better
for hfs they simply want to feature um
well to support new features that they
have implemented in the project
themselves
um and one of the bigger parts here
definitely is the cncf project
graduation um but besides it there's
more to come
so we up we saw that project graduation
um i'm not gonna bother you too much
with dates or anything point being
we joined uh the cncf project as a
sandbox project in like
2018 or something um
and well we further improved and stuff
and woo
point being we tried to graduate in 2020
so hopefully around well march
um and well
besides looking from the past to uh now
well a lot of numbers have increased so
that should probably mean something good
right
um it's growing
to summarize that slide it's where the
rook is growing further and further
uh we have done also which is for a good
amount of companies also very important
there was a security audit about rook
well an independent security audit
was performed by the trail of bits guys
um they even did the
kubernetes security audit point being
there were some
vulnerabilities we fixed them or what
else one or two small
like well not two critical things which
are still being fixed
point is we got the security audit it
looks good we didn't have too many
critical things
um in general just like the current
fracture stuff we need to improve a bit
on the ci part and such and
well so
should you run rook already who's
running rook in development or so
testing around playing with it okay
who's running it in production
oh well at least a few hands i'm happy
about that
um uh if you want
like i would really encourage you to get
in touch with me maybe
now or you can also just you know
send jared once a message on slack or on
twitter
and well kind of talk to him that we get
a bit more
um no what is called
not customer testimonials but
testimonials about people using the
project
and uh well using well using it simply
um yeah and well for people that might
not be able to say hey yeah we're using
it
it can also be confidential so well
um well
i'm working for claricle just as a point
if you want to work on rook
like to program go or something feel
free to reach out to us or to me
um but now getting back to rook
if you want to get involved feel free to
jump on our slack
rook.io is also a great place in regards
to the documentation and such
um twitter we even have a mailing list
we have community meetings so feel free
to join
and yeah
you got the photo
thank you
um if you have any questions feel free
to ask them now i'll try to repeat them
as we well
so audio issues yeah
so the question is that there is an
issue about extending persistent volumes
slash persistent volume claims uh with
csi right
yes yes um that is
solved well it's it's it's solved in
master to be that guy
but it's back ported as far as and now
to
1.2 something 1.22 or
yeah it is in 1.2 as far as i know but
not released yet or it is already in the
latest patch release
point being saf csi which brought this
feature which
is the for them the 2.0 release has
brought this feature finally
um probably worth checking out
github.com csi
i hope they've updated their feature
table below um
so the question is is it possible to use
multiple well rook
storage operators for example rook ceph
and rook etcherfest in the same cluster
um well technically speaking yeah
sure that's not a problem they're in
self-independent
um well if you use the same disk for
both there
is a chance that you know one might take
a disk first before the other or
something but
well it's um you have two people
fighting over the same disk for example
then it's
not a clash of the operators because
they don't know about each other but
just a clash of the disks on the servers
yeah if you separate like what notes
they use
uh then it shouldn't be too much of a
prop yeah it's like the same with issue
use
seth and the cassandra one you don't you
don't need to use the saffron
in the end it's just normal piston
volume clamp search and if you separate
and so it's
yeah yeah is um how high is the operator
or how far you want to bring it in for
example supporting day two operations
and thinking about the different phases
that an operator can have from
phase three with all backup and recovery
from phase five
uh yeah so how is currently the rook
operator in this sense and
how is it evolving um so the question is
uh let me try to summarize it um
how far rook operator rook operators
will go
in regards to second day operations
right um
well one of the main power stereo at
least is already covered by the
operators for example for sev
that's well the most common i know there
is the health checking of the monitors
um because well you don't want to lose
your quorum i don't
well um bad things will happen there
um in regards to backups of volumes
and such uh that's not a thing
rook is looking too much into simply due
to the fact there's already a big
ecosystem around it like
uh let me where do we have it uh
from stashed project stash operator or
well it's even an operator which has
crds as well
um there is haptic io or it well it was
previously i think it's
vmware or something now with their arc
project
i hope they didn't rename it as well
yeah well valero yeah the new name
um and there's a few more projects uh
some even more on the seth layer if you
want forza for example like becky ii i
think
um it's it's secondary operations but
it's something just due to the diversity
there
in do you want it in cuban is fancy with
customers those definitions are
more outside just back up everything for
example
well and at least one phrase that kind
of stuck with me from some people that
uh do a bit more in regards to seth
um is um
[Music]
if you want to back up steph cluster put
in our self cluster besides it and it's
like well
uh howdy integration
so you mean if you want to add a new
storage background basically
[Music]
um so the question is um
what do you need to do basically to add
a new storage provider
um well we have
we well we're trying to improve that
even further now
the main idea is that um
we have a lot of uh well framework like
structures to call it like that it's not
yet at a i would say full-blown
framework for that
but there's basically certain structures
already available where you
well you design yours it's a customer
source definition
and well to put it like that you can
copy and paste
certain parts of the codes which for
example just do the easy part of
watching and modifying your own
functions then
to well on ads like your new object has
been created you react to it and such
um there's a good amount of functions
already available
it can be still improved like i said um
it's more like we're moving
more and more to be a framework in that
regard um yeah
okay any other one
um so the question is if one rook cef
installation can support multiple
clusters
um to a certain extent yes you would
have let's assume the following you have
one cluster with the root ceph on it
and you have let's say three other
clusters every other kubernetes clusters
um you would use rooksef just as normal
in the uh first cluster to get seth
running
and in the other three clusters you
could also use
rook there to um with the um
forget the name external cluster
integration
where um you would um take the access
key and such from
this cluster give it to each cluster and
then the root have operator can also set
up the certain things like csi and such
though one important thing there to
mention is
the rooks have class in the cluster you
need to run it with host network true as
of
right now because the other nodes and
such they
need to be able to access the osd's and
the monsoon like well everything in the
end so
um that's one of the kind of
restrictions as we have right now
if you don't have any questions uh
anymore well i got a few stickers still
with me so
uh feel free to grab them
so yeah thank you