okay
thank you uh i will be speaking today uh
about
trivial world sorry uh french in a row
so it should be accustomed to the accent
i will be speaking about
three-dimensional
visualization application
for representing geographical time space
on behalf of alan rostis with many
researchers against
in this project which who can be here
today
so i will speak about what is the
problem with
time space
i will show some example of geographical
timespace representation
and i will give you some information
about the project
i can't show you make you a demo because
it's too
short in a time but let's
so what's the problem with time space
so in geography this is a geography
project
uh there is two major concept
issue say where is something where is it
and at what this sounds something is
from somewhere something else
uh but in the daily life movement
we uh thought about time where i go to
work
i don't say oh it's 15 kilometers i said
i
go to work in 15 minutes okay so we
fought in time so there is two concepts
in this geographical distance we have to
go to somewhere
and the geographical time space
so how can we represent those two
objects
the geographical time space and the
geographical distance
so i will show you some examples and
then
show you a little bit of shriving world
we'll try to
mitigate the issues so it's an old
question this is
uh the
pettinger table which is a
medieval document about a roman roman
iterarium and if you saw the the orange
line
with steps on it it's believed that one
step
is uh one day travel by horse
so it's a very old data and with that a
merchant and say okay
to go to where to where i have maybe
many many days of travel
so this is actually a solution it's not
very perfect
and we have some modern reflections on
it so this is um
famous mcl uh representation
uh it's an automotive so the world is
little shrinking
when the transportation modes can became
faster
for example at the before the industrial
revolution
you go there by horse carriage or by
foot so
the world was very big it's very it was
the next village was
already far
so and no nowadays the world is very
narrow you can go to new york in a
couple of hours
in a bunch of hours so
so it's a very great preparation to show
the acceleration of transportation modes
but you can't compare different modes
but not on the same
period so mods
can't exactly coexist
mods i mean train cars
foods and so on transportation mods
and there's no representation of
networks
so the networks are different
on those this one from
chimizu in the 80s use
an animal for this and make the
cartography of it
it's from japan and try to
show how the japan striking is shrinking
uh with the variable of uh fast rain
in and airplanes
so it's a great to show acceleration we
we have uh
from the 60s to a project after the 80s
uh you can mix a little bit the
the mode but you it's not represent so
it's not easy to see if it's by train or
by plane
and you can maybe
thought about the networks but they are
not really
emphasis and phases
this map is about is
was made by tobler which is a famous who
is a famous
uh geographer and uh
it keeps the cities at their place made
networks in it
and uh try to make strings
in the network so the edges are three
are springs sorry
so good things networks are preserved
okay and represented
modes can partially co-exist also
but it doesn't show acceleration so you
are stuck
in uh it's a picture of one time
so the streaming world um
hypothesis is to show in a 3d map
you keep all the
the summit of each cone is the actual
city it's in a 3d
projection and we we have two uh
two travel modes the fastest one is the
red line
always the red line it doesn't move and
you
we apply a ratio from the fastest to
the slowest and the slowest is
represented by the blue line
and actually the blue cone
which is it's a cone it's in 3d so it's
a cone
the blue cone summit is moving
uh a bit from the ratio between the
fastest and the slowest man
so for example with uh uh jet planes
and cars we have this kind of
cones but if you have a supersonic
planes
the cone is steeper okay because the
ratio the difference between a carb
going at 100 kilometers is very much
bigger so it gives things like that so
maybe in the early 30s you can go to
london to berlin this is the blue line
this is actual
position of the city this is a worldwide
map so each submit is an airport
actually so in eight hours maybe you can
do
that distance with a proper airplane
it's pretty much like 2060 kilometers
london to bucharest if you have
an airplane who is able to do an
eight-hour
flight if you
uh in the 60s we have uh airplanes with
uh jet engines so we can
do a little bit further and faster so
maybe we can do
still do long london berlin but you can
do see
to london new york or london
paris to new york as well and we have a
little bit
more network so you can go a little bit
in eight hour further
so and you can see the cones start to be
to be a little bit shaped and steeper
uh in the 80s and the last
half of the last part of the
20th century we have the supersonic
aircraft the concorde
and a little bit of time the triple f
one triple f was able to make that
you can watch further you can go in
eight hours you can
make a very big travel but the concord
was only six hours
autonomy so and there was only two
destinations from new york it was paris
or london
and we were on but that's it so
the network was very narrow at the time
so you can see the the cone are very
steeper and
choppy sharp sorry
and after the end of the commercial use
of concord
we are back at the same point in the 60s
with jet airplanes
the autonomy is a little bit better they
can go a little bit far
faster but not so much but the
network the airport networks is much
more dense
so you say oh you speak about
acceleration
if you combine things you can make
represent acceleration so we have the
same
visualization like mac air
and we have something like um
and you see where it's acceleration the
transportation modes can accelerate and
then now uh get slower
so this is one of the this is the
capabilities and the
main goal of the streaming project
i will be talking a little bit more of
this project
in the okay this means to
represent a complex reality uh it's for
research applications
there is no practical use but it's it
tackles uh
things from cartography computer
graphics and scientific vision
uh it's a free open source software and
mostly in
javascript you can find the code on
github
and find the uh the
research blog on ipotessport
timespace.ipotes.org and we have a small
small team so feel free to join and if
you have any questions
i'm here for you thank you
um have you uh
used this into comparing
soft notes transportation between cities
and walkability indexes
actually no the only
so you you asked me if you we
used it for slow modes actually in
cities
yeah actually no the only application we
use it the only dataset we
use are airports position and
comparison between flight mode and
terrestrial transportation modes
maybe you can do that but you need the
data for that
sorry the point i was
thinking about is that in terms of city
planning
sometimes we want to see can we
create more spaces for certain soft
modes
uh cycling and ladders and so
what is the difference um
which would make maybe this project
could help visualizing this
yeah maybe it can be uh helpful for city
planning but
uh we don't have any data set and it's
not
all um subject to but maybe you can
contact us and try to work with us it
might be
interesting yeah thank you thank you
very much