[Music]
all right i'm todd i am from lawrence
livermore national laboratory for people
who aren't familiar with that
it's a national security laboratory it's
about an hour from san francisco
and we run a lot of super computers
which is the sort of the motivation for
spac
i'm going to talk a little bit about
dependency management in general first
so so far we've heard from a lot of
different dependency managers what's
managed by dependency managers typically
it's usually what projects is this or
what packages does this project depend
on
and what version of each of the
installed packages or what what version
of each of the dependencies should i
actually install
and so if you think about you know what
does that look like as a package model
for for most package managers
it's like this it's a little this is a
node it has a name
it's got a version it depends on some
other things that some other versions
and so it's fairly simple it gets to be
complex
when you start to do dependency
resolution on this it's np hard even to
select the versions for a dag
but you know this is pretty much what
most package managers are resolving
um the concerns that people typically
have with what versions are selected are
you know what do i have correct or
compatible versions
do i have the latest version do i have
the most tested version do i have a
secure version
those are the kinds of things we've
heard about so far
this is going to be a slightly different
kind of talk
we're going to talk about building for
basically resolving dependencies for
optimization and not necessarily
for these concerns although we care
about those too so
some fairly common but maybe
questionable assumptions that your
package manager makes and we've talked
about these
today too are hey there's a one-to-one
relationship between the source code and
the binary
this is an assumption that debian makes
for the reproducible builds project
it sort of assumes that you're only
going to build source code one way
and we don't really do that in hpc um
binaries should be as portable as
possible most distros it's it's bad for
performance if you build
o2-g binaries they're not going to run
fast and so if you have something
performance critical
in your stack you need to be able to
build it
a fast way which is harder than building
the portable binaries
um the other assumption that typically
has made is the tool chain's the same
across the ecosystem i'm going to build
this thing with the standard compiler or
maybe i don't even have a compiler i'm
using an interpreted language
and so you know we we'd like to be able
to actually resolve the compiler
in the stack and then the assumption
that users
build and deploy configurations that
were tested before most package managers
are taking an artifact that someone
generated
that they tested they're deploying it um
what we really like on this back project
at least is that you know it would be
really nice if building something for
the first time were just as easy as
building something that someone built
before
so that's what we're working towards and
why are we doing that
um we build for machines like this so um
these are some of the department of
energy's current and upcoming
super computers and so if you look at
these um
the you know there's four plus different
cpu architectures and four plus
different gpus across these machines
none of these looks the same and so
typically when we're building something
we're building in a pretty new probably
bleeding edge environment and we want to
tune for the machine
right and so code is typically
distributed as source
which is pretty horrible it's a pain we
have to build it all the time
we build many variants of the same
package the code's optimized for the
processor model
and so it's not an o2-g binary it might
even be optimized for you know like
skylake canon lake a particular model of
the processor not just
x86 64. there's no standard ecosystem
most things are linux
but the user environment and where the
software on the machine is is very
different from site to site
and then it's multi-language so we're
not dealing with one package ecosystem
we're dealing with c c plus plus fortran
python lots of other things
it's pretty complicated um so
these are the kind of things that we're
building these are large simulations for
things like compressible flow nuclear
reactors
urban disasters radiological problems
things like that and so the model
becomes a lot more complicated so this
is the dag i showed before this is a
node
where you're just selecting for a name
and a version what we're tuning in spac
is this so this is build configuration
options so particular parameters that
you might pass to configure or different
options on the package
different library implementations so i
may not depend on just one library
i might depend on mpi of which there are
three or four different implementations
with different versions on each of them
different configuration options
different networks
i'm tuning for different gpus different
cuda versions i'm tuning for the
compiler
there may be more than one compiler for
my language ecosystem all of this gets
pretty complicated so what we want
is a dependency resolver that can select
all the parameters here
not just this so spac enables that
it's designed to enable software
distribution for hpc we're automating
the build and installation so we're not
just selecting from
existing versions we're actually
generating a space of packages we're
generating dags
to build different versions of things
the packages are templated so there's
one
packaged python file per package per
project i guess and then it has a lot of
different parameters so you can build
this combinatorial explosion of packages
and so we're pulling a lot of lower
level aspects of the software ecosystem
up to the package manager level that's
the build parameters and things that i
just talked about
it's written in python but like i said
we can package whatever
and so what we really want is the ease
of use of mainstream tools all the stuff
that modern
software developers are used to but for
this somewhat antiquated software
ecosystem that we have to deal with
in hpc we're doing okay it's a pretty
popular project
it's not as popular as like many
javascript projects
but it is used all over the world at
different hpc sites and so this is sort
of proof
that you know we are bringing the
ecosystem together we're getting lots of
contributions on the package side from
lots of different organizations we have
over 500 contributors now
and even the core is getting
contributions from lots of different
folks
and we're used on some of the biggest
machines out there so we're used on the
number one system at oak ridge
summit the number two system at
livermore which is a similar machine
that's where i am
and we're going to be used for the
upcoming arm 64 fx
system from fujitsu that's going to get
deployed at weekends so we have a
partnership with them
so lots of interesting machines this is
what it looks like from sort of a user
level
you can install a package just normally
you can say i want this package
just say the name of it and we'll give
you something with sensible defaults
you can get a lot more specific though
you can say i want a particular version
you can say i want a particular compiler
and a particular version of that
compiler
you can say that you want to have
threads enabled different build options
you can inject flags into the build so
you could basically build
60 versions of the same package with
different flags
you can target specific micro
architectures so you can say i want to
build for skylake
and you can also do that for all the
dependencies so you can get specific
about your dependencies and what they do
and so this is what the command line
configuration looks like so if you
install one thing
the packages like i said they're
templated and so
if people are familiar with homebrew the
package recipes look a lot like homebrew
they're just written in python
but they're also templated so you can
have lots of different versions lots of
different options lots of different
dependencies that are potentially
optional
and then there's build recipe stuff down
here and so with that
um what we're doing is is we're enabling
you to build
all of the things we want you to be able
to build you know this dag
but configured lots of different ways
and so for each configuration
of that graph um we generate a hash
and we install everything in its own
prefix and so as many
versions as you want of all these
different packages can coexist together
and they're all our paths so you don't
have to worry about finding dependencies
you don't have to worry about setting up
your ld library path these are all they
all know where to find their
dependencies when we build them
so what does the dependency resolver
do um this is we call it the concretizer
in spec
we take an abstract spec like that
that's basically you know what does it
look like on the command line
um and then we we basically normalize it
so we produce a dag that has some of the
constraints filled in
and then if you think about what the
dependency resolver is doing it's
solving this problem it's filling in all
the blanks in a consistent way so we
take that dag
we turn it into the the giant json thing
that i showed you
and we store that in the file system
with with all this provenance
um for an environment we support virtual
environments
and with uh sort of the manifest log
file model that bundler popularized
so we can do spac.yaml which is sort of
the input format it's like a bunch of
different specs like the ones that i
showed on the command line
and we produce a lock file with all that
information for all the different
dependencies in your environment
this has gotten to be pretty complicated
and so this is where
this talk sort of picks up we're taking
you know lots of constraints from lots
of different places and we're trying to
integrate them into one gigantic sat
solve
and and that's pretty nasty so there's
the stuff that i showed on the command
line
there's all the constraints that came
from the package file that i showed for
all the dependencies in the project tree
there's constraints that can be in the
environment so users can actually
specify their preferences for how
dependencies are resolved
and then there's other configurations
you can have local configuration for
your user for your site
and there's defaults from spac and so
all of this stuff sort of gets
mushed into one solve and we traverse
the dag repeatedly we evaluate
conditions add dependencies and we
repeat this until the dag doesn't change
so it's kind of a fixed point algorithm
in the
in the current version i mean the issue
with this is that
there's limited support for backtracking
it's pretty greedy um you can sort of
decide the version of something over
here
and then discover a conflict over here
and not have them resolved properly
and then um the constraints are yeah so
the constraints are ordered
so you may discover you know that
you've selected a compiler but you
wanted to build for an architecture
that it turns out that compiler doesn't
support and really you have to kind of
solve those things together
to get a consistent dag and so this
results in a whole lot of con
conditional complexity for a solver that
you know isn't all that powerful
compared to what some of these
you know full back tracking solvers can
do
and so it's gotten to be hard to add new
features in logic and it can be slow
because we're basically
building the dag over and over and over
again in python
so we started looking into what are the
options stat solving looks pretty
appealing
there are lots of dependency managers
that use sat solvers getting into the
world of stat solving is not for the
faint of heart there are lots and lots
of different sub-communities there and
they all do
sort of variants on the same thing and
so this took a lot of research to sort
of figure out
what's the best way to do this or what
do existing tools do
so picosat is probably your most simple
portable c
solver it uses advanced techniques for
actually doing a set solve but it's pure
boolean logic
and so if you want to write your solver
in pure boolean sat
it turns out you have to do a lot of
cumbersome things you have to implement
arithmetic in boolean logic if you want
to do anything like optimization so
you're really like building an adder
in in boolean logic which is which is
nuts
conda does this it ends up being kind of
slow in conda and so people have looked
at
libsall as a potential solution for that
lib solve is also a sat solver i think
it does some of this
but it's very targeted towards a
traditional package model so it seems
like libsall solves
mostly the node model that i showed on
the first slide where you're just
thinking about packages and versions
and so it didn't seem like we could get
inside something like that and really
customize it to our needs
um pubgrub is awesome i think people
have heard of that who's heard of
pubgrub
this is sort of next-gen version solving
it's a cdcl solver which is it's
it learns clauses and conflicts as it
goes along
so it's a powerful sat solver and it has
some logic in it that basically
maintains a list of conflicts as it does
to solve
and so if you get an error in pubgrub it
comes back to you and says
oh hey this depends on version another
version of this this depends on another
version of this and so you need to
adjust the version of this package to
fix your solve because it's not
compatible right now
so it essentially gives you a proof of
what's unsatisfiable
about your dag which is cool
but the model again is kind of limited
it's package inversion for pubgrub
and we would have to use it we'd have to
sort of integrate it into our own solver
and do our own custom thing and we
really didn't want to do that
we needed multi-criteria optimization
i'll get into that a little bit
in a second and tons of people's life
work has gone into basically taking sat
solvers integrating them with
optimization solvers
and making that fast and so we really
were worried about implementing a custom
solver in python
so we sort of stayed away from this the
two things that
we kind of boiled down to in the end
were
so there are these things called smt
solvers this is like a sat solver
but it actually has theories integrated
into it and what that means is that
for your boolean solve it's it's doing
basically all your advanced stat
algorithms
for the actual clauses in the solve you
can do things like
math you don't need to implement you
know math and boolean sat
you can actually use other sort of
theory solvers for the equations
themselves that go into the sat solve
so that's pretty cool you can call out
to
you know a theory solver from within
your sat solver um
it also does multi-criteria optimization
and z3 is really popular in the formal
verification community so this is for
like security people who want to say
this is a heap and it only does heap
things it will not you know attack your
computer in addition to that
so this turned out to be pretty cool um
and it also has some really advanced
proof capabilities which we're looking
into
um answer set programming is is the
other one that we looked into
um there's a really capable answer set
solver called patasco
or i guess the solver is called clasp
the package is called clingo
and the project is called patasco so i
don't know exactly what to call it
but that's that's the project this seems
like the most active asp project right
now
and no this is not active server pages
this is this is answer set programming
um and the cool thing about this is that
it's a very high level language
so you can write your constraints in
something that looks like prologue who's
who's programmed in prologue yeah um
which
which is kind of nice right it's nicer
than boolean
clauses um and it makes for very short
programs
um it boils down to sat and they do
optimization and some of these other
things
so we we ended up deciding to implement
our new solver
in asp to see how that would do
so this is what it looks like we use
clingo
that's the package i'm talking about the
asp program basically has two parts
instead of what i was talking about
before where we would basically
iteratively construct the dag
um what we're doing is uh we we generate
a big list of facts from all of our
package files and all of the different
uh preferences files that we have
um for the solve and so that tends to be
and
you know these are surprising numbers if
you if you but if you think about the
size of the package ecosystem that makes
sense
um it's like six thousand to nine
thousand facts for our typical solves
um and and so these are these really
long files they look like this
it just says hey this package has this
version declared this package has this
option this package has
you know these criteria or these
conflicts all of that goes into just a
pure list of statements that say this is
true
um and then there's a really small logic
program like 130 lines
that we concatenate with that and throw
into the solver
and um the new algorithm it's pretty
it's conceptually much simpler you
generate all the facts you
you concatenate it you send it to the
solver you take the result that it spits
back at you and you build the dag out of
that
and so um that's pretty this is a pretty
big win
um the solve time itself is much faster
than the existing concretizer just
because we're calling out to a native
package so it's like a fraction of the
second
for the actual solve um but for
um for the actual generation of the
program that's the bottleneck right now
we're in python so
actually generating all the strings to
send to the solver takes the bulk of the
time
so we're working on you know making that
faster
and so just to give you sort of a flavor
of what this looks like
asp makes it pretty easy to put what was
once very complicated logic in sort of
our custom solver
into one place so um the things that you
do when you're writing an asp solver are
you define the space
this just says that there's you know for
every node in the dag it has one
possible version that's it these are
cardinality rules they say i have one
version per node
that's what my space looks like at least
for this part
um this says don't allow conflicting
versions and then this part down here
just says hey if i declared a version
with a particular weight if i had a
particular preference on it
then give it that weight in the dag and
then this is a minimization statement it
says minimize
the total weight for all the versions in
the dag and so this is really concise
it's pretty cool it takes a
bit of cognitive load to get into this
mode of thinking and to start writing
these things down so like
despite the fact that this is like four
lines of code it took me a lot longer to
think about this than it did
about other lines of code that i might
write
um other stuff became simple too um
this is the compiler target optimization
i was talking about we have stuff in
spac
that tells us which compiler versions
can generate code for which
architectures
and so if you have a bunch of compilers
available and you have a bunch of
architectures that you could build for
because you know that you're on like a
haswell system
and you know that the compilers can
generate up to ice lake or something
like that
picking a compiler and picking a target
is it's not 100 straightforward if the
user said they want to build with a
particular compiler
you may have to downgrade the target
that you build for and so this allows us
to solve for that
at the same time and it and it was
previously like this sort of staged
logic
but now we're able to do something much
simpler where
essentially you know we say there's one
target per node we say you can't
have a node where the compiler doesn't
support the target that's assigned to it
and then the rest is just optimization
like the other ones and so this works
out to be very simple like this this was
super exciting that all it took was like
this line
and all of a sudden the targets are
right because we told it what was wrong
so the dependency logic is also pretty
concise we can easily take constraints
from different places
we can do virtual dependencies and so
this is all the logic that it takes to
say
you know i if i depend on mpi i can act
i actually depend on m pitch and that
[ __ ] or open mpi the implementations of
the mpi interface
so all that's in there and
constraints like i can only have one
provider
for mpi in my dag if i if i have both
open mpi and in pitch
in the same dag that's bad because the
symbols will conflict and so i can put
constraints like that in there
not all of this was simple like i said
the learning curve is pretty high
and there's a lot of thought that goes
into every line of code
and structuring the optimization
criteria can be a challenge so
when i first started doing this i wrote
my criteria as sort of
maximize constraints and um
instead of and so that led to some
surprising behavior so like
you know i would i would solve what i
thought was a pretty small dag but i
said
maximize the number of build options set
to their default value
and it was like oh hey i can just add
more packages to this tag to get more
build options
set to the default value and so i would
get these giant dags out of the thing
and and so you you have to think about
how you formulate the constraints so
most of the constraints are now
minimizing
so that the dag stays pretty small
one interesting example that i think is
kind of funny is the the previous
version of the solver if you said spack
install
hdf5 within pitch users would get
annoyed
that says install the hdf5 library
with the mpi implementation as inpitch
usually we get annoyed because it
doesn't it wasn't smart enough to say oh
i have to turn on the mpi support to
make that happen
right and so users would have to write
this instead and so that's fine that
that gives you a pretty nice small dag
the the new solver can be pretty smart
and so if i i was like okay
obviously this will fail if i say don't
build it with mpi
and build it with them pitch in the dag
but no it actually was like oh i see
that if i make the um if i depend on
live aec
and which depends on cmake which depends
on live archive which depends on lz4
valgrind
and then valgrind has an option for mpi
um i can get m pitch in your dag like
right there so i'll make it happen for
you
there you have to put some other
constraints in to make this same and so
i think you know what we'll do
is basically say don't search through
build dependencies for things like this
where you're saying
definitely include this note in the tag
but you know in general this is pretty
exciting because it means you can solve
for some pretty complicated things you
can see up here it tried 338 different
models
and compared them all figured out this
was the optimal one for that particular
configuration
and it was pretty cool getting errors is
still a little tough
the asp solvers don't have
good mechanisms for getting what's
called unsatisfiable cores out sort of
the minimum set of constraints that
aren't satisfiable
they also don't have proof generation
and so
one interesting thing about z3 the smt
solver
is that it can actually generate you a
pretty cool proof of you know
why was this dag unsatisfiable and so i
think we could take that and potentially
parse it and do something with it to
make it look like the good output from
pubgrub
but the z3 proofs are pretty involved if
anyone's ever seen a z3 proof it is not
like
it's not in english it is in in some
other language
and so so parsing that it will be
interesting
um so anyway that's where we're at right
now
um we have a working prototype um it's
pretty satisfying to see it solve cases
where we couldn't solve
things before and you know we've managed
to pull a lot of stuff
that is typically sort of assumed by the
distro or assumed by the build system or
just
kind of has to be tweaked by humans in
the package curation process
up into the solver so that you can
actually solve for configurations
and so so the goal here like i said is
to make it so that people can have nice
things in hpc so that it's easy to build
on a new system
and to get a new dag working in a place
you haven't built it before
um it would be really cool to be able to
use tools like fatsin for deeper salts
and so you know it the cnc plus and
4chan world are like absolutely horrible
at sember because it didn't exist when
they started existing
um and and so we don't really know the
compatibility between
uh packages and people tend to write
their package constraints
humans generate those they generate them
either based on you know what they know
what was the first version that i tested
with
um or you know what what have they
actually tested with
and typically that's kind of over
constrained right you could get a dag
working
with a different version of a library
most likely if it was pretty close to
what you had
in the tested configuration and so we
could use information like the call
graph stuff to figure out you know are
the entry points and exit points of
libraries compatible
could we plug this other package in you
know at more versions than maybe the
humans
um specified but prefer the tested
version
um while allowing you know more
divergence to get things working
um other stuff that we'd like to be able
to do that i think we can do with this
new solver is
solve for cross-compiled build dags so
actually do things like
if something has a build and a link
dependency on a library
build it once for the front end
environment where we're compiling and
build it again for the back end
environment where we would be running
and so figure out where to split nodes
in the dag
um i think i think we could definitely
do that um do things like compiler
runtime compatibility and make sure that
your lib standard c
plus library is consistent across your
dag um that's a thing that bites our
users very frequently if we
get ahead of the system lib standard c
plus plus um
and then you know do things like
integrate licenses into the solve
um so that's where we're at um if you
want stickers for spec they're up there
on the front row so grab one
and i'll take questions
sorry i can't hear you oh 25
okay right here
this one right here so this just says
install hdf5 where hdf5 has mpi disabled
right so on this node up here it says
turn off
mpi support right um and this says
m-pitch has to be a node in the graph
right and m-pitch is an mpi
implementation
and so what it does is it says it
searches all the configurations right
this isn't like an np complete solve
and and it says oh look valgrind can
have an mpi option
so i can disable mpi on hdf5 and not
link mpi to it
but i'll turn on val mpi support for
valgrind
get in pitch in the dag that way and oh
that this is how i get to it right so it
finds that
um pretty quickly and yeah so at first i
thought this was a bug and then i was
like no
no it's it's right for some definition
of right
yep
sorry
you can't i mean so there's it
considered 338 right
and and that's less than the total
number of solutions that you could find
for this
um it's that's how many had to consider
to find an optimal one
by the criteria that we used so yes it
considered a lot of solutions
you can get this thing to spit out all
the solutions but if you try that on a
bag like this it's going to sit there
for a long time generating
you know different configurations so i
guess if you consider that we have more
packages than npm
but sorry no this is the optimal one
so it's doing it's doing both a sat
solve to make sure that the constraints
are correct and it's saying
oh if i go down that path everything
will get worse right and so
no it doesn't because i know that if i
go down a certain path it can eliminate
options and say nothing down that path
is good
so i'll consider yeah so yes in the
worst case it would require you to do
that and so yes this is np complete
it can get bad yeah how does it know
something is bad
because weights so yeah we have weights
yeah like the minimization criteria that
i showed back here like so see down here
in in the the thing that we generate
right we
we have our preferences file and so we
say like okay the user really likes this
version so we'll put it at the top
the next best version is the latest and
the next latest and so on
we weight them that way and then we take
the weight and we put it in the salt
and so that's what this is doing um and
so like in the end we have like about
seven different criteria for this
and and you pick an order
lexicographically that you want them
optimized
and it comes up with an optimal solution
according to that
other questions
um it's doing like a cdcl solve so it's
conflict-driven clause learning
um so it's doing that at the same time
as doing like a simplex or some other
kind of optimization algorithm which
which is why i didn't want to write this
myself because i just like integrating
those two things seems like a nightmare
um there's papers about it but yeah it's
doing it's doing a lot of
smart stuff to find the right solution
is doing the the technique itself or is
it just
uh something like an
rpm oh no so it's back it's back builds
packages too
so it's end to end you're you you have a
bunch of package
files that are basically recipes plus
these constraints
um for basically they define the space
of packages you can build
and once you get a configuration like
you know um
like this we hand that to the build and
we say that you know
go build this right and the packages are
written so that they query the dag for
what to build
and so like if you wanted to think about
reproducible builds in this context
it wouldn't be like there's one source
and one binary that corresponds to it
it would be more like there's one source
there's this configuration in a binary
and that should be reproducible
yep
because um i guess i don't i didn't
fully understand the question have we
considered
what you have requirements yes
you can make them all optional yes
yeah you can so i mean the iterative way
of debugging these programs is typically
to sort of comment out constraints and
see which ones make it work
right
yeah yeah that's that's sort of what the
the proof generator that i talked about
for z3
and what the sort of unsat core um thing
will do for you it'll say here's
these are the cores i found for this
problem that are completely
unsatisfiable if these are in your
problem it won't be satisfiable
so i think we can do something based on
that because that's essentially what
pubgrub and other systems do
they build proofs or they look at the
unsat cores we just haven't done it yet
how do you deal with the change of
behavior in the spot
so from the first line to the second
line you because
there is a change in behavior yes so if
you
so that this depends on all the stuff
that i said went into the concretizer
right
so it's what you wrote on the command
line it's all this stuff this goes into
the solve
right but we do spit out a lock file
right
so like if if you once you solve and you
get a solution
right we spit it out as json and you can
go and reload that and
rebuild the same thing again if you want
to exactly right
and then in in another sort of sense you
can take this
and use it as sort of a reproducible
description but cross-platform
you could take this and re-concretize it
on a new machine and get something that
meets these constraints
um but you know it may be slightly
different underneath to make it work
it's reproducible on the same machine
with the same inputs right like that and
so you have the inputs you can reproduce
what you what you did what's different
is that you can tweak it more easily and
you can produce different configurations
faster
all right cool thanks
you