the next talk
is uh jeffrey vetter is going to talk to
us
about making sdrs more portable in the
area of heterogeneous stocks
good afternoon everyone uh i hope you
had a chance to go out and grab some
lunch
it's a it's an interesting experience
here
my colleague say young lee is with me
and he's going to help me give
a part of the talk so you've already
heard several of these things this
morning
where where people are porting sdr to
different heterogeneous architectures
and i would argue that's that's not just
a
an sdr phenomenon we're going to see
that everywhere at doe for example
all of our next supercomputers are going
to be gpu based and so
we have lots of users struggling with
how to
port to these these architectures so
we're part of a
dsoc program and we're
investigating the performance
portability sdr we've done a lot of
profiling and trying to understand
target architectures and this really
isn't different from what we do with our
doe applications it's different software
of course
but we sit down we don't know
astrophysics we don't know materials
design
we sit down with those people and try to
learn how to
to make their applications perform well
on these architectures and so
that's what we're doing here we're
trying to use open programming models to
do this
one of the things that's really
important is future proofing your
application
so you don't have to worry about new
architectures
needing to recode your your application
because of that
and then finally intelligent runtime
systems we've heard a lot about earlier
we think that's going to play an
increasingly important role
in addition to code generation and the
performance
of the applications and the goal that
we're looking at is being able to take
you know untouched the same application
and running on a
qualcomm snapdragon and run it on the
largest supercomputer in the world
and and just see if we can meet that
goal now it may not may not happen but
that's the challenge we're aiming for
so just a short note about
specialization so um i love this chart
by ray kurzwal that talks about the
growth of computing since uh
1900 and it really shows you where we
are today we're
nearing the end there where we've had
some outstanding gains from
cmos scaling and other things now we're
really getting into this transition
period
and i label it the sixth wave i think
there's a lot of things are going to
happen and we're already seeing a lot of
this
the first one is people are really
specializing their
applications and optimizing their code
for the architectures we have
the other one that i'm not going to talk
about is emerging technologies you know
have
you seen all the excitement about
quantum computing and neuromorphic
computing and all these other things
that's what what people are looking for
really the next computational paradigm
today i'm going to really focus on
architectural specialization i think
this is where we'll be
for for perhaps 10 years or more where
we take
the the cmos which is an incredible
technology
and just specialize it for workloads and
so that's
that's the specialization part and it's
really important that you get the
specialization right
now consequence of that is that the
architecture start to yield
very complex programming models and this
schematic i use
for talking about high performance
computing in the sense that
you know even if you are in astrophysics
or
material design or climate modeling your
application
these days has to be made up of this
stack where you have maybe mpi
some threading model on the smp and then
if you're using an accelerator uh open
acc
cuda opencl something like that and it
really varies across platforms
cuda's not available everywhere of
course it's proprietary
other things like opencl may or may not
be available
and so when you look at it in that
context really
and this is this is generally for the
dsoc program is first
how do you design that architecture i
show up on your doorstep and say i have
10 billion transistors they're yours
what do you want on your chip
how do you analyze your workload and so
part of our project focuses on looking
at sdr to try to
understand what what those features
would be
the second one is programmability
you know how you know is it really
possible to design an application with
one language and programming model
that will run across all these
architectures and you get reasonable
performance out of them
that's you know a question but it's
going to
impact all these teams writing
applications and software
they only have so much time to spend on
science and
importing software and so this was
um the the darpa program uh and it has
you know three different areas some of
them i've already mentioned and i'll
talk more about in a moment
but the important part here is you
really do assume
that you're going to have you know socs
and they're going to be very diverse
i'm talking way more than an armed cpu
and an armed gpu
they may have inference engines they may
have fpgas
and other things on them and and you've
already heard about some of the
complexity dealing with those when you
just
just have one and so
the overall structure of our project
really started out like this
you know we were looking at applications
we're using a
ontology framework to try to capture
the differences and the properties of
things in sdr
then the programming system is what
seong's going to talk about this is
really static analysis and code
generation
so if you're going to run you know your
sdr module on an fpga you just heard a
great talk about
what all goes into that right is there
any way we can simplify that
and then next you've got the runtime
system
and and you know there's a big question
there you know will lennox evolve to
handle
all these heterogeneous processors and
memories that are coming its way
or will that be handed off to another
runtime system
and we've developed a prototype runtime
system that i'll tell you a little bit
about
that's trying to explore that space and
then finally
is the the hardware and and several of
the teams
in dsoc are actually building hardware
we're not but we're reaching out and
making use of some of the more complex
systems out there
um and this is just a kind of a timeline
of how we see this
manifesting itself over time um
i'll skip that due to time so
let's just talk a little bit about the
range of hardware
that we are thinking about so so as i
mentioned earlier we
we run on summit right now and this
schematic you see it's a 200 petaflop
system at oak ridge
it's got 27
000 voltage gpus in it and and they're
all configured in this
node schematic you see here where you've
got
six gpus and two power nines
you know getting all those programming
models that i was talking about to work
properly and efficiently on that is very
complex
and then you add the fact that you've
got thousands of other nodes like this
that are communicating at the same time
and potentially doing i o
and it's very dynamic uh a very dynamic
system
we just heard a nice talk about fpgas
and being able to use them
for for signal processing we're looking
at those
and then more recently we've been
looking at nvidia's
jetson and so this is uh again it's an
soc but it's very much an aggressive
design
it has arm cores it has a voltage gpus
smaller than what you get on a v100
it's got a deep learning accelerator and
and some other
things like vision processors and and
vision processing accelerators
you know that's when you get right down
to it that's what we think the future is
going to look like we're going to have
you know thousands of skus of different
types of processors
and you're just going to buy the one
that fits your
your niche and then of course there's
snapdragon
this is the one that we're focusing on
this year and and it
isn't is not as well known but more
popular than
than the xavier that i just mentioned
because they're they're cell phone chips
right
they're very complex they've got arm big
and little cores
they have vector accelerators they've
had a tensor accelerator like a
training engine and then different
codecs and things like that in addition
to all the i o for co
connectivity to 5g and so on so
it's it's a very growing space and it
seems to be accelerating
so just a word about some of the
application studies that we're doing
and we have some tools that we'll make
available if you're interested in
looking at those
so when we put together apps
we're you know we're not experts in sdr
we're learning a lot and so we wanted to
go out and get some
workflows that would allow us to to
understand
how to profile and how to analyze these
we started with the wi-fi one
and it's in part because we really
understand how to measure the
performance of that
on a on a application level you know if
you do a file transfer and you're
running it across this flow
you can get some real feedback as to
error rates
as well as throughput and so
that's uh that's something that we've
been studying
um we've also built tools and
and these tools that really focus on the
ontologies and the performance analysis
that i mentioned earlier
the you know the first few we're really
looking at all the flows in the system
and the later ones are more for
profiling that so we built some
frameworks that let you
put these flows up run them for say 30
seconds and then do a profile
of where you're spending your time in
the flows
this is an example of of where some of
the time is going
and you know it's it's pretty much a
normal profile
the you know one of the questions is you
know are we getting representative flow
graphs and
you know is 30 seconds really sufficient
the cooler looking analysis is this
block
proximity analysis and so what we did
was look at sea grant and some of the
other
repos we had access to and what you see
in this graph over here is really a
networking diagram where the nodes
represent basically how many times
they're used and the
and the weights on the edges represent
connections between those and workflows
so
and this is useful for example if you're
trying to combine
operators that you can put on a on an
soc that's coming down the line or maybe
optimize
by creating a new module for example
and that was i let me see if i got the
uh yeah so
all of these tools are available down
here on github
we'd love feedback on them so
next working our way down uh the
programming systems is where we've been
spending a lot of time recently as well
as the runtime
system so i'm going to let sayong tell
you about our programming strategy
yeah i'll talk about the pruning system
that we used to pull the gradient of
loss to the heterogeneous devices this
gives the overview of the system as you
can see we use
two compilers the base one one is the
the open arg and here the llbm openoc is
the homegrown compiler developed by us
and we use the multiple programming
models like uh the openmp openhc
iris and heap cuda opencl so
by looking at this figure it may not be
to understand what's going on in the
flowing system so let's look at the
concrete example
so this shows how we pulled your
coordinate blocks to the headline device
using our framework
so basically what we assume is that user
can write a program
using the high-level programs like
openmp opencc in this example suppose
that
user writes a community block using
openhcg then our compiler performed
sources translation and generated output
program depending on the target adapter
that means that
if you want to run your own connected
plug on the nvidia gpu then
our compiler generate the output task
and it will run on the nvidia gpu and
if you want to run your the blocks on
the for example arm or other geometry
like
cpu then our pro compiler will
automatically generate output openmp
program and running on the dojo
architecture likewise
depending on the target architecture our
compiler automatically generate output
kernels
and one good thing about our framework
is that no matter how different type of
output models are used we use a common
runtime called iris that's
another runtime system that we developed
by ourselves so
one benefit of having common runtime
interfaces that
you can write application where one task
is running on the gpu using
cuda and another test running on the cpu
using openmp and
yet another task running on the fpga
using openshift something like that so
the kind of true intimidating of the
multiple different output models are
possible by using our framework
and we also support several other new
one like a
ship another tpu frame model developed
by the
the amd we also support like another new
one called the sql but i will not talk
detail about these new phone models
and for example if you want to put your
coordinator blocks on the jbl like
soc then we can use the the cuda for the
jbl gpu and open it for the jb cpu
and this shows the the code structure of
the openness block as you know the
original opening
gr blocks are written as a c plus plus
class
and we follow the same structure that
means that if you want to write your own
openhcc gel block then you have to
write this type of class but one common
requirement is that
every opennessy block should inherit the
common the parent class called the glhcc
basic
block what it does is that it
initialized the data structure used by
the open
openness runtime and it also assigned a
unique
logical thread id to each block instance
actually
the reason why we need the kind of the
parent class is because the
multi-threading issue as you know that
is learned in the in
the morning session original kinetic
framework provide multi-stream that
means that multiple gr blocks can
execute by the multiple different
threats
but the problem is that our openness
runtime also supports
multi-threading but the problem is that
original coordinator block
the framework used uh the c plus plus
the boost threading library based
multi-threading while
openac runtime is the the open based
voltage threading so
two systems does not know each other so
two to handle the multi-selected safety
issue by
integrating two different programming so
what we did is that
we introduced the concept of the logical
thread by using the logical thread id
that opens runtime node what kind of the
thread local data
structure should be used so it's a low
level detail about how to enforce the
stress safety
when we integrate multiple systems but i
don't explain all the details but
anyway in this open hcc block
we provide two implementation one is the
reference cp implementation which is
exactly the same as the original
kundalini block
and openness implementation that's the
openness version of the reference
provision
if you write the basic openness
implementation
it will perform the three type of task
first at the beginning of the invocation
you should copy the data from the host
memory to device memory and
launch the device kernel and at the end
of the execution we have to copy the
result back to the host memory
this shows the example translation of
the openness block as you can see in the
left it shows the simple openness
block for the the gl log module
what we did here is that in addition in
on top of the existing cp implementation
we just add one line of the openness
iterative then
our compiler automatically generates the
output host program and the kernel
program depending on the
target architecture and this shows the
example workflow
where we used our own open htr block
so as you can see here type workflow use
our gr openhash block
on the other hand param workflow use the
original reference gl blocks
so the only difference is that both
vocabulary the same thing
but one use the openness block the other
is the reference cpu implementation
and this shows the the basic management
scheme for the openness
enabled gr workflow so because the
openstack button not
after finishing available device corner
execution then we have to write data
back to host but in this case there are
some inefficiency for example
if you look at the openness of blog on
blog tool
actually if you look at the green
colored data we have three copies and
there are some
data transfers between host and gpu but
we don't have to do that
because the second the openness block
also runs on the same device indicated
we don't have to do
unnecessary data transfer between
hosting the gpu so
what we did is that if we know that both
producer blocks and consumer blocks
running on the same device then we can
reduce
unnecessary memory transfer between host
and the device
and this shows the example output of the
the sample workflow
and let's look at the performance
comparison what we did here is that
we compared the performance of the
openhcg block based workflow versus the
original cpu implementation based
workflow
then in this figure red
the block means that each openness is
blocked and
green blank means it's reference cp
implementation so so if
the both blocks label the same thing
that means that it does the same
algorithm but one is implemented openhcc
the other implemented reference cpu
and here what we did is that we run the
both
openc workflow and the representative
workflow on the
same cpu as i said before
two implementation reference cpu
implementation and openness
implementation so if we
target the cpu then even openhcc blocks
will just use the simple the original
represent cp implementation so in this
case we have to
see that both open hd block and the
reference cpu block should run equally
but as you can see in the for example
d2k do you want to d2k
our openness blocks a little bit
performed better than the reference cpu
block because when we implement the
electron cpu version inside the openness
block
we applied very simple caching
optimization that causes some
performance difference
let's look at the next case in this case
what we did is that
we uploaded the openness block again on
the cpu but using the opening at the
back in the parameter that means that
instead of using the reference cpu
implementation openness block use the
openmp implementation of
that block so here we can see
in some blocks openhcc plus performs
better than the reference cpu
information but in other blocks like
the b and c still reference cpu version
performs better on the opening
block why because some of the original
grenade implementation was
characterized using the fork library
that means here what we compared
that the the version parallelized in
openmp multi-threading versus the
version factorized in the vocal library
so let me show that depending on the
characteristic
sometimes it's better to use the
vectorization and sometimes it's better
to use
the multi threading
and next what we did here is that we
offload the openness blocks
gpu but without any optimization about
the memory transfer
as you can see here even though we
offload the computation to the gpu
because of the extra over for the memory
transfer between hosts and the device
in most cases gpu performed worse than
the cp version
because of the memory change for
overhead but when we applied our memory
transfer optimization we could remove
some
unnecessary memory transfer so in the
case in most cases openness
block performed better than cpu block
but one there is one exception
block a in this case still openness
and the openness performance works in
the reference cpu it is because the
original
cpu implementation was factorized during
the folk library that means that
still we compare against vectorization
on cpu versus
paralyzed on gpu so depending on the
computation it may be still
better to run on the cpu in the
vectorization but in most other cases
if you we can upload the computation to
the gpu and
optimize the unnecessary memory transfer
then we can be the problems of the
original reference cpu
and this is a little bit more
compressible i'll skip that
and so what we can learn from here is
that
once you create your blocks using the
openhcg and create a workflow using
openhc blocks then
you can create one workflow that can run
on the multiple different type of device
together that means that
part of the your blocks run on the gpu
and part of your block run on the cpu
another part of blocked on the fpga the
kind of true mixing of the
the heterogeneous devices possible if
you use this framework
thank you see young so uh just one thing
i want to say about that diagram
um we modified the new radio so that we
could add some attributes
to the blocks that actually let you say
where to co-locate
the the blocks ideally that would happen
automatically somewhere along the way
so there'd be a phase where you could
you could basically unify some of those
blocks into a super block and then put
them on an fpga for example
and so we're running a little short on
time i want to
tell you about iris so iris is our
runtime system
and so um we've looked around there's a
lot of runtime systems out there
we we didn't find one that ran on all
the platforms with all the different
programming models we wanted to run
for the reason seyong mentioned you know
some
nodes just don't support certain
programming models well
and so in some cases openmp is a great
i'm sorry opencl is a great choice
on things like xavier opencl is not not
there so you have to use kudo
and openmp and so we created this to
help both
orchestrate the data movement and launch
launch and manage
tasks across a diverse set of system
uh architectures um we have several
different
models here uh there we have a memory
model
that also will track with a directory
where your data is in these different
devices
and inject data movement into the
execution of the tasks if necessary
and it really looks it looks like a dag
so
you know everything in computer science
at some point seems to get back to dags
but uh
that that seems to be working for us
we're not talking about millions of
nodes we're talking about dozens or
maybe a few hundred uh
nodes in our dag and then and then
sayong talked about the programming
models
here's an example of what we're running
across today so
with iris you can take it and run it on
this node for example that has
xeon voltas i'm sorry pascals and
stratix 10 in it you can run it on a
summit node
using the requisite programming model on
each chip and then it runs on
radeon xavier and snapdragon and they
list out we list out what
what software stack we use to do that i
don't have a demo i didn't think i had
time for it but here's snapshots of it
booting on
all of those platforms and you can get a
feel for for how it does that
um here it's you know identifying that
it has the cuda platform available
and loading the shared object for that
and skipping things like hip
and uh and opencl
so the task scheduling is interesting
many of you already know about task
scheduling so
the thing i want to mention here is that
you know we're actually getting
the fun part now we've got this nice
framework that has many mechanisms in it
to let us schedule things
but we want to start exploring the
device selection policies now
you could do a simple thing like have a
hint a pragma that says
run all of these tasks on a gpu but we
could also look at things like the
profile based or the ontology based or
or one of the original ideas we looked
at was
using a performance model to give you a
rough indication of where a task should
be performed
and so and then and then once you have
that the task scheduler
executes that on the ready queue every
time
i've got a simple example here of a
saxby
and this is running on the xavier using
the gpus and the
arm cpus basically what we want to do is
run
sax beyond the the the a times x on the
gpu
and the y on the cpu and so one of the
things that i mentioned was that we we
do have dependencies
i'm running short so i'm going to speed
through this there's a c
plus plus interface to iris and there's
a python interface tyrus the python
interface is right here
it's a lot easier to explain you create
you know
data regions with iris then you you can
launch these tasks and these tasks
point to code for example right there's
the cuda code
that gets launched when iris submits
this task and it's called up for
execution
and you have to do the transfers and an
identification of
you know how big the data is there's
also the openmp version
we have to execute a little pre and post
execution code for these
but we think we can automate that with
things like open art
and then here's the execution uh the
memory management
so in this diagram it's not it doesn't
really stand out very much but
basically what happens is when you
identify these read write dependencies
on the different data regions you're
basically telling iris
look there's a potential inconsistency
there and so you need to
to manage that so it has a directory and
it
it knows to go in and move the data
from one device to another based on the
task being completed
all right i'll jump forward let me uh so
the other thing was just
that we're looking at efficiency we're
trying to get get this
execute where we can do almost 90 000
tasks per second on both the cpu and the
gpu
it's online so feel free to take a look
at it and let us know what you think
and with that i'd like to thank you know
fostom and sdr
and darpa and doe for for funding and
inspiring our work
thank you
you