thank you so i am here again
for those who were not here one hour ago
i am a researcher at ibm
research and i will present now another
piece of the puzzle of this uh
epochs project that we are leading at
ibm so i will
very quickly skip this knowledge and
same acknowledgement as before so same
people
thank you to all of them uh in the
interest of time i will move forward
so uh
again i mean i have said this already
and
at this time of the day i think i have
already seen maybe
four or five talk trying to motivate uh
this idea of uh hardware specialization
right
genius chip so i don't need to go too
much in detail the
the hardware specialization era is
already here
this is a interesting uh die photo of a
cell phone
chip processor where you can see for
example that in addition to the
traditional
general purpose cpu your today you have
also gpus
one or more and you have plenty of
acceleration in genes for different
functions in in the cell phone so this
is a very nice
example of a highly heterogeneous
process
but i i mean the question is
how do we schedule applications
processes
threads in this uh kind of heterogeneous
chip
right i mean it's not it's not
straightforward because uh the
conventional schedulers like linux linux
scheduler is not optimized for that
uh this is true right in order to
exploit the characteristics of a
heterogeneous chip so
we think that there is a need there is
at least a call
to think uh harder in terms of creating
more intelligent
and efficient scheduling schedulers for
hedogenous chips
and how does that impact on new radio
right so in my previous talk i presented
this era application where i show
this new radio ao 2.11p
transceiver but in the application there
was also a ros part with
multiple blogs doing different things
right bunch of stuff so
in general the message is today's
applications are
very heterogeneous in their nature so
it's not just about the hardware the
software is very
heterogeneous so in other words the
tetragenetic at software level in the
application is
driven the need for specialized hardware
right
actually in this flow graph we can see
that there are many blocks and all of
them are doing different stuff right
so
if we have to execute this program we
may have already an underlying chip with
some accelerators let's say
we may have an accelerator for the fft
we have we may have an accelerator for
vtrv
uh decoding we may have accelerator for
other stuff right
but as far as we know and this connects
i think very well with uh
this morning's talk by by marcus uh
the the current version of the new radio
scheduler
is not aware of this degree of the
heterogeneity
in the in the chip right which if
exploited properly
can provide significant benefit in terms
of drought put as well as power
performance efficiency improvement
actually i mean regarding the new radio
scheduler some prior work this is an
another paper from from bastian have
shown that some simple tweakings to to
the scheduler can
really provide some great improvement in
this case for
cash effectiveness right so we believe
that there is room for improvement for
example in terms of
scheduling on a telegenic chips
and this is the also the the the picture
i presented before i mean before when i
talked about the array i was
moving in this layer now i will be
moving in this operating system layer
but we are
with this project we are addressing the
entire hardware software
stack in this darpa dsoc program
so let's go into this idea of task
scheduling on heterogeneous platforms
i will present an open source tool that
we developed that is called stomp
which allows us to prototype scheduling
new scheduling policies in a very easy
and fast manner so let me introduce a
stump
a stump which stands for scheduling
techniques optimization in heterogeneous
multiprocessor i didn't want to put the
edge there so
this is but i wouldn't i wanted to have
it ingenious
uh it's an open source uh tool that
has allowed us to um prototype and
evaluate
new scheduling policies for
heterogeneous platform in a very agile
manner
that simple it's written in python and
it's very
easy to customize i mean a stomp user
can very easy
very easily uh create new scheduling
policies and plug those policy into
stump and
evaluate what happens if we want to
schedule let's say uh
a representative and array application
on a illustrative heterogeneous
processor right
in stomp there are basically three main
elements
we have tasks which are as you can
imagine the units of work
you can call them jobs processes threads
whatever
and these are the things that are
executed on our telegenius
processor right
in actually we talk about task types
right this is the most interesting part
we say this is an fft task this is a
decoding task this is a convolution task
right
then we have servers or processing
elements which are these
blue boxes here right i mean these are
your processing units in your in your
chip
you can have also different types of
processing elements general purpose
scores
gpus different type of accelerators
right this is all customizable
and then the most important part is the
scheduler this green box here
which will basically take tasks from
this queue and try to scale them across
the available
processing elements or servers right and
what we want to do is to allow the user
to write to write in a very easy manner
new
scheduling policies that can be plugged
into the scheduler for
easy let's say evaluation
so the task can arrive to this
central queue either probabilistically
or we can generate uh traces of tasks
from real executions
thus also have some attributes like for
example the service time
of a given task type on a given server
type right so we say let's see
this is an fft task that has this
service time on a general purpose core
on a gpu on an accelerator etc
we are also adding support for power
consumption so the task will also have
some power information associated
and the most important part is this i
mean the user can extend
uh the base scheduling policy python
class
and create its own uh scaling policy in
a very easy manner right this is the
logic that will
instruct the scheduler what to do with
the task at the scheduling time
so it's a very simple idea uh but very
very
at the end it's a very useful tool
so how a storm works internally there
are two uh
components one is the meta scheduler
that red box they are meta and the other
one is the the scheduler this
green box here called sched they
communicate communicate to each other
through these two cues
a ready queue and a completed queue
and the idea is very simple meta
basically will do some pre-processing on
task let's say uh to connect more what
with what you usually deal with that can
be
for example new radio blocks right so
let's say
meta will pre-process the new radio
block that had to be executed in the
system
and we'll for example track dependencies
and those
blocks those stacks that are ready will
be put in this queue for the scheduler
to
place that block in a processing element
right
when the task or or radio block
completes then the scheduler will put
that back on this completed queue so the
meta is notified all this
is done and can keep tracking
dependencies right
uh the input of a stomp stomp is all all
this
here plus this here so the input comes
as you may imagine in the form
of directed a cyclic graph dax right
where a dac may represent let's say an
application a
new radio flow graph and the nodes are
the tasks or the
blocks that we have to execute
so as i said meta does some
pre-processing on this
task one interesting thing that
meta does is to compute the rank
associated to each
task to each radio block to execute a
rank is basically a metric
that tells us i mean uh how fast we
should execute
that task right so high rank means we
have to execute this
very fast i mean but there is maybe some
real-time constraint that we have to
meet
lower rank means when we have more slack
we can wait a little bit more so
basically the the tasks are order in
this this ready queue by
rank how do we compute rank that is
implement implementation specific the
user can define
uh what rank means in he or she a
specific implementation but usually rank
is a function of the task priority
as well as the slack i mean the amount
of time that the task
has to complete as well as for example
the
task work worst case execution time
which usually is
running the tasks on the worst
processing element let's say the cpu
core right
so this is one possible formula for run
could be many others
and also meta can in some cases we can
enable
this feature that if a dog didn't
complete on time if the dog missed its
deadline
then meta may decide to drop that that
that completely in order to reduce
traffic and give more
chances to other dags to complete on
time so we have also that
option available so the scheduler
which is the other box in this
in this diagram is where as i explained
before is where the user
will plug he his or she
scheduling policy right so this is very
easy actually i mean
the only thing we have to do is to
extend this base scheduling policy
python class
more specifically what we have to
provide is an implementation for this
assigned task to server function which
basically
tells the scheduler what to do with
tasks in the req
at scheduling time in this for example
in this very
simple implementation this is just for
illustration purposes only
what we are doing is we are taking uh
the task
at the head of the queue this one here
right
and we try to place that task i mean the
scheduler will try to place that
that task on the fastest processing
element let's say an accelerator
if that processing element is not
available then the task will remain in
the head of the cube this is what
is implemented here very easy stuff just
for illustration purposes only we want
to make
more intelligence scheduling policies of
course right
then we can of course easily configure
stomp with different parameters for
example we can indicate
what scheduling policy we want to use
right so
in this case we are saying sk stomp to
go and look for
file call python script called simple
policy version 3
under the policies folder right and then
we can configure the number of
processing elements we are saying that
we have in this example
eight general purpose cores two gpus and
one fft accelerator
and then we define our tasks right for
example we say that we have tasks of
type fft with different service time for
the different processing element types
and we may have other type of tasks also
let's say
decoders or or convolutions or whatever
right
so it's very easy to configure let me
show a very simple
example how this works right let's say
we have an input dag of
five tasks of five let's say new radio
blocks
uh which is that one showed there
and then we what does the meta scaler
does is try to
determine what is the the deadline for
this dag to complete which in this case
is defined as the
execution time of the longest path the
critical path in this case there is
0 1 3 and 4 in the worst in the worst
case meaning running on in this case on
the cpu
so for that critical path running on the
cpu that is
uh around one is 1100 unit of time by
the way stop stop is unitless so the
user defines the meaning of a unit of
time
so then at time zero at the very
beginning meta will take the first
route now there and we compute
its rank using whatever formula for the
rank has been defined in this case
we are using that formula and for this
specific uh
initial case the rank is is is very high
it's infinite
um i don't want to go into much detail
here because of a
lack of time but what for that first
node basically
meta will take that now we'll compute
the run we'll put it in the red queue
and that task will execute
after the scheduler places on on the
processing element that task will
execute let's say that
since everything was available in the
chip that task was
executed not in a ship in a cpu but on
an accelerator so instead of taking 500
units of time it took 10 units of time
which is good because that gives us some
let's say time back for the rest of the
task in the in the dac right so
at time 10 after that task completed
then meta will update the rank of
of task 1 and 2 which are the ones that
now are ready because they satisfy their
dependencies right
so using the same formula as before we
compute ranks of task one and rank of
task two
and in this case in this simple example
rank of one of task one is
larger than of task two so the next one
that will
go into the ready queue is that task
number one the decoder there
that will be scheduled by the scheduler
uh
based on the on the scheduling policy
that the scholar is using at that time
and this process continues for all the
tasks in the dark until
the full dag completes basically
in a storm we also support uh multi-dog
execution meaning that we can have
multiple of these dogs running at the
same time right
in that in that case basically the meta
scaler will keep track of dependencies
across all the dags and will will update
the ranks also across all the dags
at the same time there is no let's say
sequentiality in that regard right
but this is another feature of a stone
so let me show you some preliminary
numbers that we have generated with the
stump for
an illustrative let's say a new radio
example
so what we did is we we defined the
trace of dags with
1000 dags right let's let's think about
these darks as
1000 new radio flow graph right
in this case uh two different type with
five
and two tasks with five and two
blocks right so very simple ones and we
assign priorities to these dags
one and two randomly and we define the
deadline to for
that to complete as as i explained
before like the
length of the path the critical path
running on the worst
case processing element
in this case the cpus right and we find
three three simple task type fft
convolution and decoder
right and the metric of interest is the
number of dags let's say flow graph that
met their
uh real-time deadline uh during
execution right
so we created five simple scheduling
policy very simple i mean starting from
simple ones to more complex more
interesting ones
uh ts1 and ts2 are non-blocking
uh scheduling policies which basically
means that the scheduler will
look uh uh within a window of tasks in
the ready queue not just the one in the
head of the cube but the window
um and we'll try to schedule all of them
even if
one before couldn't be scheduled because
i mean there was
no availability accelerator it will keep
looking in that window this is why
these two are called non-blocking and
ts2 is a
it's a valuational variation of ts1
where
at the scheduling time not only the
scheduler will traverse that window but
we'll
keep in mind what was done with the
previous task in that window so we know
what
what was the scaling decision for the
previous task and that allows us to make
a little bit
better scheduling decisions but in these
two cases
meta is only used for uh dependency
tracking only right there is no run
computation in this case
so then we have like an improved version
of ts2
using meta for both dependency tracking
as well as a rank
computation right and we have these
three versions ms1 ms2 and ms3
where basically the difference is just
the formula that we use to compute the
rank right so for example in ms1 we use
the task deadline its average execution
time
across the all available processing
elements and the priority
uh in ms2 is again we use we compute the
rank as a function of the tax deadline
the maximum execution time across the
different processing elements and
priority
and ms3 the rank is computed as a
function of the available slack
and the maximum execution time as well
as the priority so
five different policies let's see what
we get
so what we get is something that we what
we expected
ms3 uh is uh the the most interesting of
these five
uh policies because it's the one that
allow us to
allow dogs to complete in time in the
most cases so this chart what is showing
is the percentage of that let's say
radio flow graph that complete within
the deadline
as a function of the five different
policies
for different arrival times of dax
and as i said we have two priorities of
dax right priority one and higher
priority two
so for example what we see here is that
ms3 for this particular case
allows all 100 of the high priority
dogs to complete within their deadline
right compared to
the other policy which is good right um
and you see this is about by the way
it's a very simple policy i mean we are
not doing
it's not rocket science right i mean
some simple tweaks can help us to
optimize
the scheduling so let me
have some time let me show this this is
a video recording of how to run
stump very simple also nothing that
will impress you um but
it's just a two minute videos as i said
we use these traces of uh of dags so we
have a script called trace generator
that would generate a synthetic trace of
of dags in this case we have one
thousand dags that arrive
at different arrival times so the second
field is the
the dag id and and this is the duct type
so we have one thousand
dags that arrive to our simulated system
right synthetic very simply trace we can
generate that from real execution too
then we configure stomp using this json
file
we indicate for example the policy that
we want to use
we can indicate for example well as i
said before i mean what processing
elements we have in our system
and lower below we also indicate the
different
task types right ffts convolutions and
i think we have also something else
decoder
so one way to execute the stump is with
the stomp main script
but then we have a more convenient
script called run all
which will run multiple configurations
of stomp
uh that can be easily
defined here the in the in the at the
beginning of that script we can
say which which policies we want to
evaluate uh what is for example
the arrival times etc so this script
will execute multiple
combinations at the same time which is
very convenient
so what the video is showing just is
just how do we call that
script we can indicate well
verbose dump everything on a csv
file and this is the input dac that you
the input that trace that you have to
use so right now it's in this example
it's only one combination so we are
actually executing one instance of a
stomp and passing all that
json uh string to to um
to configure that a specific execution
so it finishes and it generates
an output file that we can easily
process with another script that we call
collect
py that will just parse the output
and in this case this will print out for
example
we can we can print other things with in
this case the average response time of
all the dags
uh for for that specific simulation
right so very simple i mean
you can run that this learn and how to
run this in five minutes i mean it's
extremely simple so um
so let me let me wrap up here um
stomp is a is an effort that is uh in
in inactive development right and we are
considering thinking about some new
features to be added
uh for example like support for more
complete input trace format we want to
also generate more
statistics i think some interesting
things that i want to mention is that
as part of this new feature that we will
incorporate we
will have support for power modeling
it's not just about
performance throughput but also power
efficiency
and something that i think we think is
very very interesting we want to explore
more machine learning like
scheduling policies right what the five
policies that i show in the example
below
uh are relatively simply heuristics
we think that we can exploit some
machine learning techniques to do even
better
not necessarily we have to go to complex
deep learning right
we can talk about i don't know simple
decision trees for example right so we
want to go into into that area
and i am emphasizing this because this
is some
some interesting area where everybody
can eventually
collaborate or contribute if interested
right so we believe that
machine learning can can provide some
very good benefits when it comes to
scheduling of tasks in in heterogeneous
platforms
and we want to move from the abstract to
the more concrete
we are adding support to characterize
real
applications like for example real new
radio walls and generate
duct traces from those real execution
instead of just creating
synthetic duct traces right but the
stump is already
a very nice tool that provides plenty of
opportunities
to explore the the program domain and
generate conclusions so please i mean
check it out and play with it and
provide your feedback
you can check out the dev branch if you
want which provides more leading edge
features so please let us let us know if
there is any any feedback
that you can provide or in any way that
you think you can contribute or
collaborate
so thank you very much you won't see my
face again today this is my last thought