good morning good morning uh
so yeah i'm excited to talk to you about
the next generation of contribution
it's a little tongue-in-cheek title
hopefully to get your attention and wake
you up this morning on a on a bright
sunday after some lovely
lambic beers all weekend for those of
you
who would prefer to follow along if it's
easier for you to read on a local tablet
or device
i've uploaded these slides on speaker
deck slash mb broberg
i also tweeted it out so i'll give you a
second to find that if you need to
but yeah while i give that introduction
hi
i'm matt i'm a full-time technical
editor for opensource.com
we're really small team that produce a
lot of content
i'd love for all of you to consider
being authors if you're at this event
you
you absolutely have an open source story
to share i can tell you more about that
i also want to give a plug to brandeis
university in collaboration with the
open source institute is running a
really interesting master's course on
the business of open source
um i'm taking it right now and learning
a ton about all the things i don't know
about open source
that a lot of this community i believe
does so just to level set with you
how i'm walking into this i'm assuming
you are a seasoned open source
participant well i
am of the github generation of open
source tell you more of what that means
you could possibly maybe not recite the
uh
sff for freedoms off the top of your
head anyone willing to do that right now
okay never mind
um while i recently learned that osi and
fsf
are different i kind of definitely
conflated them more than i'd like to
admit
uh you think you've had to contribute
before git
i think that git is basically latin uh
in
in technology it's the only thing it's
the language franca so anything before
that didn't exist
we're all just oral tradition uh you're
probably active on irc
i'm active everywhere but irc and lastly
you care about your community as do i i
think if we can all create communities
where we care about each other and
people feel welcome we'll be on the same
page but i just figured i'd level set
with you all so
and you knew where i was coming from uh
because
i'm gonna just jump right in and say i
don't get irc uh when
i was every time i try to log into it i
end up getting into a bit of a tit for
tat with name serve
i'm not quite sure who i'm talking to
i'm not logged into the right place
i feel a little like a wizard which is
kind of cool because i'm a little behind
on my sysadmin skills these days
but ultimately i end up seeing a stream
of offensive spam and i'm confused as to
what channel i'm in and what's going on
and
that as led in the communities that
participated in where irc is a default
channel i'm
always told to you know go check the
manual the friendly manual that will
explain
in great detail how to use the the
tooling work
appropriately but i'm always left with
with the sense that
i don't get it and i feel kind of
ashamed about it i mean i've got a
degree in computer science
been in the tech industry for 10 years
after four years of
it work beforehand and i don't say that
to
to brag it's actually out of
embarrassment that like oh how can this
technology continue to elude me
on a day-to-day basis when i have this
foundation behind me
um but i think it comes from where what
my
point of origin was that like for me
open source started the day i made a
github
user and a user account and logged in to
do something
and i wanted to participate for the
first time i was very excited
pretty nervous about it and i was using
homebrew on mac for those that know the
package manager
and i opened my very first issue only
eight years ago
with a a bunch of junk about why the
package wasn't working for me and me
being confused about it
and to my absolute surprise and delight
immediately i hear from these people who
are uh really big names in that
community
in my stance and they actually told me i
didn't install git correctly on mac
it was a totally trivial issue no one
made me feel stupid at all though they
immediately pointed me towards helpful
documentation
and i felt like i had done something
like somebody else
has definitely felt that silly going
into the homebrew community and when
they look through issues
they will find that path ideally get to
the same positive conclusion
and see the welcoming people along the
way and i love that experience and it
really
set me up for the success towards as i
slowly iterated towards an open source
community
and an open source career focus because
my pathways all through proprietary i
started with a proprietary hardware
vendor
i found communities that are surrounding
proprietary technology
that live on a proprietary platform of
twitter and
i eventually joined a proprietary code
sharing site and found that to be really
open source and
fun to me and i got into open course
startups
that is a different conversation we can
talk about whether that works or doesn't
and the many ways in which it doesn't
and so on and so forth now i'm very much
centered around open source communities
as a focus of my career
i've got the joy of working at
opensource.com to get those stories out
further and to coach people through that
experience
and i continue to learn about why we
obsess about licenses
by coming to fosum and by taking courses
like i am
but my pathway is not the same as i know
many others have gone through
that started with irc just being a
logical simple thing
um but for me it's still it's still this
even though i understand where it comes
from and i understand it had its its
place in time
i feel as if it's not as inviting as
that incredible github issue that didn't
shame me or make me feel stupid
um ultimately whether that's a sign of
my posture syndrome
or or not is between me and my therapist
but as somebody who's as i like to say
on the easy setting
of contribution in in this world uh a
a concept taken from straight white male
the lowest difficulty setting there is
uh by john here i i understand i have
already a bunch of easy ways in which i
can be involved and not feel too
ashamed of things when they don't go
well that said if i can feel that
awkward i can definitely imagine other
people
who have a more difficult path towards
open source
who don't want to be as out there will
have more of a challenge
and also i want to talk about this is
because i'm doing
as i continue to read a lot more about
the inclusivity and
diversity challenges in the technology
space and try to inform myself while i
don't feel ever informed enough to give
a full lecture on it
i i do know i need to start making
changes in my own behavior
in order to improve this for those that
are going to be coming
forward now that are in their their
teens and their 20s and their 30s or
are people that are pivoting from other
parts and other industries and want to
participate
i do a lot of mentoring on the side for
people who are confused as to how they
can get involved in technology
and i'm consistently asked the same
question of where do i get involved
what do i do how do i do this open
source thing that all these companies
are looking to hire
for and i can't in good conscience say
jump on irc
and see how to get involved it's
confusing it
and it ultimately could make some people
feel uh like they
they shouldn't be pivoting into
technology that they shouldn't be there
and quite honestly it's not where their
community is the one that they're gonna
pursue
that they're gonna feel welcome in uh so
i think about how we can start to
change that and one of the talks that
really influenced me recently is by kk
uh creator of jenkins he had an
incredible talk at monktoberfest about
uh the that underrepresented people are
underestimated
but he also brought up this amazing
concept uh thank you
for margaret for for tweeting it so i
could quote it
uh about the curb cutting principle that
if you think about cutting the curb so
that people in wheelchairs can go up it
it actually helps a number of other
people along the way it helps people
with strollers or with heavy luggage
bags or
anyone with any form of walking
disability people who have sight def
difficulties by creating an easier
on-ramp for
a specific target people you have a halo
effect you end up positively impacting
all these other people
and i think about what uh what we're
doing as community leaders to do that
for
our our early onboarding for people who
maybe don't i can't just quite get up
that lo ledge right away how do we make
it easy from the beginning
we may have a greater impact than we
even realized
so to put it in some context i
understand when irc
came out and became the de facto
standard it's because there's a lot of
empty space around it was
irc or nothing to communicate i guess
telnetting and reading each other's
things is something that i've read about
as well but i'll just put that aside i
don't know it very well
but if we fast forward to today the the
stats i've been able to find is that irc
is hovering around 400 000
active users in the last year or so and
we look at some of the other synchronous
communication channels that people are
talking about
we've got microsoft teams as much as
people have to use that for work and
don't necessarily love it
there's 13 million people on that slack
people love it
open source communities hate it 12
million users
riot.i am very impressive that they've
grown to well over
11 million users google chat it's like
slowly waiting in the background
but at 4 million and that's just
synchronous communication channels and
that's just recently if we zoom out even
further and think about like the ways in
which we interact with communities in
the technology space
that's an interesting noise
i'm going to keep talking while somebody
figures that out so if we think about
where communities are talking across the
industry
you've got twitter which is my default
place to
conversate with community members at 126
million users
telegram is way more massive than i ever
realized at 200 million and a lot more
open source communities are talking
there
discord is humongous reddit is a
complete beast when we think about it
is that getting pretty distracting i
think it's pretty distracting i also
don't know how to fix it
true hold on all right jazz hands for a
moment and i'll just leave this for your
curiosity
not that one
uh can we just give a little love to the
box please yeah
if that worked that was very weird
okay that's exciting
electricity is strange everybody it's
probably some sort of
the noise from the audio channel of the
hdmi yeah
the irc gods are upset at you yeah i
know i definitely
[Laughter]
thank you
it's a video guy that was amazing
cool okay so there there is a lot more
competition there's a lot more places
people are conversing about open source
than ever before
and that that can be quite um it's quite
exciting but it's also
uh it starts to make that little dot of
irc in the middle look
maybe less to be centric even though
it's center of the picture
it's definitely not the dominant place
people are talking now
oh man i'm gonna like stay up
so just a quick side by side by no means
uh
inclusive of everything that's important
to setting up a healthy community
a healthy place for people to converse
we think about just
the sign up experience the mobile access
the inboard on
the in-app onboarding of users
accessibility options
uh just comparing irc to yes the hated
but often used slack
it starts to look like okay i can
understand why people aren't jumping on
the platform that's existed for the
longest
there are other options that are
definitely maturing but the default
option
is shifting and i'd like us all to shift
with it
and quite honestly one of the more
important parts is why are we using
synchronous communication
i am not always on and i doubt you want
to be too
um it's rarely the right place to start
so
i want to take a take a moment and talk
about why i mean
just to list five i think we can go
through a hundred each one of us has at
least one
uh that it requires it always on
participation there's this
expectation that it sets a default of
immediacy
uh there's no continuity of knowledge uh
when you use synchronous communication
if i answer a question today three days
later you ask the same one
you get the same question it's it's
often not a place that is building the
type of community that we're trying to
foster
or or maybe it is but it's it's not
alone there are other pieces to the
puzzle
so i'm going to pivot to talking about
community channels and
my theory of operation it's a model
that's worked for me
all models are wrong some are more
helpful than others this one is mine
um well this one actually isn't to start
this is somebody else's
so in the great good place there's this
wonderful concept of uh your third place
where like traditionally your first
place being home where you have a
certain sense of identity and purpose
and
and meaning your second place being your
work which is uh
in our culture is is just as dominant if
not the dominant place that you live in
and there is this magical third place
that we're all searching for
it's a place where we feel comfortable
and feel connected
it's where you relax in public encounter
familiar faces and make new
acquaintances
take a moment if think of some community
you participate in
and doesn't it check all those boxes
right away that sense of feeling
comfortable and connected
to other people there are a bunch of
other reasons
that it's interesting it's a great
theory of operation and i think we're
all building
third places as we build open source
communities and places where our
communities
interact so to take that in mind i kind
of break it into this quadrant
that works for me where i think about
the synchronous communication
which i don't think is the greatest
default but it is
fantastic for casual and high throughput
conversations
it's the place of banter where you start
to build some sort of connection
while asynchronous is really the
definitive record of
what is the right answer and what is the
wrong answer we all
end up making these static web pages for
things like this there are a bunch of
other tools that are useful
there's also the power and importance of
face-to-face connection
many of us flew drive took a train to be
here to make face-to-face
connections with each other because no
matter how much we work fully remotely
no matter how much we connect with each
other
as much as i love that over the internet
experience we still need this there's
something special about this
this space lastly i think it's important
to think intentionally about your news
channel like
how are you feeding information and
distributing that context to people that
care about what you're doing
it's cathedral in the bazaar like that
you need some place where i'm
being regularly updated with information
so that i know i'm making an impact on
what i'm doing
so what are some default ones
synchronous we've talked about
asynchronous you know google groups
that's the logo for it that no one knows
about
there's github is actually pretty decent
at asynchronous communication
people kind of bend the way you use
issues to be more about collaboration
discourse is absolutely fantastic
whether you like the creator or not it's
a really powerful
conversation and threading platform
that's open source
and you can deploy yourself or use their
service stack overflow is another form
of it
and they have their ability to branch
off and use your own face to face we all
go to them we're at a conference right
now user groups and local meetups are
important
news for better or worse twitter is
where a lot of us hang out
it's certainly been my my choice and
it's where i know a lot of you from
um but then there are infinite number of
newsletters and other places where we
get our news
so to see this in practice i just want
to give a couple examples
so mozilla recently did a huge
renovation of how they communicate
internally and externally with their
community
they landed on riot which i think is
really telling that it's a maturing
technology
uh it's it's a there's great research if
you look up mozilla's synchronous
communication
conversation why they chose riot they
also want to discourse for their
asynchronous so if you join the mozilla
community they have a whole platform you
can jump on they have
incredible mozfest and then their
mozilla blog is really really detailed
they are always pushing information out
and i think it's so interesting they do
a great job of having syndicated
channels
so they push it out to twitter they push
it out to their newsletter subscribers
it's like a really tight way of staying
connected to this broad
and diverse open source community if we
look at go the go programming language
for instance
they've defaulted to slack there are
many many thousands of people
talking about go on slack on a regular
basis they use google groups quite a bit
as well as github github issues to
communicate with each other for
asynchronous
there's a ton there's gophercon which is
the unofficial official place to be
it's where people go year round and go
meetups are all over the world
and then they have the go blog but
what's interesting about them they have
more of an unofficial presence on
twitter
and email and newsletters they've great
podcasts and
uh and newsletters to distribute it out
go times one from changelog that's not
an official part of the go language but
it is an unofficial place that the
community circles
last but not least let's talk about
kubernetes because everybody else is
they are also on slack and it's really
interesting default channel is more
github it's a lot github-centric
while the the newsletter excuse me the
discussion
lists are a little bit of a back
back channel while the face-to-face is
really interesting they do
so many videos online so they're using
zoom and they're using
youtube to extend that face to face it
doesn't quite substitute the in person
because that community is getting so big
they've added this virtual element as
well i think video chats can be really
powerful in that way
in these distributed communities and
their news is just as deep
just as distributed people filling in
the gaps that they don't
but the official channel is always their
blog
so if you're looking for some sane
defaults if you're building a community
and you
you find this framework kind of useful
i'd say if you're starting from scratch
i'd really recommend not going with
synchronous
from the start and trying to build a
place where you answer questions for
people and you can create some dialogue
amongst the frequent visitors
start to get that sense of belonging uh
building and then
once people really start to know each
other and you need that side channel you
need that conversation
you can do that through synchronous but
wait until the time zones aren't a
factor
and that you have a sense of culture
already discourse is a great
asynchronous communication channel i'm
really enjoying using it it's highly
customizable it's really easy
relatively easy to run on your own or to
they have a very reasonable cost
structure
if you want to pay for it if you're
looking to do face to face from the
start
look at kubernetes way in which they do
the community meetups they're
really interesting ways to get people
connected i was on one recently with 40
people from around the world
who were all talking about the bugs that
they had squashed that week and ways in
which they made contributor experience a
little easier
i can't talk about many communities that
have that level of scale and that number
of people that during the day are
jumping in and talking to each other
and not all of them were paid to do it
there's a lot of volunteers a lot of
people who are trying to grow their
career
and the news whether you love it or not
the centralization of twitter is really
effective
i look forward to understanding mastodon
a little bit more to see if that is a
collaborative place but i think it's
going to be an and not an ore
and then newsletters are really powerful
it's a great place to be
if you're interested in running your own
website having a blog that then
syndicates to those is really effective
so that all matters because contribution
matters
so just to pivot back into the
conversation of what are we all trying
to do we're trying to build
communications of practice
because the actual footage of people
trying to recruit contributors is like a
hungry hungry hippos game
no idea if that reference works
internationally but i love it anyway
it's a great game
just to look at one of the hundreds of
sites that try to say good first
contributors
first contributors.github.io these are
just some of the amazing organizations
who are desperate for new contribution
to give a shout out exorcism is one of
the best place to learn a programming
language and it's run by brilliant
people
all of these others are great too but uh
everyone is very interested
in getting new contributions so clearly
there's a lot of demand
which means we need to meet people where
their expectations are not ask them to
meet
meet us where we already are because if
we think about
the contributor experience early on back
in the irc only days like almost
everyone who is contributing
or who is talking about what they were
doing was also contributing to something
because it was one of the same you had
to have that level of skill
um but now it's kind of shifted that the
contributors is a very small peak
in the potential contributor field and
if we think about it
there's like a little dot that's ready
to roll off in either direction of the
actual maintainers of the software
thank you um so i i just want
to reinforce that communication channel
channels are exceptionally important and
they set an expectation
and we want that expectation to be
something where people feel incredibly
welcome and don't feel like they're
being told to try harder
and maybe one day they'll be worthy of
being an open source contributor
it's going to be multi-channel it's just
that's the new standard that everybody
is using multiple channels if you try to
break it into this grid i think it gets
a little bit more sane
so you don't have a half a dozen
synchronous communication channels and
no place for the right and wrong answers
like a discourse
but lastly i just want to make a shout
out to the idea that
any place that is contributing to open
source is an open source community
so whether they're using slack or
otherwise you may not like that choice
but it is not necessarily the wrong
choice
we can try to grow people towards an all
open source community
and understand the nuances of it but
it's taken me eight years to get there
and i'm finally starting to get it and
i'd like to grow that way
but i don't want to shame or make anyone
else feel unwelcome because they're not
where i am today
so i hope we can all meet people where
they are today and help them grow into
being open source advocates and
understand the nuance of it
i really thank you for your time and i
look forward to hearing more of your
talks as well
thanks
that was super easy yeah
hello um so distinction being async and
synchronized
what i have experienced is that most
time when a community have an
asynchronous community is that they
demand that people installed the app on
the phone and use
push notification with them become a
synchronized
communication method anyway and if you
don't want to install the app
you more or less get frozen out okay so
i'm hearing the question is like is
notifications
and that sense that asynchronous
converts into synchronous in most cases
i completely understand what you're
saying there i think there is uh
a level that all technology these days
is trying to steal our attention all the
time
and trying to get us to turn
notifications on and be as real time as
possible
i think it's not a requirement i'm part
of about a dozen different discourse
services right now and i just kind of
schedule out time well i turned off
notifications
and i log into the web apps and and go
in there on my own time
so i i think it does take more
mental effort than it it should i don't
think it's a necessity to think of it
that way
and if you think about the experience
like let's say the same strategy
where like i just logged in three days
later and looked for updates
if i do that in a synchronous
communication channel i've got to scroll
back
infinitely and try to thread in my head
the conversations that happened
while in like a discourse or stack
overflow experience they're all spread
out with q and a's in their own separate
categories
so more advocating for that structure as
opposed to the unstructured
if your goal is to get to a simple like
yes no definitive answer
if your goal is to get people to banter
with each other like choose a
synchronous channel that is definitely
the place to do it
leslie how am i doing on time more
questions oh cool yeah he's got the mic
i didn't mention the mailing lists i did
not mention mailing lists i would
uh highly recommend uh so i did mention
google list but i didn't give mailman
the respect it deserves i'm on
an infinite number i'd prefer not to be
quite honestly uh with all due respect
uh discourse has a great um built-in
feature where you can use it like a
multi-threaded mailing list
um it will so i think it's a one-to-one
replacement with a better user
experience for those less familiar with
it
while also providing a mailman like
experience mailing list
so i'd love for you a disagreement
that it where we could learn a lot from
it but yeah that's that's my current
stance on it
especially for the expectations that
there are today of just a full-fledged
uh friendly experience i'd say discourse
is a
better choice to start
seeing the hand up there don't really
want to throw this
hi um it's just in regards to um dealing
with actually setting up all these
channels and
form of communication as a
community manager for example how would
you
install perhaps unique code of conduct
for each of these channels or would it
be a blanket
all channels how you interact with each
other so like for example
if it was the this synchronous you would
have to perhaps say no spamming no
doing x y and z great that kind of
aspect
yeah absolutely so i'm hearing the the
question is
that like do you have a per channel code
of conduct and per channel
channel documentation or is it
centralized firm believer you have to
have one url to rule them all
that's kind of a different conversation
but like by default like
your documentation should lead to one
place and give as brief an overview as
possible
and then link to other things so i think
a default code of conduct for across the
spectrum because that's
you're all still participating in one
community across the channels is really
important
um and then yes there may be some
specific nuance like how to what's our
reticule
versus how we use discourse and those
instructions can be in those different
channels
you