about rage coding but the history
of error detection correction and how
that led to rage coding
so thank you for coming um
and it's not working anymore
hmm
one second
okay there we go nice cool
so who am i so my name is danny
and i work for soft time in the uk where
we're working
on building a ceph appliance i've mainly
worked for
open source companies in the past so
companies like linbit and codethink
and i run a non-profit in the uk called
open source events
where we do tech meetups and conferences
mainly around openstack and cloud native
and yeah i like beer so i mainly got
interested in this topic
a few years ago after i saw a colleague
called jim macarthur do a
lightning talk on error correction
and so i wondered how this relates to
raid and other storage technologies
and i did some digging and figured out
there's lots of ways to do this
and i thought i'd provide an overview of
some of the ways that
error correction and detection is done
so the main idea
is to have a set of techniques so that
when we transmit data we can figure out
if um once we've received the data on
the other end
it's inconsistent or even better if we
can correct the data
rather than just dropping it so these
concepts have been around
since before modern computers were born
but they've come a long way so even the
older ideas are still around
in some of our modern technology so why
do we have errors in the first place
it could be human error it could be
network glitches it could be something
more random such as
uh noise on a chip or cosmic rays
interfering with the chip
all these things can cause us to receive
something different or the
data to send something different
so by show of hands how many people have
heard of a parity bit
pretty much the whole room cool so the
parity bit
is the earliest and most basic form of
error text in computers
and it's a very basic type of checksum
and the idea is that you can add a bit
to the end of a set of bits
which let you detect an error when
you're transmitting the data
so we do this by adding up the number of
one bits we have
and um if it's an even parity bit then
we
make it true for an even number of one
bits and if it's an odd parity bit
we'd make it true for an odd number of
bits so you can see here
that in the first uh character we have
two one bits that we're transmitting so
because that's even we'll add a one on
the end
and we'll send that and if we receive
the same thing on the other side we know
that no error has transmitted
um same again with k an even number of
bits
so we had a one on the end that's the
one in bold and
if we transmit it and there's an error
or there's a different number
we can do the calculation on the other
side and see that actually we should
have
a zero there's obviously some sort of
mistake so
we just drop that frame and ask the
whoever's whatever sent it to
re-transmit it and same again on the on
the third one there's another error
there
and that's an odd number of bits that's
why the last the last bit that we're
transmitting is a zero
so this concept goes back as far as the
50s and
we had parity tracks appear on
mechanical tape drives
in the early 50s the major flaw with
this
is that if you have more than one error
within a byte we're not going to detect
it
so it will only pick up um one bit error
so if there's
multiple bits within the same segment
then obviously it's gonna be a false
positive
it's still very useful though um and we
use it quite heavily in hardware
applications such as micro
processor caches uh the pci and scuzzy
bus standards
and rs232 serial and lots of other
hardware applications use it
so that's a very simple way to detect
basic errors
in transmission but we can't correct
them
um there's a decimal equivalent to this
um
and this is used in lots of different
real world applications
like social security cards id cards and
all major credit cards so this is one of
my old credit cards or debit cards and
you'll see that the last digit is
actually a check digit so how does this
work
uh i don't know if you've ever noticed
that when you're putting your credit
card or debit card number into
a web form it might automatically know
whether that's valid or not even if
you're not connected to the wi-fi
it's all happening locally and that's
due to this loon algorithm
and so the idea is this guy german
american engineer worked for ibm
in the 40s and 50s and he was the first
guy that came up with the idea of
information buckets to speed up
data retrieval and storage and the idea
here is that
that he came up with this algorithm is
that you double every digit
every other digit starting from the
right and then sum all the digits
and they should be a multiple of 10 and
if they're not then you know that
something's wrong so the last
the last digit will either make it a
multiple 10 or it won't
cool so then we get on to um
trying to do some correction and um the
mate one of the main pioneers
here is a guy called richard hamming and
he used to he was a mathematician and
professor
who worked at los alamos on the
manhattan project
in 1945 and he was on a team which was
responsible for programming the ibm
calculating machines
which had the scientists formulas check
that they were correct
and a few years later he went on to join
bell labs
and he became known to be one of the
young turks who was a group of people at
bell labs that
all had heavy contributions to computer
science
um they were all pretty well respected
and they didn't have
they weren't given the usual
responsibilities and structure uh
you know but measured by grants and
teaching teaching and papers they were
kind of just left to get on with it
and um three of them ended up going on
to win nobel prizes and a few of them
went on to lead bell labs
but all of them are highly respected
scientists
john tukey was one of the first guys to
come up with the name the the term bit
which is contracted from binary
information digit
so while he was a bell
richard hamming set one of his
calculating machines to work on a
problem over the weekend he said he said
it on friday
and when he came back on monday he
discovered that due to
uh an error uh the whole calculation
died early on saturday morning and so
he'd have to restart the whole thing
again waste two days of work or wait
till the next weekend
and this was quite common because you
had uh punch cards and so if
a card was bent or it didn't punch
properly then you know
you're gonna have an error so he then
basically went on to perform probably
the biggest yak shave in history and
decided to stack off all that physics
nonsense and figure out how to get
calculating machines to detect errors
and automatically re-transmit data
identified as inconsistent
so he published this key paper in 1950
called error detecting and error
correcting codes
and he described a few concepts that are
still core to error detection and
correction today
and these are number one is the
the hamming distance which just
describes how many single bit operations
i have to do to correct
a binary number or string so you know
for faster 19 faster than 20 this
two characters different that would be
two but obviously on a binary level
um this can also be represented
geometrically and it's called the
hamming cube
so he went on to define a system called
hamming codes
which is far more robust at checking
errors than standard parity
and what he developed was the concept of
having three parity bits for every four
data bits which is quite expensive
but it means that we can detect errors
up to two bits and also correct one bit
errors
so how does this work let's have a look
so if we have
four bits here d1 to d4
and we want to send them over some sort
of transmission channel
we can arrange them at the intersection
of three circles
so one zero one zero
and then we can calculate the parity for
each
circle so for parity circle one
we have one one bit so that's an odd
number so the parity will be zero
for parity um for the second circle
we have two one bits so that's even so
part is going to be one
um for the third circle we have again
one parity bit
so that's odd so that's gonna be zero so
we have three parity bits we add them to
our data and we send that across the
channel
now on the other side we receive
something different so we get a
d3 is turned to a zero instead of a one
so how do we
detect this um in the new circle that
we're arranging on the other side
you'll see that d3 switches to zero and
then we'll recalculate starting with the
first parity circle
nothing's changed there it's still an
odd number
something has changed there it's now
supposed to be an even number of bits
but it's not one bits but it's not
and the same for particle three so
we know that the offending bit is at the
intersection of the second and third
circle so therefore it's d3
and so we can just switch flip that bit
and correct the error
so that's the basic way that hamming
codes work
so we use parity pretty heavily in rage
some of you'll be familiar with raid
levels you probably you probably haven't
come across raid 2
because nobody uses it and that's
because it's really expensive
but this is hamming codes and it happens
at the bit level and so you can see that
there's four data blocks and three
parity date to bits sorry and three
parity bits
for um on uh there are stripes across
these hard drives
um so yeah i don't think anyone uses
this
um then you have obviously i'm sure all
of you familiar with rate five
raid four is similar to raid 5 there's
the only difference is that rather than
distributing the parity bits
across the drives we put all the parity
bits on one drive
and that means that rights are slower
with raid 4 since there's less data
drives to write to you
but since all the parity is written to
the same disk
um random reads are better so sorry so
rights are slower
because the parity has to be written to
the same disk but random reads are
better because there's less disk for you
to look
for because you have a dedicated parity
disk so
that's that's raid 4. this is raid 5 and
you're all familiar with raid 5 i guess
the way it works is it runs an exclusive
ore on the block
so for every two blocks that we write we
want an exclusive or and then we write
the result as a third block and so green
here is the
is the parity data so if i keep doing
that and obviously on different drives
i end up with a whole bunch of data now
if i lose one of the drives
i can recalculate it it's just it's
really simple just run exclusive or
again
on the other two data blocks and i can
regenerate that drive so that's how raid
5 works
so that's hamming codes that was in the
50s then these gays
guys came along in the 60s and they
changed everything
gustav solomon and irving reed and these
guys were staff members at the mit
laboratory and
10 years after hamming's paper they
published a paper called
polynomial codes over certain finite
fields
so i was reading up on this and i
suddenly realized that this was getting
really mathematically complicated
um i'm not a mathematician i was out of
my depth so as i always do when i'm out
of my depth
i um go into irc and ask a question
so i did that i went looking for the
right irc channel to think to ask in
thinking that this would be helpful
i knew there was a bunch of
mathematicians on this channel so i just
um i just asked you know can someone
explain polynomial interpolation to me
um this is the response that i got
i don't know maybe some of you
understand what that i i have no idea
but yeah yeah i um i need to
stop going to irc for as a as a resource
um the main idea behind reid solomon
does however revolve around
this concept of agawa field uh galwa
field is named after
everest galwa who is a french
mathematician and unlike our previous
heroes
had a much more troubled and interesting
life in the sense that
he got interested in math at the age of
14. he published a number of papers by
the age of 17
of which one of them was about galway
fields in galway theory
and this was a year after he was ejected
from university because his examiner
couldn't follow his train of thought and
was very confused
he was politically active ended up in
prison a number of times before he
engaged in a duel to the death with an
officer at the age of 20
and died so not the most
glamorous stories but yeah he did define
this concept called the calva field
which is basically
a mathematical field a set of numbers
which you can conduct mathematical
operations on
and a finite field or gallon field is
one that is finite and is always the
size of a prime number or prime power
and these fields wrap around so you can
conduct any operation
on the values within the field and
always get another value in the field
and you do this you can just modulate
the size of the field once you get your
results so
this can contain numbers it can contain
polynomials and it can contain
roots of polynomials and how does this
relate to
arranged coding and error correction
well
the idea is that using a gala field you
can
essentially plot any sequence of data
as points on a polynomial graph
and that's because the graph itself is
representative of the gallow field that
you're using
once you've done that you can then find
other points on the graph which you can
use as parity data so the purple ones
are
other points that we found on the same
graph and that's what we will use as our
code charts and the idea is that you
define a code and you use that on both
sides
to recover data and it's highly
efficient but
much more computationally expensive
so here's an example k is the number of
data charts that we have m is the number
of code charts
on the left we have what's called a
distribution or generator matrix
which is made up of an identity matrix
at the top
which essentially is equivalent to one
and then
the bottom piece is the uh code charts
which we we generate um so we add them
together
we multiply that by our data and we end
up with a set of data
and a set of parity
blocks um so
let's say we lose some of our data the
bit
in k we can replace those with c1 and c2
which are
what we end up calculating and we can
multiply that by the inverse of the same
generator matrix that we have
and that will give us our data blocks
back and obviously that's
far more efficient than using something
like
uh the hamming codes
so this is really really popular um it's
one of the most popular error correction
codes we use
today and it's it's seen everywhere
including cds dvds
um you can it's using 2d barcodes as
well
so um any any 2d barcode that you
scratch or is damaged
can still scan because it's using read
solomon to recover from
that damage and it's also used for
generating qr codes
so most implementations of raid 6 also
use resolument as well
so this image is taken from the
rage coding docs and ceph and it's
specifically for k
equals three and m equals two so two
parity charts for every three data
charts
so in ceph when you create a new pool um
you specify if you want it to be range
coded or not
and also which rage coding algorithm you
want to use uh ceph has a plugable
architecture for radio codes so you can
specify which code you want to use on a
pull by pull basis
once you've chosen an erasure code you
can't then change it for that pool
because you'd have to obviously
recalculate everything
so um you need to make sure the only way
to do the only way to get around that
you'd have to
create another pool and migrate so if
you're going to use an erasure code to
call and product
pool in production you want to be sure
that you've chosen the razor code that
best suits your workload
almost all of the razer coding plugins
within ceph rely on some form of read
solomon
there's a number of different varieties
though with different strengths and
weaknesses
the main plugin that's used in staff is
called j-razer
and that has both uh vandermonde and
couchy versions
those are both versions of um reid
solomon
and they they differ just in how you
generate the matrix at the beginning
there's also some more recent
propositions there's one called the
shingle the rage code
and that aims to be more configurable
and more efficient
there's also an implementation called
clay which focuses on reducing network
bandwidth and there's one called locally
repairable codes
which specifies a another variable
called
l so you can say i want my parity blocks
to be stored in a specific geo location
which helps us recover
from arranging rage coding damage but
without
straining the network too much if we
have a geo-replicated multi-site staff
cluster
so yeah the key thing to remember is
choose the right numbers for k
m uh obviously depending on how much
storage you want to uh use how much it's
gonna cost you in storage
and um also pick the right um arranged
coding plugin once you've done some
testing
uh with your workload so you you you
know that obviously it's a kind of more
final choice
so how does this relate to our work at
soft iron
well we're working on building staff
appliances and there's lots of
operations that we want to do in ceph
which are computationally expensive
compression rate coding and encryption
are all examples of this
so we're working on defining some of
these algorithms in hardware so that we
can use
fpgas to do the heavy lifting for us and
keep keep our cpu usage to just just
seth
so yeah that's that's my talk
anyone have any questions
no mathematicians in the room i guess
i read that performance was
their performance was really different
between the k and m's you choose
i read it should be multiple of two
or maybe something can you explain
why and which combinations
um so i think the the most commonly uh
so the question is
what combinations of k m are best and
how do they
affect performance within ceph um so
typically we see
people using 6 k and
3 for m or 9 and 4.
those are the most commonly used ones
we're only implementing
a few different combinations on our
fpgas
for that exact reason because each one
is going to be different how you define
it in hardware
so i think there's a standard set that
are used and
yes if you try and do it with less
m then you're going to have to do it's
going to be much more expensive to
calculate
than the number of m as a proportion so
you want to use a ratio of about three
to one i think
how does the distributed nature of sap
affect the acceleration
well i i imagine there's network latency
yes there is network latency um
so there is heavy network latency in
staff and that means that
uh oh so the question is how does it
affect um
how does the distributed nature of ceph
affect
acceleration so there is network latency
in ceph and that means that in some
cases
the the cost of going to recover the
data
in time might be still far less than
the the expense of doing the replication
of the network anyway
so you kind of have to have a bit of a
cost balance and figure out
in which cases it might be worth not
accelerating
the process in which cases it might be
worth accelerating so
it's it's a trade-off and i think in
some cases it is some cases it isn't
and that's a very important factor in
deciding whether or not to accelerate
does that answer your question yes cool
okay
well thank you very much