excellent all right folks
we are now on to our next presentation
the ethics of open source a critical
reflection
don goodman wilson thank you for being
here don thank you mike mike sounds on
yeah
is the microphone excellent
all right hi my name is uh my name is
don goodman wilson i've got this lovely
controversial title
is it not on is it is this better
okay this is going to be fun because i
like to gesticulate and i don't know how
to
just turn this off right
that's fine i'll just i'll just do this
um
so uh my name is don goodman wilson i
used to do philosophy i also used to do
computer programming type things i used
to do community
uh i have a consultancy that's lovely
and i want to talk about
some news items that have come up in
just the past couple of weeks
just two days ago news about a firm
called practice fusion broke
uh has anybody heard about that one
practice fusion was a software for for
doctors to help them
diagnose medical conditions that also
suggested opioids far more frequently
than necessary
at the request of the manufacturer of
the opioids
the us air force uh has a new game you
can play online where you can train to
be a drone pilot and practice killing
people and if you enjoy it
they're happy to hire you because it's a
recruiting tool
news broker brought clearview new york
times about two weeks ago
company that uh uses facial recognition
technology to identify people from
pictures that they've posted to their
uh public news feeds twitter and so
forth it's
apparently surprisingly effective not
only identifying the person but showing
where they are on twitter and vinmo and
other tools like this
and although i can't prove it about
clearview um
we can inferred about the rust these are
all powered by open source software
um which is a little scary um
and i think over the past six months
there's been an increased awareness that
open source software is helping to fuel
um injustice in the world what's
particularly interesting about these
examples is it's not just
us who create the software who are
impacted by this it's not just those who
are consuming and using the software
uh that are impacted it is actually
disproportionately people
none of us have any relationship with
whatsoever uh who are being impacted by
this the people who are being
uh terrorized by the us air force the
people who are being prescribed opioids
when they don't need them
the people uh who would rather not have
their privacy
violated uh using the software that we
create
um there's been a number of attempts at
addressing this sort of thing recently
um this is uh from the hippocratic
license by uh coraline
at mk uh which essentially takes an mit
stylizes and adds this
no harm clause to it uh that the
software
uh may not be used uh in activities that
uh
violate human rights as defined by the
united nations
um and i think experiments like this are
laudable
right i think the time is right for us
to start thinking about these sorts of
experimentations
but the response from the open source
community at large has not been very
positive
so we see things like licenses should
not be political
it's not open source
it's not probably like i'm willing to
accept that as a claim
but this is also not an argument right
this is called begging the question
i really want to dig into this in this
talk why is the response so frequently
it's not open source and why does this
claim carry so much weight in our
community
because it does even the osi themselves
right they weighed in on this um i
removed the the slide here because i've
only got 20 minutes
and i sort of have to power through the
argument that i want to make but the osi
has been quite clear no this is not open
source
and then you know refers people to this
faq on the opensource.org website can i
stop evil people from using
my program uh no because
that's not what open is right that's
sort of the opposite of open
and i just feel this tension and i can't
help but think we have ended up
somewhere
really bad right
what is this tension that i'm feeling
why do i feel bad about this why does
this strike me and hopefully it strikes
some of you
as uh as absurd i want to dig into this
question i want to get into this
question a lot
right uh so how did we get here
where did this come from how do we move
forward from here
and in particular why do we hold the
word open
or the concept of open in such high
esteem
why is the appeal to the fact that
something is not open source used as a
conversation stopper
right as the final and ultimate argument
why we should stop pursuing
these sorts of explorations
and i find this very curious actually um
and i want to dig into the history a
little bit
i did not touch that wire
we're going to pretend that solved the
problem
um so so so back
back in the 60s uh especially in the
united states we had this
counter-cultural movement
uh colloquially known as hippie-ism
right um and this was a
backlash against the authoritarian
structures that existed especially in
the united states at the time
by the youth of the era uh the boomers
as it were
um their goal actually uh was to
overthrow
the establishment right through a diy
mentality
and individual liberation uh their goal
was the creation of
a a new utopia where we could live
together in harmony and peace man
um and it was it was actually i mean
it's a lot of a goal right we want to
change the world for
better we want to make the world a good
place we we want to like we'd not want
to see
world war ii again we'd like not to see
vietnam again as a war
um and there's a there's this thing that
came out at the time called
called the whole earth catalog um are
you familiar with the
who who's heard of the whole earth
catalog
so not a whole lot of you we're digging
way back in time so the first edition
was in
67 i think and it was printed more or
less continuously
up until the late 70s and then all the
way like the last edition was published
in the the late 90s or
the early 2000s this is from the
introduction of the the first
edition where's gods and might as well
get good at it
okay boomer um in response to the power
of government and big business a realm
of intimate personal power is developing
power of the individual to conduct his
own education find his own inspiration
shape his own environment and share his
adventure with whoever is interested
this isn't a catalog
right this is like the hippie sears
catalog is is what this is
this is literally like meant to
disseminate information
about how to acquire tools to create a
new
foundation for civilization tools like
things to build geodesic domes because
these are interesting
things to use as houses but also tools
as intellectual tools
right and the idea was that this
movement inspired by the whole earth
catalog
was that as we find new tools we share
them with other people
right because only together can we can
we create the community to bring about
uh the world that we want to see is this
starting to sound familiar
this should sound very familiar to
people in the room um it's
it's no surprise that many of the people
who were involved in the whole earth
catalog
were early contributors to wired
magazine right stuart brand comes
immediately to mind he's a guy who
created
the whole earth catalog um
and wired promulgated the twin views
that technology was leading us to an
inevitable future of personal freedom so
more technology please
and a new capitalist order of nimble san
francisco startups was going to get us
at technology it is
no coincidence that san francisco is the
center of the tech world because san
francisco
was the center of the hippie world these
two things led one
into the other right uh a lot of the
early startups
uh uh were founded specifically uh
as an attempt to overthrow the existing
capitals hierarchy as it existed let's
overturn
how businesses are created let's
overturn how business is done
right this all stems directly from this
this countercultural movement
of overthrowing authority empowering the
people without power
and using that to create a better world
this view was summed up in a critical
essay called the californian ideology
that i
highly recommend that you go read that
information technologies empower the
individual enhance personal freedom
and radically reduce the power of the
nation state existing social
political and legal power structures
will wither away to be replaced by
unfettered interactions between
autonomous individuals
and their software right it's not a huge
leap to see a connection
uh between this ideology i mean this
this essay was critical right of this
of this view highly highly critical of
this view but this is how they summed it
up
um it's easy to see how this blends into
something like
hey i got a broken printer i'd like to
write the
or like access to the the software for
the drivers so i can make it do things
that the
the manufacturer did not intend right
because the idea of proprietary printer
driver software
runs extremely counter to this to this
notion
right of liberating people through
technology through open access to tools
uh to create the world that we want to
see this is a reference to richard
solman i know not everybody in the room
uh is familiar with the the history of
the fsf and the osi
but we don't really have time to get
into it what i want to point out is that
there's there's a very strong continuum
between the early 1960s counterculture
and the origins of the open source
movement in the 1980s and 1990s
so that sounds well and good
um so open source isn't political
right i don't think so um
the value of openness here's the claim
that i want to make because i want to
question our assumptions and really dig
into this the value of openness
is uh that openness is a tool for
creating
a liberated world a more just world a
world where people feel more empowered
right why then are we so afraid of
moving in a direction
uh that creates more justice in the
world or that is aimed at creating more
justice in the world
why are we insisting on sticking on a
track that we know
is creating injustice in the world so
i want to introduce this concept the
openness or sorry the paradox of
openness
um and i'm going to do this by talking
about the paradox of tolerance uh are
people familiar with the paradox of
tolerance
this has become very popular in an
american political discourse at the
moment because
uh uh american political discourse is
having a bit of a similar crisis
so this comes from call popper
ironically
the philosopher who first popular
popularized the idea of the
of openness as a path to justice
we were not going to go there just now
but this is a very interesting quote
unlimited tolerance must lead to the
disappearance of tolerance if we extend
unlimited tolerance even to those who
are intolerant
if we are not prepared to defend a
tolerant society against the onslaught
of the intolerant then the tolerant will
be destroyed
and tolerance with them we should
therefore claim in the name of tolerance
the right not to tolerate the intolerant
now it doesn't quite work but we can
substitute openness for tolerance here
right and we get a very similar argument
structure uh that has the same validity
as this argument
and i believe it's i believe it's
actually quite violent
um
and make that point what what what do we
tolerate
in the name of openness
so open source exacerbates existing
injustices
right uh those who are at the receiving
end of the software that we create have
no say in its creation have no say in
its deployment have no say
in the code itself because they may not
have access to computers or the
technical skills necessary
right they have no say in the the
contracts that we form
with other entities using it in the form
of open source licenses
software is used as a tool by the
powerful to assert control
and very frequently the control and
power that they assert
is at the detriment uh to the most
helpless
uh in our society in the world right and
we're contributing to this
we're contributing to this by making it
easier than ever to create software
i mean that was the goal right
here we are open source is the
playground of the privileged
you and i we learned how to code
we have free time convinced like this to
contribute to software projects
many of the people many people in the
world don't many people in the world
that we want to be
part of our communities cannot be
because they don't have the time they
don't have the money
they don't have the experience they
don't have the equipment they don't have
the privilege
to participate in the communities that
we want to create
um and that very fact
creates a an ever-growing wall uh for
those without the privilege to joining
our community
i have a whole other argument about this
but open source incentivizes exploiting
a volunteer labor force um i had to cut
out a whole lot of slides
that led up to this in order to slice
this down from an hour-long talk
but you see and many of you in the room
probably are maintainers
who just don't have the freaking time uh
to answer all of your issues um and how
frequently
uh is your software in turn being used
by large corporate entities who are
extracting value uh from
your free week in labor some of us don't
mind that like that's not a judgment
if you're happy giving away your labor
to those who are able to extract massive
value from it
but not all of us are comfortable with
that right it's not a just
it's not a just contract that we've
entered into
so i want us to denormalize the state of
affairs
i want to make the world a better place
we want to make the world a better place
right um let's stop asking the wrong
questions
and start asking the right ones so
instead of asking is it open source is
it politics free
is it enforceable these are question
begging questions
that are designed to shut down
conversation and shut down forward
progress
i don't want to hear these questions
they are not productive
this one will be enforceability will
eventually be i think productive
but frequently when it's asked right
it's asking the context of
it doesn't matter we can dismiss it
because it's not enforceable it's not
really a question it's more of a comment
that was snark um so what questions
should we be asking
this is a really good one by the way as
a philosopher like i love this question
because i'm gonna i'm not gonna lie
philosophy doesn't have answers fosse
only has more questions and it always
starts with with this one and i want to
encourage you especially if you take
nothing else away from this talk
take this away ask yourself this every
day
every day but here's other good ones
what are the forces
that have led us to this point in time
so i tried to line out some of them it
was a very biased history
right i got some of the details wrong it
came from a very personal point of view
it's multi-faceted it's long it's got
lots of people doing lots of things with
lots of motivations
it's not the only history right but
understanding
why we are where we are now will help us
understand
better how to move forward in the future
what do we owe to each other's people
i'm a huge fan of scanlon's ethics if
you've read the
the the um summary of my talk you may be
may have been expecting me to talk a bit
more about that but again
time um but as we're writing software we
should be thinking about not just what
does my
community need my community of
contributors and maintainers
what not just what does the the
community of people who depend upon my
software need
but you should be thinking about what
are the what are the downstream effects
of this software because it's going to
have downstream effects whether you like
it or not
right um and we should be thinking very
very seriously about what justice looks
like in this context
because our software has a much much
bigger much much bigger effect on the
world
than we realize that it does and then
finally how do we evolve as a community
right and this might well mean evolving
beyond open source right abandoning the
osd
uh looking for new ways of building
communities new ways of building
software as a community and
finding something that allows us to
continue to extract what's good about
open source because there's a lot of
good about open source don't get me
wrong
right and apply this in a new context
where we can increase the amount of
justice that we're creating instead of
just maintaining the status quo
and only worrying about the the
relatively small circle of people uh
that our software has an immediate
impact on
um because i believe i believe we do
have the power to make the world a
better place i believe we have a
responsibility to leverage that power to
actually make the world a better place
and i'd much rather see us succeed as a
community
uh than go down in flames in an ensuing
uh cultural war if you enjoyed this talk
here's some resources that i've
collected
prs are welcome right uh
so feel free to uh to drop other links
that you find in there
uh that that might be uh uh might be
interesting to other people
um and i think we have like two minutes
they're all gone i have seven minutes
for questions oh my god i thought this
is going to be a 30 minute talk that's
fantastic
seven minutes for questions
i'm gonna have to pass around this mic
aren't i
i have no idea how these things work
is this oh this is working now i think
two minutes
okay that's that's what i thought all
right
okay i try to go fast yeah
thank you very much for this very
interesting talk to you very um i agree
with you on
the symptoms that you show but not so
much on
the diagnosis of things to me it looks
more like
open source is one thing one solution
that was taken at a time
where as you say problems were different
um but trying to change it may actually
just be
uh ignoring what is actually causing
open source to be used in such ways
actually uh um
which to me is really down to economics
and politics
you can actually ask to the licensees to
uh to
include something about harm no harm and
so on you will always have
ways to to go around that what is harm
uh if you go for
repression and you in a country you you
harm some people that you you know you
you
i'm going to stop you right there this
is an abdication of responsibility on
our part
uh and i think that's exactly the wrong
kind of response to have
uh we have a responsibility as much as
everybody else in the world to create
something that's more just
and by saying well we we're not that
powerful enough to do it
sorry what i say is you should target
something a bit higher up than that
we should target every level including
ourselves we must hold ourselves
accountable because we are part of the
system
even if we're at a low level in the
system even if there are machines
that have much out much greater much
more outsized impact on this
we are nevertheless responsible in some
small part and to the extent that we are
we have a moral obligation to deal with
it i understand and it's a very good
thing to do
i agree on that
[Applause]
maybe you should discuss after that
because we're going to be i'll be around
thank you
very interesting should we even go
further just you mentioned the no harm
clause
should we have it like a do-good good
class like
you can't even use this for a benign you
have to actively do good
things that would be interesting so so i
don't again i don't know what the right
solution is i
am advocating a position of open
experimentation so we can find the right
solution to this
right all i know is we haven't found the
solution yet um
that sounds like a an interesting
direction to experiment yes let a
thousand flowers bloom right
okay thank you
[Applause]