with microsoft research in cambridge and
i'm here to tell you about the
confidential consortium framework which
is our project
uh it only says on last night which
might have been a mistake but it's open
source on github
so please feel free to check it out so
what we set out to do is
build a framework to make it easy for
people to construct multi-party
applications
with good guarantees so one of the
things that's often a problem is
the lack of governance mechanism so we
wanted to have a verifiable
consortium governance mechanism a system
where you can have very well defined
governance rules for the multi-party
application
which are easily verifiable to all
participants to members themselves and
to also users
so they can see that the network is or
the application is run in the specific
way that
is promised is to be run um we also want
fine grain confidentiality of course
so um people should be able to have very
fine grain control of their data it
should be possible for application
makers
to make it so that you can only see or
reveal you know what's what's useful and
appropriate for business purposes
uh we want a very simple programming
model uh everyone wants a simple
programming model we want it to
be approachable and make it easy for
people to get those guarantees and of
course we want high availability and
high efficiency it's no good to have an
easy framework if
you then have to do a lot of legwork to
make your app um you know available and
fast right
so broadly speaking um from a
from a far away distance this is what a
ccf application looks like
you have a number of of machines which
run
trusted execution environments or
hardware enclaves running anywhere so
they could be running in a cloud
provider multiple cloud providers some
of them could be on premise
it doesn't really matter where a bunch
of users interact with that service
and the members a set of members
basically provide governance so the
first thing they do is they endorse the
service
and they essentially endorse the
identity of the service and make it so
that everyone knows that this is the
service they're talking to
they also garden the service uh so
they'll you know govern the membership
sets they'll
they allow new new members to join or to
leave they can add and remove users and
all that
and they they'll look after upgrades too
so if they need to replace the code
improve the application fix security
bugs and so on
they're on the hook for that separate
from them
is an operator someone who's just
provisioning things so they're providing
the hardware
they can spin up the the instances of
the nodes that the application is
running on
but they're not trusted they're not
inside the trust boundary so they're
spinning things up
and they can provide them to the members
on behalf the members maybe the members
pay them
to make this available to them but they
do not have any specific access to the
application
they are not they're not part of the
transplanter in the application
so how do we how do we bootstrap that
how do we get that started
and for that we need a number of trusted
execution environments and we need a way
to sort of connect them together and
make them into a career network
sorry yes i can try yes
sorry um so trust the execution
environments uh
mostly everyone except well that person
left but once everyone is familiar with
them
uh and so what we get is we want
encrypted and integrity protected memory
um so this is this is key to make sure
that the operator the person who's
running the nodes on their machine
cannot have access we cannot see
anything that's happening inside the
node
um we want cryptographic evidence of a
running code so we want the ability to
assert at the distance or to check at
the distance what's running
and finally so and remote at station so
we want to be able to do this
uh remotely and this gives us a
distributed trusted computation so
it allows us to spin up a number of
enclaves and to check that
they are running in enclaves so the the
contents or anything we send over to
them or anything they contain is not
immediately visible to the people who
are running these these enclaves we want
to be able to know exactly which code
they're running
um and then we can make them part of the
networking we can distribute
our application with confidence that
information is not going to be leaked or
we're not going to have integrity issues
or the sort of
sort of stuff
so how do we do that so a node overview
so a single ccf node roughly looks like
this
you'd have a client talking to to the
node
they use tls so we we don't support
generic byte streams
we support only ets you have to talk to
us via tls
that goes through the host the host is
potentially malicious and potentially
you can look at
all of the frames and so on but these
are encrypted cs frames on the way in
and out so they can't they can't see
anything useful they can't derive
anything useful from that traffic
they're no different from someone who
could be intercepting some of the
network traffic there
so the tr section terminates inside
inside our enclave
and inside enclave is essentially two
bits this off framework which provides
a certain certain amount of
functionality and the user application
code which is running whatever business
logic there is there
so the enclave contains the application
logic and states uh it contains the
governance code which is what we
referred to earlier which is what allows
these design claims to talk to each
other
and uh fault tolerance code so code that
allows us to distribute
essentially the updates across
networking enclaves make sure that we
have availability
if a certain number of enclaves are
affected or come down
the applications still still can run
so communication between the host and
the enclave we want to avoid
equals and oracle so we want to avoid
calling in in and out of the enclave
there's a there's a number of
performance and security reasons why
it's not such a good idea to do this on
a regular basis
and you want to minimize the amount of
those you do
so the way we the way we do things is
the single local art start a single
e-course or a start-up when we provision
the enclave
and then all communication between the
enclave and the host
is done over ring buffers and so
essentially you put data on the ring
buffer
the enclaves the enclave reads it out on
the other side and then back in
i see a lot of people take pictures and
i want to point out the slides on the
website
so you don't have to if you you know if
you just want a slice
um so yeah the communication is
basically just the ts frames in and out
with the ring buffers and also
heartbeats
so we'd like to have trusted time
there's no such thing as trusted time
but we still need some notion of time
because if we're going to run
a distributed consensus for example we
need something to do timeouts and this
sort of stuff
so we take rough time from the host it's
not trusted
and the host could essentially perform a
denial of service by
withholding time updates or or sending
time updates too often and so on
while we claim this has no impact on
confidentiality and integrity basically
doesn't have an impact on availability
it does have an impact on variability so
if you want to
if you're not performing denial service
and uh you're the host you certainly can
but then again if you're the host you
can impact availability by withholding
all task frames from the enclave
and then not much variability there so
yeah for sure
then so the way we do availability is
you distribute this and you have a
number of enclaves running
set up with a consensus mechanism and so
you have to take down
you know at least half the enclaves
you're running cfd maybe a third if
you're running a bft variant right
but yeah if you take down or if you if
you uh if you own all the hosts then
yeah you can stop the system from
working completely for sure yeah
um so yeah so now that we have these uh
these building blocks
uh we can talk a bit about like a joint
protocol so if we have a network that's
already established that's already
bootstrapped so
the way we start at is we start a single
node um and then we
we gradually bootstrap the network by
adding on new nodes to that
uh to that network so the way it works
is our nodes create a key pair
very much like g-through scheme so that
that stays inside the enclave
that's the identity of the enclave and
we the node produces a quote over its
over states so that's the platform the
code it's running and the identities the
platform contains platform information
it contains microcode
version you know that type of
information as well
and then that's sent across to the
network and the network then decides
if this node should be allowed to join
or not and there's basically two two
parts to that
one of it is checking the quotes so
making sure that the node that wants to
join is in fact running
you know sgx is running the right
microcode it's running everything's up
to date it's running the right codes
inside the enclave and the other part is
governance kicks in here so
essentially a proposal is created and
it's put in our state and then
the our governance mechanism which i'll
talk about just next
kicks in and the members get to decide
if they want to allow this this node to
join or not
um in some configurations you could
decide to allow that all the time
so if you've got the right identity
running in sgx you're running the right
code and so on
maybe everybody's allowed to join uh
there's some reasons why you probably
don't want to do that
or maybe the the members have set up
some rules maybe they want to check
who's joining first
maybe they want to just check the
quantity of how many how many things are
joining at the same time
there's various problems with um having
too many joins at the same time
obviously everybody
comes in and then they have to catch up
on a crazy problem
and so the network if it decides that it
likes the node and it wants to
add the node to its configuration then
endorses this identity
and sends data secret basically to that
node so consensus can kick in and we can
start replicating state to this node
because now they can read they can read
the updates we send them
and so we have a single network identity
which is
distinct from the identity of the first
node but is essentially set up by the
first node
and this network identity is what would
be distributed so
that can be you can produce a csr for
that have it be signed by root ca or
that could be something that the members
distribute to their users
so if you think of the members as a
group of companies maybe a group of
banks or something
they could distribute this word
certificate to their users and
users can when they connect to a node
over tis
the fact that the certificate for the
nodes is endorsed by this
root cert this is how they get you know
proof of evidence that yet station has
been conducted properly and the rules of
governance have been followed properly
um and so yeah so once the joint and it
needs to catch up on state and become
part of the
power system so that leads us into
governance how do we uh
how do we build a mechanism to make it
easy for members to decide how the
network should be governed and operated
um so here we have our consortium of
members and
initially what they do is they endorse
uh the first
the first prefix of the ledger and the
configuration so we have a first few
transactions that configure our system
and the members have to come in and they
they have to stage a vote basically to
say
yes we agree this is the network we
think uh we
we wanted to start so it's running the
right version of the code it's running
with the right membership
um and um we're happy with the identity
of the node so far
um so they vote for that this is
recorded and in general this is just an
instance of our generic governance
mechanism which is
staging votes so you can stage votes to
decide things like membership
uh who should be a member of the network
uh who should be a user
um what the network configuration should
look like so i want to add a certain
number of nodes remove some nodes
um i want to update the code or i want
to change the versions of the code that
are allowed to run the network
or you want to change maybe the
constitution itself so all the votes are
governed by a constitution which is a
script which i'll show on the next slide
and this is what decides how the votes
are passed essentially how the votes are
counted
and this itself being part of our state
is something we could update also
probably with different rules maybe we
want to be stricter about that
so the constitution is a script the
votes are scripts
well so the proposals are scripts and
the votes themselves are scripts
so a proposal could be um you know we
want to make this change and then all
the members have to look at that
and they have to say yeah i agree or i
disagree but if you do
if you say i agree or disagree then you
have a check time abuse problem
because things could have moved on and
maybe you care about some other elements
of the state maybe
maybe you're happy to add a node but
only if there's already if there's not
like more than 10 nodes already because
you're trying to restrict the total
number of nodes
so in your your vote should be something
that's executable it should be something
that can look at the proposal but also
the current state of the system and say
yeah okay i agree with that or you know
given the circumstances given the state
wherein
i don't want to accept that um so
because this because your vote is
executable you get rid of these concerns
and this is how this is how we count
things
so that's all the slides and we should
see a bit of code hopefully it's big
enough for everyone to read
um okay so i'll try and go through that
quickly but essentially this is a very
simple constitution samples
uh sample some of them will look bigger
than that they'll be more complicated
but here all we're doing is we're saying
like look for most things all we're
looking for is a majority of members
saying that they agree
so if if we if we want to stage a
proposal and we want to say we want to
add a new member for example
or a new user we just want to have a
look at the majority of you
of members which are currently active
and check that they agree with that
um so we count member votes and
essentially
we just count member vote for um active
for active members so we
if we have members who have been retired
or who are joining
and they're in the process of joining
they're not active yet and so on they
shouldn't be counted in this vote
we count all the members the same we
could decide to make a distinction
we could have some tables where we store
special members who are like operating
members or senior members whatever
and maybe they have special rights maybe
they can veto some things
maybe their vote is sufficient to pass
the entire thing it's very flexible we
can do pretty much anything we want here
this is just a simple example there are
some tables where we store information
that maybe
shouldn't be so easy to modify so for
example
if the members once want to stage a vote
over
so there's a whitelist table which is
basically
some the tables are allowed to be
affected by governance and then
we have our governance script table
which is the table that stores this
constitution
if people are going to replace the
constitution you're probably looking for
something more than just a simple
majority
so here in this case we enforce
unanimity we need to have them the
number of the total number of member
votes needs to be the same as the total
number of
members that's active and so if we have
a majority otherwise
then you know we pass otherwise we
return false and the way this works is
very simple
every time a member sends a vote um
their script is executed that decides
their votes
then the constitution is run again
recounts if it's good we pass if it's
not good it's still pending the proposal
is still there
um there's a there's a way to withdraw
proposals as well if you think there's
no realistic chance of them passing
but that's sort of how it works
the types of proposals are fixed um
not really so because you're because
your proposal so this is lower
your proposals are lua and votes are lua
if you can if you can put your proposal
in terms of a lua script that executes
against the table in the key value store
that's backing this
then you can put it to a vote and the
other members
they'll have to write a script that
knows how to evaluate your proposal
and so it might be tricky for them if
you propose something officially
complicated
maybe they won't agree to it yeah
yeah your proposal is code so yeah you
have to
you have to cover so so conveniently
we'll look at proposals now
so some simple ones the first one is
just we want to add a new user um
so we're we get to see that the tables
and then
so there's a mistake should say user
cert
so we get the tables and the user search
as arguments here and
are what we're saying is we want to add
this new user
to our store so the way this is split is
the proposals are typically little bits
of codes and some arguments are
templatized and parametrized so here the
user search is passed separately is
passed in
so the next proposal is we're passing a
new code digest and we're saying
we should be able to run this new code
version in our system
and um we can have a look at the ballot
here so a vote
to evaluate that so the vote to evaluate
that will look at the changes proposed
by the proposal so it checks there's
only one change proposed
uh that the the proposal is a new code
uh proposal
and that the new code is this this new
code id that we have decided is
acceptable
so probably typically what would happen
is the member would have ahead of time
communicated with the other members and
say hey look i want to deploy this this
new version of the code
um i give you what you need to reproduce
the build
you added the code you produce the build
you get to the same id you get the same
hash over the code
and you say okay i want to put a vote
for that so you're not accepting the
proposal itself you're accepting
this particular code id that's that's
what you're accepting there
um yeah so code updates uh it's
essentially a sort of
simple three-phase mechanism you add a
new supported code version through this
vote mechanism
everyone agrees to that for a while when
you do that
as you speed up new nodes that run this
new version of the code
you want to make sure that the new and
the old versions are compatible
um and then you can stage a vote say i
want to remove the old version of the
codes
now that we've upgraded maybe the new
version contains a security fix and you
don't want to allow the old version to
run anymore so you stage another vote
see we should get rid of the old version
now because
we have a good quorum of uh of nodes
running the new version
um and then if that passes uh then the
new
the the old code is essentially um
uh removed and so nodes that are running
the old code can't be part of the
network anymore
and now you can tear them down
uh so another thing we potentially need
governance for is catastrophic recovery
so typically we run with a consensus
algorithm and it will be
there will be a formula that tells us
how many nodes we can tolerate are
failing
and that's that's basically f so if if
we're running cfd crash volt turns we
can
if we have two f plus one nodes we can
we could lose f nodes and still make
progress
if we're running with b synthetics
instead we
we need to have three f plus one nodes
then we can tolerate f failures
um but if we have more than failures
then the network can't make progress
anymore because
there's no quorum so transactions can't
be globally committed and now we're
stuck
so in that case we need to perform
catastrophic recovery and what happens
is we need to go back to the members who
are ultimately the root of trust for
this
and they so we have a mechanism that
uses key shares to do that
um there's also another mechanism that
you see in keys but essentially
you need a way for the members to um
come together and put together enough
information that they can read the old
ledger
and produce a new service that runs on
the basis of the old ledger
[Music]
and you want to have the the new the new
ledger endorsed by the old service
so if people are connected to your
service and you have not distributed the
new identity of the service to them yet
they can still connect
and they still know that this is
endorsed by the older entity
here the members have quite a lot of
power so it's up to them not to endorse
a new service or not to endorse multiple
new services for example
or to endorse a new service unless
they're happy with the state of it but
it sort of works the same way as the
bootstrapping the first time works
um someone staged one of the members
stages of recovery votes the other the
other members get to examine the state
of the service
and if they're happy with the state of
the service then they endorse it and
they can move forward
and so finally we want verifiabilities
it's no good to have a well-defined
governance if
no one can audit it because then there's
no trust you have to trust that the code
has been written correctly and that all
the votes have been executed correctly
um so for that to happen all the
governance states all the
all the tables that hold the governance
in our system all public so anyone who
has access to ledger which should be
anybody
can see what the governance tables hold
and they can essentially play through
the garden story
and if anything doesn't match like one
of the votes you know that the total
that
was counted doesn't matter and so on
they can say hold on there's a problem
there
all the guns transactions have to be
signed this is enforced by the service
as well
so you not only can say there's a
problem there you can also blame whoever
is responsible for this which are the
members
has basically made a you know made a
mistake or lied about the way they voted
for example
this happens in the same flow order as
other transactions so all our
transactions happen on the same kv
and governance is done over a set of
tables which is part of this kv
they're not separate so um the the
versions
the commit ids you get for for
governance changes and for regular
transactions are
on the same scale on the same time scale
so it's very easy to decide
you know which business transactions
should have been affected by governance
so if a user for example has been kicked
out of the system and you're trying to
figure out
exactly until when they could have
performed transactions or they should
have been able to perform transactions
you can easily because it's part of the
same
version uh timeline um and so finally
yeah
also all of this is recorded in terms of
ledger so we use sort of standard
uh blockchain mechanisms or merkle trees
to make sure that all our updates are
changed
and that you can't just go back and edit
some part of the history without it
being very very visible
later on
so it's all good to have the stuff but
it has to be easy to write applications
for it
so the first the first guarantee we want
to make is that
unless you really go out of your way to
to log like private information
uh all data in ccf is encrypted all the
time so it's obviously encrypted at rest
so all the data we have to store on disk
uh for for recovery and audit is is
encrypted
um all data that is sent around the
network
um is encrypted on the wire and in
memory
um we also get encryption from our use
of enclaves
so if somebody has access to the machine
they cannot just look at what we're
doing
so roughly speaking our application
schema looks something like this
the application code plugs in in a gray
box
and everything else is is provided by
the framework so client frames come from
the host
um that's just tls it comes to sstrs
frames
uh we have a frontend component that
just takes care of um
essentially the the ts functionality
decrypting things we have authentication
against the kv so
remember we know exactly at which point
in time which users or which members are
allowed to use the system
um because of our governance so we can
check that and then
if their identity is not allowed to do
the operation base they say what they
want to do at this point we can reject
it automatically
it's not something that the user has to
worry about so things come to the user
with this identity that's been
verified so we've authenticated
transactions and we've also authorized
them at this point
um and then the application engine can
just produce a set of
read and write transactions or single
sorry read and write transactions
against the key value store so that
in their business logic all state has to
go in the key value store that's
provided by ccf
they can perform any operations they
want but in order for the states
to be persistent to larger to be
recoverable and to be distributed and
available across the network
um it has to happen as operations
against the key value store
and then further downstream we replicate
this using consensus
so that then that again goes back out to
the host um
it's a bunch of encrypted frames um back
out to the ledger
so to be to be stored in current storage
um and at the regular interval we also
uh so we hash all the transactions um we
put them in order three and then a
regular until we sign that that goes to
our ledger
so this is this is how we get our type
of proof uh audit
um so yeah so we we have encrypted tcp
frames coming in and out to the ledger
that's sort of
coming in and out sorry of the
application that's the only thing that's
um
goes in and out of the enclave we have
an apparently larger on disk
and all application states must be in
the key value store for
all the guarantees to hold
so we have a couple of consensus
variants crash filters is the main one
we use now um
we have a bft implementation that's
still kind of work in progress but
which is available in the build for
people who want to try it so
if you use crash world turns we have a
an enclave raft variant
what we do there is if you have two f
plus one nodes you can have f two up to
f failures and the network will still
continue to
make progress uh because we've added
signatures
you can blame compromised nodes and you
can
essentially go back to ledger and
offline verify you know what has been
done and potentially take things out if
you think some notes have been malicious
but it's not happening online so if a
node somewhere is acting maliciously
they can potentially go on doing it for
some time you have to offline
check for that and you know remove the
transactions they've done
and so here we rely on the t for both
confidentiality and integrity
um if the if the t is compromised if
someone can
for example tamper with the memory we
won't be able to to detect it
online it will have to it'll take some
offline audit for it to be detected
um if you use our pbft varit which again
still work in progress but it's coming
online
then if you have three f plus one nodes
you can tolerate up to f failures but
you can target up to f nodes being
malicious
so the nice thing about that here is
that you still rely on the t for
confidentiality so if sjx is actually
broken one day
well you know your data still is no
longer confidential
but you potentially don't lose integrity
if fewer than f nodes are affected
so if you're clever enough about the way
you distribute your instances and
they're not all you know
subject to the same attacker because
maybe they're geographically distributed
or distributed across multiple
cloud providers and so on if you manage
to keep
two f plus one nodes that aren't
affected by the attack
you still keep integrity so your
attacker gets to see the data but they
don't get to
manufacture transactions that are
illegitimate
so the key value store is is basically
our very simple storage and phase
there's really just two things you can
do with it you can
get stuff out of it and put stuff back
inside um
aggressive ccf is implemented in c plus
so we'll get to the runtimes as
supported but
you can put any old c plus type in and
out of there
and then for other languages we have
mappings
transactions are very straightforward
it's like any local
key value store we've used we have
strict areas of bt and opacity
so that errors only see a consistent
state there's there's really no uh
no tricks there it's very very easy to
use it behaves the way you'd expect
you can have app driven confidentiality
because of this very flexible key value
store model so the app
decides completely how it wants to
expose data it's up to the application
logic
to decide how to do that there is no
built-in support in the key value store
to label things with certain degrees of
privacy or anything it's completely left
to the code
and you can of course store your code in
this in the store itself so
you have the key value store and one of
the things you can do is some of the
values could be
code themselves so if you want to upload
scripts if you want to upload things
that can be executed by the users um
then of course you can
another thing that the framework
provides for you is transaction receipts
so this is a little tricky for you for
the applications to implement themselves
for for a variety of reasons but
basically
applications should be able to or users
that use the application should be able
to get receipts from the application
that are signed by the service that say
that this out
this outcome happened and it happened at
this version inside the kv so if you're
talking to people who are outside the
system
and you're trying to prove to them that
something did happen or you
you did do something and you want to
give them cryptographic evidence that
this thing happened
and it should be something that can be
verified offline they shouldn't be
they shouldn't need to be a user that
system and to talk to that system to
verify that this happened
you can do that through the receipts
and so you can write your ccf apps
either in c plus plus directly which is
probably what you do for maximum speed a
little bit tricky but you know
it's not that bad it's modern c plus
plus
or you can use one of the runtimes that
we've that we've built
um so the standard one that's that's
better tested that governance runs at
the moment
is lua um we also have a project called
evm for ccf which allows you to use any
evm compatible language like so easy
to run smart contracts against the kv
store
or recently we've added javascript
support it's still a bit experimental
and there's probably the odd box here
and there still
but uh but it's coming as a supported
option as well um
so that's mostly it and the code is on
github so go check it out
and try it out any questions
yes i'm very curious that you have a
multiple station
yep i didn't hear any detail about it so
i wanted to ask is it possible to not be
a member
of the network and somehow do a
multi-station and say
okay this confidential network or
whatever
it is it has system integrity what kind
of points
do you use for the remote station
structure or some details because i
didn't see any slides about it
sorry acid working yes it's working uh
the real test station so uh sorry maybe
something i should have made clear is we
use the open enclave sdk
um and essentially at the moment so the
opening client sdk supports sgx mainly
so our stations are just sjx
at station there's a standard sjx at the
station and open enclave is adding
support for
armed trust zone coming pretty soon so
once they do we'll hopefully be
multi-enclave
um
they don't have a mechanism for that
yeah they don't have they don't have a
mechanism for that now yeah that's true
but at the moment if you run this yes
and it's using the format that's
open and click is using that's that's
right which is which is intel
enclave node and i'm not part of a
confidential network
yeah i can still verify
you don't need to use an open cloud node
so open enclave
provides a small utility library but the
intel sdk does as well
checking the remote attestation provided
by an enclave it's just a matter of
getting the right certs and the right
crls from intel in the right format
structure yeah the format is public i
mean it's specified in the intel sdk
documentation
so you don't have such use case where
someone wants to
externally verify your network so we do
and so if people want to do that
so as a user you can of course trust the
network identity because it's been given
to you by members and it's endorsed by
members
but if you want to verify the enclaves
for yourself before you connect one of
the things you can do is there is an
endpoint that allows you to get a list
of nodes
and the attestation for each node and
you could yourself verify that station
for each node
and make sure that it's running the
right version of the code uh
against an up-to-date you know intel jx
enclave and so on so you can do that
yourself as well if you want to
so if i would like to do that to develop
an application using the library you
mentioned
yeah you can absolutely do that okay and
then verify
yeah and so you'll be able to verify
that basically these nodes are running
um with a given identity so they'll have
the the public key
uh for the pair where they hold the
private key that's kept inside your
class
like the measurements yeah sorry what
the measurements
the measurements that are in the station
of the nodes yes
so it's the identity of the node the
code that the node is running and
the platform details yeah that's what
sjx at stations
provide to you yeah but i'll still be
bounded by the agx server
essentially to get the attestation so um
if you do this normally then yes you
have to talk to
the intel servers to get the search and
so on uh intel has a mechanism to to
delegate this so i know that in azure if
you use the microsoft cloud for example
uh um
yes you can use a microsoft service and
you can set up your own service to do
that
but you have to talk to intel it's
probably not super easy but it's
something you could probably do
yeah yeah i have business cards and you
come to me afterwards
yeah yeah okay good but thanks for the
answer thank you
so you have basically
i'm sorry how scalable is the framework
uh so that's a really good question
uh so the largest test we've run uh so
far were with about 20 nodes
so we run that to do performance
benchmarks that we put in the initial
technical reports
that we published about a year ago and
this was
across two regions so adamant azure only
supports sjx hardware in
uh east us and uh west europe regions um
so this is uh
sort of ten dollars like tennis one side
nine nodes uh the other side
and can you scale it to a larger number
of nodes like we hope you can
um the benefits are not super clear so
if you use if you use raft if you use
the cft implementation the only thing
that
more nodes lets you scale is reads so
you can scale the reads across the notes
but the writes still have to go through
a single leader
so you're making the leader the leader
busier because it has to replicate to
more nodes
um but if you have a really heavy
workload you know it might still be a
nice thing
you can also upload a signature
verification in cases where you have
proxies so
if your commands that come in are signed
um because the nodes are part of
uh are verified and a part of your
trusted compute base you could
have them verify the signatures before
they send stuff to the primary but it's
not a whole lot you can
offload to secondaries um in that
situation
and in in pbft unfortunately it's worse
than that because
um really every operation is a right
conceptually um because you need to get
proper consensus on it so it's not just
a leader doing things and
pushing updates out so in that case you
could you could scale up to a large
number of nodes but it's probably going
to cost you a lot in performance
it will give you good availability so
you'll be able to lose potentially a lot
of nodes
um but there won't be there won't be
super good benefits so there's work on
going and this is slightly longer term
work
it's probably not something that's going
to come out this year to add sharding to
ccf
and to really scale out to larger
volumes at the moment
um if you run ccf applications the best
benchmarks we have for applications that
are written in c plus plus
somewhere in the vicinity of like 50 60
000 transactions per second
so you can run like some stuff already
it's not it's not extremely large scale
but you can run reasonably large
applications
across two data centers geo-replicated
and so on and with sharding we're hoping
to do more
so i don't know if that answers your
questions
uh okay so the question is if i'm a new
user uh do i have to sign anything
and the answer is uh you don't have to
so it's it's standard tls
so if you have as a new user you won't
automatically
be allowed to take part in the service
unless the service is configured to be
very open
typically it's tls end to end so what
would happen is you have to talk to one
of the members and say
i want to participate here's my identity
can you add me that member would stage a
vote to add you then the rules the russo
government should apply and you know
you'd get it
now there could be schemes where you're
automatically allowed to participate
because your cert has been endorsed by
some identity of course and then the
governments might decide to do that but
you know
basically that's that's how the scheme
works and so once you've been added you
establish a tls session and you can
start talking to the service and that's
good enough as far as service is
concerned
we do support client signatures to
support use cases where
people might decide to proxy things so
if you are a client and you want to talk
to ccf
but you're not able to establish a
direct kiosk connection for whatever
reason
you could you could build a command sign
it with your identity
send it to cc have someone else send it
over to ccf they need to be allowed to
talk to ccf as well through their
identity
but the command would be recorded with
your signature and with your correct
identity um
there's a you know there's a trade-off
there it's it's a lot slower to do that
if you're trying to sell a lot of
transactions
um but on the other hand it means you
can sort of root through uh anywhere you
want
um so that's that's also nice and so if
you're trying to build some workflows
where you want verifiability for user
transactions as well as governance
transactions maybe you
you would want to enforce that so if you
have some very sensitive user operations
maybe you force the users to sign and
then you store the signatures in the
commands and people can offline verify
things
uh sorry i don't know if i'm running out
of time or not
no no but see vessel is getting closer
do we still have time or
yep one
you final question compromise in the
recovery yes um
so could you potentially even because
your hex is trusted you said you
you have to trusted members
like at the end basically the key shares
you mentioned yes could you basically
also use this uh to roll back the whole
uh like a whole state so in case of like
a
large scale compromise yes so that's
that's a good question and so the answer
is yes so if the members could decide
that they'll agree
that the last 20 transactions did not
happen and
so this is a good thing sometimes if
there's been a problem but it could also
be a bad things because the members
could be colluding
and what protection does the user have
against that and the answer is if
they've kept their receipts for those
transactions they could say i did have
this receipt
it was committed at this version and it
was signed by your service and although
you truncated it
post recovery i have proof that this was
in there in the ledger
and so you still have some defense
against that if the if the members
decide to truncate things because
they want to remove a sort of
inconvenient rather than illegitimate
operation
but yes when the members get together so
the process the way it actually works is
you spin up a bunch of nodes they look
at all the ledgers
they they verify um all the entries and
the signatures that are in there
and they give the members back
information about which the which which
one is the longest and has still been
globally committed
um and then the members can decide to
vote on that they could decide to
shorten the prefix for whatever reason
the signatures in the literature to be
clear signatures are done by nodes
so they allow you to attribute the
operations to particular nodes if you
know that some nodes are compromised
then this is how you can decide to you
know truncate various things
you