hi
um so initially another colleague of
ours was planned to
give this talk uh paul horn but he's
unfortunately sick so i'm
here instead my name is max what you
already said we all work for neo4j
specifically in the graph analytics team
and today we want to present you one
new or not so new project that we are
working on supposedly we are working on
this project and that is the
neo4j graph data science library um some
of you might already have used or not
have used the graph algorithms library
basically this is the successor of it um
i'll
go into the details about the history a
bit later for those
of you who don't or haven't used it so
far
what is the neo4j graph data science
library it's
basically a add-on for the neo4j
database
which is a graph database for those of
you who don't know
um and we are an add-on for that
that allows you to run graph algorithms
so
the neo4j database itself is more than
oltp database so it's um it's mainly
used for
um short queries uh that create only
um smaller parts of a graph using mostly
the cipher query language
um there are in with insight for their
support for some algorithms like
shortest path
um for example um but the neo4j graph
data science library gives you a much
broader
access to yeah graph
global graph algorithms
and we have implemented a broad set of
algorithms or
there exists a broad set of algorithms
we have items for community detection
and clustering
for example label propagation we have
algorithms for similarity calculation so
for example you can
calculate how similar are two nodes
given their neighborhood
therefore we use node similarity using
jakar similarity
we have centrality algorithms such as
page rank
we have some link prediction and
pathfinding algorithms pathfinding
we have dijkstra a-star
and then we have some auxiliary stuff
like graph creation for
the in-memory graph and another thing
the
library basically provides is is an api
for
implementing your own algorithms there
are certain ways you can do this the
easiest way is using the prager
framework
that was introduced by google it quite a
while ago so we also support that
and that allows you to easily write your
own algorithms and then also
make them available in neo4j through
cipher through the
procedure api
so when would you use the graph data
science library or
gds as we call it because graph data
science is pretty long
oh no no that's otherwise first we start
with some of the timeline information
so as i already said initially this
project started as the
neo4j graph algorithms library which was
a project that was bearheaded by the
neo4j
um deferral or labs organization led by
michael so he initially initiated this
project and it was uh
spiked by an external con by external
contractor avant-garde labs paul who was
initially
supposed to give this talk he um spiked
this project he's been working on his
project for quite a while and as you can
see this was already in
uh it started already in q1 2017
and then they kept on working for this
for a while yeah the library was already
open source and public by then you could
use it
and at some point in time um the neo4j
product engineering took actually over
so we came into the picture
um to actually make it a fully fledged
neo4j product and that work started in
q1 2019 so last year since then we've
been working on
mostly productizing library doing some
code refactorings making
sure that all the algorithms run in all
the ways you would expect them to
and also so that they have basically the
features that
users want them to have which is not to
say that
uh when when michael and paul and the
other guys are diverged that this
developed that they didn't focus on that
but
we talked to uh potential customers and
then
look what they actually wanted for
algorithms and then took a smaller
subset of the algorithms that already
existed and made sure that they run
in the best performance that we could
like
make them run and now we are at
basically today
um q1 2020 and we
are or have uh basically reopen sourced
the project so while
uh we were initially developing it as
neo4j product engineering
we had closed towards the project for a
while and we have now open source it
again the link for it i'll show you
later
and we will make a first
preview release i think next week and
then
in q2 2020 this will be
globally available through the usual
channels
mostly the neo4j desktop if you want to
try it out
so now when would you actually like to
use that
so we basically make the decision
between um
as i already mentioned the more oltp
focused so
like online transaction focused uh
workloads where you have small
short lived queries that you basically
run over and over again just with
different parameters for example for
example if you want to drive your
website then you would
um do more otp style queries where you
only touch a very small subset of your
graph
and this is where actually neo4j with
the cypher
language like performs on its best
that's not to say cypher
and neo4j both support also queries that
can do
more analytical or can support more
analytical work
cases or workloads but
from both the query language and mostly
neo4j it performs at its best when it's
oltp so short-lived graph
localized queries and then we have the
graph algorithm
algorithms library which is more when
you
actually uh when you want to
uh analyze the entire graph so you're
not really
not really knowing what you're actually
looking for so it's more
you have you have basically an idea um
of what you want to
analyze or maybe you have an idea of
of a hypothesis and you want to prove
that hypothesis then you can use the
graph algorithms library
and discover new insights in your graph
by doing graph global aggregations
so as i said when you run uh
more cipher style queries then you then
you only use a very localized part of
your graph and you actually know what
you're looking for you so you know that
i'm looking for a person named this and
that and i want to know its neighborhood
but when i'm using the analytics library
then i'm basically using all of my graph
or a very big
part of it and i'm basically digging
into the graph finding new information
finding new insight
and then maybe feeding it back and
that's where you call it graph data
science library maybe
feeding it back into my data data
science workflow
that is now aided by graph processing
uh yeah uh so how
does our library work how would you use
that for those who haven't basically
used the
um graph algorithms library
so we currently we always start off by a
neo4j database so you have your
graph loaded into your neo4j database
and it's living there
and here i'm using a graph which
basically i used
colors to the nodes and nodes with
different labels for example
and what you then do is because inside
of the
graph data science library we are using
an in memory model of the graph to
basically
empower those very fast
graph algorithm runs so we need we can't
really rely on the
layout and the store layout of neo4j so
what we are doing is we are taking
reloading the graph from neo4j into
an in-memory model so and that's what
you would always start with
you load your graph you can project the
graph so that means you can
rename labels you can skip certain
labels
so you can skip nodes with a certain
label you can skip relationships
you can rename relationships and also
you can
load certain properties or not load
certain properties and you can even
reverse the direction of edges
into you and memory graph so that i've
visualized here so we've basically
skipped the red notes in this
visualization and now we have our
subgraph in memory
this graph now lives in a thing that we
call the graph catalog
um basically it's just what you would
imagine it's uh
the graph basically has a name and you
can retrieve that graph by the name
within as long as you stick into
or stick in inside of the graph data
science library
so we've loaded this graph now into
memory uh and now it's time to run an
algorithm
so here for example we do some
clustering in my example
so you specify now i want to use this in
memory graph and i want to run
for example a clustering algorithm and
then what you get is you get another in
memory graph or
some information about that graph that
says well i think those nodes belong to
a cluster and the other nodes belong to
a cluster
and then as a next step you would
consume this result you could run
another algorithm on that graph maybe
using the information from the first run
or you consume the information that the
algorithm
returned to you and you can do this in
two ways you can either
write the results back into neo4j this
mostly happens by
writing a node property so for example
if you do the clustering
we would write a property on every node
that says well this node i think belongs
to cluster
with the id1 or you can for some
algorithms like the similarity
algorithms you would write back
a relationship to the graph and another
option is you can stream back results
so if you don't want to persist the
result of the algorithm you can just
stream back the result
inside of your cipher query and then use
it in your in the driver
or your application program as you see
fit
so these are currently the two ways that
we are supporting
um and yeah the most important thing is
the workflow always starts currently at
neo4j then you load a graph you can load
as many graphs as you like or as fit
into your memory
and then you can use them for
for running algorithms and then you can
consume the result
so what kind of algorithms do we have
are already hinted towards that we have
community detection to find clusters of
nodes that somehow belong together
we have centrality or importance of
certain nodes
patrons probably the most well known
there or between the centrality
similarity algorithms uh link prediction
and pathfinding
and search those that are currently
marked in bold font here
are the ones that we have actually
productized by productize we mean they
here we guarantee some some form of
matureness of the algorithm
by our team and by neo4j
basically that is if you use that if you
use those parts we
hope that those are bug free run as fast
as they can
all these things and i think it's time
for
a demo now so i
actually
where's my mouse
[Music]
um i have this neo4j browser here
which is huge i'm sorry for that i can't
really change that
um i'm gonna zoom out no okay so
um what i've loaded into this graph is
basically the game of thrones data sets
that
we we're using for many examples so it's
basically
an extract of how people in the game of
thrones
books um when people appear together on
a page
then we basically create notes for those
people and then we link them together
with an edge and so we have edges
interacted with so people interacted
with another in a certain book and then
we have those interactions also
split up into these different books we
have some more information that we're
actually not going to use in this demo
so this is actually the most
important information we have persons
and then they interact with one another
this graph is loaded into this neo4j
database
we can run a simple query here to see
to get a bit of an idea of how this
graph looks like
um this basically just uh counts the
average number of
interactions between the people so in
average people interact with another
or people interact with 6.7 other people
in the book
the person who interacts with most of
people has 170 interactions that's just
to get an idea i think it's about 5000
notes and
slightly more slightly more edges in the
graph
um yeah and now we can dive into the
uh graph data science library
as i said the first thing we always do
is we have to load a graph
that's horrible um so what we do is we
use the
cipher procedure language here because
we are as i said we are a plugin so
you can use the graph data science
library wire the procedure calls
um so the first procedure call is that
we would do is we would
say gds which every every of our
commands are prefixed with
then graph that's basically all the
catalog commands and then creates
because we want to create a new graph
and what we say here additionally is we
want to call this graph got into actions
because we
from the got graph or game of thrones
graph we load all the interactions
then we specify a node projection and
that means what kind of nodes do we want
to load so we have
a very simple form you can specify
specify
many more things if you like but here
you just want to load every person that
is in the graph so every node that is
labeled with the labeled person
and for relationships we want to
load all the interactions relationships
and then we have a thing that we call
projection that means
because we need to know in which
direction do we want to load
uh the relationships because of how we
store them internally we need to know
do we want to have them in their natural
direction that is
how they are in the database from no
from one node into another because neo4j
every node is directed
do we want to load them in reverse then
we would say reverse or do we want them
undirected
and then undirected we basically store
them twice in every direction
and that's what we're doing here so we
basically get if one person interacts
with the other person then it also also
the other person interacts with the one
person
so we load this graph um run the query
and then we get and we get some
information back about what we just
loaded i mean that's basically
the same thing we named the got into
actions here's what i said we just
specified in very simple form of a node
protection
uh here's the extended form and then it
gives us some information so we have
only two thousand nodes now seven
thousand interactions or relationships
and it
took 767 milliseconds to load that
um right so now it's time to run
a first algorithm we're going to use
pagerank for that
where am i here i guess most of you do
know
i can't find my way back no
ah there it is so we are running
the patreon algorithm now uh page rank
as i said is a centrality
algorithm so it gives every node a score
about how important is it to the network
um and here again we can basically
demonstrate how
our um algorithm syntax looks like so we
have
again gds our general prefix then the
algorithm we want to run and then the
mode we want to run on as i said there
are two
different ways of how we can consume
algorithms it's either by writing or by
streaming
here we stream the results back to the
user we say
we want to run this algorithm on this
graph in our catalog got interactions
and that's basically it because we don't
want to specify any more or any more
detailed
things about the algorithm we just run
it with the default settings
and when we run it we almost immediately
get some information back
in this case we see that jon snow is
apparently the most
important note in our network with a
page rank of 17 point
something followed by tyrion lannister
and ceci lannister
for those of you who've read the books
that kind of make sense at least to me
they are the most important characters
in the book series
so at least it's returning what we would
have expected
um to show a more detailed example
because we're running out of time um
we have no that doesn't work because um
yeah i think we don't have much more
time for more examples
um so let's switch back to the
demonstration
right the presentation i mean
again um just a short wrap-up of how the
algorithm syntax looks like we have
always a call because we want to in
cypher
we want to run the procedure we have the
algorithm name and then the mode
we have the graph name and then the
configuration so you can specify many
more things for the algorithm for
pagerank for example
you can specify the dampening factor
or whatever configuration you have or
when you write back you can you have to
specify
into which property you want to write
the page rank value
we have usually three different modes we
have write we have stream and then we
have a stats mode which basically just
returns
the metadata about an algorithm runs
basically just as writing
without the writing but it gives you
some information about how long did the
algorithm take to
compute maybe some information about a
distribution of the result
here's another example with weakly
connected components so you can see you
can specify many more
properties or yeah configuration options
for your algorithm run
and with that i want to thank you for
listening as
i said we have open source the
repository just last week i think you
can find it under neo technology just
graph analytics on github
uh currently it doesn't build uh we
haven't
it doesn't it is green but there we
haven't released anything of our build
configuration yet that's a bit of a
problem
we're working on that soon you will be
able to also build that but
at least you can already have a look at
the at the code and
hopefully at some point start hacking on
it and trying it out
thank you
so uh questions we have
time for maybe two or three questions
um is the data science library uh
accessible from like
titan or other languages so the question
is if it's accessible from
from python or other languages um it is
kind of through cipher i mean you can
use the python cipher driver and then i
mean what you're writing is basically
just cipher queries you can
prepend or append cipher statements
around your algo call as you as you see
fit
there's currently no way of basically
writing your own algorithms in python
we've been thinking about that we've
experimented a bit with that but we
don't have anything that is working in
that direction currently
allows you to use
next tuesday in amsterdam in the
graphics
just maybe uh two things it's actually
uh slash neo4j slash graph data science
if you want to go to the
version of it
it's also available online free for
download so the book that was around
here
um just go to neo4j.com and you can
download the copy of the book which
explains all the articles
that are part of the library
and with the pre-release that max
mentioned for next week
we will also do a docs prerelease that
explains all the api that he just
sketched over
in of course very much more detail
so yeah thanks again max
you