okay so we moved to our next talk
please welcome r1 we'll speak about jpeg
2000s
uh good morning everybody my name is
aaron and
today i'm going to talk about jpeg 2000
um just a show of hands has anyone ever
intentionally stored an image
as jpeg 2000 okay
that's impressive um so it was actually
designed to replace
jpeg um but never about 20 years ago but
never really made it
um but i has been one of my obsessions
for the last
five years and i think it's actually the
codec of the future
and that's what we'll go into today
so to understand jpeg 2000 we have to go
back to its predecessor jpeg
and i'm going to take you back into the
90s
to the rise of jpeg so
um this was standardized in 1992
and it really came of age with the
internet as
with the dawn of the internet and by the
end of the 90s
uh about a quarter of the internet
traffic was uh
jpegs now um we all know that was mostly
porn
but uh still that was that was an
important way of
of rising up in the internet and now we
all have a jpeg encoder
a decoder in our pockets in our phone so
it's extremely successful
standard but there were some issues
so um here you have on the right picture
of a flower and you can see
this is about a one bit per sample image
so you can see
the block artifacts that you get
in these that you've all seen over here
because
jpeg uses an eight by eight uh pixel
block to do its compression and so
um when you get very low bit rates you
start to see the boundaries around the
um the pixel blocks the eight by eight
pixel blocks
so that's a big problem another issue is
it's only lossy so if you need lossless
compression
uh you can't use jpeg there is another
there's a lossless standard for jpeg
but nobody really uses it and it's a
completely different codec framework
so um which is an ideal we're also
limited to eight bits so if you wanted
to do a medical
or remote sensing you can't use jpeg for
that
more limitations are you can only use
three components
there's limits on the dimensions of the
image uh
to 16-bit and one of the big
issues is recom rate control so the only
way to actually
uh target a specific rate for an image
is to continually recompress
until you get down to that target image
and um
each time you recompress you're losing
data so it's really not ideal
um so those were the limits um
that gave rise to jpeg 2000
which was supposed to address these
limitations but it also added a whole
bunch of new features which i'm going to
go into
in a moment so um only six years after
jpeg was standardized
this jpeg 2000 they began to standardize
typic 2000 um it was based on the work
by david taubman his thesis work
uh those are the monikers for um the itu
and iso
uh standards and it is free uh
taubman actually donated his ip so that
he would make sure that it was a
royalty-free codec
and um when you introduce a new codec
you definitely want to have better image
compression than the original
so that is in fact the case so jpeg 2000
has
up to 200 percent better performance
than jpeg meaning you get smaller images
for the same
um uh um same
same same bit rate or same uh signal to
noise ratio
um but besides that um you look at the
um artifacts between these two images
it's the it's about
it's a one bit per sample image of the
lena image but you see
um on the right is jpeg 2000 um
because of the transform for a jpeg 2000
we do a wavelet transform
versus a eight by eight uh transfer for
jpeg
so when you lose data you just blur the
image
uh you don't get those pixelated
artifacts in jpeg
so that was a big advantage
for the new standard
and also it supports lossy and lossless
in one framework
um which is nice the only difference
being losty and lossless is um the
transform is a little different
for lossy and there's quantization where
you lose data but otherwise the
framework is exactly the same um and
then you can get
visually lossless uh encoding where
there is
loss of data but you can't uh the human
eye can't detect the difference
so that's visually excuse me visually
lossless
um one of the big innovations though is
the progression um
that it introduces so um progression is
used by a codec to um so that the
decoder can do a partial decode of the
image and still get something
useful out of it and here this is what
people are mostly familiar with
is a progression by quality so you can
see that
image of the butterfly being downloaded
and
already by the first second or third
frame you can start to see something
useful even though you've only
downloaded about eight percent
of the image so um jpeg 2000
allows you to um create quality layers
and that you can and package up those
layers
and if you progress by quality you can
progressively download and get a useful
image when you haven't downloaded the
the complete result and this is how we
do it
so that's an image of a castle in eight
bits
so these are the bit planes for all the
bits in each of those samples
so that's the so that's the most
significant bit over there
and so we create these bit planes and
each plane is
compressed uh there's three different
passes that we
run through the through the plane to
compress it so it's very
computationally expensive but we create
many different
uh layers or or passes
for that image that we can then package
up into different quality layers and you
get a very fine-grained
uh set of quality layers that you can
break the image
up into and and that's
a graph of the distortion as you
build up the bit planes so for an 8-bit
image you could have 23
different passes and each pass can be
packaged up in different
quality layers using this epcot which is
the formula the algorithm for for
determining these
quality layers and um and so
that was a big innovation but there's
three other different ways of
progressing in jpeg 2000 this is
progression by resolution so that's a
that's a wavelet
uh transform of this image we we do low
and high pass filters
on the x and y coordinates and so we
actually uh on the top left you get a
low res
thumbnail of the original image and then
high pass
high pass bands they're called sub bands
so there's four different sub bands and
so built in baked into the codec you
have
lower resolution replicas of the
original image without any redundancy
and we would do this wavelet transform
maybe four or five times so you inside
the actual image there are multiple
lower resolution replicas that you could
then as you're decoding
um you could bring those images out
without actually
storing extra data as a thumbnail it's
actually built in so you can progress by
resolution
if you if that's how you encode it
there's also a progression by spatial
region uh
you can see these are the original sub
bands that
we had from the wavelet these big blue
boxes
and then inside we have the precincts
and inside the precincts we have the
code blocks
and so you can actually encode by
precinct and store the image
progressing that way and that's useful
for let's say you have a scanner
let's say you're limited by memory you
might want to encode one
precinct at a time and then move on
and it's also useful for random access
into the
into the image and the final one is
progression by component
so if it's an rgb image you can
break it down into your luminance and
your chroma channels and you can
progress by those channels and if you're
a grayscale printer maybe you can just
throw away the chroma
and keep the luminance so that's that's
another progression that you can get
there's a bunch of other features that
you you have in jpeg 2000 one is
error resilience so you built into the
code stream when you're encoding it you
can
you have to terminate each code stream
segment and you can terminate those
segments in a way that
when the decoder is decoding those
segments it can tell whether there's
been an error
in the segment and also we have these
precincts that contain
errors in the code so if there's an
error in one precinct it can't
migrate into the next precinct so we
contain errors that way
we also have recompression resilience so
typically an image might be compressed
and decompressed multiple times
and so uh the codec is doesn't
lose a lot of information for the for
the subsequent
compression and recompression like
decode and decode so
it's um it's a that's another feature to
have that we have
um and then you get random access into
the code stream from
if you do uh progression by code block
so if you have an enormous image from a
remote sensing
let's say you want to just decode a
small piece of the image you can
actually put markers into the code so
that you can locate that
particular region of the image and
decode that
which is useful for for huge images
we also do low latency because it's an
intra codec so each frame is encoded
individually and so you can um get very
low latency unlike uh for example h.264
where you have groups of pictures
that are encoded together each frame is
encoded separately
and you can get low latency that way
also a region of interest where you just
increase the quality in a certain part
of the image let's say you're doing
video conferencing you want to focus on
the face so that's
built in as well so with all these cool
features um
who adopted j2k um first of all with
medical
imaging it's uh considered the gold
standard because you can do lossless
which is important for legal issues and
you can do high bit rates like 10
12 and 16 bits so medical imaging it's
popular
in remote sensing because you can
support 16
000 components if you like so and very
large dimensions so it's popular
there um and also a few people realize
that whenever you watch a movie you're
actually watching jpeg 2000 decoding
because it's the standard
for digital cinema and the reason is
because of that resolution by
a progression by resolution because the
4k image that you encode
has a 2k image built in so the 2k
projector can
actually just decode the low level
sub band and throw away the rest so it's
backwards compatible and that's
used it's a standard today
and so what went wrong with all these
wonderful features
yes there is an xkcd comic for this
um well first of all patents
um there was a company called lizard
tech
which uh claimed all wavelet based
codecs were there where
you had to license from them and that
was eventually invalidated but that was
caused some fun for the emerging
standard
microsoft was uh the monopoly in those
days and they had their competing
standard called
xr jpxr so they didn't support jp2000
there was browser support was poor even
this is 2015. you can see only 20 of the
browsers support
the standard and um hardware support
um the hardware vendors were waiting for
the software
uh people to be able to display the
images the software vendors were waiting
for the hardware to
produce those images so it they never
really
supported them in hardware and finally
performance
this because of the complexity of the
codec it's very very slow because of all
those
passes through all those bit planes it's
a very very complex codec and so it was
very slow um and jpeg was already there
so that was good enough
so those were all the reasons why
it never really made it um
now there's been a change in the codec
to address the performance
called high throughput jpeg 2000 and
they keep everything the same and they
change the block coder which is the
piece at the very center uh of the codec
that actually
creates the bitstream and that's what
what creates all those
bit planes and all those passes so
they've simplified the block coder
and um this gives you a big speed
increase
uh 10 times possibly and it's was
standardized this year
sorry last year 2019 and so it's also
royalty free
and the difference is that it's actually
friendly for gpus and vector
calculations which was
different than the original encoder
which was designed when actually
multiplication was expensive
so they tried to avoid multiplication by
creating branches and
and and doing a very serial approach
and so that doesn't really work on
modern hardware so this one is designed
um with cindy in mind there are fewer
passes
and you just sacrifice the quality
scalability
that you had from the original jpeg but
everything else is the same
and you can also losslessly transcode
between the two formats so you can
encode it one way it for speed and then
later
convert it to the original for
distribution and they're trying there is
a decoder in it by within script and
that will
hopefully address the browser issues
that they had with the original standard
um these are the open source toolkits
open jpeg is the
and the granddaddy of j2k toolkits
there's grok which is one that i
maintain
and there's something called open jph
which is only for
high throughput jpeg 2000
and any questions
i i i have a lot of time for questions
we have
questions from um the online
uh forum a lot of questions about jpeg
access
right actually i had slides for jpeg xs
and i took them out because i
i thought i would be going over time but
um so
so yeah i can talk about that a little
bit um so
jpeg xs is actually a competing standard
for the same
space it's based on a wavelet transform
it's also low complexity low latency
the big difference is that it's actually
a patented standard it's being promoted
by intupix
and fraunhofer the people who brought
you the mp3 patents um
they are way hoping to license that
so i'm hoping that the open
solution is going to win but they're
they're in the same space and actually
from what i've heard the j2k is actually
faster
than the um than the jpeg xs
and it's actually the image quality is
is higher for the same bit rates
so um so it looks promising but that is
a competing standard
in the same space um how do you think
also about any questions
what about the new energetic standard
called xl
with the google algorithm that will
start next
sorry the question is um how will the
new jpeg xl
standard compare with jpeg 2000 um
actually i'm not i actually don't not
familiar with the xl standard
so um i can't really comment on that
but um
some people from google and it's
great compatible with jpeg but as
complicated but has additional features
from
really um yeah well um yeah i
i i can't really it's hard to say but
it's um i mean the more standards
i think i mean the nice thing about
standards is there's so many to choose
from
and um so i think it'll be it's it's
we're actually in a renaissance a jpeg
of jpeg standards and there's uh there's
there's xt
i think which is backwards compatible
with jpeg but adds
hdr and things like that so i think i
think it's a good thing that
i i'd have to learn more about this
codec to comment
so you mentioned that it's a very kind
of a scalable project that you can
extract low resolution images from
uh
so the question is would is it possible
to decode an image
starting with the lower resolution first
and progressing
upwards is that yes so you can start
um so yeah that's that's the whole yeah
yes you can so that's the whole point of
progression is the way if you encode it
and store it
by resolution then you can actually you
can actually choose i only want the
lowest two
or three resolutions and you throw away
everything else and you can only
you may not even just send that low
resolution piece
so yeah it's designed to do that
um oh sorry the question is
is it possible to only truncate by
resolution
and then throw away the rest um well you
mean
from the encoder to actually encoding in
terms of
if you wanted to store lower resolution
textures
you could literally store the first 10
of the file if that date is held in a
linear in that linear fashion
um you would not become i think you
would if you
it wouldn't really be compliant because
the the header would say i have 10
resolutions and you've only
stored three but most of the decoders
are used to handling all
um abuse of the standard and so they
will
um handle that they will only you could
you could store it it would be decoded
they might complain about it but they
they would decode
those lower so it's that's that you
could you could definitely do that and
there's actually a
i didn't go into there's a there's
something called jpip which is a
progressive
format for for doing this actually
there's that for for sending it over the
wire
there's actually a a standard part of
the jpeg 2000
standard for doing progressive um
sending it progressively over the the
network
yes
the question is is jpeg 2000 available
as mxf so
mxf is the exchange format for um so yes
so ms
mxf supports jpeg 2000 and so you could
you could package it
um
well this is very new so i think you'll
be getting i don't think mxf supports it
they're going to be adding it to mxf i
know that and they're going to be adding
it to the digital
cinema standard and i think everyone's
going to be adopting us because
it's uh just fixes some problems and
doesn't really have much of a downside
for those
workflows because because you don't need
the progression by quality
so much for for in that workflow so
um but mxf yeah i don't think it
supports because it was just
uh end of last year that they
standardized the high throughput so
it but i think it will come
so the question is how much slower is
jpeg 2000 versus jpeg
it depends a lot on the implementation
so
the for example open jpeg was really
in terms of open source toolkits so
so david taubman has his own codec
that's um
closed kodak called kakadu which has
always been very fast and had all the
features
and the open source toolkits were slow
and
and filled with bugs for the longest
time
but recently um they've gotten quite
fast so they now support multi-threading
they've tried to optimize them um so
i don't have actual numbers but um
on a modern machine with a good with
even with open jpeg or with my
uh toolkit um i think you're you're
looking at maybe
twice as slow for the j2k but with the
with the with a new high throughput i
think we could actually get faster
than jpeg because it's designed for um
gpu and for
for vector operations so i think we can
actually get faster
than jpeg which is going to be really
cool i think
yes
[Music]
so the question is what's the expected
encode time for
for it it depends on the size of the
image and a 4k image um
okay so uh on modern hardware um
so so to so now you could get you could
encode that okay encoding
see the some of the codecs they don't
focus on encoding they focus on decoding
and encoding is slow it actually open
jpeg gets single threaded
but um so encoding a 4k image um
it's like an 8 bit uh 8-bit image or a
12-bit
8-bit um i guess maybe you could do it
um
uh 10-15 frames per second on
on a modern machine and with the
multi-core with the you know with the
new uh thread rippers and all that you
can really
get a good performance but um it's it
would it would really depend a lot on
the image
and the content and how compressible it
is and
um how many cores and all that but um
you can
you could get maybe 10 15 frames per
second
encoding on on a modern cpu and
the decoder could be even um maybe 20
frames per second
decoding a 4k which is and the and the
high throughput is maybe
three or four times faster than that
when you do the whole encoding the block
coder is much faster but the whole
codec is going to be on significantly
faster
last question
so the question is is encoding and
decoding different
in terms of speed um there's actually
there are actually some tricks you can
do in encoding that you don't you can't
do in decoding meaning because you know
the whole
you actually know all the pixels in in
it
you actually know all the pixels that
you're going to be encoding before
you're encoding them so you can actually
do some tricks to speed things up
but um i think decoding is going to be
faster than the encoding
it's the way it's designed because most
you usually decode many times the only
code one time so it should be
it depends on a lot of other factors how
they implemented it and
and that sort of thing thank you
you