yeah welcome
at this afternoon i'm roland
i will talk to you about ptx list as my
previous speaker already
mentioned it i'm a systems integration
hacker at
pingatonix we are a
small company in hildesheim near hanover
if you've heard about it yeah so
what is this oh sorry
yeah so what does pit exist in one slide
it's basically a build system like if
you know yokto
or open embedded or build route or even
open wrt
so you put in
things you want on your platform
on your embedded device and then you
wait some hours
and then you get an image out of it
which you can flash on your
target and
her building blocks are basically going
to make
we do a lot of dependency handling with
it because it's
basically built for this so we can reuse
it
and we do the dependency handling in
k config and
which also gives us a nice nice menu
for the user to select the packages that
you want and select the sub options and
what not there's some glue code in in
bash
and a wk
which handles the
dependencies between k config and make
so it
basically transforms the k config
symbols
the dependencies from k config into the
gnu make
dependencies and does
some other things under the hood so you
don't have to type so much
yeah the first versions of ptx just go
back to
at least 2003 that's the
earliest version i could find there are
probably some
older versions but i couldn't find those
um yeah so it's basically older than
uh i think build roots started in 2010
and jopto is 2001.
oh okay then i'm wrongly informed uh
excuse me about that
but uh well it's an old project and uh
i think uh it isn't known so much so uh
basically
that's what this talk is trying to
change but now we do
mostly monthly releases so every release
every month there's a new release and
which is
basically just version bumps for
packages so
yeah the overall license for ptx tests
and
all the recipes are gpl2 yeah
and now we also have this shiny new
logos
since i think one year ago
because we're basically just a
collection of recipes we have this uh
this cooking penguin and an online
documentation which is generated from
restructure text in swings
and you can read this online yeah some
statistics
um i did this for the for the previous
release uh
2020.01 is already out but
my slides were prepared last month so
we have about 914 target packages
and 184 host packages
and we're also providing some
pre-built two chains for about 18
plus minus platforms uh architectures
like uh
mostly arm like arm4
and v7 are very big
and of course the 64-bit version of arm
and there are also some people using it
on x86 but this is not the
main focus and uh of course uh
risk five and then some older power pc
architectures yeah
i think the basic thing which you got to
see
for on the user interface side is this
menu config
[Music]
we have two big i say
too big but they're not very big menu
configs
on the one hand we have the menu config
for your user space
for your user land which you can select
in which you can select all your
target packages like uh i don't know we
have here
shell and console tools scripting
languages like python for example
uh networking tools i don't know ip
tables uh
nf tables what you need disk file
utilities communication
applications well everything that
doesn't fit in the
into the other editors like
vm and nano
um test suites web applications nginx
you name it and graphics and multimedia
like
qt wayland
yeah and xorg still
and on the other side um everything
that's not
user land uh like kernel and farebox
sorry bootloader which is spare box
for us uh but you can also build of
course u-boot
and um i don't know opti is there
in in it um basically everything that's
um
below the the user land uh is
selectable in this platform config so
we have this bare metal side on the
platform config side and
everything that's above it in the menu
config
and this is also what the typical bsp
looks like on the file
level um you have one folder configs
which you have here the ptx config which
is
what gets selected in the menu config
and
this is basically the k config
configuration for the
from which the menu is generated
and in it you have a platform
so this is everything you select in the
platform config
and um in the platform there are usually
some other packages that are also using
kconfig for their own
configuration like for example here the
kernel you
i guess you have a kernel um without the
kernel
i don't know if everyone's ever anyone's
ever tried it but
maybe it's possible i don't know but um
also the conflict for your bootloader
which in this case is bearbox
and yeah that's basically everything in
configs and you have
some rules some package rules if you
want to
build some custom software which is not
already in pjxist
you can generate package rules in your
bsp
and this is basically a dot in file
which contains the kconfig menu entry
and the make file which handles
everything about building the packages
yeah and then there's this folder in
between here project root
i will come to this later this is
basically everything
which you want to overwrite but i will
say
something about this later yeah the
basic structure
is the basic idea is that your bsp
structure is structured exactly like the
ptx this upstream structure so
we have the same structure in pt exists
when you install it so everything that's
not found here
in your bsp is searched instead
in the upstream htx this installation
folder so
you can extend pdx this however you want
and use the same structure with it yeah
um
every package is built in stages i guess
you have this in
other build systems too um
yeah it has a get stage and extract
stage to prepare a compile and install
and the token install stage and which
basically if
the get stage fetches everything from
from the web
um and
then the extract stage extracts the
tarball which you just fetched and
applies the local patches which you
maybe have in your vsp or in upstream
btx
the prepare stage runs basically
configure or cmag or
mison or whatever build your system your
package uses ptxtest has
already support for many of those
and i think it is fairly easy to
provide support for other build systems
too
[Music]
and we'll see later how this uh
is handled in the in the rule file
itself in the mac file for the package
it's basically just a variable usage
yeah and then the compile stage
basically just compiles the packages
package like it is normally used
the install stage installs it into an
isolated directory so
many packages uh install
many files by default which you don't
use or don't
need on your target system for example
if you build acute then
[Music]
you have a whole lot of libraries which
you maybe don't want to install
so the next step is this toggle install
stage which
cherry picks a set of files
into your root file system or
your ipkg package later
and you can overwrite
any one of those stages in your makefile
rule in your package make file
but you can also reuse a lot of them
which we see
just now oh no
just a quick information how to apply
patches
you put your patch queue into a patches
folder in your vsp or
in the upstream ptx test package
structure if you're using
a pdx test in a development version um
and you name it like the the version and
the
name of your package in this case
puzzybox with the version number
and there is a serious file and the
patch file here
and the usual
[Music]
the usual thing is that you uh put
packages
for the uh which um sorry the usual
thing is to put patches for your
packages which
are from the platform config like
the kernel or the bootloader or anything
else in this area
into this
config slash platform folder
yeah but you can also put it in in there
and have it for all the platforms which
you want
so um you can edit this uh this patch
stack
uh by using quilt or git after
extracting the package
and then changing to the package
directory where it's extracted yeah
uh this is what i wanted to tell uh how
a package looks like
in the inside this is basically the the
menu section for the package you just
give a section
in which of these one you want to
uh want to have it project
specific is the default section which uh
is just uh here
and um
then you select basically the the
dependencies that your package uses like
in this case lib usb so lib usb gets
built before
your package gets built so all the
headers are found and so on
and also in this case because we're
using
cmake in this example you also have to
select the cmake host tool
so ptxtest can build your package
yeah and every package is a tri-state
option
so you can set it to yes no or
module which you can see which we'll see
later what
that does then we have the makefile
as i said it's a lot of assigning
variables like
the version number and the md5 for the
downloaded package version
for this url and the source where it
gets extracted
and the license files
and the license files are really cool
because
uh ptxs can put them all together in one
big pdf
so you have kind of a report about all
the licenses
you're using in your package yeah in
your image
um and if you're using the default
tools like cmake or automatic you often
don't really have to do a lot of these
and can reuse all the internal ptxtest
functionality to build it so the next
steps are really
short and reuse everything except the
prepared the target install stage
and then the prepare stage we are also
only setting this
config tool variable so to cmake and
we are setting these config options for
the cmake
to maybe enable our usb functionality
but this depends of course on the
package you're using
and then in the target install stage we
set up our
variables for the ipkg package which
gets built later and
basically we're then only copying
here should be a file name which i
missed in the example
but yes
this is the cherry picking part
and we have three package types as i
already said we have target packages
which are get
installed on the hosts like simply busy
box core utils whatever
and the host packages are only there for
uh having a compatible build environment
so
we try to support most of the linux
distributions that are out out there i
think that
the earliest is something like scent os
six yes um which
doesn't have an up-to-date core utils so
we have to build the courier tools
ourselves so all the packages which are
using
i don't know tar with dash dash
uh m-time versions or something
can do that yeah and the third part is
image packages
which are also from the platform config
and
you can decide there what kind of images
you want to build
so i will talk about layering a bit so
ptx just started up with platforms
so platforms are the oldest mechanism to
layer things on top of each other but
there are
five different others uh we'll start
with platforms
um in this example i'm maybe using a
platform
for raspberry pi so i have a kernel
with a version 419 i built an hd image
for it
and the raspberry pi needs a
boot partition for the bootloader so i
enable this
and because it already has a boot loader
internally
i don't build a bear box for it and in
the user land i
in this example i build a system the a
busy box and a cups
and if i now want to extend this support
to other platforms
i can just build add another platform
like for example a platform containing
arm v7a and on 64-bit v8
and i can choose different kernel
versions here
and with this also maybe a different
patch stack
if your if your platform support is not
good enough
upstream and i can choose different
images which i need
and maybe a bootloader another
bootloader like in the
other platforms and i talked about
that packages are tri-state options in k
conflict
so you can set these options
to maybe m so modular and
maybe you want to have a debug
collection
software collection that doesn't
get installed by default on a user's
or a customer's target but you still
want to be able to debug
some packages in your system so
you set this these debug packages to m
and then choose them at a later step in
a collection config file
and in the debug collection you enable
them and maybe in the release
collection you don't enable them yeah
these are collections then we have
alternative conflict files as i said
before
[Music]
we had this
this additional folder here project root
and here are two conflict files everstep
and shadow
in utc and
you can use this with packages that are
using this
install alternative macro in their
target install stage
for example in this example uh
for cups cups is installing the edc
print cap file
and you can override this by
any one of these locations so first
locally in your bsp then it gets
searched
further up then in the
project root directory from the pdx test
installer
and then in the cups installer and then
in the cups built here
so you have a lot of options to
overwrite
config files for different
configurations
a new mechanism uh which exists about a
year now is
called k config divs um which is
basically
just uh divs on simple diffs on k config
files um
if you are using a custom kernel image
for example you want to have some debug
symbols
in there you set the conflict file to
something like config debug which is
living in the platform configure as
earlier but um you tell
protects this this ref config variable
and this points to another
kernel config in this case and then
internally ptxis computes
the diff between what you select in this
k conflict file
and this k config file so you
do a many config for your kernel debug
and then enable these three symbols
and uh these two symbols later get uh
written into the
the k convective and
at the first stage the first line is
an md5 sum of the ref config
in so pdx knows when to
uh recalculate this diff
and k config divs are also the
one of the building blocks for base
layers
so as i said before we had this idea to
have the same structure in our bsp like
in in the upstream ptextist
installation folder and extend
locally where we need it but we have a
better idea
and our problems on computer science can
be solved by another level of
indirection so
we use recursion
in this case we have one bsp
which is a whole bsp by itself it has
the same structure
as before and we want to layer our bsp
on top of it so
all we have to do is just create a link
named base
to this upper or lower layer
in this case and uh everything you
now select in the ptx config is
calculated as a div
to this pdx config on the district layer
and you can
enhance your your bsp
in relation to the lower layer by
adding rules for example and this is
great if you
don't want to share all your rules in
one layer for example your customer only
gets an open source layer
that gives you only an open source layer
and wants to layer
their own property software on top of it
and this is
one way you can do it
some more goodies which got added in the
last stage there is now
a command to give information about one
package
uh and one to give information about
ubsp
and as i already mentioned is the
license report
which basically uh collects all the
information
from the kernel from from the package
recipes and dumps into one big pdf
and also extracts all the the copyright
files
yeah if you want to try this out you can
have a look at districts which is a
pre-configured psp for
a variety of death boards like nitrogen
6 or
even the raspberry pi some versions of
it not the 4 version sadly
and you can also use an qmo if you want
[Music]
short things about contribution you can
patch the sand patches patches are
welcome
currently about 85 percent of patches
are in-house but maybe the changes
yeah so are there questions
[Applause]
so the my package example that you
showed us
has um a usb in the in the prepare
yeah section it has a d usb on
what um what would you suggest
if i want to have that configurable
um you can add another kconfig symbol
which is dependent on the onto the top
symbol
um so you basically extend this
this symbol by another sub symbol
call like yeah and you can
switch it on and off and then you can
use a macro here
which just looks if this k config symbol
is switched on or off yeah all right and
is this
is this something that is uh halfway
common
in yeah in the packaging i just used a
simple example here but this is really
common
and also for for controlling what
dependencies my package will pull in
in in the cups example which i showed
here you can build cups with
uh many different uh dependencies like
png support or
whatever not yeah and is that
does that have to be then set per
package
in the ptx config yeah this is also
written to the ptx config because
it is in the menu so it gets written
into the ptx yes but does it has to
does it have to be configured per
package
or is there is there some some uh some
standardization
on these on the naming let's say of
these sub
um sub options so that i can set them
globally for the whole image
in one place yeah this is usually for
the whole image yes
okay
okay then i think the time is
up thank you