hi
um i'm mark villards and
this isn't frank eichler sorry
he couldn't be there
but well i i will try it's a bit of a
pity because
frank actually did all the work
so that's not completely too frank
that most of the
the server work and the client work was
done by
aaron or mary who is also not here
but well so if the presentation
is lame that's on me
the code is actually pretty good
okay um we all three work
for redhead but
the goal was very explicitly
not to make something just for rel or
fedora so
okay so the summary is
uh we have a debug info
v demon uh
we realized too late it should have been
dwarfed
barf demon of course but well
now we're stuck with the name um and
it's essentially just a file server for
the
king artifacts uh
uh why would you uh need debugging
artifacts
because maybe you have ducks in your
code
some people do create lots of bags in
their code
so that's not a problem
you debug your program you
install all your debugging stuff
you use a debugger
not going to talk about that
a debugger yes what is a debugger a
debugger is
anything to introspect your program
basically
anything that uses this kind of debug
info
that we serve
[Music]
so
uh right uh it is about native code
if you write in some scripting language
you're
already happy because you always have
your source code with you
yay um it is relevant for go
or rust
there are some improvements that could
be made there but
they're not really relevant it should
kind of work out of the box for
goal arrest 2 and
well i will show a demo of some of the
things that work with it
so um
no so for for the debugging info
uh uh basically compilers
these days are pretty good
always do use minus g
and you do use dc
which says for tracking assignments
which makes things really really nice
and don't disable them the kernel
disables
for for tracking assignments which makes
debugging kernel cuts really annoying
apparently kernel hackers don't
debug it
there was once a bug in gc that
generated something bad and since then
the kernel has disabled this don't do
that
just use a fixed compiler
sorry um
there are various tools that can
compress your uh
debug info which is kind of uh useful
because it's really big uh so some
examples of that uh there are also
there are some subsets that you could
use which are already
useful well like like convert showed
that
we want more that's basically it
and um
there's the source code which is also
pretty big and which is
kind of interesting because you don't
want the source code
the pristine source code but the source
code that was actually used to build
your program
which is sometimes different because
your builds
might post pre-process
your sources or generate them on the fly
so um
in general you use minus g and you're
happy
except uh
if you don't or if make
uh strips it
well then we really can't help you
but you might be using someone else uh
uh their uh their belts are well
distro packages uh uh
or you you might be
debugging remotely or in a container or
from outside the container and
where are your where is your debugging
from
um so the the
the idea is in in all those depends
we want to provide you with one
way of getting at your uh deworking file
um right so why
doesn't everybody ship all their debug
stuff because um
basically the diva game follows
uh your reverse compiler
that goes from binary to source and
describing that is oh
big it's what five
till five 15 times the size of
receptor executable
so yeah
especially if you would like to have it
for a complete
distro it's really
big so no wonder that people
try to move it away and it might be hard
to get it
so
most distributions
at least provide you with some way to uh
find it so uh fedora does it
pretty nicely i think but i work on
fedora so
that's uh um
as you can see gdb says just says well
just dnf debugging for install
uh that's packets
and uh it even gets all the dependencies
and
uh so finn might
rely on glib c so we'll also pulls in
the gleb c uh the inverter info so
that's
it just works except you have to be rude
for it
to install it uh and
it's pretty big so you'll have to have
the
this ways uh and
well um for
uh for ubuntu
i'm not that familiar with it but that
also makes it
immediately harder for my for myself
there is a a a different difference
between debug sims and debug ddps
it seems uh about debian and ubuntu now
produce debug packages for everything
but uh
basically you have the the same
limitations and then you have
other distributions
which don't create any keyword
information so what do you do while you
rebuild your
program with the way you hope it's the
same program that you
did back then um
so the the nexus kind of us
always has an interesting approach which
is uh a dwarf fall system
fuse uh thing which is actually pretty
nice
uh this is
kind of what we want although
we wanted something slightly simpler
and something that doesn't do
that is easy to set up for about
distributions in your local
builds
right so
it's pretty useless that you have to
have privileges to
install debug info uh
it would be nice if uh there was a
mechanism that combines the packages
with your
local builds and maybe ufa a team
that that publishes some
of the account
and we always want access to
the actual source code used
so the debug m4d
is a simple http web server
it has three
it is two it has three
i missed one it it has
three get requests uh one for the
executable
uh that that seems weird that you might
want
the executable but uh you might be you
might have gotten a corval
from somebody and
you you want to debug that so you want
to get the executable you
want to get a debug info
and you want source code
and basically that's the whole hspd
server
they're all indexed by build id
you can run it on any port and
the servers could can federate to each
other
so the build id is is
kind of the thing that ties it all
together
ability id
x swing basically
has over your whole executable
it's unique in
the way that
if you have a reproducible build it
generates the same
it should generate the same build id
and you
use it to uniquely identify a build
but you cannot use it for verification
it's it's not a security
thing it's also if you
uh a build id
is generated by the linker for every
loadable
module program library kernel module
kernel
and what did i want to say oh yes
and
when you then split that loadable module
like
in the main executable and debug
info you copy over the build id
uh that also makes it harder to verify
because
the build id is calculated over the hold
so you would have to
merge them um
so um the viva game for the
uh is fairly fairly simple
uh the version that was released you can
point it at
uh your
build directory or at a
collection of rpms
in current git you can also
point it at a collection of
depth files
and it uses slip archive
so it can basically
use any archiving formats that you
use
it it creates a database
and from that
it it serves the files you want
the client is uh even simpler
uh uh
the uh if you have support
uh like a gdb well it's not integrated
yet but i will demo it anyway
uh
you just set an environment variable i
have
all my debug stuff my sources there fits
them
and we have a little example program
debug
info defined give me the source or debug
info
or executable for this hex code and
with the source the source path that's
it
oh right let me just show it
um
oh right i can't see anything on this
screen sorry
um so
go away
so uh
yeah oh
yeah i said
unprivileged that i'm using docker files
and
no how
really it's me okay
you script your whole demo and then you
can't
run the demo because you lost your
password
um yeah let's first
show uh
so we don't have uh we don't have any
debug info insult
we do have a future steve again for the
insult
well just to show that up
that i'm not
lying yeah
so we start a server which
yeah um
we start a server with lots of uh for
business come on
yeah so lots of
was the look in
create a database here
scan it every
couple of seconds index all the rpms and
the files
that you can find in this directory
and basically it's it indexes
them and you're done
well
we don't really need that window anymore
except to see
that it actually gets the files there
because this is all running locally um
the demo is actually too smooth it just
works and
you should see it downloading but it's
immediately there
so um uh
oh i should have shown you
okay so in the demo directory i
put the uh i happened to put
the debugging for rpms for
bass and telepse and well everything i
need for the demo
so um the this
this window is too small
support is built in in the elf uterus
tools
so even
though we don't have any debug info
installed it's
it it gets them from
the client that we we have a back trace
with
source files and symbols
so this was for an rpm based thing
maybe we we want to build something
uh locally uh we make a winery
and we
we strip the thing that we are going to
install
so
in this scenario you you you have your
built
directory you you give your binaries
stripped to your co-workers to run a
different machine
which we now create
yes so
we use spotman and it right
so on this
machine which we just created there is
the stripped binary so we run
ddb on it and ah
there's nothing this is uh
frustrating
yeah so
yeah yeah um
so now we do it again but we uh
we give it access to the debugging for
the
server that we are running and
uh
so it uses okay it's it's cheating
it actually uses the host
network but it's as if it is on a
different machine
and it actually finds
the symbols it you should have seen it
download but it was so fast it
immediately guesses
it gets them from the cast and
if i do start yay
i can be back my program um
and this would be the scenario where you
have a team
which uh presents their their own uh
built environments to the server
it it it also works for system tab
for example give me
all the oh you can't see what it's
uh right give me all the the
functions in g lab c
that started vf printf and
it was too fast again it's
actually it it got the dlfc debug
files from the previous run because now
they're
in its guess
okay the demo actually worked
um was it too smooth
probably it was yeah it should have
crashed
i should have made the network slower
but what you can't see actually do i
have it here
that no i don't have it
oh what uh oh i could do this yeah
the server has
well html page or actually
these are statistics from
[Music]
prometheus the
anyway people that do metrics like this
style of
presenting statistics uh
well you you can see that the the little
file server htb server
knows about a lot of file names in
two thousand uh 2400
two built ids and it
it actually worked really yeah
okay how do i get back to my
presentation
uh
sorry
ah where's my
where's my presentation sorry
uh oh wait
and now yeah okay
that's good thank you
okay
okay so what what what what did we see
what does it do
[Music]
um
you put all your your uh your
debugging profiles in in in directories
uh it's uh you tell uh you can tell it
to scan rpms depths uh uh
for your full build what
anything yeah wow it
it it does need a a bit
of information to cross-reference them
uh especially for the yeah
right for the the source files that's
not always
easy sometimes uh uh on fedora
source files are put in a separate
package from
the actual debugging file so that is
some
what tricky this so um
uh you you
you can basically let the
the server running it scans
uh what you have if it is built
directory it also will
clean up what's not relevant anymore
if you put new rpms there it will index
them
and uh
well it's it's basically a little sql
sqlite database
and
it it it also supports dwz
which which makes the indexing also a
bit tricky because
uh dwc
compresses debug info by
putting common
elements in a separate file
but essentially a dwc file
is also something with the belt id
and you can just request it
um i feel a question coming up there
okay um
it's it it's uh
um
well basically sqlite is nice that's
that's a message from this this slide
um
yeah um it's
all right yeah so um
it it it it indexes everything
and you can really nicely
partition uh what you do because you can
make servers query other servers
the debugging for the server
is also a client so you can say if
you don't have the build id
go one server up
and you could do the same
inside your company or your programming
group where you
have one server that
questions all the others um
yeah so the the uh the the
the the client kisses everything which
also means
that uh the servers kiss
uh everything uh and uh
there is a uh
and there is kind of a simple client in
elf utils
the debugging for the client
but it's not much work to create your
own clients the the simple client
just uses lib curl and has
a uh least
recently used guess of files
uh well basically you you you to
to implement a client you have to be
able to make http
requests and that's it
um so um
oh this was the minute thank you
this was actually the slide i was
describing quite the client sorry
let me go back what i should have said
uh here now this is good
i already said most of this but uh
the the the scanning
can take long mostly because uh the rpms
uh are
compressed the decompressing reading
takes most of the time
the database can become
a bit large but that's mainly because
there are is so much data
especially if you try to
index all the rpms in the fedora ecology
build system
that that is really big
uh uh but
in in these it's embarrassing parallel
problem you you can just partition it
you can have multiple directories
multiple servers
you can even merge databases
um so like i said
there is an implication of the server
and of the client in elf utils that was
released in
last month i believe
in 0 178
there is now support for
deb files and for more parallel parsing
of
your directory trees in the current kit
directory for the next release
uh there's a prototype gdp client
on a branch it works perfectly
tom are you going to review it
yay there
there are several clients on the way i
i have a little list uh and there are
already some public servers if you
if you want to try it out right so
this is actually already too old because
the slide was made
before the weekend
but there's there are two experimental
servers now
one for system theft
that frank is running
and one for susa
they are
frank is trying to to get the most
common
binaries that you use with systemdev
for all the different distros uh
there uh the open sushi one
tries to index all of the the tumbleweed
is the
last one uh for opensuse they're
both experimental so if they don't work
sorry
but uh hope hopefully others
uh do that we had a talk with
um alex
larson i believe who does the flatbacks
and he was also looking at
making a a server available that
uh serves the the the debug info for
for flatbacks uh and he actually wanted
to
write his own server but the server is
so simple that
you can also do that uh so for the
clients
uh uh
so of course the lsu does tools use it
by default
uh system tab uses it
because uh elf uterus provides it
uh twice the same thing uh the
bin neutral some vinegar totals can use
it that's
merged in git uh the gdb pets is
proposed then
tom is going to merge it no
but and there are some in progress
i believe another check was also
recently done uh try
reloading that page um
there's also some help wanted uh
and uh we volunteered
aaron for most of the work but i'm sure
he wants
help um
yeah so for the uh the
client support would be nice either
directly or using
the elf utils a simple client
okay i don't know what that is
you should think about security for the
server
a bit more uh
uh of course the cd became file needs
always to be improved but that's
if you can help with that that would be
nice um
if you could run a server for your own
stuff
that would also be nice let us know that
we put you on the page and
we get lots of people debugging your
stuff because
it's so easy uh
well and and we i think we
hit the right spots by making it file
based
built a built-in index
but we might want to
see if we can improve the protocol
either by making things uh
making it smaller for example i
just want to die tree for
this thing or just the foul table so i
don't have to have the
whole debug file
and maybe the other way around for
example if you
try to trace all the
modules in the kernel then uh you'll
currently have to fetch 2000
debug info files separately and
maybe you can batch that but i think the
the current setup is so simple that
it's good that we started with this
do i have time for questions okay
but there are no questions but i was
curious
what was wrong
what was wrong with the next approach
you mean
uh yeah
yeah um
well there there's nothing wrong with it
but
it it is a much more complicated
client it's a fuse file system which is
nice
and
i i think what we have now is easier to
set up and easier to federate
and i think that's something that
is good
i i think you could maybe take
that fuse file system
approach and build it on top of this
yes come on is the
server being run on
does it have to be run where your build
directory is
um because potentially if that's the
build directory it's also the
host maybe it might be
yeah so so the uh
yes it has to have access to your wealth
directly but you could
maybe have your belt directly mounted
yeah
but but you're right that is one of the
things
that's also why we have separate
indexing of rpms and whole foul
trees
you could you could make it smaller the
the interesting thing about
having it on the host is that you are
sure to also have all the
header files as installed on the host
so in a way you you have to have it on
the house to
have the complete picture
okay i think i stopped before
being dragged off the stage
you