okay so we've got another lightning talk
from alexis celia
go ahead um so i'm alexi or cloudhead
and i'm going to talk about the problem
of
peer-to-peer code collaboration and what
we're doing at monadic
around this so
um i'd like to start with git because
i think this is today the foundation for
code collaboration it's the common
ground
and what i mean by that is that um you
know despite us
using maybe gitlab github or mailing
lists or whatever it is
there's always at the center of that git
at least for most people
and if we want to talk about
code collaboration therefore we should
start with git
um however uh
there are a few things missing from git
as a protocol
um and this is why things like like
hosted platforms
are so popular um
so i broke it down to three categories
there's discovery
so this is the problem of finding change
sets to merge or finding peers
finding remotes places to push to things
like that
canonicity which is to know which is the
upstream that
i should download my changes from or i
should download a release from
and social artifacts so
i get the bare bones get only
only supports code and if we want things
like issues
and uh and uh pull requests or things
like that um we need something extra
um so let's look at what has been
done to resolve these so first of all we
have mailing lists so this is kind of
the first solution
that there was and um
so it's it's fairly simple in a way
but in terms of user experience and
usability it's not great and so
from there we kind of moved towards um
uh what i'm calling hosted platforms
and here we have our usability and
you know it's it's become really
mainstream um
but we have another problem which is um
a lot of these are not free software um
they are not necessarily
resilient in that uh they are run by
for-profit companies
and they are they're controlled in a way
that
does not allow communities to sort of um
stir them in the direction that is best
for the community
so um
what does peer-to-peer have to say about
this is there is there something we can
do with peer-to-peer technology um that
could fill this gap that get the
protocol
has in terms of code collaboration
so first of all just to explain why we
would want to do this so
peer to peer systems are resilient and
this is the most interesting thing about
them
they're economically resilient which
means that
they don't depend on making a profit and
this is simply because the burden is
shared across
the network and the community so
typically users host nodes and therefore
we don't need to pay for hosting
um politically resilient which is
to say that there is no authority or
or country or government that can shut
down a peer-to-peer network um
easily for everyone at least
and finally technically resilient uh
because there's no single point of
failure right it's quite hard to ddos
or to dos a peer-to-peer system
um so
before diving into into our solution i
want to talk about an example
peer-to-peer system that
i really like called secure scuttlebutt
and the reason i want to talk about this
is that we're going to use
we're going to take some inspiration
from it
for our code collaboration solution um
one of the coolest things about
scuttlebutt
is this what we call a social overlay
protocol
which is that um essentially replication
works
based on your social network so if you
um
in in the center here you have uh the
the user
um in the pink circle then you have a
circle of friends and a circle of
friends of friends and
everything within the the two circles is
replicated by the user in the middle
right everything out of the circle so
the dotted little
uh little squares are not replicated so
essentially you choose what you
replicate based on who you follow
and you sort of by proxy choose
friends of friends and you also
replicate those
and this has proved to work quite well
at least
for the size of networks scuttlebutt has
um another cool thing about this is that
um uh
you essentially um
each so identities are cryptographic
they use public keys and therefore it's
very easy to verify
uh if something is um uh
legitimate by just verifying the
signatures on the content
and we're gonna we're also gonna use
this uh property
uh cool so what about code collaboration
so how do we how do we sort of take
these ideas um this
kind of scuttlebutt ideas and the things
we talked about resilience and how do we
uh get to a code collaboration solution
so our project is called radical um
[Music]
and uh radical essentially get plus
uh peer-to-peer um
and um there's a there's a few
kind of properties it has that i'm going
to introduce quickly
um of course it's offline first so it
keeps that property that git already has
um it's secure um
in the same way scuttlebutt is secure in
that it's it's all based on
cryptographic identities
and so everything is signed every single
object in a network is signed by someone
um and of course it's peer-to-peer um in
the sense that
um you don't really need a server
although in some cases we'll see i
could be useful but it's not required
um and the the design is based on three
technologies which
um we kind of take our inspiration from
um
so scuttlebutt i just talked about um
where we
we take the um the follow graph but
instead of
a social network we use a network of um
of clones essentially of uh of
repositories
and their remotes um there's tough the
update framework which
um maybe some people know about um which
uh
is a is a way to sort of uh
authoritatively um
update a set of maintainers for example
um or a set of metadata around a project
um even under under attack like a stolen
key and
and things like that and finally get
which i already talked about
um which radical is is uh really based
on
so why why why git
so of course um you know as we talked
about as a common ground for
uh source code collaboration but it's
actually
cool for peer-to-peer in even more ways
right
um so for one it's optimized for full
replication so this is great for
for peer-to-peer offline first systems
um second it's designed for the bizarre
model and it turns out the bizarre model
um where there's no real um you know
kind of central server you push to
um works really well for peer-to-peer
where there typically isn't a central
server either
so this works really well for us um
finally pac files pack files are really
really cool um and it's one of the
reasons why
um certain sort of uh peer-to-peer
networks
didn't work for us uh like ipfs and i
can talk more about this
after the presentation um because pac
files
is an interactive protocol which makes
uh replication super super fast
um and most of you know about it so i'm
not gonna go into it
um cool so let's talk about the the
architecture of radical quickly
um we don't have that much time but i
think just kind of um
going briefly into it so each user
essentially
um is this uh this yellow
sort of square and um each user runs two
or
has two essentially copies which are not
really copies or hard link but
they're they're they're two logical
copies of the repository there's one
working tree
which is the uh the working copy which
is the one you kind of
edit and commit and this is what you use
day to day
and there's a hidden replicated copy
which is what's being replicated to the
other peers
right and so from the working copy
standpoint it looks like
typical you know if you'd use github or
whatever but in the replicated copy we
have other things
so um we have for instance um
remotes of remotes so as i don't know if
you can read it but
you can essentially um we we store two
degrees out
of all of our remotes and there's some
other sort of hidden branches um
which give metadata around the project
um
so the concept of a project is just kind
of like a set of repositories
that all have the intent to be one thing
one logical thing
and a contributor and this is the
information on the specific clone or
specific
um tree essentially that that you have
on your computer um and so the the the
purple
um the the replicated copies sort of
replicate amongst each other
and the user pushes locally essentially
it's like a it's a file protocol
push so it's instant um
but the the get push is when you want to
publish when you want to make something
public essentially
and before that it's just kind of your
own
your own copy and so diving a little bit
into the
you know what what is this idea of
project and why do we use tuff and
things like that
um so this is kind of a mock um
view of this this project file and so
it's it's essentially in a disjoint
branch right it's in a
branch that is hidden and you have of
course like project name
but the most important thing is you have
a list of maintainers right and these
are public keys
and updating this list of maintainers
requires essentially a signature from a
quorum
of maintainers so um
you can essentially verify this when you
clone a project and verify that the code
is essentially
approved by the maintainers in some way
and the way this works is that this
initial project file which has the the
initial list of maintainers
is hashed um or it's it's committed and
the
the um the commit hash becomes a project
id right and so that's what you share
and so when you receive a when you clone
a project you have the project id
you verify the the project metadata file
and you verify you sort of go through
the history
of that file which is again in its own
branch um
and verify each step making sure there's
a quorum of signatures
if there are updates like adding
maintainer removing a maintainer and
and so forth and then
each clone so so there's there's one of
these project files for the for the
entire uh
project for the for yeah and there's one
of these contributor files for each
clone in that project right so each
person will have
their own contributor file which has
their signing key
and which also has refs that are signed
by that sign-in key so this is
kind of the the counterpart to that
which says that
um i as a contributor or maintainer
right
um i'm signing this reference saying um
i approve of this this is a legitimate
change right and so in a peer-to-peer
network you can sort of attest that
things are um
authoritative basically and you make
sure that someone hasn't just
you know cloned a cloned project changed
the maintainers and then
signed a bunch of refs and you have no
idea if this is still
something you want to build and use
essentially
um in terms of replication i'm not going
to go into
lots of details either but you know
essentially um
we're building a gossip-based protocol
where um
when you have a new uh ref for something
uh you just announce it to your
connected peers uh you say hey
here's for this project id here's a new
ref and here's the hash of that
ref right and then the
appear will just fetch and they will
fetch through the git protocol
because that's what's super fast um
fetch the ref of course they do all the
validation then if it's the first time
they see your project they will go
through the whole
uh project metadata first without even
having to
clone the source code and that's one of
the cool things is that having
um source code in one branch and having
metadata and the other things in other
branches you can
sort of do a shallow clone and just kind
of verify the the authenticity of the
project before
you download the whole source code um
yeah and by the way for i'm not talking
about like how we do issues and
and pr's and that kind of thing um here
but it's the same principle so
um there's there's going to be hidden
branches
uh with issues with revisions and so you
could also
you know maybe you're just interested in
issues and you don't want to download
the whole source code
because your user who is not a developer
and you just want to create an issue
right
so um these will work kind of in the
same way
um and that's about it
um you can find out more information on
the website
uh it's it's still in heavy development
but there's there's more info there
so we've got a minute for questions if i
could just
is there a way to revoke a maintainer if
somebody goes rogue and starts putting
malicious changes in
yes uh so is there a way to revoke the
maintainer yes
um again it depends on kind of the the
quorum and the rules of your
of your project metadata file but
essentially um if it's two out
like two out of three for example and
you want to remove one maintainer you
need two signatures
and then of course the the person
downloading the project will verify that
that was
legitimately removed that maintainer was
allowed to be removed
how secure is radical uh that's a
complicated question
um so as secure as can be
um so we're building it we're designing
it in a way that
um we're using everything available to
make it as secure as possible
and as i said like everything is is
signed and
um can be verified and attested
essentially
okay awesome thank you very much
[Applause]