yes
thank you so much well thank you for
having me so it's indeed it's the last
of the day so it's like
outside and i saw like a lot of people
already drinking beers and stuff so it's
like i hope that there are still people
in the room so thank you for listening
so this is like last year my my
colleague chen was here and he
he presents for the first time we've eat
and what we're trying to do
and we've done a lot in the year so
today i want to
i want to show you actually an update
and and way more things about wev8 and
a lot of things have changed also the
things that we've changed into
so quickly agenda what i want to talk
about so first i want to talk about
what it is because they were you know
we're new we're new on the scene so yeah
so what is it secondly i want to
talk about what has changed since last
year or presented here and this year
um i want to talk a little bit of the
about the technology and last but not
least of course i want to give a
demo i want to show it in action all
right so that's the
that's what i'm going to do so first
about the um about we've gate so we hit
is an oversourced smart graph that's
what it is
and what we mean with that well the fact
that it's open source that is the usual
suspects right so
source lives on github but you can use
that using docker docker compose and
kubernetes so we have that all out of
the box for you
it is smart because of something which
we call the contextionary
and if you never heard about the
contextionary that's fine because we
invented it and i'm about to explain to
you what it is and what it does
um and i want to use i'm going to use
one buzzword
sorry for that but what i but it has a
serious it's
a serious notion so sometimes people
talk about like the ai first
architectures
so like can we build systems that have
like these machinery models built into
them
that we can build new solutions and
actually new ideas and that's why we
try to solve with semantic models so
what makes it in our case what we like
to call smart
is the built-in semantic model and the
graph is well
i don't have to in this room i don't
have to you know share with people what
the graph is but the
we we've chosen to use graphql and the
reason why i've done that is because we
see of course there's like
a lot of graph experts you know you
sparkle or sorry for those kind of
things
but sometimes when we have developers
who find it a little bit more difficult
we see that they really like to work
with graphql so we really
embrace graphql and it's like completely
100 graphql based
so that's how we define what our smart
graph is
and with a smartphone you can do three
things first thing is semantic search
so what you can do and that's also what
i will demo to you what we know from
traditional search if i may call it like
that we search for keywords
right so if we write about um uh
the company apple we actually need to
search for apple
but in weeviate you don't necessarily
have to so if you add company with the
name apple
but you search for example what's the
company the business related to the
iphone
it will still find your data object
company with the name app
what we also can do based on that is
automatic classification so we can
automatically make edges in the graph
based on the semantics
of your data object and last but not
least
we can do knowledge representation and
this is after
what's always also referred as like
nowadays it's like
it's the knowledge graph but it's like i
wouldn't say we're necessarily a
knowledge graph but the
you can create a similar representations
so those are the three things
the three use cases that we can help you
with so
something important to share based on
what we did last year
so the best way to explain is a little
bit on time
and what i mean with that is like that
we saw of course a lot of
databases in the past that were more
relational based right so just
you know wrote column row column
structures and tables
and then of course we got these um uh
graph databases uh so for example i had
the people from new orleans room so they
made a beautiful
beautiful database like that and we
chose a year back
to store information with giannis
and what we did was that we had that
semantic element that what i will
explain the confectionary
i will explain what that is we had that
as a feature but last year we decided to
just
double down on that semantic element so
we got completely
rid of the implementation in giannis and
we
create basically everything ourselves
and we that means that we now
only have that contextionary to store
that information in
and we've actually this is a crown so we
actually figured out like this is
actually
we're really happy that we made that
decision because now we could really
bring something
new you know to the to the stage
something different and a different way
to handle your data objects and work
with them so
we store everything in a semantic space
that's what we do and now if you go like
wah semantic space
i'm gonna explain what we mean with that
so but just keep thinking when i talk
about semantic space i'm talking about
the contextionary so imagine it like
this
if you go to a
i'm compliant as you can see let's say
if you go to a grocery store
and you have a shopping list and on that
shopping list you might have four items
a banana washing powder you're looking
for an apple
and a piece of bread so if you go in the
supermarket and you find a banana
you know that an apple is going to be
closer by
than the bread or the washing powder
and if you move towards the bread you
know that you're actually getting closer
to the washing powder moving more away
from the fruit
that's how we store data in the space
and so that's the
metaphor to actually imprint the problem
that we solve and
we do that to something that we that we
call the contextionary and i want to
give you a little bit of background
where we're coming from
and um what's different to other
solutions that around here so
if you go all the way back again time to
the uh
to the 1950s it was like a famous quote
and it said like
a word can be characterized by the
company it keeps and
what it basically means that you would
say that the word paris would be more
closely related to france than it would
be to
holland for example or the us and new
york would be more closely related to
the u.s
than for example spain
and that basically went for all words
and a lot of research was done there
and then we jumped for it and then with
the whole machine learning boom
we saw there was a lot of work being
done with um
with based on machine learning and these
word embeddings
and then what we also saw it was and it
was like we got first word to vac
got glove and nowadays have what they
call in the academic realm
which they call a state of the arts
called bird but
if we now put on our engineering hat we
really fell in love with
glove and why did we fall in love with
glove because
bird has multiple representations of a
word
in that data set but glove doesn't gloth
has
one vector representation for every word
and the critique that it often got was
that well if you for example have the
name apple apple can mean of course
um fruit but it can also mean the
company
and um but we wanted to solve the
problem in a different way
but as engineers we were very happy with
this because now we could index it we
could index those words
in a storage mechanism so if you start
alleviate you can imagine it like this
it's an empty space that you start you
choose a language not a programming
language but a spoken language
so let's say for example english and
this space is filled
with all those words so for example if
you find apple
you find nearby fruit you find nearby
company
and you might also find iphone and these
representations that we store
they have a 600 dimensional
representation
which is very fancy but just it has to
do with compression that kind of stuff
and the thing that we did is this if you
store a data object like this so for
example the class company
with the name apple found it in 1976 et
cetera
and in when i demo i will show you how
that actually works but
if you've studied information what we've
yet is that it creates a string
of the words and the concepts that are
in there and it takes those concepts
and it funnels them down how does it do
that it says like it takes the euclidean
distance
it combines it with e this sounds very
fancy but with a logarithmic function
based among the occurrence of the word
so for example company
might occur less often than the word
apple so then we say the word company is
more important
and then we even work with word boosting
so that you can say certain words are
important in my data object
but what we do with that is that we
create our verge
our first object in our graph and it
gets its own
factor representation so now if we have
an
empty v8 with those words in that then
we store our first
um data object as you can see there
there it is it lives that's where it
lives in the vector space that's what we
mean
so now if we query for let's say
a company an iphone it can look in the
nearby space and find the data object
so now without even having iphone in the
data object we can still find it
and that's the thing that we created
that we thought okay
this is this is our thing right this is
our our golden goose act because
now we have different ways of creating
graphs and actually query through them
so this example for example might look
something like this
so if i have a data set with companies
and this would be my graphql
query where i said get give me things
which are companies and i want to have
their names
but explore them by iphone i might get
this result
apple and as you see iphone is nowhere
in the dead object
and if i have that same data set and i
would say well
a little bit more abstract organize
these companies
on the concept of redmond i might get
back microsoft
and that's how we structure our graph
so um and so that's basically what we've
hear this and as a developer we've had
comes with a few features
so the first thing is that's that
confectionary comes all out of the box
you don't have to do
your training you don't have to set it
up whatever it comes all out of the box
um or basically all out of the container
i should say
adding data happens to the http api but
crawling data
to the graphql api it's completely
containerized so you can run it wherever
you want
um and because we use that vector space
it's very very
scalable you can skill this that space
very very tremendously big so i think
the the biggest one that we ever tried
was a few
it was a few billions it gets pretty big
and something that we have in the
pipeline and maybe i can show you that
next year
but is that we also can create
peer-to-peer networks of viviates
so that we can point to semantic
elements in different graphs
so that we don't have to agree anymore
on our ontologies
or on our schemas but that's like that's
that's in the making
so a little bit about graphql so i have
so when i demo that so
how we structure our graph here this is
the um
the ux if you will of our graphql so we
have
a get function first the other one is an
aggregate function but i'm going to talk
about the get function
we have a semantic kind which we make a
distinction between things and actions
nouns and verbs you have the class the
class as the property
a property might have a reference and
then the property
itself and what you can do you can have
these semantic filters on top of that so
there you see for example the explore
filter and they can search for concepts
but you can even move away from concepts
of move towards concepts and i will demo
that to you in a bit
um ah well demo so now we get to the
demo so now you might wonder
how does that actually look so what i
did is that i
spun up a um a
docker container if you want to do that
yourself if you go to our website send
me the technology
and then you simply click with y8 and
then you find all the documentation
the installation gives you just a weave
yet but what i'm gonna demo to you is
this
news publications data set and if you
click that one
there's just one simple docker compose
command that you can run that you can
play
you know around with it yourself so
there's a meta endpoint
which i'm just running just to make sure
yes so that is running well
so let's first look at the schema so
this is an example of schema so
here you see i have the class
publication and i have i have
the name name so the name of the
publication but for example
so i set the headquarter g location
which is
our geo coordinates has articles et
cetera et cetera this is how we
structure
the schema that's important because we
will see that back
when we use graphql to query and the
things that we actually store
look like this so for example here you
see an article the article has an
id a beacon is a reference in our graph
but why do we call it beacon because we
do it in a space so it's a beacon in the
space
and then here you see for example a
summary of the article the title of the
article
and the url where the article actually
comes from so that's how it's structured
so we've created a simple um
uh gui that you can use to actually
uh you know look through and search to
the
to the graph so you can visualize stuff
but i wanna i wanna
dive into the um the graphql queries
so let me show you a simple query so if
i say
get things and i want to have
i want to have a publication and i want
to see the name this would be
a valid query then you see why i see
vogue financial times wyatt new york
economist etc now what i now can do
is that i can say well
i want to oh i want to explore
for the concept let's say
business and i'm gonna limit it to three
results just that it's easier readable
so i know i said do the same query but
explore based on the concepts
of business so if i now run the square
you see financial times the new york
times international times etc
but you see the word business the meta
tag it's nowhere there
that's what comes from the contextionary
or if i would say
fashion and i would run it then you see
it starts for example with voc
so that's how we structured it and how
it works
um but that's not not only going for
like small strings but also for larger
larger text objects so for example if i
would say get
things article and i would say
show me the title of the article
and run the query so now you see all
these articles about
a variety of topics you see brexit so
you can see when we when we
actually pulled that in but just a
variety of topics in here
but if i now say well i wanna do i have
those articles
i'm gonna use the explore function again
and i can i say well i wanna explore for
the concepts
let's say music
and i'm going to limit the results again
just for the sake of readability
so same query but now based on the
articles so if i run this you say like
you seek
fair enough the first one has the word
musical but then it's about
gwen stefani and then it's about john
lennon so you see the word music
is not necessarily in there but it
organizes it like that automatically
so now even if you want to filter
further in this
in this graph what you can do is that
you can say well
the question we had like how do we do
pagination because if you have a 600
dimensional space what would be the next
page so what we've done is this so we
said well we
can actually for example move towards a
concept
so i can say well uh move towards the
concept for example of the beatles so i
guess you already know what will happen
if i do that
so and i give it a certain force the
force is how strongly you want to push
towards this concept
inside the vector space so let's say
it's a little bit arbitrary but let's
say
85 percent so if i do that now you see
that john lennon the article with john
lennon comes first
and if i say like i'm more like a
stone's person i hate the beatles
then of course you can also do move away
from the concept of the beatles
same query and we see john lennon is
gone and now the question is like okay
so what makes it
so like now the traditional graph people
are like yeah but i haven't seen
the graph in action yet so that's just
very simple because we could say for
example
has authors and we can say on author
the author has a name so this is how we
structure the graph so now you see here
so you see the graph object here
that says first the title of the article
and it has
authors and then actually the authors
that are related to this
to this article i think if time allows
it there's one more thing
can i still quickly show one more thing
yes so the uh there's one more thing
which i completely forgot because
there's another problem that we also try
to solve for this and i want to show you
that going back to the publications so
quickly going back to the publications
things publication and an essay
name of the publication when
when you glanced over this you might
have noticed that we have all these
publications but we have the
international new york times
the new york times company and the new
york times in there three times
which is a problem because of course you
want to represent concepts
but in the database we have the same
concept represented three times
so we have something for that what you
can do
is that we can say well we want to group
concepts together
so then we say i'm going to do the type
merge them together
i'm going to give a 4 so how big do we
need to look in the vector space before
merging
and then i can say well do that with
five percent
so if i now run this query you'll see
that it merged together
the international new york times new
york times company and the new york
times
but if i now do a graph query so i say
has articles
on article the title of the article
it even now merges together those
different articles
from those different publications into
the same concept
so that's what we have that's how it
works
uh oh way more features the automatic
classification i didn't even get to show
you that but you can play around with it
because
well we're at fosdem so this software is
open source you can play around with it
you can set it up yourself you can
create your own graphs
semantic graphs i should say that's my
story
in a nutshell thank you all for
listening and
if you like it and if you go to our
website then i just have one question
so this is our website if you go here
then you can sign up to our newsletter
if you want to learn or you can click on
the github star
button if you want to and it'll promote
a little bit so that's
but this is our website thank you very
much for listening
[Applause]
thank you very much thank you
uh i actually have two questions you
said that your
semantic uh let's say makings
are based on love but for larger text
sentences would you do a simple
averaging
because globally
and the second question is i guess so
you showed us in examples
where is based on single words but can
we actually input the
sentence in that case i suppose
your model will have to cook up a
vector embedding for that is that
actually sustainable
if i put it on a server then everybody
tries to you know run your model to get
there
how did you solve that resource problem
so two questions sorry about that no no
why are you sure about it
i know that those are great questions so
let me let me start with the first
uh answer to the first question so um
and and sorry if i went over that
quickly
too quickly because it's um um
this whole everything what i told is
also on the website in detail
um but that's what's happening here we
always
use this same algorithm so if you would
have a
that object with a longer sentence like
for example the summary or the title of
the articles that you've seen
it applies the same
algorithm so it says like first i take
all these individual words
then i find the center position between
those words
then i weigh them based on the
occurrence so certain words are seen as
more important than others so it weighs
it towards that
and then we have this optional word
boosting that you can say but in this
specific case this word is very
important
so move more towards that that's how we
create those vector positions so
regardless if you're querying or if
you're
um adding data that's how we do it
so that's why we also became agnostic
about the fact that gloves about single
words
and because we learned that if we so we
the first prototype we did way back was
very simple
we say okay i have the word apple
show me what's nearby and then as you
would expect as glove does it says like
well i found iphone but also
found fruit and then we did something
very simple
we said okay now go and sit in the
center between
apple and iphone show me again what
happens
and then you see actually um that that's
successful and if i if i may i can
actually
quickly show that yeah i'm the last
talker so
thank you like i should have waited
till you had said go ahead
and then thank you so um there's a
confectionary endpoint
where you can say well concepts so if i
now literally do what i just said so if
i would say
apple then you see here apple itunes
google preview
on this and now of course in this
example we don't see
of course the fruit but let's say if i
would do apple and not based on the
company but on fruit
so i concatenate them apple and fruit
you see how it now starts to
get better and better in those results
so and that's how it
the algorithm works so you can play
around with this also yourself on this
on this end point and the other question
yeah it was
weights uh that they you know better
look at the slider kind of uh ti-5ds
weights
at least frequency so if and you have to
you know hook up these uh vectors for
the embeddings
every time we make a query is this
sustainable
for the normal servers you have some
solutions there
that you can tell us yeah sure so we um
um we of course we're also like we're
also a business so we have like uh
so the core is like open source probably
built like a shell around that
so we currently have six companies using
this on a large scale
in in a variety of industries uh
wholesale retail
oil and gas all those kind of things and
these graphs get
pretty big and especially if you scale
the kubernetes cluster
it's fast which is something i'm now i
could say that we
fancy like architected that but it was
actually something we got for free
because we just the data model is just
vectors only vectors and that's of
course very fast
to scale and to search through so the
answer to that question is
yes
can you use this for translation uh like
you said
your vector space um is
built in one language but again you
compare vector spaces by
uh looking if one concept is associated
with all these things
and in your second vector space another
concept is also associated with the
same things and you've already linked
some some concepts can you
translate use that for translation
i don't know and i love the idea so
we're definitely going to try that out
i don't know i don't it's a great idea
we haven't we haven't tried that yet so
what we currently do is that we just
have we have a review in a language
so um uh dutch french english
of course um but we haven't tried that
yet so um
if you don't mind then it would be
fantastic too or of course you can try
that yourself
or we can do it together but that would
be fantastic it's a great idea and
i don't know thank you
thanks very we are much
over with the death room nice talk at
the end um
yeah i hope you all enjoyed it enjoy
foster tomorrow enjoy the evening of
course
and maybe see you next year thank you
thank you
you