and welcome everyone for the last talk
of the mozilla room
and this one is about community and what
makes them come
what makes them stay gloria the show is
yours
hello everyone welcome to my talk what
makes people come and what makes them
stay
my name is gloria jumo i'm a computer
assistant
systems engineer and i'm also a mozilla
tech speaker
and i've been volunteering with a lot of
communities
with people all around the world and as
i've been doing that i've been seeing
different challenges
and various interesting things
which pushed me to want to improve on
various skills so that i can be able to
be more effective in communicating with
people that are different than me
or have a different background so in
doing that i've been
curious about what makes people come and
live because
sometimes especially when i started my
first
job while i was happy to begin my first
job
some people were happy to be living and
so people were happy to be coming
so that made me feel kind of weird like
okay while i'm happy to start someone is
announcing that they are leaving
and i've been wondering at what makes
people live
and i realized that sometimes it's out
of our control
sometimes reorganizations happen
sometimes
layoff happens so that one you can't
control it
but we can control what makes people
live
when they decide to leave so that is
what we are going to focus on today
and i'm also going to share a short use
case
on how mozilla utilized some of the
things that i'll specify
to do that effectively
so one thing to know is that the tech
industry is one of the
industries with the highest attrition so
a lot of people leave the tech industry
and
the tenor for a lot of tech companies is
about two to three years people join a
top company for two to three years
and usually after that they leave the
companies that people stay at
for like five years or seven years are
not that many and so that raises a
question like what
makes people stay longer at certain
companies and what makes them leave
and also as i show here the turnover
rate was estimated to be
23 between 2013 and 2018.
with 192 million people
leaving their employers so that was
something that was forecasted by a group
called haze
a group
and before we see what makes people stay
it's important to see what attracts
people to certain organizations certain
communities
and certain companies
so usually what attracts them is their
needs
and their wants usually they have
certain needs they need
a job they need money they have various
needs that they need to meet
and joining an organization a community
or company
is the logical thing to do but also so
people join because of their wants so
if you have privileges you don't
necessarily need to join
a company because you need to but maybe
you are at an age where you
you no more need to work but you just
want to stay active so you just
do it because you want to so when you
have certain privileges
it's easy to join organizations because
of your wants more than your needs
but the question is are people's needs
met and that is very related to the
demographic of people you want to
attract because different type of people
have different needs
so whenever you want to think of what
people i want to attract to my company
you have to think about their background
and what type of demographic they are
coming from
but the thing that is important here is
that specific demographics have
key similar needs so for example if you
want to hire
more mothers in your companies a lot of
them will
be very happy if you have parental
support
or you give pareto leave or different
type of benefits that cater to their
needs
so having that in mind is very important
because if you don't have
things that that cater to the needs of
the people
you'll be wondering why don't certain
people come to your company and the
question is you don't meet their needs
so here are some few examples for em a
generalized
group for example one thing that might
be they might be looking for is
acceptance
so if someone that is usually
marginalized comes to your company
organization and they feel that you are
not accepting of them or you are judging
them
that's one reason why they won't stay
there for very long
another thing is people with
disabilities they might be looking for
accessibility
that being in your organization premises
or maybe the products that you have that
you are creating
and if they are not accessible enough
certain people that you might
want them to use your products won't use
them
so it's important to keep those things
in mind
the needs usually are more important
than people's wants
because that is like the key reason why
people join companies
and those two things are very key to the
satisfaction that someone has when their
needs and
wants are being met you get more
satisfied people
so now the question is let's dive deeper
into this like what exactly makes people
live
we must first address the barriers of
entry because
before someone can leave we have to see
what are reasons that stop them before
they even enter
so the barrier to the access i have like
six things that i'll specify now but
they are more than this
one of them is bad fit that goes both
ways bad fit
for the organization or the company or
bad fit for the
person that is joining the company the
history of the company
some organizations have a bad history so
some people
don't really want to have anything to do
with them
and other things that are we control as
humans like poor performance or reposter
syndrome
could be reasons why we stop ourselves
from
entering certain organizations and then
another thing that is important is
weak networks some people don't have the
network that will
lead them or guide them to your
organization and a lot of organizations
pay a lot of attention to people that
are referred into the company
so if someone has if the demographic
you're trying to attract usually has
a weak network then it's less likely for
them to land
a job at your company if it's based on
if it's heavily based on referrals so
another
thing is red flags a lot of people check
red flags in job descriptions
and if you have certain specific words
that they're looking for
they won't consider your organization
another one is how much people know
about the company
some companies are for example both for
highly technical people and for
non-technical people but because they
market themselves
very heavily on the technical side some
non-technical people think that
they have no place there so they won't
even think to apply at those companies
so
the way you market yourself and what
people know about you and what you do is
very important
and also another thing is lack of
diversity some people don't want to join
non-diverse companies and one thing that
is interesting to notice is
if you check in silicon valley a lot of
the
companies the top ones at least the
the highest demographic is usually
related to
where the ceo is from or the race the
ceo has
so if you see a lot of top companies the
highest demographic is
let's say if the ceo is caucasian it
will be caucasian
and if you check deeper into that you
might see that the second
highest demographic is sometimes the
spouse of that ceo
so if the ceo is caucasian and their
spouse is asian
you might see those as being the highest
demographics but that doesn't mean that
changing the ceo
will also change like the demographics
of your company
but that just shows that how
the people you put to lead sometimes
affect
like the people that feel comfortable
entering your company
or not entering your company and
another thing that might be a barrier
for people
is the bias that exists in recruiting
practices
like the the applicant tracking system
and the people that build the ai behind
that shortlist who will get hired or who
will get interview or not
if they have unconscious or cautious
bias
that could be a reason why it's a buyer
for people to join the company
for example someone was saying that in
his company
a lot of women were unable to pass the
interviews
so they did like a research to figure
out why are a woman passing the
interviews
and they realized that a specific
interviewer in the company
usually plays harder questions for women
engineers so at the end of the day it's
like they couldn't pass
those interviews because they got harder
questions than their male counterparts
counterparts so that is how this one was
a conscious
bias it wasn't unconscious and that is
how some ways
people affect who gets in or who doesn't
so now we are spoke about what makes
people live
and these are some other reasons of why
so break those down as well lack of
opportunities for
advancement this applies to anyone no
matter where you're coming from
if you don't have opportunities to
advance like what's the point of being
in the company
a lot of people want to be in an
organization where they see
a future where they start from a and
they can
go ahead and get to a point let's say b
but if there's no opportunity to do that
it's like
they feel that they are stagnant so that
is one reason why they live
another key one is unsatisfied with the
senior managements
the decisions that the senior management
does also they might not trust
the leaders anymore due to different
decisions they have made
so that is one reason why they live
another one is the work environment
and the culture some places
let's be honest they are very depressive
to work at
so if someone gets there they won't stay
for that long
and the culture the culture how much
welcoming your culture is
or not and how much you welcome cultural
ads
instead of cultural fits because
cultural ads means you allow people to
bring more of themselves into your
company
but cultural fit means more that people
have to fit what you want them to
portray in your company
so that might make someone feel that
they can't stay there anymore
so another thing is people want
challenging work
they want to feel that what they are
doing is having an impact and the more
challenges that they overcome
the more likely they are to stay
and then other things like compensation
and benefits and rewards
to their contributions some people
don't feel rewarded for their hard work
even if they work hard hard enough so
that is one reason why they might live
so now seeing all that i thought it'd be
interesting to look into women in tech
because a lot of companies
and organizations want to attract more
of them
so one thing is being pushed to the
management track
a lot of women in tech feel that okay i
started as an engineer
but somehow the hr of people want to
put me into a managerial role and i
don't want to leave my engineering role
so that is one reason why someone might
live
if they feel that you are not supporting
them in their engineering journey
and you are driving them into more
non-technical roles
another one is being the only
while that might be seen as a positive
thing for some people
for some others they don't feel
comfortable in being the only one
at the company so they try to drive
efforts to bring more people
in order to not be the only one but if
that is also
met by
a negative stance that will make them
probably
live at a latter time so another one is
feeling the pressure to overcompensate
for your competence usually sometimes
when you have woman intake some people
feel that
you are not a good programmer or they
feel that you are a diversity higher
so it's like you always have to prove to
those people that no
i'm competing enough you don't really
have to prove
but there's this pressure that some
people feel that
i have to keep proving myself i have to
keep proving myself and this is some a
personal thing
but sometimes the environment is what
makes people feel this way as well
and there's a research that was done by
toptal where it says address 5.4
of github users when there's over 10
millions of contributors
from random samples are female so if
you're not places like open source
communities
sometimes other females need feel that
they need to hide and
their identity or they just don't
participate
so now let's look into other groups like
underrepresented and marginalized group
they have the same feeling of pressure
to prove themselves that they are not
diversity hires their skills they have
they have the skills that are needed for
the job and they also
sometimes feel the pressure to
participate in
organizational diversity efforts like to
be in all of those diversity videos to
be in all of those photographs
to show that their their company is
diverse when sometimes
it's the opposite and that constant
pressure of being like the only person
in the company that is
somehow visually different because a lot
of
people like using visually different
people in their pr's and photographs
can bring a lot of pressure that will
make them feel that they have to live
so now let's look into open source
communities
in open source communities one of the
reasons why people
who live most likely is low or no
appreciation
of contributions to projects in the
beginning people start because they want
to contribute
to something but the more they see that
you don't appreciate what they do
especially when they aren't getting paid
for that as well
it makes them feel that what they are
doing is important
so then they are more likely to leave
another reason why
it's they get burnt out and this is more
important for volunteers because when
you don't get
compensated it's even more harder when
people
continuously ping you like can you fix
this bug
why haven't you fixed this yet and it's
like okay i'm doing this on my free time
why are people not being able to
understand that
i need time to rest and you constantly
push yourself
and that eventually leads to burnout and
you have to live then another one is
miscommunication
that happens usually due to the diverse
nature of
contributing to open source people are
from different countries most of the
times
different time zones and also a lot of
the communications happen virtually
so that allows a lot of miscommunication
to happen
and that might cause some people to
leave due to arguments at some point
and then another one is losing interest
in the project or conflict of interest
when you don't believe the mission of
that project
anymore or the organization that is
behind that project
so you decide to leave
and these issues are like a waterfall
and they cascade
they begin somewhere and if you don't
take
charge of the situation before you know
it it takes over
so as i said again when you don't meet
people's needs
and their wants they are less likely to
end up being satisfied
and all these things with needs and
wants somehow reminds us of
maslow's pyramid of needs
where there are certain needs that have
to be met for people to be happy
and some of those needs are fitting into
this
pyramid
and as i said it takes more than a great
job benefits it
takes more than getting a lot of money
or stocks
or having game rooms happy hours
one-third of new hearts quit their jobs
after six months and
employees knew that they would leave
after one week
that makes you wonder like why would
someone join a company and live after
six months
or how why didn't they know before they
joined
that they would leave and they knew it
after one week
and that is happens for various reasons
one thing is expectations vs reality
we go to a job with certain expectations
and sometimes that isn't met and then
reality strikes us
usually on the boarding session i
realized okay things look very
disorganized here
it looks like i don't exist i don't get
a lot of work
i'm told to study and it's two months
into my job and i'm still studying
when will i get work to do um
you can't communicate with your managers
that well a lot of things happen
and then when you go to hr everything
gets put under the rug
so you're wondering like is this really
what i was thinking it is it's not
so you're waiting for the right time to
leave but you can't leave that early
so usually six months feels somehow okay
for a lot of people to leave and then
they leave which is why it's very
important to put a lot of effort in your
boarding
session because usually in that first
week it's when people know
that okay i'm going to stay here for a
long time i can
sense that or i'm going to leave pretty
soon
it's okay we have seen what makes people
live and now we want to see what makes
them stay
we have seen a lot of like corporate
statistics from corporate
environments now we will check a bit of
the academic side
what does academia says makes people
stay
and i'll look into a research done my
friend of mine called
anne barcom a phd
where she analyzed what makes
volunteers be more consistent in their
contributions into
open source communities so one thing is
their
motives why they joined the
project that is very important because
if people join for example just to
enrich their resume they might
give like one or two contributions to
the project and then leave
but when they join more because they see
the bigger picture of it
and they want to see that project grow
or because they are using that tool and
they want to see it improve
they are more likely to stay for longer
one thing is societal norms
how society view open source in the
country the person is from
so in if so if open source is viewed
negatively
in a society people are less likely to
join and
stay into open source communities
another one is the psychological sense
of community
when i joined the project two people
welcome me or
it's like i don't exist and i don't get
any help and there's no documentation
and there's a lot of confusion happening
all of those things are
being taken into consideration and as i
said in the
previous time like when the needs are
met
and when the expectation matches reality
and they feel satisfied they are more
likely to stay
and also another thing that makes them
stay in open source projects
is the organizational commitment how
much committed they feel to the project
the product or the organization
so one question to think about is how
effectively do we meet the common needs
of the demographic we are trying to
attract
and now use a specific use case of
mozilla
so mozilla has a lot of volunteers from
all around the world
and a lot of people uh usually join
with this uh flow they got
they got the knowledge about mozilla
through other friend
or online social media
then they got an initial opportunity to
contribute to a project or join
the organization and then they had a
great experience while doing
that they met a lot of people that they
liked
or they liked the culture of mozilla
and when proposed by others when
proposed
other sets of opportunities they decided
to stay
pass on the knowledge and continue to go
through this loop
over and over again anytime the
experience
that things are great anymore the
culture
changes to a negative
direction or they feel that there's lack
of opportunity
that might be a time that a volunteer
might decide to leave
but usually this is the flow that most
people
go through over and over again so i
decided
to give like a personal example of what
attracted me to mozilla
and what made me stay i joined mozilla
through a project
through a program called outreachy which
offers internships for people that are
underrepresented in tech
or marginalized and prior to that i knew
mozilla
due to firefox and also because it's a
tech company
and i'm in the tech industry
so after i joined that internship and it
ended i was thinking about
how can i continue to stay in the
community is this the end of it
and no it wasn't the end of it
i was asked to write an article about my
experience as a
web developer in turn and then while an
employee was reading it
they thought oh we have these certain
opportunities why don't you
join them so i was given an initial
opportunity
to continue being involved with mozilla
so that is what i showed here like
initial opportunity
and then after that because i had a
great experience the people
were great and also i had a great time
in relation to the culture of mozilla
when proposed with other opportunities
such as the
mozilla tech speakers program because it
also matched with what i was interested
in
that made me stay and continue being
involved and going through this loop
over and over again so that is one way
by which you can retain people to your
various communities you always have to
give them opportunities that they can
grab
on and stay if you don't give them
opportunity
and the moment that the opportunity
cease to exist is a moment
when you begin losing a lot of
vulnerable community members
so i'll go through quickly a few
suggestions and approaches that you can
follow
to make people stay more on your
organizations
and projects so one thing is honesty is
the best policy
people's expectations need to match
reality so you have to make sure that
what you are
train and what you're telling them
before they join your company
is true another thing is
research make research to set the right
expectations as i said
who do you want to attract what do they
need how can you offer
that to them
another thing is figure out ways to meet
intangible needs
as i said the perks that you give
are not the only thing the salary that
you give is not the only thing
people have intangible needs that
when met are more likely to keep them
there because they have sentimental
value for them so that is something that
you want to add
as well another thing is
uh have sincere create sincere efforts
to be inclusive
don't just make it a pr thing
and then consistently evaluate common
practices
and see what works what doesn't work the
things that don't work
stop them the things that work do more
of them
try to understand why they work
and lastly people are very important a
lot of people say
that they are in a company because they
have great co-workers so that just shows
how
people are very important to others so
you have to make it
uh just make a point to hire good people
and make that a priority because when
you do that you have good vibes in your
company and more people who want to join
so here comes the end if you want to
follow me
you can find me on github on linkedin my
name is surname and you can contact me
through my website if you want
so that's it i think i have a little bit
time for some questions
thank you so do we have questions in the
audience
hi gloria interesting talk thanks um i
run a small research team seven people
and sometimes people leave uh sometimes
that's okay because it is time for them
to move on sometimes i would have
preferred that they stay
um are there ways of
finding out when this is likely to
happen
i i normally find out at the annual
evaluation where we sit down for two or
three hours and we really think about
things
but sometimes once a year is not enough
and
are there key signs that you would look
for that someone is
unhappy yes so one thing you have to do
is
as i said communication is very
important if you have like a meeting
with them
once a year or i don't know you won't be
able to see the signs
because for example let's use the
natural world when someone is sick
they have some symptoms before
showing the full blown effect of the
illness
if you are not monitoring the person you
won't see understand what the symptoms
mean
and you know it when the illness has
run its course or things are really bad
so you have to monitor people from
before and people usually complain about
what they don't like
whether to you or to co-workers if
someone gives you a complaint about
something
over and over again or even goes to the
extent to go to hr
you have to understand that if this
person could place long enough
eventually it will cause them a lot of
grief and they'll think
if i'm unhappy why am i here let me plan
leaving
so if you make people are happy in your
organization
and it doesn't have to be everyone
sometimes
specific things make some people unhappy
but if that thing
goes with your mission then i guess you
can't do anything about it maybe it's a
conflict of interest as i said but if
that thing is against your mission and
what you want to portray
you want to make sure that as i said you
evaluate what you're doing
and change that so you have to closely
monitor people's complaints
and if you do that you have better
understanding of when someone is about
to leave
any other question
so