the next talk will be
from thierry carres he is the vice
president of engineering
at the openstack foundation and he will
present to us
why open infrastructure metals
[Applause]
so hello everyone a quick introduction
i've been actively contributing to a
number of
free and open source software
communities for the past 16 years
and my first first name was in 2005 and
back then it was very much like it is
today
except it was much more difficult to get
food there were no food trucks there
were no
open cafeteria and it was not as
pleasant as it is today
the idea behind this talk
really started with the paradox we are
here at fosdem
the free and open source developers
european meeting
because we believe that open source
is a superior way of building superior
software
and yet if we look at
what we are using day to day
to write this software i'm seeing
like in dev rooms yesterday even in this
room today
even in the freedom track i'm seeing a
lot of macbooks out there
and sure those might run open some
software
but the operating system delivering it
to you
is very much proprietary so even here
in this temple of free and open source
software
people are using proprietary operating
system to build
open source software and before you
start
laying the blame on your neighbor in the
in the crowd
i'm pretty sure a lot of you are using
github
i've thought it's free as india for open
source projects
it's very convenient has lots of
features
but it's also not open source so can we
really say
that we believe that open source is a
superior way
of building superior software if we are
not trusting open source for things as
intimate as our laptops operating
systems
or are developing tooling
benjamin macko hill argues that free
software is only as
free as the tools you are using to
build it and i agree with that because
if you're using proprietary tools
to build open source software then
you're subject to the whims and the
limitations
of that service provider and your
software is not really free
the runtime side of this paradox is that
a lot
of the open source software that we
write today
ends up running on proprietary
infrastructure
and by cooperative infrastructure i mean
amazon web services google cloud or
microsoft azure
sure you might request a linux vm or a
kubernetes cluster to run your
applications on
but the infrastructure service
delivering that
vm or that cluster to you is very much
proprietary
so in the same way that will advocate
here for using more
open source in your development
infrastructure
in this talk i would like to advocate
that we do the same for our runtime
infrastructure and use open source
solutions
for providing infrastructure what we
call open infrastructure
because it's better but also because it
matters
and so first what do i mean by
development infrastructure what do i
mean
by runtime infrastructure or computing
infrastructure
and why do people need it if you look at
the history of computing
it's all about piling up layers and
abstractions
and this is primarily done for two
reasons
when there is market pressure on one
side when you have a given company
owning
a certain layer the way to displace the
old king
is by commoditizing that layer and
building a new layer
on top of it where differentiation is
happening
that's basically what microsoft did in
the 80s and the 90s to displace the ibm
pc platform
which was dominant at the time on the
other side there is developer pressure
developers are looking for more
convenience so they are interested
in building new layers to abstract the
differences between the lower layers
like web browsers being used as an
application platform
to abstract the differences between
operating systems
and this piling up of layers and
abstractions is happening on all sides
of our industry
like if you look at application delivery
for example traditionally you would
represent
applications like this like users on one
side and applications on the other
but the way you deliver those
applications has been evolving
20 years ago when i started you would
procure some physical hardware
and as an application deployer you would
install an operating system
and then all of your dependencies and
then your application
on top of that but we started to add
more and more layers
uh first we added hardware
virtualization abstracting the server
your application is running on from the
physical hardware that actually
runs it then we added a new layer
cloud apis to allow you to
programmatically access
those virtualized resources so you have
programmable infrastructure on one side
and cloud native applications
being deployed on top of that
more recently we added a new layer cloud
application deployment apis which is
basically what kubernetes provides
higher level primitives that you can use
to deploy complex
applications on this programmable
infrastructure
and so the infrastructure space has been
evolving we are seeing an evolution
towards with developers and application
deployers wanting to care less and less
about infrastructure details we are
seeing an evolution towards using
commodity hardware
so when your needs increase rather than
scaling
up and buying a larger server or more
specialized server
you scale out by buying a lot of simpler
similar machines and you spread the load
among them
we are seeing an evolution towards
commoditized runtime environments
so rather than having a highly curated
entune runtime environment that you have
to make sure
it never dies you are moving towards
using disposable easy to recreate
runtime environments that you can easily
kill
and recreate from scratch
and we're seeing an evolution towards
lighter and lighter runtimes so
we from physical machines to virtual
machines to containers to functions
and there is no reason to think that
this evolution will stop there
and finally as we add those abstractions
the share of complexity that is handled
by software compared to hardware
is increasing in order to optimize
utilization in order to
reduce development and deployment times
or costs to change more often to react
faster
so we are building more and more of
those layers in the infrastructure
space and as you pile up those
abstractions
it's clear that there is a growing
separate role of providing
infrastructure for others
to deploy their applications on and this
is really the population that we care
about
when we are talking about providing open
infrastructure solutions
the people that provide that
infrastructure can be
private infrastructure for the needs of
a given organization
or it can be public infrastructure for
anyone around the world with a credit
card
but it's the same job and that's really
the new role that we're trying to
facilitate
so now that we set the stage and explain
what we mean by um
by computing infrastructure and the
people that are actually trying to serve
why should you adopt open infrastructure
why should you prefer it over
using property infrastructure that is
already
available and ready to use
well the first reason is actually
obvious uh open
infrastructure is based on open source
software so it shares all the benefits
the business
practical benefits of open source
software and sometimes it's easy to
overlook them where we
probably in this crowd have been using
free and open source software for a
while and so
sometimes it's easy to overlook why a
business would
choose open source software the first
benefit
is availability the fact that there is
no barrier
monetary contractually or otherwise to
trying out the software
with all of its functionality the fact
that you can simply evaluate it for
future use play with it just have fun
with it
the fact that there is no friction going
from that experimentation
to production so it's really to me
one of the major benefits of open source
software but even more important
especially in the corporate setting is
sustainability
when an organization makes the choice of
deploying
software it does not want to be left out
without maintenance
because the vendor changes its mind or
goes
burst and so the ability for anyone to
take and modify the source code
means that you are not relying on the
single vendor for for long-term
maintenance
it also conveniently avoids finding
yourself locked in
because the cost of switching software
is just too high
and you end up on the vulnerable side of
the deal
another key benefit of open source
adoption
in a corporate setting is that open
development methodologies make it
really easy to identify and attract
talent
companies can identify potential
candidates
based on the open record of their
contribution
to the technologies that they're
interested in and conversely
candidates can easily identify with the
open source technologies
that organizations are using so they can
join those companies
with certainty that they will be able to
capitalize
on the experience that they will have
there it's much better than working on
proprietary software
which you are not even allowed to talk
about
and you will have no chance of
encountering ever again in your career
from a technical standpoint access to
the source code means that you're able
to look under hood
and understand by yourself how the
software works
or why it behaves the way it does this
transparency also allows you to conduct
independent security audits
for looking for vulnerabilities
but beyond that the ability to take and
modify the source code means that
you have the possibility to find and fix
issues by yourself
without even depending on a vendor this
really further increases your
ability to react fast to unexpected
failures or unexpected behaviors
and finally last but not least with open
source you have the possibility to
engage in the upstream community
producing the software
and influence its direction by
contributing directly to it
the organizations that engage in
upstream open source communities are
more efficient
they're able to anticipate changes
they're able to voice concerns when the
community is making choices that would
adversely affect them
they can make sure that the software
to their future needs by growing the
features that they will need tomorrow
and those are not like abstract or
philosophical benefits
those are really practical business
benefits
and the main reason why companies all
around the world today adopt open source
software
including open infrastructure
but using open source software for
providing infrastructure
also gives you three additional benefits
which we call the three c's
capabilities compliance and cost
so first capabilities
so back in 2010 when we started
openstack there were
people saying that there would soon be a
standard cloud with standard size vms
and that competing against amazon web
services in providing
that service was a losing ballot
and yet 10 years after we're seeing
clouds in all forms and shapes we're
seeing um
io optimized instances we are seeing
memory optimized instances cpu optimized
instances gpus
bare metal instances so clearly one size
does not fit all
and some of those features if you want
access to a specific
feature set are really overpriced in the
in the public cloud market because it's
really difficult for
them to provide those specialized
resources
with the same margins as they have for
their standard size vms
and some features that you might need
are not available
so for example if you want to piece up a
specific piece of hardware within your
servers
well it's it's difficult to find it in
the public cloud if you want an atomic
clutch in your servers
well there's just no public cloud that
will offer you that
even if they are using it themselves
and so using
open infrastructure you can actually
decide what you put in your servers
you can have the extra flexibility the
extra extensibility the
the feature set that you want exactly in
your servers
um open infrastructure also allows full
compliance with local regulations
uh it's especially important in europe
because we have very strong privacy laws
and uh so data locality in particular is
very critical
but we are seeing that concern transfer
to other parties like
governments potentially being spied on
by the countries where their
public cloud resources are based
and or strategic organizations like
airbus or the atomic
research groups which are potentially
also spied on by the same foreign spies
and finally we're seeing more recently
concerns from
companies that are competing with those
public cloud providers
and and running their infrastructure on
their services like netflix for example
competing with amazon prime video while
running all of their infrastructure in
amazon web services
with open infrastructure you decide who
has physical access to your servers
and finally the last c is cost so as an
infrastructure provider
if you're interested in providing
private infrastructure for for the needs
of a given organization
there are a number of of proprietary
software solutions that you can
choose but those really have
a high licensing cost so the cost can
add up quickly if you start using really
your
infrastructure the licensing cost really
adds up
and so using open source for the
solutions will
allow you to keep those costs under
control and if you're a company
interested in building a public cloud so
for anyone around the world with a
credit card
you can start from scratch there is just
no solution out there so you can
write something from scratch and to be
honest you will probably get to
something working really fast
after all like openstack nova was
written prototype over a weekend of
coding so it's not
rocket science like you can get to
something working really fast
but there is a reason why in the past
year
openstack still saw 47 000 changes
uh 10 years in it's because the devil is
in the details in all the corner cases
and so being able to rely on the
community sharing the same code
will save you massive amounts in
development and maintenance costs
over the long run
so those species are yet another reason
why you should adopt open infrastructure
but now i want to talk about
how open infrastructure facilitates uh
interoperability and hybrid cloud
scenarios
so at that point you may wonder hybrid
cloud like isn't that a buzzword from
industry um well yes and no
the traditional thinking behind choosing
between public and private cloud
goes a bit like this
so if you look at the price profile of a
public cloud
and you graph the cost of your cloud per
cpu core
with public cloud it looks a bit like
this you pay a certain price per cpu
core
until you hit the number of calls and
then you hit new pricing tier and price
goes down a bit etc etc until you hit
the final
pricing tier and you pay that's the
price you will pay for
uni extra units forever the price
profile for
private cloud on the other hand looks a
bit like this you have this
high investment upfront then you hit
economies of scale
and at some point you need
the point of diminishing return so it
just goes
like this at the end and so the choice
between public and private
infrastructure looks simple like
above a certain number of core makes
more sense to use private infrastructure
while
under a number of cores it makes more
sense to use
public infrastructure but in reality
things are a bit more complex
because this assumes that your the
amount of resources you consume
is the constant over time and in reality
your usage
probably looks more like this like with
spikes and drops in usage
so what really makes the most sense
economically is actually to use
private infrastructure for those
resources that you're always using
and use public infrastructure elasticity
to
absorb the spikes in usage which is what
is called hybrid usage
and open infrastructure is really great
for those hybrid scenarios because you
can use the same software on the private
side
and on the public side that allows you
to optimize cost because
you can use private infrastructure for
all those resources that you're always
using
and you can use public infrastructure
for those spikes but it also enables
capabilities and compliance
because if you need specific hardware
for specific
workloads or or you have data locality
requirements you can run those on the
private side of your infrastructure
while still using public cloud
and using the same software and apis on
the private
and the public side allows you to reduce
applications costs because you don't
have to validate
separate versions of your applications
based on where they're running
allows you to move applications around
from the private to the public side of
your infrastructure and vice versa
examples of open source software that
provide that kind of interoperability
include openstack which provides
interoperability at the infrastructure
as a as a service layer so you can find
private clouds running openstack and
public clouds running open stack
but also kubernetes which provides
promises interoperability at the
application deployment layer
so any cloud that provides kubernetes
gives you
gives you some interoperability there
so open infrastructure is pretty great
obviously
i'm trying to make a case for it but it
also makes sense for tomorrow and
what do i mean by open infrastructure is
future proof
well obviously it's hard to know what
the future holds i i
certainly don't know that but we're
pretty sure of a few things we
are pretty sure that abstractions will
continue to be piled
we've gone from virtualization to cloud
apis
to application deployment apis this is
clearly not over
we're also pretty sure that there is no
technology that will end all
technologies
we are using vms we're using containers
we are now using functions
and there is no reason to think that
containers somehow is the end
to all things there will be new things
invented tomorrow
and we're also pretty sure that we'll
need to provide infrastructure for those
new
those new technologies infrastructure
will always have to be provided
applications will always have to run
somewhere
i mean even serverless servers
and in that uncertain future open
infrastructure can help because with
open source
you invest in communities you don't
invest in products
and those communities tackle a problem
space they are not
only producing a specific narrow
solution
so for example the the openstack
community is not
about producing openstack it's about
taking the perspective of the
infrastructure provider
and helping them build and operate open
infrastructure if we need to create
other
pieces of technology other open source
projects
like if that community needs those to
provide open infrastructure
then they will be able to do it so
investing in that community lets you
share issues and other infrastructure
with other infrastructure providers
and build solutions for tomorrow
whatever you need there
so to summarize
that's really fast so to summarize
we've seen several reasons why as an
infrastructure provider you should adopt
open infrastructure some of them are
like rooted
good business reasons based on the fact
that it's open source
uh some of them are more specific to
open infrastructure like
capabilities compliance and cost we've
seen how it
enables interoperability and hybrid
cloud usage
we've seen how it better prepares you
for whatever is coming up tomorrow
but there is really a deeper reason
why you should choose open
infrastructure and it's that
open infrastructure enables innovation
i mean i love open infrastructure
because i don't want a world where
all of the infrastructure needs will be
provided by a couple of internet giants
or worse by a monopoly
why well first monopolies are bad i'm
pretty sure
that's something people can agree with
they really distort good market
conditions
in the end they limit innovation and the
prices go up so having
concentration of cloud of infrastructure
providing in a
couple of big shops really creates a
problem it's not really sane
but what's even less sane and i would
say borderline dangerous
is monocultures monocultures are
vulnerable
so if half of the internet is running
off a single
infrastructure provider then it's not
resilient at all
a single class break can lead to
catastrophic failure
and what used to be mildly annoying
because you could not check your
facebook feed anymore with more and more
devices
being connected to the internet and
relying on the internet to function
what used to be mildly annoying can now
be life-threatening
so it's really important that we have
diversity
to avoid monopolies and monocultures
but beyond that giving everyone access
to infrastructure providing technologies
allows everyone to play and innovate
if you restrict innovation to a couple
of big shops
you're limiting what the world can do so
it's
important that we have strong open
source infrastructure providing
solutions
available for everyone it allows us to
distribute the future more
evenly and that to me is really why
open infrastructure really matters and
why i would like you to adopt more of it
tomorrow thank you for your attention
[Applause]
it's like 30 minutes for questions now
so
does anyone want to ask any questions
i saw you guys
thank you for the wonderful presentation
uh i have just one quick question what
are we doing to address barrier of entry
so take a little example i work for
startup
we need to spin up infrastructure today
and fast
i can do it in amazon in two or three
days
but i care about open source we care
about freedom and not being vendored
locked in
what would be the way to do the same
with say openstack
so you can you can opt for a public
cloud
sorry you can opt for a public cloud
that is
actually based on openstack we have a
number of public clouds
uh in europe in particular it's
difficult to make a dent on the public
cloud market in the us right now because
it's
it's really a cutthroat between amazon
and microsoft and google but
in the european market there is really a
strong footprint of openstack based
public clouds
uh because we have unique concerns in
terms of data locality
and regulations so it's pretty
attractive
we have like an ecosystem of companies
and not like
name any of them because that would be
from getting one of them
and making enemies but you have options
you have options that will
let you benefit from the fact that it's
ready to use i'm not saying you should
do private clouds i'm saying you should
take into account the fact that
at one point you might reach a level of
optimization where it might make more
financial sense
to start setting up your own
infrastructure
especially once you have the your needs
start stabilized
it's easier to know how much you
actually would benefit
from implementing some of it in a local
private
infrastructure but you can prepare for
that future by opting for
uh openstack based public clouds uh in
your
in we have a marketplace thanks
are there any other questions
[Music]
okay thank you very much for your talk
[Applause]