okay let's move on to the next talk of
the day
let me introduce you to stefan
[Applause]
[Music]
uh afternoon everyone thanks for taking
your lunch time to come and listen to me
talk today
when i submitted this talk after i
submitted this talk i realized that the
title of the talk was pretty generic and
in theory i could come in here and talk
about pretty much
anything i wanted to so i sat down last
night and i decided right i'm going to
start
telling the story of this little boy
called nigel
who had a dream i'm not actually going
to talk about nigel i'm not going to
talk about brexit
thank god it's off the off the table for
today
instead what i'm going to talk about is
versioning and how do you manage
versioning in
a python project and in some cases in
kind of projects in general this is
going to be mostly focused at people
that are
packaging their own projects so
libraries that you're submitting up to
pie pie or whatever
but some of the things i'm talking about
here today will be useful for
basically anyone working on software
whether it's a web application or a
library or something else entirely
for each of these i've broken it down to
three different sections
and each of those i'm going to break
down into two sections i'll get into
that in a second
before i do that i should probably
introduce myself
i'm stephen i work at red hat i've been
working there for about three years
still don't have one of those cool red
hats i'll get one eventually
i work on openstack and have done since
before i joined red hat
for anyone that doesn't know what
openstack is it was the cool kid on the
block until kubernetes came along and
stole our lunch money
um as a result the one big difference
though between openstack and kubernetes
is that openstack is almost entirely
python
the contributions to openstack has made
to the pipeline ecosystem i'd say are
pretty significant
as a result of my work on openstack and
the spare time stuff
i've ended up contributing to and
maintaining an awful lot of python
projects
and i've used a lot of the tools that
i'm going to talk about here today
in those projects either by choice or
it's been forced upon me
so before we dive into the actual tools
themselves a quick
kind of recap on versioning and what do
i mean about versioning and
managing change and stuff so
you probably should care about
versioning if your software
has users if it's something more than a
script sitting on a server somewhere or
on your local pc
and if it's something that you're
expecting to change or evolve over time
so you're planning to add or move
functionality
and from the python perspective
versioning
number wise we're usually referring to
this pep from a while ago which
specifies
version identifier strings like this
most of the time
you're not going to use all of this most
people talk
in more generic terms in terms of things
like
semantic versioning and calendar
versioning like ubuntu and that kind of
thing
basic idea behind versioning of course
is that your users should know when
you've introduced changes
into your code when you've gone and
removed some functionality that they may
have relied on previously
or you've added some cool new whiz-bang
feature that you want the world to know
about
so i promised three different kind of
focus areas the first of these
is packaging so again this is mostly
useful for people that are packaging up
their own libraries and publishing them
on
pipeline
i'd imagine that most people that have
written packages have ended up using
setup tools
to do that uh obviously a replacement
for the the legacy
tools project there are cool new kids on
the block here with regards to
things like poetry and flits that kind
of thing i'm not going to talk about
those today
instead i'm going to talk about two kind
of plug-in projects
that exist for setup tools that you can
use to kind of help
make your life easier the reason that
you'd want something like this
is the way that setup tools normally
manages its version is
you put in a static string into your
setup.pi document or your setup.config
document
and every time you update that based on
the new version of your software
um there's an infrastructure management
track here there's an automation track
here
and there's a couple of tracks in yanson
uh with
the idea being that developers don't
like doing stuff manually when you can
automate the process
and as far as this static string stuff
goes it's usually duplication because
you're usually managing your version
information somewhere else typically in
the form of
git metadata git tags git branches that
kind of thing
so the first of these two tools i'm
talking about setup tools scm
and pbr are plugins for setup tools
that allow you to pull out that get
metadata
from your repo and automatically inject
it into your package
but they work slightly differently
one thing to note the first of these is
a kind of broader python ecosystem
project
the other one is an openstack project
that's used
across pretty much every single
openstack project and
anyone else that wants to use it i use
it in my own project square a lot
setup tools scm is by far the simpler of
the two
you say that you you put it in as your
requirements
for the setup stage of your package
and you set this boolean config option
saying whether you want setup tools to
do your
versioning for you and you as soon as
you've done that it will go
and it will figure out what version of
your package is inject that into your
theme and then when you go to build your
tarball or your wheel or whatever
all that stuff will happen magically for
you which is all lovely
pbr does almost the exact same thing
um but it also does a whole load of
other cool stuff
that i'm not going to go into because
that's a talk in its own right but it'll
do stuff like it'll generate change log
files for you it'll generate an author's
file
it'll manage release notes it'll
do basically everything under the sun
for you whether you want it all
or not is a different matter but very
very powerful tool
and the main advantages like i said of
using these tools is that you can just
completely forget about versioning from
the perspective of actually
having to hard code some strings
somewhere
you just tag your package you build your
tower balls and you push them up to pipe
i and you are
done all very nice and handy
the second of the three focus areas i
want to look at
is how do you actually declare
individual
changes in your package or
your library to whoever is consuming
that library
whether it's someone in your team at
work or someone some random on the
internet that just happens to consume
that
and the normal way of doing this would
be
either you don't document it or you
document it in some giant
change log file that people have to go
down and skim through to
figure out what the hell has changed and
why does version 2 of this library no
longer contain
these apis or has changed the behavior
of them
and developers like
the idea of coding a aversion string
into your package
they tend to hate writing ducks and if
you can get them to write docs at all
you're doing pretty well
so what you'd hopefully be trying to do
is get
the documentation to live inside in the
code
itself and this is what projects like
django in the previous talk and other
tools like sphinx
do themselves they have their own custom
tooling built around
the warnings framework where you import
something
and it's deprecated in django 2 2 and
then removed in django 3
3 or 3 0 you'll see a warning pop up
when you run try to use that api saying
this still works but it's going very
soon to switch over to something new
and you can go and reinvent the wheel
you can go do all this yourself
but why would you do that when there are
tools out there that'll do it for you
so once again with two tools first of
these is one that's from the board a
python ecosystem and another one has
been developed
uh within openstack to uh to serve a
similar purpose
as with the last one i have a clear
preference
um which i'll try to not highlight too
much
deprecation is the simpler of the two
it gives you decorators that you can
decorate
random functions with and you can say
that the thing has been deprecated what
version it was deprecated in
when you plan to remove it if you plan
to remove it and
some details for the um the user to
actually figure out
why these things have changed and maybe
what they should do instead
you go and you run this code and you'll
see
warnings like this popping up with your
code exact same kind of thing you'll see
if you've ever worked on
django or if you've ever used sphinx
from an extension perspective
very simple very easy to use debt
collector
initially looks very very similar
again a version of removal versions some
messages
to help inform the user as to what's
actually changed
and the behavior looks almost the same
[Music]
but it also lets you do things like move
modules between different places move
classes that kind of thing so you decide
that you want
to move your compatibility module under
the utils
module you can do that you can put in a
an alias essentially in the old place
move all the code across and then
eventually remove that alias once
everyone has had time to switch over
uh again super super powerful tool
and a very useful way of avoiding
reinventing the wheel
it looks almost the same when you're
actually going running
the third of these then is
possibly the one that's most useful to
almost everyone here because this
doesn't necessarily
require you to be working on a library
this is also useful if you happen to be
working on a web application
or some qe application of client
whatever
you want to be able to expose not just
api changes but any kind of change
back up to your user and say i've gone
and removed
this thing or i've added this thing and
the way that people
like as a reference earlier normally do
this stuff is they write this giant ass
change like file or news file or change
this file or whatever you want to call
it
and they pump in all the information
that they want either
iteratively as they go along through the
cycle or some
poor fellow has to sit at the end of the
cycle and try and figure out what the
hell has just happened
which is not fun the other thing you can
do is try and pull this information
from for example your git logs just do a
diff between two different versions but
that
means you have to be very very
regimented in terms of what your git
commit messages look like
um if any i because i work on openstack
i tend to use garrett
on a daily basis so i change like commit
messages tend to make sense and then i
switch over to github and i see pull
requests and it's like
fix up this typo fix up another type of
fix up another typo
they don't make very nice change locks
and one other big issue with having this
giant as changes file if it's done
through the course of a cycle then if
you have multiple people contributing to
a project
you end up having merge conflict hell
where
you have three or four features going in
the space for two weeks the first guy
that happens to get their
feature in gets their change log updates
in
everyone else has to re-spin their
patches and keep respinning them just to
update trivial changes this is an
example from sphinx
in this case i just gave up writing
change logs i figured that the
maintainers would go and do it for me so
thankfully if you're not sphinx there
are two different projects that you can
use
to do this for you once again one from
outside of openstack and the other one
from inside openstack
the one from inside openstack is super
super powerful
maybe too powerful but town choir the
first of these
[Music]
ultra easy to use you write these
five news fragments you dump it into
some predetermined location and the
fragments have a specific
format they have a ticket id whether
that's a github
issue tracker number pull request number
whatever
they have a type of release note so if
it's a feature
if it's an upgrade impact that kind of
thing and then they have
the suffix and this is all restructured
text-based
might support markdown i've never tried
it um
go figure that out but you write your
change log
into one of these files and at the end
of your cycle when you get
decided you're releasing my package 0.9
you'll go and run the town fire command
and
i've passed this with the draft flags so
i can actually see what i want on the
command line but what that will do is
it will read all of those fragments and
it will go put the
order them accordingly squash them into
one giant news file
and dump that out into again a
pre-configured
destination you can then
version control this add a release
0.9 commit and include that as part of
your
tarball that you push up to to pipe it
very simple again very nice and easy to
use
and this is what projects like toxics
possibly pi test and a few others as
well
vino is a whole other level of
complexity so
from the high level it looks pretty
similar you
only instead of having to manually
create a command it provides these sub
commands that will create
the the abstract for other the
fragment for you again into a
predetermined place
and that's a yaml file with restructured
text
snippets inside so you can have a
release note for a particularly large
feature
that has for example it adds a new
feature it deprecates an old feature
and it also has some upgrade impacts
that people deploy in this
library need to be aware of
but you don't actually need to go and
combine this thing at the end of the
cycle because reno was smart
and reno's aware that you're using a git
repo
and it's aware that uh i knows that at
the end of your cycle you should be
tagging your commitment
or you should be tagging your chosen
release
thing to say this is release 0.9
and if you go and run if you go and run
reno
you can specify a particular version and
it will skim down all the way through
your git tree
and it will figure out which of these
release note fragments you would have
map to a given release so uh
i added five release notes for zero nine
to 1.0
it will take just those five and it'll
put them out into a nice restructured
text file that you can include in your
documentation
and it provides stuff like sphinx
extensions so you don't need to actually
worry about
having to go and generate that file
manually you just put in the directive
somewhere
and uh yeah it's just nice and it just
works
the only time reno breaks down is if you
do what sphinx does
and they have stable branches that they
decide to merge back in on a periodic
basis
um then reno gets confused with like
circular dependencies and that kind of
thing
but generally the way that i'm used to
projects working you decide that this is
going to be my saber release and you
branch off
and you just back cherry pick bug fixes
as you're going along and those bug
fixes just happen to include release
notes
so your stable branches get all the new
release notes for those bug fixes that
you're backboarding
like i said this is what we use across
the entire openstack ecosystem now
so this is an example of release notes
from probably nova
maybe something else and as you can see
we didn't write this single page this is
all a whole load of release note chunks
that people have contributed as they've
gone and worked on these features
and at the end of the cycle the thing
has just been automatically generated
and will continue to be automatically
generated
every time we build our docks
and that's town cryo and reno and with
that i'm going to return to us
regularly schedule broadcast and get
back to talking about brexit
so yeah quick wrap up uh version 101
three kind of focus areas uh how you can
use your packaging
to automatically automatically version
your software through your packaging
how you can indicate to consumers of a
library that you
have made changes to your the api of
that library
and then finally how you can go and
document these changes to
both api consumers and everyone else
and with that thank you very much for
coming
[Music]
and i'm happy to take any questions here
or afterwards
here we are
[Music]
yeah we have time for a few questions if
you're interested just raise your hands
and please exceed the room quietly
okay
i said quiet please
thanks for the talk um do you do you
think there's something missing
something you haven't do you think
do you think there's something missing
something you some tool you
some process that is still broken and
some tool that you feel like you haven't
written yet so if i
i think the question was i think the
question was uh
is there still something missing even
with these
um
probably the the biggest thing i notice
missing
is uh probably testing and a lack of
understanding around things like
semantic versioning
so uh it is quite common
the way that we do release of version
package management
in uh in openstack is we use constraints
we say this is the upper bound on every
package that in openstack that you can
use
so talks cannot not talks but
deprecations cannot exceed version 2.0
and at some point we will decide to bump
2.0 up to 2.1
and quite often for random packages uh
2.1 removes a feature
and it shouldn't because 3.0 should be
the feature removal version
so i guess yeah a lack of testing and a
lack of understanding but that's
software issues that i don't think
libraries can really help you all that
much with
if you know how to do semantic
versioning properly and you
remember to make sure that you bump your
version when you remove something and
whatever then i think this gets you
90 95 of the way there to what you
actually want
all right i'll just repeat what you say
actually does this still manage uh
version numbers but i do some advertise
been just with package building because
for instance our projects we have
conventional like like four or five
different places of projects
and use tools such as filters
so that the question was for tools like
pbr
do you have the ability to get the
version
elsewhere in the project instead of it
being statically
yeah so from within the python code
itself
pbr provides a couple of uh
essentially wrappers over uh package
utils or something
one of the setup tools subprojects
that will give you the package version
all the information about your installed
package
the only problem with that is that it
relies on the package
actually being installed so it won't
work for example if somebody just dumps
the tarball out somewhere instead of pip
installing it
um if you do that i'm not actually sure
i haven't done that with a python
package for a long time
so is that
anything else
[Music]
if not thank you very much enjoy the
rest of your life
you