are we good we can go what's up
everybody how's it going how y'all doing
I'm Jeremy this is brian i'm sure you
all in gym that know us by now can also
call me shmoogle because ipv6 is too
precious anyway we're here to talk about
ipv6 we here last year we talked a
little bit about it we're just going to
kind of give you guys you know look back
at the good old days IP version 4
results of the launch day that happened
last year some of the challenges that
we're going to be facing in the near
future and regards to implementation and
stuff we've run into so far and you know
some of the security and compatibility
issues you'll see when you're going from
IP version 4 to IP version 6 so to start
with we have a video yeah we're gonna
have to hold the mic down so hopefully
you guys can hear this and 10 points to
whoever catches the movie reference
these are just a few of the images
it isn't what we talked there's been no
86 limitation here no transitioning
event for the environment is a beaver
fork
exhaustion an ipv4 exhaustion that
happened earlier this month it was
supposed to provide internet to the
population bring connectivity to the
masses well it worked the people here
got connected it spreads
everyone
I beautiful rapidly spread to the point
where we knew we would run out of
address space but we were so
short-sighted we didn't have a plan
their 4.3 billion ipv4 addresses we just
split
quick there were solutions the ipv4
exhausting for the pro pre-renovation
saw whirring Gordon right now
transitioning strategies to give us a
version 6 exhaustion
how we have internets work for this
shameless corporate blog yep integrated
broadband services close anyway I did
that was just a video we put together
based actually on the talk we did last
year in regards to mitigating IP version
4 exhaustion we can talk a little bit
about more that in a second but again
you know my name is Jeremy Brian we both
work for I BBS I work in the network
engineering group I've got a ccnp past
the CCI written working on prepping for
the lab so we've been tasked with making
the internet work for everybody that's
right transitioning to IP version 6
Brian you want to say our meetings
apparently we support about about one
and a half million cable modern devices
just put it closer to your mouth yeah
anyway right now we support about 1.5
million cable modem devices through our
corporation we also have five of the
home dsl and most of the providers we
support services to about 250 service
providers or smaller mso's cable
companies dsl companies harper the home
companies they don't have much budget
much engineering support services of
their own so they come to us to figure
their problems out and one of the big
problems is is they're out of IP for
space and they have to figure out a way
to get to IP version 6 so last year when
we're here we talked about some of the
solutions that there are to mitigate the
exhaustion of IP version 4 whether
that's brokering with Aaron and the
specified transfer listing service that
they have you know reclamation of IP
version 4 addresses through using
private addresses for cable modems MTA
so on so forth and then hardware and
software net so we've had a little bit
of experience with these over the past
year just for some review IP version 4
deployed in the 80s internet protocol
version 6 was brought up in a round 1999
you have the differences in the address
size the 32-bit versus 128-bit
hexadecimal the addressing format
kind of displayed there your prefix
notation is a little bit easier in IP
version 4 versus IP version 6 and then
just the sheer number of addresses and
even the deployed in on IP version 6
there's been so many changes since 1999
that if you were a compliant at that
point in time they are you probably be
compliant today so even today they're
still adding and updating the spec yeah
changes every day it's actually really
interesting if you've watched the way
that IP version 6 has evolved over time
one of the one of the biggest things
with IP version 4 is a network address
translation that became very necessary
in the 90s due to the pending exhaustion
everybody knew eventually we're going to
be out of address space so NAT was
invented as you know kind of a solution
to that obviously an IP version 6
there's you know real no real need for
net so at one point in time there was a
form of net and IP version 6 but that's
been stripped out of the protocol since
so talking more about IP version 4 then
there was you know highly limited
address space NAT was seen as the bane
of innovation because they just
abandoned yeah it was just a band-aid I
mean it basically took your public
addresses and you shared either a single
or multiple public addresses and that
resulted in issues with application
layer gateways several devices that
depended on you know functionality of
having all the ports available on the
public address space just broke when it
came to using that so over time there
were solutions that were developed
around that but it was still issue so in
IP version 6 they rip NAT out and
there's plenty of space for everybody
and that is a bad thing when you do that
and that and that so a lot of cases
you'll see where you're trying to
reserve IP space or control users like a
hotel environment they may double or
triple match it before you got the
internet so that breaks a lot of tools
you may use near your computer
so IP version 4 versus IP version 6 i
wish i had the mortal kombat theme here
but i don't just in regards to the sheer
number of addresses this is again this
is just review you know have about 4.3
billion roughly if you round up of which
only 3.7 billion are actually publicly
addressable the rest are either private
or shared address space defined by
little i asked so on and so forth ipv6
has a really big number available will
actually a 340 unda Cillian 282 de
Cillian 366 not an alien 920 octillion
938 septillion 49 6360 lien 463
antillean 374 call it really is and 456
so that is a little bit more you know
you get to the if I'm if I'm going to
point right here is IP version 4 roughly
and then the rest of the way up is all
of IP version 6 so I think somebody
calculated there was a IP address for
every three square feet in the Milky Way
galaxy one IP address for every atom on
the surface of a hundred Earth's so
we're doing okay there's a cutter little
few more so we think I know the funny
thing about that the funny thing about
that is when IP version 4 first came out
you know the AI na was just like here
take this implement it use it in your
network I was experimental to it was
experimental at that point in time well
people took it and they implemented it
and oh my gosh now we're out of space
they're doing the same thing with IP
version 6 they're giving out these huge
allocations to people saying here please
take it use it implements it no real
regard for what happens if we run out of
these huge allocations that you're
sending to us well know that the idea in
regards to the huge allocations are
giving out now is that you'll never need
another one hopefully but Aaron recently
modified their policies instead of just
handing out / 32 s of IP version 6 which
was a single address in IP version 4 but
is a lot in IP version 6 they're
actually allowing you to get smaller
allocations and
returning some of that address space to
pay less per year because people just
don't need that much and they also
supposedly they're not going to give out
more than fifteen percent of the whole
address space initially so they're Reese
opposable that's what they say so
basically go request for ipv6 addresses
are going to give you pretty much
whatever you ask for but you will you
know you will pay for it your annually
with Aaron but supposedly they're only
going to give out the first fifteen
percent and then start you know locking
it down a little bit supposedly until
the spec is revised as they say so the
image you see at the bottom your screen
here Aaron IP version space for
available this 2.48 / eights remaining
basically we're out pretty much I mean
the global registry is completely out
and this is the bad space I mean this is
like the Bogue andheri the blacklist
space they got back even if you got an
address block in this there's a good
chance you won't give to have the
internet because these are really bad
addresses well aaron aaron has said as
depletion occurs as you know the address
space starts to run out they're going to
start to run into that nasty address
space that's just really the dirty
bottom of the barrel stuff and they
won't have time to scrub it completely
because people are so hungry for the
address space again that they're just
having to kind of look at it and say
well I think we cleaned it up in here
have it yeah the fans exceeding the
supply so it's good stuff so here's a
beautiful chart showing about where
we're at right now the interesting line
here is if you can look at the blue line
this is the asian-pacific allocations
it's like all of a sudden they went out
that again actually the funny thing
about it is I had written down here that
wonderful reference to there will be
blood they actually approved
inter-regional transfers so the
asia-pacific folks can drink Aaron's
milkshake I can drink it up so this
little purple line here this is aaron
going down steadily steadily steadily i
expect before the end of the year for
sure Aaron will be completely exhausted
and there's talks of some organizations
in Asia or even the u.s. possibly buying
companies of South America to get
address space
so they can go ahead and start locking
in outer space and work on transfers so
technically its regional you're supposed
to keep the address blocks within the
region but now it's gotten so low where
they're allowing some exceptions to the
rule and larger companies are actually
going and looking to find cheaper
solutions to get address space because
the cost of an address is anywhere from
five to fourteen dollars right now and
it's not going to go down it's just
going to keep going up that's ridiculous
I actually you know because sorry how
about there it's not better all right
we're good what I was going to say is I
was actually talking because we work in
the cable industry we have a lot of
experience working with different
providers talking with them about
whether they get address space from
their direct service provider because
even cable providers have to get
internet circuit from somewhere whether
that's 80 or comcast in this case
comcast is getting ready to charge this
guy 400 bucks a month for a / 24 s worth
of IP address space juicy address is not
bandwidth per month so I mean you can go
out to Aaron and get I think it's a / 22
for like fifteen hundred dollars
annually so but the problem is Aaron's
about out so you know what are these
smaller service provider is going to do
when it runs out then we get back into
the hole mitigating ipv4 exhaustion
brokering black market IP addresses so
but the companies are looking at
acquiring other companies there they're
actually viewing the IP address
resources that companies have as an
asset and it's it's actually a
measurable asset now due to the
depletion so last year IP version 6 was
launched
uh-huh it's climbing high but yeah it's
really not past four point three percent
so this is Google's graph the toll
disclosure here this is actually the
traffic all native IP version 6 traffic
that's gone through google gets up to
about 1.3 percent as of yesterday when i
pulled the graph or a couple days ago I
guess but still it's not a lot not a lot
of native IP version 6 traffic yet so
even though it's out there it's in the
wild it's been deployed there's still
not a lot of people using IP version 6
what's going on with that there's still
consumer challenges to a certain extent
windows XP last year had like thirty
five percent penetration still it's down
to about 17.6 1078 the kingpins for sure
not ate so much as seven but the problem
is most people aren't connecting their
individual machines directly to their
internet connection usually have a
router or something like that at home
right so people don't usually replace
their routers unless they break so you
probably have a 56 year old router
sitting in your house for most folks
anyway that there's no chance it will do
IP version 6 at least with the way the
spec exists today so the interesting
thing that we've seen in our labs is
even different consumer routers
implement the spec differently we'll
talk a little bit about that more in a
bit but I don't know if anybody heard
about the debacle well we'll talk about
that in a second but they remember the
cisco linksys debacle i think was last
summer where they did a forced cloud
update on all the consumer devices and
basically
drew me for a loop they're forced update
on the consumer devices and said hey you
guys gotta register for our cloud
service if you want to use your internet
connection well you can about imagine
exactly how well the consumers took to
being told what they have to do so that
was a big issue for linksys but you have
to understand what they were trying to
do is from my perspective new I
understand what they were trying to get
out they were trying to make it so that
all of the linksys routers are fully
capable and updated to the latest
firmware so they can accept v6 addresses
and read all of your data but no I'm
just kidding they probably a good
attention they went about the wrong way
yeah so I mean that was a lesson learned
hard and now Cisco is actually selling
like sister belkin so it doesn't matter
anyway but comcast actually there was a
news article this week they fully
deployed IP version 6 on all of their
eres infrastructure I'm not exactly sure
since I don't work for comcast how that
compares to their Cisco infrastructure
but you know probably 5050 roughly that
is a milestone I mean there's been some
growing pains again we're getting into
the consumer router differences here we
have a lab at the company we work for
we've got a cisco 7246 vxr ipv6 is
aliens yes by the way and we've got you
know cable bundle on there that's
configured with all the necessary
commands to make dhcpv6 work because in
the cable world you have to use DHCP in
order to track your customers so if you
get a clear subpoena requests on
subpoena is not a big deal but Clea yeah
that one you got to worry about and some
of the other things do is you just need
to control out the allocations as you
issue amount so you're using the same
platform so you really need to keep the
same basic theory going instead of just
throwing statics out there you need to
stick with gcp and one of the first
things you run into is d HP v6 this is
really only supported very few operating
systems you got to be if you're on the
Mac you got to be at least snow lion to
even see it and then on Windows 7 and 8
mm-hmm what
Snow Leopard whatever was mal mine it's
some the line is Josh's new operating
system that they haven't released yet
but we just no I'm just kidding but um
anyway was interesting because we have
three different router vendors in our
lab right now we need to get a netgear
and the belkin but we don't have yet but
we've got a sous d-link and a linksys
the linksys router we were working on it
and it would accept an IP version 6
address but it wouldn't hand anything to
the devices behind it unless he put it
in bridge mode which is really strange
and then asus just didn't want to play
nice until we did a firmware update the
d-link won't accept an individual IP
address that has to get a / 64
allocation so it can hand out addresses
the devices behind it it's very greedy
so it's it's really goofy because every
vendor has a different implementation so
as we move forward hopefully you know a
firmer standard will be developed but
for now there definitely are a lot of
differences in the consumer router is
available to people that go to Walmart
and buy a router today and our idea with
our testing is to basically match up
what a consumer can purchase because you
know when you're dealing with an ISP
unless they're giving you the equipment
you're probably gonna want you to use
whatever you have so we're trying to
figure out what what they can go pick up
at best buy or walmart and how
compatible it really is so we can kind
of gold certified devices we know work
and then say you can use what you want
but we can we can support these devices
and we're trying to get ahead the
ballgame well trying to the complexity
in regards to the configuration so it
was interesting he brought up static
addressing earlier who's going to type a
static IP v6 address into their device
you'll probably do it once you'll do it
once but you probably don't want to do
it again everybody know how to copy and
paste it's a very useful skill when it
comes to any person six one of the other
say what that's right truncation
abbreviate we're actually going to get
into that in a little bit but I'm
talking about some of the carrier great
night issues too so like he was saying
when you have NAT on top of mat on top
of net on top of well yeah if you run
into some problems things break not
everything works as intended because it
wasn't designed to function like that so
you know your video streaming your skype
calls you're in there netflix and their
xbox don't work they call and call and
they call and they are very upset so
yeah you got to make sure all the more
compliments to keep them up on on the
internet is compatible with their
current devices and a lot of devices in
the house won't be iv6 compatible so you
have to have some kind of edge device
and if i can't get online and play with
my pandas in the world of warcraft to
access that's right but I be virgin 6
has ipsec built-in doesn't it yeah yeah
it does it does make end-to-end
encryption a lot easier in IP version 6
but it's not backwards compatible it
introduces a whole host of new problems
when you're trying to implement a brand
new protocol on your network this is
actually one of my favorite slides the
link local address in regards to how
actually host communicate on a network
so what we've seen in our lab testing is
when a host comes online it's a sign it
assigns itself its own link local
address which is like the 169 254
addresses an IP version 4 but it
actually has a use IP version 6 its the
hole let's see fe 80 followed by 5854
bits of zeros the last 64 bits is the 48
bit mac address with FF fe stucked in
the middle so if you know if you're on a
network and you know link local
addresses every link local address has
that devices MAC address in it while
with FF GE and
you can just rip that right out and hey
look I've got a whole mac address table
that's a little bit of a security flaw
unfortunately all hosts when they come
online especially if they're using
dhcpv6 or slack a stateless
auto-configuration they'll use their
link local address to talk to their
local router and say hey I need an IP
address hey what's the address of this
neighbor that I need to get to so on and
so forth so there's a lot more traffic
on an ipv6 network that you have to be
mindful of in regards to what we had an
IP version 4 let's talk about intrusion
detection intrusion prevention systems
they don't understand the traffic
they're going to drop it well ipv4 is
incompatible with IP version 6 ipv6
isn't backwards compatible with version
4 so you have to have network devices
that understand both and are capable of
filtering both yeah I mean they're going
to run dual stack and they actually have
to be able to correctly interpret all
the standards within IP version 6 any of
the security security potential risks
you have there and that's going to be a
very interesting landscape as we move
forward so if you you know if you have
an exploit it may not work in v4 because
it's locked down and you know the
security systems in place can prolong
that but with ipv6 every device in the
network's public
it's connected to the internet so it's
out there so how do you protect all
those it's actually pretty interesting
that was there was a tat an attack that
I read about this week while I was
prepping for this talk in regards to
pack lamp packet amplification so the
router header in IP version 6 is a
simplified version of the v4 header what
you can do is actually you can place a
zero and the routing header of each
packet it causes them to travel in
dilute path so the ping-pong exploits
take advantage of the wealth of / 64
subnets available in the protocol that's
what every router is going to get in
your system is they're going to get a /
64 so they can delegate addresses to
devices behind them so it basically
allows attackers to send packets from
one non-existent connection together
thus you're not unbeatable sorry but um
it's kind of like an ARP attack on a
layer 3 platform with v6 it basically
results in an endless series of ICMP
unreachable messages so networks it just
flooded with garbage data there has been
an RFC that's been proposed to
depreciate the router heading of zero
hopefully that will go through soon
because this is one of the biggest known
ipv6 exploits at this time so you have
your issues with your security
information and event management systems
no there's no current security
information event management system that
fully supports IP version 6 yet so
you're not going to be able to ID
multiple addresses by the same host
because everybody that has a link local
address will also have a global IP
version 6 address there's there's no
efficient way to track that yet so it
sometimes they're running dual stack and
the running both brother calls at the
same time yep
so talking about the issues with grep
and you're logging servers there's
different ways to display IP version 6
addresses we were talking about
truncating the addresses earlier so you
have your first method where you don't
drop the leading zeros and you have your
second method where you forget to use a
double colon or you just have the actual
RFC 5952 standard you're logging systems
all may use different logging methods so
you have multiple different IP version 6
addresses throughout your different
logging systems there needs to be a
standard basically is what it comes down
to if you don't have a standard then
you're just going to be like well I'm
going to grip this style address well
half your logging systems might have it
the other two-thirds might have well the
other half might have this one and then
keeping us may not use RFC 5952 anywhere
so it's important to understand the
standards and try to reconfigure your
logging and you know system information
event management systems accordingly you
kind of need to pick one way to display
your addresses and stick with it because
if you if you script anything the track
stuff or monitor anything you really
need to stick to one format or you're
going to break your stuff
and again this is a result of the
evolving IP version 6 spec so the one on
the bottom that's the best one that's
the RFC that's what you should try to
stick to if you can other issues no
reputation based protection this gets
back into the whole issues with the
current ipv4 spec and handing out Aaron
handing out the junk space right now
there is currently for IP version 4
reputation based protection there are
known malware hosts known sources about
net so on and so forth that are just
like nope denied sorbs blacklists on so
forth boge on space right well it's like
a chicken and egg thing which is the
same issue we've had with the content
regards to IP version 6 what comes first
the host of the content well you know
the same thing here you have a bit of a
chicken egg egg situation in regards to
reputation based production nobody has
established an ipv6 reputation database
so no one's using a reputation based
security database with ipv6 address and
therefore no one is building a
reputation database it's looping logic
you're basically screwed until somebody
takes action and even once they do build
it I mean you have such a large range of
addresses from Aaron you just start
spamming off the new address you just
move down your block to another area and
you it'd be difficult to block the whole
subnet because then you're blocking a
huge chunk of address space which if
it's a service provider that could be
thousands of thousands millions of
customers so how you manage a blacklist
will also change dramatically so that
and that talk ties right into the next
point effective rate limiting is almost
impossible in IP version 6 due to the
sheer size of the spec it's just
impractical especially since most
current standards deal out / 64 subnets
to edge routers so for some perspective
anyway a slash 96 an IP version 6 is
roughly equivalent to the entire IP
version 4 internet there are four
billion 294 million nine hundred sixty
seven thousand two hundred 96 / 90 sixes
in a single / 64 so that many IP version
4 internets exists in 1 / 64 which is
what we're handing out to customers
saying here have all this address space
so the customer can just be like
well I wanted to do an attack on this
site oh that IP got blocked let me just
switch to one of the other millions and
millions and millions of addresses I
have and just slide right through it so
what would we do what will we do build
solid transition plans I mean that the
same can be said it's just networking
101 right you've got to make sure that
you're aware of what you're doing what
network elements it's going to impact
and implement one thing at a time so I
mean you on y'all's got understand that
you're going to be running dual stack
probably another decade so even if you
get IP 6 up and running in your network
your core is the easiest place to get it
going it's out to the individual
endpoints we're gonna have problems but
at the end of day you're still going to
be running a dual stack you're going to
be running both address spaces so you
have to be able to manage that migration
of Wendy you eventually finally drop the
v4 space and that probably won't be like
you said for at least another decade m8
ipv4 may never go away we may be dual
stack forever just depends it's hard to
say at this point auditing your IP
version 4 network that's definitely
something that's really important you
got to clean up throw out upgrade clean
up and kick out out out modeled or
outdated features they ought to consist
of ensuring every aspect of your network
that can be effectively upgraded to the
next level especially firewalls
intrusion detection intrusion prevention
start with a clean uncluttered slate it
makes it much easier to implement IP
version 6 again you want to do the
gradual implementation update implement
IP version 6 compatible network elements
individually so that way you can monitor
anything that changes any sort of
negative impact on your network you can
just roll that back real easy see what
went wrong try again usual suspects such
as VPN tunnels malicious traffic
requiring authentication everywhere so
on and so forth the syntax that was an
interesting actually thing I wanted to
go over the syntax is it's pretty
similar type your version for right it's
just hexadecimal so at the base of it
all it's pretty much the same you just
got letters in your numbers
but knowing the syntax makes it much
easier to quickly deal with the security
breach or implement necessary
countermeasures since it's already been
around for more than a decade there's no
shortage on information on IP version 6
there's a wonderful 188 page guide from
the National Institute of Standards and
Technology ok the US government if you
want some light reading so and just keep
in mind when you do find in research
information ipv6 or deployments or
moving forward check the data
documentation if it's pretty old there
may be rfcs that have been updated and
upgraded since then you don't want to
get an upgrade path as something isn't
going to work and then you also have to
verify how how much support the
equipment you're trying to deploy it on
really has and just try to run with the
latest firmwares micro codes iOS is at
pdh images you know whatever you need
but make sure you're running the latest
code that's supported in v6 so you're
not already behind the power curve
before you start and in regards to the
big red button I'm big believer in big
red buttons it's a kill switch ipv6
attack if you still have IP version 4
space have a very easy either scripted
method or at least scripts available to
you in order to quickly revert to IP
version 4 and rear out your traffic out
that bay area getting attacked on v6
space and you can still run dual stack
or v4 space you might just want to turn
the v6 off for a while because obviously
by this point I hope you know what
you're doing in regard to type you
version 4 because if you don't god help
you so the too long didn't read version
ipv4 here here to stay for a while at
least another decade ipv6 is picking up
steam slowly upgrade upgrade upgrade
dual stack and it will be okay you
really will start making your budgets
like yesterday because the quicker you
get in front of this about off you're
going to be and the more experience you
have and let's well the more marketable
you'll be also that's not going away
there's no more v4 space left so jump on
and as soon as you can
that's it thank you thanks guys