all right cool so hi everyone I'm gonna
start a little bit early and though it's
not quite half past yet but I've got
quite a lot of content to go through and
I wanted to make sure that we finish on
time so I'm going to be talking about
red team pepper buzzword but more
specifically we wouldn't be talking
about converting experiences and jobs
and projects experiences that we've all
gained from doing projects etc right and
into tools that we can use in the
industry as security professionals more
specifically I think the tour title I
gave was a perspective on you know
research and from an offensive security
perspective
I'm Vincent you your speaker for today
all right this isn't on okay we go all
right so what's the talk about right
it's about writing tools mainly but more
specifically the reasoning behind
writing tools right and the some of the
ideas that I've had and the ways I come
about having new ideas to do new types
of research and the process I go through
so it's to aim its aim to help people
are looking to do research to understand
the process I go through to make these
tools happen and make my research happen
and some of the results from the
research that I've done and the benefits
that we we can obtain from doing the
research it's gonna be more about
getting started in research to my
specific journey to share that
experience with you all so if you're
interested in writing your own tools you
can maybe learn adapt on some of my
experiences to help yourself
you know get started it's not a rock
star talk it's no I don't have any zero
days to share today but you know I hope
that everyone can gain a bit of insight
here because I've heard a lot of people
in the industry where you know I always
get questioned about hey I want to do
some research where do I get started
right I want to marry a new tool watch
what can I do and this is aimed to help
low tech there those people out there
that I want to wanted to get started so
first of all Who am I I'm Vincent you
I'm a consultant at science security in
Hong Kong we start around the year and a
half ago now and
I've got a bunch of certificates grass
certified I've got osep oversee ECT PS
quite recently because as a boy I play
around with the labs on LinkedIn and
Twitter as well so if you want to reach
out viola channels to ask any questions
I'm happy to chat with anyone as well so
red teaming right it's become a buzzword
all sales guys using it everyone talks
about red teaming these days but yeah we
use the word red teaming and it you know
attract a lot of attention in the
security industry well essentially I
like to think of it as like when we do
that red teaming engagement the whole
idea is just to understand how well our
security investments are doing right
we've put a lot of money and time into
implementing security in our
organizations we want to understand you
know how well are we doing where has it
been its goal of protecting our
organization or are we now more
difficult to hack and there's the
process of simulating the footsteps of
an attacker
we simply according to the cyber kill
chain quite frequently nowadays and
that's quite useful and as we'll see
later on in the talk as to how I select
my types of research to do and the
result would be to learn you know from a
back of a red team would be to know the
strengths and weaknesses of your
organization when defending against the
unknown because if you're always
defending against things that you know
about then how do you know you can
defend something against something like
you haven't met before and it's aim to
address those types of concerns so we
need tools and research everywhere I say
red teaming here it's not just specific
to red teaming right so if we're red
teaming a car from this perspective
right we're trying to break into this
car we might look at different aspects
right like the wheels for example or the
window or the headlights or even the
cloud abyss connected to the cloud in
some way all the internet right
we might even look at the driver or
someone let's do maintenance on the
character we might rank it in that way
through other avenues and then I see
pentesting was more like looking at just
the wheels right but in more detail in
more sophistication but you know there's
benefits to both approaches and the red
team approach and I've always been able
to see more you know from a
outside-the-box perspective and from a
penetration testing perspective of being
able to look at specific components in
more detail
- but the the takeaway from these slides
are basically regardless of what your
day-to-day role is and what types of
exposure you get in the security
industry there are areas where you can
always contribute in with your own
research and with writing your own tools
and and you know it will benefit
everyone everyone else as well so in my
opinion there's the following types of
research you know it's like the rock
star level where people finding O'Day is
fuzzing and all of that good stuff
finding CV ease all the deep tech stuff
I'm not going to be talking about what
as much in this talk I'm going to try
and focus on more of like the ad hoc
research type stuff you know we find the
new area like we're interested in we
want to quickly see whether we can
leverage something from that new area of
research or developing tools fill out
research as well so I'll be focusing
more on the latter two so the tools are
really important regardless of what your
role is or what profession you're in you
know if I if my laptop broke today and I
needed to take it apart to you know
start looking at the internals this try
and fix it you know I could open up the
case in a number of ways where I could
get hammer and smash it open but let my
laptop won't look very good right
afterwards or I can actually choose a
screwdriver that's designed for the task
at hand and I think the takeaway is when
we have more tools we can make it more
consistent the way we do things and we
can also you know we can professionalize
the way we do things and make sure that
we're less prone to mistakes where we
make the task get a lot more efficient
and easier to to complete and so before
we had Salter this is an example of one
of the tools I wrote a couple years ago
so we know there's like a PowerShell
command for example the top here we know
this is quite easily detectable by
antivirus right and back in the day when
we wanted to change up and break
signatures in instance static files we
had to and start off the skate in the
text etc and maybe every time we had to
make a new payload we'd go and edit the
text manually or even script up elements
of it and we'd have something quite
simple and but it'll do the job right
it's a
fix it or work and then after we created
tools all we had to do was run one tool
against that code and then we'll have a
new output every time and it'll be
consistent I'll be less prone to
mistakes I'll have less syntax errors
for example and my code will still work
and it will do the job and it's tried
and tested too it works every time and I
can add additional complex features
which I'll show in a bit as well but
before we go into I want to go over you
know so how do I actually decide what I
want to research right and what to
research one way I do it is by looking
at the cyber kill chain so when doing
like a Red Team engagement it's like the
reconnaissance varies weaponization
exploitation you know whether it's
persistence and then you know actual
movement in the organization or actions
and objectives a bit more and target
specific in those cases but I've always
focused more on the earlier stages so
the reconnaissance and weaponization in
command and control phases I've written
tools I Dom linked linked into my in for
reconnaissance of doing a weaponization
bit shoot like cactus or morph HD and
weaponized so cactus torch was based off
from James for tools and research
previously which I tried to make work
and we can use it as like implants and
payload commanding control you know
around domain fronting or subdomain
takeovers so I pick things like quiet
I know that I can apply straightaway
into my day-to-day job and that's how I
pick research so it's a pretty good way
to if you're designing on some into
research you can pick a specific step in
the cyber kill chain and then find
something that might interest you that
you can look into I'm from a penetration
testing perspective you know I've done a
whole bunch of things as well this isn't
very specific but if you are doing a pen
test for example on a specific
technology or web application right you
might be doing you know one of the
vendors outside even in the technology
boots right if you do in their web
application you might find specific
vulnerabilities or even let's say you
finally use an enumeration book that's
time-based right and so you put in the
username and it you know there's a
different delay time if the username is
correct or incorrect
you can write up a tool that can do a
lot for that specific technology wrote
and you can make like repeatable every
time and you can share that tool and
then everyone else can have that
repeatable effects and we can enumerate
user names from application and it's
about you know applying and finding
areas that you can write a quick tool
for in your specific area of research or
day to day roles I think and I never
think I hear quite a lot when that you
know so someone's come to me and they're
asking hey what area of research can I
do I give him some idea and then they're
like hey I'm not a developer sure I'm
not a developer I try and shy away from
it as well and you know I'm not a great
coder for example so a lot of my code is
just patched together it works it's not
beautiful code I'm not the best Python
programmer in the world
you know I patch it all together and it
worked people give new code updates and
official optimize my code for example
and that's because I share my code out
there and people are get other sets of
eyes and people can contribute so like I
said but if the code is somewhat
readable if you make it somewhat
documented and readable and
understandable people will actually
contribute to your code that you push
out and they'll keep it up to date a
little add new features etc but more
importantly keeping it up to date as
we'll see with one of the tools that I
wrote the login process broke quite
recently and the community decided to
submit fixes quite useful a quick quick
slide just to break it off a little bit
for me oh thank you I'm plugging the USB
into my own device okay right nothing
everything all right cool so just to
break off the slides a little bit for
the rest of the talk I'm going to go
over a few case studies of tools I've
written in the past I'll go over the
sort of idea as to why I chose that
piece of research and how I went about
doing it and the process behind it and
the some of the results and benefits we
gained from it
so morph HDA that has anyone seen this
tool before or used it before right if
not I'll go over it now anyways but yeah
more fish tear was a tool I wrote a
couple of years ago because I hid the
idea where they say files are actually
used why
often for infecting machines as a
malware infection vector so HTML
applications can run JavaScript vbscript
etc inside these fouls and it's a
commonly used vector a lot of people use
it you might generate it for our
Metasploit for example or a couple
strike three and work back cetera
there's a variety of ways to get these
payload cells but the thing is it's in
the public space for it so a lot of
defenders will be writing signatures for
these things right really dumb
signatures what might just find the word
PowerShell with like VB script in the
same file right that sort of thing but
what we what I found was like we know
there's a common way to fix this issue
but I just obfuscating the strings
within that file but when your other
Skating strings in that file like I said
before if you're going into the file
every time and trying to change up the
code or you know just tight pack code
yourself and mess mess with it a little
bit it gets really complicated and
you're more prone to errors you know it
can break if you're you know you have to
test it every code change sort of thing
and it might be six months later before
you have to do another payload right or
even a year later and you don't remember
that syntax and you have to go back to
VB script syntax you know it's a dot or
a plus or a or a ton symbol to
concatenate strings that type of thing
and you might not necessarily want to be
fiddling with that when you're on an
engagement and the time pressure so you
know like I said it's time consuming to
do and also humans are not really good
at being random right I can keep copying
pasting the same command to you know add
more in the in the file but I'm not good
at being random at all and a computer
can just randomly generate this for me
and I can have custom obfuscation per
campaign if I'm doing a whole bunch of
phishing campaigns and I could generate
you know maybe 50 payloads if I want to
send everyone else's every single person
different payload for example and I can
add fake code paths you know I can add
benign code that can just make it a lot
bit more difficult to read than
different code streams so if someone's
trying to step through the code it gets
a lot more difficult for them so if
you're a bit lost right now
the key takeaway is you know
this was just a few days ago when I scan
this just to make sure and see what it
looks like nowadays but you know before
before you do any obfuscation whatsoever
it's 26 engines we'll find the static
strings in the in the script or it
that's about half of the virus all
engines but immediately if there's no
Sun boxing well you just don't wait for
the Sun box to work yet but there's
around two detections on virus talk
after the processing get through the
tool three is later since I wrote the
tool so I wrote it around three years
ago and at that time it was zero
detections and now it's two so you know
pretty good after three years it's still
not very detected and it's still usable
so it's not like the tools gone out now
right you can't use it at all
so there is a long term benefit of
writing tools as well it's actually
simpler than you might think right you
might look at a tool and I've had people
ask this in candidate interviews as well
all right have you heard of the tool
morph HDA how does it work right can you
explain how it works how was it
bypassing a TV and is actually simpler
than you might think it's like four
steps pretty much the first steps to
read the file in the payload in and then
pass the text of interest list different
sections within the file and then just
process the text transform the text
change the code up and then just write
it back out as a foul you know it's just
the simple weed process a little bit and
write the file it's a lot more simple
and learn you know some people make it
out to be but if you're lost his is a
quick demo just to see what the tool
does so this is the morph hdthe all is
it gonna start or maybe it's starting
okay there we go yeah there's a bit of a
delay so you know we begin by just
generating HTML applications straight
out of COBOL stroke detected by I pretty
much and a lot of antivirus engines like
I said before 26 out of 52 it's still
pretty good I suppose and you can still
bypass something's but majority like
people are using semantic or McAfee etc
learn you want to bypass a lot here I
run morph HDA with the Explorer mode so
this is another mode that I implemented
because our a default Pichet files born
out of a HTML application container
where if you see like running powershell
that might be suspicious right you can
find my insists this mom for example and
learn the process spawn chain but here
it makes it spawned out of explorer now
after reading the tour get a whole bunch
of office gated code and it writes it
out to pound out hitched here and here
I'm just comparing the payloads a little
bit so previously you could see words
like W script got shell and PowerShell
so immediate flags to a defender and you
can immediately see oh it's a PowerShell
payload but if we generate this then it
gives the defender a little bit more
work to play with they might have the
Sun box it to find out where its
connecting out to you know what is it
it's a PowerShell payload what is it
right and they can do a bit more
analysis it gives a it gives the blue
team a bit more work to play with if
you're doing it in a simulator the top
and most important of all after you do
all of the processing you have to still
make sure the payload works right so I'm
just gonna bring it in this unboxer just
to make sure like it's still running and
I still have the full payload working
waiting for the Sun watts to get
infected it takes a little while the
internet was quite slow in the hotel
when I was recording this but yeah we've
got 2 or AC 2 and you know it's around
twenty twelve megabyte file it converted
it from around you know maybe like 50
kilobyte 50 bytes or something even IV
know how long it was but but yeah it
you know it's had loads of fake code
streams changed up the text you know
added arithmetic expressions etc just to
you know mess with a AVL but so the sort
of like key benefits from this tool I
wrote where it was what we can now
reduce the time needed to obfuscate
these payloads if I needed to make fifty
or if I wanted to make a hundred even
because every single target I'm
targeting I want to give him a little
specific instance of a payload so it
looks completely different then I can do
a lot now as well I don't have to spend
half an hour doing it manually and the
complexity and sophistication of these
payloads have increased right like
before the blue team could have just
looked at the script and saw that
PowerShell command and they knew all
right is PowerShell can write it in the
report now for the incident response but
now they have to do a little bit more
maybe you have to run it in a sandbox we
look at in Wireshark or actually try and
find write a script to pass through the
obfuscation so you know it adds a bit
more skill so they have to do a bit more
of an exercise when fighting against
these types of payloads in a attack
simulation so we're increasing the sort
of like value for our customers as well
all right onto the second talk so the
second talk I wrote was a I'm going to
talk about is LinkedIn and my int so we
know in a lot of attack simulation
engagements we do fishing right and
fishing is one way that we know a lot of
adversaries are breaking into
organizations we've always been getting
employee names and details from social
media like LinkedIn in since moving to
Hong Kong and the mainland China area
I've realized what a lot of people don't
actually use LinkedIn they use another
social media that's mobile based called
my mine and so I've written tools for
both of these types of sort of social
media platforms so I can target you know
more people and get names for more
employees so layers myself like
injection points to where I did this
sort of research and made this tool and
actually previously you know when we
wanted to do lists we might have to fire
up burp for example and then go through
Google and then loop through pages and
next Rapids and then you know pass a
little bit or go through LinkedIn and do
the
you know it was it was a bit of a hacky
process but actually LinkedIn is a lot
more simpler than you might think once
again it's it's it's a Python script it
basically connects to LinkedIn logged in
you know as you would in a browser gets
a session token' connects to LinkedIn
once again looks for your company of
interest that you're interested in and
then you know gets the employees passes
freely employees extracts their names
and details from the responses reformats
it all and puts it into a nice report
and sort of format and then output it to
a text file great so we'll see a demo of
that in a moment
or my aunt's right so my my my was a
little bit different they have they
don't really have a web application they
say they have more of a just a mobile
app and the difference here was learned
I'd have to play with them all that
lapped intercept the API and make it all
work it isn't that much more difficult
if you've done much mobile testing
before learned all it is is setting a
web property on your mobile phone and
actually using the application to get
all the api's that you'd need to connect
it so similarly you log into the API
like you've extracted from the mobile
application then connect to that social
media network find that company name
once again get live employees even
better on my mind I found out that you
could just dump 50,000 employees all at
once if he wanted to so you don't where
as on LinkedIn it was restricted to
around a thousand employees I will look
for the pages once again pass it all and
then spit it out in a HTML template so
there's a quick demo of LinkedIn just to
show you what it does and saw the
benefits if you're not quite aware from
just meet like listening to me so I've
run the LinkedIn tool here I'm just
gonna use uber as a example I always use
it because I've got a book about you
going on so it's not as sensitive so I
fill in some fields you know until today
it still works pretty well and we can
see it's extracting employees the hotel
Wi-Fi was a bit slow so I've speeded up
the video a little bit here we'll see it
start shooting through in the moment
so yeah here it's extracting a lot of
employees is spitting out some error
messages for people that don't have
photographs on LinkedIn that let's point
the the tools finished and that was
within the three minutes maybe and I'm
able to get roughly a thousand employees
off LinkedIn get a nice HTML report
template which I can view in those nice
photographs and the job the location I
get a lot of Hong Kong contacts because
my I'm in Hong Kong right now so it
gives me people in the same proximity of
people in the same network you can
actually specify specific location
you're interested in and you can get
employees for that specific location
I've got a CSV file as well for the
people that want to cut out those emails
for example and put it into other tools
it's for processing so you might put
into a phishing framework or into a
brute-forcing tool for example and you
can use these as well
so once again we're reducing the time
necessary to perform a repetitive tasks
that we doing across many engagements
you know if you're spending less time
finding employees of an organization
you're actually spending more time doing
something else right what will that be
for you know doing reconnaissance for
other social media or you know finding
breach passwords maybe a lot sort of
thing you so you're spending more time
on other aspects as opposed to looking
for employees that might take hours if
in some cases and it's less confusion
now there's one go-to tool before there
were a lot of other tools some light use
LinkedIn api's some light used like
other methods to get to getting
employees maybe from Google but now you
just got one ghost at all and you can
just you know you know it works and it
does the job so yeah it reduces like
complexity alright so now for the third
one I'm gonna give a quick disclaimer
I'd rather if people don't record this
if possible or at least don't share it
publicly so yeah just keep it within the
room if possible a Microsoft or are you
aware with the issues I spoke to like a
senior as your p.m. they were like we
know about the issue we're not I don't
know it was like half a year ago I or
even up to a year ago and they
don't care so I'm just going to talk
about it and you know please just no
video and photographs as possible so
it's all public knowledge flow so you
can actually figure this out as well
so subdomain takeovers using the cloud
are quite popular
we know Asher is like really vulnerable
right now Amazon CloudFront that used to
be vulnerable but leave I did a lot haul
a lot of precautions in place where
they're validating your domains before
they allow you to use it now in Amazon
Alibaba is over clouds as well in the
local proximity in the Asia region are
also vulnerable to these types of
attacks I looked at it quite you know
briefly not not as much in depth because
I sure has a lot of good stuff for so I
play with Astro quite a bit in this bit
we're gonna I'll go over what a
subdomain takeover is so it's basically
one alright let's say ticket exchange
that Microsoft comm this is one that
I've identified as being viable you can
even if you've got your laptop right now
you can actually dig for it yourself and
you can see lights in the vulnerable
state so in step one where if you do you
do the dig request rate you'll see that
it actually resolves to the C name of
ticket exchange dot Traffic Manager down
there
and then in step two you can see that it
doesn't resolve to an a record so if no
one wants to be ticket exchange to
traffic manager yeah so why don't we be
like ticket exchange that traffic
manager doesn't it so you know I'll take
over it I'll be like yeah and what
happens is but even even after we do
that like research right we I don't want
to just know that ticket exchange that
traffic manager net is vulnerable right
I want to know Ana larger-scale
what companies are vulnerable what other
organizations of what other domains are
vulnerable and I'll go over that as well
so what I do is I take a large list of
traffic manager net instances because I
know traffic manager uses a starlet
traffic management net and then I'll
loop through all of them and I can use a
tool that subject you can run on github
and it will loop through all of them and
I'll tell you whether it's morrible to
subdomain take over there is a lot of
false positives here and sometimes
you'll see with the traffic manager
instance I just talked about I've
reserved control over it so you can't
just go over and take control over its
head
I'm talking about it but in that case
where you know if someone's already
taking over it but they're not enabling
it learn it will make it look like it's
still in the vulnerable state if you
just looking at the DNS record we've put
our own like private sort of like
research and way to do it to sort of let
me do that false positive route but I'm
not not going to share it here in this
presentation but what we can do is if we
can take that research and we can
automate it every morn for every few
weeks and have this alerting the
monitoring system we can alert off
specific domains or even compares the
vulnerable domains to elections have 1
million for example to assess the impact
etc and then give ourselves alert or you
know I can get email every month to say
these are the new ones that we found and
I can use that to help our customers if
our customers subdomain is vulnerable I
can use like in an engagement with learn
for weather like a pseudo waterhole
attack or in command and control if I
want to use the wrong domain for command
control or I can use it to fishable an
employee so you know I can do a lot as
well so they're like legitimate uses for
these things as well in in some of our
red team engagements if you lost as to
what's happening here is a quick demo
here's a sure Traffic Manager subdomain
take over here we're actually on Azure
just to show I mean though it's not fake
it's all not sure I've got a ticket has
changed got Traffic Manager garnett
already registered we're gonna dig it
again and ticket exchange but Microsoft
calm and we can see like there's
actually missing a records right so
there's no a record and then this pretty
much shows like it could be in the
vulnerable state it might not be an
injured person but we can register it in
traffic in Azure Traffic Manager so I've
registered it here and I've set an
endpoint light goes to I'd use take over
that mega court that ICU which I on and
then I can just manipulate like a record
to my own servers it's over good to get
changed at Microsoft calm there's no
content exists because it's not enabled
yet and then I go back out to the
overview but I can enable a profile
and we'll seal it actually quite quickly
if I dickly a records again the AC name
again we'll see that now it results to
my server so I've got control over this
domain at this point yeah it's not my
server plant page and all of the bug
bounties I do as well because learn it
it you know it doesn't damage the
reputation of the organization but here
for this proof-of-concept I'm just going
to type in some information I'm some
content some text refresh the page again
visit the website and we see we've got
control over Microsoft subdomain so if
you were a malicious attacker right
someone could use this for fishing you
know you can put it like an office 365
page on there for example where it learn
suddenly you you add a lot of trust for
employees I doing this type of research
don't generate SSL certs really like
high profile domains because the whole
stock team's gonna go after you so you
know you'll have some legal consequences
so just like you know be careful when
doing this type of research so you well
from the back of this research you know
ahead of time if your customers
vulnerable I found loads of banks
government entities across the world and
you know even even like national
railways companies that said they were
all vulnerable to this type of thing and
the shipment and logistic companies as
well so there's a lot of there's
actually quite a large exposure right so
if you can do this on the large scale
you can find out a lot of these
companies and then if the one of your
clients you can help them you can you
know provide this information to them
and you can simulate attacks that might
not have been possible if you didn't
have this knowledge you know watering
hole attacks have being quite hard to
simulate from a red team perspective
legally because we can't just compromise
a website on the internet and be lot
what web site right but whereas if you
find that your customers subdomain is
vulnerable you can use that tool and
maybe hold some content to them fish
their own employees and we'll the last
sort of like section I'm going to talk
about is as your app c2 so we know from
the previous case the dealer roger has a
lot of subdomain takeovers right and
Traffic Manager is really easy to play
with because you can just direct traffic
to a c2 server or a server let you
control whoever
but as your apps are a little bit more
you know you can host content on it but
we'll see like it's actually a little
bit more difficult I have to learn the
scripting languages like dotnet all
right fair enough PHP like I have to
learn how to write a web app in these
languages which if I'm on an engagement
you know quite giving me like 10 15 days
I don't have time to be messing around
with figuring out how I'm gonna stack
hosting content on this subdomain
takeover around on there and one of
their domains so what I've done is I've
just created a proxy in in Python where
it's just proxies traffic to a selected
the main or selected back-end a server
like you specify so what I did was I I
take the connecting client into the
azure app where I pass it for the
request I get the get request the
parameters the parameters in the URL
body and in etc and then the headers as
well the cookies and other headers if
you're using I don't know maybe I don't
recommend using the export we did for
header for example for you know
commanding control but if that was the
case then you need to make sure you
proxying a lot as well right and there's
a lot of other headers that might be of
interest as well and then I basically
just craft a new request to the target
location so my attacker control server
controlled server and then just send
that same request to my server get the
response and send it back out to the
connecting client so just access this
proxy between the as your app am I am I
am server so when the incoming request
comes in if I've got bad at PNG then
I'll just create a new request with that
same same information so basically just
mirror-like that same request for it
these are the some of the things that
you have to be concerned with when
writing this type of thing the host
header I stick it as my target server so
we'll see in the neck in the demo a bit
where I actually just configure and then
it'll proxy request to my server so if
you lost again here's a demo so I'm sure
your application command and control so
connect me dot Microsoft comm is
actually a domain I found I was
vulnerable to subdomain takeover once
again in as your websites right so
there's no a record you can see
missing but we've got this name in our
website we can go ahead and deploy an
application as that name and we can take
over a lot subdomain
so here I've created this Flast
application which just acts as the proxy
I set the target server to my attacker
control server I've run the application
it takes a little bit of time to deploy
so I speed up the video all right so it
takes quite a few minutes so we're
speeding up rapidly like 15 times the
speed and then you know it's doing all
the deployment stuff it's pushing out
this application on to larium
application cloud after it's finished
deploying we can then visit the website
but we'll see light it doesn't work
there's a 404 website not found I
figured but actually you can't use like
the free version and they've been
charging me quite a bit money for doing
this so I've had to go and upgrade my as
your account so what ended but here I'm
cloning Microsoft's website for example
just there's a POC so I'll clone that i
refresh it again it still doesn't work
because it's not configured correctly
yet I go to a sure again click on the
application services click on that
instance go to custom domains and
because it's already pointing to the
correct location I can type in connect
me Microsoft calm here I'm validate like
this this domain actually works go down
and I can add it as a custom domain now
if i refresh this website again we'll
see like connect me that microsoft come
actually host a website that looks like
Microsoft's web site right on my own
server but the key point of this was to
make it work for command and control so
I'm going to generate a malware
executable here and then run it in the
sandbox just to make sure I'm actually
connecting to connect me up microsoft
calm and it's actually working this
two-way see too
so here's the sandbox I'm just gonna
paste it in I've got wyshak for anything
so we can monitor like the situ is
actually working
I don't you take CCP I figure that I
don't want any I don't want to make any
SSL certs under Microsoft's domain so
see two channels working I checked over
and coal box straight to make sure like
the to like force to a situ is working I
censored that a little bit because I
didn't want to give out too much about
my CT channel so yeah if I do a
screenshot it will work because it's the
to two-way command and control working
and to the connect meet up Microsoft
calm and we can see there's a screenshot
of a lot of lot of lot of the Sun box
and it's a bit cut off because I'm high
DPI in the sandbox and I didn't
screenshot and the in the right
application but if we look at the DNS
records we can see that you know it's
actually going to connect me that
Microsoft icon yeah so by doing this
research I'm now able to have command
control over subdomain takeovers like
I've run Azure applications and a lot of
actual applications were actually used a
lot more than traffic manager and a lot
of banks and you know like even
financial organizations are actually
vulnerable to these types of takeovers
I've found the bank in Hong Kong for
example that was vulnerable and you know
I communicated these findings to them as
well
but you know if it was a client then you
might be able to use one of the
subdomains to to use it as C 2 and if
you're the blue team and you see this
right in your dashboard you're like hey
there's one of my you know our cloud you
means get compromised or something right
so you know adds a bit of an interesting
situation to to the attack and one can
increase the sophistication a little bit
so yeah that's about it
but the key takeaways are I think it's
really important to decide on what type
of research you want to do I like I said
I normally pick it from the cyber kill
chain somewhere in that kill chain if
possible
so I pin know I can directly apply it
again to my work you could do the same
as well and a lot of the tooling
I write is you know it's hacked together
there's no fancy GUI exit sure there's
no you know I'm not a GUI application
guy I don't write much bootstrap code so
I can't make it look fancy where it's
not got a dashboard but it works it does
the job and I think people shouldn't shy
away from writing tools even if it's a
simple concept I've had people say why
are you writing at all to do a few DNS
lookups but to me right it works it does
the job every time and they don't have
to remember those exact things to look
up hence why it's going to be useful and
I always Sheila cooling if possible the
community will help you evolve and
update your tools as well so thanks a
lot I'm Vincent you find me on Twitter
if you're interested in to meet the mo
some things ask about anything if you've
got any questions now I can take it as
one if we've got time yeah might have
been a bit faster no okay
yeah okay
[Applause]