good to go alright hello everybody my
name is Isaac Dawson I'm CEO and founder
of link I we do continuous a discovery
for external facing websites and
infrastructure so just a quick word
about who I am
as mentioned CEO and founder prior to
that I worked for a company called
Verico that did dynamic and binary
static analysis I was the lead for the
research and development for doing
research on attack strings trying to
automate like sequel injection but make
it so it didn't actually destroy all of
our customers data so trying to do
things at scale safely prior to that I
was a application security consultant
for Symantec and at stake overall about
19 years of experience professional
experience in information security so
real quick I just want to give a rundown
to what this is this talk is about so
the asset discovery problem what is it
why should your organization to have
some sort of asset discovery program in
place how the industry has really
changed in the past ten years or so and
how automation has really moved
everything forward much faster than
before and I want to cover how to build
your own program within your
organization so if in fact if you are a
bug bounty person you can probably take
the same information and use it for your
bug bounties but for an organization you
may want to use this information to
build your own program as well and I
want to cover the the benefits of having
one as well as not having one and then
some final remarks so to really set the
stage for what the importance of having
an asset discovery program in place is
let's use this fictitious company called
I don't whatever company comm so you
have your your standard firewall with
your web application servers the
databases in the backend now this is
probably highly monitored and highly
secured quarterly scans monthly scans
everything's going great but then
marketing needs to set up some website
and they have a pretty tight deadline
let's say maybe two weeks a month that
they needed get a website up it needs to
be able to take information from
customers but they can't really put it
inside of the the protected and
monitored network so they decided to put
it into the cloud it still needs to be
able to update information
in the customer database or have some
sort of connection back to the the
infrastructure on the back end now maybe
this marketing team is smart and they
work with the security and operations
team they got a firewall in place
everything's patched of things looking
great so campaign time launches users
sign up buy products whatever
now after a certain period of time this
site knows is no longer needed it's no
longer used anymore the campaigns over
but let's say six months to a year out
someone starts probing this organization
so maybe they're trying to find
vulnerabilities sequel injection and in
the the web servers for company comm but
things again our quarterly scans secured
so they start probing across four
different sub domains and they come
across this marketing website now it's
been six months to a year
it's basically forgotten hasn't been
patched hasn't been updated and it could
be compromised
so from here they really have two
options one if there is a pipe back to
the protected and infrastructure they
could use that or they could try to take
credentials from this marketing website
and reuse it on other parts of the
organization now this may seem
hypothetical but I've already heard
about three or four cases during this
caucus conference for people like yeah
my marketing site got compromised a
person from duo just mentioned it
yesterday as well and I've been on
customer calls where we give them a list
of assets and that they didn't know they
had and wow that sites two years old I
had no idea what I was sitting there or
it was a developer's virtual machine
that they stood up and they forgot about
it we're just gonna shut that off right
now so these things absolutely do happen
so let's use another example of if you
don't have an asset discovery program
some of the risks or issues that you're
going to run into so let's take an
example incident where there's a new
exploit that was released for apache so
immediately you're going to have some
questions how many my websites are
affected or who do i ask to get that
information is that information accurate
and up-to-date what versions do I have
is this applicable to me and even is
this site even under my control
maybe I'm outsourcing to a marketing
company and it's using my domain but
it's not something that I can control so
now I have to communicate with that
third part
to get them to patch so all of these
things are going to take time to answer
and if you don't have a list of assets
that's up to date and there's an
emergency you're going to be having some
problems you're going to be working
against the the the incident time wise
so the question I want to ask is how
long would it take you to answer these
questions so maybe a week if you have to
if you have to communicate with third
parties maybe a month all this time
there's an exploit that is being
exploited across the internet so the
second question would be is how long can
you afford to not have answers to these
questions so to make things even worse
now we have more much more than before
like 10-15 years ago we have this
changing landscape where developers are
bringing machines online we have new
hosts that are coming online these hosts
use different programming languages so
now you have to lay out two levels of
things that you need to keep up-to-date
with the operating system level patches
the language that's being used patches
and these applications have their own
sets of dependencies so maybe they're
using jQuery maybe they use a Redis
back-end is that Redis back-end that
just got turned on is that maybe
unauthenticated and sitting on the
internet so these systems coming online
and offline you also have dependencies
on top of dependencies because maybe all
these systems aren't running in your
infrastructure maybe it's running an
Amazon or Microsoft Azure so if let's
say Azure has an outage how many your
websites are going to be affected if you
don't have this list your inventory list
and it's not being completed and
something updated again these are
questions that you would want to have
answered before an incident occurs TLS
certificates is another great example if
you're not keeping up to date with your
TLS certificates when they expire and
they do expire your parts of your
organization will no longer be
accessible if it's an API system
maybe mobile client only goes through a
certain API gateway and if that
certificate expires now your mobile
clients don't work another kind of
concern with this changing landscape is
if depending on
size of your organization cannon
probably has this issue with mergers and
acquisitions where they're bringing on
completely new organizations and they
have to migrate them over to their
systems but that's going to take six
months to a year to two years for that
to actually occur if ever so you have
all these systems that you need to be
concerned with and if you don't have
this list it's just going to be
extremely hard for you to really to
prioritize your security programs so I
want to take a quick look at the the
industry response and how technology and
processes have kind of changed and where
we're heading now I think most of us in
the room would agree if any of you deal
with product security or any sort of
product development that everything is
moving towards continuous automation so
we have C ICD and now thankfully we also
have security trying to integrate itself
within this pipeline so with these new
automation routines we have security
trying to integrate itself at very
specific points but overall everything
is moving towards a continuous system
because it just it increases the
productivity and it increases that the
features that we can push to our
customers
and continuous security is becoming a
large part of that B and there's this
concept of continuous assurance where
you create a baseline of what you think
is secure you monitor it maybe new
features are released and you need to
adjust your your baseline and it's just
this model of continuous assurance so
all this is telling us is that we're
moving into this this era of continuous
security and I would I want to say that
probably within the next five years or
so we're going to have most of our
security testing being done continuously
it's going to become completely
automated the days of organizations
using the excuse of you can't scan
production I'm think are coming to an
end because guess what we're getting
scanned all the time everywhere so it
only makes sense for us to utilize these
security tools because attackers are
using it against us anyways and a lot of
this really has come out from bug
bounties and I don't want to say bug
bounties have really changed the game
but I think they've really exposed what
the game is to the
like that we are moving towards this age
of being scanned constantly attackers
are creating maps of our external facing
infrastructure they're using this
information to build up lists of assets
technologies dependencies there may not
be an issue today but now they have a
list to see if something occurs in the
future that they can use against you and
bug bounties again I think I've been
really good at exposing this and showing
that bug bounty people have a higher
chance of getting paid their bounties if
they automate a lot of their tasks so
they're moving towards this everybody's
in fact there was a talk earlier today
where two gentlemen were talking about
how they were automating their bug
bounties programs to find low-hanging
fruits so this basically means just
scanning for all the easy stuff so that
they can focus on the more critical high
level stuff but those even those
low-hanging fruits are usually critical
vulnerabilities whether it's SSR f or
xxe injection or any of these other
types of attacks they can be used to
break in easily in an automated fashion
and that is probably the last thing you
want you would probably prefer someone
having to take the time to try to break
in your organization than having a
script do it so I want to talk about
maybe building your own asset discovery
program I don't know how many of you in
here are in that position where you're
able to build something like this but if
you're not you can use this information
to talk to your security team or your
operations team and I really want to
talk about why so one of my beta testers
I was talking to them and I'm like so
why did you use my service or whatever
and they basically said I don't want any
surprises I don't want to find out that
this marketing site had been hacked and
for two years and I didn't even know
that service existed I just don't want
to be surprised I want to know what's
out there what level of patches or what
versions of software I'm running and I
think that's are probably a really good
use case for a lot of these these
organizations they just don't want to be
surprised so if you don't have an asset
discovery program I would say probably
the the one of the largest issues is
it's really hard to prioritize your
security and operations per
so patch management has been flying
around a lot here at this conference and
if you don't have a list of your assets
well you can't patch them and I really
feel like the first step in any security
programming is knowing what you have so
you know how to protect it and if you
don't have that it's going to be
extremely hard you're gonna be working
against the tide to really try to keep
your systems at a good baseline of
security another kind of issue that I
see is more of an organizational issue
where there's gonna be finger-pointing
and blame and I've seen this in
organizations in the past where if
something let's say the marketing site
does get compromised what people are
gonna start blaming a marketing well
it's not really marketing this fault it
was everybody's fault because security
forgot about it marketing forgot about
it so if you have this list in place and
you know who the owner of it is it's
much easier to work together to really
solve these types of issues and going
back to the point of if a incident
occurs or there's a new attack that came
out it's really time consuming to answer
these a lot of these questions and
that's not something you want to be
working on when you're in emergency mode
you want to be remediating your issues
as soon as possible not trying to answer
where my websites and the benefits of an
asset discovery program I mean it's been
pretty clear like you're able to answer
a lot of these questions you're gonna
have proper prioritization Incident
Response becomes much easier once you
know where things are who the owner is
what versions they're at and it really
helps you determine your third-party
dependencies and risks I don't know how
many of you here are familiar with the
source composition analysis that's
getting more and more popular where
organization product teams and
development and developers in general
want to know all of their their
dependencies so it's like a third party
chain supply management risk issue you
can also do that from the outside as
well because there's tools that allow
you to determine certain versions or
what software you're running from the
outside so it really helps you build up
a list of your dependencies in there and
their risks because there are going to
be vulnerabilities that are going to be
released that you do need to know about
and you do need to know if they affect
your services and products in particular
other kind of as non-security related
issues that really a passive discovery
program helps with the system health
checks TLS certificates is more of an
availability issue latency issues if you
have a good program in place that's
doing continuous monitoring you can get
good read back for feedback for how
latent your requests are so how do we
get started well first off you're gonna
work with your teens this is well it's
something that could be done by just the
security team I wouldn't really
recommend it you really want to get
input from all your teams especially
again if you're a product development
organization so one thing that I've seen
work in the past is to have product
teams submit their information or
product team owners someone where you
can delegate to say okay you're creating
this product it's running these servers
with these dependencies and these
dependencies are at these versions so
you get them to Delhi you delegate that
information so you can collect it in a
single shared single source of truth
neither maybe it's a document or a wiki
someplace where people can update it
with their information you probably want
to talk to your sales and marketing
teams see what websites they know about
what what are they used on a day to day
basis extracting information from logs
like syslog if you're using AWS there's
cloud watch is a great resource to be
able to pull out which domains and which
sites you're using as well as obviously
that the list of instances that you have
probably the best one the most bang for
your buck is just talking to your your
system operators to get DNS records from
their DNS servers a lot of them let you
export it if you can export those DNS
records to use that information again
put it into a shared document or wiki
and security reports hopefully you guys
are scanning your networks on quarterly
basis at least you can use that
information again to build up this list
so let's talk about some techniques this
is kind of just a very high-level look
of some of the techniques you're gonna
want to use to to really extract them
once you have that list provided from
the internal let's take a look at it
from the outside now so techniques such
as doing DNS lookups if you have a list
of IP ranges just do reverse IP address
lookups using the tool like dig
extracting host names from certificates
so a lot of certificates these days will
be you can apply for a single
certificate that matches multiple
domains and sometimes you can use that
information to extract additional
subdomains you did not know about zone
transfer are scraping host names from
websites is another big one where you
just load up the web page and then you
just take all the links out and
sometimes it can include subdomains zone
transfers I don't know if anybody here
is familiar zone transfers from DNS it's
amazingly still effective I'm surprised
how many sites or DNS systems are still
configured to allow zone transfers from
anywhere and second insect 3 walking so
n SEC is a called like next-gen security
or next security basically it's a DNS
SEC record type where you can think of
it almost like a link to list where it
has a link to the next record so if you
have a company com it'll have another
record for bida company comm and see and
you can literally just walk through the
DNS I don't know why I was implemented
for for DNS SEC but they realize their
mistake and they started to work on
insect 3 which now hashes them but
there's ways you can still do off
offline cracking of the hashes to again
just walk through the domains there's if
you're more interested in these types of
attacks or these types of techniques
just Google n SEC walking you'll find
tons of hits and then brute forcing to
find subdomains so this is like you take
WWE company or comm and then web comm
and then VPN comm so you have a word
list that you kind of iterate through to
find all these different sites
permutations is pretty similar except
for your permit ating on various aspects
of a domain so if you find web one
company com you're gonna try to calm
three calm et cetera so depending what
I've seen in past with certain
organizations is they have like naming
schemes so maybe they'll name one of
those their servers like red combi no
more blue comedy com
so if you have a initial list or initial
host name you're going to want to add
permutations of that naming scheme and
that will help you find sites in the
future
so one major really just a goldmine
information these days a certificate
transparency so major certificate issues
issuers submit anytime they issue a
certificate to a new company to the
certificate transparency servers which
lets for this conversation considered a
public database there's multiple servers
so there's I think there's like fifteen
or twenty now that you can basically go
to and literally query from index zero
give me all your certificates that have
been issued since 2017 or whatever so
the reason certificate transparency
exists is to really help organizations
kind of monitor to make sure that no one
is like say trying to issue google.com
certificate from let's say I don't know
Singapore so it's this way of monitoring
the the certificate sis the PKI system
to make sure that the bad things are not
happening the benefit is that anyone can
query this so these servers are open to
the Internet you can just if you know if
you have a d-- a certificate
transparency client you can just go
ahead and query it and pull out
information and there isn't a massive
just massive amount of data so this is
my data set right now i've been running
it for a couple months now i've got
about six terabytes of data with 19
billion records now a lot of these are
duplicates the again there's like 1520
servers so the certificates may or may
not be issued to each one of these
certificate transparency servers so
unfortunately got to collect them all i
would not recommend doing this there's
better ways of doing it which i'll talk
about in a second oh actually just to
show you what that data looks like
here's just a sample that i pulled out
from my dataset obviously that's way too
small let's bring up the magnifier so we
have inside it so I pull out very
specific data but it has the oil you
can't even see that just when I pulled
it out the server type it came from and
of course I can't move across here there
we go oh it's not following that's
annoying everyone so basically there's
just a lot of data that you can pull out
thank you
it's not even showing you I'm sorry
apologize wasn't looking that makes much
more sense so here we have the name of
the company we have certain certificate
properties that I've in particular
wanted to pull out you have the the
actual certificate CN or the common name
which you can pull out as well as other
verified DNS names inside of those as
well so for example cloud fair you when
cloud for issues a certificate it'll
actually do a bulk issue with multiple
domains inside of it so you'd me you'd
been need to be able to pull all that
information now but again it's just a
ton of really good information if you're
trying to find additional subdomains so
what services can we use to build out
our asset lists CRT shell or SH is a
free service that you can use from
Komodo what you just put in a domain
name query and it'll give you all your
subdomains pulled out from the
certificate transparency servers there's
things like hacker target which you put
in a domain name and it gives you all
the subdomains virustotal if you were if
your organization is large enough and
you have a s numbers or IP ranges you
can use these search tools to just put
in an IP address and I'll give you a
list back of all the ranges that exist
sometimes you can even put in company
names the last one blog rapid7 com is
it's a really great project by the
rapid7 team called open sonar where they
just do internet wide scans they do
internet wide DNS queries and you can
use that information in a a de Vos
Athena which allows you to search for it
so you can search for domains that are
specific to your organization so that
was kind of the passive acquisition
there's more of an active acquisition
that you can use the most popular these
days is OS a mass project definitely
highly room it we recommend checking
this one out it's written by Jeff Foley
again it's an OS project they have a lot
of the the the these systems are these
excuse me these links in here are
included in a mass so it'll do it
automatically for you
there's this service called search
stream from Khalid aughh which monitors
the certificate transparency servers in
real-time so what you can do is you can
just write up a quick client say you
want to match on your domains and then
have it basically alert anytime as
certificate is issued from search stream
for finding technologies used by your
assets you can use URL scanned at i/o so
this uses whap Eliezer on the back end
but what you do is you submit a URL it
goes to it takes a screenshot it takes
that screenshot and while it's loading
the page it actually extracts from
JavaScript all the the server
information the server headers
JavaScript versions that I can find
other things you probably want to do for
if you're creating your own active
acquisition program is for monitoring
expiring certificates I mean you could
just do this with an open SSL client if
you wanted to and just knock it out in a
bash script or you can use one of these
pre-made ones not too complicated some
other popular tools you got port scanner
zmapp very fast but only single ports so
I would recommend using probably masscan
if you want to do multiple ports unless
you literally are just want to scan your
entire organization for a single port
and map the tried and tested and true
it's slow but it gets the job done
sub the subdomain resolvers there's mass
DNS for name permutations you have alt
DNS so you can use all these tools in
combination but it is going to require
some scripting you could you're going to
need to either schedule this using cron
or some other type of scheduling system
to use a master to your enumerations you
use you create have to create a search
stream clients and get API keys for URL
scan and then you can start to build
your own little pipeline so the first
thing you're gonna want to do is to
parse public data records as I mentioned
certificate transparency is probably the
biggest one and the open sonar stuff you
can use AMS there's a a track feature
which allows you to do differentials
between scans so you can do actually
check the difference between them and
then you take that list of assets and
you load it into URL scan you can batch
submit them and then you can get the the
results for all your technologies and
dependencies as well as also take those
sites that responded
as a proper HTTP site to check
certificates and explorations now you
can take all this information and you
can post it to a shared document or a
wiki or if your if you your organization
uses slack you can post it to slack so
there's pretty much anything you can
really do and and I think what's one of
the more interesting things about
creating your asset discovery program is
you can really customize it any way you
want so if your organization's worried
about brand protection so people are
trying to register domains for typo
squatting or whatnot you can use again
if you have that list of initial domains
you can use tools such as DNS twist to
see if anybody's try to register domains
that look very similar to yours and you
can also put this within your search
stream client so you can say okay not
only do I want to know if new
certificates are issued for my domains I
want to see if people are trying to
issue certificates for domains that look
very similar to mine you can use
malicious compromised domain checks such
as Google's API for Safe Browsing you
could even script it up to do a curl
checks if you wanted to look for
specific files maybe there's one of your
site's gets compromised through an admin
panel and you want to check that all of
your sites don't have that admin panel
exposed you could script it up so some
other considerations IP addresses might
be useless this one thing that I first
really came to the conclusion of when I
built my own system that's over time
especially with content delivery
networks a lot of these host names are
just being there's a content delivery
network in front of it's called cloud
fronting or fronting where IP addresses
over time just don't really mean
anything anymore they they can't really
point to your site so if you're trying
to scan something with an old IP address
it's not going to point to your domain
anymore it's pointing to someone some
other organization if you're doing brute
force I think it's built into a mess but
I'm not positive wildcard DNS domains so
this is a domain if you send any type of
query to a subdomain it says yeah
there's a domain here it's not actually
true it's just responding yes to
everything so keep that in mind
and there's wildcard DNS checks so you
can you can use I think Google Chrome
does some sort of testing for it if you
look at their source code you can figure
it out
hosted services again like AWS and
whatnot you need to be careful scanning
these things AWS is can be pretty strict
about what's being scandal though
they've just recently
change their pen testing agreement to
allow you to scan your own
infrastructure which is great but I
would not recommend trying to scan from
their infrastructure also be careful and
gentle with hammering specific services
such as websites and DNS you're gonna
want to have some rate limiting in place
especially for DNS you might think the
DNS will be able to handle everything
but there's definitely some
organizations running some older
versions of DNS that are not able to
handle everything so always if you can
let people know that you're going to be
doing these types of activities before
you do it so they know who which which
people that communicate with if there's
an issue so that pretty much covers
everything I want to talk about I just
really want to drive home the point that
asset discovery is really no longer a
point in time it's not something you
just do once and just like hey I have an
asset list I'm done things are just
changing way too quickly way too often
you need to keep this list updated and
up to date so that if there is an
incident sibling something does occur
you have real-time answers for those
types of whatever that incident is and
honestly this is this is more of a
preventative type of system where you're
really just trying to keep things up to
date know where they exist know who to
communicate with and hopefully your
organization will be the better for it
and that's pretty much it thank you any
questions yes what's been the most
surprising benefit that a customers come
back with surprising benefits yes well I
would say probably knowing that there's
sites out there that they didn't know
was exposed that they could shut down
that probably the biggest one how about
in your experience I just say the same
yeah yeah and so he mentioned the other
day about costs so that's something I
hadn't thought about your actually if
you have these sites that are online for
two years you're burning money like
there's there's no reason for you to be
running that site and if you could just
shut it off you're saving money so
that's another benefit of having an
asset discovery program yeah we look for
expired SSL certificates Knox I care too
stuff's about advanced as sales tickets
but they're an indicator obsolescence
that's you have an update the SSL
certificate no one's luck no one's using
it yeah good point any other questions
great thank you he asked me to for his
risk crowd system wants you to go to
this website and sign up it's risk crowd
the risk crowd comm thank you