hello my name is Ben to dig report I am
currently a hawker pentesters
bounty hunter and researcher what I want
to call it I work at Hakka Hakka one as
a hacker personally i've also co-founded
a forum where we create content for
people that are new to the book party
scene and now for over 600 walnut
abilities I'm 90 plus companies on how
much more so today I want to talk about
recon I call it a little things it's an
addition of a talk that I Volusion down
last year so what do I do it mostly is
for self-improvement I wanted a way to
find Amit I'm passionate about that's
going to build my career there
networking with companies I've worked
with meeting engineers on the other side
in an adventure getting hired at hacker
1 and I've also get to work with cool
hackers like team on the right or on the
left you guys and I also like the
competition so my buddy and I we compete
on a daily basis - and we talk about
each other so every time I let him ask
me he posts the tweet and then
eventually on the next day when I pass
in and also who doesn't like to make
extra cash good goin ease if you guys
aren't familiar with bug bounties you
can sign up on any of the platforms
there's no contract or there's nothing
you just sign up
want to work with you find
vulnerabilities and you step into them
and even offer cash you get paid through
our couple Facebook and Google also do
their own PayPal as well there are other
platforms but I have a focus on hacker
one mostly because to have the higher
range payments and also have a lot more
targets and how that can happen
so recon the definition of recon from
the military perspective is figuring out
what's out there that's not controlled
by your family forces but as a hacker to
me it's understanding how the
application works what is being used to
build application finding all the
possible entry points whether that's all
the IP addresses on their subdomains
other acquisitions and everything that
pretty much they own and it's also
finding all those files and folders that
are left behind by developers and I
think I agree with this tweak a lot of
us spend a lot of time doing recon just
because we have a passion for it and
it's also a lot more fun than just
sitting there staying at the scene
application for the whole day so to give
you guys a little bit of an idea of what
we're going to talk about this would be
much more open up for an entire talk as
we go through each category I'll
highlight him we'll talk about it and
keep on moving on you know some point
we're also going to talk about how we
can do all this automated so you don't
have to be doing manually one by one
everything I put up here it's either on
my Twitter with github so you don't have
to worry about taking pictures if you
want to go for it I don't mind you but
if you don't want to focus on the
material there so asset discovery is the
first step of understanding what a
company is all about so for this portion
of the talk we're born
we find subdomains by brute force and
we're talking about difficut
transparency so asset discovery is again
we there's a bunch of tools out there
can do all of them if you'd like
and you feed it a directory directory
start a text file that has all these
words and keywords and supplements out
that been created by somebody else you
get a domain name it finds that and all
those summers that exist and gives you a
list of what did UNIX is if you find
that the open or a staging environment
you go out for that entire subdomain and
you find all the stuffing mines that are
behind it but all that stuff is boring
you can't find everything that's out
there if something has random characters
in it numbers the company name team name
you're never gonna find that is with
food forcing on this you have the four
million line text file and you do some
really cool stuff with it so I want to
avoid more in the directory the brute
forcing method for supplamine enforcing
to find those subdomains by using such
as an agent expense if you're not
familiar to get transparency there are
ton of databases out there we can pretty
much see every certificates been issued
to a company
the first one that I always look at I
enjoy using before they started charging
people for it was census now I get
thousand dollars a month for an API and
I don't feel like donating a thousand
dollars for an API key but we look at a
search and it gives you you can find a
ton of good stuff so as I mentioned
earlier you can't find something that's
a snapchat - amen - gateway with boot
forcing because there's no way you have
the word snapchat your word list
- now next so this is one day
certificate transparency becomes a
little bit easier to do it takes the
best time to go through the databases
I'm looking for rather than building a
tool that does all that for you
the other one is sure then if you're a
student you can get a new brush or
family I totally missed as a college
student I wish I knew but if you don't
have their colors you know any college
can buy one for 40 bucks and it's
probably one of the best investments you
can do as a hacker this for me I was one
of the best investments the good thing
about sure lenio you can pretty much go
through all the certificates you can do
my port number of hosts an organization
you can combine all of those results
which we'll talk about examples at the
end of this as well
search border is a very very good tool
pretty much the same thing I use source
quoted a lot just because of the fact
that it's a really cool API if you go to
your website itself it gives you this
blob of JSON but if you clean it up with
a little bit of one-liners with JQ which
Walsh is gonna show you guys in a little
bit as well you can get it pretty good
list given to you right and the other
one alternative I also combine them both
its certain SH the good thing about that
is you can use a wallet card so you can
put that before after and as you can see
it's finding anything that the key word
you were looking for all those combat
training diamond so there's definitely
that you can do search for doesn't serve
part it doesn't match we support the
wall part which makes a little bit
difficult to find are they're doing
so you think certainly the stage has
been very pop you also have a really
cool API and the next one is using open
source intelligence so this is where the
source
transparency stuff kind of falls into
the same category but because of the
sake of just looking for stuff domains I
want three categories there with the
supplamine finest the other two things
to look for are IP addresses you can go
to Aaron there we go for most big
companies like Google Yahoo Facebook
they have other acquisitions automatic
pulled into their scope within six
months of being acquired such a hacker
knowing that what company was acquired
by them is really powerful so you can go
to conch base we put in the company name
I'm looking for all the four companies
you can see a list of all their assets
are in scope Tibet alone gives you
another list of domains that you could
do the last steps to is buy all of those
subdomains yeah they gonna tackle okay
well so I go on Aaron so you can
actually look up a company and look at
all the iPads that they own so for this
one we go to Aaron type in Yahoo I
brings up this chart you click on the
organization and you go to the related
networks and it gives you a list of IP
addresses that your mom nmap and then
all the other content discovery
we'll talk about next also show then is
the thing you just go Yahoo and it give
you a bunch of them but it comes down to
what you trying to accomplish and how
passing it out so content discovery is
where all the fun begins so you have all
these IP addresses all these
acquisitions all their stuff domains
what do you do next until you start
looking at you want to for me instead of
having a first
at one point I want to be able to just
see what is this I posted the first
thing I do is grab the screen shot then
do a little port scanning I don't do all
the port numbers or select port numbers
that I think are comments I think about
20 30 then I do a directory brute force
and then I get to JavaScript
so again ports can't screenshot the
crawl these different files these are
the list of common shop for all the
switches that I take and then using any
of the tools on the right hand side to
research and we'll talk about that next
also check out the robots.txt there's
been plenty of times when I'm looking
for an admin folder and it's always just
things that were lost at txt don't know
why you're gonna give me a admin panel
that's really really nervous but always
check that out at always Hoss also
always keep your archive for all you're
doing for your brute force to the good
part the best part about directory
search is that every time you run this
tool it could say a reporter call the
father Tom and it's reports directory we
can do next is find a JMX console or
JBoss that's one one one one in
subdomain and you have done hundreds
elements for us already
you can do it grep through all your
results and see how many of them are
vulnerable so you can see how 72 of them
some of those are false positives you
also see that I have nine that gave me
401 Sammy's every possible particular
folder which is that there is some sort
of a login method by us and I want to
say like half of the times that I've
tried
not now you will see there's automation
so all these cool banners all work but
if you're going against a company like
yahoo and they have 40 48 positions and
4000 supplements on Jesse our comm
running directly brute force on every
single one of those one by one it's a
little under point in this little border
so we'll start with one step at a time
so the first thing I want to look for is
all the AWS instances I think we have
been sick and tired of hearing that
every big company or government branch
has been breached because they had a
misconfigured mystery bucket so why not
look for those you can do that by doing
Google or going on github which I might
go to you're going you can find a lot
more sources and get hub is who doesn't
commit their codes to get out right so
the other two that I need you to look at
so that's what it looks like for github
on the Left 14,000 results some of those
may not think on the right side are just
doing an s3 bucket Amazon there's also
tools so this one is called lazy s3 this
is actually written by me and a friend
leaning over admah what it does is give
it a company name for this one I put in
tests and we have given it a lot of
different environments and permutations
what it looks for like test keyword
input
we see it when it's put in test - up in
that staging test - admin down put prod
and then they put tests it was all those
different permutations in the
developmental stages so you want to make
sure we look we covered every single
possible path
there's also another tool called s3
bucketeer this is also ran by a friend
of mine named Tom dev that's the exact
same thing
this was his idea he did an impasse but
he was locking a lot of different
patterns so we did an investor II and we
did it in Ruby and we give him the same
exact pattern so we have both of those
working I use both I usually use the one
on the right more even though I wrote
the one on the left and that's mostly
because if I don't have Ruby installed
somewhere matches the easiest one to do
both of these require to have a AWS
configuration file server box but once
you set that up and give it your AWS s3
keys in your own configuration it uses
that to look for all these different so
we talked about s3 I mean we talk about
search pottery and we didn't talk about
how we can automate it so majority of
everything that I do is ran in batch and
that's because I'm using different tools
in different languages and the easiest
way to run them all with a ruby rust
python go batch becomes a lot easier
it's a little bit messy but it gets the
job done
so the first thing is you want to pull
data from search bar so the first thing
I do is I pull all the domains that are
given by search Potter I go for the end
this thing I'm a JQ I clean up the data
given to me and I
just to make sure it's not getting me
certificates that want another company
and I've been out data into a folder for
the company name into the company dot
txt file so all those dollar one signs
are the user so you want you ain't
directory your brute force same thing
okay we create an alias you tell it to
read the file that you wrote the lines
in your text boundary then you want the
screenshot the same thing I'm just using
exactly the syntax that's given to the
readme file and just dump again an alias
so I don't have to type an entire line
every time I want to go on this tool I
just type in a screenshot or search
butter and give it my input if you wanna
make it even better you throw it all
into one alias and say hey when I give
you this recon alias all these three
again you just give me the results which
brings me to my next tool called a Xena
con so they say week on does the same
thing in addition to other tools it does
and it grabs the headers for the side
and also the dig host and it generates a
very cool report which I'll show you
guys after this one so I suppose I type
in you know NASSCOM lazy Buchanan's calm
because all these different sources and
tools to generate a
means the next step it starts looking at
which ones are reachable and which ones
are not reachable so it's pretty much
when you got your insight that we can
access with the curl and everything else
that's not accessible and we want to
have those I keep all the logs up every
time I run these scans just to see which
one has gone from our Neutral to each
other later on they can different you
and sometimes there's a lot of them so
this one I wanted a picture they're
taking screenshots but 73,000 URLs
wasn't fun I really don't want to wait
on that it has to be done but just to
show you guys what it looks like this is
the report gives you the hostname on the
left side show the research on the
right-hand side I take two screenshots
one from 443 and one from ad and I
realize all those stickers every now the
password and username
you can do it all online because people
are doing it nowadays now they're
probably doing this professionally for a
while so what do you do you want to look
for the credentials why you want to find
the easiest entry point without the I
tokens surprisingly you can find a lot
of thing for different comments so get
them we can't do all these with tools so
this one I think is from truffle hog I
honestly don't use and then these tools
just because of the fact that I'd like
to really dumpster-diving thing and
reading every file because sometimes
maybe I don't find a password that
follow I wanted to but there's some
subdomain or an end point that I would
have missed if I didn't open the file
manually and a lot of false positives
who come through what miss tools not
that they're not great but it's just a
personal preference for me to go through
there manually on this I want to go at a
bigger scale of Dennett was coming so
there's a lot of different patterns you
can look for so if you're going
github.com
you can first start with company.com and
then give it the keyword depth so if you
want to find more subdomain do I find
the credentials either developer is the
staging site whatever that is
and then you can also use there's a lot
more cues and the one on the right those
are the ones that I see happening a lot
more than anything else the best one
that I found so far was the egg state
Pocky where I got access to a company's
entire financial account of a belt and
that was because they accidentally
submitted
codebase to github and they're all boys
that they later looking at it like you
are spec transaction using their PayPal
API people whole thing about so there's
another tool out there that a lot of
people don't use it's a robot so this
fire on the wayback machine and we do
the same thing we go through the wayback
machine together you can give it a
website for this one I'm giving hacker
de Paco one calm and it will give you
all the versions of that site with all
the different dates so I'm desperate to
have 2014 highlighted and what it does
is it pulls up the 2014 version of this
site and you can right click and pull up
all the JavaScript files and see all the
old endpoints that may or may not have
still been left behind so you could be
the new people all the JavaScript files
you find interesting new and olden
points and you explore them but why does
a JavaScript file matter I gave it two
end points on the best part but there's
been times when I see cloud and since
said to have their potentials hard-coded
in a JavaScript file and those alone are
really valuable because you can just get
access to multiple instances and such
just one and then a lot of more bugs
come out of that eventually by itself so
this thing's up to my next tool which is
called Jay Forrester
so what James parser does is you give it
a text file or JavaScript file you can
feed it in a one two under text file or
JavaScript files and you would highlight
all the finds so you don't have to
mainly dig through all
they're not in the nicest format the UJS
Forster gives you all the ones that you
need depending on how many file to give
it then you start buzzing the API or
whatever that size the next doctor
diving attack use Trello don't be this
person and you give it a keyword
organizational everybody in the wall can
see this fellow boards and you can find
some really weird stuff just company did
it completely wrong because they had not
only that I've given me they have to be
password and WordPress password or
hostname all the kids be I've been info
they're also given their daddy account
passport in the pin number so if you do
a lot more with their with any account
that you can do with FTP trouble isn't
the only place there's always different
based insights that you can go to and
but the examples are difficut chains
fancy sites there were two instances in
different times that I just put in the
hostname and either the court or
rabbitmq and sure enough
and the passwords for the default
credentials actually boarded so it got
me in and out pretty nice the next one
was looking for Jenkins
so most Jenkins and sisters are supposed
to be internally accessible but
sometimes the domain or the host name
may not be x1 directly but if you get an
IP address for it it's an entire
different game for this case I just put
in host name
that's where Jenkins popped up an
instance clicked on it there was no
authentication required at all
I clicked around and there was all the
building it's three keys and a lot of
other information I could have used the
other one is sentences not too long ago
I actually got a Jenkins instance access
to Jenkins instance of snapchat this was
honestly maybe 20 minutes of work I went
to census popped in the corporate domain
which you have to look for I can't tell
you what it is but if you do a little
search on hacker 1 you can definitely
find it yes this one was when you go to
it it just planted prompting you with
the Google authentication and I just
happened to accidentally click on my
gmail and I actually was happened to log
into it because they forgot to just make
it their organisation alone nobody from
the outside and if you have access to
Jenkins and the Guru scripts is
available there's pretty much GT for you
you can just go in there and run any
squares this one I'm just
testing for RCE but obviously it could
do a lot more like read files pivot or
whatever else want to do but because the
bug bounty and we don't want to piss
snapchat off you don't to piss anybody
off of these bug bounties there's a
point where you stop and this both my
stomach just show him that I can
actually man discovering end points that
were hidden on in JavaScript files this
is actually one of my favorite ones big
shadows of my body is lying so example
using js4 sauce so we found this
javascript file within one of the pages
that was supposed to just send you the
link to download the application when
your phone number and it sends your link
so we found out whether tuned in from
Sarris there was airbnb.com stash API
that's v2 and then goes to anyone's
there was some Cooper visit for one of
them you have to have your phone up in
your profile and then the SMS allowed
you to use the API to send yourself a
text message but there is a limitation
on SMS we can only use 100 sets of
characters and you can't get a lot of
that out of I website with hundreds of
characters and you also have the
limitation of making a handful of
requests per hour so that was kind of
boring but we'll come back to later
there's another one that was the
personification so the push
notifications if you're not familiar
with its those notification if you get
on your phone on your team
we're also doing this one also required
this one also require could have the
Airbnb out installed your phone
verification had to be done and you have
to be logged in the best part about this
was there was no character limitation
because it's a push notification and we
had no authority on our and so we can
send as many requests as we wanted
buzzing this was the easiest thing to do
when you don't have a limit so we
figured out base from the JavaScript
followed we figured out that there is a
request that kind of this one the two
things I borrowed a few more the user ID
in the object ID and if you submit any
Bob template this is what I love on a VM
me it gives you an error and it tells
you exactly what you need it tells you
hey I need a template from you and I
need to be one of these so we did it -
both we gave it just a whatever is it
something invalid you gave us all the
templates that it has so we can pretty
much to our own account for so we
decided to do was okay my user ID is
double what happens if I just send
myself a test with the body of the table
being test and the body of it being a
test as well and sure enough my phone so
we figured that we could send arbitrary
notifications but that's kind of boring
I mean yeah I could be fishing
I could send random messages but it's
even better if you can actually deliver
it with user IDs and their object ID and
be able to pull out reservation
information and that's that made it a
little bit more fun when we started
receiving
random notifications on our phone and
getting text messages information that
did not
other economy we're using and it gave us
that information on our secondary
account but this by itself is a nine
thousand dollar bounty it took us a good
six hours to figure it out because we
were getting tired of reading javascript
files but eventually so let's go back to
the dumpster diving thing one of the
findings that I usually do is most of
these companies aren't by themselves so
example Google my eyes off of it you
want to look for those umbrella company
first before you focus on the
acquisition for example if I'm doing
this before it was out of it I just
combined those two and one of the things
that was submitted about 20 or so days
ago was an ftp password
some really interesting data he gave me
access to the entire server for years so
I finished last year with a big bang and
to the next year that was a lot of
drinking there's a lot more than just
FTP for that company right some
companies don't have a lot of
information on there whatever
credentials you find but the key is that
what's the next step for a lot of our
bounty hunters we don't know what that
next step there so we have to trust the
comprehensive under investigation or in
some cases they tell you to go to the
investigation before them so for this
one I've done this in this company
particular
I'm sorry guys are watching but a lot of
time to just put in their company name
site comm FTP look at the recently
recently indexed boughs and you find a
lot of really cool stuff so I've gone
anywhere from FTP the PayPal that we
talked about I've also found an instance
where it gave me the AWS key and then
they WS instance that they were using
was a configuration file for a another
database where you connect it to and you
can just create yourself a user account
for all this types that we were using
that database and it just escalated a
lot more unfortunately for me that
company didn't see a lot of value on
that they gave me four 50 by the end of
the day that was also for 50 for work
the other one that was great
can't complain but again it all comes
out the company size and whatnot as it
is hoping the other thing but this one
is this was a internal development site
but what they missed what does it have
all their employees credentials it was
encrypted but as a malicious actor I
don't care if it's an encrypted
harassment these after days after days
to figure out its potential company but
yeah there's also all those instances of
history I'm just talked about again I
think one of the targets a lot of
companies it's not intentional but
people forget so this was actually sent
to us an echo 1 Peter your skier who is
one of our really great hackers and he's
also an engineer Shopify now he sent us
this really weird and important it's a
hey so I found this s3 bucket that
belongs to you guys and I was pretty
much able to go use the CLI for AWS and
pretty much
every file that's on there's a new SS 3
I said steel like some tax for the
bucket pretty much but it's even worse
when you can write to the bucket you can
do more than just read it right you can
rewrite follows you can fish people or
whatever they pose so that was a really
fun one and that landed him $25 there's
also times when people create is see
names they pointed through s3 but they
forget to go claim it on their account
I mean we see this a law and half of
wine so look for those if you see a
supplement comes back it's pointing
through is pointing to AWS instance
always check it out that's why I take
screenshots because if I think I
screenshot the first thing I see is that
you know us error that says no such
bucket then I know I got to go around
and clean this book if anybody else does
so that's why there's screenshot
everything comes into play so we talked
about recall we talked about the digital
dumpster diving and we didn't really
talk about how we can do all of this
together for one big change so
originally I found this domain target
calm the the first step that we talked
about was asset discovery so I find this
stage a development site it's fake but
kind of the pattern that they had so the
content discovery advanced mode
with your keyword hotforwords and then I
did a github search for that exact
internal file and he gave me this clue
on github that's okay we have this
endpoint as an API you can do other
stuff with it so I took the API and I
typed in the same thing internal the API
- internal in point and I found a really
cool command that had a internal
authentication so the have an
application that looked for a Heather so
instead of having unit type in your
username password they have a header
that you put in your request and that's
completely bypasses their login and for
me to be an outsider that was extremely
valuable because when I send it these
this was a stinky root command and I got
an okay so that was an indication that
something's fishy is going on and I said
geez people I was like hey I'm having
your end just don't panic it was me but
I'm gonna investigate what this was
which I did more digging and I did a
little bit of I brought all the
JavaScript files on the login page so
you go to login page right click look at
the JavaScript files and sure enough
there was a bunch of other endpoints
that I didn't know about and I started
making requests to those internal
endpoints and one of the things that we
have to get a long time also we don't
know if we'd force any of them
also there's the fact that the password
expired executions on top of it but in
the name my goal was to show the impact
that I could get a bunch more
and giving me a almost $5,000 comment
which was really fun again yeah that was
a entire talk I I'll be around till
tomorrow please keep in touch I'm gonna
reach out to him in any social media
it's always a mistake I can be judge me
via email
directory see all of the that can
program we work with we're also hiring
if you're looking for a job
remote we're also hiring for a lot of
positions and if you really like this
talk I'm also offering a training you're
not almost the opposite USA in San Jose
can also get activists in Canada October
again all the tools that I've talked
about the top forward the top that the
ones where I mean do research is
open-source github a big thing give you
guys the organizers here in Econ for
especially eats s Tyler and ministers
everybody here I think that's worth
listening to be an entire time I wrangle
love about my findings a big thing you
know all the hacker one community
members if you go on Twitter and look
for bug bounty protips and under the
hashtag we're gonna tip you can see a
lot of tips out hackers are sharing the
daily basis a lot of these were driven
by muting those big thank you as I have
Tom dead Patrick John
[Applause]
so dear lizard recon tools integrate
with what was it
crunch space for recon I was like so
this was the biggest version of it
there's another version coming to have
more sources and there's more things
like right now it's just super silly
question that last bug bathey was like
five thousand two hundred and thirty
eight dollars so definitely cut her and
see conversion no so now moment because
you can invite another researcher to the
program so we did I go based on target
so a one program tomorrow with
company X and the company says hey
everything the owners in school then I
do all these things that I talked about
one that company there's also times
where I create a list of sites so I my
tool that I have I feel it to another
bachelor that says hey are you talking
about this list run this tool and target
to see what so how the companies that I
go to every month or so when you come
[Music]
so if I get the chance to get into
someone's Network for example then I
stop there if I get in a society that
allows would you be in their corporate
VPN I stopped asking some companies tell
me yeah go ahead want to see how far you
can go with this some companies
something no no no please don't touch
anything at all because we don't and it
all comes down to your relationship with
that Congress company with a decent
black almost every month then there's
that trust that they know I'm not a
malicious I'm just trying to I saw in
the common github searches for keys I
didn't notice a removed keep couldn't
you put in like I removed key search and
then it finds that Wayback Machine it
and see if it's there so forget me can
actually look at the commitment history
right yeah so if it's still there enjoy
you like just because I seem like some
people start with something like so I
actually do
just because that invites hackers and
submitting a vulnerability on that side
whether it is successful your still
which is going to a bug on your platform
looking at the companies that are
offering a bug bounty program there is
just gonna pick your target so the one
that I recommend to a lot of people
would ask me how they get started
the brother fits the really good takes a
start now the ground your program thing
but everybody in the time they don't pay
for anything but to have some websites
from the early 2000 there's plenty of
companies if you want to get paid
there's Yahoo that guy was going on for
four years so you might get it might be
harder to find vulnerabilities on there
because pain right but in the day it
just comes out to your investment for me
took about six to eight months
when I first other four years ago but it
wasn't for the cash market and we just
said I was going to college not man what
I want to do and I didn't want a college
degree but now we're just going to I
went from business computer science and
business and then I gotcha
but it was mostly to figure out what I
wanted to go to my computer so bug
bounties were video paying you for years
ago and I like the idea of hacking so I
got involved with that community but
there's a ton of hackers every month
that come out skills of your time in
percentage of time or what you're doing
are you doing more recon after the
hacking or the balance or so I go
between three things one is recon the
second one is developing my tool when I
get tired of hacking the third one is
ripping up an actual college in the park
so I talked about the Airbnb stuff even
though Airbnb had a lot of things in
scope all the websites go I focus on the
main app itself because it was so huge
dependents were great and there was a
lot of so I spent
it was that's when I started learning a
lot nobody was looking at baby in me
because he looks now but if you actually
sign up and go through everything it's a
huge application and that was when I
learned a lot of this stuff that I
learned a lot of the tricks because have
you done any formal planetary
penetration testing and like written a
reports for that and where I'm going
with this is do you have any opinion on
whether report for like that formal
contact for this so it's an entire thing
right
[Music]
the versus bug bounties I have the
freedom of looking at this from anywhere
in the world anytime your boss or
anybody myself and I did this for my
entire glossary of college and I made a
six digit salary just by doing work now
is because I
and that's the biggest thing to the
power stand you have to buzzer all
methodology before you become so the
methodology helps you out win some /
some large percentage of your targets
don't work out right well the
methodology I talked about this one with
just my recon knowledge right there
but if it's a site that's just an
application - what about this different
game well you start you focus on one web
example scripting that's all I focus on
the next thing is you want to find
ss-sorry you find it depends on the
application what is it doing how does it
process that data what kind of data is a
process if it's an image busting site
and there's definitely more holes you
can do it there's different photos you
can do that look at because the xs/s
board
what does I see another sign that's ok I
mean you're a lot of good user important
you sign things are going to put other
things
yeah but if if you need course material
to learn and we also have what they call
hot girl one-on-one numbers 1 0 1 so
it's pretty much what we call her hack
of Education site it walks you through
all these different woman pollute ibises
labs for that YouTube videos for it if
you don't have access to a 71 hack lock
we give you all the labs and you created
on different scenarios but at the end of
the day it's you whatever time you put
in for yourself is six to eight months
and I did I felt my entire upper
division courses because I was going
litter to my class then I realized I
just want to get out of school because
it was getting so I just get out of the
way but I was spending I want to say
thanks for not school because I wanted
to be in
yeah so I think at least when I look at
some of these joint companies and I read
their requirements and they're like you
know test us but don't be checked
anything you know how can you do that
well depends on how you do it for
example a find a sequel injection you
don't have to pull their credentials you
can just give it a sneak where they can
sleep for five seconds concept if you're
going to get any more communication you
have to meet the NC passport father it's
a shadow file you can read it a random
process power host
that's what they mean don't don't take
it too far as with newer hackers they
don't want you to cause downtime right
so whatever safest path that is for you
to show there's a vulnerability should
be the one that you go through so again
for the injection ones I tried to do
something like curl my which I can see
the logs for it
I say hey there's the because yes