all right so welcome everyone we're
gonna be talking about operationalizing
in frightened Journal program for you as
well as what against you and how you can
do it we'll start by talking briefly
about what a threat intelligence program
is what it entails what are some of the
basic features of having a program where
do the basic outcomes and then we'll get
into the nitty-gritty of how you can
actually automate some of the more
complex parts of it so that you have
have the ability to then keep your cheer
ones up to a tier 3 level and
functionality but not necessarily in
knowledge base or practice so quick
blurb about me
I'm Christian nice to meet everyone I
also go by Barney cosmos or cosmos by
most of my friends because they're all
too lazy to say my full handle I was
previously the pen testing and threat
intelligence lead for 80 mg my book
developed and ran the service line I
moved on to me the talisman threat
researcher specializing top-billed out
in French all some programs Mehldau as
well some of the iron anthing services I
actually spent my last year redesigning
completely one of this socks for the
portion by my Viking is not often one of
the enemies for stands I do a lot of the
for the last five years I've done a lot
of the course audit question authoring
and I also have an instructor for 560
and 504 so that's your G pen and your G
CI h horses so I like to jump right into
these things first let's talk about
thread himself brand new tell is really
the sugar and spice on top of all your
security programs it gives you that
context and I'm going to come back to
that word a lot because it's one of the
most important words when you're talking
about their intelligence so considering
that why do we need threat intelligence
for intelligence gives us the context to
know how to deal with the attacks that
we're facing it also can potentially
give us the advantage over our
adversaries by allowing us to make
preemptive moves
knowing that we might be attacked in a
certain fashion in doing so it gives us
a lot of different advantages so friend
tensions from a non cyber student
perspective is typically viewed as
having intelligence on your adversaries
as well as being able
the same context perpetrates down in
suicide perspective now in a cycle
perspective it can allow us to
preemptively select things you might
want to patch in advance to help protect
against you know threads in the wild
weren't threats that we my finger on the
rocks for example when MSO 867 came out
back in the day those companies that had
already in early adopters of the threat
intelligence program had already been
the first on that hatch list so they
were already communicating with
Microsoft in order to make sure that
those DLL and that nati ulnar ability
was being passed prior to the public
disclosure on it so that's a little bit
about what it is how we can use it and
how you can really get started with a
program so let's say you know you got
your C so he had the buzz word tomorrow
we want to start a thread intelligence
program what does that look like what
does that tell and what you need so
historic trend conscious program the
barrier to entry is actually pretty low
you really just need an analyst who have
the ability and the knowledge and the
skill set to start doing intelligence
there are lots of open source tools and
utilities there's things like buyers
total you have new tech spread exchange
if you're looking for IO C's or to start
at baseline but even less than that the
basics of their intelligence really come
down to add in context of already known
pieces of data so for example your
organization's subscribe to a news feed
generally could be Yahoo unity could be
just seeing that it can be CNN whatever
use that you want to subscribe to having
that finalist actually on a daily basis
go ahead collect and curate that news
before the c-suite level executives have
a chance to view in the museum freak out
about it and then come down to the
analyst to ask the questions being able
to actually write a little blurb that
says hey this is the non-technical
breakdown this is why we should or
should not be concerned and this is what
as an organization that and its core
that context part is threat intelligence
so as I mentioned one of the use cases
of this is to prevent fun so but it is
up here I doubt and our misunderstanding
of our actual threat landscape so one of
the things that French culture can
provide you instead of having your
executive go out ahead of time and see
the article in news
perfect example aquabox appache began
instructional mobility came a really big
thing those of us in the intelligence
community have already been talking
about stress through months and months
and months in advance of a breach and we
were already informing our clients hey
you really should touch this we haven't
seen it in the wild yet but it's an easy
outward facing vulnerability so if you
guys worried one of the earlier classes
they were doing here about
reconnaissance one of the things he said
it seems to go to show ends going to
look for you know whatever is out there
already there's for a keynote this
morning and we touched on auto schooling
which was that collaboration between
show an and Metasploit these are both
really good methods that a lot of the
tackles and adversaries for high-level
and low-level are going to use in the
first phases of attack having a fair
intelligence program really helps to
prepare you to prevent something like
that so desirable outcome sort of some
of the desirable things that we can get
immediately out of our threatened
sovereign we have our analysts our
analysts knows our environment they know
how to contextualise data for an
environment and they have a basic
understanding of multiple technical
disciplines so they have a basic I our
understanding a business understanding
and they also have a forensic
understanding so they can speak to each
of the contexts now we can start
deciding well do you want to have a deal
18 feet do you want to have a weekly or
monthly need you just want to normally
start with it's a monthly fee I like to
estimate on average therefore a monthly
fee you need about eight analyst hours
per month to generate that one
newsletter and we'll talk about what
that newsletter will consist of in just
a little bit now if you were going to go
to something like a weekly newsletter
you would probably wanted to
get out who me as opposed to eight hours
a month for that newsletter then give
the analysts plenty of times you curate
contextualized understand digest and
then give you a business readable output
now you might also want to consider
having different levels of output from
your Intel program and what I mean by
that is it's really good for a part of
your security awareness program as your
why do you turn a user base to have an
opt-in program or often newsletter where
anyone in your organization can opt-in
for a security context newsletter now
there are use cases where you might not
want all of the data that you're putting
in this newsletter to be publicly
available so similar to how the FBI and
other three-letter organizations use
certain emails to distribute between
tech leaders of companies that are
relevant to them your threat
intelligence program because that's
really just a larger threat Intel
program and sharing program when you see
like that beside exact and all the I
socks
those are really just large group
funding crowd source Intel programs so
when you're internalizing it for review
I make use of those and you want to be
able to emulate those functionalities so
when you have your daily weekly or
monthly needs you might consider having
two one core public consumption within
your company and one that's specifically
for the security personnel that's
restricted that way any sensitive data
that you put into restricted email
doesn't become public domain so we
talked a little bit about some of the
skills in again I'm just gonna highlight
then one more time here right you need
someone who can be a critical thing or
someone who understands you then have
the ability textual eyes that deal again
I'm going to come back to that word a
lot you know I'm not a fan of buzzwords
but in this case context really matters
organizational awareness having with
someone who is really really good at
hand testing I are in forensics and has
a good understanding all those practices
but doesn't have an understanding of
your organization what your network
looks like it's not really beneficial to
you a lot of cases when we take threat
Intel because it's grown all around the
context there might be mitigating
control so a threat that is normally
rated at an on a CDSs score might
actually be fi for your
because hey it's protecting something of
nominal value or be it might be higher
than a 10 for you because it's
protecting something of great
significance to you conversely if
they're also naivety get in control so
perfect example of this certain
applications that are web pacing if you
have a lap in front of that and the web
has a particular signature that you know
will block and attack that's
communicated control so regardless of
whether or not that server is now
patched in this example we use the
pollachi stress if I have all the
signatures that I could think of our
bocce struts I can say thoroughly then
get in control now I'm not advocating
for not catching and using mitigating
controls mitigating control should only
ever be used as a temporary fix but it
is the way to give you a larger period
of time to do your testing and make sure
you don't break your production
applications the ability to identify key
assets so that comes back to my previous
point right we need to know where are
our keys to the kingdom
what is important to us as a business
one of the things that I like to talk
about a lot is insecurity you need to
win your goal is a security provider on
the defensive side and you need on the
offensive side just to win and it's
impossible as a defender to say I am
going to successfully block every time
so how do I win as a security provider I
redefine what I consider winning to be
so if I am a credit card company and my
piece of the kingdom are the PII and the
credit card data and that's sitting in a
base that's encrypted at rest and also
encrypted during transit I don't really
care you can botnet my entire
organization to have complete control
over every endpoint
if you can't decrypt back Anna I still
want you have control over everything in
my organization but the thing that's
important to me is still mine so
identifying the key asset and what
really matters and having that context
there's the word again is really what
makes this possible
scripting the aggregation while not
mandatory is really really useful for a
threat intelligence analyst and this
allows them to do a lot of automation
and minimize those number of hours that
are actually
or to generate these news feeds now you
can't replace that analyst entirely the
automation because what you're really
looking for is that critical thinking
that ability to contextualise
and that's not something that we have
the ability to replace but we could save
a couple hours and go to different news
sites and having an automated digest
that we can now as the analyst go
through and then start writing our
blurbs after we digest the information
context matters I will scream that from
the rooftop anyone who has a threatened
total compensation and does not talk
about context does not know what they're
talking about because that's already
tell his threat Intel is context if you
ever get into a vendor conversation with
a threat intelligence provider and they
don't say the word context kick them out
and go kick again because you're not
picking the right ones
so boiling down into that newsletter
what is the process of developing the
newsletter look like first you have your
analyst collect their news articles so
you're know the Alice's then go out and
they can do this either manually
automated they can use something like
feedly they can do it via scripts and
have a list of sources that you've
predefined as things that you like
they're going to go visit these sites
they're going to pick articles that seem
interesting and potentially relevant to
them as the client then they're going to
read and digest now the reason we
allocate so much time in threat
intelligence for generating something
that might appear to be just a simple
newsletter that feel like someone could
have written in an hour or so it's
because we really want that analyst to
be able to digest and understand what
they're reading
when specter and meltdown female
Google have put out some really really
good write-up write-ups on the
vulnerabilities and what they actually
entail and there was a lot of reaction
in the beginning similar to what
happened with brohamer so those of you
who aren't familiar with brohamer row
hammer was a very theoretical experiment
in which using magnets and other
electromagnetic fields we can actually
cause a bit jump in
we'll feel in a chip and cause data to
be written now the really cool thing
about that which you can do it and
there's actually now a remote version of
that that works but when I say it works
I'm gonna put the air quotes up for that
one it works in a lot of environment
because they have that perfect
conditions to be successful and even
then on last estimate it was only
successful about 52 to 67 percent of the
time and I try to be specific acts are
important now the reason for this was do
Denisha attack without having actually
understood that full meltdown
just like with meltdown expected without
understanding what speculative execution
actually was you could not context let's
back to your environment and prioritize
your passion the difficulty of execution
of an attack is one of the most vital
pieces of information threat
intelligence can gather breathe because
that tells you what your priority really
is so we're going to our
contextualization case right we're
digesting our articles we want our
panelist to go out read the article
understand the article find the sources
met the sources or the reference in the
article and do their own research we
want to make sure that they're not just
creating an article out of one source we
want to make sure we exhaust all of our
sources on the topic finally we want to
decide it we're going to divide between
the two or more newsletters are we
saying that the data via contextual ad
to a certain extent should only be
available to certain members of our
security team for example in are we
placing ourselves at risk by allowing
any one of the organizations you know
hey there's this really really bad
gulnur ability that we're really
vulnerable to and someone could exploit
tomorrow and we'd be dead as a company
that's probably not something that I
want anyone of my company to know
because they might be afraid they might
start looking for their jobs they might
be motivated to disclose this for
monetary or personal gain and that
creates another risk for me so managing
risk is also the part of the threat
intelligence providers we want to make
sure that we're contextualizing the data
to the right people at the right time
and making sure that
people were receiving our data other
people were privileged to that data and
finally you have the output of our
process which is one or more newsletters
in the most basic form it's simply going
to be an opt-in newsletter that we
publish on our internal website thing
hey guys if you guys are interested in
security or your mother's news money
people and you're going out you're
reading the news every day and then
freaking out because oh my god there's
this email credit harvesting thing I
heard about what happens if I get a fish
well I know know that okay my
organization is doing something about it
this is what our mitigating controls are
this is what's in front of me and this
is what's protecting me as a member of
this organization and then your manager
a restricted info letter which normally
would consist of strictly your security
teams and only the heads of those teams
so anyone who would be privileged to you
an FBI letter a yellow paper any of
those things those are two of the people
you would want to be on your restricted
list now I always complete show up signs
every christen tation I do always have a
stone one because I never want anyone to
leave in presentation I do and and be
like that's great that was cool what did
I do
how do I use that so we're going to come
back to this in a second or one of the
things we're going to come back to you
is what does it actually cost me have in
for an intelligence program and what's
my return on investment look like
because one of the hardest is to justify
insecurity is your return on investment
and you can't justify a budget to your C
so when you're asking for money for all
these cool tools if they don't know what
they're getting out of it so we talk
about threat intelligence we've talked a
little bit about what it was you talked
about how to start a program now I'm
going to teach you one of the more
advanced stages how do we automate this
how do we operationalize it and make it
a part of our daily workflows what did
we do to make this usable to our
analysts well I'm glad you asked and we
have a couple of requirements that we're
going to talk about here to make this
usable for analysts in a very effective
and automated matter now we a platform
for the sake of examples
any demonstration here today we'll be
using multi go for those of you who
aren't familiar multi go was developed
by Aventura it is a threat intelligence
platform that's predominately used for
gathering data via api's we're also
going to need some source data now I'm
going to show you two examples I'm going
to talk a lot about the difference
between the two one of them is going to
be strictly from an external perspective
and what can be done with that data and
the second is going to be a more
in-depth model that leverages lots of
data that you have internally already
that you're already collecting so for
our source data we're going to be using
buyers total as our external threat
intelligence platform resource our chip
we're also be using local network data
and data box now the last thing and the
most important part of guard
intelligence program when we talk about
it a little already is people so when a
lot of dating and operationalizing if
your intelligence program there's two
roles that are really important and
smaller organizations this role may be
shared and this is why I talked about
earlier one of the skills that might be
really did have scripting for the
automation purposes so you're going to
need someone who's good at customization
of orchestration someone who's really
good at x-rated websites reading and
writing from 80 guys and making tools
work together and play nice with one
another integrations personally you know
I program
half a dozen different languages you
know I can list those all day and for me
the one that works best right now is
Python that's my personal current
favorite that's always subject to change
the second part you use that threat
intelligence analyst the person who's
gotten and actually had all the context
that makes this data usable so because
we're going to be talking about multi no
in this scenario I'll offer you up
towards the end a couple different
alternatives there's plenty of open
source things you can use things like
crits if you're using the high or miss
these are all things that you can do if
you're using something more commercial
if you're using an outlay siient product
like JIRA to match your tickets or if
you're using something like snow service
now send us any of those it is possible
to add integration to top of this that
help you to do these different things
that we're going to talk about here same
thing if you're using directly out of
your Sam you
using your sims building case management
utilities or you're using some
integrations a lot of the things we're
about to talk about are still possible
within there and I'll talk about as we
go through why I like multi go and Brack
based platforms for this particular
grocery so what I have up here is an
environment set up this is actually a
diagram again from service website
because we're going to be using multi go
in this example and I'll talk about I
know there's a lot of stuff on here
we'll talk about what the mandatory make
this process work and was optional so of
the things on the end here we have to
start with a client these are optional
the differences between them again
they're multi to a specific this will
vary as your mileage will with different
products in this case we have classic
Excel and ze the difference between them
is the number of objects you can have on
a single screen of time Community
Edition is free you have 12 objects on
your screen at a time and return twelve
objects of time then you move up to you
plastic which is ten thousand in Excel
which is unlimited
so that's your platform that's where
we're going to view them and emulation
our data the next thing we're going to
need is a server of some sort that
server is going to be our gateway to our
data so multigo has two different
options they have commercial transform
servers in the context of multi go to
transform is is the pre-built script
that doesn't work for you it goes out
and gathers the data process it parses
it and prints an engineer view the
commercial transform data server is
going to be hosted by multi go in their
cloud you can opt for an on-site edition
of it for various privacy reasons so
that you're not exposing yourself by
potentially giving your attacker an idea
of what you're looking up about them and
really that's just there's a lot of nice
things about chicos already built for
you integrations with a lot of
commercial products and a lot of
commercial tips things like CrowdStrike
recording future be my key my mouth all
the things are really already built into
the commercial transfer this gives you a
lot of time and development money the
other thing that they use is an internal
transfer observer so internal transform
server here
June is pretty
demonstrate is pretty mandatory what
that does for you is it allows you to
actually access the data parse it
locally and it also allows you to
distribute it amongst multiple clients
as opposed to just doing everything will
be under client if you were to do
everything locally on your client you
can still make this work it's just a
little more heavy on the management and
I'll talk towards the end of the
presentation about some of the cost
associated with this particular approach
and then we can also talk about what
costs might look like your different
product ranges if any one I'll leave
that open to the Q&A section and we can
talk about what products you guys have
your organization's or your familiar but
and I can pull from you know my
experience what those cost models look
like for each different product the next
thing is the most important here that's
a transform server your transform server
can actually be the same server as your
distribution server or your commercial
transform server all that means the
transform server is representative of
where your code piece is going to live
for your transforms again this means
that's just different sets of scripts
that will actually go out and gather the
data and do something think of the
transform as the thing that does the
thing great so you have two different
data sources we're going to talk about
here you have public via sources public
data sources might consist of things
like your jeep Public DNS online
databases like buyers total costs of
total hybrid analysis search engines
like Google Bing Yahoo asks social media
Facebook Twitter Twitter's one of the
bigger ones Facebook is about a lot more
restrictive and how you can actually ask
that their data they've limited access
to the graph API so if your organization
is not one of those two organizations
privileged so that that might not be an
option for you any longer unfortunately
online API so really the sky is the
limit if there is an API or if you can
simulate a man interaction you can
interact with that and pull that data
and of course that leaves it open to any
other public data source now the
internal data sources this is where you
have to do a lot of your development
because there aren't any commercial
transforms that multigo offers openly
and freely to you for your internal
and because everyone's data and their
organizational structure is different
that's your mileage may vary but the
amount of development you might need to
do to get this data so internal API
you're using slug if you're using the SM
if you're using Q radar any of your sims
so they all have open ad eyes you can
dump the data in there and make queries
system blogs if you're using another
utility if you want to pull directly
from syslog if you're a small
organization and you only have a few
servers you can do it that way internal
service like your ad servers your DNS
servers if you're doing DNS management
be it something like IP blocks to make
sure that you're managing your different
DNS allocations you might want to pull
that data in and any other internal data
feeds you might have one of those
internal Indians might actually be your
intelligence music letter you might want
to pull that in then you can link it via
specific specific IO sees that you place
in those newsletters or attacks simply
because you kiss all right so I've
talked a lot about a lot of things so
I'm actually going to show you a demo of
two different scenarios that are based
around this game for scenario and what
the difference between using strictly
public data and strictly internal and
public data look like again this is in
the context of multigo your experiences
will be a little different depending on
what platforms you choose to use so all
i've done here is i've started with an
unknown attacker that's just an empty
graphic it's just a way for me to
visualize what I'm doing I've identified
in my organization that there is this
malicious executable that's doing things
that it shouldn't be called this party I
see for the sake of this example will
consider that it was either flag by a
bee or we're able to find it during a
hunt I'm now able to take that piece and
I'm going to resolve that to a hash I
think Nick you did it manually I can
look it up based on what I know it might
already be available to me that hat I'm
actually only right click on that icon
and I've got all this data so all that
data was pulled via the virustotal
API via the public data transform which
is freely available for all multi go for
user now what's really cool about this
is I've taken the virus little chip give
it at my house we got all the good eNOS
data back from our shuttle and put it
right on my crack so it's really easy
for you to manipulate and all this was
done in another second to be a
right-click that's the beauty of this
typical automation approach is that
wonderfulness of having all your data
from many sources in one platform now if
you're paid for a private subscription
to something like SWAT or passive total
or premium buyers total intelligence
account you can also put those API keys
in here and use that in as well now
what's really cool is I have every aps
signature I have I can search from you
Texas and I can now cross search this
back to my organization I've used that
hash in the information I got from my
Moodle to resolve its and water cry so I
know hey this sample that's this part WC
filed over the after nasty well now I
can tell you if you want to cry
so is this from a strictly public
perspective right we haven't done
anything really significant yet they're
required in the internal data or audit
even anything yet so let's look at what
that would look like this is the same
chart after I've added some special
transforms that Everton and a lot of
native here now you'll notice we still
have our unknown actor icon we still
have our diskpart nobody identified and
the results in the house all these
errors that you see I don't know how
well you guys in the back and see them
are actually just relationship errors
that are pointed and directed towards
how we derived our data so one of the
reasons I like using graph based not
going through this is because as humans
we function in a neural network matter
which means that we function as a moral
graph that's how our brains actually
function that's how neurons fire which
means that for most individuals looking
at a spreadsheet or columns of data is
not as efficient or easy to understand
for the average person as something like
a graph and that's really how you take
your cheer one who just knows how to
look at data and right click and use
something but doesn't really understand
it this is how you can make that tier 3
level function of gathering the ontology
using it accessible to your cheer ones
and twos so now what do they do well
let's talk about the new things that are
on this diagram we've talked about the
sample that Hashem is pumped about the
new Texas be pulled back from a virus
photo let's talk about what's new here
so one of the things that I was able to
do be in integration I pulled in some
box and I've identified that this
particular sample actually came in
through a spam email someone what we
don't think there was an either
malicious enhancement or they visited
website in this case we're getting say
there was an attachment it was on
Christian at Tesla Tom's email that's
where it came from we can actually right
click on that and there's a transform
that's gonna run in the backend that we
developed then it will search our Active
Directory instances and say hey cool
almost Christian at Tesla comm who email
address is that that's gonna be resolved
us to me user and they have Christian
Nichols to know about email others okay
that's great
know what we she knows it all won't be
Sheen's does he own in this scenario
we're gonna have guys that I only have
one machine but if I have multiple that
will be good to know show up here so
think we're gonna resolve the machine is
we're gonna make a query to our access
management database so if you guys are
using ServiceNow you're maintaining a
asset inventory the SCM TB worker using
managed engine or using 98 other spice
works whenever you guys are using you're
gonna make a query to that and say hey
can you correlate this user to machines
and then give you the machine names and
their IP addresses and I'm gonna store
all that information in that new so
that's simple I have a relationship now
between the unknown after an email
account the user who owns the email the
machine that that piece of email was
delivered to and where the malware is
lately sitting and I can cross correlate
that not traded by guess in fact that is
where the malware is now we have that
relationship as well so I know that this
part of some piloting this part of easy
from some unknown actor which we know
results of this hash which we know is a
sample wanna try and add these new Texas
is in our environment that's great now
let's do something about that so now
that I have all the music
I want to find other machines in my
environment with the same sample or
things that are no new taxes so I'm
you're lying here I right-click on that
sample again and who's the source data
from below to do another query we have
custom transformed Oh unfortunately I
can't show you all a couple of
transforms I just don't have enough time
a food an example the basic one on the
next slide and a lot of those are very
proprietary didn't applying to
developing for and internal to yourself
so it's really hard to show this in a
presentation like this but in the Q&A
please do feel free to ask me was
involved in person at the ADA in
obtaining that view we can discuss it
privately that waits for contextualise
for you as well so now I'm taking that
hashtag search across my entire
organization
this can be via if you're using a white
listing tool or if you have a style
engineer environment across write
anything that's blogging the different
various hashes if you have the ability
degree EDR people to actually spin off
each search on every endpoint join up by
us you can create that integration as
well so I've now identified three more
computers with water cry on it and I
resolved those again via the theme
transform is previously moving in
Reverse seeing this doing a dns for work
versus reverse lookup shoot three more
users so now I'm going to have four
total affected users one key text and
for computers that I have to remediate
and I know that it's water crime awesome
right now if I wanted to I can take this
a step further and if I'm using the ER
from my environment I need add
transforms that keep the data out of
multigo and actually go out of
quarantine those machines remediate
those machines where possible run fire
stands on those machines again the
beauty of using an approach like this in
automation is you're limited only by
what kind of DNA you have access to what
kind of tools you have access to and
what you can program so we'll talk about
after this what a transform looks like
so what is it under the hood transform
look like if we're going to write our
own so this is just the basic Python one
multigo supports multiple languages
worth pearl shell script Python and I
believe Ruby under the hood out of box
you can add custom an integration for
different languages so you use whatever
you prefer and this is just a basic
search so we're going to use the multi
blue transform library to import that in
this case I also have no ancillary file
that I've written called callback
manager which manages my held out
queries for this example of code we're
going to be talking about how I resolved
the users and machines to IP addresses
and the user an email so I'm going to
have this multi old transform that I'm
going to instantiate here I'm then going
to create this variable that's going to
store my health app resolution so I'm
just going to call that all that breast
I'm going to make a call to my LDAP
manager which has a sub function called
user query which takes an input of an
email address so it's going to take the
email address I put in here which I
actually use my corporate email I have
in this example Christian and L about
global and I'm going to do a resolution
so I've actually put an abstract here of
what the data that is returned actually
looks like so I've been returned back a
object class which in this case was an i
network person Pio i sx account and a
shadow account so in this case where I
was clearing an open LDAP server because
I was running a Linux environment
for example my UID was Christian that's
my username my surname was Nicholson my
given name Christian so this is just
like I said but you would expect to get
back from any open L that query right
now I've added a couple other things on
the backend that query in my old f9
restrictors auxilary data so you'll also
notice at the bottom that I asked for my
last night when I key and last nomachine
name something really cool to note about
this particular implementation if you're
familiar with Python you'll have notice
that all of the variables it's a
dictionary made up of lists and the
reason for that is what if I have
multiple items so in the case we're not
class I have multiple object classes
what if I have more than one email or
more than one you know have Elias
whatever have more than one class know
my keys so if I'm retaining all my T's
and I have an implementation like IP
blocks in in my environment I can
actually go back and get you know the
last five or ten you know an IP
addresses and then cross-correlate make
sure that there's no other infected
machines by one multiple devices and the
last note machine name so again we're
just gonna do a quick DNS lookup for
that one
so all of this data gets returned to me
I'm going to parse it out and I'm going
to use this entity so I'm going to
create a new identity an entity in multi
local language is every one of those
nodes that you saw on that map each one
is an entity and each one has a datatype
so in this case we're going to be making
a person datatype for a reference in a
user so I'm gonna say I want to add a
new entity using again I'm going to use
my multi code transform object here I'm
going to make a stuffed last called
empty identity I'm going to tell it that
it's a person object you can also define
custom objects if you have you know
custom servers or applications that you
want to make it more expansive it is
supported by the transforms library I'm
going to provide it Ella back res I'm
going to say give it variable one to
start with which is my username I'm
going to also tell the set of the paint
so we're setting the type of again to a
multi Godot person which is a class
authority
in my multi-view library basically says
hey this is a person type variable and
the reason that that's really important
useful is that's gonna drive what type
of transforms you can use multigo as
very context aware so if you're clicking
on my papers or the hash it'll provide
different options of what types of
transports you can run and when you
write a transform you're going to define
what types of objects it should work on
so it's really helpful for organization
you'll never try and run a DNS lookup on
a person's name it's obviously you're
not gonna really expect any results from
that I'm going to set a value so the
value is the actually data that I can
serve with which again it's going to be
the first object in here and I'm also
going to set an entity weight what the
entity weight means is in my graph if I
want to do a weight distribution to make
it easier and more visible where I want
certain entities to hold a higher value
and there will be more visible as I'm
dragging objects around that's what the
week does it's really just a visual
helpful identity and it defines your
importance level of the oxygen we're
discussing in multi the world I'm then
going to tell it loves my display gonna
look like what should the text that I
see on my screen underneath the icon say
and do I have any additional custom
field in this case I do I have all this
data here I want to be tied to those
objects so I'm going to assign that data
to the additional field object and what
that will do is it'll actually
automatically create via the library
each field which in the multi goal
interface lots of come up in a separate
user pane that's very easy to see then
I'm going to tell it to send a message
to the user and let me know hey just
give me a little comment that says yeah
I completed my task
I've run everything in the background it
succeeded you can get fancy here again
this is just a basic example you get
error handling
you know you need require API keys and
they're missing
you can add handling in here for that as
well again it's really accessible so
you're limited only
imagination and then I'm going to tell
us to return the output onto my screen
and that's why I got all those custom
knows all right so before I move on
we're going to come back to the snow
white before I'm in shock let's go and I
just want to offer you some alternative
popular options
we talked a little bit about using
something like misprints or anything
else you have in your environment like I
said they're really the sky is the limit
you can swap out your data or whatever
data you want to use I've actually taken
this approach and this approach was
actually really inspired by completely
arbitrary other things so there's a
really big tool by Palantir called
Gotham that was designed for big data
manipulation for those of you who are
familiar with it it's predominantly an
HR tool and they've added a cyber module
onto it it's just another giant graph
based out of the database it's very
expensive and inaccessible to a lot of
people which really led me to develop
this approach for myself this is also
the approach that I used as an MSSP
model at a variety of different jobs
that helped in the past when it
delivered the service to a client now
some of the other interesting things
that you can do here like I said we
touched it a little bit on
you can add integrations to actually go
out and do something with your data you
can have auto report generation you can
use these graphs to auto generate
tickets for you and maintain ticket
notes again because it's all automated
your your limitation is really only by
what kind of tools you have accessible
what you want to integrate and what you
have the ability to program so I
promised we would come back to the stoic
moment so there's no one moment here
really comes down to a couple keys
bounce so the exact implementation that
I just showed you on this screen using
the tools that I showed you to the
maximum capacity would cost me about
$100,000 in my first year now that gets
me a virus little private license
freezing ETI and that also gets me all
the different ancillary multi know parts
that I want for five users for the first
year that cost jumps down to about
$30,000 in the second year again this is
just a pricing model for multi go full
disclosure I have I'm not
with turbo or multigo at all I'm just
using those this reference prices for
your program so assume that your total
outlook over two years is gonna be about
$170,000 now what is your savings
where's your intern I'm an investment on
that you're saving in time that's really
going to be the biggest thing you're
gonna save on here is your time that
you're outputting so on average I've
automated the job of a tier 3 tier 3 as
a consultant generally ranges at a price
range of about 200 to 350 dollars an
hour depending on your consulting firm
sometimes it's a little less than that
I see that as low as 150 less than open
scope consultants that are more at a
tier 2 level or cure 1 level you're
going to go up between $89 if they're
more commodity skills so figure you're
saving that much money per hour for
every hour at Interstate now the whole
example that I showed you from start to
finish of that graph took me less than
five minutes now let's get all that Thea
typically between jumping between every
interface identifying the interface
identified where in the interface the
people did who typically take the
average analyst between 30 minutes to an
hour so I heard used between 30 minutes
and an hour's worth of work about five
minutes BMI automation platform you and
that's not counting if I were to add an
EGR tool either custom or not custom on
top of this now an alternative to multi
go if you're a very open short source
shop and you don't want to use something
that creates a mist or something you can
definitely develop something entirely on
your own it's a very simple graph based
database so you're welcome to use things
like graph is and all the other
wonderful Python libraries out there and
develop all this on your own you can use
things that are already pre-built like
Mozgov from Mozilla or grr from Google
and integrate with those platforms as
well but this type of approach both of
those have already include graph based
management platforms inside of them so
you can just build on top of that I'm
still get the steam general how could
look and feel so overall I'm seeing on
average over 2 years the average
employer consultant is between 115 to
$140,000 if I were to insource known as
a salary this total cost over two years
it was about a month 70 so if you are
saving over $100,000 a year
with this type of communication and
remember I'm also taking this data
accessible to a tier one who is far less
expensive for me as an employee then
it's year three there's a couple
different other things we can talk about
if you want to talk about return on
investment on this one but I really do I
got started to come close to the end of
my time and I want to leave plenty of
time for Q&A so with that said I'd like
to jump to Q&A any questions about
threat intelligence in general the
approach I demonstrated here what
platforms you can use feel free to shoot
your hands up if not if you want to ask
me out the presentation I'm more than
happy to cut a little short so that you
can approach individually I know
sometimes I have one likes to ask
questions would you share any tips or
nothing it's about orientating the
threat intelligence program to the
business sure that's the next question
the question was what are some tips
about worry achieving a threat Intel
Berger to the business and it's a really
hard question to answer in Greek because
it's really gonna matter again we're
going to come back to that context
matters fly it's really gonna matter
what your business is if you are a
financial company you might want to pull
in financial data from some more public
sources or you might have internal
sources or spreadsheets that you might
want to pull into your popcorn's in
order to identify where your assets are
where your money Joe generated revenues
are and what's important to you to
protect but it's really good question so
the question was what are some of the
more exotic rulings and data sources
that I've seen or integrated with the
solution like this bad thing about that
one per minute there's a pretty
interesting one I've actually done
ICS and scalar integrations with stuff
like this which would actually gather
environment variables from og systems
and environments my gathered performance
data from 10 machines I'm a really big
fan of you
analytics I think that from a threat
intelligence perspective that really
helps to predict what might happen slunk
and Ewing largest lung analytics and
creating cremains bump reports and
analytics observations are other really
good data sources to pull and stuff like
this that really gives you a baseline of
what you should expect and you can then
identify the difference there I think
one of the most exotic ones was when I
had to split up we were taken from a
ticketing system where we started
getting that data into the platform
manipulating and enriching it pulling
the ADA from about 20 different sources
and then pushing it back out and then
distributing into two separate kicking
systems while also managing all the
synchronous data that one was probably
when the most complex and exotic things
I've ever had to do there was a lot of
parsing of proprietary formats that had
to be done so it made it a really
interesting implementation anyone else
as far as parsing company emails to just
say hey I'm concerned about this issue
and then it just searches the email for
keywords in there and tries to figure
out what the threat is
what's researching yes so I've actually
so the question was around has it gone
as far as you look at company emails and
actually read the bodies and get
information out of those and then meet
the students based on it so actually for
a recent client of mine we didn't want
to buy a fishing solution we wrote and
develop and python an entire fishing
solution engine did just that we would
actually go ahead and query for emails
that were reported into but you go to
email box read them parse out the body
automatically can submit all of the URLs
and the attachments to every sandbox we
had the environment so across canoe on
fire
ETI weeds in it the hashes as well as
the actual samples for analysis in the
sandbox
give all that data back generate a
ticket pull it into the Intelligence
Platform
and make a decision on it we also
actually added some machine learn
in there with key words to trigger on so
we were able to identify if there was a
DLP event occurring in that email as
well or compared against a list of
pre-existing emails or emails we've seen
in the past as well we did a lot of that
with regex the side prize which I'm
actually currently working on is I
started writing a entire library in
Python for doing regex DLP definitely so
the question was are there any gotchas
when you're developing intelligence
program that I've run into or discovered
along the way and what kind of problems
have I run into a lot of times
especially when doing like a mass
emigration like this in a threat Intel
program you start to experience a lot of
people coming out of the woodwork snafu
for access to data that they should
never have access to or might not have
had access to and on the same side of
that coin you might find that you start
to discover a lot of data that is
unknown to your organization a lot of
shadow by key groups that now he can
become managed you're not as mezzanine
intelligence analyst who's discovering
all these things and now sweeper access
to all these things you're not always
the most well-liked person because
you'll find that you start tramping on
some people stomping grounds and they
don't taking control or making
suggestions they might not like as much
so my best piece of advice is in in my
experience the best thing you can do and
you're trying to build these programs to
mitigate things like that is build good
working relationships with other teams
you know follow the best principles of
never burn a bridge and I always like to
approach a conversation when I need to
ask them for something I always like to
be prepared to something to offer them
in return that I know they're going to
want that really makes another
conversation
getting those integrations up and
running a lot smoother also having good
content user awareness training ahead of
time before you say to use hey we have
this really cool security newsletter you
could subscribe to you can still find
that there are a lot of people in your
organization who are you know they're
know interested in seeking any advantage
or any special insider thing that they
can get out of your company they're
interested in it just because it makes
them feel special because they have
something that's restricted so you'll
notice that a lot of people might come
and ask for these things without having
a real good understanding of what that
it is and that's why you know when I
first started building critical program
please don't we ever have Monday to eat
and I learned very quickly that was a
bad idea and that's why I now stay when
I present to you I would really suggest
you have to at minimum are restricted in
a non-restrictive the restricted one
normally is better suited for having a
very business contextualized high-level
work and also very technical details as
a relation or ganesh n' and then the
public consumption for your internal
company itself is really good for just
having that high-level no giddy gritty
details and why it was mitigated just
that it was mitigated by something you
had excellent question anyone else
that's a really good question how do i
measure and determine my success of my
Intel program and the answer is really a
little bit obstruct your your return on
investment and your success of your
program is again going to be subject to
your definition of success and before
you start building a program you should
really define what your success that the
program means that might be metrics that
might be your your definition of success
is that you have within your company of
500 people 100 people subscribe to the
public newsletter because then you can
check the box on your user awareness
training and say yes my users are aware
of security risks that they're facing
musician your success definition make me
I want my see stone to be aware of
emerging threats that might affect your
organization and how they affect us so
that they are better prepared by either
reporter ask them hey aqua Cox did you
know ahead of time about this
vulnerability that you just got popped
on or what are you doing to solve this
vulnerability or mitigate this threat
that your competitor is now facing that
those are really important things that
you can use to measure success and your
bearing for success your mileage may
vary it's really gonna depend on what
the goal of your friend Intel program is
and the reason for instantiate it you
know if like many companies your your
instantiated on thread becomes perfect
this aids a buzzword and it's new and
hot and popular in industry right now
and you're you went to a conference like
this and you heard them talk about
threat Intel and we're like oh cool
that's the thing that I should be doing
right now
that's probably not a good reason for
you to have a program and if that's why
you want to program you should really
think a step back and decide well why do
I want it jumping to actually being in
the presentation talking about what it
gets me and keep those things and use
those and metrics has my intelligence
led to me
patching something that was then spotted
in the wild later on so did not get
again that threat that's a really good
metric or threat Intel programs was I
able to prevent something that I know
what if otherwise affected me
did someone who has appeared to me in
industry get popped by something that I
prevented because of an article I read
or because my analyst according to fall
out ahead of time one of the other
things that I really didn't mention a
lot during talk is you can really take a
purple teaming aspect to this that's
that red plus blue team methodology you
can add vulnerability data in here pen
testing results one of the most popular
integrations that I've done in that
graph based platform was actually
thinking like next rows necess
that data and vulnerability data and
cross correlating it to the threat
because then I can come down and say all
right this is the threat you chose to
either accept or mitigate the risk this
is why you're not opt and that really
gives you again that extra context on
what happened why it happened why it
cost what it did and how much it
actually could have potentially cost you
all right if there's no other questions
then thank you guys you've been a
wonderful audience