yeah so you okay alright guys I'm going
to go ahead and get started up here
we'll play the looking for nail room
apologies for the little technical
delays there today I learned that you
need to power a VGA HDMI adapter so guys
can pick that up as well thanks for
joining me today we're gonna be talking
about something I'm very passionate
about my thanks to the any kind team for
having me here this is pretty great
second year awesome real quickly about
myself my name is Jake Letta I am a
manager I work in San Francisco but I'm
from the Capital Region so it's good to
be back actually there's two speakers
here from the Waynesburg new york so
it's kind of cool I think I've been
abandoned for seven years now I've done
a lot of different things that maybe
penetration testing it's a response
teaching external education or mobility
research all sorts of fun things but I
really enjoy infrared as an operating
system it's a learning platform so today
we're going to be talking about that I
included my twitter handle on here but
I'm not very good at Twitter so I have a
contact beast-like again that has more
information on how you can reach me if
you're interested in any things I'm
talking about I want to learn more so
just a quick agenda here's we're going
to be talking about a security feature
on the infrared call that's the Android
we're talking about what it is what's
doing for you in the background and then
we're going to talk about what things
look like before we how does the Android
so go back three or four years and look
at the Android ecosystem and how
exploitation was then and then we're
talking about some new techniques if
let's say you're a penetration tester or
you're doing any auditing what is the
problem in escape look like now what do
you what the things you need to keep in
mind if you're actually trying to attack
and device that it's using SEO effort
and hopefully we have some time for
questions and answers if not I'll get
the conference all today and tomorrow so
feel free to fly me down and ask me
exciting us Android questions so just
some of the goals and hopes and dreams
for people in the audience first and I
want people to understand what a scanner
it is and you probable tip I'm gonna
wear this on your phone it's kind of
just running in the back
doing good things for you but just
understand fundamentally how it works
and why it's there and you know what
it's doing to secure your data and if
this is something you find interesting
and want to learn more about to revive
starting point for you
so if Lassiter penetration tester or if
you just want to go buy a new phone and
start auditing it one of the tools of
techniques you're going to need to use
to actually get started
now the last one is kind of
tongue-in-cheek here but is to just
really talk about Android security kamas
matured over the years I've heard a lot
of comments not just to me but just in
general about infrared security and I
think one of them may be the most mad is
when someone said the only secure
Android phones let me throw on the trash
and okay there's some problems with
Android but it's not the worst operating
system out there there's one worse
things just look at Windows a few years
ago compare that to the new versions of
iOS Android I think it's a stark
contrast in terms of security so those
aren't open up hoping you guys can get
on this so let's talk about ICT and
right here so before we get talking
about this Android and how it works and
we need to kind of just do a little bit
of formal definitions here in terms of
access controls so everyone is familiar
with that controls whether you know it
or not you use them attain ultimate
digital and just in real life but
essentially it's restricting its some
sort of subject or a person or thing
access to an object the object could be
by all the subject could be a user
that's how computers work in we have two
different models here we have the
discretionary access control a lot of us
are familiar with this on Windows and on
Linux by default those are discretionary
access control models in which the
subject can pass control on to other
objects for example on Linux if I owned
a file I can do as I please with that
file which is good for you know sharing
data but it can also lead to some
security vulnerabilities which I'll
demonstrate here and it's just a little
too permissive on things like Android
devices the other model is called an app
or a mandatory access control system and
this is when the policies governed by a
central authority in most cases is going
to be the kernel
Android's both the colonel is enforcing
this and owners even if you own quote
unquote file there's really not much you
can do to share and change things I
can't just say hey I want someone else
to have this file the policy master
really is the person who does that
dictation there and just some examples
here obviously we're talking about SD
Android you can also call it SC for
Android ur SD Android doesn't matter and
I also just wanted to conclude on here I
trusted BSD which is the framework that
Apple iOS uses so this I want to just
kind of point out this this isn't just
an Android thing it's also an iOS it's
on many security platforms so let's take
a look at the lights yeah system and
suggest some weaknesses here in terms of
how it applies to the mobile ecosystem
so first off let's say you have a server
in your house you have you know baby you
mean maybe a couple users for you and
your wife your kids or something or no
yeah awesome so processes running on
there maybe they have users as well and
then you have this sort of like elephant
in the room root user which you know
everyone tells you not to use because
it's very powerful but it's there
and when you are Roo you can do whatever
you want on the system and unfortunately
or fortunately Android is based off of
the Linux kernel which means that this
root user is also there on your phone
even though the Android runtime to play
things like Angry Birds don't need root
privileges and they should right doesn't
make it doesn't make any sense however a
lot of things historically run as group
on your phone
things that you take for granted
everyday things like your volume manager
which is not keen on melting file
systems or your battery sensor David is
running probably historically as root
what this leads to is the problem where
they're vulnerable --'tis discovered
these are the targets that attackers are
they're looking at the volume manager
they're looking at the battery sensitive
looking at any other sort of privilege
process because they're running its room
and once your room you can do all sorts
of exciting things on the phone also the
second point is mostly because I've seen
developers - very silly things in the
app space they can do what they want
with their files and you know maybe that
is a good thing but Google has a whole
platform on how to share data securely
but not everyone does that
right you can do whatever you want with
your files because of the way you learn
a stack works also things like IAP tolls
which are calls to the colonel or you
know unix sockets do not have the
ability to fit into laces that model and
we can't actually enforce controls on my
apples unless we actually restrict file
access to which we're sending me out
which we'll talk about in a few slides
and really we can't get as fine-grained
as we need to write think about think
about like the volume manager right so
the fly management one purpose it
announced drives like a super sister
Alice cries you know I'm out right now -
I'm not surprised it does be privileges
to do that because it's a very sensitive
call Oh what else does it need access to
well I would be nothing a configuration
file maybe a couple other files that
needs access to but it doesn't mean the
entire capabilities of the process and
it gets very messy in trying to
implement that with the traditional and
exact to actually say here's what this
process can and can't do so a lot of us
know more - Millie ER with this this
just illustrates the the nine standard
bits for file manipulation and access
rights on Linux you can ignore the D at
the beginning that's just a directory in
this case but we have read write and
execute these are our like actions here
and we have a three different subjects
we have the owner of the file we have
the group associated with the file and
then we have this guy over here other
right we have everyone else this is just
the negation of the user and the group
so this is any other user on the
and do things to this file and I can set
these bits freely if I am the owner of
the file let's walk through an example
here so let's say we have Alice and
Alice wants to use our information in a
file and she creates the file she puts
the data in the file that she wants to
and because the term files you can do
freely with this file
she now wants to share the date of a Bob
so Bob can access the file you can see
the data as well so she can just send
the permission so Alice maybe she's not
a security person she's just a developer
or she's just someone a hobbyist or
something and she's testing other
permissions so that Bob can access it if
she doesn't want to create a group maybe
she does have the ability to create
group if she just says all right anyone
else you can read this file well maybe
what else didn't realize there is that
by saying the other flag everyone else
besides just Bob can access his file
and now people like Eve or attacker here
can now access that file analysis lost
their data now I know this sounds silly
and contrived in why would anyone do
this but this is this is real life right
this is the applications on your phone
doing this back in 2013
I did some security testing of a bunch
of voicemail application so it was like
this new smart voicemail way that smoked
a bunch of carriers where they were like
you know taking the audio from your
voicemails and transcribing give me the
text messages the saw running on your
phone that's all fun and games but they
were storing all the files world
readable so any app that was on your
phone could just if it knew the path
access to your voicemail all the wav
files and the audio or the uh the text
data that was transcribed from them this
is a big deal right these are production
applications running on a lot of phones
and by default they're installed by your
carrier right so companies like Verizon
Sprint
18t they're including these apps on your
phone whether you realize that or not
and they're doing stupid things like
this so this is a problem so let's talk
about how I see ways to make a
difference here so I said I've seen
Linux because that sort
like the base the base project that I
was created back in me ladies by the NSA
so it was developed under the name
security enhancements for Linux and then
in about 2012 it was ported to Android
and they changed the name and now they
call SCE Android but if you call the
SELinux it's essentially the same thing
the port is different in regards to that
they added new features that support the
intro ecosystem so traditionally SEO
annex was mostly profiles and other
Linux II things but there are other
things I enjoyed that matter such as the
property subsystem system services
subsystem that are not part of SC Linux
process project it only needs to be
they're really more specific towards the
influent so they have ported and they've
actually gone in very separate
directions so Google is no longer
committing to the upstream project which
I'll talk about a few more slides it's
kind of pain but anyway it was
introduced into the AOSP I'll be calling
it this for the rest of the slides this
is the Android core developed by Google
the Android Open Source project is
freely available you can download it you
can build it it was introduced in 2012
but at the end of the year when I 4.2
what's that jelly bean jelly bean came
out he wasn't doing anything it was more
like experimental community they were
just testing things probably using it
internally in end of q3 of 2013 we saw
SC Android move into permissive mode
which we'll talk about here but again
it's not really doing too much at this
time and then in q4 of 2014 so just
about 4 years ago with the introduction
of lollipop we saw switch to enforce
mode so what is mrs. Miller courses
enforce mode well permissive mode was
designed so that the OEMs the developers
can test their policies before they
actually applied them because if they
just rolled out this new feature all of
a sudden everyone's phones are just not
going to work
there's a lot of tuning involved here a
lot of manual analysis that you have to
figure out who needs access to what and
none of this stuff was mapped out yet so
if I didn't permissive mode basically
it's logging things but it's not
preventing actions from taking place
within forced mode we actually block and
optionally a lot of all violations that
occurred so if a the battery demon tries
to access the network driver that's
going to be blocked and it's what any
log potentially you know so my testing
can figure out and the biggest thing
here the most important thing here is
that this is required by Google's
compatibility test suite which means
that if you want to make a phone and
have the Play services on it which is
you know the whole Google runtime you
need to support an SEO NXT enforcement
no questions no changes or you'll get in
trouble by Google and you can pepper
your that you it's required by Google's
compatibility suite so that's important
we'll talk about that and some
shortcomings there but I think that's
great that Google's done that it's sad
that a lot of people turn it off so what
are some of the goals here right so I
talked about the root user and that user
needs to go away it really doesn't need
to be any single user on Android
especially when nobody has access to
that user you can't just plug your phone
into a Linux machine and then type sudo
su and run a command room because no one
has access to read
so no user no proxy should be running as
the root user so then one of the goals
here is to basically neuter that that
user make it not attractive to try to
find processes running through instead
make the context for those processes
very restrictive and make it much harder
for an attacker
also we have all these system David's
again things like the volume manager the
Bluetooth thing all these things running
installer naming all these things are
high value targets on entry and we need
to make them much more difficult to gain
access to and that's these guys here so
devices of device drivers
unix sockets all kernel all kernel back
file systems why does a application need
access
doesn't make any sense for Angry Birds
to be able to access the Sisyphus those
are kernel structures to view
information or set information in the
kernel that normal applications need no
rights to or devices there should be no
reason to have to be talking to replace
your and it's not just say we're going
to get rid of those original Linux that
we're actually going to keep everything
that was there and we're just going to
bolt this on on top of it which just
adds another layer of complexity for an
attacker so my goal here isn't to show
you how to make rules we're not writing
the rules together we're not flying
rules of my demoing rules I just kind of
showing you the format of what a rule
looks like so we can talk about how they
work what the actual start analyzing the
policies on our phones so the first
thing here everything is gonna give a
label all objects whether it's a file a
process to the socket it's everything
it's only here this is the format we
have our action which is either alive
allow or deny whatever the domain this
is basically the subject so this is who
we're talking about if so you'll say
like hey this person here and then this
is the the object type is going to be
the label for our object so this is
something you set for example you could
call my file which is not a good idea
what you could do that the class is the
category which is to say these are
defined categories by Google things like
miles sockets property service there's
plenty more you don't need to edit these
you just basically say this is a file
and that's what you said the class to
and then the permission is the actual
operation you're performing on the
object read/write open-eye octal
whatever you want to do to that
particular class is going to be your
permission so we are going to write one
really good rule here it's just all
night rule and let's say we're a
developer iPhone and we want to work we
have this new binder and we're
introducing it trust me Oh Ian's
introduced lots of new buyers and we're
calling it my tool it's instant bin
directory or whatever and it basically
has a configuration file that it's
laughing so we're going to create an
arbitrary label here called my tool
underscore file and we're going to label
this right here and then we're going to
label also the my tool config file as my
tool underscore thing and then we're
going to create a rule to add this
mapping in these particular actions that
we want it to have it's very
straightforward
allow my tool file my tool to think file
read so now any other operation
performed on this file attempting to
write from it or to it sorry attempting
to execute it attempting to do anything
else other than issue a recall is going
to be tonight it's going to be like
actually so you can see how fine-grained
UK you can really have a process that's
a very singular task and make sure that
it only can do that one task and we'll
see just how big of a deal that is when
we start talking about some of the
exploits we see in the wild and why it
matters so rules are defined in these TV
files if you just google like SC Linux
te Google source you'll find a bunch of
them on Google's hungry clothes but
there are dozens of TV files it is all a
boilerplate framework for you if you
just now go to the indigo open source
project and you want it to start
building a device have a really good
starting you do need to change things
especially you start introducing you
hardware and software we have a good
start there's all these macros to help
you here and you will need to change
like there's no real questions there you
have to change things to work on your
device and that's going to be to the
advantage of the attacker because the
people who are making the changes are
not Google and are not people who do
this probably a day in and day out and
breathe security just bills get the
process here we have all of our TV files
which are rules all of our definitions
up here this is like this black box here
that bundles it all up compiles it and
out pops this little tool here it's on
your phone it's a binary file call se
policy and sitting in the directory on
your phone
all the rules inside of it and the
colonel is going to load that guy up and
that's what it's going to check every
time it wants to do any sort of action
on the phone it's gonna come into play
when we actually start looking at any
particular device so let's look at what
it looked like before and I have a
couple of case studies here and I think
it will strengthen the shortcomings of
Android so it used to be as I kind of
mentioned a couple times now a race to
read it was as soon as you execution the
game is over and you just put the phone
saw rootkit what you wanted to and in my
experience this is one to two estimates
we're not looking at anything crazy
especially in the early days and you
could pretty much do what you wanted on
the phone like for this group users from
local kernel modules that's probably not
something that any production phone even
needs to support at this point and some
phones it's turned off but the fact that
the root user is there and can do that
is a problem and again as I mentioned it
numerous times now a majority of the
injury core processes outside of things
running Angry Birds are running as root
so there's a huge attack surface here so
we're gonna go back 2011 here and talk
about the ginger break vulnerability
which affected gingerbread which is so
long ago but still worth talking about
this was one exploit that exploited the
volume manager game and which I've
already brought up which was running a
screw that is essentially designed for
when you plug in an SD card every one
phone statistique cards or when you plug
in you a speed you want to mount a drive
the volume manager takes over and says
yeah I'll I'll apply this for you I'll
format things for you problem is there
was some issues with it particularly an
exposed meddling socket which I'm not
going to spend too much time talking
about the whole explanation here this is
already documented I didn't find this
other people did but essentially you
have this this socket that you can open
here and that link type and you just
send a message to this socket which is
linked up with the kernel and then it
does something which ultimately leads
you to be able to introduce a sec UID
binary and for all the security folks in
the room know
I said you I denied areas that we
control the games over right you can
execute that route so let's look at this
if we compare it with SE Android so a
lot of these actions almost all of them
are completely just muted right we no
longer can open net Ling sockets sorry
this is not a thing anymore right you
shouldn't have been able to do that
anyway I don't know why you would have
been you just can't do that anymore
even things like padding files in the
proc directory there's no reason why
process should be trying to figure out
it's command line by accessing the proc
file system there are other you guys
that can be used for that I guess if you
needed to do that just doing things like
walking off the tables end it anymore
these actions right here like being on
the call remount just not gonna work in
this context you can still do send you I
need although this has changed a lot in
more recent versions of Android however
you're still running in the same context
after you set UID so it probably doesn't
really matter too much so completely
removed even if the vulnerabilities
still existed on the phone today oh we
saw this was a few years later 2014
reported by John Sawyer or J pace on
Twitter he's a very popular a very loud
person on Twitter who talks about
vulnerabilities if you're interested in
a lot of his work on early Android
exploitation it's very inspiring for me
to learn about these things but this
particular vulnerability affected HTC
devices and it was local privilege
escalations a root using a UNIX socket
so again we're noticing a trend here
I've even talked just on UNIX sockets
and custom how silly they are but the
truth is everyone uses UNIX sockets on
the enjoy because they need it for IPC
in the Linux face this one was so
ridiculous it was just the UNIX socket
that there was a there's actually a
driver that was loaded that had a
function call that move file and it
would execute it as like the kernel
context so any application with the
which let's be honest every application
needs the internet nowadays could
literally just move and copy files and
do things to aspect privileges so we're
talking one exploit here one single
thing to go from the lowest privileged
app with the internet permission to
complete control of your phone of course
this is fixed but here's the big thing
it was accessing the UNIX socket in the
dead socket driver
there's no reason any application should
be interacting with those this was for
HTC to do some privileged things I don't
really know what they were trying to do
here but there's no reason that should
be interacting at all even reading from
that directory so this this whole vector
this whole suite of vulnerabilities as
effectively been mitigated as an
unprivileged app just because you can't
even tell us anything in the dev
director that's good that makes that
makes me feel good about things a few
years later this is one that I actually
reported to Qualcomm this one was a
vulnerability in the net D daemon which
was in Qualcomm specific for work
branches which is still millions of
devices outside military devices
this was around for a long time so I
found this in 2015 but chances are
others I was hanging around for quite a
while now this is a cone excuse net room
in this case it's radio but the radio
user is a privileged user on Android
notably and has access to the base man
which need also some other issues there
again we're talking one exploit as a
third-party application to be able to
access the base man so there's
particularly mobility besides just
accessing the base band it can also
allow you to read and write SMS
again why is the net deep the net D game
is responsible for assigning IP
addresses managing your DHCP leases why
can that read or write your SMS database
well they didn't have a way to say that
this particular process needs to are
privileged but they can't do these
actions so we have this huge attack
surface I also do filesystem activities
that like write to directories on areas
that it really had no right
do and had really good access to the
property subsystem which will see if we
come to play a little later but the
property subsystem is essentially like
the Windows registry and with also with
events that you can trigger on when
interactions are made there see the
setup alerts for when this property
changes do this particular action which
is really fun if we can actually make
changes to those properties so let's
look at this one that's the injury
well this one's face I just can't do
that anymore because the netd gaming is
running under a policy that doesn't let
it access the contacts anymore that's
good
the base page you can still access it
unfortunately there's really not much
you can do about that because it's
designed to interact with radio the file
system access has been revoked so you
wouldn't be able to do that
unfortunately you can still alter and
it's the network stack because again
this is the networking David and the
property subsystem has been completely
revamped
with the introduction of SD Linux or se
Android so that has changed and it's
much more restrictive now there's one
last idea here I just want to point out
and that is basically that not
everything's changed right a lot of
embedded devices that aren't Google
sponsored phones are running Android
things that you don't even probably
realize that conference moments are all
Android based now you your cars are
running in from all children's toys
that's a lot of children's toys oh my
god and just insert random IOT device
anything sure refrigerators are running
like Linux or Android and the truth is
like the cold hard truth is people are
just turning this off because they don't
need to use it they don't want to
develop it
they're just shutting it off and I've
seen this numerous times and I put it as
finding blocks and reports like a
straight up just turn this off and
there's just no one but just because
this is hard you have to do a lot of
tuning and all these developers
especially wants to or economy of China
no offense are just not thinking about
security as before
they're trying to push the product I eat
our children's tablet that I don't know
what it lets you do have your kids learn
or something is they don't care about
SEO X they don't care about us he
enjoyed everything is running on Groupon
those phones like it doesn't matter it's
back we're back in 1998 again here and
it's very easy to compromise anything
that's not a Google sponsor for okay
let's talk about monitoring devices
wordlessly so I like I was when I was
doing some work previously a co-worker
of my comment done when I can exploit a
for a vulnerability he was like and this
looks a lot like a Rube Goldberg machine
and I was like what's that it's if
anyone's going like mousetrap before
like we're like the ball hits the lever
which lights a candle it's like all
these different actions that have to
occur that's kind of what we're dealing
with now that's the reality what it
looks like now where it's not just lets
one run exploit and we root over here we
have to do all this silly things jumping
from context to context potentially just
to get if the rights we need to do a
specific action
so yeah that's ourselves different
questions no longer LS and run our PS
and run graphical route that's not gonna
work anymore
well we need to think about is what's
our okay are we trying to write into the
SMS babies because then we need to focus
on context that have access to that are
we trying to release an exploit that
gives us root privileges so we can
actually solve malware well you have to
focus on context or target a context
that has a suspect or user doesn't
matter it you can have a really low
privileged user that has all sorts of se
Android
modifiers which give it more right than
you had before and then my favorite
favorite things to talk about
all right changes by the OEMs it changes
to the Android Open Source project
because this is where the bugs are sick
I've talked about this for years and
I've reported
dozens of vulnerabilities in vendors
like HTC Qualcomm LG these guys are not
as good at security as Google has been
in protect
there and that's just my opinion but I
mean that's what I've seen that's where
I'm staying so I like to focus on the
differences so if I have a huawei phone
what's different look let's look at the
Android policy the SELinux policy and
say what changes have a big is your
sequel airing changes even if it's like
some ones that are forced turning on
that doesn't mean they can't tweak it
and change the way things work right
they can't figure something out they'll
just slap on a modifier that gives that
process full rights so ok so let's say
let's say we're getting into more some
more technical detail so let's say we
actually want to we have a phone and our
friend is giving us we want to start
looking at it the very first thing you
need to do is you need to get access to
the policy box and the labeling class
these are all gonna be present on the
phone on most phones they are accessible
the biggest one here is SE policy SE
policies have binary file that's loaded
up by the kernel which tells you all the
rules that are gonna be performed the
rest of these are just for labeling
right so this is the file context which
was in binary format for one version of
Android it's going to happen
mappings from filing to move context
same thing for services service name to
move context properties properties to
context you get the idea last one here's
an XML file that has our labeling for
applications this is how applications
need to behave because even applications
get labels now to pull these off you can
use the Android debug bridge shell user
if you have a firmer no I'm pulling out
of that I've used that the past or maybe
I can't get to the yes the Android files
because sometimes they're just not
accessible but you get them from a
firmware don't most of these files are
clear text it's super easy to understand
with the exception of the file context
which was converted to a binary format
and nougat and then they immediately
switched it back I couldn't find any
parsers that were written not in C most
of my Chinese forms I don't want in
Python and it's someone you know if for
some reason you're testing a new your
phone it's easy
by their policies while try the Pinery
context file just it's just a simple
script that just parts of the structure
is pretty straightforward now
unfortunately this se policy file which
is a binary format through and through
is a completely different story so we're
gonna circle back really quickly I just
want to show you how this works let's
say you run an ADB shell command so or
this is specifically for the Huawei
honor running in this case I believe
this isn't good
I'm ready to be shelf and then I'm
running the ID come in and you can see
my context is nested right down here at
the bottom after all my traditional
Linux death thinks here all the groups
and users I'm in here's my context I'm
running as a shell context so that's a
good starting right if we're gonna start
poking around on this phone we need to
assume we're starting as the shell
context not so much the shell user
obviously it's still important as well
but knowing that running is the shell
context is key because that's the access
we have okay so we have our context we
have a parts testing policy file I
encourage you to go on google and type
in parsing SE policy Android you're
gonna get this link right here it's on
Stack Overflow it's like four years old
and it's someone saying hey I just want
to parse this file can someone please
help me and this guy says well I've been
looking into this you think this would
be easy
blah blah blah as I'm talking about it
and really comes down you because Google
has fork the code they they're kind of
doing all this stuff behind the scenes
and they're not really publishing the
tools that a normal user would use to
search as an policy because why because
om don't need this they have their own
testing Suites and the only person means
this is me who doesn't have access to
the source code it doesn't have access
to the TV files this is stuff for
attackers there's not publishing that so
I reached out to the give up guy who is
maintaining the SE policy well mostly
just be su nice work of Android or deny
the mainstream project
and I said hey you know straight schools
really helpful like what are your plans
to support Android and he very kindly
replied the next day and said hey I have
no plans of doing this so thanks anyway
he closed it
so basically we're not gonna get any
mainstream support for STD policy
parsing which sucks so let's go back to
this guy here this is a his start of his
question or his answer well here's his
answer all you have to do is first clone
Android which is about 70 gates last
time I checked and then set up a build
environment which is probably a day or
two of work yeah and then you download
this other tool and make these changes
to these four files it's all these
dependencies by the way if things don't
work there's some alternate instructions
here then you can finally do these other
operations here which will help you
build some other core libraries yeah so
you can do all these things and it
actually works so if you take the time
to do as I say Google this this is the
process right now right this is the way
things work unfortunately once you have
the binaries in the bindings you know
you can share them with your friends or
whatever but the trick here is you need
to get access to do all these steps just
to be able to run the SE search command
which in its glory is here so the SE
search command is going to be a way for
us take the policy file which is binary
and then run searches for in the context
we care about really straightforward
easy example here I'm going to search
the SC policy file for that honor that
polyfoam show me all the files that I
can write to as this gel contacts here
they are here all the labels that I have
access to where I have the right
privilege and then do that additional
layer here look for the things that are
different how about the stuff Huawei
sensor this is some new sensor new label
that was not part of Android it's a very
easy process to do that
here you can just basically dip this
list it you know these things will stand
out this one even says Huawei in it so
it's even easier well what is that
let's find out let's find out all the
files that are labeled as this at best
Huawei sensor and look at this these are
all again on this the kernel fact
filesystem sisyphus in the system every
these are direct interfaces to read and
write to potentially the kernel which in
itself is not a vulnerability right it's
just an avenue for an attacker to now as
a monk privileged user potentially
interface with the kernel send data to a
receive data from it what happened so
each one of these will need to be
investigated but what can we do with the
Huawei ALS info structure I don't know
but this is the process you take you
find the context you map it see things
like files look again properties are in
the important services are going to be
important and you're gonna want to look
through what exactly this context can do
and it may not be beneficial to go
strengthen the goal right you may not be
able to find a context that has access
to something super sensitive which means
you're gonna have to go back to every
Goldberg machine like model where you
have to jump around and you just take
baby steps get yourself into a platform
at first and then focus on something
more advanced the property subsystem is
also like I said really instrumental and
key to the injury model and there are
some properties that you should be aware
of that if you're in these times if you
have access to this context and you're
gonna already have code execution or
some sort of privilege escalation that
would be this system problem if you can
get a context that has this you got a
lot of surface that you can now it cover
because you can now interact with a lot
of system properties that normal apps
are not expected to be able to access so
you can make all sorts of funky changes
the properties that other processes are
loading from Italy also maybe look for
those triggers I'll sell you
you can actually have actions occur when
you modify properties also the default
CTL problem label is the lingual
required to start and stop in it
services and it services mostly Ranas
routes though and they're not usually
labeled the very restrictive labels
because they're just not so getting in
one of these two is going to be really
big again look for non ASP properties is
an example right here this would be
running the SE search and I'm looking
for if I'm the net d-david so let's say
we exploited my qualcomm bug here and
we're looking for properties that we can
set on quali honor we could set all
sorts of stuff in addition to read only
ones which are kind of fun I would like
to be able to write to read only ones
but that's just that's kind of how
things look here also all these ones
down here these are all non Android Open
Source these are all added by glowing
right so now I can now modify the camera
tuning dump property which again no I'm
not sure what that does but now you take
this as a starting point it's our
reverse engineering the binaries
associated with these it or looking at
these and you may have managed actually
been building all right additional files
all sorts of exciting things this one
this is ro probably one just also
there's another Avenue you take if your
goal is to just kind of map out the
context
look for ones that have learn called
capabilities NFC ways so capabilities
are these like power features that you
can just tack on into a process and let
you do all sorts of good things so how
about dak override let me talk about
what acts are and I mentioned that we're
gonna use the old lending stack and
we're gonna pull this on top now you
have a context the deck override none of
those rules apply in the kernel level it
doesn't matter if the file is readable
as anyone if you have that
Dec over I agreed obviously just for
reading sis module we can now we can out
randomly enforce if kernel modules are
loaded by having the SIS model
capability but as you can see down here
I'm looking for all the contacts that
have a exist module and the net D
capability aren't that big data has the
ability a little kernel modules or how
about this looks like we have a Wi-Fi
driver or something so there's still
avenues here that can be use it for
those of you who have to go with kernel
modules just let you load code in the
Linux kernel once you can do that it's
again game over because we can directly
F owner this one lets you basically you
just kind of destroys the file
permissions very similar back override
and some of these are just like super
privilege right I have this well I think
this is the Huawei networking daemon
here this thing to do everything right
so basically what this is saying is
don't worry about this process know just
don't apply the SE Android policies to
it it can do pretty much whatever it
wants so these are your high-value
targets and so things you're in love
with you to any particular phone can
have a number of these that you should
actually focus on so I wanted to kind of
wrap this up I know we're a few minutes
left here and just do a little quick
case thing so in 2016 well early 2016
I found a bunch of bugs in grenoble
phones that they try to downplay it but
it affected like 60 other different
models mostly international that the EU
root code execution also a privileged
context so not only can we have a remote
execution we also had a very privileged
context and it was kind of fun to spend
a lot of time creatively yeah you guys
like brothers should he go here but
anyway we were born into them and they
were receptive eventually and we finally
got a chance to blog about it
no more I wasn't started I'm pretty
proud of it it talks about in very
technical detail how we went through and
each PC to use that word son what they
are how they work how they play typing
so I'm going to talk about it very
briefly here but essentially it's code
execution is route through a a semi
protected unit side so again everything
kind of comes back to the state court
metals things like unique sockets since
the past really the targets we want to
focus on what we found is that there's
this process nak server is running his
route I was running a fairly privileged
SELinux I see every context it listens
on a local UNIX socket for those of you
not polluted UNIX sockets it's really
just a socket on IP addresses it's just
some sort of way to communicate between
ID processes and I I kid you not the
purpose of the statement is to receive a
command on the UNIX socket it executed
this is the literal definition of a
backdoor and this was on every little
phone worldwide so this let's pretend
that SC Linux is not around let's say we
didn't have it one gullibility game over
right where I done we have a process
running his room it's the same thing as
that HTC ball turbo that Chancellor
reported to the 14 but this one was on
every mobile home however there was the
Android on the phone that I had which
means we had to jump around a little bit
we couldn't just interact with the UNIX
socket because as you see here if I try
to connect someone using just so cat or
something I get permission denied and
then if you copy the kernel buffers
we'll see that yes there has been a SC
Linux prescient violation you cannot
access this out of that socket that's
wonderful but who can access that for
that socket that's our very next
question is if I can do it
okay well turns out if you're a system
app or a platform app you can do that
and there's also 60 or 70
platform apps on the phone that I was
happy
five by the way so now our target ship
now we're just going to find any running
process that's labeled as platform app
and here's one right here the idea
friend application this was their
Lenovo's implementation of the content
the contacts app which had a nice little
bug in it where they basically loaded
jars at runtime that were on signed and
executed code from them so we could
create backup of the app and then modify
the jars so it was code execution as a
platform app which is wonderful so now
we can talk to a socket you're just a
fun little picture of us running the
vulnerability by the exploit here we
basically create a bunch of custom
backups to your stage our payload and
then we can trigger the bug by talking
to the Uni sockets sending a the command
for it to run and lo and behold we have
a shell through here with this this
context called group Channel so like
they even knew what this was they label
it as root Channel because this was
meant to run group commands again it's
not a completely compromised in my mind
it was you know job well done you can do
a lot but there's a few things you
couldn't do for example you really
couldn't mess with the kernel too much
so we can't turn off that's the Android
that's great
that's actually pretty good and you
couldn't read my house so we couldn't
create like a persistent backdoor phone
but again we probably need one more bug
from here and we can buy some driver
that has issue with it and with that I
want to close things up here so just to
wrap up if you have a phone that is
sponsored or proved by Google that was
released after 2014
there's a very strong chance that your
phone is protected by a secret and
that's great you don't have to do
anything you don't even know that's
there you don't need to know it's really
changed where the attack surface looks
on phones and it's changed what the
Tigers are looking for and I think here
is another wrap up by them but masking
what this stuff is kind of a pain
because you have to go this lengthy
build process to get the binaries that
you need to actually plumb queries but
from there it's just using this
search by Harrington to dig around and
look for exciting things on your phone
the exploitation process has really no
longer justify group and then exploited
which for the longest time is when I
would you know just do ps4 ooh and then
I would look at unix sockets and find
which ones mapped to each other and then
I would just paused to that evening
socket and so we figured out what it did
I can only do that anymore which is good
you don't want that's a new case unless
OMS are disabled against the Android
which I could assure you with that here
are some additional resources so if you
want to learn more first definitely
start with this slide this slide back
here the case for security has enjoyed
this was written by God the NSA
basically championing us the Android say
hey this is why we need this he goes
through like four or five key sites
about why this is important is
beneficial very good starting point
really illustrates some of the case
studies I went through you made a lot of
good information there last year I got a
chance to see the a if we will talk
about why he's the head of security at
Android and he was talking about why
they decided to use SD enjoy but are
their motivations and put they see on
the Google side which again I'm work at
Google I'm not sponsored by Google but
this is a great idea it works very well
I also recommend checking that you can
find online recipes are just technical
applause this is these guys right here
oh man if you want to learn all the
functions that have been modified that
Linux kernel to support this there is
those of your slides right there the
Android documentation is also quite good
so check that out and then I included
the links to the fireEye blocks
Qualcomm elated vulnerability and Noble
vine and with that I wanted to see if
anyone had any questions I know
everyone's antsy it's lunch
does anyone have any questions kugel
Sims look very good actually Samsung
would be my I think my second pick so if
the Gould cares a lot about this and the
Nexus series the pixel series is what I
own anyway I wanna give you phone just
just buy the Nexus 5 pixel they don't
need my recommendation samsung also
cares a lot the other Korean
manufacturers are less less good they're
receptive but they're just not quite
unwell Samsung and then you've got a
whole different ball game you could be
diving this of the Chinese ones like
Xiaomi Huawei those ones just really
aren't as good they're actually getting
a lot better the Huawei honor I was
messing with earlier this year was
actually much better than I thought it
was gonna be
yeah the honor it's very good I had to
show me five to me five and that one
who's not very good bunch of bugs on
that pad it was hard to get a hold of
the show-me guys at report but anyway
they're much sort of doubles here below
I would say so
like Google mostly craniums in the
Chinese ones
[Music]
interview questions so they're there
forking the project and they're usually
they're usually pretty supportive of
things like SEO instance up they usually
make changes as well that's the question
I get a whole bunch when I talk about
the OEM stop they're always like well
how about like sighs you mob are they
doing and the question is I really don't
know I'd love to spend more time like
actually looking at with first decide to
monitor all these other various things
like that are doing my guess is they're
also not quite as good as Google I would
imagine that they're doing their best in
there they're probably keeping it on
yours I think all those os's want to
they want to still have the Google Play
services so they still need to use
things like I think I actually haven't
won that one plus I just don't have any
more plus devices but I actually would
really like today whether old is like
oxygen loss or whether they call it a
little for injury so I'd look at theirs
either but it's very similar like
they're working off it they're doing a
lot of changes that if I get my hands
No so it really comes down to is like
what phones do I want to buy because
some work it's like supporting what
they're like hey bones here so I I have
like hundreds of phones just like
sitting in like my closets up any
they're like brand-new phones that I
probably should sell but I buy only look
at it I actually really liked blackberry
phone so black guy came out with the
ribs if you know that doesn't fifteen
that's up to the phone that I found the
Qualcomm bug on smells like so excited
I'm like oh man I have the blackberry
and I'm like oh wait it's like every
phone but that phone was really good
like those guys they must have hired
like a really in the weeds because that
was actually what started Emma started
all this research is like I got the
print by my blackberry and I'm like man
the stink is like a rock like what is
going on here and then I realized all
the sexy lady so who's the end of the
way and then I would like try it on like
a nexus so I'm like man this is actually
like way better than will be started
with so I guess the answer your question
a little better blackberry is also very
good any other questions in you say or
you set up there about that with the
changes it greatly complicates hacking
it or breaking it for an attack surface
greatly complicated meaning that there
still could be a possibility of breaking
it yeah absolutely I don't mean I think
any seven and it's that making it harder
this is a good set right direction but
unfortunately there's something like an
unhackable phone is like for me the
harder they can make it and the harder
they can make it without even knowing I
think it's also a good idea but I mean
yeah there's I mean look at the Qualcomm
thing which works with s the Android but
although one works with se Android this
isn't B this is also isn't the only
feature
right like things like the Amer you
which have you talked about it has
really changed the senior as well that
provides secure cool and secure
framework there's a lot of other things
schools doing as well just to make this
threat landscape smaller but yes it's
it's always gonna be yeah I mean that's
a concern I think I think the developers
probably are aware of exactly what
function calls Maps permission thing so
they probably just read a sack or floor
phone mission or something and they're
very loose about that the other thing
too is with Apple models you're trusting
the OEMs right you're trusting that in
order to get the phone number I have to
provide information to do that guarantee
any phone in the market right now there
is a bypass for reading the meia without
because someone's going away maybe I
guess I don't know why but they're gonna
write an API in turn a subjective
immission constraints so the model kind
of falls apart when that's like
fundamentally broken I think the bill
Grady is does help you understand what
the app can do you'd probably need the
ability to load kernel module that in
the kernel either like or instruct over
on structures or disable it from the
kernel so you need code execution not
just as the root user but in the kernel
to kernel is the I guess you could
technically I guess overwrite the policy
pop all right so if you could if you
could somehow remail file systems it
over a policy file one label in files
that would be a attack vector there the
problem is those are all sort of
assistant partition because the DM very
that partition cannot change or the
phone so that's like I said more
features here you if the ID a like
persistent like boom kits or backdoors
on Android are kind of dead because you
have to also disable the Ameri which is
way harder and requires much more things
because you can't make changes to
sensitive files anymore so like you and
it's on with the SU binary is a trick
now because they have to have like a new
file system for it because they used to
just throw that high on the system
partition and then now you have a assume
I'm Harry but you can't do that anymore
[Music]
I think Google does I mean I honestly I
can't speak to exactly what they're
doing just cuz I don't have a lot of
visibility into that many arguing things
but is it enough maybe a lot of it also
comes down to I have a lot of homes that
are Google's sponsored are approved
which means that using third-party app
stores and who knows what they're doing
right like used to be a lot of the
Chinese phones have their own markets
and it's you have a whole different
ballpark when that's not what Google
intended for things to do and I think
that that is probably more of a risk to
me is having the other markets that I
think Google does that or something I
imagine if I wanted to I think it helps
in terms of like this thing and this
like whole thing America probably not
there like definitely like data
investment stuff like the actually
they're changing how encryption works do
they're actually go into a more I Oh s
like model work there's like a key that
derives other keys which then are you
some like profile basis that's like I
think it would Oreo but I don't know if
it's gonna affect this process because
all this stuff is gonna be once the
phones on and run again once that also
is transparent to us that but I'm sure
it helps like everything else right
anything they can do think it's harder
okay
great and then that's all the questions
here guys this is my contact
you want to talk to me man name email
it's on there but also my personal email
my Twitter tweet at me all forgot I
retweet things and just some of my other
stuff before our research blog I kind of
put stuff on it when everybody gets
people stuff my blog my website my
github what's wrong as well so thanks
for joining us with you guys something