it is Islam thank you for the
introduction this is joint work together
with colleague Britta Hale and Sebastian
lower both here as well as the Tebow
yogurt and it's about key exchange so
this nice principal this neat principle
that allows to remote parties to
establish a shared symmetric crypto key
over in secure connections now in
practice turns out that this keychain
step can be quite a bottleneck so assume
you have one message that needs to be
sent back and forth between the client
Alice and Bob the server and this means
that Ellis has to wait for this one
round-trip time before she can actually
send beta so now if you're on a high
latency for example a mobile networks
this will incur quite an overhead quite
a delay of potentially many hundred
milliseconds so a solution to this is to
employ a zero round-trip time key
exchange protocol a keychain protocol is
around your time it requires only a
single message to be sent from the
client to the server in order to
establish a key this means that Ellis
along with this key exchange message can
already use that key to encrypt data
that shows travels along with that
message he doesn't have to wait for a
response from the server now they're on
to time T exchanges theoretically not a
new concept but has gained quite some
practical attention over the last year's
for being an explicit goal in Google's
quick protocol as well as in the
upcoming TLS version 1.3 they are
however two main security drawbacks with
0 at time T exchange they're both kind
of stemming from the fact that is that
the server cannot actively contribute to
that exchange the first one is replay
attacks adversary may simply go and copy
the key exchange message and the
accompanying message the competing data
being sent and replay this to the server
now the server doesn't take extra care
who will just decrypt this data again
and basically what you have is a
replayed message
replate data in items now turns out in
some settings this is essentially
unavoidable as for example has been
discussed by erik rhodes scholar and
adam Langley at last year's real-world
Krypton the second big issue with
toronto time key exchange is forward
secrecy or other the lack of it so the
server will use some kind of secret key
to authenticate and derive the session
key for that key exchange nowadays
adversary later compromises that keys
because there is no FML contribution
from the server it has everything to
decrypt the data because it can derive
the same key just simply again now as
you know forward secrecy is considered a
crucial institutional and very important
security goal in particular to prevent
mass surveillance but it means the lack
of it here is particularly unfortunate
but commonly considered an inherent
limitation of the round-trip time key
exchange in this work we are ever show
that this common belief is actually
false so we build a 0 nship time key
exchange protocol which achieves full
forward secrecy so to understand how
this works let's first have a look at a
somewhat related scenario that of a
synchronous messaging so here Ellis
wants to send some message over to Bob
without any preceding communication well
this can be solved of course by pure
simple public key encryption you just
encrypt this message under the public
key evolve in it what you want to do but
does leave you with the same problem of
liking forward secrecy of course now
already back in 2003 karate halarian
taps showed how to achieve a chorus
notion of forward secrecy by employing a
hierarchical identity based encryption
scheme under settings so for this you
would divide time into some course
intervals and then the secret key
correspond stage of this interval now
virtually comes and compromises some it
some secret key this means you cannot
decrypt mess
just from earlier intervals still within
the same interval it can decrypt all
your messages being sent so it's just
giving you some coarse grained notion of
forward secrecy and this is why in 2015
Green & Myers came up with a more
fine-grained approach to forward secrecy
which they called punctual forward
secret encryption and for this they
fused this hive approach with an
additional attribute based encryption
scheme and it allows you to take the
secret key of some interval and puncture
out the capability to decrypt specific
ciphertext you've seen already and by
this removing this capability you get
forward secrecy for these life at X and
this is where our idea starts for this
work so our core observation is that
this type of spunk sharable forward
secret encryption relatively directly
yields forward seekers around to time T
exchange our technical contribution is
then twofold so the first thing is we
establish functionable forward secret
key encapsulation as the core building
block for this protocol so here
encapsulation simply means instead of
encrypting a message we're encrypting a
symmetric key we then show how to build
such pls camps in a generic way from any
hierarchical identity base camp such
that we achieve strong CCA security
without relying on the random Oracle
that way improving over the previous
designs the second step will then show
again generically how to build from any
such PF s kem a forward secrecy around
to time key exchange protocol it's part
of this we formalize what key exchange
security means for forward secrecy
around to time and proof that our
protocol achieves the security you want
to see them now l don't have time to go
into any real details let me give you an
overview a glimpse of how our protocol
works so we have Alice and Bob Ellis
holding the public here Bob and Bob
corresponding secret key now in order to
run a session what Ellis will do is will
substitute with simply encapsulate a
symmetric key for Bob and tense over
this encapsulating ciphertext at this
point you can immediately use this key
as well to encrypt the start encrypting
data on the other side what will then do
two things first of all it will decap
cyl eight the key and just find able to
decrypt the data that might be arriving
from Ellis now the second step is will
take its secret key and puncture out
this remove the capability to derive
this key again and this is what gives
you this immediate forward secrecy so
how is this puncturing functionality
enable in the protocol in this design so
essentially the secret keep up holes is
a part of a hierarchical key structure
in the beginning but will hold the root
node in this tree now with a hypertext
arrived let's say 01 but we'll use this
root node to derive the secret key
corresponding to that cipher text in
order to D capsulate it will then
puncture this key embedded which means
it removes all the nodes on the way from
the root note to this leaf node in order
to not be able anymore to decrypt to
derive this key again instead as the new
secret key it will store the siblings on
the path from the root to the leaf and
this allows him to derive still all the
other keys in the tree now this process
is repeated and when I knew the next
cybertek survives it first p calculate
the corresponding with the corresponding
secret key and then punctures out this
capability now the spot we'll just
proceed like this the secret key size
will grow rather quickly namely linear
in the number of sessions that Bob's
running so we need to do some more here
and we do is we need to add another
layer on top of this tree which
separates the which devices three into
some course time intervals the two
parties agree on and can be for example
date now when one time interval is over
that can simply remove the corresponding
subtree and by this reduced
size of the secret key back to a
logarithmic amount of data to be storage
okay so what are the properties of the
scheme net of this protocol well first
of all it is useful forward secrecy
through this puncturing approach it is
as soon as the key exchanges over
leaking compromising the public the
secret key of Bob will not affect the
security of this session anymore
puncturing also gives you replay
protection at least on the key exchange
level because you simply can't be
capsulate the same ciphertext twice for
performance we did a rough
implementation based on a hype scheme
based Bible ezekiel's and tom was
published at crypto 2014 as it turned
out this was not the optimal choice I'll
come to that in a second but we still
want to share this initial evaluation
with you here so first of all on the
client side encapsulation is very
efficient taking only a few milliseconds
like in order of like 10 milliseconds on
a regular laptop on the server side the
purity capsulation of the key in order
to be able to decrypt takes the same
amount of time but arriving in the tree
the corresponding secret key depending
on your hollow tree looks like maybe
relatively expensive and can take up to
roughly a second and this key
allegations key derivation step is
particularly expensive in this dkp
scheme so this is why it was not an
optimal choice and which means that
puncturing in particular can be very
costly or is very costly because they
are potentially many intermediate nodes
to be derived in order to come up with
the next punctured secret key still why
this is now another practical
instantiation there is hope for two
reasons first there are other schemes
which have more efficient key delegation
so that's not a particular focus on hype
schemes but there are other schemes for
example by gender & silverberg where
this step is more efficient and it's not
this needs to be looking looked at
second the dkp scheme provides the
strong notion of adaptive security we're
actually our scheme only requires the
weaker weaker notion and they
selectively secure
t-that means there are there's quite
some space for improvements both on the
implementation side as well as for
research in better suited hype schemes
that can be then just plucked into this
generic construction okay so to
summarize first of all fully forward
secret the round-trip time key exchange
exists so we show this way providing a
simple protocol which is provably secure
and where the core building block
punctual forwards secret p encapsulation
can be built from any hierarchical
identity-based chem screen the big open
question is how to make this practical
both through optimized schemes and
optimized implementations of the scenes
right this brings me to the end of my
talk thank you very much for you
so we have a couple of minutes for
questions go right ahead hi i'm
interested in your thoughts on denial of
service attacks against bed scheme i was
thinking if the initial size of the
message Alison's Bob's Heather
particularly small Mallory could for
example just send enough of her own to
puncture out a large portion that tree
or if its large enough that's not
feasible just send enough the hopefully
overwhelmed memory on Bob side trying to
keep track of this tree before he needs
to expire it yeah so so definitely a
meanness and because there's some quite
some heavy crypto involved on the
service side does resilience is
something to to be looked at in
particular you want to add potentially
if you're if you're under under attack
you want to add some cookie mechanisms
to be sure that at least the clients I
want to talk to you a legitimate and
really do want to talk to you and this
kind of stuff but it's beyond what what
we look into here thank you okay hello
can you talk about how your scheme works
with a fleet of servers that don't share
real-time state because that's what
session because sold for us in TLS and
if we didn't if we had shared said we'll
probably just use essentially session I
did so can you claim talk about that
right sure so the industry basically so
one thing is like you have to sit on the
cross the time and then within a time
interval the the tree is basically
formed along the ciphertext so what you
could do for some kind of load balancing
is that you would say pile like I split
the rain or leave the space of these
ciphertexts among my service that I have
and then each of the server has to keep
consistent stays within this share of
the of the type of texting i was
thinking more about am geographically
distributed network like clouds or
assignee caps we have like one pop in
Europe one in the US and we can't just
look balance between the two based on
ciphertext okay and we would need to
look into this closer I don't ever think
it absolutely
execution the puncturing step seems to
rely on the message actually arriving
could the adversary attack forward
secrecy properties of the system simply
by dropping messages sorry can you
repeat that love could be adversary
attack be forward secrecy properties of
the system simply by dropping messages
in so the point it's like you will get
you will do the punishing assumes a
message arrived so in particular if you
if you can if you hold the message in
slide and like that you you compromise
in that sense you compromise basically
the service key before he sees the
message and can puncture you don't get
forward secrecy guarantees yes so you
need to process yeah you need to need to
see the messaging to process the message
in order to like say ok now I I can't do
this again yeah but dropping a message
doesn't have to be something
deliberately performed by an adversary
the networking will do that on its own
sure sure like but if the messages drop
then like in the same time you don't you
don't see the key then yeah you sounded
secrecy there yeah I was just going to
ask it's kind of a really basic thing
about implementing this this protocol
seems to require the ability to forget
data that and if you're doing this one
like a mobile device with flash drive
with standard flash memory that's not so
easy have you thought at all about what
you need to do to to make sure that you
can actually forget the data or is that
just something is outside the couple
you're working on no so for now that I
mean we didn't look into this but thanks
for any type of secret or forward
secrecy where you need to forget a key
at some point in time in order to not
reveal it anymore you're in this trouble
of how to how to securely erase data yes
that's like--that's wont to do so
ultimately gos 1.3 decided not to do 0r
Kiki agreements but instead do 0r TT
resumption with a shared symmetric
secret and you can take it along with it
I'm wondering it seemly you can adapt
this method for forward secrecy to a
final eq servers used to decrypt the
tickets where when you encrypt the
ticket you don't use a single key for
all the tickets you are encrypting but
you go walk down this tree and pick
something from the root
encrypted and then when you receive it
again later times them you erase the
symmetric key you used along the path
you mean like using this together
instead of using this the leaf node as
your secret key like the appreciate key
in the TLS style design so this is a
simplification geez on the server where
you have keys encrypting tickets and the
concern is that the ticket encryption
keys has to be kept for long periods of
comics 10 urgency to work over those
periods of time and this idea of going
down the tree and erasing might help
ameliorate that maybe let's let's plug
on it apply may be any more questions ok
we're out of time anyway so Alex thanks
Alex thank you very much
[Applause]