okay thank you and so I don't think that
anyone can overstate the central role
that the passwords have in securing our
life and privacy anything that is
available and can be written in bits is
protected somehow with passwords at the
same time the one it's undeniable that
the states of security of passwords is
catastrophically bad but before I go
into that let me just tell you about the
names of my co-author think that the the
top touches of several works with such
letter from with auto corrected yahoo
aguilas CI a--'s little 16 and malia she
runnin em so again we are very dependent
password but passwords like to abandon
us they are regularly lost on stolen in
thousand million hundreds of millions
lately than 1 billion in a single isn't
and you can go to league source com and
see if you're lucky enough to have some
of your accountant on puzzles listed
among the three billion that's what we
have it's about one password third
Internet user so this is definitely a
bad situation and an acceptable state of
affairs and the question is do we have
to live with these or we have better
ways so getting rid of pastors all
together is unrealistic they are too
convenient they are to massively
deployed asking users to choose strong
high entropy independent passwords with
equally unrealistic and the question
that we are here is whether
cryptographic and health
and let me ruin the surprise the answer
India's definitely there are techniques
in cryptography that can help improving
the state of insecurity of passwords and
we will show some examples of different
solutions to different problems in
different settings and the nice thing
about the what I'm going to present is
that they are only solution is very
simple techniques very well established
essentially blind the diffie-hellman
that originated with David Shawn
Thornton liske were first to use it use
them use this technique in the setting
of passwords and our work has
similarities with work done by boil and
we will cut this in the more modern
terminology of oblivious BRF but when we
implement stuff we implement it with
blind official man this is mature
technology even if it's not use it's
ready for deployment in the real world
and I'll go over such dissolutions very
briefly and I will be very happy to talk
to any of you that is interested in the
subject and particularly people think
that they can help transferring some of
these things into practice so the the
mainly source of the path of leakage are
offline dictionary attacks they they are
the product of the deadly combination of
the low entropy passwords which come out
of the inherent limitations of human
memory and of server compromise an
attacker that compromises the server
guess what we call the password file
which contains hushed versions of the
user passwords and with the hash of the
password an attacker with the dictionary
a list of potential passes can check
which of the password thing the list is
actually a particular users password if
a user chose the password in in the
dictionary then it will be found
what make this very effective is that
the very special software hardware
dedicated hard work to do these
exhaustive searches of our dictionaries
and they can do many many millions of
sets of these things per second so this
is a very practical way of breaking this
a password at the same time maybe the
worst news is that offline dictionary
attacks are unavoidable upon server
compromise whatever the doesn't matter
what your protocol does and what your
algorithm does if there is a way for the
server to check that the users password
is the user passwords them the same
thing can be done by the attacker we get
a password so we have to live with with
the thing yet the hope is to be able to
make this unavoidable exhaustive attacks
in a section and we for that we either
need to use high entropy passwords or
add more elements to the protocol
devices servers and so in the first part
of the chakra we'll be talking about a
way of taking the burden of choosing and
memorizing passwords away from humans
because as long as we have to do that
then low entropy password is the only
option and for this we know the solution
there is a a sorcerer but for managers
that keep a list of passwords that the
user can take in a device or access on
the clip online and it keeps it
encrypted on the master password so that
the user only needs to remember that
master password in that sense this
removes the need to remember many
complicated person you can have only one
hopefully non-trivial master password
now this is this a good type of solution
in in practice the way we think are
implemented is not always great if you
have any a list of passwords which
included under master password and a
cycle that find the list can do an
offline dictionary attack on the mat
surface or this week defines the master
password kinds of also all the battles
of the user also if Assad having a
device on a server exactly the attacker
is inside that device then when the user
enters the master password can be
learned that way and again all the
puzzles are compromised also there are
problems sometimes in the communication
between the user and the device and in
additional to all of that many of these
other managers actually so use of chosen
passwords which means to gain the
somewhat low entropy and repeated among
different servers which is one of the
bad things that happened with puzzles so
can we do better and the answer is yes
we cannot leave for the next 15 days yes
I I had that I took it because I didn't
want to spend time do so now extend even
more saying that they had let's make
passwords great again so so he is a
dream password store all passwords are
kept in the in a user's device or online
the user memorizes a single master
password as in any password store and
now all puzzles are going to be random
and independent of each other which is
the way they should be but in addition
an attacker that gets hold of the device
of the store or even has full control of
the device there's nothing and nothing
about the individual store passwords
nothing about the master password okay
so how does that work first of all what
I think that thing I mean in an
information-theoretic nothing I mean
it's a dream the password store so we
can ring with information theoretic
security the information store in the
device is going to be independent of the
master password and independent of the
individual very password okay so you see
that you see that storage and you see
nothing about the the master pattern of
the individual passwords the clear they
but the master password is never
entering little clearer six way into the
device or the server so that an
eavesdropper that is in the line between
user and device that will not learn
anything even an attacker that is inside
the device at the time that the user is
entering or interacting with the device
learns nothing okay so it we call these
things for utter store that's perfectly
hide from it sets you can see this fbh I
what I ultimix the next and for no
exaggeration
okay so let me show you how this works
so we have a user and user we have a
remote server client machine and a
device the user starts by inputting the
master past or PWD will be the master
password which is sent to the device the
device as a PRF key okay so this is a
scheme based on the PLF PLF can be h
mark cbc mark or something like that the
password is sent to the device device
has whiskey case of the day it computes
the PRF using the key K sub D on the
password this is sent to the terminal
client machine my machine gets that way
value bit of Paris odd and college RWD
and RW z is actually the password which
is specific to that a server and now
between the client and the server they
run whatever protocol the riveter with
rwb so RWD the pseudo random password
that basically the user had to register
initially with the server think Google
Facebook your bank whatever so each one
each server that are each account that
the user has will have a different lwd
and the way you compute it is you add to
the PRF computation the URL or some some
identifier of that service or or the
account and we are not making any
assumptions on the path of protocol we
just say lwb will be the most typical
protocol whatever you use with that
server will be used with our WT ok so
this solution already gives you a part
of what I wanted it one is whiskey
because other diseases to the random
then offline attacks are infeasible if
the dictionary will be too big to to run
the Vatican II also the storage here on
the device is K sub D which was chosen
independently of the master password
they are the individual password so the
storage if you find the storage unit
rates of these you don't learn anything
about the master password the problem
with the solution is that the matter
paso PWD is being sent in the clear to
the device so anyone on the link here or
inside the device controls the muscle
purpose to avoid that we move to an
oblivious PRF an oblivious PRF is
exactly the same idea except that now
after getting the password from the user
the client machine client machine
chooses a one-time key with which it
encrypts the password okay so now the
path organs encrypted to the device the
device does something with that and
output an encryption under that same key
of the PRF value ok now for doing that
the device does not need to decrypt the
control it does not delete the password
and it does not name the PRS value
either because the PRS value is
generated already in encrypted form
these were the magic of cryptography
something to play and if we have that
then we are okay because now the
increases PRF is only learned by the
client machine that has that one time
key that the creeps the PRF get rwb and
it's being used before so as before
because RWD pseudo-random them offline
attacks are infeasible because a
discouraging the device is still
independent of the passwords but now we
also have the master password hidden
over the wire and from the device so
this is nice the only question is how do
we implement something like this ok so
if you know about fully homomorphic
encryption that
implementation this is not what I would
have called mature and an efficient
technology so instead we'll do something
simpler than that here is the
implementation user enter the password
the client chooses a one-time value are
ok let me say first that how do we
define this particular oprf the
particular vrs takes the PWD the
password hashes into an element in some
a predefined root and the kk v is an
exponent ok on on that on that group and
the oprf on pewds hush the PWD racing to
the power of kb that's the PRF so now we
go back to show our slave machine which
uses this random exponent hi and what it
does it takes the hash of the password
we've got the password from there from
the user and races to the power of our
we call that value a well that the
device has to do is to take a and just
ready to the paypal of kb when they when
the client machine gets developed be it
recipes to the panel modular r which
basically cancels they are in step 2 and
what it gets is H PWD to the kv which is
how we define the oprf ok and now we can
do our use RWD with the server as before
RWD to the random then there's Oakland
attack KD is independent of the wdr WD
but now we have the damask pattern is
perfectly hidden on the wire and from
the device and I say perfect in the face
of shuttle security because the the use
of these exponents are essentially works
at the one time pad here and nothing
information theoretically is is
a lick on on the password so essentially
this is the dream pastor store that I
was talking about and that's it that
that's all you need now so on this can
work with any client server at some sort
of all its server transparent and not
only secure the performance between
client and the communication between
july the diversity just a single round
send the hush of PWD today are gets back
this value to the KD and the trip it's
one exfoliation for the device to actual
incisions for the client and one hush
into the group any difficult man group
when we need something called the one
more difficult man assumption but
basically any deep in helmand group
acquiesce we believe this is the halter
so you can choose the film a group that
is best for this type of operation so
we've taken these ideas and build
actually a password manager that we can
sink and we show an implementation as an
android app a usability study i will not
be giving references to papers during
the talk again i have a URL with the
page where you will find an annotated
references for the top because i'm
touching on quite a few works a servitor
science so you can it's a facebook or
google or your employer does not need to
know that you are using this list on
because again the password the partial
protocol can be anything there's no need
to have any means of protecting the
channel between the client and device
you don't need physical security on
these extra keys and you can use any
form of communication Wi-Fi Bluetooth
internet whatever and what is very nice
is that this allows for a
implementation where the device is
implemented online which you can use
instead of the devices of back up to the
device or both of them together and you
get all these all these properties on
this online solution to summarize the
security at phone device compromise you
get & Co national security the only
thing after the attackers does have the
key from the device then basically this
reduces to a online attacks but on the
RW d value okay network attacks are
unconditionally secure because the
communication has this one time passing
nopee ki has been assumed by the way
none of the words I'm showing them
another way all the words that I'm
showing it do not need a pki which after
many talks that showed us how bacteria
is is a good thing offline dictionary
attacks are infeasible because of the
randomness of the RWD the only of line
at dictionary attack that is possible
here if the attacker gets the device and
also the server then it can run a low
flame attack and that is basically
unavoidably online dictionary attacks
are infeasible because of the random is
an independent LW DS and even there is
some defense against but for leakage for
example if you find an r WB for one
server doesn't mean say anything about
other LW DS even if you find the master
password you still need the device to to
authenticate and there are some
differences also against phishing while
adding the URL into the PRS full
security against possible leakage or
client of compromise requires two factor
authentication and we also have some
recent work doing some hopefully
interesting stuff about two-factor
authentication I also listed in this in
the in the list of in the references
okay the second part of the talk is
about how to protect valuable secrets
when all you remember is a password and
here protecting in both secrecy
unavailability and valuable secrets we
have been examples from Bitcoin wallets
usercontrol cloud backup like like like
multi was doing secure messaging keys
how do you do things so that the user
must be dealt to the clip stuff and
private is for public relations many
many many examples and now since we want
to protect both the secret your
availability in this case just a single
server is not enough we need a
multi-server solution the single server
would be a single point of failure for
secrecy if the secret the server is
compromised and there is an offline
dictionary attack against it that can
compromise the secrecy and availability
of course if you have a single server
when the server is unavailable this
sequence is unavailable to so we want a
multi-server solution and of course any
cryptographer will tell you that the
solution is to use a secret sharing
screen and really we want to share among
and server and be able to retrieve from
t plus 1 servitude even if you if you
stick to tea let's say a Bitcoin wallet
doesn't mean that you need to do this to
the Bitcoin wallet the bigger value you
can click on authenticate and put it
whatever you want you do the second
showing 222 the key and you retrieve
from the placement service availability
is protected as long as T plus 1 servers
are available and the secret is
protected as long as no more than T of
the service is corrupted now we have a
problem because now the user will come
to a server so I give me back my shell
now how does the server will know who
she should give this church come anyone
that comes and get the share than anyone
to get the secret so of course the
server will have to authenticate the
user
scored using a password what is the user
going to do is going to choose the same
password for all the servers so now
instead of one point of failure we have
n point of failures any server that is
compromised you find the password and
now you can access all this other
servers so of course if you ask the user
to choose the independent random
independently password for the different
servers that is certainly unrealistic so
we have a problem with this approach
what we really want is this primitive
called a password-protected signal
sharing and a notion that was introduced
by buggers Andy at all it has two stages
the initialization stage in which the
user shares the secret among the end
servers after which the user forgets the
secret completely only remembers the
password at retrieval time the user
contacts if that was server the only
thing that he remembers is the password
and that's enough for him to reconstruct
the secret and the security has to be
that an attacker that breaks into tea
servers there is nothing about the
secret or the password both of them are
secure and when I say that as a factor
of H into the service I mean it finds
everything finally share to find the
password file and any long-term keys I'm
not assuming anything that remains
secure and underserved the only attack
Avenue after that is it for the
attackers to try to get your puzzle and
go to the the the servers and if you get
to the password then it can impersonate
otherwise it has nothing that you can do
offline attacks are a used are
impossible as long as they are at mostly
corrupted server I'll skip this one and
what we do is we give a very
surprisingly efficient scheme it
requires just in the respective three
that's really good the instrument Reggie
questions Wow okay so it's a single
single equalization fire for each server
the declines as 2x transitions in total
independent of tnm just two exponents
issues each one the server declines does
do also three multiplications or
additions in the elliptical
implementation which are like
inexpensive operations the communication
is a single message from the user to t
plus 1 servers and and one message is
sent back from the server to the users
is no communication between the server
now there is no authentic no PK is with
me there's no secure channel other than
for initialization in which case the
user wants to identify an authenticator
servers it is sharing the secret with
but not after that and by the way a
multi mention that may be seeking
sharing like this may not be practical
enough or something like that these the
cost of this thing is less than because
of of a TLS interaction with the server
so this is really really inexpensive and
I will not talk about how this looks see
the papers what I'm going to do is the
very first tell you about this xaxa
protocol which is a protocol for this if
you have a single silver situation and
what is the best protocol that you can
run at least a protocol with very nice
properties by the way this is the
protocol that is our PPSS scheme but for
the case N equals 1 T equals one and a
very similar protocol was already
proposed by by Boyle several years ago
and I mean I have liked to show how an
idea of how this works I will not be
able to do that but let me tell you what
the properties of these things are so in
any single server pay
what is called an asymmetrical augmented
take you want that the security such
that if the server relax enjoy if the
attacker breaks into a server it still
needs to run an offline dictionary
attack for example if you share if you
put the user password in the clear
inside the server this is not a good
solution you want to force the attacker
to do a dictionary attack so that's
something we always wanting this kind of
servers we want that no pre-computation
prior to the time in which the attacker
breaks the server will help the attacker
this is what we use a secret salt for
and we would like that the server will
never see the password in plain text no
reliance on t ki and if possible to be
able to offload the hash iterations that
you do for key stretching on the user
side I mean there any any balancing that
you you want to do and the regular thing
that we do now pasodoble TLS has the
first two properties but it doesn't give
you three four five in particular that
the server when it decrease the TLS it
is the password in the Playtex of course
it's very dependent on pick a yard
without the ki pls brakes completely and
you cannot do this a flaw offloading if
you don't want to reveal the dassault
other other protocols in this is a type
of protocols in the literature gets one
three and four but the combination of
215 is actually unique or at least from
the protocols I know if you need to to
this protocol which actually has all the
properties so it's a very strong
protocol and I'll show you only one
thing they to understand that protocol
you take things as i showed before and
you just move the server to the side of
the device and that's it and now you run
the same protocol that you run with the
device before you run it with the server
and this all you need to do and even if
you want to do a full AKA of indicated
key exchange for example with h & QE you
still get
a 22 message protocol if you want to do
explicit client authentication you need
to add one more ok let me two minutes
for conclusions one minute one minute so
subtle battle ok so we all agree that
the partial vulnerability is a big
problem we will always to show that
patterning security is not debatable a
cute ography has some interesting
solutions in these different settings
and all schemes that I present our have
our basal security former security
models and proofs of security anyway
mature efficient simple technology just
waiting to be deployed and here you have
the references this long one you can
make if you want to write down it's in a
file to our LAX easy thank you
[Applause]
yeah okay thanks in your first protocol
really elegant I really liked it you
said you can use it with your google or
your employer or whatever what if your
employer is one of these evil employers
that forces you to change your passwords
every 30 days I hate them yeah I hate
that but what do you like where did you
in click your little just encrypt
gunshot not confuse us with engineering
problems yeah very good question and so
the solution basically is that I mean
the best solution I can think about is
that you will keep the counter you can
if you are willing to store your
accounts on the device then it is it
because the account will will store the
counter and it will be able to the PRF
if you do that then is simple if you
don't want to do that then there is a
programming either the user will have to
remember the counter or write it down or
you know something like though if the
site you're trying to log into requires
you to have a symbol and a number and
like and it anyway the there is another
engineering question what happens if the
passwords are not being on the past we
have to be serious in books like these
on this and that and these are all
solvable in one way or another but but
yes so but I don't think any of these
things really kill to the solution all
right why we go again
[Applause]