so you're all expecting a talk at the
quantum session but that's already
announced this will not have much to do
with quantum or post quantum
cryptography but if you want to be a bit
in stayin in in that area I will try to
explain what white box crypto is it's
related to secure software and try to
think because not many people have
looked actually into this how we can
turn the post quantum crypto into white
box solutions and that would be a
fantastic research area all right so
this talk is based on work which also
they're the only feels and Phil server
all at nxp at the time we worked on this
and currently both Charles and co are at
sparks left and our paper was already
presented this summer at chess so what
is white box crypto so in order to
understand this let me try to get an
overview when we talk about crypto we
often talk about you need to understand
who is the attacker where is this
adversary is it internal is it external
when you think of internal it can be the
user it can be a virus and what is
realistic for your particular use case
so the old way of thinking about this is
the black box model so you assume that
the endpoint are trusted parties and the
attacker observed data being transferred
so this is from the let me call the 80s
and then in the in the 90s there was
this new model which people refer to as
the gray box model it's related to
Hardware implementations and imagine you
have a smart card for instance which
your crypto algorithm running on it
it'll shown that if you measure for
instance the power or other external
information meta information about this
implementation while they're running
yeah you can use this information to
extract the private key material used
during the execution of the scripts
graphic algorithm
so then we come to the white box model
which is related to the gray box model
what is not related to hardware is
related to software execution so now for
instance think about a cryptographic
algorithm running on a device you own
but it's implemented in software so easy
example for instance is in mobile device
and again we assume that adversary can
be the owner of that device so it can
even be the user of the device and still
we want to protect the price key from
being extracted even by the user running
that descriptive graphic implementation
so and this setting where you want to
among other things ensure that the the
cryptographic key cannot be extracted
from the software implementation is
referred to as the the white box attack
model so why are we interested in this
white box attack model who is actually
using this so this was originally
proposed early 2000s in a setting of
digital rights management and take care
of streaming content from somewhere for
instance to it to your setup box and
then the the party who is streaming the
movie to you does not want you to have
the key which can decode this movie
because then you might be able to get
this key to a friends and then he can
watch this movie as well then there was
more or less a decade not too much
attention to white box crypto until a
couple years back when it was a renewed
interest in this technology really after
the introduction of HTE so hez stands
for host card emulation and ID behind
this is that it emulates and software
your NFC or near field communication and
the idea is that it replaces the secure
element or it emulates the secure
element in software and this is for
instance in practice use that you can
pay with your mobile phone or take a
train or any other transit
and in practice how is this
cryptographic key in this implementation
then protected because why do you want
to protect this you don't if the user
would have this cryptographic key it
good for instance to a rollback attack
which means I pay my fare for my train I
struck the key and I just upgrade to any
other amount i have or I roll back to my
the data i had and then i have the the
previous fair and i actually didn't pay
at all and how this is done in practice
is with this what then you are in this
white box attack model and if you have a
cryptographic implementations secure in
this model people call this white box
implementation and we see an increasing
and increasing demand of this in
practice so in 2014 fees are MasterCard
announced their support for host card
emulation and in these payment protocols
if you implement them in software it is
a requirement that you either protected
with white box cryptography and
according to these studies we will only
see an increase of these HTE solutions
in practice and phones and other mobile
devices which actually support this
technology so in practice what do they
actually protect it mainly symmetric
crypto so we're talking about AES and
Triple DES and how these keys are really
protected already in practice if you
have a mobile phone for instance not
only payments but also your the apps
which are allowed to install from your
Play Store or any other app store you
have on your phone and it's very likely
that this is protected with white box
cryptography so when you think about
this how would you actually try and
solve this problem what should we think
about why do normal security
cryptographic implementations in so far
not work because it was already shown
actually before the invention or
introduction of white box crypto by
sameer from somewhere that if you just
load your crypto key into memory and you
would just scan your memory and look at
the location with the highest entropy
that with very high probability this is
the location of your particular key and
then you can just dump it extract it and
then you have extracted the key another
easy way how to extract the key it's
with technical sbox blanking attack so
you just have your implementation of for
instance AES you just replace desk box
with all zeros and then the cat X
ordaining you just the implementation
outputs the key so we need something
more advanced so then of course the
question arises is a white box
implementation even possible the answer
of course is no because if you want to
build an ideal white box is
implementation you could just create one
day lookup table for one specific six
key but this will not be very practical
bisque even modern mobile phones don't
have this much storage in practice what
people propose so in the original paper
in 2002 by Chow and others they propose
the technique where you replace every
algorithmic step in the algorithm in
this case AES with a lookup table and
then you're the goal is that you put you
try to obfuscate these look-up tables by
putting input and output and coatings on
calls to this lookup table so on the
right here you see a nice overview how
then the flow of the algorithm would
look like and then this already gives
rise to much smaller implementation but
still orders of magnitudes larger than
the original a s and their proposed
solution was around seven hundred
kilobytes and it actually didn't compute
anything here it was just a sequential
series of table lookups in the hope
where you it was fixed for one
particular cryptographic key in the hope
that the attacker is not able to deduce
any information about the key actually
used and partially store things look up
tables
in practice however so I've been the
remainder of the talker will be
discussing how to extract the private
key from a white box implementation but
in practice you would use much more than
just like books and I just want to tell
you to give you a bigger overview in
practice people apply codification anti
debugging just to make the lives of
Decker more annoying and different
platform binding techniques which all
serve different purposes like I said if
you want to have anti roll back
protection or something which is called
code lifting you want to protect against
these types of attacks as well so code
listing for instance is the simple
attack that you don't want to extract
the price team but you just copy because
it's software you just copy the entire
software solution putting on another
phone for instance and if you then run
your cryptographic algorithm you
essentially have copied to the price key
because it was embedded in there and you
get the same functionality so if you
want to protect against these types of
attacks you meet other types of
countermeasures I would I will be solely
focusing on extracting the private key
from the implementation and last year at
your crypt was a really nice overview
talk by christian Kohlberg about these
other techniques related to obfuscation
and how attackers and people try to
protect these things how that works in
practice so oh it's good to state that
all efforts in academia to build white
box implementations have been broken so
it's completely unknown how to build a
secure white box implementation of for
instance a s of all the standardized
that approaches but how do these attacks
work in practice so first of all they
were very white book specific so you
need to know exactly what approach was
being implemented which n coatings were
put on both tables which cipher
operations were exactly implemented
where and in which set of look-up tables
and if you knew this and then you could
reverse
engineered code because you could assume
that they would put some code
obfuscation on top of it target the
correct lookup table and then apply your
algebraic attack and extract the key so
we studied yeah we looked into a way how
to make this a bit easier so I will try
and explain briefly how we took the
attacks from the gray box model so how
people attack hardware implementations
and how that also applies to this
setting of white box implementations and
our attack works automatically it's very
simple so see for instance we had the
chess challenge this year so one of the
challenges we created and was related to
white box implementation and you could
try our two tools which we released and
see how it actually works in practice
you didn't need any knowledge of how
this was implemented in practice the
only thing you need to know is which
algorithm is implemented so you need to
know in practice there only two choices
is a des or SAS and then you can put as
much codification on top as you want we
don't care it just ignores our attack so
what's the ID it's about tracing so
trading binary so when you look at a
cadet vapors and academic approaches
there are all nice and they're open
designs you know exactly what's going on
but in practice what are companies doing
they don't specify at all their
algorithm and you don't get the source
code of course although it should be
possible in this attack model but in
practice you just get a binary book
which you can inspect and then our
initial idea was let's try and collect
information and using dynamic binary
instrumentation tools and for instance
that the popular tools for this our pin
for enter platform or four grains which
lots of people use for debugging or
memory leakage detection but actually
it's a much more advanced to which can
do much more things so we wrote plug-ins
for these tools and so and we released
them ahsoka source which allows you to
trace the execution of the traces of
execution
and we'll do a mean with this it traces
all the reads and writes into memory so
all the memory locations or the
instruction locations and then we wrote
a visualizer which visualizes these
reads and writes and then we're going to
use these traces of these so that all
the memory accesses and try to find
correlations the same way as you try to
find correlations in a gray box attack
model so yeah we wrote plug-ins for
intel pin and 44 grind and we were
especially interested in foreground of
course because that supports the arm
platform so that means mobile devices so
how does a just to give an example how
does the official trace you look like so
here you so this was inspired by a tool
a spark slab and so the time is on the
y-axis from top to bottom and on the
x-axis you have the whole range of the
memory addresses and the different
colors is either and access to an
instruction memory read write or read
and write so this is a typical picture
when you execute a secure software
crypto implementation so why do we want
reduce this because our attack only
needs one piece of information and that
is what kind of crypto algorithm is
being implemented and like I said in
practice it's either a s or des so here
for instance you see a trace a
visualization of a trace of white box
implementation and the actual crypto is
just a tiny bit on the bottom and large
from the right and there you can clearly
see nine blocks nine times four blocks
so this is a hint that it's probably a s
because the 10th round is slightly
different so you see this pattern and
then when you have your guests eyes AES
you can mount an a a specific attack but
what if the white box is a bit smarter
and it has completely unrolled its
algorithm you'll just see a straight
line like this and of course this will
not leak any information
then you don't look at the code but you
just look at the data so if you just
look at the data pattern how it fetches
things from Ram you would see 1 plus 15
nice look-up tables it exes so that
means it's probably des and then we had
another nice example of another white
box implementation which had also its
memory access pattern sequentialized so
then three hard to tell what's actually
going on but look at the far right
that's the stack and it turns out that
is really hard to hide information or
access patterns on the stack so if we
zoom in on this so this is exactly this
green bar on the right if we zoom in you
again see a nicely access pattern of 1
plus 15 so it means that probably the
implementation is computing des ok so
once we have decided which algorithm is
actually being implemented we could just
give us let's see if the gray box
attacks are attacking a smart card for
instance if that works here as well so
the naive approach of course would be
for your white box implementation to a
smartart and measure the power
consumption that should give it if you
work but this is of course pretty stupid
because we have much more when a white
box attack model much more powerful of
that model and each bit which accesses
memory is equally important so the idea
is we're going to serialize bits and
then you get the equivalent of a
hardware power trace which looks like
this just values 0 or 1 and it doesn't
reveal much it's already officially very
hard to identify the multiple rounds in
this race but if you would use
autocorrelation you would immediately
see them but
once you realize what you're actually
measuring on what you're doing and this
would be the same as you would in
hardware probe the bus so each bit of
your bus individually and you would not
not measure any error so it's an
extremely powerful attack and so the
hope is of course that you need much
fewer traces and it's much easier to
extract the secret key compared to the
attacks on hardware implementations
where there is inherently much more
noise and you cannot measure the
individual bits that easily so we went
online of course and we try to collect
white box implementations which were
publicly is able and we just said let's
check out this actually works and to our
surprise it actually did work it's
something we did not expect from the
beginning so the first implementation
online is from breathalyzer he put his
white box implementation online in 2007
so it was couple years later already
broken by one of these algebraic attacks
and after actually finding his
implementation back on some internet
archive and that was most of the work it
took only 65 traces and the trace is
just running the software implementation
which takes less than a millisecond and
then automatically our tool would just
collect this trace serialize it and run
a standard DPA attack and the secret key
was outputted and similar for the other
white box implementation so in practice
in the hacker open source community
these open source implementations pop up
in these capture the flag challenges so
at the heck oh you or SSDI see so in the
middle too so there we only needed 16
traces but we should say that these were
designed to be broken in a day so on
this hacker events so they put no and
coatings on these look-up tables which
makes it easier for the algebraic
attacks but of course also much much
easier to find correlations and then
another master students finish who force
master thesis implemented the most
advanced
temic white box approach which we then
used and created a challenge for
ourselves and this was based on the
approach of economy and use these dual
ciphers that you can represent AES in
different ways and here actually we
needed a bit more traces initially 2000
which still is less than than a second
to collect these traces but in the end
after fine-tuning detected its
implementation it was only 500 so that
of course leads to the question what's
the intuition why this correlation
attacks actually work and this was
elaborated a bit more on FSC paper last
year and yet the intuition behind this
is that encoding which you put only
look-up tables do not sufficiently hide
the correlations when when this piece
are actually used in the implementation
so this of course opens a lot of
potential work for for follow up quickly
because these these white box
implementations are deployed and used
already in the world so what about
countermeasures so the most common
countermeasure in the hardware community
is that you are going to try and create
random masks or random delays you're
gonna mask values but we're in the white
box a tech model so we assume that the
user has full control over your platform
so if you just carry a random number I
can just set the entropy to zero because
I you can assume I'm root for instance
on my android phone and thereby
disabling the entropy and your
countermeasure doesn't work anymore so
this approach does not seem to be the
right path so what about having some
sort of static random data in the white
box another counter measure is based on
threshold implementations which they use
in hardware that seems like an
interesting approach to go for here as
well and of course more on the hacker
side of things what about detecting if
you run in such a DB I framework
detecting if you run with in foreground
or a debugger but it seems like the in
decorah community there are lots of
papers who
introduce new techniques how to detect
this and then other techniques how to to
get around this and of course these so
dca so this attack it's not a holy grill
it might still when you lose use large
and coatings on these look-up tables
because then there's yeah there's no
correlation anymore between then and the
output but that means you get larger
look-up tables and things actually might
become impractical too large and too
slow and practice and moreover the
original algebraic attacks will all
still work so after we put this online
other people's almost notably the people
from riskier they looked at this as well
so independently and they look more at
software fault attacks so the other type
of attacks we know from the gray box
community and that approach was a very
successful as well and they show that if
you in this white box a tech model you
just flip a couple of bits in these
look-up tables even if there are n
coatings on top of them it's similar as
a photo tech and you can extract the
secret key material as well so we
released all our software we use so the
facial Iser the tracer and the code we
created to actually perform a CPA a tech
or DPA attack because to our surprise we
were not able to find any open source
see PA two together with all the scripts
for the implementations I showed earlier
which we attacked so people could
actually can try and do these attacks
themselves so if you feel encouraged
please come and help and extreme these
tools if you know white box
implementations which we could try and
test let us know we're always interested
yeah in extending our tools and adding
more expertise or test countermeasures
for instance so to conclude it's clear
that software only solutions become more
and more popular especially in the HCE
environment
and they rely heavily in white book
script so the the attack I quickly
described it's just the counterpart of
the DPAs extra larger community you
don't need any expertise it's just a
matter of you download two and you run
it against your white box attack if you
know which algorithm is being
implemented and this of course raises
the question is the level of security
and especially maturity of at least all
the white box schemes we tested is very
questionable we could easily break off
them and this gives rise to a couple of
questions so for instance a symmetric
trip though there are companies who
offer solutions for asymmetric
cryptography so think our essay i think
ec d sh but actually in academia it's a
completely open question how to do this
so it would be interesting to have
people would start to study this in
academia as well because in industry
they keep other design secret and i
think there's a need we need a way to
measure the real security level somehow
like we do in hardware implementations
the security of such software solutions
so this is just the beginning i would
say so probably we will see much more
advanced attacks and countermeasures of
course and then attacks on these
countermeasures in the near future and
yeah that leaves us with with a final
question which I don't know the solution
to what is actually the real level of
these white box schemes which are
applying is a CHC solutions which are
currently implemented on our mobile
phones thank
great we've a minute or two for
questions please hello mr. photos from
Luxembourg you mentioned that you your
tool can be used in the cases where some
additional application is applied and
that was not a bit clearer for me so did
it test it on some implementations of
AES where it's like within a group of I
know some garbage code that does nothing
or you used on the implementations we're
like carefully designed to look up
tables and doing that using associated
code we're ninety-nine percent doing
some completely unrelated tarea stuff
can be countermeasure so yes we did try
it on code where were codification or
garbling of the code was present so good
countermeasure indeed is if you put
random the laser or random garbage at
places because then if you want to try
to do the correlation it becomes much
more difficult but then it because it's
if full control over everything you
could just see which steps were not used
subsequently and then it would be so we
try this and then it was very easy to
write a tool which would just more or
less align your traces and remove all
the garbage out again and so that is
when you include garbage code but when
you do real code obfuscation some
transformations on the gold that is
simply ignored because we just execute
occult and look at the address is being
accessed and that's that's the only
thing we need so there's code
obfuscation we simply don't don't care
most of the cryptography that we study
at this conference or that we discuss
here and it either designed to protect
the user or to empower the user and
white box cryptography does not do this
so if you view it like that how do you
evaluate working on white box
photography born a moral standpoint
it's a very good question indeed so it
does not protect the user it's really is
protecting the implementation or the
entity providing the implementation yes
so I don't know morally or
philosophically how I want you to
categorize these things it's a good
question I mean I mean consider how you
have elevated so I would so in my
opinion I think there is an use for
white books implementations for sure
because how else would one try to
protect if there's no hardware secure
element or something available how would
you protect your how would you want to
implement that French as a payment
solution and software I mean there is a
need for this so there is a need for for
white box Krypton there are companies
they're doing that by the way there are
companies that are selling white box
crypto to protect credentials and keys
for you on your mobile the crap that
they're doing it I was only going to
mention that there are other
applications here you know like if you
don't have hardware and you want to
build an ATM or some other machine which
you know where the owner of the machine
and really in sometimes the user of the
machine has a legitimate interest in
keeping it secure because you don't want
someone to to to sabotage the ATM and
skill all the money out of it yeah but
for ACM it's exactly 480 in motion space
is often art where but here but I agree
there are lots and lots of following
sketches yes