no i'm gerry geiger and i'm here to give
you a talk on a function of him with
exposed so grab that link right there
tiny CC /d signs rock dash exposed that
is the whole presentation all of the
links all the code and all this stuff do
you guys need from this presentation are
going to be at that length this will
link directly to this presentation you
be able to look at it you can follow
along and grab the leaves from there
that's the easiest way I thought to
distribute all this stuff because
there's a couple different github repos
and things so grab that if you guys have
any questions throughout this entire
presentation just please stop me and ask
your question if I'm going too fast I'm
talking too fast if I say something that
doesn't make any sense phone now I'm
open to that I want to make this
presentation if you guys how'd it be
educational so yeah so without further
ado we'll move on so our Jennifer today
is a who am i or you kind of intro thing
looking into tools this presentation
kind of turned into a we're kind of an
intro to reverse engineering Android as
well as expose you can't really do use
this expose framework thing without the
worst engineering some of the Android
applications so we're going to look into
that what to hook finding the functions
with any applications that are you
talking about finding the functions you
want to cook and take advantage of basic
hooks writing basic hooks to replace
methods to do all sorts different things
we're going to be had a couple practical
examples these last three bullets each
one has a practical example so basic
books were those changing returned eyes
things reverse engineering you'll have
Bo be times where you know you have an
application and you need to figure out
what it does but maybe there's something
in the way or there's some sort of
strange algorithm to calculate something
you can kind of make the appt do the
work for you in that case and then
disabling security checks specifically
certificate
kind of get in the middle show made a
middling some traffic after every
disabled certificate pinning within the
app so I'm gonna go through all this and
more I promise so here's the intro i am
j guy Graham wombo lombo down in I like
spongebob is I'm 22 it's fine in for a
second RIT it's my last year i'm
graduating i'm going to a company called
grim after graduation griffco calm very
small 15 people now really cool place to
work my hobbies and interests cts
reversing exploitation all that stuff
poking android collecting acronyms what
is it with this field in acronyms yeah
crazy so red team our development that's
uh my other work that i do but i like
android and so work on that so for you
guys so this a little
audience-participation part any rit
students raise your hands p rit students
just make sure you guys are way going to
gauge body and spread and in java
programmers anyone program a job and
before a couple people all right good
good android users I mean introduced
forgotten here yeah there we go it's
good android application programmers
done any app app 10 or anything okay use
expose before heard of it ah there we go
this is good then written any xposed
module is you're getting people in here
they've done that excellent this talk
will be perfect then none of the above
any of the people is just alright there
we go people only level perfect so this
talk is still for you don't worry so
what is n expose sounds hot yeah it is
it's it's really actually awesome it's a
funky function and resource hooking
framework so that means you can
basically take a function or resource
that an Android application uses and
change it to do whatever you wanted to
do so returns parameters exceptions all
of that and UI elements on the UI
elements part is not something i'll be
covering in this talk because it's this
this is a huge topic like this framework
does a lot of stuff so we're gonna go
just mostly for we're gonna go entirely
for the function
part of us UI elements is something else
that I'm looking into even and it's it's
kind of complex I'm not really an active
so this stuff has kind of been
interested in for me to look into so
it's minute written and maintained by
this guy named Robo 89 there's this
github he has all this stuff is
open-source his xposed framework which
is a modified app process he's got that
on there he's got the Expos bridge which
is a java jar which will be talking
about it's all up on there so you can go
look at it and see how it works so like
I said it replace the app process which
has been actually the next slide how
does it work it doesn't change a nap
signature this is a question that i got
from someone when I when I show them
this talk before it it was practicing
does it change the apps signature and no
it doesn't it doesn't modify the
application that you're hooking in any
way it does in the background but it
does not modify the package of stuff so
it's a replacement app process that
basically adds the expose this expose
bridge jar to the classpath and any java
programmers know a clasp at it is
basically what we're it loads all your
resources I can include for see so
you're including this jar that basically
has a bunch of functions that you can
call so when it starts when the first
process on Android is called psycho and
every process force off of that so if
you can cook in a zygote which is launch
the app process you can hook into every
single process that launches cycle is
actually like a java java process like
launched by app process and then every
application spoke elephant so if you add
a Java class a char to that app process
module you can actually get that into
every single application unloads on the
device so that's how this is all done so
yes before anyone asks you need root to
do this this talk is more of like a you
know for your own personal like okay I
want to do this with this application
knowingly you're not going to put this
on someone's phone and use it for like a
coder like like back door or something
so tools they live among us so I got to
explain some tools before we go any
further so you guys are kind of aware of
what's out there for Android reverse
engineering when you get an application
an APK
Android's run these APK files they
contain all the resources all the java
classes and everything and there we good
job so you need a java decompiler to
really look you can basically look at
the source code sometimes it's office
gated sometimes it's not but these two
tools will basically allow you to
decompile on android applications the
one that I'm going to be taking
advantage of in this demonstration so
i'll be doing is jad which i found more
recently but better the d compilation
seems a bit better it takes the java
classes and it just basically takes the
bytecode and puts into back into a
pseudo java for you to look at so it's a
lot easier to look at them java bytecode
which is really obnoxious desta jar an
80 k tool the way that you need to you
need to convert your indicates two jars
so that's why we have Dexta jars because
inside an APK there's this thing called
the decks and classes that text and
that's basically all the codes that
application is one file Dexta jar takes
that file and converts it to a java jar
so you can actually decompile it with
these with dad or JD giving an APK tool
is useful if you're reverse engineering
application as well extracts the smaller
the java bytecode and then the resources
from the package so you can look at
those and change them if you want so a
apt i'm going to be using this one
actually pretty pretty heavily um this
is a party android sdk and it allows you
to see the resources inside a package
without unpacking it your d compiled
code doesn't have all the strings that
you're going to look for because you
know if you're reversing something
you're going to be looking one of the
first things you look at its strengths
ok i'm going to find the circus train
that you know i think is pertaining to
the part of the program that i'm trying
to get to the strings aren't all in the
application on
like they're referenced by number in a
resource so you actually have to use
this tool to find out where those
resources are and you can use this tool
to actually look for all the strings
within the application and you can grep
for them so from there you would
basically say okay I'm looking for this
string has this ID and I'm going to grep
for that in a code didn't compiled code
and now I know what location that string
with that so that's a you kind of unique
thing with reversing android classes
that you know kind of have to do so
we're gonna be using that I wrote some
custom tools to help with this because I
was tired of doing these commands over
and over and over and over again and I
got really mad as you can see at this
last one because some fun sometimes
there's obfuscation within these classes
within these within these jars and
sometimes they'll be named the classes
hospitals will be named like this a
capital A or is a capital a capital A
and I don't have a case-sensitive file
system so these overwrite each other as
soon as they unzip so I had to write
this big like else curve it's not really
a big shell script but a shell script to
take it check if it's already there and
then unpack it this also has the shitty
options so that you can that you can
unpack class our jars that have these
ridiculous classes so the first one will
take it will take an APK file it will
convert it with vexed ajar to a jar it
will unpack it by just unzip a jar file
is simply a zip file and signed zip file
and then it will unpack it and if you
can hide everything so you can start to
look at all the code in all the classes
so does that all in one jad actually
takes a class file at a time so it's
really tedious to go through and okay
i'm going to compile this one now and if
you compile this one now so this this
tool basically helps you do everything
almost search string allow you to use a
pt's apt to search strings if you find
say you're looking in the code somewhere
and to find a reference you can paste it
as it the first part of the second
argument
search string and basically it will tell
you what strength at ease so this number
this big long decimal number or hex
number or whatever you paste it and you
can use that I'll show you an example of
that constrain an example for that later
so you can find them here like you
settle the links for all the tools for
this presentation or in the presentation
itself so make sure to check those out
so what so hook we have to find
something to go after this involves
reverse engineering the application so
the process that I usually use this is
this is it you gotta get the APK first
you have to get ahold of this file as
the application you can get it at ATK
for fun calm which is it'll give you any
case don't hire things i sometimes use
this just to check out cam in a poke at
this this application and grab you know
grab it offline i'm just i don't have a
USB cable i'm just trying to in our vs
ok before you can get it in this
directory on your phone so if you use an
adb shell and you get shell access to
your phone you need room to get into
this area we need to do this all this
expose stuff anywhere anyway so you
should have that already convert it to a
jar with our dexter our program so
that's literally next to jar than the
APK you've extracted decompile with
theater jad RJD GUI whatever you prefer
jazz with command line tool only and JD
who actually has a humanist maybe smash
your head against the obfuscation like i
said i will i was actually show you
guys later one of the applications that
i have is heavily office gated like this
that's why i had to write that one tool
and the class names are just horrendous
identifying the relevant classes and
functions so you can do that by standard
verse engineering techniques looking
through seeing how things are connected
reading the code understanding it trying
to find i usually start up with strings
honestly like looking at you know what
what strings are there that's one of the
demos actually
going to do is looking at something
trying to find out how it's doing
something via the strings so I've come
up with a couple different scenarios to
kind of give you an idea what use cases
for this would be so before we talk
about those these are like this is the
meat of the programming part like you
need to understand what all these things
do to be able to program a module the
exposed bridge is that class that we
talked about before that gets loaded on
when they expose thingy the exposed
hooks app process or the modified
process loads the path the jar this is
the jar that loads you need this to be
able to build these modules are they
essentially compiled to apks and the
xposed framework will apply to any
employment is able expose helpers find
hook method if we're going to be living
on this this is it finds a method by
class name and method name and
parameters and will allow you to hook it
and change it into whatever way you want
call method is something that I've used
before you can call methods out of line
I don't have a specific example of that
in this talk but I think it's a really
cool thing that you can kind of do just
all right before this function runs call
this other function and then get the
return and do something as a result of
that I exposed hook load package is a
class that your is as a class are going
to implement so you're implementing this
tunable core packages so on a pin it
every time this will get loaded and then
you'll see it check you can check for a
package shame if it's the package name
you're looking for us to have you're
trying to hook you continue if not you
just exit XD method replacement and XD
method hook are really important those
are the two things that actually do the
work for you and they're used with
finding quick method so these two are
they do exactly what they sound like
this hooks a method and this
Title II load package load package
program is essentially a package
information will be using that to
identify if this is the correct app that
we're looking for if when were writing a
modular and then the Expos bridge that's
basically logging helper than i'm going
to using a lot so I threw that in the
bottom that's like the base expose
bridge well again so module structure
I'm providing code in this talk for a
skeleton there's a skeleton creator you
run the script with a bunch of arguments
it will tell you what they are and it
will create a new module for you that's
ready to build so you can see into it
directly and it will hook the app that
you want or it'll create a package for
you that builds and you can just modify
the code from there so you want to spend
time fighting with building build stuff
so you need this expose bridge rd build
it this is just the whole project
structure I'm not going to go over this
too much because there's examples of it
the only important things to know are
exposed at Nick which is a new thing
which is added as an asset that
basically says run this class when this
module starts like grab this class which
is the one that will be in here java
you're accompanying whatever acne and
plugs java so this path minus the java
will be an exposed in it saying when you
load this module load up this code and
that'll do that so a side note on
building installing it's but with Gradle
it's a build system the output the
output is an apk and it's sent to at
bill's outputs APK after a fashion bug
day okay so that's the file you'll be
installing on your device to install the
module feel free to sign it if you want
this is just a debug app it will install
just fine with this command right here
so I've been using that I've just been
using the debug versions and it works
just fine so now we're actually going to
give you the meat of the code of package
hooking what package loads so like I
said load package there's one of the
things we've seen before and another
important part of this is a handle
little baggage function so we're using
this for implementing this function
handle load package so this function
will launch every single time and
package gets loaded up so every time you
open an app every time an app opens this
will run as you have to check is the
package name equal to what I'm trying to
find if it's not quick just go off just
leave if it is then we want to hook
methods so this is the main Skelton
you're going to be using applications
you can also hook you can also cook UI
elements in a different way by
implementing a different class and also
a zygote itself so the main Android
process which is pretty cool but this is
an application hooking talk so I'm
talking about just loaded packages so
any questions so far I try to speed
through the beginning because it's not
really it's not the title of my topic so
this is the more important stuff so this
is all about finding hook method like I
said this is really important going to
be living on this this is going to be
our main thing that we're gonna be using
it finds a class it does exactly what it
sounds like it finds a class measured by
name and helps it to do whatever you
want really so there's five different
scenarios that I've come up with and
have small examples for so you guys get
a feel on how this kind of works you can
return a constant so true false 789
spongebob whatever ignore it completely
just make the function to do nothing do
something before it's called do
something else entirely or do something
after it's called successfully and so
this is the main way you call this you
specify the class name that it's within
LP Prem class loader is always the
second argument the function name in
quotes and then if there's any arguments
you need to provide them as you need to
provide them in a certain way which will
show
my example come and then the actual hook
itself which is one of the two that i
showed before XC method hook or XD
method replacement so you'll begin
placing those so our first scenario is
really we want to make that function
just returned a constant value and this
is useful for hey maybe you know you're
verifying a passcode and this app will
let you in and last you verify the
passcode successfully alright so we want
that just to return true we don't care
what it does we just know that it
verifies the passcode and we have the
correct passcode of course so in this is
going to be in calmed up and got apt up
mane it was always the return trip so
here's actually when I said fine and
hook methods here this is where you
would put this finding hook method so in
class come back at me yeah it's that
same argument all the time verified
passcode takes a string as an argument
this is what I was talking about with
arguments so when this finding hook
method is finding a method it's going to
look for a method called verify pass
code in this class with that argument
string class if the passage is a duck
class I'm not sure why that's just be a
that's just a syntax and then you're
using XC method replacement so we're
replacing what this function does
entirely with just returning a constant
we're gonna return true alright and what
that will do is make this function
return true every time so that's really
cool scenario two is we just want to
make it to nothing this is more like
used for void functions because usually
not annoyed functions will expect some
sort of return and it doesn't try
anything if you'd like pressure app but
there's void functions to all sorts of
things like if we're just you know we
have a function called check security
and we don't want it to do that no
security here very similar same time
banks at this time is one
no arguments so there's no argument
after the function name itself we have
XC Vatican replacement do nothing which
is fairly straightforward this will just
make this method not do anything at all
do something before the function is
called so there's no code under here
because it's on the next slide is a
little bit more involved that's why it's
the third the third the third fourth and
fifth or the more technically like more
require more programming so say we have
a function called transfer funds it
takes a string account number or
something in the class kombank a pin and
we want to just before the function runs
we want to change that argument to make
it say our account number or a different
one whatever whatever that may be so
instead of just your ex cement
replacement you have to make a new XE
medical and so essentially we have to
override the function call before hooked
method so this code will run before the
hook before this method transfer funds
runs and you can access this really neat
because you can actually access the
arguments of this function right before
it's called you can change them or you
can dump up the logs for dota v want
with them and so this is this X roast
bridge log I was talking about this will
dump out to the ATV logcat so log cats
essentially androids logging system
it'll dump with the tag expose so if you
grep for expos in your adb logcat help
but you can actually see this will come
up with change the account number and so
you know it's working I use this a lot
for debug that's a lot of foreigners so
you have to override the method because
you're creating a new X a method hook
and we'll be sticking with the HTML
for a little while because that is
before hooked and Elsa as an after hook
method which is the last suitcase here
any omission somebody runs still with me
thank you for the head mad after she ate
it so we can do something else entirely
instead we can you know make it crash
the app or do something so same Bank
example check password ok string
password we're going to do kind of the
return constant thing but we're also
going to dump it to the log so we're
just replacing the method entirely and
we're gonna say ok don't the dump the
password out might as well grab that
while we're at it and return true so
we're doing this function returns a
boolean so our friend XD vectors
replacement is back this time are
actually creating a new one and we're
saying override the replace hooked
method auction and we're saying ok
here's our here's our brand by the way
that's got all the information about the
arguments that object that is part of
and returned on a few things sorry is
going to cover that for me so we're
logging it expose bridge log and we're
sending that we know it's a straight
argument so we're just asking interest
rate to make sure it's a string and just
sending that to the logs and then return
true so this function will now return
true always and also give you the
password which is alright doing
something after the function is called
so we have this function called generate
token and so in this case we want to get
we want to get a token so we want to get
a valid token that we can use to request
things say this is a van hat that's or
that generates token on the client side
and it's got a certain algorithm or
something I'm not really sure but
whatever it does this returns a string
that has a token and we want to get it
because we want to be able to make our
own request to their server and we want
to generate it so we'll dump it out to
the laws so we're going to soon assume
that returns that string back to our
friend XD method hook or overriding
instead of before box method
so very straightforward we're just
logging out Quran it result so I show
this as an example because you can get
the result of the function put it
somewhere do something with it and maybe
it's a certain value do something else
with it like you can write whatever you
can write a Java you can do before or
after or completely instead of other
functions within Android applications so
it's really awesome so I'm going to do
the classic words with friends hack of
words with friends client side is the
words checking some client side so we're
going to disable that and play whatever
we want I managed to come up with a game
where we both played shady off each
other which I think it's pretty funny so
we have this game right here where this
is about to be pretty shady I'm going to
get a lot of points in a couple minutes
here so I'm gonna try to play I like
triple letters right let's play I got
J&Q it's perfect right so I'm gonna try
to do this my mom the module that I
wrote is not enabled currently so it's
gonna yell at me and it's gonna say no
that that is not a real word which you
can check any dictionary I don't I don't
think I don't think that's all right
word so I'm going to enable this I'm
going to talk about how you would go
about finding this so if you haven't
seen the Expos interface before i'm just
going to enable this and reboot and then
while i'm rebooting i'm going to talk
about how i actually found this the
process that I went through to find this
all right and I wrote all my commands
down so you guys don't have to like
painfully watch me take a bunch of
commands in so I'm going to spare you
the decomp elation of this because it's
literally just that new line here's the
command it will decompile needy hate the
compile will essentially make a
directory called out and a jar called
out yes I understand and a jar called
out
a jar and hope and inside the app
directory is a bunch of they'll leave
classes but find cup there we go so
should hear the decompile classes these
are the concerns of fully these are the
photos with the full bytecode classes
and hear the actual decompile classes
each and so those are the ones are going
to be looking at so let's use a apt to
find a string so we're going to be
looking for the word valid I think
that's a good choice because you know
we're looking for valid or invalid words
and I know that this is also somewhere
where I can find the valid work camp so
this is what we're looking at right here
sorry whatever it is not a valid bird we
saw that pop up on the screen when I
tried to play that ridiculous word and
we're going to look for that so apt also
has another function and it allows you
like I said you can look at the
resources within package so we're
actually going to try to look for sorry
this is not a valid word within the
resources and find the ID like I said a
lot of the times your strings will
actually not be in the D compiled code
itself they'll be referenced by number
so we have to find that number an apt
will actually let us do this if we
search with grep for that exact strength
as you can see here's this resource and
here's the code that we're using like I
said jad has it detects so if we grab
for that in our code hopefully we will
find that you can see where this is
being printed out
and sure enough we found it in one place
like I planet where we're getting this
resource for saying that's not a valid
word so we're actually going to go to
that and check out what is there and why
that's saying that everyone can see this
our area we're going to do want to blow
it up anymore have okay so we wrote down
the line numbers because anyone forget
126 so as you can see here's our x value
with sorry that's not a bad word and
here's the word checks as invalid word
that's not the place we want to get if
you look a couple lines above we want we
want to get you back right valid word
yeah that's good so if P which is a
class method called peace it's a
little-bitty obfuscation working for you
it fee that work so we want to make P
return true so we're going to go up to
feed which is in this lent it to go and
it returns a boolean great but we want
to kind of go a little bit deeper than
that because if this is doing other
stuff relating to the app we don't know
if this is going to trigger something
like this big long line or something
else in here is going to trigger
something else in the app so I like to
go to as deep as possible so we can see
that flag is returned if there's not an
exception so this function this really
strange function that flags being
assigned from we'll go check that out
because I know for a fact I tested it
that if you hook a pee and make it
return true it doesn't work so we'll go
down a little bit deeper so it's a
little bit of trial and error so we'll
go to this class and leaders the
function here's the function that was
just being called from P so this
function also returns a boolean and as
you can see word specified is not valid
so basically otherwise return true so
you want to make this function return
true always so this is the function that
we're gonna be okay this is the function
we're going to be looking at and run our
module based off so now we've identified
the code that we need to hook and we can
go check out our mod show mod code
step 8 okay so this is the code this
sure looks somewhat familiar these
imports are all the stuff that we talked
about on a first like import import
slide this is the full pass for them
from natural jar and like i said this
code is online so you can check that out
after our handle our I exposed hook load
package we're implementing it
implementing the handle load package
function and we're checking if the app
name is calm single words which is words
with friends is I deep packaging it logs
head you're cheating okay it logs that
just to let you know that it's on and
then it will hope the function that we
hadn't calm zengo words d ay ay ay so in
that class this motion and then just
returns true so this takes a string as
we saw we're going to make it return
trip so the reason I'm looking calms and
go words d ay ay ay is because it's the
path is calms and get words daa and the
function name was a with a string
argument just so we're stuff so I loaded
this up it rebooted in crashing and
we'll go into words with friends and
this person's gonna be unhappy a thing
so this is like the classic example it
should still have my word to all right I
was a lot of points so that's the
classic say I'm going to resign because
I feel bad if this person um so that's
like the classic the classic like
function hooking example right there
where I can play whatever I want just by
changing the return value of one
function we've got a couple more
examples that are more relevant to
security minded so verse engineering I
know extract information understanding
code if you're going to be your
engineering Android app you're going to
be
looking at a bunch of really like a lot
of really unimportant code on only
trying to find a certain section or
something that is in the code that's
obfuscated adore populated afterwards
obfuscated code of variables they can be
annoying fine so if the app checks its
own signature your decompiling editing
the smiley code and then recompiling is
ruled out completely you can do that you
can dump with expose you can dump
variables to logs a patent in calculated
just make dad do all the work for you so
let me make sure to look so
yeah okay so how many people in here
I've used the record of you can all
right good I have a good audience set so
their api key is actually calculated
based on the app's signature so we're
looking for that in the app I mean scary
difference commands the get bites method
is used on the variable one requests are
signed so if we hook that function we
can dump everything out to the logs
including the API key itself so every
time is a side note this ad is heavily
office cated and like i said it's the
reason I wrote that shell script to
unpack them the obfuscation changes
every time he had is updated so my
practicing my demo they had updated
itself because this is a slightly older
version it still work on the new version
I just haven't like taken the time to
reverse it I was my gentle is just
crashing over and over so I was like why
like why is this not working you can't
find that class really because they get
renamed every time the app is recompiled
which sucks so I out of a lot of
reversing a lot of a fox but I play with
this app a lot I have a lot of reversing
I found that the API key is actually
stored in this right here and I'll spare
you that that huge explanation but we
want to find out where this is set and
try to hook that function or try to find
out like what this is actually doing I'm
not in the right window that's got to be
the right project so we're looking at
where this is set and luckily it's set
in just this area so we'll go into that
file and check out why this is being set
this was lying through six okay so as
you can say
the way this is all being calculated is
this s1 is being fed in to this is a
doxy function a DC function and an s-1
is calculated based on the app's
signature and shawwal the base 64
encoded sha-1 hash map so that's passed
into this agency function and then the
return of that is put into the API key
so we're assuming that ad dots that he
generates this keekee ID that's used to
sign necrosis this is the prime example
of not being able to decompile it and
read the pilot because if you decompile
the application yum packet and try to
repackage it its signature will change
so the API key will change so don't eat
the request would be valid what's up you
actually can do that you just have to
another application can read with the
signature of another APIs and then you
just hard code what that signature is
right there yeah that's one way to do I
had tried to do that and the actual
mechanism for the actual mechanism for
calculating the API keys the next I'm
gonna show I try to just grab that code
extract the signature myself and do it
but writing an exposé module turned out
to be a lot easier because it's hooking
one function to just dump that out and
give it to me instead of having to
calculate it so we can see that a DC is
what we're looking for so I will go into
that and show kind of where that's
created 937 day so this is our c
function within the ad class it takes
can be five hash of the input that a 64
encoded thing and then runs this
function a
on the dittus and that function is on
line 2 17 and especially just does a
bunch of shifting and ridiculous stuff
on this array to calculate some sort of
key and the array that it's doing that
on is essentially at the bottom here
it's a bunch of it's just all the hex
carriers you can have so we're looking
for some sort of hex thing and need to
dump that to the logs so where to dump
it how do I know that the get Pike's
function is relevant here I know from
previous research that the each request
has user longitude parameter to it so
they're sending a request to an API via
HTTPS and I know there's a parameter
called user long is associated with it
so before every request is tacked on and
I'm assuming that they're going to sign
it right around there so this took a bit
of work to get to that but it's a good
example of you know kind of associated
this file qf Chad and as you can see
we're adding salt and hash so whatever
is in s4 is the hatch that we're
generating so the API key is used to
sign every request with a hash if your
hash values not correct then it rejects
what you're trying to send it so s fork
is our hash and s4 is being assigned
from this function a which I promise you
is a function that just takes a tix
you're basically to request URI and then
it will take the key which is the API
key i was talking though and it will
hvac it will do any keen hatch on H max
shot 10 is the API key and the thing to
hash is the request-uri those will both
get dumped out of logs so we'll see
those later so essentially we're using
get da get fights so if we go
function we can just dump that straight
out of logs those have a couple more
things but we kind of know what we're
looking for ok so our module this is a
little bit more if there's two things in
here because i use the attack as another
example so again I exposed load package
implementing that handle load packages
are function that we're going to be
overriding here are implementing it
checking if the application name is yet
and then we're loading the module we're
cooking the method get fights here so
we're hooking java.lang.string and then
they get bites method of that so you can
hook java internal classes anything
that's accessible the java you count so
we're creating a method hook and before
it cook set we're just going to say this
object this string object specifically
just dump it out to the logs prefix by
got bites so I can grow up for it fairly
easily so this cool you can actually
access the object that's inside or the
object that this is being called on so
whatever string it is I can grab it and
dump it off the logs so now with any
look I'm going to close this first
because it freaks them with any luck
when I open the application I'll be able
to see that it's dumps out
yes I look tan able Wi-Fi perfect thanks
again wpa2 it was connected to the wrong
internet that's one okay let me go back
to the app though so now our got bites
function it's two out of three demos
that work of maize okay so our God bikes
got bites tags here we can see this is
the key that we're looking for and so if
you actually have before they
implemented more security someone wrote
up a big Python module to basically make
requests to their end points so you
could add you like add users make posts
up oak download things and so they they
didn't let security the people were just
scripting downloads of this and it got
wiped off the planet for a couple days
so that's the key to through the side of
a request and now if we have that key we
can throw that in that application and
actually query like the RIT gig act from
where we are and now so as a side note
i'm going to make sure you refresh the
page here as a side note this right here
this API get messages accuracy this is
the endpoints career this is what it's
hashing so it's hashing this H max draw
one hatch this with this keep so now
with that API key within that module we
can actually see that we can we can get
the GAT feed from their API to the
Python script so we're using that to
sign request to their server yeah
they're pretty bad if you haven't heard
of you gag before it's essentially like
4chan in like a 10 mile radius it's
terrible all right we'll get that off
the screen all right I got to disable
them ought to show you guys the next
part and then
so today yes to replace your life that's
fine I wanted to do all right so we'll
say laughs
so the sampling secured chicks so it's
reverse if you've ever reverse engineer
an application in Android application
and tried to figure out what it's doing
reverse engineering application and
figuring out how its building its
requests this stuff is way harder than
actually span in middle lane if you
command in the middle you can see what's
what's doing when and you can actually
just you know grab the requests so we're
going to do the same thing with you jack
and I'll talk about that on excellent
section so if the app employed is doing
a thinning you're out of luck pretty
much you need to disable that somehow or
manually reverse engineer it you can
disable spit a good thing with expose so
we'll do that so the practice our second
practical example is yet again um David
toys 50 penny so essentially what
happens when you open the app and I'll
show it and you're trying to man middle
it will say no I can't even middles and
say you have no internet which is
obviously false because I have plenty of
internet so I've through a bit of
reversing and figuring out things i
learned that SL is still up here
unverified exception is thrown when the
certificate is unknown so we're going to
basically find that in the code and hook
the function that's throwing enough to
do nothing so man the middle some stuff
how many going on time ten minutes it's
very fiction
so Rep yeah rip it so we're going to
grep in our d compiled code like I said
I saved you daddy compilation step
because it takes a little bit to go
through everything especially with this
because there's so many classes let me
actually show you all of the class names
there's your ridiculous I added the
numbers because they were the same name
and like I said on a case-sensitive file
system so i'm going to scrap that again
so it appears in a couple places i try
it out most of them but we'll go with
the first one because that's the one
actually works and because the first one
right all right go back to my glad I
decided record these commands so we have
this function that throws appear on
verified exception at the bottom so
here's that so we don't want it to do
that and as you can see as well
certificate pinning failure ok so this
string builder is the theta it's
returning stringbuilder two strings
what's returning as the exception
message and so as you can see here it
says certificate hanging failure we have
that CD drive so we don't want this
function to happen at all because it's
going to start an exception so we kind
of make note of that arguments it takes
a string and a list and what it's called
a so NCAA with the string and a list so
now I'll show you guys and if you
haven't used beiser by the way this is
what I'm using to put this put my phone
up on the screen I was thinking about
how to do this talk and I was I was like
I can I hold my phone up or lose an
emulator or what but this is actually a
lot better so I'll show you guys that
without this enabled it yells at me and
it says internet connection
actually appears to be offline which I'm
definitely online I know that I've got
Wi-Fi that has internet so it's
something's going on right now I'm
trying to man in middle of traffic so I
have it I have a certificate installed
from burp I have burp suite running over
here and it's grabbing the stuff so if
we go back here and we'll show the
module code before I reenable already
enabled it now and then well I'm showing
the module code it'll reboot and we can
show that it's actually I put it here
for a reason okay modules yea enable
okay so this is the same much we looked
at before but I didn't show you I didn't
explain this line of code which is
disabling certificate pinning i also
have an example in here a replacement
method that just logs whatever string
its past and then returns null finding
Huck method and CJ that was our class
and then function name first argument is
a string second argument is a list and
then Ellen that loves attention and then
our we're replacing the method we're
just saying hey man just don't just do
anything all right so we don't want to
throw that exception so if it doesn't
run it's not going to throw that
exception function you may be saying a
well if that function does something
else that is where things get
complicated you actually have to start
like really digging into this and
figuring out like what to do but like I
said this is a basic intro to explicit
rework and how you can help stuff so I
figured out that it doesn't do anything
else besides just get painting that's
all the checks so we just don't do it
then I'll be fine all right waiting for
my phone to Pluto so first wheats
running you guys have had you guys
having how many people you spurt before
or sweet yeah Roxy in the middle the
issue is here HTS we need to cert you
can install the circ within the Android
certificate store and that will allow
you two met in middle traffic that
aren't traffic's that's not certificate
and so it verifies a certificate you're
outta luck and so basically that's what
we're disabled within this application
so waiting for my phone it's going to
yell me
any questions while we're here this is
my last part so good did you publish the
Python script the wholesale yeah it's
somewhere on the internet is I did that
I had had that from a while ago it
wasn't mine but I had like made changes
to it so that I could I could I updated
it so that I could query it again
because they've changed their API a
little bit since its kind of broken
right now there's a lot of features that
are out there like message posting
uploading and downloading because I
think they're rate limiting now you used
to be able to just download things like
continually and now you can't do that
anymore they've actually improved their
security to go which is good for them
but i think it's the martin and it's
called py AK jack and there's some code
that I've contributed to that that i'm
not sure if it works anymore have to fix
it but if you guys want i can publish
just the part that gets the messages and
prints them out to the screen sure kind
of you demonstrated method hooky with
objects that are from the java standard
library how is the framework capable of
hooking functions that take objects that
are defined inside of the definitions by
the application yes but you need to
basically get the d compiled code and
like make it acceptable for reading
because it needs to know what the class
is to be able to accept it you can
recreate it you have all the code so you
can recreate it that's a little bit more
painful and that's kind of outside the
scope of this talk because it takes
forever to do that if you're looking for
a cool example of that i thought one of
the projects that i fall on it has
helped me did all this talk early I
really lost as on the last slide
talk about it when we get there good oh
just a former common with a slight
question so you sort of mentioned you
really do anything too terribly
nefarious with us but one of the issues
I've seen with android app sec is that
it's pretty bad you're not wrong now so
immediately my first thought is let's
try and hook something that's doing
client-side input validation have you
been covered with that um I mean I've
seen a couple laps but I mean yeah like
words of friends of that example like
that's the appliance I Belgian yeah sure
something maybe a little bit more
nefarious something where you actually
doing like you know parsing for SQL
general I haven't looked into that
that's definitely something that's like
mymy idea with this talk was I have
these applications that I know work and
our fun examples yeah but this is
definitely like I said extendable to
whatever else you know you can write a
module if you can think about the module
like if you can think about a function
that you want to hook with inside the
application you can change you can
change the functionality the reverse
engineering is like i said i was about
half this talk and it is a big big topic
that people really need to get further
into and that put out a hold two three
talks devote to it itself so if you can
find it you can change it pretty much
within ok is your question someone all
right so now we'll launch the app and
we'll see hopefully cross my fingers on
my last demo that it will grab it will
grab the yes and at this point we can go
over to our burp I'm know this font
small I'm sorry and we can see that it
squaring the API successfully and I'll
actually put this in a vim window and
just show it to you here copy
and so we can see that here's the API
here's the actual query to the server
and we are meddling all the traffic now
and it's not yelling at us because oh
hey you're not connect to the internet
we disabled the certificate pinning
check and now we can get all the traffic
in the middle and we don't have to spend
the time reverse engineering that whole
like section of code that compiles this
whole request so we can see them as they
happen so like getting messages or
posting things are uploading downloading
whatever all right
alright so other resources in the code
the coaching this presentation the
reversing tools the KPK decompiler
script and the string search script on
there as well as the module are the
unzip or expose mods has a couple mods
there's one extra there's a fun module
that will monitor google play music for
Taylor Swift songs and skip them so I
thought that was fun it was it's an
interesting thing that's interesting
module to look at as well because it
access class attributes it's a kind of a
practicing accessing class attributes so
song name I to figure out what the hell
that was and resolve it dynamically so
that's a really cool little thing the
there's a development tutorial by a guy
that created the xposed framework he
actually this small little tutorial has
changed the clock read like change the
system clock read so he actually has an
example of cooking zygote which is that
first process and looking for the actual
android UI so you can hook things with
an android UI and not just in
applications but that was coming outside
the scope of this this talk the XDA
forum there's a physics a forum for
everything into it and there is one for
the xposed framework and module
development and modules themselves so go
ahead and check out out here interested
the export source code was something
that I looked at a little bit just
interested in it because it was just
it's a really cool project and the guy
that maintains it the guys have
maintained it really like just
mind-blowing stuff how they came up with
this and I was going to rewrite at
process like great snap dress is the app
that I was talking about Brad snap
perhaps the source code for snap perhaps
is great they have stuff on obfuscation
like doing the obfuscation for snapchat
it's basically a big snapchat library so
you can like no screenshot notifications
I think we can change the weather you
can make it to like going a million
miles an hour extra filters or stuff
like that it doesn't work currently
because
update it that much but if you guys want
to submit for us I'm sure you do both of
them the source code is there and that
has a lot of examples of hooking stuff a
lot of creating your own you is if
you're looking into cooking UI elements
and things like that that's definitely a
project to look into and I did well on
time Wow how do you put any of the
questions from you guys you're more than
welcome you approach me afterwards and
yeah thank you guys for listening and
coming to the soccer
you