what's going on everybody so before we
kicked us off we wanted to give you a
shout out we don't really think that
this many people would come to our talk
so super pumped that you guys showed up
hopefully it doesn't suck but regardless
thanks for coming out we really
appreciate it so to kick this off cool
so my name is Jared Stroud I'm an RIT
cocooning security master students
sparse alumni CCDC alumni and I would
describe myself as a start-up
enthusiasts to whatever that means to
you so I bright and then the same thing
basically and I have cool shoes that I'm
rocking today so so to go through a
little bit of the agenda that we had set
up for today we're going to talk about
where the background for our talk came
from some previous work that's been done
what the motivation was that let us do
this talk and then we're going to dive
in into to DevOps tools ansible and
saltstack and talk about how their
functionality can help you scale and
automate your read operations but first
so trigger warning we have a lot of buzz
words in our talk hope you guys get
super pumped if you're not then I mean I
guess you can leave if you want I talk
like hopefully will be pretty cool but
just DevOps in general then it comes
with a lot of buzz words so just a heads
up and for anybody who is about the
whole like I'm going to take a drink
after every buzzword I about for /aa now
you're probably going to be on the floor
so I wouldn't recommend
so we keep saying this worth DevOps in
this big old DevOps hype train that all
right a bunch of people keep shouting
out but we're going to establish like a
ground basis of what we mean when we say
it so really at the end of the day it's
whatever tool allows you to automate
something and be reliable against a
variety of environments so whether
that's spinning up several different
nodes in AWS to using the same kind of
infrastructure but putting it over in a
different cloud provider there's these
tools that allow you to replicate
reliably deploy code push out tests just
continuously so some of you guys might
think of like Jenkins ansibles all-sec
obviously we're going to talk about
today we don't mean it in the like
philosophically where it's like it's a
cultural thing and it's how many scrum
meetings you do so just that kind of a
basis it's really just making sure that
whatever you're doing is reliable across
different infrastructures so going on to
the motivation Brian and I both do some
malware analysis and look side projects
and hobbies so we always really liked
when we see malware that's using the
inherent environment and society tools
to move laterally through a network so
it's not doing anything super crazy but
it's using tools that are already there
something that's already there for the
advantage why bring the guns into the
place where you can just use their guns
right that kind of idea has anybody seen
Chris gays and Ken Johnson stock auf dem
boobs all right so a couple people for
those of you of not it's actually a
pretty cool talk they talk about how
people like mess up a lot of things when
doing DevOps stuff so for example
pushing API keys to github or leaving
their docket directory publicly
accessible for their website so that you
could just pull it down so we thought
that would be cool to also like build on
like another DevOps talk based off of
that kind of stuff so that was another
motivation for our talk yeah and also
competitions how many CTF players do I
have in the house nice I'm an acct see
alumni or attack defend people just in
general for these competitions yeah nice
so if you're not familiar with CCDC it
stands for collegiate
defense competition and it's basically
when a bunch of college students go and
sit in a room and there's a group of
professional red teamers and they make
us have a super bad time to an
inherently vulnerable environments so
the whole idea behind some of these
attack defense ETF slow if you're not
familiar with them is that you'll have
an infrastructure it'll be vulnerable in
some way shape or form whether it's just
like super simple things like the fault
creds exploding a web app or some kind
of custom network surface that you have
to actually create an exploit for and
then take advantage of the machine once
you get onto the machine you need to
find some kind of token and replace it
with your flag so that the corresponding
scoring engine can give you points so at
the end of the day the only thing that
really matters about this is speed but
to continue some of the things that we
talked about all of this living off the
land mentality is going to become really
interesting with DevOps tools because
these are already inherently trusted
tools within an environment they're not
going to fly a gayby they're not going
to flag your needs or other network
controls that you have and they're
allowing for remote code execution so if
I said something to the effect of you
have something on your box that calls
back to me every 10 to 15 minutes and
that runs any command I give it this
sounds kind of like a botnet right I
could be talking about a DevOps tool
they're really analogous with the same
thing and we'll dive into that in a
second but to kind of talk about the
objective here is that we want to
automate these attack defense ETFs to an
extent we know that there's going to be
an infrastructure that's inherently
vulnerable right we're always going to
have some kind of default creds that
we're going to be able to get onto some
boxes with and we want to be able to do
this fast some of the ways that people
are trying to automate this now everyone
that competes in these usually have some
kind of subset of Python scripts or
shell scripts that allow them to you
know automate some of the simple things
that they're trying to do these don't
really scale out well especially when
you continuously add more machines to an
environment or you go from one
competition to another so that's where
this whole DevOps mentality of run wants
but run everywhere and accomplish the
same goals can really be advantageous to
these competitions just one quick note
about
is that like we're talking specifically
on going back to red teaming at
competitions as opposed to like from pen
testing perspective so when your pen
testing you might not get default
credits and stuff probably like you most
likely won't so that's where like we're
coming front with that but for the pen
test people on the house didn't forget
about you so if you're trying to
automate say like am i single dump
across the entire network or it's my
sequel then they have no signal
databases or they have kind of a
plethora mixed match of these
technologies you can use these kind of
DevOps tools to chain things together so
when you hit a machine that has Redis or
mongo DB or my sequel or postgres
whatever the case may be you can run
these series of tests depending on what
they have so you can kind of on the fly
make your own tools to get some of the
low-hanging fruit so while our talk is
mainly related to just automating these
red team attacks etfs definitely want to
make sure you guys are still thinking in
the realm of how this could be used for
contest engagements so with that we're
going to dive into ansible so out of
curiosity has anyone used ansible here
nice school got some hands so ansibles
really attractive for a number of
reasons first off it's completely
agentless so all it operates completely
over ssh to the remote nodes so if you
have ssh access to a remote host you can
automate ansible to run something called
a playbook which talked about in a
second on said host the best practices
mechanism relies on you having SSH keys
on the remote host but there's nothing
stopping you from just having passwords
that you try against the host so if you
put this in a for loop you can now run
these ansible commands it basically is a
brute force mechanism to then launch
other evil things which we're going to
dive into additionally Red Hat just
bought ansible in 2014 so this is going
to become more of a prevalent tool that
I believe you'll be seeing out in
industry Ike uses layer 7 for users
completely SSH for communication and it
can actually be installed with hip the
Python package manager so if you just do
pip install ansible you now have an
school on your machine
so a simple ansible architecture kind of
looks like this you have your one
ansible master node so to speak and you
have these things called playbooks that
i keep alluding to so the idea here is
to have repeatable task execution to
accomplish the same goal regardless of
what your infrastructure is it's a
developer machine not a problem
production servers your entire data
centers as long as you have some kind of
access via ssh to these machines you can
execute ansible playbooks so going into
targeting based on what your needs are
ansible inventory is how you go ahead
and specify the hosts that you're
looking for in an infrastructure so off
to the left here we see a format where
you had just the brackets you specify
what kind of category these hosts are so
you can say database servers web servers
one of the case may be and then you can
just list underneath them IP addresses
or folder called by domain names
additionally you can pass an ansible
port which would be a different ssh port
for that machine passwords and usernames
so like I said before if you don't have
keys on the remote host it's not the end
of the world you can still access them
just by doing a command-line argument to
provide the password so this will kind
of allows you to break down all the
database servers I have these scripts or
these sets of tests I need to do to
accomplish again on those machines so
this like i said before can just be
changing a banner or stop jumping the
big excuse me dumping the database
entirely so finally to the thing that i
keep talking about ansible playbooks can
be described as executable documentation
they're in a really easy to read yeah
mol format as of the time of this
presentation they have 200 plus core
modules which allow you to do a variety
of tasks against an environment and it's
just they execute sequentially so you
list what you're trying to do and it'll
just go through and then execute it in
that order you can also just specify
only run the mics evil commands against
these hosts or kind of chop it up
however you'd like it to be these
playbooks can be platform independent
however what is set in theory doesn't
necessarily translate to practice there
are some caveats that you need to be
aware of so
definitely test this before you just
kind of go out and think that everything
will work super fine so as I said before
it's in a yeah mol format and you can
specify the options of what you're
running against with tags so let's see
what one of these playbooks looks like
so this is the typical structure it's a
pretty small playbook at the top here
you see you specified the hosts so dub
dub dub going back to the ansible
inventory file and specify the remote
user that you want to run as and then
you can specify some variables for what
you're trying to accomplish later on
with these tasks so up here we see we
have a github repo and we also have a
pastebin document that we can download
code from and then run it if we so
choose and a directory where you want to
store things on the remote host so we
see going through these tasks you seen
this naming tag this name tag is more of
a descriptor which will actually fire
back to you when you run these if the
status was complete and what you've ran
so the package is it going to install
get get URL pretty intuitive right you
know it's going to go download something
says where to save it and what
permissions to save it is you can
schedule tasks with cron etc etc so
everything that you probably have some
kind of shell scripts for that you've
used in these attack defense scenarios
you can take and port to ansible fairly
easily or build up pretty robust tasks
with ansible so when you run these guys
the really nice thing about ansible is
that you get visible feedback almost
immediately so in these attack defense
ETFs from a red team's point of view
it's not just about got in the Box got a
root show i won you have to usually keep
track of what you're trying to do and
when you did it so a lot of tools don't
necessarily have a reporting mechanism
and I can kind of be a pain to sit there
and be like ah what did i do like an
hour ago to team six right well if you
divvy up your inventory file in a way
that you specify what team is
corresponds to what IP address or what
domain names danceable can just
immediately provide that feedback along
with what time that these executed on so
it's kind of a nice way to keep track of
when you're doing things so as you see
running this against the remote host
this is what it looks like from the
remote host aspect this downloaded the
paceman script and I
Who am I to all see that I'm roots so
it's pretty straightforward in terms of
how you can execute these modules
speaking of modules these are what goes
in the interval and small tasks and if
you're already thinking of like hey I
have some super-secret sauce things that
ansible might not already have tests and
for you can actually make them yourself
and all they are are simple Python
scripts so if you already have Python
scripts and corporative into ansible is
going to be super easy and that's
another attractive feature of this is
that it is all in Python so this is
right from the ansible documentation but
it's really just any task that you're
trying to accomplish on a system and get
immediate feedback for so these usually
aren't very like large functions it's
usually like really small things like
changing some setting in a config file
adding users dropping SSH keys whatever
the case may be this is typically what
you see with ansible modules and they
kind of like allow you to perform some
basic tasks that being said nothing
stopping you from writing some kind of
Python cryptolocker and then running
this against remote machines and making
the blue team's have a super bad time so
now that we've gone through all of that
we kind of have a nice warm fuzzy
feeling of what ansible is and some of
the capabilities of it we're going to
talk a little bit about some of the
offensive operations so to speak that
you can do in these kinds of
environments so once again they are
geared towards the competition's that
college students compete in so fantastic
this is a little bit outside of your
normal day-to-day operations so how many
people here have red black cap Python
awesome so you guys are familiar with
the github botnet there where you just
immediately establish some kind of agent
on the hosts and then you have it pulled
from github and execute some kind of
tasks well using the crown module
corresponding with the get module you
can set up to schedule ii pull from a
git repo so this seems you know pretty
easy because you can't necessarily
guarantee how long you can be on a box
when you walk into these instructors you
don't know what other teams are going to
do and you need to maximize the Mouser
is that you get on excuse me the surface
area of blocks that you go to rather
than staying on one box and securing it
you might lose a foothold in another
machine so you have to move fast right
so this allows you to immediately
schedule tasks so that whatever you put
in this repo will execute on the host
machine so that way you don't need to
worry about you actually maintaining
access through ssh or anything like that
you can just update that repo from your
machine it'll pull down and execute
whatever that case may be so if you lose
SSH access not a problem that cron jobs
they'll execute and you're still going
to be able to spawn another shell and
still have access to the machine that
way so we have a nice ansible playbook
that actually accomplishes this on a
github repo that were like sharing some
of these tasks at the end of the end of
the talk so just like before when you
run this that green gives you that
immediate feedback saying that yes it's
executed okay where you see yellow
that's where things change so that's
where a file was updated my file was
deleted whether the case may be and any
time you run any bash command it'll
always pronounce change because it's
going to redirect to standard out by
default unless you specify to go to a
file or something like that so once
again you can immediately know if these
tests aren't executing successfully
against your environment or someone beat
you to it so for the blue teens so going
to like CCDC because i know that ansible
was used successfully at the NEC cdc
region this year and spilled by default
does not log on the master node but on
all the end nodes that's logging into it
does leave some nice little traces of
the tests that's commute executing ass
so we see that we have a highlighted red
ants little hyphen gate URL we saw this
in a previous slide this was obviously
downloading the paceman script to be ran
later also at crontab we see in this
really terrible read dark blue appear we
have ansible and then scoring engine
that being said this is an open source
tool there's nothing stopping you from
changing these values but just so you
know by the default this is what's going
to be left on machine when you run said
tasks so now we've talked about like
super basic way to god machine make sure
that you can come back to that machine
and a little bit while you're
trying to move throughout the network
but really at the end of the day you
need to be really really fast right you
can't risk other teams getting on these
boxes before you and just like
firewalling you off so antipolo has a
lot of ways that you can optimize it
we're going to talk about a few of them
here so some of these optimization facts
allow you to basically skip a lot of
core things the ansible would do that
would be advantageous to system
administrators but not so much
advantageous when you're just trying to
move fast and execute things across to
machine in a competitive environment so
SSH pipelining basically limits the
numbers of SSH connections but will
maximize the command executed over them
so it cuts down on overhead of how many
connections to a given machine Forks
obviously more threads depending on the
tasks that you try and execute what your
machine can handle you're going to have
multiple SSH connections to multiple
machines by default it's only five you
can scale it up to whatever your machine
can support but the the most tedious one
is this gathering facts so when you run
in command against their about host it
does this thing where basically profiles
the system and understands what certain
variables are so what is the underlining
packaging system what is the underlying
colonel this that and the other thing
and that cannon gets passed into some of
the tasks depending on the variables and
tastic you're trying to execute that
being said some of these take a very
long time to accomplish if you just need
to know the underlying packaging system
they've trying to do the platform
independence way you don't need to do
this like long tedious task right so you
can go ahead and disable this or fine
tuning so that way you don't spend all
this to the time on a machine so to give
you kind of an idea of how long this
took with a simple way to figure out the
uptime of machines against two machines
this happened about 46 seconds so that
seems super long than me just to get up
time on some remote machines to run that
against right 46 seconds to get off time
of to machines so this is before the
optimization so after we went through
and we said I don't really care about
this gathering facts I want the many
Forks as possible and I don't really
care about I want SSH pipelining we're
able to get it down to just point a
little
10 seconds so that was reliable too we
tested this three times so once again
this is definitely your tail more
towards the CTF side of things because
you do lose some of the inherent
functionality that's just admins would
use this tool for but now we're going to
talk a little bit about DevOps with dev
ops and that's where things get super
buzzed already so apologize in advance
everybody but Brian's about to take over
and talk about saltstack and why this is
advantageous but we were able to
bootstrap salt on three machines from
scratch points it to our master salt
master which bride will talk about in a
second in just under two minutes and 25
seconds so this was a pretty fast
overall and we'll talk about why this is
important in a second I think there are
a few slides like down the road where I
actually like listed the like
bootstrapping command so like I'll show
you get those guys you know in a bit but
there's like one command you can run
that only uses Python to pull down and
you're all lived to which is default
python module you don't actually need to
a pip install anything additional so
what it does is it pulls down the
bootstrapping script from salts website
and it will execute it so that it will
install the salt minion on the nose to
point back to your master and you can
push out like different tasks to it you
can solve so yeah we talked about that
and good but that still means that there
isn't there there is so sport for those
old dirty bass tracks that everyone has
right so if you compete in this
competition you start collecting as a
series of scripts that you've used from
A to B and you collect them just in case
to be useful again so it's super easy to
port these two ansible and use them in a
variety of ways once again we have these
kind of stuff up on the github so that
way we can show you guys like a skeleton
key of how you might be able to use
these in these attack defendant
environments so Anton was pretty cool
but I'm a big fan of using salt for this
kind of stuff there a couple of reasons
for that mostly its architecture was
which I'll get into in a bit but a
little bit of
background is that I'm as I mentioned
it's agent based so how it works is the
agents on the salt minions will check in
with the master you see if there are any
tasks that are signed for it and if
there are then it will execute them and
index checks in on a fairly regular
basis so like a few every few seconds by
default so another interesting thing is
that the master meetings run as root by
default so dirty computation events it's
useful having root on the box with salt
minions because you're rude on the box
so by default the master runs his route
but if you're actually using this in an
enterprise you can change that and you
can also configure it so that it uses
some sort of external authentication
like LDAP or Active Directory
Integration and so you can actually
limit the commands that like different
people and your organization are able to
actually execute and what host they can
do that but from a competition
perspective that's not really a 22
necessary by default salt listens on
port 450 5 or 4 5 06 and I read that in
their documentation by default saw
minions try to connect to ideas to the
host salt so when I first read that
mossley oh you could probably take
advantage of that somehow like if you're
able but I mean if you're able to get on
some of these dns server they're
probably gonna have a worse problem than
that so uh so a couple of like the
terminology that salt uses is that it
uses what's called a salt grain and so
what those allow you to do is narrow
down your target set so you can say I
want all of the Ubuntu boxes or
everything that is debian-based or
anything running the Linux kernel or all
windows machines things like that and
then you can give them tasks to execute
so that right there an example of
running Who am I on everything that
Scoob unto uh so there are salt modules
two different kinds there are execution
modules and state modules so the
execution modules are just a bunch of
built in modules that you can add two
states so for example the command module
is a built-in excuse execution module
and
with the state modules you can write
them and their files that basically can
configure any of the hosts that are
checking in however you want them to so
we'll get into a couple of different
ways that you can use those for and so
the state modules are similar to ansible
playbooks that's basically the same
thing and they're also a yanil format so
the syntax is very similar as well and
then there are salt formulas which are
pre-written salt states that are like
pushed up to the official salt formula
repo that people write so that if you
want to enable rdp on windows boxes
somebody went through all the time and
actually figured out how to use those so
you can actually take those and build
those into the salt states that you're
writing and then there are what's called
salt pillars which are also just salt
state files like the yambol format that
are just a bunch of variables so if you
have a salt state that adds a bunch of
users to the machines what you can do is
in the pillar files you can say like
here this is the username I want this is
the name this is the UID this is the GID
this is all the G cos information that
you want to add for these users so it's
really like fine tunable to be able to
take advantage of salt pillars and then
so why you salt for like from a
competition aspect why I really like it
is that as we noted before it uses a
polling mechanism so the minions check
into the hosts there's nothing stopping
you from running the master on port 80
and 443 which will most likely be
allowed outbound so once people figure
out how to write firewall rules they'll
usually block ingress stuff in there's
like not really any reason that people
need external ssh access to their hosts
so they'll probably block you off that
way but chances are that they're still
going to allow 80 and 443 out because
everybody allows without and people
really suck
running egress filters in general anyway
so yeah that's another cool reason why I
like it uh so as I mentioned before
there's bootstrapping so you can install
if you just upload this all minion
executable to a windows box you can
assault with one command and it will do
everything in the background for you
there's no additional configuration that
you need to do you just say hey I want
to point this at this master server and
it will take care of everything else and
then that's the command that will
download the bootstrap script for like
Nick's boxes and it will configure it
and then point back to the master so so
what would you do as a red team or for
an event any ideas no I 0 who's driving
what all right yep right good call all
right any other ideas yeah add users
good idea any other ideas nice good god
so what we do is we came up with a proof
of concept with a few of these things so
dropping ssh keys adding users ensuring
remote access is enabling ssh and rdp
and like installing stuff basically so
if you're dropping sui de binary's if
there's no GCC on the box you're
probably gonna have a bad time compiling
that so you're going to want to install
GCC in order to be able to do that so
here's an example of what's called the
top file so every time minions check in
they look for this file and inside the
top file is where you list all the other
state modules that you want the minions
to execute so these are just a few
modules that
I wrote with the extension of the ND
next one because that was a soft formula
that I was using that will like the
wild-card there the start will say on
every host that checks in I want you to
install like these packages add these
users and make sure these services are
enabled and drop some scit binaries so
this is before i actually had windows
hosts in the environment than i had to
add that after I guess I just forgot to
change that because probably have a bad
time like dropping sui de binary's on
windows but so yeah the next so here's
an example just what i did for
installing GCC so easy at the top there
you're using grains to actually limit
what hosts that are checking in so this
is saying that every linux box installed
GCC out and then you can see down here
install them on debian based os's and
it's called vim enhanced on like red hat
based phones because an ass mixer so if
you tell you a job as your ID binaries
so on your cell master server you would
have a source file that every time the
minions check in they will make sure
that they have this file on the box and
they'll store it in tempt SRC CC and
then there's the command to download I
mean to compile and then change the
owner and file permissions for the
executables themselves so that it
actually is an su I do binary and you
can write a for loop that says I want to
install all of these I mean compile all
these
and put these at these locations so for
each file you can give it like a full
pass to what do you want to drop them so
to make sure that ssh is running on
Debian RedHat base OS is this is
literally all you have to do is say SS
agent sshd and then if it's not running
it will make sure that it's running it
will restart it for it so one thing that
you're going to want to do is cover your
tracks and that's actually really easy
to do so you can just configure a log
level to be quiet in the salt minion
configuration file and if you don't like
default it runs as warning and so that
doesn't actually list any commands that
run successfully it will stuff that you
do not want correctly so what I do is I
ran Who am I but it spells way am I
wrong and you can see at the bottom
there am I not found for anybody that's
sitting in the way back sorry the fog
was really small but this was a really
small picture so going back to
triggering everyone so the agile Red
Team workflow so how you move with
environment and how you operate as a red
team so typically the whole idea behind
being successful in these competitions
was uterus get onto the box you'd
persist somehow do stuff and then profit
at the end depending on how long you've
had that box for and how the scoring
service works so if it was checking in
for a banner making sure that it was
always your banner so that you would get
the points for it right well the way
that we're proposing now is using
ansible playbooks to quickly move
whatever it is your secrets losses to
all of these machines and then using
saltstack for that long term access to
bypass egress filters doing DevOps for
your DevOps buzzword yeah so we're going
into about 15 minutes left we're gonna
try to do a live demo for this we left
15 minutes because we're sure this live
demo is gonna be a lot of demo if you've
ever been to done they usually fail so
as we set this up do
guys have any questions that you want to
shout out about the dev ops or ants will
install sex stuff in general no
questions yeah okay so i should probably
zoom in on this produce everybody see
that well we'll make it a little bigger
alright cool okay so let's go you can
see on the top there that's on the salt
master server and what that's doing is
every time a minion checks in for the
first time it will list its keys that
you have to accept in order to be able
to start pushing stuff to those boxes
yeah so we're going to go ahead and run
this ansible playbook which just goes
out users ansible to install salt sec on
all these machines and then we'll call
back to us so then we can execute
whatever commands we want so all it's
doing is executing that bootstrap
command that was using Python to install
the minion so like we've mentioned
before it's actually pretty quick to run
this but running it across like the
three hosts two of them are Ubuntu and
one is sent to us and so the Red Hat
based ones like will check in quicker
that takes about a minute for everything
to be configured and installed so that
will show up under the unaccepted keys
in a bit for the Ubuntu ones it usually
takes a little bit more because it runs
apt-get update to update all the repos
every time the script is started so that
takes like two to like two and a half
minutes for those to complete once those
are completed the salt minions
themselves after you accept the keys
have to do some background stuff to like
finish configuring themselves so even
though like they check in and you
their keys they still might not be you
can see the first one finished so that's
the center west box it still might take
a little bit for the hosts to be
configuring so you can't send command
immediately it might take an additional
minute and then after that next minute
what you can do is then you can execute
all of your state files that you want to
send out to all the hosts so that would
be this stuff that you say add these
users drop su ID files install GCC job
SSH keys all that good stuff so it's
important to note too that I mean the
word key might get in a way but all of
the communication between the salt
master and millions is encrypted so
another bonus so that whatever you know
custom thing that you have written
typically what I've seen these
competitions they're not encrypted so if
you just do TCP dump you can see what
your competition is running against your
machine and then better prepare yourself
to defend against it or just take over
whatever IRC bot that they have if you
go to their IRC server so this kind of
eliminates that from the scenario by
just adding a salt master that can
execute commands over an encrypted
tunnel so like we said there we see the
three changed so that way we know that
salt has successfully been installed on
these machines so DevOps I'm pretty hard
together right now we're using the
ansible to install saltstack feel pretty
good about it Brian right now is
accepting these keys so that way it is
you up all night so he can assure you
out commands as master to all the
meeting servers so now you can see that
all the keys have been accepted so what
I'm gonna do is like in spell sorry
gonna go ahead hit the mute Bundy so
what you could do is salt and then the
next thing that you type is what
specifies the hosts that you want to say
send information to so what I'm saying
is that every host I want to basically
send a
test ping to tell me whether it's alive
or not so that's actually pretty cool
that those all worked on the first time
was not expecting that so that's cool
because usually takes a little bit for
those to finish configuring in
themselves in the background so now what
I'm gonna run well what I'm gonna run
and try to like type correctly is
applying all the states so what this is
going to do is every time all the host
check in it's going to look through look
for the top file and you can see that
our DP was enabled and it's still
running so on the windows box it was
good to go so it might take a little bit
more probably take about another minute
and a half to add all users drop the Sui
de binary's drop the ssh keys and yeah
it does anybody have any questions yeah
read like proxy around so at panoply
which is an event that they run at CCDC
which is a cici's primarily team event
except for the last day they'd run
something called monopoly where they
allow all the blue tumors to just try to
take over environment and change the
flag so there's always a music box and
everyone goes to the music box to change
the music for the entire room I'm not
sure what team got it last year but they
just started playing games of Thrones
music throughout the whole thing and
they were blocking subnets and stuff
like that so that was one of the things
that kind of like you know if we were
faster we would not have this problem
and listening to this like really
daunting music just blasting through the
speakers so that's a frustration that
kind of sparked it too so you see that
it just succeeded for all three boxes
because green is good so that's gold see
so now if you want to try to ssh in
anymore so we dropped Jared's SSH key so
hopefully this works so you're gonna
know try bill so bill and that box
should have his SE now we're in so this
yeah so once again through salt minions
on all these boxes are running as root
so these are as good as root shells if
not better because it hasn't this nice
and cryptic command communication
exports all these really cool salt files
so that way if you're in environment
you're like hey I suddenly have all
these windows machines but I need to do
something never done with Windows the
salt community itself is pretty active
so you can go grab a state file that
could be for like a legitimate purpose
of configuring some kind of service and
totally use it to your advantage so
there's a large community behind this
for like DevOps and system
administration there's nothing stopping
you from taking them tweaking them at
using them to your competitive advantage
which is really what this is all about
so we also drop sui de binary's compiled
one and threw it in the path and we call
the watchdog d so you see you just run
that command and then your route so even
if they disable root login you can still
have root on the box
so all in real time you saw let's do
this three machines a couple of minutes
and this is continued access so we'd
like to open up to any other questions
that we have because this demo worked a
lot better than what we planned for yeah
yeah you absolutely can so the one of
the problems with some this is it comes
to the trade-off with the ssh pipelining
is that it's reported that where you're
transferring like larger packages so
depending on how big what you're trying
to get from A to B is it can take more
time so like at minutes 0 if you kick
that off and you have all these pre
packaged and ready to go that by all
means we'll work it might take a couple
lecture seconds but in the long run that
could be advantageous if someone else is
just going to start firing rolling off
subnets and whatever reports that may be
yeah awesome question so puppet is
puppets really cool and so is in chef
the reason that we didn't go with Chef
is because the infrastructure overall to
set that up and start managing it it's a
little bit more heavier whereas with
salt and ansible you can kind of walk
into a competition and just have a
laptop around this the chef server tends
to be a little bit bulkier depending on
what you're trying to do but for a
puppet I believe for the non Enterprise
Edition there's a limit of how many
nodes you can have if i remember
correctly and also just for ansible and
south sac both being in python and both
having that yambol format it's super
easy if you have something that you want
in the ansible playbooks to be converted
to long term stuff for salsa so that is
really the like very middle there's no
reason you can't use those tools we just
chose to go with these yeah
absolutely all right well if you guys
have any more questions we just wanted
to kick it off with other be more but
we'll be hanging around here if you guys
have more questions thank you very much
for your time I'm sure thank you