hi everybody if you're me okay so this
stuff first talk I'm doing here because
this one is ApS security testing for
hackers or impaired security testing one
one so we're gonna go over some basic
things about api's security mechanisms
the different ways that you can approach
testing an API and then some examples of
some bugs that I have found in a px so a
little bit about me uh yes I'm a
security researcher and an engineer or
get zip car specializing in web app
coyote and infrastructure security and
my dreams are own and do not represent
my employer so right now what I'll do
that this talk kind of clip into two
parts so the first one is going to be an
overview of API attack vectors and so
I'll just go through some of the basic
things that so you may or may not know
and just talk through them with some
famous examples from recently and then
the next part I will talk about the bugs
that I actually found so the first thing
to kind of go over is common API
security issues and a glance so one of
things that I like to know to people is
API bugs are a very common source of a
lot of the newsroom here about security
holes or people being able to access
things they weren't supposed to
everything from Twitter to Facebook to
Google+ to smaller companies we see a
lot of things about the API was misused
or mishandled or access was given where
it wasn't supposed to and so those kinds
of things are really in public sphere
now so I'd like to share this kind of
information with people when they ask
about those bigger news stories so
security issues and bones of API is
typically fall into a few distinct
categories so there's there are a bunch
more but the core ones that I want to
focus on today were access controls with
authorization and authentication rate
limiting input validation HTTP methods
third party API abuse and then some
other application and logic errors that
are kind of sprinkled throughout so the
first one that we'll discuss is access
controls so from the basic get-go we'll
defer to some definitions here so
authentication involves proving that you
are who you say you are whether you're
an admin or a guest or a developer
authorization involves granting access
to the resources that you requested
based on your identity so access control
schemes tend to follow a pattern this is
very general it's not really pointing to
any specific type of application but
usually the client or user will make
your request something that requires
authentication of some sort the server
will process that request and we'll
check for a few things so those are an
account or session already exists in a
database or if you've already been on
the site before if the requested
resource is actually within the access
scope of the client so are you actually
authorized to view whatever resource
here requesting if there's any other
previous cookies or tokens that were
used in the request that may be point to
you having the authorization already if
they're way to the earth the if the
route to the resource is actually valid
so how did you get there you get there
from Google Dorking or did you get there
from within the application itself any
other conditions and then any other
conditions the server might expect
beyond this so it's successful the
server will give you a token or a
session ID or any other identifier to
mark who you are throughout the session
and then any other requests that need to
be authenticated will follow this
pattern again so some common ways that
people test for access control bugs
include numerating potentially
restricted endpoints so anything in the
admin scope developer test any internal
API endpoints modifying session tokens
so either reusing or you know modifying
them in some way or or putting junk data
in there attempting to bypass
restrictions on access with I do
indirect object reference and modifying
your request with additional parameters
so people put things like admin equals
true or test equals one or things like
that and modifying referrer headers that
the application might expect so you can
actually smooth those and say that you
came from some other part of the
application so a famous one from this
past year was canary bread so Panera
Bread had the API endpoint exposed that
allowed for access to client information
so this was you know credit cards and
you know usernames emails addresses and
also to other info and the client
records were sequentially numbered so it
was quite easy to enumerate the entire
database by just incrementing and I
think that figured what the actual
amount was but there was about tens of
millions of client records that were
leaked through this so this is an
example of just a access control bug
where this definitely wasn't supposed to
be something that a normal
unauthenticated user was allowed to
access this should be strictly for
developers and authorized people so the
next bug class that we have here input
validation so input validation is super
important and it's something a lot of
people usually consider when they are
hunting for any kinds of bugs but it's
very very critical to remember that
input is anything that the server takes
in whether it's from a user third party
apps or other internal mechanisms so
common places to test input validation
and API and being within the request
header parameters within the URL
parameters in the request like we said
before file uploads for very very
important ones as well to play with and
different request methods to so
depending on the architecture of the
application specific parts of the
request making process in unsafe ways so
you see this with any any sort of web
application whether it's in you know a
API or an older application but the
common bugs would be improper
parameterization over
Quest's within the application logic so
are they just concatenated variables in
in put together and treating all it put
as trusted lack of input sanitation and
escaping unsafe characters and all sorts
of other sanitation there sanitization
techniques improper handling the
parameters which actually we'll get to
in a second and insufficient controls
for data types past so any past you know
a PDF or a zip file or can you pass a
bunch of Unicode and is that properly
handled
so another famous one another famous bug
is an input validation bug that I
thought was really interesting so
Germany has an eID system that allows
for people to identify there or use
their real-life identity online and so
some people had tested this and they
found that the requests to the Eid
system required request to be signed
which is you know great access control
and input validation and so the
application didn't account for the same
parameter occurring multiple times so if
you were to put you know and user equals
Andy and then end user equals Sam it
would process the last the last
parameter that was passed to the
application so a lot for an attacker to
get their initial request signed and
processed and then piggyback onto the
request with another parameter which
means that they would be able to do
things like change their identity
entirely within the system so this
person was able to actually change their
first and last name within the German a
ID system using this and so I'll have
the slides available but there's a
notion YouTube video and a blog post
about it you can read so how many ways
to test buzzing there's a lot on here
there's things you can post forward your
things you'd normally post for it any
sort of application which is remote code
execution cross-site scripting local and
remote file inclusion sequel most sequel
injection request splitting
deserialization xx EE and anything else
with template languages
encoding errors which is another
favorite of mine like junk characters
control characters emojis and Unicode
points that don't have any data
associated with them which is a another
thing that applications sometimes forget
to include processing for file upload
phoner abilities which would be can you
upload a something with a gift header
that's actually PHP or JavaScript and
things like SS RF though tools are
commonly used for these kinds of things
are burp which is the gold standard in
my view for fuzzing and using the
repeater to insert junk data into
requests other enumeration tools like go
Buster Durov Astaire using set lists and
other github repos that have a lot of
Awesome fuzzing payloads as well as just
general application parameters that
might be useful and then custom scripts
which I'll get into in a little bit too
so pro tip here's a speed up your
fuzzing by making head requests to API
endpoints which I'll also get into later
so right limiting so rate limiting is
something that I think doesn't get as
much attention as it should in a lot of
applications because api's are built to
expect a high load and a lot of requests
and so this functionality of it can be
actually used against it and we used to
quickly enumerate an endpoint and so
there's a lot of common ways to test for
a rate limiting so you can make a bunch
of requests and see what happens and
check the headers to see if you get any
responses back that are rate limiting
tokens but you can also try to make
requests in varying states of
authentication so sometimes rate
limiting bugs only happen or you are
only rate limited if you are at a
certain access level so you can try as
an authenticated user authenticated as a
developer as a bot with a deactivated
account or user or with just bogus fake
credentials general tso api wasn't
properly implemented rate limiting can
be used to make it have normal amount of
requests and actually cause other issues
like Dawson as well
um restricting API area HTTP methods is
another important thing to consider here
so applications are built to support a
lot of different methods for different
purposes whether it's for inserting
client records or accessing you know
modifying certain things you can do put
and delete requests and some of these
methods can be accessed on authenticated
and sometimes the scope of the HTTP
methods is actually beyond what the
application actually expects so there
might be something that you can do a put
request on or delete request on that is
actually a get or post parameter and you
basically would be able to find
undocumented features of the API with
this so though it's good to look at the
API spec documentation and see what
actual methods are requested and compare
them to what HTTP methods are actually
allowed based on what the server tells
you and so even if they're not included
in the application logic if an
application is lazy with the way that it
parses methods and has no logic the
person is being really weird things can
happen so the next thing that I have
here is third party API abuse and so api
is call other api is to do what they
need to do and so the relationships
between a target api and third party API
is is typically trusted in some way and
so because there's an implicit trust
between different api's in certain
scenarios either can be leveraged to
access privileged resources and so there
are some common ones here like request
splitting to make additional requests to
a third party API through a target API
server side request forgery so you can
use the API to resolve a URL and trick
it into making requests in the context
of the server itself so you can use it
to enumerate the internal network or
gain access to server metadata and then
unhandled input from a third party so
sometimes you might make a request to
your third party API that gives back um
data that was unexpected and it can
cause unexpected outcomes within the
Apio you're testing so I have some
examples here that kind of tie in to the
bugs that we just discussed so I'll kind
of highlight them as I go through them
so the first one here is it was in
discord and so this cord has an API that
is a very very robust it has a lot of
data types that can be passed to it a
lot of parameters and a lot of access
controls on it and so with a partner of
mine we were testing out the discord API
to see what kinds of requests you can
actually make and see how they are
implemented within the application so we
were testing the invite scheme so
there's when you are inviting somebody
to a discord server to chat they create
a either a one-time-use
invite code or a is that code that
doesn't expire and so we found that the
invite scheme for direct messages was
the same as those for server invites and
so we were playing around a bit just in
in burke and we found that the PM invite
codes are actually only used internally
and assumed that a user is already
authorized to be in a group DM if an
invite is actually used as a discord
also had two API is available to test
all the stuff out on an older one and a
newer one and so that's another an
important thing to remember when you are
looking at AP as a whole is are there
more than one is there a development one
is there one that is deprecated and for
some reasons still available those are
all really important things to consider
in the second so our methodology here
was we had written a script to enumerate
invites and so we made a request to the
API to see if an invite code was valid
and you can actually figure out whether
or not the code is valid by just making
a head request and reading the response
so for this we were able to make about
hundred requests per second and we found
about one valid invite for per minute
and we've randomly generated invites
rather than trying to brute force the
entire key space because an invite code
is six characters long alphanumeric and
so trying to brute force that from
beginning would take a while still
doable but we felt it would be better to
just try to randomize it and ended up
finding out that generated codes seem to
be used as seeds for future codes so we
actually were taking valid codes and
then changing parts of the code itself
to check for further codes and we only
enumerated temporary invites which are
six characters although there are long
term invites which are eight characters
long and so here's an example requests
we had successful requests versus failed
requests so you're making this squirrel
request it's authenticated as well to
the discord API within a betray invite
so the one on the left is lol yes the
other one is a little no so lol yes one
and gives a 200 response and the fails
one gives a 404 so it's easy to write a
quick Python script to be able to
enumerate these things and see which
ones were valid and which ones weren't
and so the impact for this was we were
able to join private servers as well as
private root DNS so the DMS were strange
and actually wish I had a screenshot
included in here because the it looks
the same as a server invite where you
are invited to join a specific server
but it just has a list of user names in
them and you can just join and people
were pretty freaked out when we found
out about this but it is interesting
because as researchers who don't really
hang out on discord that much just
jumping into a random group DM was kind
of kind of funny and weird so yeah the
next one that I have is due to mobile so
if you haven't heard of due to mobile
it's a website templating service that
people use to make mobile websites for
their
their desktop website and so they
basically templates the it takes an
existing website and it turns it into a
mobile-friendly template but it also has
an API that's built in to process
external links and convert them into a
mobile safe format so it tries to script
some JavaScript and CSS and attempts to
load the websites into the preset theme
which is interesting so right off the
bat I was able to in testing this to get
past the filtering mechanism and bypass
javascript filtering with onload
directives in image tags but I could
also access the mobile sites internal
rendering API to load other api's within
the context of this website on there but
where any website on their platform so
there was about 30,000 websites and you
could do the same thing to just load
arbitrary URLs into the template of the
website and so this allowed for xsrf
attacks also on Duty's infrastructure as
well as loading some of their internal
resources as well so that's just the URL
scheme is down there so a lot of things
like this the doodle mobile API being
used to access internal resources this
is a router at one and 2.16 1.1 that one
and yeah this one I wasn't able to
actually sign into but the fact I could
then use this to enumerate the rest of
the network
it's pretty scary but the real scary one
is being able to load their US keys into
any of the doodle mobile websites that
were templated and so this is an example
of being able to use one API to call
another API and be able to enumerate
information from there so the impact was
it led to the disclosure of private AWS
keys and sensitive information in the
production AWS account for the whole
enterprise through SSR F I was able to
load and potentially modify internal
router configs and other resources by
accessing these and it was definitely a
really interesting bug to explain and so
with that 20 minutes
if you have followup with me I do have
any questions or comments or concerns
feel free to email me at blackhat Zipcar
com
also if you are a security focused
developer we are hiring and so you can
hit me up as well the resume if you are
looking to get into the space so with
that I asked if there's any questions
from the chat well somebody in the chat
pass if there's any additional resources
for reading about API hacking I mean all
of us but I've looked at has nearly been
tossed stuff as well as strand and block
posts
so a lot of the sort of thing is just
stuff that I've ended up doing work or
through other testing so I would just
Google API hacking I guess somebody
might go to thing not somebody has other
things