okay folks time for the next talk it's
sin Voigtlander okay userland Colonel
talking about researching iPhone space
band I'm very excited to hear this talk
I think the the whole idea of mobile
hardware security research is one that
yeah the problems that are causes or the
vulnerabilities caused are well
understood but you know how you get into
actually understanding where things are
broken and how that can be fixed
probably isn't so looking forward to
some illuminating us all on that topic
right now I'll end it up to you thanks
research based band just because it's
[Music]
Jason from the team you're coming
through really in and out and the volume
super low can you check your mic
settings real quick make sure you're
coming into the right Mike
I'm sorry fools pay any better now
okay so just continue from here so the
reason why I started to research
[Music]
documentation about how they communicate
separated system this system also means
that the users no control about it and
no control also means that you cannot
verify the integrity and security of
device which makes it a very huge tech
factor with a lot of problems to
companies concerns
under attack by the devices that you're
so it's also a radio communication which
makes it a huge attack factor as well
because they can one corrupted baseband
can work its way to corrupting order
basements as well the likelihood of
vulnerability is existing in baek's
about baseband is high this is because
it's black box no code is public so many
people can discover abilities only with
expertise knowledge about the basement
so my talk is also to make it easier
researchers in the future to access my
basement my eventual goal was creating
custom for alpha basement chips so that
as the seven attacks can be prevented
with the firewall unfortunately this was
to complicate it because it requires to
know everything about the hardware of
the basement but I've been able to
research lots of discover a lot
what a spaceman it's a chip on your
mobile device in my case I researched
the baseband used and iPhones it's
completely separated in iPhones from the
rest of the hardware and the rest of the
operating system so it runs its own
operating system it uses its own secure
read-only memory its own random access
memory flash chip and its own processor
I'll talk a bit more about processor
later in this talk so what the basement
is mainly used for is cellular
communication so when you make a call
when you text a friend or a colleague
when you access the internet over LTE
that is all done by debasement chip and
the only way that basement chip is
managed on the mobile operating system
is true kernel drivers a demo basically
interacting on the high-speed USB
interfaces of this basement device and
it also is a modem so you can send
carryout commands to the modem at the
basement or in the stands
so the baseband and 32-bit mobile Apple
devices is a Qualcomm chip in most cases
all the devices used Intel chips but
everything after the iPhone cheechee
pretty much uses a Qualcomm chip one
thing that was very special about such
early chips or crop was that they
supported voice over IP LTE calls and
the architecture is mostly are 32-bit
but the newer iPhone iPhone 5 from the
32-bit Apple devices uses the hexagon
DSP processor which is from Qualcomm
itself they developed this processor and
this processor also has some increased
security mechanisms to prevent execution
of certain battery communications for
the base band on iOS Apple's operating
system go through to demand calm calm
calm Center
to the kernel extension for the rest
there is no references to the base band
or whatsoever so to learn more about
this basement shape and Apple devices I
started to look at Apple firmware in the
Apple firmware IPSW which is the format
used by Apple and it's basically just
chip zip file that you can download
through iTunes
there was another zip file called PDF W
which is the baseband firmware and in
that basement firmware another zip file
as I said you can find binary images
with an info property list file an XML
file containing information about the
images like the bundle ID which is just
reverse DNS string and subversion
information probably because Apple needs
to know a lot of each device so the
binary images are 32 bit elf binaries
and that's good pretty convenient I'm
taking a look because the elf for merge
has a header containing a lot about the
references and symbols used in the
binary sadly the symbol tables and the
simple segments were left out but a lot
of information about the size of the
segments and the codes still was in
there what I also found through pin work
in work is the fighting utility that you
can use to examine firmware when you do
not know what from rarely actually is
you can use it on any file and it will
tell you the offset of certain file
types in a file so that you can learn a
bit more about the file you can also
look at the entropy for finding a lot
about the structure of the file and I
used it and I found
that most basement images also had
certificate at the ads so that means
that they work outside with a ticket and
certificates using sha-256 signatures
and in the main basement image that you
cannot see in the picture here and the
presentation but in another I will show
you it again you can see the AMS s
basement image which is the operating
system of the basement and it's build
upon the ok L for kernel which is a
hyper personal I'll talk about it more
later so that operating system the okey
L for kernel is just a custom
proprietary fire variant of the original
ok L for kernel and they also seem to
implement some Linux kernel but you
cannot see that as this is in the
protected random access memory sorry
protected memory internal memory so what
I found from taking a look at this
operating system is that there are
shared memory devices over buses in this
case high-speed USB that you can access
except they are all in their own context
as you can see here in the image on the
right bottom you can see the do care for
kernel starsk as it is a hypo first is
to divide all drivers and different
contacts and all apps and different
contexts so that they are completely
separated from each other prosecutor
reasons now I'll show you a bit how this
kernel looks like in either because Ida
was pretty much able to get a lot of a
lot of functions back from the the
kernel one sec yeah so when looking at
this you can immediately see that this
is an arm image these are all
instructions
yeah references to after you air but
let's take a start at the header at the
header points you see that it tries to
load some data there you go a little bit
below and you see that it doesn't memory
initialization I've had to type - I had
a file - where I had the symbols and
everything but I lost it sadly anyway as
you can see the year is the first
reference that tells you that this is
the OTL for a kernel and this is the
initialization and then this is very
important when an error is detected this
basement device will enter download mode
which is a special mode a protocol from
Qualcomm for restoring whenever
something goes wrong on the base bands
so you can flash restore images and
emergency images I'll talk about them
later
so looking further there are a lot of
more references to functionality even
metrics so let's go to the strengths as
this might look a bit of complicated to
you but you if I go to metrics it will
come clear to you that they also keep
some metrics only toys and you're all
the kind of metrics that they keep which
is surprisingly a lot of metrics
validation that kind of information so
this is something to look at you because
it's very custom kernel of the oki'll
forecast aversion so I also discovered a
crashes will jump to and fiber DRAM
instead of the filesystem which make is
it a lot of a lot harder to fuss because
the crash locks you won't be able to see
you won't be able to see what registers
contain values so you won't be able to
identify debug crashes run a core
and they did this probably because they
do not want their firmware to be
analyzed and stare architecture to be
broken and malicious way so let's talk a
bit about the boot stages of the
debasement chip at first you have the
boot roll and the boot rom as you know
can only be flashed once so you cannot
change anything in here and the boot rom
could change the root certificate
authority hash and also the root
certificate authority certificate used
for code signing so that is where code
signing will compare against and you
also have this bootloader on the boot
ROM which is called the primary
bootloader so in a primary boot loader
loads the bootloader from internal
memory and that bootloader has a
signature and that loads a custom kernel
so like the okay elf or kernel with the
Lynx girdle but the Linux kernel runs
outside the trusted memory and it also
has a signature everything is go outside
so how does this look you have an elf
binary with a header executable code
segments the signature of this codes the
root certificate there's the special at
the station certificates and some
padding so this header also contains
reference to the signature the
destination where the code should go
into the memory of the base bands the
size of the image and the actual code so
when taking a look at the actual elf
header we learn that there are other
references and well in many times of
bootloader vulnerabilities one single
mistake in parsing this header or having
a wrong reference or having control over
reference without it happen without it
being on the code signing checks kept by
Paul's the secure boot
so that's why I displayed this header
here there are a lot of offsets but
Qualcomm states that they are actually
validated I'll talk about that later
there's the hash table segments which
also contains the code signatures so
about the hash table segment if the hash
table segment to read signatures of each
part of the binary and a certificate
chain the certificate chain is basically
three certificates the root certificates
the CA certificate and the attestation
certificate and each certificate
verifies the signature of the next
certificate in the chain so you have the
root key hash that's in the bootrom the
root key hash validates the root
certificate that root certificate
verifies the signature of the CA
certificates etc etc and this is how to
secure boot mechanism kind of works so
how do they how does Qualcomm parse
their basement firmware when it's loaded
well from their own documentation I was
able to get the following an image is
loaded into internal memory and that
internal memory is protected and trusted
but only available when the device is on
make sense right but external flash
memory and random access memory are not
trusted just an image must be
authenticated to it in the trus binary
in internal memory now I'll talk about
that a little bit more because there's a
thing that they that sounds a lot secure
but it is actually not that secure and
of course the elf headers and the health
program headers are parsed and validated
eventually the hashes of the code sign
signing also validated and then here's
the thing about that first boundary that
trusted zone that you can get the image
copy to an internal memory from for
example flash memory to get it allowed
to be executed so the destination what
address the code should be copied to and
the size of the code must be within a
white list now the destination for
reverse-engineering bootloader that the
code is copied to a 0x8 well 32-bit
integer starting with 0 x8 and the rest
zeros and an addition that they add to
that checks is that the Aramaic is also
self evaluated so you cannot cross any
overflows by parsing these images except
also death was not yet secured as
qualcomm states it to be and the above
applies to header certificates and
orders size are all set calculated items
that are used in the secure boot so at
first i took a look at the actual
implementation of the cryptography
because believe it or believe it not
cryptography is usually a thing that is
hard to implement very correct and when
you find a flaw in the cryptography it
gets easier to get code execution at
food because you can just assign your
binary image or exploit a vulnerability
in the signature checks so at first like
I said there are three certificates the
root certificate authority that verifies
the art association certificate
authority and optionally there's an
objective
attestation certificate that's unique
for each firmware but it's optional
though in all devices this attestation
certificate is usually embedded because
code signing is enforced
some prediction devices you'll pretty
much always find an attestation
certificate certificates the are signed
by the next certificate chain and the
verifications is is done by calculating
and shut 256 hash dishes of the root
certificate authority at first and that
was much the value that's stored in a
Rob kind of like with the Nintendo
switch sorry the Nintendo 3ds the boot
night strap it also completed a hash
value from shared with the value in the
wrong
server side signer cannot refer the
authorization of roots certificate
authorities because the root certificate
authority signs at the station
certificates directly and is insured to
the wrong on device it means that if
certificate gets compromised there is
pretty much nothing that Qualcomm can do
and there will always be well the
possibility of signing your own code the
root certificate authority and inter
stations certificate authority are
similar to SSL certificates and this at
the station certificates is an important
one and very different in comparison to
other certificates because it contains
some core specific information for
Qualcomm encoded in organization unit
fields so these fields I'll just quickly
walk to him because they're important
they serve also as a additional
vegetation against downgrading to from
firmware so let's say you are able to
sign any codes then there's also this
thing that's the software ID of the
image is compared to the previous
version that is installed and if this
version is that isn't installed is
higher than the version that you want to
restore then it prevents it from
downgrading to that version
there is also debts each firmware is
unique per hardware device and hardware
identifier basically consists of a
family unique chip ID basically and a
model ID so that makes a signing process
pretty unique to each device so that you
cannot sign for a bunch of devices just
for once device specific but like I said
the attestation certificate is validated
by the other certificates in the chain
so Qualcomm pretty much signed for any
device now there is also a debug field
but of course when you patch it for for
adding more debugging to the bootloader
that won't work because it will break
the code signing chain and this time
value is 2 which is disabled
oh yeah and then there's this field
software for size
first of all okay can I just change the
size to my posted signatures but well
they stayed in their secure pews the
comments that it's not used for
validation just for information only but
this one the algorithm that's used is
also for the verification of signatures
is also stored in the organizational
unit field or certificate and that's a
weakness because shall one is a way
weaker signature verification methods
than 256 so it's considered a weakness
of course most certificates nowadays go
much 256 but since you can patch this
yes that will break the signature chain
if you patch this to show on it will you
shall want to validate and basically
relax the signature verification a
little bit because even when the
signature is broken it still tries to
verify this which I want and when it
compares this to the Turnitin 56 Shosh
in the bootrom it will only compare it
to the size of the sha-1 hash
now the core Chrome operating system
coming back to that again a MSS is very
useful was very useful in reverse
engineering how Qualcomm works when
everything is boot loaded and started it
also contains a lot of assets asserts
two absolute paths with also the name of
source code files I tried looking up on
the internet but couldn't find as
everything is proprietary I pretty much
hope them to be leaked but they were not
but eventually I started working on my
own elf parser to analyze these files
and parse them or easier and coming back
to the okiya for kernel that's used in
this operating system this code was once
open source and you can still retrieve
it through the web archive so if you go
to web not archive.org and you go to the
okie l4 kernel you websites okay oh four
laps open kernel laps that was it
open lips there you will see that it
that you can still get the source code
I'll release the source codes or my
github repository of you already release
it there because they removed it from
the site and the reason for that is that
well open collapse pretty much is
duplicated since 2013 and everything
that was once open source is now
proprietary and private and they also
remove the code their entire website is
down which new up archive you can still
get the source code so I compared that
source code to the Ida image and it was
almost the same
almost any function that was originally
for okay l4 was still used in the iPhone
5s a MSS image now the OS bootloader is
the operating system boot loader
generally loaded each time that the base
band is being booted up
it's not I Oh s and a folder slash user
slash firmware slash baseband you can
find it there and it's loaded each time
but of course it's also code signed and
then I figured out what the header was
as you can see here in the picture so it
also says this image destination pointer
that's a pretty important one because
that will tell what address it should
load the code in of the trusted memory
so you can control that and when
creating a firmer image basically if you
just make it 0 X 8000 or within the
boundaries then it will tell it for that
it will be valid for that part but of
course this code signing is not one of
them if the device bootloader implements
D load which is a protocol used by
Qualcomm for emergency debugging and
flashing there are two types of
implementations of this protocol
streaming T load and T load but this is
amazing because each time the basement
crashes so you just need to find a way
to crush your baseband
the device will enter streaming alert
and this D load accepts commands via
high speed USB that can be fast if you
know the come on types luckily I found
out the source libraries that pretty
much already implemented the structures
of these commands that you can set to it
through routers be packets
high-speed USB packets and this D load
boat is on the door of the basement so
yeah you can pretty much not break it
it's to prevent the base band from
breaking
so here's some details that I was able
to forensic ly recover from the iPhone 5
through strengths utility or Linux
through padlock through radar qu and Ida
yeah so there are some internal names
that I got for the specific basement
version of the iPhone 5 also you can
retrieve the data center that the
basement was signed with by looking at
the certificates you can see version
numbers on the programmable ROM and the
knobs which is pretty cool because the
nut is from micro Tech which is what the
empty stands for then it the 29 F means
the 29 family of micron technology it's
4 gigabytes of storage 16 K of pages and
this is some revisions now
the iPhone 5 is a little different to
his predecessors because it uses the
qualcomm hexagon DSP 6 processor what
makes the hexagon is B 6 processor
different from normal our processors is
that the hexa-core processor implements
some special memory protections that
verify the context for which pointers
are referenced this is - that's for what
I understand this is to prevent
attackers from executing from contacts
where they shouldn't be executing which
makes it harder to exploit this
architecture but the hexagon SDK is
publicly available and the special
instructions you can even use with a
hexagon SDK of course not all private
instructions are in this SDK Bergere a
lot of useful instructions will be in
the SDK you compile source code for the
hexagon which which you will use when
exploiting box in the hexagon
architecture dan this was like a gold
mine to me I found there a special
debugging modes try a streaming reload
allows you to dump certain memory
regions via a USB file serial command
line so you can talk to us be lightspeed
sorry you high speed USB interface
buffers you catch up the topic who are
buffers the door
you can even do Rob and well
some other core memory files which is
pretty useful and I could show you how
it looks like and either I wasn't able
to use the x-rays this decompiler for
this but luckily I was able to decode it
with snowman she can see this is the
code and this is very Tom suit and down
here you can see but it can up it is
basically well this is where the offset
so the SDRAM is it offset 0 x8 0 0 0 0 0
etc etc and this is the files it will
dump it to the dogs will go into
environment wrap so yeah that was pretty
cool to discover are useful for future
debugging when trying to analyze
different ratified box in Sahara boat
which is the recovery mode in which you
can restore normal images like updating
the OS bootloader etc etc this is also
the mode in which each time the images
are loaded what the basement is booted
up so you can at first the file system
is loaded that the internal apps
bootloader is loaded and that the
firmware and software images are loaded
for the processor the boot authorization
is done and a checksum is done to verify
that would succeeded completely and
everything went fine
run section for executable code is
created and also what I found here in
this architecture is that there is no
word exploit mitigations so that also
means there is executable stack so
pretty much yeah execute anywhere kokom
also has a power management which they
refer to as rpm but it's pretty
complicated so I haven't looked into it
so what mate analyzing is for
easier I used tool searches bid walk and
retire too but there wasn't that easy at
the beginning what it made it really
easier to analyze this perma is that the
firmer I was not encrypted Finn Rourke
screwed up the instruction it produced
some rubbish some Lib files but it was
maybe not that efficient at first but it
was still informated as disclosed me
that the images were elf images and it
also disclosed me that the images were
not encrypted and it also told me that
there were three certificates and at
what locations they are they were and I
could extract a certificate but rarity
at the station certificate etc etc but
Archie was not quite useful because in
this case because basically I didn't
knew that there was an additional header
for the well basically the qualcomm
image is above the elf header so yeah
that pretty much made me disassemble it
wrong offset so yeah after debts
I got returned to to work and I could
disassemble the entire file from the
right offset but my solution to this
before I knew that there was this
special elf sorry a special header above
the elf header I started working on my
own I'll Foster and it worked fine I
just didn't have seek and see to search
for the elf had had a magic and I
started partially the elf image from
there
so if actually I also created a
structure for the mobile basement file
format and eventually I might work on an
offset finder so that you can find
common functions used in the bootloader
and operating system for later batching
curse that brings me to the following
known vulnerability is a basement
firmware it's not actual vulnerabilities
these do executable stack and no address
space layout randomization but it makes
it pretty easy rental abilities are
found for an attacker to override
functions in the firmer like specific
checks such as the well to signature
checks and this yeah it's it I still see
it as some kind of vulnerability because
address space layout randomization
should be implemented in such devices
they were but that all the i-45 is not
that old many devices already had a SLR
back in that days but also it's not
uncommon for basement chips not to use a
cell or due to performance Denner is a
buffer overflow that I found in public
TV eastn I tried to use but then I
figured it was just a buffer overflow
that she overflow into a kernel debugger
buffer and well you cannot control in
any way through this so that was not
sufficient and in the ancient times of
the iPhone 4 there was an X lock 8 equal
stack based overflow that was exploited
for basement unlocking but sadly it's
been patched so that brings me to the
following cool thing that I again found
is that on the forum I found Qualcomm XD
app which is an extensible debugger for
the Gawker basement
I was pretty complicated because this
base bed to be the license but the
license was provided on the forum so I
thought ok just for research purposes I
try it out
sadly this license was expired but as
you can see I managed to patch the
software and there was just one single
jump not zero instruction that I could
patch to job zero basically its Intel so
it's not that hard in either you can use
either Petra for that and that job not
zero jump to a function returning the
remaining days so I pretty much patch
that
you
and good interior use for this tool but
I've not been able to use this tool yet
because I do not have a serial USB
device for about working with the chrome
high speed USB protocols then I decided
that saucing probably was the best way
to trigger some bucks in the waistband
so I started researching how can I
access logs for what a basement crashes
and I know that logs are saved in iOS it
can be synced to a PC by the Apple 5
conduit protocol but locks did not
contain any registers only imagine the
error code when a crash occurred so I
pretty much found how to enable
extensive logging by reverse engineering
complication center and Emin and iOS
that talks to the basement and based on
that I still got some more output but
still the registers as basement crashes
are stored in a basement at private RAM
and the access to this environment Ram
is not to be prohibited I wasn't able to
access it but there are police or
undocumented commands you can access to
the environment rare
so building the buzzer is quite a
challenge and I'm still working on one
because it takes a lot of effort to
effectively force all protocols and
these protocols can be very complicated
but these are protocols used by Qualcomm
which you can use for fussing the queue
my protocol is pretty extended and it's
a new complicated protocol but also you
are complicated it means that yeah there
might be bugs there so this is probably
the most protocol profitable protocols
when you want to first baseman's from
Qualcomm you can also first rusa hard
restore mode in which you can upload
restore images or estilo data load
interfaces for emergency resource but
there is one protocol for Diagnostics
that's also has a lot of commands and in
the past there was this speaker pop
commands for well letting you take a
look at search of memory creations of
the basement and this was exploited to
again unlock a basement a carry-on large
basement but it's patch now so also
Dayak is a good interface of fuzzy
classic true 80 cables is also a good
way but it's a bit harder because Apple
removed all serial interfaces to the
basement so there's only a way to fuzz
80 commands through their communication
center and you would eat a jailbreak for
that to access that communication center
and I checked code into it for frozen
key commands
and yeah well there's another attack
that you can do on lower level when you
are in ASDA load and the load mode and
that's by just trying out rather program
images so building leaf Ezzor can be
done on top of lip qmi which is an open
source library for the queue my protocol
for welcome lip Obst which is pretty
much used for all other protocols in the
queue my interface
the 80 commands are of course many of
them are proprietary but there is some
documents online leaked or even
documented by other researchers and well
I've put a link up here too so 80
commands that you might try out for
fuzzy but well the GSM stack itself of
base bands is also vulnerable aspect and
this is the only expert respect on which
you can remotely compromise basement
devices so for for saying fire radio you
would need to hack your f1 and screen
radio installed on Linux and you can
pretty much sense type-0 as a mass and
other specific parts of the GSM stack
that you can tortured and sent to fire
radio so yeah in the past you could sent
80 commands over serial interfaces like
I said Bertier disabled nowadays the
iPhone 5 and higher but now comes the
cool stuff there have been four
abilities in the secure boot of Qualcomm
and honestly it was like a big big
flowing welcome they cannot touch this
because yeah you can pretty much restore
to any bootloader in there because you
can just let a bootloader always be
valid so as you can see this is the
secure dude file in which it compares
the signature length but yeah it
compares using the signature length from
the image header instead of the
certificate chain so in theory you can
just bail person different lengths and
make the image valid but the next one
the next is I also have the code for
this vulnerability but sadly due to
proprietary reasons I will not disclose
the code of this vulnerability here in
this slide but I can disclose the
problem the problem instead where
basically I forgot your opponent's the
entire image signatures entire signature
verification so when you restore this
bootloader it's affected you can restore
to you well you can pretty much it's
always valid so when loading an elf
binary the secure boot loader was not
probably verifying elf headers and the
program had us before loading any
subsequent segments from an elf file as
a consequence it's possible to skip
verification of the segment's entirely
if the respective program header
actually the points to a segment
containing data used for cooking every
clarification is missing so basically
just remove the sacraments of the code
signatures and the bootloader will be
valid because there's insufficient
policy this is a really really really
big flaw in a basement bootloader secure
food chain and this is the only way I
know so far to get code execution of
boot without actually having to do a lot
of stack buffer overflow exploitation so
yeah this is the best case of exploiting
the base pads and since you can exploit
this by just taking a side boot loader
of this version but even a side
bootloader you can restore always using
a spark
I believe the iPhone 4 as the iPhone 5
are both affected by this book idea for
for as well
so future developments on creating tools
useful for researching basement
accessing interfaces of the of the
basement and I also want to create a
tool for loading custom for my images
through the protocols of clock hope so
you can restore cuz the boot loaders and
that kind of things for future
development screening confirm Ram and I
of course will take a look at this image
signature verification being missing in
a specific version of the bootloader
I'll try to find the specific boot order
version so that you can use it use it to
restore the custom program so these are
some references I'll put these slides
online after this presentation that you
can use if you want to access these
interfaces POSIX Nature has helped me a
lot during his research so big shout out
to him go follow him on Twitter
it's POSIX nature just like here good
job and then there is also some
resources that I used as bokram is a
very cool group researching local
basement they have created custom
firmware for open-source well some
consumer-based local basement chips but
yeah for the iphone 5 and everything
basement is proprietary but a lot of
information came from Ozma Crawford is
presentation also Qualcomm has a lot of
internal documentation but it's all
proprietary confidential so you should
just sign up signing up is free and
anyone is allowed to sign up you can
access the information there yourself
just do not share it with other people
whiskas that's the policy of Qualcomm
then there is the cour telephony
framework that you can look at from iOS
where the communication center is based
the Devon that communicates with
baseband I took a look at someone who
dumped a header files from metroburg
also tutorial here on how to inject code
communication center and debug and these
libraries they were also very useful
when creating tools for examining the
basement then at the very last I want to
give a big thanks to the developer of
this utility this utility that provides
the full command line for accessing
protocols of Qualcomm so if you have a
device that opens itself for Universal
Serial bus communication via high-speed
USB then you can use this tool to get a
command shell and yeah interact to its
all the protocols Oracle so that's the
presentation for now are there any
questions