[Music]
elana said that it's her favorite topic
I have to say it's not my favorite topic
even though I decided to write a book
about this which I'm working on and one
of the reasons I don't like this topic
is that because it's basically something
that scares us we if we look at a
picture of camera surveilling us it's
not a nice picture it gives people
chills and the panopticon effect but I
feel that it's important to understand
it and even in crypto space very few
people understand how financial
surveillance actually works what is
being reported who receives the
information and so on so ever since
maybe high school I was fascinated by
offshore companies and tax havens in
high school I didn't have much income so
I didn't have many taxes to avoid but I
really liked the idea that there is a
way out there how to avoid all these
surveillance and taxation and and kind
of get a little bit of freedom and one
of the reasons that I started looking at
financial surveillance is the backlash
and and and the attempts to crush these
tax havens and actually what I would I
realized that the laws about
international taxation didn't change
that much recently and how this fight
against tax evasion actually works is
through the banking system so you can
still start an anonymous company or at
least relatively anonymous company in
one of these tax havens this is my
favorite Panama City many of these
buildings belongs to belong to banks
it's fairly developed there are some
countries that are not as developed as
as Panama
but basically the the way to start an
offshore company is always the same you
can do it it's it's doing business in in
a foreign country which is still allowed
so so we go you you register your
company you get your documents and then
you realize that it's very difficult to
open a bank account for this company and
that's actually how the enforcement
works so we need to understand a few
things about surveillance I got this
idea from Jonathan Loggins and Paul
Rosenberg's book the new age of the the
New Age of intelligence which I highly
recommend to read and the idea is this
so so if we look at this castle that's
the enforcement agencies these are the
rulers and we cannot see what's
happening inside it's just a big
building with walls and we don't know
what's going on inside how it actually
works so you can imagine this is NSA or
or some tax office financial police and
all these institutions this is what we
see there's some institution and we know
that it's watching us the view from the
castle is very different this is the
view from the castle if you stand up on
the wall and you look down you see
everything you see there's someone
walking they met they probably had an
affair you you can derive a lot of
information about these people even
though you don't see what actually
happens so so if two married people have
an affair with someone else and they
meet somewhere and then they get out and
their hair is messy you didn't need to
actually see them having sex in a barn
or or somewhere else you can derive
because you know a lot of information
about people you know okay this person
is married his wife is somewhere else
and so on so the view from the castle
is has these properties the only the
only only place where these analogy
doesn't hold is that there is no more
one castle there are many organizations
and the question is how well they shared
share the data how well they cooperate
because if they combine their views of
the general population the information
is even stronger and it can have even
more impact so I said that offshore is
no longer controlled or enforced by laws
but by by the banking system so the
first thing to understand is what is the
context there is a very clear difference
between targeted surveillance and mass
surveillance so targeted surveillance
means okay someone has reason to believe
that you are doing human trafficking or
something really bad they get a warrant
they come to your financial institution
and they say okay did there is a court
order the judge said you need to tell us
information about this person
so let's targeted surveillance even in
non-financial surveillance this works
pretty well and and it will continue
working it is very hard to protect
yourself against targeted surveillance
if you have your phone it is usually
using encryption sometimes the
end-to-end encryption which is very hard
to crack on the mass scale but what what
people or what these enforcement
agencies can do is they can attack your
phone specifically using zero-day
exploit or installing a back there or
something like that and then they can
learn more about you what I will be
talking about here is mass surveillance
that is watching all people like from
the view from the castle
and deriving information about everyone
so it's very important that these are
two very different ways on how to do
surveillance a lot of people say that I
really like the the graphics from the
CCC conference nothing to hide which is
which has a lot of censored context and
so I brought it up because of this issue
with transparency a lot of people say
that if you're not doing anything wrong
you should not be hiding anything and I
believe that this might be true for
governments and public institutions yes
they probably should be transparent so
we can all check them I'm not sure how
well it works in practice but that's
something that we can we can strive for
but if it's my personal information and
if I don't even do anything wrong I
might have for example both Kryptos in
2012 I might have bought 100 Bitcoin I
don't want anyone to know and it's not
because I'm I'm not willing to pay taxes
it's not because I'm using it for
something wrong I just don't want to be
a potential victim of blackmail and and
theft and I don't want other people to
threaten me
so I believe that privacy is legitimate
requirement and we should we should kind
of strive for keeping our privacy even
though we have nothing to hide we don't
need to be bad guys in order to want
privacy so how does it work who is the
police station in this and I would like
to start by a very interesting thought
that I got from Robin Hansen's book
elephant in the brain he was saying that
in the US
and some of some other countries it is
forbidden to drink alcohol in public so
we cannot just get a beer and walk
around on the street not the case in
Czech Republic and Germany at least not
in practice but what people do is they
they get a paper bag and they put the
bottle with alcohol in the paper bag
it's still not allowed and all the
police know that you're drinking alcohol
because why would I drink my water out
of a paper bag doesn't make any sense
what it does it gives an excuse to
police not to prosecute you
they have them done everything they have
seen nothing wrong so so they have an
excuse and this is interestingly how
financial institutions work if they want
you as a customer so so the states the
countries they kind of want banks to
enforce these anti-money laundering anti
tax evasion or all these rules on the
other hand the bank wants you as a
customer especially if you pay a high
enough fees so as Helena said there's a
lot of money being laundered every year
if you want to invest money with a
private bank they don't really care
where you got the money from but it's
not their business all they care about
this if you are going to pay the fees on
the on the trades and so on everything
like that so I had a very interesting
experience a few years ago I I was
becoming a client of Bank and I went
through this am l know your customer
questionnaire and the banker said the
first of all he said I apologize this is
not going to be nice and I will probably
ask you how often you have sex and
what's your shoe size but in order to
make this work please answer these
questions but please answer only yes or
no so he kind of told me to put all my
financial history in the paper back he
didn't really want to know where again
where I got my money from he didn't
really want to you know hear my life
story and what kind of an entrepreneur I
am or anything like that even though I
had to send them my professional CV I
didn't ask for a loan so that they
didn't really care so he was asking me a
series of question and he specifically
requested that I only answer yes or no
because the only thing he wanted is to
fill this form and then have me as a
customer so when we kind of outsource
this policing this police station to to
these financial institutions which are
often private they're very effective at
what they need to do but the question is
if if they're doing what the countries
are trying to do them or they they're
kind of trying to to get an excuse okay
the alcohol is in paperback I don't need
to deal with this person so I'm going to
because it's very confusing there are so
many rules there are so many reports and
no one actually knows what kind of
information information gets reported to
who there are there are public
institutions there are private
institutions and they're very
interesting ways on how these rules are
made so first of all there is no your
customer probably every one of you
steadily had to go through one of these
processes and they're followed by all
the financial institutions including
most crypto exchanges that deal with
fiat currencies so they want to know
your identity who you are
is usually by showing some kind of ID
card or passport or something like that
they need to internally determined the
risk in terms of the tendency to commit
money laundering they are trying to
create customer profile and they they
will monitor your transactions against
expected behavior so that's why a lot of
financial institutions want to see
account movements account statements
from the previous banking institution
they probably also want a letter of
recommendation in order to see that
you're just a regular customer you're
not weird in any way then they will
probably ask you for a utility bill
which is the way to determine your
residency so tax residence is quite
complex and the rules about tax
residency are not unified but most
countries they want to know where you
usually reside and one of the ways that
is plausible is by showing your
electricity bills so if you are living
somewhere and you're paying for your
electricity or other utilities then
you're probably live there and then you
are probably a tax resident there so
that's that's interesting and very
sometimes want also your tax
identification number which is something
that the government assigns to you what
is very important is that it is very
difficult to cheat the bank with nominee
shareholders and nominee director sits
directly fraud so what you can do even
now you can go to to Seychelles or to
Cyprus and you say I want to register a
company but I don't want to be publicly
visible so I'm going to hire a nominee
shareholder nominee beneficiary owner or
nominee director so these are the people
who will probably never met and they're
registered on the on the business
registry and they're the face of the
company in public and they have a
private contract with
which says okay I am on the public
business registry but this person
actually owns the company if you go to a
bank and you say this is the real owner
they will kick you out immediately like
that they have they have a list of
common nominee shareholders and actually
if you do it you're committing fraud
which equals jail time in most countries
so even though you have this perfectly
anonymous company if you have a bank
account the bank knows who is the
ultimate beneficiary owner and they will
report this information to your tax
office which we'll see later so one way
to do offshore these days is start
company in a tax haven but don't have a
bank account only use crypto so we will
talk a little bit more about that what
is important kyc is usually kept on a
file so this information is not directly
sent anywhere it is only available upon
a request so it's targeted surveillance
the problem is that sometimes the result
of of this kyc is that bank will not
want you as a customer or the financial
institution there are watch lists this
is interesting and not many people know
about it watch lists are this global
lists of problematic people one of them
is called world checks by Thomson
Reuters and they use several sources in
order to compile this list and some of
the sources are not very nice so for
example they've been known to use gossip
media so if some tabloid published a
picture of you with a known terrorists
or something like that even though you
just you know went out of the bar and
the person was standing there they're
likely to include this information in
your world check file at least it
happened a few times and there are a few
documented
instances when this happened they also
use forums they're also very very weird
forums like some white supremacy nazi
forums where Nazis are discussing some
some Muslim people and and this is
actually used as a as a source of
information
[Music]
they're also recently started to use a
list of icos and advisors I have a
friend who became a technical adviser to
a company that did an ICO he was listed
on the web page and he had a problem to
open a bank account because he appeared
on one of these lists so so it's really
not nice what is the problem is that by
contract these watch lists they're
they're not the company says that the
financial institutions doesn't use this
as the only source of truth so they are
supposed to investigate better if you
appear on one of these lists the problem
is that usually when when you have a
yellow or red light and you are on this
list the bank will just refuse you but
they will never tell you why so it's
like oh sorry we will not do business
with you we are a private company and
your business risk goodbye so we will
never know that this is the reason why
why they don't do business with you so
kyc the next thing is tax residence I
said that it's usually determined by
utility bill there are some there's
something that is called tax
identification number that has been
rolled out through oecd not all
countries introduce the tax
identification number so when the bank
requests your tax identification number
and your country doesn't issue it
there's a website where you can say okay
this one didn't roll it out but other
than that you will probably need to
get this number and it's based on every
country does it a little bit differently
there are some people that don't have
tax residence these are for example
perpetual travelers that don't have any
kids don't own real estate and they're
just traveling all the time so they they
have no tax residency unfortunately this
is business risk for banks so they will
force you to say which countries your
tax residency even if you legally don't
have a tax residency and what is
important during the research about this
I was speaking to many members of of
Bank risk departments and they say that
they over report so if I'm a slovak
citizen or if I'm a german citizen I'm a
Panamanian tax resident in a Cypriot
bank the Cypriot bank will report to
both Germany and Panama just to be sure
so a lot of people say all cool I have a
YouTube utility bill from this tax haven
that means my bank won't report my
private information to to my country
where I'm citizen and haha that's that's
how I hacked this no it's not true they
they will report to like if they have
any suspicions if you have a wife from a
different country they will report to
that country as well because it's there
they don't treat this tax information as
private that much taxation itself is
quite difficult topic
I don't unfortunately have a lot of time
for it but tax reporting is automatic so
as I said kyc is kept on file and on
request
but tax reporting is automatic
according to CRS we see this common
reporting standard it happens every year
at the end of the year they will report
that you have a bank account or an
exchange account they will report your
balance and if they know about any any
dividend income for
example that you had that they will also
report this so this is automatic you
cannot avoid it easily there is another
way how we can avoid CRS and that is by
by being in a country that didn't sign
it which the only fairly developed
country that didn't say CRS is USA and
the US territories so vodka is produced
predecessor to to CRS and it's a it's a
very interesting product of of the
United States that I export it to the
world so so the only way to avoid this
is by not being an American and banking
in US or US territories even better so
Porto Rico US Virgin Islands anything
like that this could change anytime
because vodka is based on bilateral
agreements right now it excludes US
territories but that could change any
time or of course don't use bank and use
crypto there's this these are income
taxes dividends and account balances
also there is a lot of reporting
especially within you on other taxes
like VA T so we have vit forms which
companies need to send to their tax
office in order to say how much business
they did with within the European Union
this is mandatory requirement for anyone
who is paying dat also in some countries
like in Czech Republic and Slovakia you
have electronic reporting of
transactions one of the reasons why I
like parallel police is because this
doesn't apply in parallel police because
parallel police is boycotting and we do
not send this information
there are also tax telling me cash
limits which kind of force you to use
bank accounts on transactions for
example in my country in Slovakia it's
5,000 euros in France it's even less
it's 1000 euros so you so you don't you
cannot actually legally buy even even
more expensive laptop with with cash
anymore
okay so kyc taxation anti money
laundering and source of funds so this
happens in two stages the first stage is
when you're opening your bank account
they want to know where you got your
money from how much will you be
receiving and where did what is what is
the source so so is it the business
activity to do any heritage or any other
reform also when you receive money and
it's anything out of ordinary so
anything out of what you expected then
they will require some more information
on incoming transactions so many people
think that it's difficult to send money
it is actually more difficult especially
in international banking to receive
money so if you receive money they will
in most cases require both invoice and
the contract so they want to see okay
this is for services delivered and who
is the company they will often for for
larger amounts they will often want to
know even the business profile of of the
party to be sending you the money so the
tax information is reported to Tax
Office's ml information is reported to
financial police which is a completely
different organization with the same
owner which is the state but it's a
different organization and they do not
currently at least in European Union
cooperate automatically so if you have a
bank in Cyprus and you do a suspicious
transaction they will report it to the
financial police of Cyprus even though
you are from Czech Republic let's say
the problem which is also a feature a
little bit but I think it's more more of
a problem there are no clear rules so
you cannot say okay if I do crypto
transaction for 500 euros I'm okay
because that's below limit now if the
system of the bank says that this is a
risky transaction then it will get
reported and it can be even a hundred
euros so there is no clear criteria and
another problem is a few people from the
banking sector they told me that the
financial police is complaining that the
banks are sending too little information
so so the problem is that the banks have
to over report because they have kind of
an informal quota so if a bank is
supposed to file 500 reports per year
and they don't see any suspicious
transactions then they will need to
report some that are not suspicious of
the financial policies happy so this is
actually happens to one of the banks
that I talked with so you can be
reported even though your transaction is
perfectly okay they have all
documentation and you just kind of was
picked because they need to fill the
quota it's interesting the quota is also
not public so so one of the bankers I
was talking to he said that first they
were under reporting so then they said
okay it why why should we be the
police station they're the financial
police let them investigate and they
sent every transaction to the financial
police and they immediately got a call
and said oh why are you spamming us with
transactions we don't want so many
transactions so he they kind of tried to
see okay so what do you expect is the
hundred okay or do you need so just just
to have a rough estimate in Slovakia the
number of reported transaction per
country is four thousand approximately
four thousand per year so it's not like
every your crypto transaction is
reported what would happen though is
that many transaction
goto so they won't be reported but the
bank would just say okay we cannot
receive this money also AML doesn't
concern only financial institutions so
in some countries the law offices real
estate agents and even some some private
companies that two completely unrelated
business have to report transactions
according to ml so they are required to
kind of snitch out on on their customers
even if they don't want to I don't know
how they're going to enforce it but
that's what's happening okay
censorship so private companies they
might choose not to deal with you if you
go to a bank and they say sorry you're
not a good fit for us we don't want your
customer that's the right like I also
don't do business with anyone who wants
to do business with me I I want to know
if the project makes sense if if they're
trustworthy I check their reputation so
it's perfectly okay for any private
institution to say I'm sorry we don't
want to do business with you on the
other hand with cash limits the banks
require you to do to use the banking
infrastructure the financial system
infrastructure to do some kind of
transactions so for example if no bank
wants to do business with me but I want
to buy a house and I have the money in
cash there is no way to legally buy a
house because I need a bank account I
need a way to send it through the
financial system
so in some countries thankfully crypto
is not considered cash for example in
Slovakia so I could just send them
crypto and I didn't break any law but
there's some kind of catch-22 and no one
is responsible so governments say we
don't want to regulate what private
companies do and then they say okay but
you need to use these private companies
for certain situations so it's kind of
responsibility diffusion there's no one
is really responsible no one can do
anything about this because it's no
one's problem
so one kind of censorship is we don't
want you as a customer another kind of
censorship is we are not going to let
this transaction through so some some
cases of censorship the first case is a
guy appeared in gossip media with a
politically exposed person they were on
the same party they they got introduced
into the watchlist and no bank wanted to
open the bank account for the guy
discussed in Nazi forum by Nazis one of
the one of the cases everyone owes
WikiLeaks when when the credit card
company says we we don't want to process
this transaction for this organization
porn sites and gambling sites have
problems they're there they have
problems because the transactions are
they have a high risk of chargebacks a
lot of companies that deal with legal
pharmaceutical drugs or things like weed
so we dispensaries are in a gray area
and it's very difficult for them to to
do banking because technically what
they're doing according to federal law
is illegal so so actually dispensaries
deal a lot with cash even though if they
can accept credit cards they still have
to somehow convert it to cash to buy the
weed and so on so there's a case of sam
harris which is a popular podcaster and
pattern decided to censor his
transaction they kicked him out as a
customer because the credit card company
requested it so so that's interesting I
wanted to compare unbanked people in
Europe to unbanked people in Panama so a
lot of people say oh it's a it's very
bad that there are a lot of unbanked
people so in Panama more than
approximately half of the adult
population do not have bank accounts
on the other hand it's no problem to
come with a suitcase of cash with US
dollars and buy a house because they
don't have cash limits so so it's kind
of a very different situation being
unbanked in Europe is much much worse
than than being unbanked in some
countries where it can still use cash so
banning of cash it's according to World
Bank it is something that countries need
to adopt in order to introduce negative
interest rates we already have negative
interest rates but if they become
negative 3% or something like that every
sane person would say okay I'm not
paying the bank to keep my money in the
bank account I will just withdraw
anything put it in the pillow or hide it
under the bed and there it's at least
zero not negative three percent so the
only way how you can prevent this is you
can say okay there is no cash so either
you have money in a bank account with
negative interest rates or you don't
have money so this is an official
document of World Bank if if the country
is where to adopt negative interest
rates they recommend banning cash
completely also cash is anonymous and
uncensored all so it's a very nice
feature of cash unless you are in in a
situation where the transaction is is
illegal so then it's still answerable
but also illegal
so there's cash limits also there's this
push for cashless society everyone
please pay with credit cards and you
know pay a few percent fees to the
credit card company so this word is also
happening also if you want to pay take
cash over border the usual limit is ten
thousand US dollars so you cannot just
you know bring 1 million euros to
Switzerland and put it in a bank there
so the way to do it is with crypto so
the question why who made up these rules
how did this become reality
so the usual answer would be lawmakers
of course they make the rules but
actually it's a very small fraction of
who is making the rules also there are
financial institutions they make their
own rules because they don't want to be
seen as bad actors they want to seem as
a good members of the society so that
they themselves introduced and they
self-regulate but the landscape is much
wider so of course there is osed that's
the invasion of tax reporting common
reporting standard is osed which is this
international organization what is the
last known is an organization called
called financial action task force or
fat McGuffey is the French translation
this is a small thing think of maybe
less than ten people sitting in the
offices of oacd in Paris so it's a
private nonprofit that writes most of
international anti money laundering
regulations they publish great lists and
black lists of countries so this is very
interesting because it's a network the
enforcement so if you are using
international transfers you want to know
that you are dealing with a reliable
partner so so if someone is sending you
money to your financial institution the
receiving financial institution would
ask okay what kind of rules do you
follow
and there are some standards and most if
not all institution follow this
financial action task force rules so
these are recommendations they are not
legally binding
there is no Parliament ever voting for
these rules they're enforced because
they're enforced by by this industry by
spreading through Network effects that
is also how USA is exporting their laws
so FATCA the tax reporting for
Americans is a US law so why should
Slovak Czech Panamanian whatever bank
and force these rules it's you know the
the US law the US law is in the u.s. so
what they did is they said okay all the
financial institutions in u.s. have to
follow these laws and also if they do
any transaction with any other
institution there are two options one
option is that the corresponding
institution also follows these rules so
they also accept FATCA even though it's
outside of US jurisdiction or we will
send 30% of every transaction that's
done with the institution to the IRS to
the American tax office so really any
institution any banking institution if
they touch America or anyone else that
touched America they can either get a
cut from the transactions through this
network of 30% or they need to accept
this rule so it's interesting because no
no members of parliament in slovakia
ever voted for or at least not in the
beginning of of this this law but they
still have to comply right now it's
enforced by bilateral agreements as well
so so it's kind of more complex
international but but the exporting was
very very surprising and very effective
actually so I don't know if you have
ever feel the FATCA form I don't do any
business with America I was not born in
America I don't have any relationship to
America and I spent a lot of hours in my
life filling American tax forms so
that's really interesting
I mentioned companies that are creating
the suspect lists and also
recommendations there are European Union
working groups they often create
also only recommendations which are
followed so they don't need to go
through the usual process and
intermediary and correspondent banks so
it's very interesting
good example would be again Panama so
Panama uses US dollar they don't have
their own currency so that means that
every international transfer from Panama
currently goes to an US intermediary
bank there are three big banks that act
as intermediary or correspondent banks
and they require all Panamanian banks to
follow some rules so in Panama no one
voted for for these rules they're
actually not even explicit but if a
Panamanian bank wants to I don't know if
a Panamanian wants to buy fertilizer for
their field from from abroad they will
have to deal with a request from some US
intermediary bank even though if they're
not doing the business with the us
directly so that's also interesting so a
lot of private and independent
institutions that are not controlled by
any kind of democratic process make up
the international financial rules so
it's very nice and easy to complain you
know these banks they're evil and and a
lot of people for example say that these
banks they perceive crypto as a threat
it will destroy them and that is why
they why they don't want to deal with
crypto so I think the story is much
easier the story is if they perceived
that this could be a problem and you are
a person with a free account that's
paying two euros per month in fees and
there is a risk that they will have a
problem because you're sending money in
and out of crypto exchanges and doing
weird stuff they will just say okay this
is not worth it
the risk is higher than then what we
what we get so we have our big retail
business to protect and we don't care
about you know 500 weird people that
go to Krypton artist conferences so they
just say okay it's not worth the risk so
again that's the responsibility
diffusion the financial institutions are
not to blame they're doing all they can
to to increase and grow their business
and politicians say we didn't make up
the rules which you know that's what the
banks chose to be to be doing so that's
very interesting situation I would like
to show you just this slide from a
report on corporate surveillance so I
was talking about financial institutions
which are private but the private
financial surveillance landscape is only
part of a bigger landscape of
surveillance so these are financial
services but there are a lot of
companies there's a lot of
specialization about how how these
companies are building your profiles how
they're learning about your behavior how
they're DeRay deriving new information
from the behavior you can google google
it the whole report is online so it's
part of something that's been recently
called surveillance capitalism for
example PayPal shares personal financial
information with more than six hundred
third parties I'm not making it up you
can look it up on their website that's
the list it's public institutions
private institution risk management's
credit rating organizations and so on so
next time you buy your stuff with Amazon
know that this transaction potentially
sends information to 600 other parties
the problem is of course internet is
free so if you're using free service
then they need to make money somehow and
the surveillance capitalism is not very
effective in enforcing
compiling this information sharing it
and making money out of it so if you are
not paying for a service then you're the
product and
the designs cabbage this landscape is
really huge and it's not only about what
you do but what what you do says about
you so if I go to a website I didn't
tell anyone I'm a creep to honor his bat
if they see I read five krypton or his
the articles and then pay for a ticket
to Prague doing hackers Congress they
safely know that I am so what to do
about it first of all you can use crypto
instead of bank accounts also you can
use services like lamium which allow you
to pay your invoices in a traditional
banking without kyc without registration
using crypto using Bitcoin please use
non ky6 changes support them there are
many hold huddle and bisque are maybe
the most interesting you can use also
ATMs here or anywhere else where they
still function you do not need to be
exposed to crypto volatility if the
volatility of Bitcoin is not your thing
there are ways how you can avoid it for
example you can enter a short on bit max
perpetual swap which will fix your
dollar value of your coins and even get
paid interest rate which is currently
around 10% PA you can keep most of your
coins say safely in your hardware wallet
so I'm saying this that just because you
want to use crypto doesn't mean you need
to you know be okay with all the
volatility you can you can do it this
all hurt surveillance capitalism so
there will be a backlash but please do
it pay for stuff free stuff means
surveillance pay for good products and
services and if you have a choice to pay
with crypto even if you're a hot ler
please pay with crypto you can buy it
back the same day but please use crypto
to keep your keep your privacy so I'm
writing a book about this it's just a
template cover if you want to know
it's out you can register some address
email address even anonymous I don't
care and I will send you an email when
when the book is out it's maybe 1/3 done
and thank you I'd like to I let you talk
because it's interesting but we have
maybe one question or one or two quick
questions from the audience
sure I'll be also around so if you want
to check don't be happy before someone
raises their hand I have a few additions
to what you were saying the the FATCA
rules that are very new like a few few
weeks ago they released new set of
recommendations that require custodial
services in crypto to transmit personal
information together with the
transactions so I thought yeah
but in any case this is one of the most
crucial and important things that
happened and not many media have
reported on that could you elaborate a
little bit on that
well the takeaway is don't use companies
that require your private information
then they will have no private
information to pass but the traveler
rule means if you're sending money from
an exchange that knows who you are at
some other exchange they will also need
to pass the information of who you are
to the other other company we don't know
how it will be implemented it's just a
recommendation anyway but how did we oh
yeah there's also I you know you
mentioned that they don't want the banks
are scared to deal with potentially
small customers and getting to trouble
because of them I just recently was
dealing with someone who has huge
businesses in a particular Bank we're
talking you know potentially hundreds of
millions of dollars and he also has
private account there and he wanted to
purchase five million worth of Bitcoin
mm-hmm and his bank said no yeah no so
it's too and it's also so what is what
is interesting that the banks have this
small department of account managers and
usually much larger Department of Risk
Management and some of the bankers I was
talking to they so a clear business case
they wanted someone as a customer and a
bank clerk in risk Department that's
making you know thousand euros per month
said no we cannot have this one hundred
million worth of money from this
customer because it's no not good enough
for risk and they couldn't push it even
through the board so so they're very
risk-averse risk risk management
department they want to keep their job
so so and it's very easy for them to say
no because there are KPIs they don't
care if the bank makes money that's
right okay is there any question no okay
now so thank you very much one more
round of applause for you right now
thank you
[Applause]