[Music]
[Applause]
so first of all thank you everyone
obviously for organizing this and also
inviting me here a brief note on the
timetable
it says I'm presenting with a colleague
of mine Paul Zeidler unfortunately he's
sick should I move this away from my
mouth about oh good yeah okay yeah
unfortunately my colleague Paul is sick
so I'm gonna be doing this solo for now
so yep basically what I'm gonna be doing
in this talk as was previously
previously kind of introduced Terra zero
was very much kind of something that
occurred a lot of the time within the
art space and very much kind of we were
trying to use as a bit of a kind of like
a series of experimental projects and
what I want to do given the context of
the festival and opting out is I want to
try and contextualize that within a kind
of Nilla jism which is on on the on the
screen up there which is cancer
ecologies so the structure of this talk
is kind of gonna go as follows I'm gonna
kind of go through a brief discussion of
cancer economics which I'm sure a lot of
you are aware of but maybe just so
everyone's like on the same page and
then talk about okay what what is this
term contra colleges that were kind of
playfully trying to define here and then
hopefully I'm going to kind of
contextualize a lot of the work that we
did with Terra zero or try and
contextualize counter ecologies as kind
of springing out of this and becoming
maybe or more politically or kind of
like action informed way of engaging
with some of the topics that we've been
playing with for a couple of years so
the main questions of the talk really
are what are counts for economic
ecological actions so what is counter
ecology in a very broad sense and then
also we're just kind of crypto fit into
all of this and so there we go so cancer
economics generally is also known as
counter establishment economics and it
was defined by Samuel Koch in in 1974
basically just as a tactic to kind of
enable the creation of a voluntary or an
Agora society and this was kind of best
expanded upon in his 1980s public
in 1980 publication the new libertarian
manifesto and very simply poor algorism
kind of dictates or is based on the
premise that all forms of association
between people should be voluntary and
so it kind of split from at the time the
US libertarian movement in that it
followed from its idea of self-ownership
but it kind of really also held the
principle of non-aggression is a kind of
an integral or like a key tenant to it
and it was basically defined as the
study or practice of all peaceful human
action that was forbidden by the state
and the kind of things that fall into
this category are obviously like
alternative currencies which a lot of
the people today are going to be talking
about in a new form but they have
existed for well centuries illegal
migration smuggling mutual credit and
mutual aid groups substance farming and
off-grid energy generation and this
graph this on the board is actually
although credited to Derek bronze from
from his article vertical and horizontal
algorism
actually came from a Swedish academic
Hope Boylan's analysis of cancer
economics where he defined possible
actions that you can undertake via
either their being vertical or
horizontal in their strategies and so a
vertol vertical strategy would be just
building local or neighborhood networks
of infrastructure so we have this idea
of Community Technology obviously
something that the parallel Polar's crew
are really doing with their approach to
kind of introducing new comers to crypto
via having a node set up here doing a
coffee kind of doing this very locally
based introductory talks that are kind
of bringing people into the fold of
using something like an alternative
currency and then also represented on
the board we have horizontal which are
kind of the more traditional black
market approaches to kind of evading or
existing outside of the state so non
state sanctioned trade of any kinds
which aren't necessarily look how old
based in the same way the vertical
approaches are
and this problem of location in terms of
how we can interact with our environment
or how we can do something new is maybe
a good segue into starting to try and
define counter ecologies this this term
that I threw in at the beginning that I
haven't actually explained yet and I
suppose it's based on the idea that
whilst it might be viable to actually
build counter economies in the
traditional sense especially as with the
case with crypto kind of like when they
have a purely digital infrastructure
that on either local based or can very
easily across whatever state lines so
cryptocurrencies marketplaces like Silk
Road obviously being perfect examples of
this the problem with councilor
economies or like counter economic
tactics that surround Ecology's is the
localization is obviously a massively
important factor of it because they are
usually based around a specific area and
with the case of a specific ecology
either this can't move or it's kind of
state and the problems associated with
it are determined by its locale so the
broad kind of initial definition we're
playing with and feedback on this during
the Q&A or afterwards is massively
appreciated because this is the first
time we're kind of presenting this it's
basically seeing what kind of
organizational models or what structures
we can try and create to like bolster
the sort of aims that we were working
with or experimenting with in terror
zero that I'll talk about kind of after
this and so really we can just
understand it in spatial terms in its
relationship to kind of existing
ecosystems so because there aren't
really any new frontiers to kind of
populate as the cyberpunk movement was
kind of populating the digital and kind
of like taking it taking the ground for
itself or creating new ground obviously
in the physical world is incredibly
difficult to do that outside of maybe
doing something like seasteading which
either requires loads of money or just
hasn't wax as of yet
the governance of kind of physical
spaces is already mostly mediated either
by the state
or by private ownership or by royal
ownership but all of these things really
are kind of already bound within legal
frameworks and so the starting point for
this idea of counter ecology was
basically the creation of tactical
spheres of influence on the eco sphere
which don't rely on the means of
optimizing the production of goods or
services or and all kind of integrating
this into existing economic or state
programs and very very simple examples
of this would just be kind of the
production of non registered and non tax
food or the illegal planting of trees to
kind of optimize the health of a local
bio top and so you can kind of
conceptualize it as as a supply layer or
maybe underneath black markets so
underneath these kind of like horizontal
tactics yep still on the board and so
it's kind of environmental action
towards ecosystems which supplies us
with material abundance in like a very
broad sense outside of this market logic
so for instance kind of co2 capture and
really we're trying to reconcile eyes
the place of material production outside
of state apparatus and outside of
existing kind of hierarchical corporate
structures and perfect examples of the
sort of actions that already exists
within these lines and definitely also
fall under kind of definitely also fall
under kind of vertical counter economics
tactics the first of which and maybe the
most immediately approachable would be
something like guerilla gardening so
guerrilla gardening is just gardening
growing plants often kind of vegetables
or fruit or herbs that are otherwise
useful in spaces regardless of who owns
them if anyone owns them but quite often
it's also done on private land or land
that's owned by the state so they're
quite often moved along or there's a lot
of tension between the people who are
actually engaging with it and the owners
of the land and maybe a kind of larger
expansion upon this which is something
that nicely segues into some of the
projects we've been doing is the work
that Carl Hess was involved in a couple
of decades ago so Carl has is maybe most
famously known for
political writings and his activism more
guerilla gardening particularly hardcore
guerrilla gardening at the top of trees
I am so Colchis
worked with the appropriate technology
movement and was involved with kind of
creating self kind of like DIY and self
managing technology in a neighborhood in
Washington DC called Adams Morgan where
they basically were engaging in how you
can create very easily manageable easily
up kept rooftop farming solar grids fish
farming in basements this kind of thing
and it was very successful at the time
on this really local level and so to
kind of go into the next section of my
talk what do Paula Nile or do I know cuz
I'm heroin think that we can kind of
bring from our previous experience in
the crypto space obviously in the art
space as well and how can we maybe start
bringing these things together and like
creating new ways of doing stuff like
what Hess was doing and to kind of
contextualized Tara zero this started in
2016 as a project which we were kind of
very interested in this history of kind
of autonomy in the blockchain space
which was obviously coming out of very
cyberpunk notions of autonomy and
science fiction as well and we found a
lot of ideas that people had for these
kind of autonomous entities existing
using crypto in a very very basic way in
like a very mechanical sense and this
was essentially the one of the earliest
examples that we found which was just
from a thread on Bitcoin talk where a
user called Jules basically posited the
idea that a software agent could exist
on its own for the first time because it
would be able to pay for stuff like
hosting CPU and memory using Bitcoin and
because these agents can now own their
own wallets this was seen as a certain
mechanical autonomous entity and this
was very quickly expanded upon
especially once the etherium kind of got
going so this is a quote from one of
vitalik veterans kind of like relatively
early
larger posts which actually led to the
creation of what we now call his dolls
where he was kind of questioning whether
this human middleman was really
necessary for the form of mediation that
corporations currently have and one
thing we actually found afterwards was a
threat by an author called car loader
who actually posited something called a
diode and which was a DAC for a natural
system which actually was had a lot of
synergy between well there was a lot of
synergy between essentially what he was
positing here so kind of using these
block chain based organizational
structures that had some element of
autonomy which is the debate like there
is a lot debate in terms of what
autonomy is actually there but let's for
the moment kind of gloss over that I'll
come back to that later but there was a
lot of synergy essentially between this
thread and the original Terra zero
concept but we found afterwards but we
have actually since spoken to Karl and
he was just super happy other people
were playing kind of in the same
ballpark as him so that was pretty nice
but yeah from all of this we came up or
we kind of presented the original
concept piece for Terra zero and this
came from thinking okay what if we
actually expanded this idea that you
know the very simple mechanical agents
that kind of jewels presented and you
know taking some of the kind of
organizational mediation or the lack of
organizational mediation and they're
replacing it with contractual mediation
the butterman was talking about and we
took this a bit further so we actually
set up a situation where a plot of land
was able to be interacted with an owned
via a dhow so the DAO acted as the
mediating and interface between this is
eco system and everyone else so it's
basically an artwork and a prototype for
a self-owned
kind of technologically augmented forest
in 2016 and it basically just conceived
of a framework or we laid out a
framework in our concept paper where bio
forest was able to just very simply sell
licenses to log its own trees while
automated processes though a mediated by
smart contracts which now is very simple
at the time we had to explain what's
more contracts worth a lot more
and so we which would be pulls idler who
should be here and the other co-founder
Paul calling envisaged ourselves buying
a plot of land and then signing this
over to a Dow and over time the logging
licenses and the funds that the Dow
would bring in by kind of selectively
selling its own trees so essentially
kind of like pruning itself to maintain
the healthier state that was possible it
would be able to buy back the land from
us so it was a we kind of almost giving
the Dowell mortgage initially and this
was kind of a conceptual exploration of
how inflexible smart contracts were and
how you could kind of tactically use
this so very simply if you made no
technical interface by which the
contract could actually sell the
ownership rights to its land to another
party and the land was legally signed to
the Dow which is another big F that I'm
going to come back to once I've kind of
gone through this explanation then there
wasn't actually any way in a technical
or legal sense that the forest could be
sold and brought back into the cycle of
land being bought and sold and then
stripped of his natural resources so is
this kind of very basic attempt or like
very conceptual like high level
conceptual attempts of appropriating
kind of capital at capitalist mechanisms
of resource exploitation and actually
laying out how a piece of ground could
start playing an active role in economic
flows whilst actually also directing
avoiding direct influence over itself so
this very very rough approximation of
what a self sovereign ecological entity
could actually be and what did we learn
oh sorry I completely missed this as
well this is just a fantastic cartoon
with regards to the difference between
legal rights and this kind of legal
rights of a corporation which we were
kind of playing with and trying to
appropriate obviously usually people
think of legal rights of a corporation
because it is usually this kind of
faceless grotesque thing that makes
corporations incredibly difficult to
kind of like legally interface with or
hold accountable and we kind of wanted
to appropriate that and give it to a
forest for better or worse and we were
we had a very we had a test site just
south of Berlin which this is just kind
of a stripped-down satellite image of
that we were kind of just using as a
technical playground as well and is
still going on as the technical
playground okay so what we learned from
this or what we learned from this
original concept piece that we've been
kind of mulling over for a while that
obviously there's been a lot of
development in the clip so in the
blockchain space especially with regards
to legal interfacing and what dowse can
and can't do particularly effectively
and the first of these which has kind of
become very evident in the past two
years you know everyone 2018 was the
year of the doubt and now 2019 is
apparently the year of the dowel again
is that dowels as organizational models
or like testers for new organizational
models are fits it like they're very
very interesting but the way that they
were initially conceived of and spoken
of so kind of like harkening back to
this quote of italics this is an
incredibly kind of mechanistic
repositioning of what mediation is it's
kind of just stripping everything down
and just hang ok cool you can
immediately and implicitly replace what
are actually very complex social
relations with quite simple mechanical
procedures and what we've kind of seen
in the last couple of years has been
this you know more and more projects
kind of engaging with thousand like
building dowels is that you have the
difference in the structural makeup
between the kind of main dowel models
and the first of these well the fact
that this structural engagement actually
exists really seems to suggest that
actually dowels are just kind of social
solutions novel social social solutions
to organizational problems that come
about because they're kind of bolstered
by this these certain forms of
autonomous mediation but they are still
inherently social forms the social is
not being replaced by this kind of
completely automated structure and so
Moloch Dowell on the one side of this
for those that don't know is a
essentially a reformatting of the kind
of guild model which is it's focused
around a very specific issue
so the initial Moloch Dao was built
around funding East 2.0 development and
there's very very little interaction
chain as the kind of nick szabo quote
above me suggests what it basically is
is a guild bank that that you can either
add new members to the dao and that's
voted upon by all the existing members
and they have shares that are delegated
to them and then they can then use those
shares to vote on other proposals be
those proposals i as an existing member
would like to extract x-- amounts of
money from the dao for this project or
is an existing member of the DAR would
like to add this other member to the dam
and that's it so it's incredibly simple
there's very little interaction on chain
and its really really reliant upon the
forms of social coordination and also
socially based reputation that are
actually far more akin to kind of
previously existing coop models so
really Moloch Dao is just kind of
leveraging the security and the minimal
but very secure coordination aspects of
something like the etherium Network to
kind of achieve an augment this
cooperative structure and this exists in
contrast to excuse me larger scale
organizations or Dao kind of models like
that are coming out of kind of Dao stack
development in Aragon who are working on
very very complex systems of having
obviously voting on chain but then also
you know kind of having tokens
representing refutation and the
different levels of how much reputation
you have and how much financial stake
you have actually kind of affecting then
the weighting of votes and all of this
so
the fact that there's this kind of like
quite hectic milieu of experimentation
with the house and down structures if
anything kind of just made me want to
say that the tech is really just a kind
of another substrate to try and build
new social coordination models the one
and there's a really interesting tension
that kind of arises out of this but
there also arose out of actually trying
to take this original concept of Terror
zero and actually trying to implement it
and that tension is actually something
that is also maybe a tension that exists
within you know much of the crypto
community or at least the kind of like
the crypto community that are kind of
more looking towards the or relying or
building among the kind of the political
the political and the kind of like
parallel society aims of people like the
cypherpunks or you know kind of like
relying on an Agora see maybe philosophy
in some sense and that's what this
interaction with the legal world is so
what we kind of have seen out of what's
happening with Dow's and also what we
found from tera zero was where that
limit or like what the scope of autonomy
that like blockchain tech an actually
give you and so even though we talked
about granting ownership rights to a
dowel in our original concept paper kind
of as an experiment with non human
autonomy in some sense but also kind of
going back to the the Szabo point I had
earlier as a kind of security measure
against the land being taken away by
kind of making it impossible for the
land to be granted to someone else with
the use of real estate or the
interaction between real estate or
physical space and kind of having some
kind of ownership denoted in the way
that we usually do within the kind of
purely digital realm especially within
the realm of kind of cryptocurrencies
and cryptography were key accessor like
key access actually just denotes
ownership those two things are wildly
different and
you have to interact on some level with
existing legal frameworks if you're
trying to integrate buildings or land
with any kind of blockchain based
application simply because the state who
said the laws have the monopoly of force
at the moment so regardless of how good
or how well thought out you're kind of
you know your your your cryptographic
substrate is if they don't want you to
have the land or don't recognize you is
having it then you don't have it in
their eyes and they will take it away
from you and there are quite a few
groups that are starting to engage with
this in different ways so there's a
group called des Antrim who are based in
Zurich who are currently kind of setting
up the prototype for a building which is
actually owned and it's processes are
kind of mediated via a series of smart
contracts so they're working quite
extent and they are actually working
with legislators in in Switzerland and I
believe and there are also groups like
koala who is setting up kind of what
they call is like minimum viable legal
interfacing for dowels so how can you
have dows existing without bringing the
whole thing into the kind of legal
structure that they were basically in
village to you know to help people get
out of but how can they in the the ways
they need to actually still interact
with this so you can actually build with
them and both of these projects are
still kind of starting out so it'd be
very interesting to see where they go
but the kind of TL DR of this kind of
these two kind of chunks of findings
that I've just thrown at you is that
basically crypto won't actually in and
of itself necessarily solves the issue
so what we need to kind of look at with
building these kind of counter
ecological tactics is how can we very
very strategically apply it and very
strategically use it to kind of bolster
either existing social relations and you
know kind of stuff like guerilla
gardening or stuff like the project the
call Hess was involved in and how can we
essentially use it to bolster like this
or relations that already exist or bring
about new tiny technological solutions
that kind of can incrementally help us
build up into building something new and
autonomous from the things we wish to
gain autonomy from so what are the
actual uses of censorship resistant tech
or autonomous infrastructure and how
could they apply be applied to augment
already existing ecological cancer
economic actions and I want to finish
the talk by going through two other
iterations of Terror zero that we did
last year and kind of highlighting some
of the mechanisms that we were playing
with and also hopefully some of the ways
that we could kind of expand either kind
of like vertically or horizontally going
back to to pare Boylan's point from
before and the first of these was a
project that we call flower tokens which
in a certain sense you could
conceptualize as a black market for
flowers which it was very much a
small-scale experiment that was actually
also a technical experiment looking at
natural resource tokenization which led
to recognitions actually of a lot of the
or recognizing a lot of the limits that
actually came with crypto and how it
actually really interacted with complex
forms of social coordination even within
this kind of like turret tiny control
case experiment so it was an
installation that was built in trust
which was a co-working space in Berlin
and the system had 100 that's the point
yeah
so I had $100 in it and was basically
just in this 4 by 5 rack and it had a
kind of semi automated watering system
as you can see down here and I say semi
automated because we still have to
really up I kind of maintain it and this
shot or these two camera shots which you
can actually kind of just about see
there this shot itself is from this
camera position of that so it was
monitored 24/7 by this camera and in
contrast to the first tera 0 forest it
really just focused on one aspect which
was this how do we actually kind of like
tow
real-world assets what is actually
necessary to tokenize because obviously
the process of just tokenizing
everything because you can actually in
itself is really something to avoid but
what is that what are the very small
useful pieces of information that we can
tokenize and how can we use them or why
would we use them and basically this is
the web interface that we set up for it
where users were able to buy trade and
speculate on these kind of tokenize
dahlias and the state of the tokens
sorry so as we see here just very simple
stuff like whether it's blooming the
height its growth rate over the previous
days
these were monitored by the camera that
came before so we had a program running
plant CV which is just a plant
specialized model of OpenCV in orders at
which updated it every 24 hours and yep
so the system just ran for three months
like I said it was a very small-scale
technical experiment and the initially
we sold all of the flowers for naught
point ninety which at the time I think
was about thirty euros I can't remember
and the highest the one that sold
highest on the first day actually sold
for 450 euros which was kind of bizarre
and users could then burn their tokens
and get their plants out of the system
which actually quite a few people did
which is maybe like a an interesting
little small-scale thing where a lot of
people just wanted to keep the token but
then a lot some people actually wanted
to burn this oak and get out of the
system which if you just view a token as
an abstract digital twin of a real-life
thing is interesting see who did and who
didn't and okay yep so basically this
was some of the plant cv information
that was gathered and these are just
some kind of prepping pictures of us
actually planting it so - and these are
kind of in there just to reinforce this
idea that even though from
these pictures it looks like a perfectly
encapsulated autonomous system actually
even trying to set something up as
small-scale as having a hundred flowers
in Iraq and an automated grow and kind
of like an automated watering system
involved a lot of people doing a lot of
work this is Marcus taking one of his
plans out and I included this picture
because one of the things this also
showed us was you can't be too strict
with your technology when you're
engaging with nature because as you
might be able to see all of the plants
basically started growing way too high
so actually our kind of computer
verification mechanism of actually
having everything processed by OpenCV
started failing because everything just
started kind of smashing together into
one mass or against the ceiling and so
kind of taking some of this and taking
some of this knowledge and seeing okay
these are the limits of maybe why we
shouldn't try to mediate everything to
strictly or monitor everything to
strictly we then built a project called
pram not even which is kind of or was
examining the kind of emergent
possibilities of like human and non in
human interaction on the most granular
level we could think of trying it out
and this was basically using a software
framework using a decentralized software
framework to allow for kind of a
technologically augmented organic system
to engage in social and financial
contracts with the broader environment
so kind of harkening back to the idea
that we were playing within the concept
paper but really stripping it down into
okay cool we have a bonsai tree that's
doing this instead of an entire forest
which is also far more financially
feasible as well so it started off as an
installation and a prototype that was at
the shingle pavilion in Berlin and the
system itself just consisted of a bonsai
tree a web interface which this is a
better picture of quite a few sensors
like two of them you can see here which
kind of existed in this ring that was
sitting around it and it's kind of
enclosure and a small contract and
these software and hardware systems that
it was embedded within we kind of
envisaged as almost like technological
prosti prosthesis which allowed it to
which allowed for this creation of like
a financially mediated social contract
into being between the operators of
whatever space it was in and tremana the
tree itself
so basically when people committed to
having the tree in their space they
committed to care for the needs of from
the diamond which are watering trimming
trimming its leaves making sure it has
enough electricity making sure it has
enough server space and the open Bazaar
Edition at the bottom was just a bit of
a wild-card where people could donate to
it and it would buy like nicer tools for
itself to be trimmed with which is and
the way that prama pays for this is that
people engaging with it on the web
interface so as we can see here you know
I know this is just Prem not paying for
all this stuff basically you could go
into the web interface and you could
donate a bit of money to it so the idea
of being that when it didn't have that
much electricity left
hopefully someone would come in and give
it you know 50 cents worth of ether and
then Prem there would ping the owners of
the space it was in and say hey here's
some money can you water me or something
like that and so this was kind of an
attempt to position a very small
ecological system as instead of being a
passive object that needed caring for
and constantly had to have humans
watching it it was more that pramana
demon was a way of starting to explore
the potential of non-human systems to
actually kind of gain the state as the
vasami autonomous peer so instead of
having the interactions between human
actors and the system into like a purely
financial eyes way it shows that you can
maybe make an autonomous system that
humans have to interact with on the same
level of a social contract as I would
were I to be buying a coffee from peril
only paulus even though there is a
financial transaction there it is
actually still essentially a social
relation
that is financially mediated maybe and
actually what we kind of wanted to do
with this and this was toured
successfully for over a year now yeah
not only can you actually create this
kind of very minimal non human autonomy
but you can actually crowd fund it just
from strangers on the internet as well
and so I suppose the conclusion of this
or what we can then bring what we're
kind of trying to elucidate as these
tactics and bring into this still very
nascent notion of counter ecologies is
some of these mechanisms we can use to
kind of at least maybe tactically
bolster some of the ideas that I talked
about before so these guerrilla
ecological work or like self organized
farming initiatives we can maybe take
from art pieces like Fender demon and
then actually give some form of new
financial or new social autonomy to
these projects or at least enable them
to kind of start existing outside of the
restrictive systems that they're
currently placed in Thanks okay thank
you max thank you for the for the
presentation and now we have a time for
a few questions so anybody in the
audience would like to ask and follow on
topics on counter ecologists okay thank
you hi thanks for the presentation I'm
not familiar with dolls so I would like
to ask in the case of pram Nam
is there an artificial intelligence
involved that's taking decisions for
example it sees one day left for
electricity one they left her water
okay which one prioritizes and does it
how does it decide for itself okay so
that's kind of a two-pronged question no
there's no there's no AI even mission
nothing and there really is just Python
libraries so in terms of the
differentiation between okay cool so I
have this much left for water and this
much left for electricity
we actually didn't we didn't actually
build that into it wasn't all just one
wallet that it was going into there were
each separate little wallet right so and
that was kind of partially done just to
see what people prioritized above other
things because for instance on the
screenshot that I had before electricity
was always running really really low but
for instance and trimming it as well
which is something you have to do to
keep the bonsai healthy was usually
quite low but people would always pay
for water so it was a certain also
seeing how you can split up the
different social interactions just to
see what would happen
luckily we were never in a situation
where the system would have died so so
you had different wallets for different
needs so this is okay because I thought
there was a pool that money pours in and
then this Dao decided itself ok and the
decisions were just the decisions were
super super simple so we just had a we
just have like a soil moisture sensor in
the pot for instance and just knew that
it had to keep between a certain level
okay thanks know it obviously you could
expand this massively but just at the
time it was very minimal just as an idea
hello I know the talk is about well
closed ecosystems keeping in mind that
you are a colonist person I would like
to know your thoughts about global
warming and how the media is approaching
that topic how the other media is
approaching little bit yeah creator Tom
Berg and all that kind of things
I mean complex questions to a sort of
big question um I suppose the way that I
would kind of like ground it within this
is the the idea of a synth like the idea
of a single consistent narrative with
regards that global warming is actually
kind of in and of itself a little bit
ridiculous because obviously you can't
it's far too complex a phenomenon to
actually like view as a single entity
but also in terms of the possibilities
for action
and I'll very specifically say that this
idea of the individuation of the
responsibility of climate change of the
idea that everyone should use plastic
straws and actually it's really your
fault not people who own jets or you
know like what have the 100 companies
that have 71 that basically commit 71%
of all the co2 emissions and all of this
I would like that individuation of the
narrative is kind of ridiculous but then
and then it sounds slightly paradoxical
to a certain extent but you or you can
do as well outside of there are like two
tactics you could basically take you
could go down the route of engaging with
that issue so you have a hundred
companies that contribute a massive
amount of co2 and trying to engage with
that on some level or you could also
work maybe in a way that's more akin to
what people like but kind of like the
solar punk movement are essentially
advocating which is like okay cool the
solutions aren't going to come from the
top down so maybe we just have to build
and bomb up and obviously this will
start off I was like a series of look
how based things but hopefully that
thing can spread and become some kind of
a network yeah I suppose that's all I'd
throw up sorry it was a bit of a
curveball of a question so that might
have been a massively incoherent answer
as well but yeah okay maybe follow the
animals response here to the Greta which
was published I think two days ago or so
so a little last question who would like
to have okay
yeah thanks we'll talk like my questions
a bit so you're trying to build yourself
governing or self-organizing plant
system or like maintaining and yeah I
mean these were sorry yeah so and maybe
this has wrong words but like so ease
are you trying to kind of take the human
out of the loop like and then my
question is why and if you're not trying
to take the human out of the loop then
it's my questions like why are you doing
this because in the end boils down to
people trying to preserve nature and
people not trying to preserve nature and
why building this restricted system
around it or smart contracts and yeah I
suppose answer to that would be it's not
really we're not trying to do it in as
polarized away as that I mean like
obviously the the work that we were
presenting there is incredibly polarized
because they were kind of presented as
these experiments that were presented
within an hour context right so it was
more about on a broader level what kind
of mechanisms can you actually take out
of that so for instance with Bremner or
if you you can just have a system where
people can pay into it maybe people who
aren't actually attached to the projects
at all which is an idea that actually
came from the forgot the name of the
piece now it was essentially that the
tele garden so it was like a robot arm
that was like looking after a garden
that people could control from anywhere
in the world over the Internet and
instead of kind of trying to completely
remove the humans or and kind of
completely automate everything it's more
of like where can these little things
fit in that maybe you could for instance
in a more transparent way like crowdfund
or you can automate certain aspects of
it there could then mean that like five
people could actually run a far larger
area of a garden or something like that
so it's really just kind of like looking
at where you can slap this stuff in and
experimenting with those as opposed to
trying to completely remove people from
it and completely automate everything
because that's not either necessary or
like technically feasible so it's really
just kind of
anything with okay you have certain
forms of autonomy that started to come
about with stuff like dolls with stuff
like small contracts I know that these
are experiments as well these aren't
necessarily things to be scaled and
reproduced but it's to be learned from
and maybe you learn not to do that
I think with some of the stuff there are
certain structural mechanisms we could
at least take from it does that is that
yeah okay before I think to max I would
like just paint up if somebody would
like to follow this discussion maybe I
definitely recommend you at 7:00 if I'm
right guys from parallel garden project
VG's para una police base will introduce
you into their work however gear have
they work in hydroponics or the project
of the fan bot so definitely at 7:00 at
Institute of krypton RG but now I would
like to definitely thank to Marx for his
presentation and I hope that with this
project he will not just inspire other
people to think about Contra ecology but
I was more thinking maybe a little bit
infect them you know because that's the
approach I think we need anymore
okay so thank you and thank you guys for
coming
you