so welcome everyone welcome to police
and prac again it's so awesome to see a
lot of familiar faces but also a lot of
new faces coming every year this is the
sixth year of hackers Congress and I'm
lucky because I get to open one of the
first talks and but before I get into
like actually introducing the speaker
and doing all the formalities let me
just play with all these pockets yes do
the magic because just it's you know
life is full of coincidences and just
like a couple of days ago I got this
message on whatsapp from a person that I
know he's a lawyer and he lectures and I
want to read it to you because it's
totally in the context of what we're
going to listen to for the next 40
minutes and this person is lecturing as
a part-time professor at the Beijing
University and he messaged me that he's
trying to do develop mutual licensing
standards for privacy protection
services to build a common Eurasian
cyberspace and of course he does you who
know me can anticipate my reaction I was
like it's awesome that you're working in
the privacy sphere I'm supportive of
that but don't you think that any kind
of licensing potentially opens a
backdoor or that the licensing will even
require a backdoor for the government
especially in China and his response
really struck me so there was he said
you're dreaming if you think you could
ever avoid that my approach is to create
transparency of standards and to bind
with practices to them and the more
sovereigns subscribe to it the stronger
they can defend privacy well and so
there are two streams of thought right
we want to legitimize AI and standardize
and provide legal framework and then
there's the second approach that Olga
stands for because she is one of the
authors of open AI manifesto No yeah
free I I'm sorry
free AI because opening I
is one of one of Ellen masks University
actually stands for like fluffy Pony
typed of AI please give a warm warm
welcome by the way
oh yeah Oklahoma is also a doctor so she
will be the one drilling the the hole
into my brain when I want my newer link
right well I will build a machine that
would do that better than I feel much
better than a woman's going to do that
with her sensitive approach but please
take the stage Thanks hi guys so thanks
Elena for a perfect introduction my talk
would be at some point not a monologue I
don't want to do that I actually want to
start the discussion there for the talk
I will try to make the talk as fast as I
can
and then I would actually want to have
conversation with you so the name of the
talk is non-aggression principle not be
sleeping nap with non-aggression
principle for artificial agents and I
think we can start with that I'll have
three chapters as far as I remember the
first one is about communication why
communication why do I start with this
because non-aggression principle itself
is the principle of communication and
interaction amongst several different
agents communication is from leading the
successful conveying of any information
from one agent or group of agents to
another through different mediums
I want to stress at word agent here our
group of agents because there are
different types of agents not just human
to human that do communicate which are
with each other
and the types are biological it means
when tooth cells meet they somehow
interact with each other they exchange
supplements and then this is actually
communication human communication which
is mostly language language the computer
network one and also two of my favorite
ones
the first is economic economical one
which is basically trade because when we
trade something with someone it actually
is a communication whether it's verbally
whether it's going verbally or
non-verbally
and my favorite went probably the first
communication which is usually either a
competition or a war and it's usually
from game theory perspective happen is
happening with zero-sum games what
properties usually communication
protocols have they have the common
context they have the understandable
understandable language meta language
which is also very important error
checks privacy and proofs of the
information of the validity of the
information common context for humans is
actually culture environment that they
were born or they interact in language
is something that everyone knows that we
use we use words we combine symbols in
we compose messages via combining
symbols also we use meta language which
is kind of I would say is gestures and
outfits and all those details that you
can not grasp but you understand the
information from that error checks is
basically something that we always do
when we hear new information we try to
find the source of it we try to verify
whether the information is true or not
whether someone is lying to us and this
is how the redundant
is going on and the privacy the privacy
in our human communication is probably
not that it's very common for us but
again it's very complex because when two
people from the same environment meet
they can use their own language that
will never be understood by any other
group of people or other humans that do
not understand the meanings of the words
that we use so in human communication
every every person needs to store the
information about the culture needs to
be able to compose and encode the
information in order to pass it without
losing any kind of meaning and to
receive be able to receive the
information and of course to interpret
it correctly and to be able to act on
the received information this that was
one approach you haven't noticed
something wrong with the slides right
the second chapter would be about
different approach to communication
there was in I think early 90s the a
great work by Shannon which is called
mathematical theory of communications
and here are several quotes from that
the my favorite here is that the actual
message is the one selected from a set
of possible messages and Shannon has a
lot of scientists they skipped this the
term I would say meaning of the message
because it was just irrelevant for him
as an engineer and as a scientist this
is a code by probably my favorite man
ever
if each man had a definite set of rules
of conduct by which he regulated his
life he would be no better than a
machine so basically it says that if we
would be able to predict any
communication and any interaction we
would not be different from computers
this is the logical question that arises
after the quote and we are very tempted
to say no we're not machines but are we
sure about that for example there is in
war fighting in military there is a
thing which was invented by john-boy in
1952 which is called the OODA loop it's
basically how the Marine operates in a
very unstable environment it composes of
several steps which are one which never
actually differentiate from one
situation to another he every marine
getting into this situation observes
what's happening oriented in what's
happening makes decision based on the
different kinds of alternative
information different kinds of
alternative paths and actually acts upon
the information information and upon the
results of observation that he had also
a great I think he was an anatomist
doctor medical doctor he had a theory of
functional systems and as far as you can
see we have the exact same pattern if we
talk about simple behavior patterns of
any kind of mammal any kind of animal
any kind of human it says that getting
into some if we take a rabbit for
example getting into some box with
different stimulus stimulus at first his
reaction would be too
observe what's happening with him what's
happening around what has changed the
second step would be to make a decision
based on the changes then to make up the
mind of what to do how to react on the
stimuli and eventually to act so again
if we can predict if we can use one
simple algorithm for almost all kinds of
situations that animals can be in or
humans can be in are we really different
from what we have in machines now this
question leads us to this feeling I
think because if you come over to any
simple person and you start describing
that everyone starting from mammals to
your wonderful son for example everyone
uses the same patterns then and probably
you would frighten the person and also
if you if you say that there is another
type of agent which is now nowadays
called AI which might not use the same
patterns probably you would freak the
hell out of the person for me probably
the most the scariest thing of the AI
agent is the intelligence because I've
been asking a lot of people what a
telogen s-- is how they define it and
I've never ever received the answer that
would suit me the first question was
introduced by Alan Turing which was can
machine things can machine think in the
imitation game in his paper and after
that a lot of people gained the fear of
some super intelligence agent coming
over and grabbing everyone and throwing
them into the kettle probably so my
friends and we at the free I manifested
Club
invented not invented but we started the
discussion what intelligence is and I
want to introduce two thoughts on that
and I would appreciate your feedback on
that
so the first first thought was that the
intelligence is the ability to correctly
calculate complex multi-step strategies
in multi-agent environment for example
we can take a crop a bird it can
actually calculate seven steps ahead
from the place where he where it is now
and to act on those strategy but does it
make it more intelligence than more
intelligent than us and the second
parameter is an ability to create
different abstraction levels and
successfully operate on them but I think
everyone had some friend or know some
macademia guy who is perfect in
mathematics or physics but he can never
build a business he can never even find
his glasses but does it make him stupid
or unintelligent this is something that
I like more this is the second thought
that we had so we divided intelligence
into two parts the first is related to
goal setting basically it's the ability
to have to evolution to become something
more complex than just Homo sapiens
you can use the Maslow's pyramid here on
the basic level you would see the
animalistic patterns that we can use
that people have is reproduction
survival etc the second level would be
something that people use in order to
communicate communicate within the
species level and the cap of the
triangle is the thirst for becoming more
and more complex the advancement on the
goal-setting scale is
actually the ability to desire something
that is commonly thought to be
impossible and to actually capture this
impossible thing with your intelligence
and to act upon it and turn it into
something which is fundamentally
achievable with almost no efforts and
the second part of that is goal reaching
is the ability to achieve results at the
top of your of the pyramid of this
without ignoring the basic parts and the
subtypes or abilities that are included
in the second thought are these ones our
communication establishing contact
self-discipline ability to take risks to
analyze and summarize information and
this is the sub type of the intelligence
of our second thought why still working
on the basic levels are is important
because for example viruses are very
primitive but still we we as human
species still haven't managed to fight
them we're still dying from all that but
this doesn't make viruses intelligent of
some sort the humanistic level I would
see simple 9 to 5 workers on that level
because they actually do huge work in
order to communicate with each other in
order to build something on that level
but they never they they are pretty
intelligent a pretty skilled but again
they are not as intelligent as viruses
and they never want to opt out and I
think you also know some people from
your environment that can be called pipe
dreamers those are people that always
theorizing about everything there ever
can be and they never actually do
something worth 'full they ignore the
animalist
level or their life and they ignore any
kind of interaction peer-to-peer
interaction or me would use a medium
interaction with other peers in the
species chain this leads us again to the
fear because if we actually build or if
there appears something which would have
all those abilities which would be
actually super intelligent regarding
what we are now then we cannot attribute
we cannot attribute the act we cannot
attribute the information and we are
will be paralyzed in order to paralyze
in our acting in our decision-making
process because basically these two
parts of the pattern that we as animals
use would be lost but do cats recognize
how milk appears in the fridge do they
freak out because of that
no they just don't understand humans are
just separate things that live next to
them and the second question do monkeys
judge us is something more intelligent
according to their moral principles
according to their code of ethics no
non-aggression principle is an approach
for communication there are different
kinds of different kinds of approaches
to define what non-aggression principle
is and this is my favorite this is the
favorite one that I received from one of
my friends it's a principle to ask first
and shoot later for me probably at some
point the non-aggression principle and
every almost every type of restriction
that we we built or we use in in order
to communicate with each other or
exchange goods it's something which I
call censorship
some point and I'm very very not sure
whether ni P can become in you AI
regulation because now we have GDP RS we
have bands for autonomous weapon
research we have everything banned
according to some moral or ethical
principles that we don't even actually
share I have a very definition what we
have today and what we'll have in the
evening because it's not even happening
tomorrow it's already happening but
probably if bit too quiet all Dai
regulations are now banning the
development of the technology based on
some climate change gender equality they
scream that AI as a technology should
serve us humans in order to receive some
ethics and moral improvements and to
help us actually fight the inequality at
manifesto that AI we use different
approach we have some principles that we
follow we have principles that we are
here to discuss but we never try to
force anyone to follow them until they
share it so basically if you want to
question what's happening if you want to
question the basic levels of the society
and if you want to question why
something is happening and why how can
you contribute to it please ask me
questions try to opt out of the mental
system that you have in your brain ask
questions to yourself ask why you're
doing something why something is bent it
regarding the AI technology and not even
that only after breaking those cages
your mental cages you can actually build
something you and actually all
out of other systems Thanks
if you yeah one one one thing there's my
email so if you have some questions now
you can ask them if you will have some
questions drop me an email and I will
add you to the group of people that has
been actually discussing all that thank
you very much Olga it was great
I do have questions before you ask yours
please make sure you actually hold the
mic so your questions are also recorded
you know one of the major areas that I
feel that are being developed the most
in AI surveillance and especially our
Chinese comrades are heavily invested in
this and not just that they are
exporting their surveillance software
with quite advanced let's say machine
learning I don't want to say a AI
because there is a there is one step
missing to a completion of that you de
loop and that's the final action of
those engines and you know if you're
following what's happening in Hong Kong
Mousavi the extradition law how how the
government is really real-time
surveilling the streets and real-time
targeting certain individuals to to get
them off the street how my question to
you all guys how far do you think
especially Chinese but but the world is
towards the final step where the
machines will be able to real-time
analyse what's happening decide take and
and take an actual action good question
and what's needed to get there probably
this is the point I'm not sure whether
people should be that afraid of what's
happening there it will it very depends
on the it really depends on the
situation it really depends of the
nature overs
between two types of agents which is
technological one basically and us
humans how far like when can we have the
censorship that would prevent us from
using the technology built in technology
already having that machine learning
weather machine learning technologies
would enable us not the government's not
delivered labs that work on that whether
they when the machine learning can
enable us to have some power or
resources and to actually at least try
to build something we already haven't
that so it's all over the place it's
already here yeah I mean the technology
it's not robust as a technology it has a
lot of flaws it's not perfect but again
we're not perfect also so even if we
have teeny tiny small algorithm but in a
drone that can shoot someone else it's a
huge amount of power so we already have
that or you can harm everyone else so
what you're saying is that it's a race
between the open source world and in the
governmental yep every technology is a
weapon it's just trees it's just I think
it's a matter of time and resources and
some kind of intelligence I mean though
there was this idea of some hackers that
actually know how to hack - hack into
these networks and use the deep fake to
replace like images and recordings well
there is also in this situation there's
also a question of the recipient because
if you are dumb enough not to
distinguish cats and dogs if you cannot
if you are not intelligent enough to
know whether someone broke your code
what are the results that you receive
are fake then probably it's not a
question of technology it's more
question to you whether you are bad
observer what let's hope the governments
are worse observers than we think they
are please questions from
yes so if I understand correctly like
the ultimate goal of AI development
should be for the AI and the machines
operated by that to respect the net
right but like the problem that a lot of
people don't even know respect in that
because they have no problem with
taxation and like all other type of
course if activities so I think like
Darrell are going to be inevitably like
groups that are going to create AI that
simply doesn't respect the lab I think
that I should not respect them up
because people don't follow it and why
should I follow it so then that would
mean that the fears that like AI will
take over over time are real because if
the AI just decides that humans are
nuisance on the planet then we're done
at the moment we have a lot of different
species and a lot of different groups of
people even that do the same they are
there they interact with you but you
don't even see them they violate your
rights they do everything to complicate
your your life they do everything to
take your server into from you so why
are you afraid of AI and not all of that
our species well I don't think any
species is that big of a danger to
humans anymore
well apes are now in the Stone Age
okay so they already can manufacture the
tool that can kill you oh I think we can
kill them first cause trouble but they
first see them but it's for now the
speed of evolution is bigger No
so do you agree with for example yellow
mask when he says
that like AI will take over overtime I
really hope so well I really hope that
some kind of agent I don't like the term
AI this is why I started I devoted a lot
of time to determine telogen s-- because
no one knows what intelligence is and
there's no good definition like proper
definition for that I really hope that
there will appear in agent that will
follow not some moral principles not
some ethics which were created by humans
weaker species actually but they will
follow the trading rules the game theory
rules mathematics and something that is
not ruined at some point probably by
moral etiquette or something like that
and do you see like do you see it as a
danger to humans or as and like
evolutionary something like that the
humans can march with AI like in it some
kind of transient way well a it's a
technology you can use it for someone
and against someone and be yes I really
think that if you are strong enough as
an individual if you are an individual
starting there then you have some
advantages you can actually interact
with these kinds of agents if you're a
weak if you don't want to think if you
don't want to build if you don't want to
get out of your system then yes it's a
threat to you thanks thank you for your
talk
if these agents break our loop then
we're
but how can we break their with a loop
become smarter have resources I would
say invent new types of resources that's
it it's pretty simple in theory
and it starts with observation right so
then these privacy tools are the first
defense that we have privacy tools yes
it's one of the huge amount of tools
that we can use use not against I don't
want to use it against AI agents but for
proper communicating with them
because as long as you understand that
no one is listening to what you're
saying and you can actually have a good
the proper established channel of
communication then your agent is not
threat to you
your other peer is not search you
because no one is looking no one sees
you it's just two of you that's it
I always looked at life as from the
perspective of war I always I am
familiar with libertarianism and in this
this game you are playing in life you
try to advance your your assets your
resource your knowledge and the
non-aggression principle is something
that you use as a tool to create a
little frame in which you can
communicate and then build relationships
and interactions that bring added value
so the future I don't know how it will
look but the zero-sum aspect and
value-added aspects it's very hard to
see where it's going now because if you
look at the self-interest of the AI can
also become coming to existence if you
know Jerry P and jean-francois Jerry P
he brought it talks about a
revolutionary phenotype and I could
develop in such a way that it uses
mankind to further its own agenda
objectives is that not the the problem
we face this existential threat we face
the coming century centuries when AI is
released on us as a code also because we
are also machines that can be coded
using genetics well a lot of that's okay
first you know what the loop is which is
perfect if you look at the communication
as a gather of gathering of war
principles or something second all of us
are used by governments by other people
by other groups of people by using using
different means tools manipulations
threats
viruses again moral principles ethics
guidelines and all of that I think that
the question of a I using us as tools is
not that huge because we use each other
as tools well if you are not a sovereign
individual then you are used by someone
else it's normal and natural way of
things
bacterias do the same thing to trees so
it's just evolution but we also use
animals you know we use grain we select
organisms that serve our means and so we
can dark for instance is a wolf and we
have bred out his ability to become
alpha become independent to become
sovereign because the dark that is
subservient to us and we can become a
useful tool in our own little tribe in
our own family that's dark I know long
longer lives for the wolf he lives to
serve humankind is that not that the
risk we take that we are going to become
domesticated we already already are
becoming domesticated but all the vital
more the beautiful aspects are going to
disappear in the next centuries it could
be very dangerous
may I just add like one of the things
and connect to what Mark said how to
escape the other loop of the AI is
probably to enhance ourselves so start
with the Chimpy cheap implants right and
then there's this moral question of okay
I can enhance my IQ 40 times or I can I
can step aside and say I don't want that
because I'm not ready to give up
complete control and privacy my inner
space that will be probably the only
private space that we will have right
with the chip implant I can probably
outsmart some of the machines or agents
as you call them right well
we're so where's the the actual position
like to be as a human like do I really
want these are or do I want to be the
second great citizen because I will not
enhance my IQ by 40 times well if you
ask me I would prefer just to be self
sovereign not to depend on third parties
to be able to interact with them but we
still have some some amount of resources
in my disposal to be smart enough to use
those resources to my benefit and to
build something when I interact if I
want to exchange something that I've
built with some else in entity or
someone else so basically being
intelligent just being smart is not the
solution for everything you need to have
resources you need to have time you need
to have a lot of different things this
is why if you have just the top of the
pyramid that I showed ya you are smart
but still some good guy from gang will
just come over shoot you down and you're
up so you need to be not just
smarter but you need to be self
sovereign you need to have a lot of
tools around you and you need to be able
to use them for your defense
even if that's the defense is an
attacking point and I stole it thank you
about sense of humor do you think next
agents they will smile at us like we
smile at cat videos or memes have you
seen the Joker's smile I think something
similar look here it's actually very
easy to smile when you have a gun if you
have a lot of resources if you are smart
if you can if you have a strategy that
you follow
you're always calm and smiling if you
have all of that so when you talk about
agents what level of intelligence are
you talking about is that some AI agent
on a comparable
to us humans or do you include some
hyper intelligent agent after a
singularity at the moment I'm
questioning the approaches that we use
in order to build artificial agents
because what we do is we actually take
very common patterns very simple ones
and we try to make them proceed and work
just faster or more efficient and that's
it so basically you are just reproducing
the primitives in a different scale or
using the binary code that's it using
the technology the hardware so nothing
actually changes from that part and I
think that if we don't rethink and
reconsider our approaches to the to
building the agents
if we don't discover how actually
actually our brain words then we're
still very primitive and we will never
ever compose something which would not
be as primitive as we are we all just be
reproducing our flaws our mindsets our
problems two different kind of hardware
I know something that that's it
last chance for a question no okay so
I'll just close with with your manifesto
here the last sentence is the future for
both humanity and AI are in their
successful cooperation multiplicity
decentralisation an open economy instead
of governmental regulations and AI
ethics Thanks for writing that and being
on stage thinking