[Music]
dear Krypton locust dear freedom lovers
welcome in Prague welcome in Central
Europe welcome at HC P P and really
happy that you come here please your
hand who is here like the first time
just first time yeah ok who is he'll the
second time third time oh cool so we had
a lot of like at first timers so let me
introduce shortly my name is Pavel loop
tag and I'm one of the organizers of
this conference this unique conference
in Central Europe I'm also the
co-founder of parallel polish this
unique unique place you're just here and
I'd like to open HTTP Congress and tell
you more about what what is going going
on and what interesting workshop
presentations lightning talks
interesting events are waiting for you
so before I would like to explain you
the slug and opt-out we decided to
choose for this year because every year
we have a bit different topic and this
year we decided for up out so what was
the idea behind behind this decision
firstly after so many years we realized
that we tripped on our kissed
voluntaries libertarian freedom lovers
be where we are and also we will be in
the future always in minority and and it
is really crucial to realize this
important fact so it means that that
democratic system we are just leading
now cannot lead to more freedom or more
free society
so it is really important to realize
this file to cope with this fact but
don't desperate because because what we
have now is a global internet community
with connecting million of people with
different different people with the same
taste and a taste and this taste of
freedom and this is exactly what pearl
pol is trying to do so we are a
community now fully working in
Bratislava and Prague probably starting
in one money in Barcelona or there also
in Vienna and what we are trying to do
we are trying to connect all these
people with the same taste for freedom
together and we are trying to show these
people how it's possible to make a
parallel society and how to opt out of
the system so let's collect this
community and this conference you you
you will see a lot of presentation how
it is possible to use current crypto
technology and various legislation hacks
various legislation loopholes our
legislation tricks to achieve more
freedom so what is important achieved
new freedom using gullibility and
flexibility opt out of the system so
this is a very short explanation and now
I'm going to describe our dear speakers
we'll have at this year of the
conference so first one and one of the
most important one is Robin Hanson Robin
Hanson is is inventor of the of the term
super key maybe you know that these few
turkeys is a society the concept of
society which is based on prediction
markets so Rob enhancer is really
focused on prediction market he wrote
two interesting books the first book is
called the elephant in the brain it's
about it about statuses of in our
society and the second one is the age of
M it's about possibility about future
society where it will be possible to
make a kilometer of human brain i
strongly recommended to read
bodies books this year Robin Hanson will
have a presentation here about radical
concept of criminal criminal proposal
how it how we can how we can change our
approach to self
criminal criminal act another very
important speaker will be loose cuenta
loose Q&A is the main guy behind the
project Aragon Aragon del Dallas is
decentralized autumn's organization for
those who don't know what is what that
exactly means so in these days the
government are loose with Ramona poly
over issuing money thanks to
cryptocurrencies but still they have
monopoly over business licenses so if
you want to create company you can
create Czech company you can create the
US company but still the license the
licenses are issued by the specific
governments but in the future probably
this won't be true because they'll
basically means that thanks to smart
contracts you would be able to create
any decentralized organization or any
decentralized company store agreement
between order of this company into the
blockchain and and start completely
decentralized unstoppable unstoppable
organization and exactly well this loose
go and we'll have a presentation another
interesting speaker is Nikhil Metatron
Nikhil me to town it's a guy from from
Oxford and he will have a presentation
about non existing states about very
interesting States you are probably not
ever
we have kobani and dissident from from
Cuba his name is Renaldo Escobar Casas
also will have another people from China
and probably also from North Korea
so we try to have people from all these
dictatorship countries they will they
will tell you what's going on in this
country how they are fighting for more
freedom how what kind of technologies
they use another important speakers
Trevon case he is from Philippines and
Trevino will have a presentation how it
is possible using his pretty bad
passport to get visas and residency in
the most most countries so he's like a
some kind of state hacker
ken shook insolent can can is
responsible for writing really important
book the name of this book is I think
it's stories of Jonathan gleeble it's
the unartistic book for children and it
was translated it was translated
probably to 100 languages different
languages in the Slovak language and
Czech language and if you if you want to
teach an orca to your children maybe you
should start with this book strongly
recommended and then we had a lot of
regular speakers with their new
mind-blowing presentation like Paul
Rosenberg smuggle your blood see Europe
and bednar and much more
unfortunately we I don't have time to
speak about all speakers we will have
this year at HTTP but we have more than
45 speakers together but I would like to
mention three important panel discussion
we all have here the first one which be
moderated by me it's called crypto
liberation community panel so it seemed
that in Europe now we have like growing
crypto liberation communities in
different cities so people from Germany
from Austria from Spain from Slovakia
from Czech Republic from all this
country that are trying to build
parallel policies or their own crypto
liberation communities and I decided to
invite all
these people at one place and we'll have
discussion panel for cues on crypto
liberation and put crypto liberation
communities also we will have very
interesting panel with the bio hackers
with the name by ahead yourself and also
this year we will focus on virtual
reality so if you're keen of virtual
reality
don't miss the panel beyond beyond
virtual reality lighting in dogs also we
all have a lot of lightning talks for
cues on very different topics for
example a Lonavla nova maybe you know
the sad she Satoshi
woman she will have a presentation about
her recent book called little Bitcoin
will also have like interesting
presentation of Beach Canary just
project use to time logs and also
you'll have a workshop so you probably
had or we probably get this HTTP special
HD htpb badge so the the author or
creator of these of these badges he will
have interesting presentation and
workshop how it's possible to make your
own badge
also we'll have another presentation
about electrically conductive fiber
cloth is also another presentation about
bitcoin lightning first Bitcoin a
lightning ATM how this how is possible
to make on lightning ATM machine we also
will have guys from Riyadh Vienna they
will do workshop about black crystal
it's a hardware workshop charlie from
from parallel police Prague he will have
workshop how it's possible to make
double spending or at least how to how
to hack application which application
widget on verified number of
conservation so he created interesting
applications so definitely don't miss
the
this workshop if you are interesting to
to do double spending there will be some
guys talking from moderate community I
think about new hardware volleyed and
also some other presentations about
cracking private keys and also will have
like a projection of not a completely
new film but about new film about
Czechoslovakia crypto community which is
still in progress and I think tonight
you you can see premiere of this of this
film and the last thing is that in front
of parallel police there is like a huge
truck
it's called decent truck and because we
consider our thoughts and ideas to be
really important we decided to spread
our ideas physically and we bought like
a physical truck we call we call it
doesn't track and we would like to use
these
Desson truck to visit a lot of places
and promote crypto key crypto liberation
cryptocurrencies so I think at these
times already open
so don't hesitate this doesn't track
when you go out of pearl polish and
that's all thank you for being here and
enjoy your first second and third htpb
Congress thank you
you