[Music]
good afternoon ladies and gentlemen my
pleasure to introduce introduce you our
next speaker each result he is
originally from Canada living in Toronto
he is our regular speaker he visited
HTTP last year also two two years ago
and he will have interesting
presentation about insider attacks I'm
especially interested this presentation
because because I'm like a security
expert but security consultant and I'm
involved in this topic so welcome Peter
thank you you know I'm glad he said you
especially interested because we're
consulting not because you wanted to go
pull off insider attack but yeah you
know and dishonest devs I mean you know
that's certainly going to be a thing
people are gonna do it in you know you
really got asked like and I always kind
of look at security this way you and
what are we trying to prevent you know
what's the what's a bad thing we're
trying to prevent and there's a lot of
issues you know I think we have
governments of course who just like
encryption just like security want more
power over you basically and you know I
mean I'm also an Australian sis and one
of the things I'm kind of worried about
is this which is Australia I vote what
year and a half ago two years no passed
a law where essentially they can go
force people to add backdoors to
technology and you know it's a very very
harsh law I mean you could be a
developer working at a company working
on open source projects and you get
contacted by someone claiming to be from
the Australian government and they go
and tell you well if you go tell anyone
about this other than maybe your lawyer
you're gonna go to jail and by the way
we have a few changes you wanna go make
to your big project and if you tell your
boss you can go to jail if you go and
you know say anything about this you can
go to jail oh and by the way everything
I just said it's basically not tracked
you know judge didn't approve it it was
just kind of rubber stamped at some
government agency I mean at least that
got in the law but you know it's a scary
thing
and as bad as this for the devs well the
reality is that's an example of a
dishonest if from your point of view you
know that dev is doing something you
don't want them to do and you also get
stuff like this you know this is one of
quite a few examples I went and found
but essentially it's one of these many
many alt coins fork of the Bitcoin
source code and a little I'm not the
easiest to read but they're you so you
know that's like IRC bootstrapping and
here it does something funny see read
whatever whatever well it turns out one
checks you know compiled us and it
resolves macros and all the other stuff
off P open well what does P open do well
just opens arbitrary process based on
something called like proof message off
proof message privacy or something
no it's basically a backdoor someone
sends a special IRC command it just runs
this magic message and then they can do
whatever you want and you know it's a
little sketchy as to whether or not this
has happened who is actually at fault
there's like many many levels of meta
but allegedly something along these
lines back toward you know exchange
cripsy and stole a big pile of money and
for my understanding cripsy while they
were having a server with hot wallets of
multiple different currencies all
running together and I'll go talk more
about mitigations for that kind of
scenario but you know obviously you
would have wanted to go catch this if
you were crip see I mean even if all you
were doing was running though one one
thing you definitely want to go catch it
and so we can kind of boil this down and
you know I like boiling this down
because ultimately security software is
different than other software you know
if I have Adobe Photoshop my goal with
Adobe Photoshop is to edit some images
you know maybe more for my face into
some celebrity or something you know
there's pretty clear to the user whether
or not it's working you know that's
that's kind of our first line here you
know does our software do what we want
it to do
and even if you don't have technical
expertise you can determine the answer
it's that question for the most part
you know you wanted to do something did
it do it Chrome with security software
is a real question there is does our
software not do what we want what we
don't want it to do I don't know how
much I screwed up but you see like the
whole thought process is very different
we're trying to say well what things
could have it had done that we wouldn't
want it to do ensure that actually does
just what we wanted to do it's a much
harder problem and it's also a problem
is very difficult for other people to go
figure out and you know sort of like I
mean I don't know if you've seen the
Simpsons one but sort of like the anti
Tiger Rock you know I claim I have this
rock and it keeps away Tigers well does
it keep way Tigers and do you see any
Tigers I know I guess those shirts are
kind of orange sort of like a tiger but
other than the orange sure it's like
it's doing a pretty good job keeping
Tiger was way in fact I claim that it
turned the Tigers into volunteers you
can't really disprove this right but you
know that the anti Tiger rock is even
better example this what we're really
concerned about in the security world is
the anti Tiger rock that was made by the
Pro Tiger foundation and inside the ng
Tiger rock happens to be a little
microphone and it's recording you know
all your conversations about Tigers and
uploading GPS coordinates to the roving
band of tigers are gonna go Maul you it
can get even worse than that because we
often have secure hardware you know and
security related stuff I mean I got that
in my little presenters gift basket
thing I guess you might have got one too
I've really I've never been here as a
normal person so I don't know what to
give to you guys but what's in that
thing
like and it's even worse because you
know I come here like I'm all you know
cool Peter Todd but well they know who I
am and they just gave me a bag with one
of those things in it like should I
really be plugging that into my laptop
while we're at it okay my bakes still
there well you know I used to be a
electronics designer so I figured I can
I can totally solve this one I got a
heavy object it smashed it open and I
held it up to the the window in my hotel
room and one of you guys is probably
gonna figure out which hotel room I have
but at least I'm leaving that tomorrow
and I happen to know that USB has four
wires two of them are signal two of them
are data well I see two wires going from
one end to the other and I see you one
kind of going a little circle there and
I happen to know or at least I think I
do that the signal wires are in the
middle and the data wires on the on the
outside pretty good right I thought was
good enough and now I know that my
laptop is separate from my phone you
know the other end of that cable going
off to my phone which is rather
important because I'll show you another
port there you know my uh my security
key but this thing 39 or 1394 it's
actually a firewire port which might
date my laptop back a couple years but
firewire is famous for having the
problem where anything connected your
firewire port could just download main
memory or right main memory to it really
whatever wanted so you know as silly as
this thing is it is actual real security
it did something it prevented something
from happening which was my phone
communicating my laptop and my laptop
communicating my phone you know that's
that's all good that's kind of useful
although there's kind of issue of I mean
I did all that but how do you know that
your little block USB condom actually
did something you don't at least you
know how to check it but me checking it
didn't directly help you in quite the
same way and you know I think I've seen
a lot of people making these kinds of
criticisms about the security of you
know Bitcoin and other software you know
your note is not a full note unless you
read the protocols back and write all
software yourself
cetera et cetera and you know the way I
like to refute this is to really talk
about whistleblowing when I go read the
protocol spec which in Bitcoin of course
is the source code as it is in any same
consensus
system I can go read it I can think
about it I can decide for myself did it
or didn't it work that's all well and
good for me but important thing is if I
do find something that's wrong I can
tell all of you guys and as long as you
guys are using the same software me and
noticing this is effectively
whistleblowing you know I am finding
something wrong and telling you guys you
can go make an informed decision whether
or not you'll still use the software now
there's a lot of caches here you know
for instance are you actually
downloading the same software as I am
you know are you actually using the same
versions and so on but in the big
picture this is a good idea you know
this is really one of the you know real
core things that make software different
from hardware and that if you have
software on hardware that secure the
software can be audited by others and
there are many processes place where you
can be sure that you're running the
right software and chances are if there
was something wrong with it someone
would notice you know the big picture is
all well and good but how does this
actually work in practice you know how
close are we to this ideal well I
decided to make a little program and
there you go I call it a hole your base
I'm not going to show every single
command i typed in but since you know
made my initial commit there that's your
that's in rust by the way yeah go rust
and it's a pretty cool thing right it
you know it tells a user of course that
they're securing the base because you
know you want to tell the user that
you're securing something so they think
it's secure and then you know here very
important it makes impossible to read
write or execute the base of course you
know you can't do that yeah just can't
get it and you know just to be clear
base security I'll check that all right
and you know you might go run that
command and you might wonder it was is
this really a good idea does this work
and let's go and have a hypothetical guy
which will call a good guy and oh yeah
there's yummy push and stuff you know
but
well if ignore that it's like it's not
too important but you know this is the
good guy right get clone he sees it up
on github and it is actually live by the
way you can go download this although uh
you might want wait slender to talk
before you run it and you know there's a
crest is very convenient you just do
cargo run you know compiles whatever
securing base based security done pretty
simple right well you know you might
want to double check what that actually
did and ah funny enough you know you
might have noticed well that command
thing like if I just say command new and
rust doesn't actually run the command
yeah that's what's called a builder kind
of builds when I'm about to do in memory
but to actually like run it I got to go
and do this you know output thing and
expects as well you know something
failed whatever and you know I'm mr.
good guy he figures well I mean I always
would go fix this so he adds a patch the
ID Etta commits it you know actually run
the process pretty a pretty good change
right and there we go so let's go assume
that you know you put a pull request up
on github
waited a bit I'm pretty fast so I you
know get back in a in a few minutes and
do get pull numerating whatever that are
etc all right well oh that's funny
there's a there's a readme file now and
there's a there's a main file with some
changes so you know I mean what actually
changed ah if you're trying to get lock
well Peter Todd merged remote tracking
branch you know actually run the process
looks pretty good right like a few guys
were arrested do you think at this point
it'd be safe to run the command alright
if you guys were arrested I'm not
watching this talk what do you think
would be safe to watch the command well
let's actually see what the file says
huh that's funny
cuz this here that's sort of the do
anything no matter what and I guess to
do anything a matter what said it do
anything where others oh that's funny
it looks like it's gonna make every
single fall my computer writable and
readable an executable and I don't know
I mean I got nothing against communism I
guess but you know I don't want to share
my follows with everyone so gee yeah
what went wrong here and I want to kind
of approach this at many many different
levels and maybe the very simplest level
is well why does this bug happen in the
first place you know like why why didn't
I allegedly at least assuming I'm a nice
guy write the code where in the first
place and if we go back a bit there you
go version one well people who use rust
will know that rust normally would go
tell you if you're creating something
that should be used
you know this whole bit of
misunderstanding but command ideally
you'd get a compiler error which
actually currently arrests doesn't
happen and which I should add a pull
request to this tonight but all right
that bit of ergonomics we could go fix
that and even then you know we we fixed
our root cause but what's the next thing
that went wrong you know what happened
next well where are we here you see this
commit in this commit in get you know
this is ultimately just a hash of all
the different files and all the history
and then this bit here this is serve
just a nice thing that's get basically
just showing you well you know what's
the difference between this and the
thing that came prior and unfortunately
get I don't think really a security in
mind because it doesn't show you what
actually changed here like remember if
you proposed some changes to me what
you're seeing here is
the difference in those changes but I
somehow have to go add those changes to
my repo and in my repo I added a readme
file all right so I have one set of
history you know you have another set of
history and I have to go merge them
together which means that the
differences are actually differences
between this and this and this and this
and the way it works is the
user-friendly thing of well assume that
whoever wrote this is a nice person and
just did the obvious thing which was
only do this changes if you actually
look at this commit and I didn't figure
out a way to actually show this on
screen but of course it doesn't actually
merge this it merges something totally
different and gets you I just don't show
this you know in a fortune I'm not very
surprised and I kind of thought of this
writing up this talk is you know could
this happen well sure enough it does but
you know it's not written by people I
think you have security in mind I mean
even fact that these are sha-1 hashes
like back in 2004 2005 whenever get was
made cryptographers were already warning
leanness shall one's not secure you know
and currently if you're clever and have
a bunch of money you can make collisions
to sha-1 hashes so that one hash could
be matched by multiple different files
yeah there's a lot of nuance it's
exactly what that statement means and so
on but long story short like it's not
really the right tools be using yet it's
sort of the only tool we have
but even if you solved say these
problems I mean there's still more that
can go wrong like for starters who
actually made that change
well alright in this talk obviously I
did probably but I'm gonna go claims you
guys you know I always try and give a
talk about how great kit was and I
didn't I didn't make that commit well
who might have well let's go back a bit
to ah there we go yeah right so I wrote
some code I committed it and then I
pushed it to github but what'swhat's
this actually saying here you know a
sent a host github can't be established
key fingerprint you wanna continue I
mean I know I do always type yes all
right how many you guys type yes
well yeah and nothing like in get
actually knew what computer I was really
talking to so it'd be quite plausible
for someone to man and middle attacked
me there you know I'm not Leslie gonna
notice that the code I wrote got changed
on github you know I'm I'm just doing
code locally and if I have more than one
computer Chancellor I'm gonna have
different repos there may be a little a
sink and I don't even I'll admit it's
pretty often I'll just type get pull
when I'm pretty sure I had my laptop was
up to date maybe maybe it was I don't
know I'll just type git pull and maybe
I'll just look at it with git log with
the patch thing see what emerged you
know these these problems exist in many
different layers and that's just not
secure but it's even worse than that
because alright let's suppose we fix
this let's suppose we you know made the
get thing have a hash of gets identity
or so on what did I do just prior to
that well I made some commits that's all
well and good I probably ran it at some
point
in fact the good guy also ran it and
where are we here we are
notice how he did run the code before he
actually like looked at it I mean that's
pretty easy mistake to make
again I'll admit even I wound up doing
this more than you know more than once
again and the moment you run that code
cargo could have done anything it could
have gone back toward get to go and
patch out you know these disks so you
wouldn't even see it
like anything at this point she's
totally untrusted really you know the
moment I ransom code from the source
that I'm trying to view it's over
but even if I looked at the code you
know all this projects doesn't have it
any sane projects is going to have
dependencies and it's pretty easy to go
have a complex project with a bunch of
dependencies and have the review
not review the dependencies you know
someone asked me to audit some source
code at some point I'm gonna go stop and
I personally know of an example list
which I ran into in practice which
course is the Z cash trusses setup and I
was asked by Zuko to be part of that as
he cashed trust it set up and I'm one of
what is it five people or seven people
or something who initially made those
secret keys essentially that get turned
into a public key that then makes all of
Z cash work and with Z cash if the
secret keys are compromised
you can go counterfeit Z cash currency
it will well G cash was pretty clever
about it they used something called
deterministic builds which they would go
and you know have a set of source code
and compile it in a way that someone
else could then rerun that whole code
chain rerun you know that compiler and
get the exact same output so then when I
did this trust setup I started off with
like everyone else did burns DVD
produced allegedly by this deterministic
build process and at the time my
thinking was well you know this is all
well and good I'll just you know get
this DVD
they say it's chairman state bill they
know where it's all coming from you know
etc of course I don't really know what
that software did but you can go out at
it and it's reasonable to audit the
dependencies a little back and then when
I actually looked at in detail pretty
but a year later I realized well the
term is to build was using like non
deterministic sources built you know two
days ago and no one can recreate them
and they knew at the time that this
whole thing was going to happen so in
fact anyone who ran the rust or had
access to the russ compiler the old
process could have back towards e cash
of course as it turns out z cash that
version zero also had a bug in it that
could inflate the currency undetectably
anyway so
didn't really matter so much but again
like kind of a problem there and then we
can also go ask come in all right this
all sounds totally broken well you know
do the usual big slide thing what went
wrong I think we know how do we fix this
well if you were in this position where
somehow this command suddenly went and
rewrote you know your whole file system
who would you blame I mean I did the
merge right well I mean that's not
signed so right there your average
project kind of kind of fails at this
and since this isn't signed I could just
as easily claim no no this whole SSH
business it really did happen you know
it's not my fault it's github fault or
some man and it'll attack well you know
in terms of how do we improve things
like step number one is actually be able
to assign some blame and figure out what
happened and you know my consulting
practice I wind up getting a lot of
clients who you know have databases of
things often the databases are internal
totally trusted sort of run by their
system ins and even I tell them you know
you really want to go out at a
blockchain to this and when I talk about
a blockchain I mean a chain of blocks I
mean a blockchain and cents get almost
is purely so that you can go figure out
which administer and made it to put in
valid data you know which computer got
compromised currently I can't really
figure out any of this because we don't
have any keys attached so how do we fix
this number one like actually start
signing some code I mean it seems silly
but people aren't doing this at all you
know outside of a few projects Bitcoin
core being one of the few few exceptions
and you know Bitcoin core every single
merge request is signed by someone and
there's a script
to actually verify that these signatures
are correct and from the approved list
in case you're wondering that's kind of
your answer to the question well who you
know who has push access to the github
repo in theory that that that's the
wrong question to ask the right question
to ask is who has a PGP keys on the list
of verified committers but again that's
all well and good you can go verify in
reality people aren't running you know
people aren't using the commands to
actually go and do this you know people
don't use git in a way where every time
you type git pull it actually checks
this so what can we fix this well
fortunately gotta go change how git
works you know we got a make it actually
check signatures on things and actually
have rules around this you know rest
itself it's heavily reliant on bots that
go build things why don't these bots
actually go sign the you know sign the
PGP port request that they make they
just don't yet github to the credit
actually does now with github when you
go and say edit a file within the github
web user interface the commits do get
signed so there's some traceability
there but for most part you know
projects don't do this and you know in
this example with cargo again the list
of cargo packages and the actual
dependencies and so on no one actually
signs them you know there's a github
repo on github of course with the entire
set of every single cargo package out
there and that at least you know again
like the rest is doing much better than
most projects on this but that at least
has hashes so you can say you know this
Russ library or create as they call them
actually match to this file but if that
if that list of all this isn't signed
again what actually went wrong when my
cargo downloads the wrong thing you know
I wouldn't even be surprised it doesn't
properly check you know certificates and
whatnot again something I can look into
but so much of this is broken they're
also why was it
that when I said cargo run it ran in
environments that could touch my source
code anyway in effect in this case I
mean there you go good guy at desktop is
that like his desktop where he has
access to every single thing on his
computer I could that of rate read his
email again developers tend to go run
their code in environments which access
to everything you know I at least that's
actually a cubes and that's at least
cubes virtual machine dedicated just her
restive element Oh frankly even I'm not
very good at this I mean I share that
across few different things you know we
need better tooling for all this and you
know I say all this but I think I'll
kind of close with given that we have
government's doing things like saying we
got it back to our crypto you know we're
an environment where we may have to even
do development anonymously Riley is
there a few projects have an honest
developers and all these issues become
even harder even when they're all fixed
when there isn't really someone to blame
you know we're probably not going to get
to the point where every single commits
reviewed properly you know every single
dependencies reviewed properly a lot of
this is still going to be about people's
reputations and I don't really know
what's going to happen if we've made
your projects with serious money behind
them to release serious consequence it's
like tor I mean you know people's lives
are at risk with tor
we're anonymous devs exist and we have
to figure out how do we review this
efficiently to get around the fact that
one of these devs doesn't really much
reputation to burn you know no one's I
mean no one goes to jail right now for
these kinds of bugs and no one's kind of
gonna do that in the future if we're
talking about a Bitcoin with a bunch of
pseudonyms behind it
like these are very real issues and it's
only going to get worse the threats only
get worse in the future so we need to
start solving this stuff now while it's
possible and also I think as paranoid as
this whole talk is part of what we also
need to solve is how do we do
elements and how do we run programs in a
way where for the stuff that doesn't
matter you know for your computer games
for your fun projects and so on none of
this stuff has to be done I should be
able to run some fun game on my computer
and not have to worry about it attacking
other things and if that's true at least
that side of the development doesn't
have to be so paranoid because the
reality is these kinds of processes
applied well are kind of toxic and I I
can't get away from that so you know I
think it's really up to the OS
developers to move beyond this and with
that thank you
Peter can you hear me yeah okay great
Peter thank you very much fair tolk I
mean I started to code in rest a few
months ago I totally fell in love with
this language so it's just amazing love
it and guys if you have any questions
raise your hand place and yeah great hi
thanks for the great talk I want to ask
were there any attacks that were done
because of militias that they were
caused by a malicious merge that you are
aware of that had the consequences I'm
not aware of any in to be honest I
Fraulein Oh may have found something
that hasn't actually noticed before
probably not but you know oh well there
you go I mean if you look at github the
git commits don't lie I did kind of rate
this that part of the talk about two
hours ago so but yeah I'm sure I would
not be surprised they're out there and
sounds like there's an example any other
questions
your hands yeah thanks Peter but it
seems that the rabbit hole goes even
deeper with the processor compiling the
code you can have backdoors in the Intel
processors so it wouldn't be enough just
to have a deterministic built I don't
know what would be enough I'm glad you
asked that question because I'm actually
a little more optimistic about that we
relative to most people I think you see
hardware is relatively limited in what
it can do you know strong AI does not
exist yet and if I'm using hardware that
was that came from the past prior to
when I wrote my stuff or at least
somewhat prior it's really really
difficult for hardware to know how to
back to our code written into the future
now there's exceptions this as an
example if I were his buddies would say
the guy who wrote the you know Intel
MINIX OS hiding around your your Intel
CPU maybe we could go work together to
go compromise something but it's much
harder than just you know it's
bugged merge request like it's it is a
risk don't get me wrong but I don't
think it's actually the biggest risk out
there and I think once we solve a lot of
these issues those kinds of problems
will not I mean a lot of stuff like it's
sort of like if you have a bunch of
problems and you go solve them the
hardest you know the easiest ones for
the hardest ones sometimes you just go
find out the attackers just keep on
moving on to one you know one after
another you know some cryptocurrencies
have this kind of issue where they keep
on trying to add complexity to the tax
and the complexity is just a trivial
thing to fix I think the complexity of
building backdoors that really survive
multiple revisions of software is very
hard you know this is why with rust for
example I don't think it's that likely
for the rest compiler to be backdoored
in the sense that the people compiling
rest an iterative process would have
likely gone and you know ran into this I
do think it's fairly likely that say Z
cache could have because the situation's
a little different with Z cache it was
something it was a known target at the
time whereas with rust if I go back you
know 10 years and start compiling
compilers it's not that likely that bugs
gonna affect something now but you know
in theory it could and I think the best
thing we can do there is do you try to
get more cross compilers I mean there's
a project written in C++ that can
actually compile rust and the clever
thing does it turns off the borrow
checker so it doesn't actually check the
codes perfectly correct but it's still
enough to get it compiled and more
people should work on that stuff and
also go plug my own project open
timestamps which quite simply proves
data exists in the past if it exists in
the past you need time-travel to go and
change it or you do the attack in the
past well very frequently you can rule
out the attack now you know and you can
go show by the fact that that timestamp
exists when you know when your window
vulnerability was and how unlikely it
was so definitely something to think
about and instantly Bitcoin core a bunch
of the people with merge access some you
know with that with those public keys do
in fact timestamp every single commit
don't be shy okay maybe I have a last
question so you mentioned that you
develop in a different environment so
what kind of virtualization do you use
or maybe some container or Alex C or
something well so for my desktop machine
specifically our cubes another yeah and
cubes is kind of nice cuz it it's
designed around different realms which
are different virtual machines and on
top of that it makes it fairly easy but
also you know has good security for
moving data around from one virtual
machine to another and it's actual you
know proper like hardware level
virtualization it's not you know some of
the Linux container stuff it's always a
little dubious but you know is it
perfect - no but I think it definitely
reduces the chance of someone sneaking
in a you know get commits into one of my
projects and reading my mail and I do
think we need to do better I mean we you
know someone needs to go write a plug in
the car go to fire up a virtual machine
when you compile a project and you know
copy your code over and actually do all
of the compiling somewhere other than
where you're editing but you know at
least with cubes we've kind of got some
of this soft and instantly if you want
to do that project two cubes does have
by adidas disposable virtual machines
which are relatively quickly too quick
to fire up so you could fire from a
virtual machine move the code and do the
compliation and maybe keep it around to
going do changes but you know someone's
got to write it okay thank you very much
Pro answer how dare any last questions
oh we get wanna light
thanks for the talk Peter one of the
challenges to some of this tooling seems
to be like economic incentives like it's
hard to productize them like you know
whether you can like do work on it and
then I sell it in earn money um
I wonder if you had any thoughts of how
that like how that problem can be solved
so more people can afford to spend time
I'm like making better tooling I'm sort
of solving some of these problems you
know I wish had good answers to that but
I think this is sort of broader open
source problem where you know in general
how do you get funding to go do things
there the public good and I think you're
quite right so I mean I'm especially
with an example of github where some of
these issues are service rated by how
it's much you make much more money by
running a trusted service that people
pay a subscription to you know maybe for
some of this stuff what we need is
closed source software or at least
software with the code available but
you're stupid you know it's still not
released under open source license and
you go pay for copy but I think the
bigger issue you may even be ignoring
that how do you actually get dibs to use
this stuff you know we like it's easy to
go sign and get commits install PGP and
you know you set up some stuff and it
just works
I mean I've signed get commits for years
I figured out how to do that probably
back in what 1999 or something like it's
it's not that hard but so many people
don't do it the tooling exists for that
we don't really need more that we these
tweaks to it but you know to at least
make an improvement it's all you know
everything's already there it's just how
do you get devs to actually do it and
unfortunately I you know after the talks
like this like I don't see good ways to
do this and you know maybe some of the
lawyers in the room might start singing
like liability law and stuff which is an
ugly tool to have to use but you know
maybe that's the sort of thing you need
I mean I I used to work in you know
electronics engineering and I'll make
the point then Canada of course I
couldn't call myself an engineer because
that's protected title if you actually
call your
an engineer you know you're filing off
paperwork where you're testing to the
safety of something with your future on
the line you know if we regulate a
software that way yeah probably some of
these problems would go away but it's
not really something I think many of us
want to do and maybe that's sort of part
of our incentive there if we don't do
this we don't fix these issues we might
see engineering like regulations and
well what does engineering like
regulations come with I'm sure it'll
look like a lot of other engineering
where it's a bit more of a closed system
many have to go pass the right courses
get the right certifications to go work
in the field you know if we don't solve
these kinds of problems maybe that's
actually where things are going to go I
think more likely I mean even
engineering world had it developed now
it might be actually much more corporate
thing with only a couple companies even
allowed to do engineering
and at least engineering is democratized
in the sense that anyone who goes
through the right process can get their
stamp it still could be a lot worse than
that
but I know maybe that's enough incentive
for people I just wish I had a good
answer and add two questions come on way
I still time oh there's one
Franco great talk I think the signing of
comments is necessary because do you
know would do or get blamed someone else
basically you can say like Linus
Torvalds
may twist commit and they will push it
very positive because github is using
some meta meta data from commit and it
will show that he pushed bad comment but
it's not true yeah well it's interesting
and all off to give credit to github for
this at least in there you is they the
notion of verified commits on the
website so if you sign a commit with PGP
key that you've associated with your
accounts it will actually show off with
a little green checkmark in a way that
won't happen if I just change the
metadata but that's a trusted system
where I'm actually trusting github to go
do all that and I don't actually know if
they've done it I would also remind the
project from Frank Brown and sperg Lara
they present it last year goat goat
chain I think yeah and do you think that
maybe the answer is some vote system for
developers so we will let's say I trust
this developer it has two beasts one and
it will calculate the score of a project
trust less of a project well you know my
suspicions with other stuff is most of
the problem is really just adding a bit
of crypto to it so we can have some
accountability figure out what happened
when something went wrong you know my my
suspicion is again I'll kind of go back
to sort of whistleblowing concept is
that what's most important is to make
the attacks easily detectable and make
sure the tax or things that happen to
all of us rather none of us and you know
I didn't use this term but certificate
transparency has revolutionized the web
certificate business and well what is
significant transparency is basically a
thing that means that when I go login
you know to my bank
on my web browser on my device that I
know that the certificate that's
presented to me by the other serve
server would have been known to the SIS
admin's of the bank and I'll say them a
little more precisely so without
certificate transparency I have a chain
of certificates from a root of trust you
know set of entities that I just
unconditionally trust that claim to go
sign certificates that's claimed to be
for my bank what certificate
transparency does is adds a step where
that first sort of linkage and ensures
that those chief gates were published in
a widely visible database called a
certificate transparency lock or as I
would call it a block chain the people
buying certificate transparency hate
that term but yeah that's ultimately
what it is and you know Bakhtin's but
making something publicly visible and
easy to ensure that other people could
have seen the same thing well because
that happens I now know that assisted
means at my bank can check those logs
and look for certificates issued that
they didn't want issued now it doesn't
directly help me but it does mean that
the syph get authorities who have this
you know have this role as a route of
trust that now they have a disincentive
to abuse it because they won't get
caught and there's quite a few stiff
good authorities who CT has essentially
shut down their businesses because their
attacks got easily detected and they
were d trusted you know we need to the
same thing with software and my
suspicion is if we do these things what
we're actually gonna find is that things
like adding you know web of trusts and
trying to have developers out tree
though other and so on yes it will still
be useful in higher security things but
I suspect that by itself will be enough
to make most of these attacks go away
although unfortunately the other side of
it then is sort of social thing it's
kind of fun to be part of a web of trust
to be vouched for by other devout divs
you know the fact that this stuff's kind
of
doesn't need these sort of second layers
may actually hinder progress on getting
stuff implemented so maybe we need to go
push that just to somehow gamify it if
you will and get more devs doing these
things I don't quite know the right
answers there but you know I certainly
at least technically know all right
least I know at a technical level the
sort of measures that could catch a lot
of these attacks hi Peter
thanks for the talk I have a question
it's regarding the spam attack that open
PGP repository had during June basically
they could keep like all the certificate
certificate it's there I wonder if maybe
using a blockchain not sure if Bitcoin
or any other secure enough we can like
this miss that a spam attack because you
need to spend money in fees I mean you
certainly could do that we certainly
could make adding a signature you know
and maybe I'll explain so what that spam
attack was was Chris PGP does have that
web of trust you can essentially vote
for other people and the way PGP works
is there sir centralized databases and
centralize the sense that any you know a
small number of people run these but
anyone can go run their own and make
copy of it that go passed around these
signatures vote you know these vouches
from one person to another and the way
PGP tooling works by default is it just
downloads the full set so if you go and
add a signature to my key the tooling
will download that signature even though
I never actually approved it and there's
some reasons why you want that such as
you know I want to you know if I'm a
peach peas or I want to go learn but all
the signatures I don't want to have a
manual you know approval attempt and so
on so certainly if you kept that model
you could use things like Bitcoin to
make it expensive to spam and that would
probably solve most problems but also
point out you can also solve a lot of
problems just having people vouch for
their for the signatures from other
people on their keys essentially an
approval process you know why should you
be able to add data in my key without me
proving PGP could easily fix this except
for the fact that PGP is a widespread
protocol the tooling is kind of crufty
and so on you know this is again when
these hard problems and unfortunately I
think I've seen a lot in the security
world people not only really hating PGP
but really hating on PGP without any
recognition of what it is good for or
how you would get alternatives and
improvements and I see very few people
actually interested in replacing PGP you
know we don't need to get rid of PHP we
have to replace it because we are
dependent on it security guarantees you
know we don't use it as much as we
should but like it is kind of our last
line of defense against a lot of these
central centralized attacks by
centralized attackers so we have to
replace it you know we have to make that
ecosystem work again what's the right
way to do that well you probably give
ten more talks on this but it doesn't
need to be done and it's not enough to
just ditch it and it is ok to if each
piece replaced by something that only
devs use you know this whole bits of
like everyone's you know pet gorilla
needs to be able to go use PGP is I
think a narrative pushed by people who
may have bad incentives here and don't
want us using security you know secure
tools we need to look at this saying
while you guys are professionals you
people are developers if you want to
participate in these ecosystems of
security sensitive software here's some
of your minimal requirements and the
minimum requirement might be using PGP
version 2 which might you know did some
of this stuff improve on other stuff but
the port of thing is somewhere you are
getting a signature there so yes I think
this is fixable and you know blockchain
might be a part of that if thank you
very much for your talk for s first
thank you guys for coming to this talk
you