rectangle attacks
um
in this session we have two talks
the first talk is a new Properties or
double boomerang inactivity table
the authors are changing
situation dampage label the speaker is
welcome
hello everyone my name is I come from
Institute of information engineering
I appreciate this opportunity to make
the presentation
[Music]
there are five parts in my presentation
the first one is the preliminary
it is known that Boomerang attack is one
variant of differentials and
differential attacks and the aim of it
is to construct a long differential by
using two short ones with high
probability and there is assumption that
the two trails are independent
then researchers focus on the dependency
between the differentials the sandwich
attack was proposed some which attacker
divided the suffering to three parts e0
em and E1 sandwich attack has all the
dependency in the middle part em
now let's review some definitions used
in Boomer attack
dtgs usually used in differential
attacks
dttr1 F2 means the number of the pairs
satisfying the conditions that the input
difference is Alpha one before the Xbox
and the output difference is after 2
after the Xbox
PCT is the Boomer connectivity table and
the BCT up one beta2 is the number of
the cortex satisfying the conditions
that the input difference in the
occupies is after one before the Xbox
and the output difference is beta 2 in
the lower path after the Xbox
compared with VCT the ubct as one
condition in the Upper price
everyone Alpha 2 Beta 2 satisfying and
three conditions
similarly lpct the lower pctm it is the
number of the quotas satisfying three
conditions that there is one condition
in a lower path
EBC ta is the extended BCT it is the
number of the quarters satisfying the
four conditions
so are they suitable set for one Xbox
informal attack in the yam there are
always some rounds so how about two
continuous Xbox or three or two
continuous Xbox systems
first we give the definition about the
double Boomer connectivity table so look
at the figure F R1 and Alpha 2 are the
differences in the Upper price for the
second for the first Xbox and the beta2
and the bit 3 are the differences for
the second Xbox in the lower path a dpct
F1 beta 3 is equal to the sum of the
lower dbct other one of two beta 2 and
beta 3 where the lower ddct is equal to
the upct times the UB City for the first
Xbox and the times the LBC for the
second Xbox
from some DB City we find that
for all Xboxes non-zero dpct occurs
mainly when Alpha 2 is equal to beta2
that is in the DBC tier there are mainly
Lander switch and Xbox switch
especially for some Xbox
there are only land switch and Xbox
switch
that is for all F1 and B3 DB this
equation is true and from the equation
we can obtain a relationship between DBC
and DDT and it also reduce the time
complexity for DB City from for definite
Dimensions to three dimensions
such as the Xbox of
present AIR block mips and a twin or
this Xbox are hard and for others such
as craft skinny project camera they are
General Xbox
some extensions of the property
the first one is the further for a hard
Xbox not only the dbct but also tdct uh
the equation is always true so for tpctm
there is always a relationship between
the tbcd and the DDT
the second one is we catch some property
about the block surface with complex
linear layer such as ES
table shows the number of actions for
each for each value for the DBC T
actually use the AES and the basic DBC
team for the yes
from the table we can find that the
basic deficit here the XBox server is is
hard without zero values and DBC here IG
with the complex linear most values are
zero this point observes our attentions
now let's see some application of the
new property
the first one the through the same
Boomerang distinguisher with a different
text box how DBC uniformity and the hard
Xbox matter we take the seven round
distinguisher of craft as an example
this table shows the property of the
distinguisher with the different text
boxes
from the table we can find that craft
and the present share the same DDT and
the BCT but the present has a better
vbct than craft and the Xbox of presence
is hard the result is that the presence
has a lower probability than crafted
camera has a better visit here than
present but present with a smaller PPC
here and
the Xbox of Commerce General the result
is that the presence has a lower
probability
these three Xboxes share the same DDT
BCT and the DBC team and all of the all
of them are hard so the result is that
they have almost the same probability
I'm the smallest obesity and the
smallest dbcg and both the Xbox of them
are hardened
uh the reality that they have the lowest
probability
from these observations we found that
apart from the uniformity of ECT and the
DDT the uniformity of DB cities is a new
major Criterion to evaluate the
performance of Xbox
and the second application that for the
AES the DB city was complex linearly has
too many zero values
inspired by this way we compute some
distinguishers
with about the block servers based on
AES such as three as under directors
yeah
we found that three distinguishers of
them
have zero probability
so
that is for a hard as box with a complex
linear layer should be treated carefully
the
um I'll give the a map module to search
for the boom range with the Clusters
cluster probability briefly
in the previous works there are always
two steps to search for the boomerang
distinguisher step one is to search for
good transcripted booming characteristic
with the least active expenses and step
two is to search for the best
institutions
in our work way
give a formula for the probability of
clusters firstly and then give and a new
map model to search for good clusters
directly
in e0
or in E1 we use the numbers of cells
which needs to be Zero from uniformity
to describe the probability
cm to describe the probability where cm
is the sum of the number of seals which
needs to be Zero from uniformity the U
the number of
uddt2 and lddt2 the number of mpct and
the number of visit here
for example use our formula we can give
the conditions for the 13 Rounds the
distinguisher of craft
indicate that the conditions are closely
related to the actual probability
then
for the MLP model we give some rules
about the attribute attribute
propagations
through these operations such as suffice
the actual operation and the rule of
modding of a modding modeling of the
table and the modeling of the upper and
the lower boundary
the objective function is to minimize
the number of conditions
and using and we use the new Pro new MLP
model with
two
Neo Boomerang distinguishers of The
Craft with a higher probability than
before
uh now this is the conclusion
um as far as the way and give some
properties of dbct such as the lender
switch and Xbox switch happen in most
cases for all Xboxes and uh first
um had Xbox only the lender switch and
the Xbox switch are possible
that these properties has that the dbct
is important to evaluate the performance
of Xbox and hard as the box with a
complex linear layer should be treated
carefully
the second way
give give an image model
to search for the Clusters at first we
give a formula for the properties for
for the probability of clusters and then
we give the model with the cluster
probability
thank you for your attention
that's all
thanks
any questions
I have a question
a
on Pittston
on page 10.
I wonder if it's possible that uh
Alpha 2 on the left
can be different from the other two
other
writer
there's either either the middle part of
the picture
and at the same time the
better to
can be different from the Earth to
the beta 2 in front can be different
from the better to
impact yeah yeah but there is the
assumption that the two
uh the opposite sides are equal
to can
they are not
uh it actually uh better to and and
better too
yeah yeah
uh
is not equal to bet3pm
but in our work we have the assumption
that the two sides are equal
okay okay
thank you
thanks
on page 26 uh
um three years and the Deoxys are OAS
like suffers so I would like to know
um besides as long suffers that's
incompatibility exist in other servers
uh yes it is possible
for these Xboxes with the
property the
it is maybe for others block servers
okay thank you
hi
thank you for your presentation I was
wondering did you try to use the milk on
skinny
that seem a similar MLP model
and skinny
ah
I'm sorry button
did you try to use the milp on skinny oh
yeah yeah I I have a tried to
application apply the model to skinny
but the results in that way it didn't
have the
more
more lower probability
so we we didn't show this result
okay thank you and on craft more than 10
rounds
did you find any distinguisher or was it
the same done in the literature
wow
did you apply it and craft more than 10
rounds because I you have yeah yeah we
have a
uh yeah uh we have tried to uh try to
applying the model to the distinguisher
more than 10 rounds but it's also we get
we didn't look at the good results
yeah thank you very much
thank you
oh hello
in my understanding that the safety has
a strong connection with a linear layer
in Cipher and the biased suitable
situation I think is the if if the
linear layer is a binary Matrix but for
the bitwise commutation and and even the
mdis Matrix
I want to know that what's the advantage
of the DB City over the BCT UBC LP
safety framework thank you
uh firstly for the Xbox tpct is
is equal to upct times lbct and there
are four Diamond Dimensions but uh
there is a but we can use DDT to compute
dbct with only three dimensions so the
first it can reduce the time complexity
and
for General Xbox system
the the
equation is always true so
enter
in DBC TN
the lower DB City occurs mainly when
Alpha 2 is equal to beta2 so we can use
we can also use DDT to replace BBC TN
with some
um
if in uh
in many distinguishers the computers
very complexities so
sometimes it may
we sometimes it is true it is too huge
to compute the uh the probabilities so
maybe use the DDT to replace DB City now
we can get the probability
um
in a short term
under the the hard Xbox assumption
yeah
okay and the next question is
I will try to consider the
DB City while the entry value in the MLP
model or even the
a specific value of the deposition
and because I noticed that the MLP model
you present that only focus on the
Obesity obesity and our utdt yeah
uh
[Music]
the MB City include includes the DBC TM
and
um
in our
in our MRP model
okay and the last question is
is there any connection between the
boundary of AI and the
DB City and on the maximum maximum
number of T in the PCP
sorry
I want to know it's there and a
connection between the
boundary of aim and the maximum number
of the typicity of uh
specifics
staffer
uh
yeah
for the
for our hardest box the TBC team this
formula is always true we can use we can
also use DDT to replace the TBC TBC TN
okay thank you
okay
I think we don't care attempt for for
other questions uh thanks attention for
the talk uh let's have the next talk
thank you
um
uh the next talk is that 80 automatic
search of Pokemon distinguishers for ARX
servers the author said that whole one
uh one situation although the speaker is
welcome yes
feature
[Music]
record
um anyways
hi everyone my name is my report is
about saturated automatic search of
Boomerang distinguishers for AI ciphers
this is a joint work with one about time
and since the way
uh Boomerang Crypt analysis is a
technique to connect to a short
differential characteristics to form a
new distinguisher covering more rounds
the whole cycle is separated into two
parts for each part a differential
characteristic is applied then under an
independence assumption these two
characteristics can be connected like
this figure
then however previous work found that
this assumption may not always fold and
several techniques were proposed to fix
this problem
one of them is the sandwich framework
like this figure in the middle a new
part is separated out for the switch and
denoted by em uh special cryptanalysis
is put on this part to analyze the
connectivity of the characteristics
typically the crypto analysis on em is
reduced to that on the nonlinear
operations
for SPN ciphers it is reduced to the
crypto analysis on the Xbox
as this as this scenario
since the Xbox
is typically small we can enumerate all
of its inputs and the result is a new
table called Boomerang connectivity
table
in 2020 researchers found that we still
need more variants of the BCT which are
the ubct lbct and the ebct
I'm until now the crypto analysis on
Xbox's coverage but what about the
what about the boomerang activity table
on the other nonlinear operations in
particular we are talking we are
thinking about the BCT on the modular
Edition
to the best of our knowledge there is
only one previous result
but the definition of these VCT is given
without many details and it it is also
claimed that the difference number uh it
is the one below the figure it is
claimed that this difference must be
zero but however in our work we found we
noticed that if we view the modular
addition as a special Xbox like this red
equation
uh all the previous techniques on Xboxes
can be applied here and the formula is
as below
uh you may see that this formula depicts
a very large BCT it has four dimensions
with each Dimension has size
um maybe 16 bits 24 bits or 32 bits
so to compute Computing the whole BCT
it would be impractical and sometimes
infeasible
so we are thinking about is there a fast
method to compute one arbitrary entry in
this BCT if so can we construct same
models for it and furthermore are there
any new results on the AI ciphers
based on this motivation our
contribution separated into three parts
first we design dynamic programming
algorithm to compute to efficiently
compute the tables
second we constructed models for these
tables and finally we tag specially as
examples and improve the previous
results
okay let me introduce the computation of
the BCT during the computation there are
two important equations here
they are they depicts the relation
between the modular addition and the xoi
operation
here I want you to focus on the
recursive definition of the carry
function
for example the C the carry 0 the ice
speed of C only depends on the previous
speeds on X Y and C so does B this is it
is is an important property for our
algorithm
with these two equations we can
we can rewrite the definition of the
Obesity into a
a much simpler form
with this new definition we have two
observations the first observation is
that every every this equation is a
restriction on the I minus one state of
L and R but what about the M minus one
speed of ion r the answer is they can
take arbitrary values because this is
the only restriction derived from the
definition
the second observation is that the four
bit string can only take a possible
values here I concatenate for
carry bits into a for hobby string
based on these observations we can
partition the BC the definition of the
BCT into several subsets uh by the
values of the bits of lnr and these four
B strings since every values of the bits
of the LR is are valid so we can sum up
all of the cases into a new form
here we did not here we Define the new
function f to represent the rightmost
part
because the original part is too
complicated
okay now our goal turns into how to
compute the function f
a trivial idea is to partition the
function f Again
by these variables but these times we we
notice that some of the values of uh the
M minus two feet of L and R uh could be
invalid so we Define the new function G
to denote whether the chosen value of
these two bits are valid or not with the
function G we can continue to sum up all
of the cases
and now the computation becomes this uh
again we Define a new function T to
represent the summation of the function
G
here I want to know that the function
function P can be pre-computed because
its input is only two four bit string
and another for big values
and you can see again we have a
recursive definition of the function f
and this is very perfect for a dynamic
programming algorithm if you are not
familiar with this kind of pro this kind
of algorithm you may think about the
computation of the Fibonacci theories
the computation of the same
before showing the our algorithm I want
to know another
important property we found
it is a symmetry in the computation
this symmetry helps to reduce the time
complexity of our algorithm
okay here comes our algorithm line a is
conforms to the summation in our formula
and then we found a way to booleanize
this algorithm by uh if if the value of
T is non-zero then we Define a new
variable TB to be in one if the value of
T is zero then we set a zero value TB
with this modification we we obtained a
new computation of f as the below one
uh this equation contains only Boolean
operations and this equation can check
whether F whether the function f is
non-zero or not
based on this new computation we
multiplied our algorithm you can see the
line eight light also conforms to
to the max operation in this formula
this algorithm is able to check whether
the BCT entry is non-zero or not this is
our first step into booleanize the
computation and Boolean booleanization
is important for set models
furthermore we want to control the
computation folder we found another
important observation
for all you in this set if the value of
T is not uh or non-zero then we have
another recursive definition of the
summation or function f
please remember that the computational
BCT is also the summation of function f
So based on this observation we derive a
heuristic check
I call it partial obesity if k out of n
minus 1 these equations are required to
be satisfied the resulting BCT entry
would be 4 to the power of K plus 1
times a number q that is we just Express
uh this red sentence as Boolean
expressions
a k of term
this idea comes from the partial DDT by
the previous work
with uh the this partial BCP we are
expecting uh cancel out the small values
in the BCT and obtain a size reduce BCT
However the fact is that currently we
lack enough knowledge about the number
two second the resulting partial obesity
still contains still contains small
entries
but luckily our experiments show that
the model always returns BCT entries
with value around 4 to the power of K
plus one this is enough for us to
construct the assets models
Here Comes our complete model uh based
on this based on the previous algorithm
we model line 8 as the first of first
Boolean expression
for line 10 to 13 we create another
Boolean operation or Boolean expression
and heuristic trick is applied to the
first Boolean Boolean expression
uh I want to know that our model cannot
return the the exact value of this entry
it can only select arbitrary entry in
the BCT so previous the previous
searching model cannot apply it here so
we have to come up with another
new Frameworks searching framework
our first framework is
um our first frame will aims to file
aims to find Boomerang characteristics
with high probability
we treat we just tweaked the thresholds
in switch in the switch that is the size
of the partial obesity and then search
the characteristic until we found the
desired characteristic this framework is
passed but maybe some better
characteristics
our second framework is quite
complicated we first set a threshold to
zero that is we consider the whole
obesity
and then we found the upper bound of the
probability of the boomerang
characteristics then we treat the
threshold again and this time we also
treat the upper bound of the probability
then we enumerate all the
characteristics and how the number of
the characteristics then we return the
largest cluster as the result
due to the enumeration this framework is
this framework is slow but can take the
advantages of the clustering effects
this is our results
we found
current best boomerang distinguisher on
spec 32 and spec 48 we also fixed the
previous probability estimate estimation
of Lee
uh you can see in this table five uh ax
Tools return the precise result in a
very short time much faster 10 hours
so we do a comparison
uh the first result is that you may
think that our algorithm is very similar
to the AIX tools but they are in fact
constructed from two different
perspectives our perspective reviews
more mathematical properties behind the
modular Edition which are not published
before
as
you have already seen AI tools is faster
and more precise
and finally also the most important
thing is that our technique is capable
of searching characteristics while ai's
tools cannot
okay let me do a conclusion uh our in
this work we accomplish three results
the
um efficient algorithm the set models
for this table and new results on these
two ciphers but there are also some
limitations on our technique
the first one is the the current
computation of the tables are not quite
convenient and not very convenient to be
modeled
if you look into my code you will find
that our you can find our model is quite
large
so uh the current models for the switch
are too large if we want to search uh
the some some complicated Cipher the
model May would be invisible and third
the optimal distinguisher are still
unknown because our technique is a
heuristic technique
and finally comparing with ai's tools
our computation of the probabilities are
slow
all the codes are publicly available at
my GitHub repository you can download
the code here
thank you very much for your attention
I think we didn't have them for further
questions thanks dash one for the nest
talk
the standard sessions
foreign