session of today and we have another
session of boomerang and rectangle's
attack
with two nice papers so the first paper
is automatic search of rectangle attacks
on Facebook ciphers application to warp
by if your
engineer and Lloyd croquette and loik
will give a talk
thank you for the introduction
so today I will speak about our new
model to compute rectangle attacks on
Facebook ciphers
so in the first part I will shortly
introduce differential crypto analysis
and boommark attacks then I will speak
about our new model to compute rectangle
attacks and I will finish with a
conclusion
so what is the differential Crypt
analysis so the the
method to compute distinguishers in a
differential Crypt analysis is to have a
plain text P1 to Cipher it with an
encryption function EK and give us a
cipher C1 then we choose a second plain
text P2 which is the result of p1xr an
input difference Delta p we say for it
also to obtain a C2 and our objective is
to compute what is the probability to
obtain the output differences the Delta
C knowing that we have an input a
different data B
so a variant of this model was uh was
designed by by Wagner which is a
boomerang attacks in the case of Boom
brung we do not want to compute the
probability to have a difference from
alpha to Beta but to have a difference
from Alpha
and then we put an output different
Delta and we want to compute the
probability that the
decipher of the two uh the two pairs of
the pairs C3 and C4s go back to Alpha
so to compute the to compute it we
we separate the cipher into a two-step
function which are e0k and e1k and we
compute one apartheid we go from alpha
to Beta and one lower Trace
we choose a Lambda and the Delta as a
differences
one variant of this attack is a
rectangle attacks instead of using a
ciphering and deciphering we always use
a save first ciphering functions
the problem with this representation in
two trays is that they can be uh have
incompatibilities between the
differences that are in the middle of
the distinguisher
so sometimes we can have a better
probability and sometimes we can have a
worse probability than expected
so to Contour this drawback the sandwich
attack was introduced and then we can
compute the probability of the full
Boombox distinguisher by Computing the
probability of the upper trailer
distinguishers so the probability to go
from alpha to Beta
then we compute the probability of the
middle ones which go from a beta to
lulanda and that go back to Beta And we
compute the probability of the lower
part which is from Lambda to the delta
then we can compute the overall
probability by uh multiplying the
probability of each part
the problem with this representation is
that the attacker needs to uh to
indicate of to cut the cipher into the
three parts so uh the learn and the
quarters introduce a new kind of model
that allow to compute the overall
probability without selecting the runs
which belong to the upper to the middle
and to the lower part
the model of
of the Run encoders work in two steps
and we are we need to add one more step
which is a key recovery to compute the
attack complexity
so in the first step they compute the
truncated Defensor characteristic which
is an abstraction of the problem
and in the second step for each
Tranquility differential Boomerang they
compute the instantiation of this
truncated Boomerang and that give that
gives the
manga probability once we have the woman
distinguisher probability we can make
compute clustering analysis to refine
the probability of the distinguisher and
we need to add one key recovery part to
uh to be able to complete the attack
complexity
so in the model of the run and quotas uh
one woman transition is represented by
the following variables so we have uh
four uh differences which are alpha
along the beta and Delta
and we have two trays which are
represented as encryption and decryption
so in the encryption uh in the
encryption phase we have three variables
so a big data indicates if the
transition is active or not
3x and the 3sb indicates if the input
differences or the output differences of
the transition need to be fixed or need
to be known to to compute the the
distinguishable probability
we have the same variables but for the
lowercase which are a free x low a big
Delta low and the first below
the problem is that the model of dolon
and Al was designed to be used on the
face on SPN ciphers and was applied to
skinny but we want to use it to uh to be
able to compute a boom long
distinguisher on phase State Network
so in the case of SPN ciphers when we
want to decipher the the messages we
need to inverse if each set function of
the ciphers but in the case of the
faceted networks we always use the same
encryption function we only inverse the
the branches between the third part of
the ciphers and then this change as a
kind of boomerang transitions that we
are able to use
so on the left we have the boom one
connectivity table that was designed for
SPN ciphers and on the right you have a
face type woman connectivity tables that
are used that were designed for faceted
Networks
so you can see that only on the left you
can Define one
one probability that use only Alpha and
the Delta as a parameters
but if you are on the right as you only
use a s box in uh directed Direction
you can be able to compute the
probability uh from Alpha and Lambda but
you can not use you cannot compute
probability that go from alpha to Beta
and go back to Alpha so we need to use a
different uh transitions that uh
then that was the defend for SPN
so we change the rules that were
designed in the model of the run and L
to match the SPN transition and we adapt
them to only use uh as boxes in forward
Direction and that give us the new rules
that are defined on the right and that
are the rules that are
um designed to match the facetail
conditions
now I will speak about our new model
that was applied to up so what what was
presented as at SEC 2020 by your bank
and quotas it was designed to be a
compact our implementation
and uh you have the description on the
safer just here so for each round you
have one Xbox function and we add a
xor between the state and the k
then we Excel the two branches and for
some branches you add one constant for
each round
so uh for our model we have the same
Boomerang representation that was done
by the model of dulon and quarters and
we have the same search steps but we
have some differences we add some
optimization uh that was dedicated to
app to improve the computation process
and if we change the s-box
representation so we change the S blocks
rules and as the transition tables to
merge phase tail networks on the same
tables and we also integrate Jack laser
attack complexity in the optimal
optimization process
so um how to compute the attack
complexity uh we need to add some rounds
before and after our distinguisher to
conclude the attack complexity
and for in the case of the attack of the
zero and the quarters you have the two
predominant term of the data complexity
that are just here
so the first parameter of this uh two
equations are s which is the number of
quartets that are required to match the
Boom distinguisher
we also have n which is the number of
bits of the block of the ciphers
we have NB uh ND and NF that uh that can
be computed as the number of runs that
are added before the distinguisher the
number of front of the distinguishers
and the number of funds that are added
after the distinguisher
P Square Q square and error are the
probability of our bong distinguishers
and you can compute also a MB which is
the number of bits which need to be
guessed in the K and RF which is the
number of bits of the ciphertext
which is active which are active
so um we can directly integrate this
kind of equation in the model to
optimize the overall time complexity
instead instead of
improving only the distinguisher
probability
so our new model works with these steps
so in the first step we compute
the the abstraction of our attack
complexity so it is an approximation and
in the second step we improve our result
and we are we ensure that the attack
complexity given in the Second Step will
be the best attack complexity that is a
uh that is computable by our model and
we can add some clustering analysis to
refine the distinguisher probability and
to improve the accuracy of our attack
complexity
so now I will show some results on the
web so to compute the distinguisher on
work we have the following results
so until 22 runs we can compute the
distinguisher probability in less than
uh two days
but the number of days the time grows
exponentially when we add some runs but
we see that for 23 runs the
distinguisher is not usable in practice
in the attacks
have a complexity Ayers and the excess
exhaustive key search
we also test the accuracy of our model
by uh evaluating
experimentalized distinguisher
probability of our model so in the model
currents you have the probability that
was that was computed by our model and
on the experimental column you have the
the experimental evaluation of our
distinguishers
and you see that we have a very close
results but the more we add the rounds
as the biggest the gap between our model
approximation and the experimentary
evaluation uh increased
so this model allows us to find a new
Boombox distinguisher on the 23 runs
this Boombox distinguisher was beaten by
the model of adipo which was uh
presented uh just after this session
and we compute we are also able to
compute why new uh rectangle attacks on
26 round of work
we also apply our model to Twain and L
block s and uh Portland and blue case we
find a closed state to the art
distinguishers
to conclude we provide a new automatic
tool to compute the rectangle attacks as
can be easily adapted to uh over a face
Networks
the model can be overtaken by the model
of adipo when the clustering effect is
important
but even if we made a concession of a
distinguisher probability we can obtain
a better attacks than only optimizing a
distinguisher probability
that's all thank you for your attention
thank you loik we will take some
questions do you have questions in the
room in Kobe
yes
hi Luke thanks for your presentation
would you please tell us about the
running time for of your tool to find a
23 round distinguisher for war just the
distinguish another whole attack what
can you repeat yeah the running time
yeah your tool to find a 23 round
distinguisher I think it's about uh
uh two weeks yeah yeah thanks so much
do we have more questions
so nobody here do we have questions in
Beijing Maybe
I don't see any more question I have a
short question
um you didn't talk about the tools you
used to model the attack I think you use
constraint programming can you comment
on how this compares to mail per set
because we've seen different papers
using different type of tools
in fact the the model was done in two
steps just
just say the ear so in the first step we
use the constraint programming but the
underlying server is a set solver which
is a picket set
because the model is mainly working on a
Boolean variables to set solvers really
dedicated to to this kind of constraints
and in the second step we use a Shoku
which is a constraint programming solver
we use this tool because in the second
step we need to
to represent the Xbox probabilities and
this kind of constraints are not really
well
are not really well uh implementing the
set or mihp solvers so in the case of
constraint programming you have a
constraint tables that are already
dedicated to this kind of representation
that's why we use a set for the third
step and the CP for the second step
okay thank you
so if there are no more questions we
will move to the next talk
thank you thank you
so the next paper is titled throwing
boomerangs into Feister structures
application to clefair warp L block and
block s and Twine
it's a paper by Jose nadipur Marcel
nagelar and Maria ashleather and the
speaker will be Hussain
thanks for introduction
hello everyone I hope you have enjoyed
the conference so far
I'm Jose hadipur from grass University
of Technology and I'm very pleased to
present our work entitled Brewing boom
ranks into Feister structures which is a
joint work with master nagala and Maria
Ashley so a long story short when we
started this work in the first year of
my PhD there was no tool to find
Boomerang distinguishers or fighter
sniper so we decided to fill this Gap
and we managed to provide a very easy
and fast a very easy to use and fast
method to find Boomerang distinguishers
for Firestone ciphers we applied it to
several black snipers such as calefia
warp l-block and toyne and we got a
series of improved results uh
to mention just a few we improved the
boomerang distinctions of warp by two
rounds we improved the boomerang
distinguisher and Boomerang attack on
clivia by one round
by the way our method is not limited to
final snipers it's essentially
applicable to any strongly aligned Xbox
such as skinny as
so this is my plan for the rest of this
talk first of all I will tell you which
parameters are effective in the
probability of uh in the success
probability of boomerang distinguisher
then I will show you how we can create a
constraint programming model to
considerably effective parameter into
accounts and find a nearly optimal rain
distinguisher then I will discuss about
one of the applications of our tool to
warp and conclude the talk
so let's start by the first part
assume that you have two short
differential transitions for black
Cipher e with a super high probabilities
p and Q respectively but they are they
cannot be linked because Delta 2 and
nobla 2 are not the same you cannot link
them in a basic differential setting in
this case boom rank distinguisher comes
to help and the core idea of boomerang
distinguisher is actually combining
these two short definitions in
adaptively chosen playing text cipherty
setting to do so we encrypt a pair of
plain text with different Delta 1 then
we modify the drive cyber takes by the
same difference Noble three then we
decrypt them to drive the corresponding
plain text and we check if the
difference between P3 and P4 is Delta 1
or not
you see four differential transitions in
this shape
if this uh uh two same transitions at
the top and two same transitions at the
bottom
if the upper and lower differential
transitions are statistically
independent the policy of getting Delta
1 back on the other side is actually the
multiplication of probabilities for
these four differential transitions
which is PS Square t squared
but these two trails are not independent
in practice
that's why the idea of sandwich
distinguisher was proposed uh in
sandwich distinguisher we essentially
put an additional part in the middle of
distinguisher to model the dependency
between upper and lower trade
in other words a sandwich distinguisher
is essentially composed of three uh
small distinguishers two basic
differential distinguishers at the top
and bottom and a small boomerang
distinguisher in the middle
just like a sandwich
if the probability of two basic
differential distinguishers at the top
at bottom are p and Q respectively and
the probability of a small boring
distinguisher in the middle BR then the
entire quality of sand which
distinguisher is PS squared TS squared r
we have enough information about p and Q
we know that P can be determined by the
number of active as boxes in e0 Q can be
determined by the number of active
responses in E1 but uh what about r
let's take a look at the middle part in
more detail this shape represents the
middle part of Sandwich extinguisher
when it includes only one Xbox layer
it's the simplest case
uh
as you can see if the s-box in the
middle of sandwich distinguisher is
active in at most one of the upper or
loyal Trail then we can bypass it for
free the probability of boomerang
transition over this box is one
if this box is active in at most one of
the upper and lower trays you see if
Delta is zero or Noble is zero we can
bypass it for free it's called a ladder
switch it's some sort of super positive
dependency between upper and lower
Trails you have always heard about the
negative side of dependency but this is
the positive side of dependency
this is for file subscribers they are
almost the same the only difference is
that the inverse of this box doesn't
come into effect
but the ladder switch still works if the
input of this box is zero
in one of the upper or lowest rail we
again pass this box for free uh the
probability of moonlight transition over
this box is one
so um
I want to show you a very interesting
example regarding the effect of leather
switch this shape represents 11 rounds
of a skinny
this Trail this differential Trail
which is colored in red
is shown to be impossible in pt22 the
paper which was presented yesterday
these differential Trails is also shown
to be impossible because of dependency
between round cues you know if you
compute this probability using DDT
framework
um you can say okay the policy should be
for example two to the minus under 79
but if you go through the details and
check the dependency between round keys
this differential Trail showed to be
impossible but when we put them together
we get a boomerang distincture with
probability one that works for any key
for any plain text everywhere anytime
because there is no overlap between the
red and blue propagation over the Xbox
layer remember the ladder switch
all of the s-boxes in this shape are
active in at most
one of the upper or lower trays
theoretically the probability should be
one I experimentally verified it by 2 to
the N random keys or plain text is
policy is one
so what it means
it has two I think lessons the first
lesson is the impact of leather switch
if you want to find a Bound for R the
probability of boomerang switch a
boomerang switch in the middle of
Sandwich extinguisher it's enough to
only count the number of common activist
boxes between upper and lower trade
we should just we just we should just
ignore this boxes which are active in uh
only one of the upper or lowest rays
and the second lesson is that uh
dependency issues in the in building
block Trails of boomerang switch has no
impact on the validity of the resulting
Boomerang structure you see two uh
impossible Trails yield a boomerang
signature with probability one
so let's recap this section uh
we wanted to see the effective we wanted
to discuss about the effective parameter
in the entire probability in PS squared
key Square R formula p is mostly
determined by the number of activist
boxes in e0
Q is mostly determined by the number of
active responses in E1
and R is determined by the number of
common active Sparks between the upper
and lower propagation in the middle part
if we can create a constraint
programming model that count uh that
counts the number of active responses in
e0 and E1 and the number of common X
squares Plus in EM we can have a rough
estimation of probability
in addition the cost of calculus boxes
in e0 and E1 is higher than the cost of
common actors box in EM because of the
exponent of PQ
the exponent of P here and P Squared Q
squared is 2 but the exponent of R is 1.
so with that in mind let me introduce
our new method to search for we rank
distincture it's pretty simple
and fast enough
it has three main steps the first step
is uh finding good truncated trails
which aims at minimizing the number of
activist boxes in e0 and E1 and common
activist box in EM
the second step is instantiating the
discovered truncated trails with
concrete differential trays and lastly
when we have concrete differential trays
in hand we compute p and Q and R
separately we put them together to
compute the entire probability of
Sandwich extinguisher let's take a take
a look at the first step in more detail
this is actually the most important step
of our method in this step we divide a
block Cipher into three parts
we create a constraint programming model
to encode the propagation of truncated
Trail in e0 and em in forward Direction
but when we switch from e0 to em
we switch from the propagation from the
normal propagation to a propagation with
probability you want
we create another CPU model to encode
the propagation in E1 and em in backward
Direction
again when we when we propagate the
propagation when we propagate uh the
difference through E1 as usual we switch
the propagation with probability one
when we go to em
we are also interested to encode uh the
common activist boxes in the middle part
assume that U and L represents the
activeness of the sparxus in upper and
lower trade
to detect the common actress boxes we
Define an additional variable for each
box in the middle the additional
variable s
and then we include three inequalities
for each Sparks in the middle
accordingly s is equal to 1 if and only
if the corresponding Xbox is active in
both upper and lower trade so this way
we can count the number of common
activist marks in the middle
then we include an objective function to
minimize the number of active Sparks in
e0 E1 and the common activist box the
number of combinative source in the
middle we also assign some integer rates
uh which are denoted by w0w m and W1 to
adjust the probability
so uh the in the next in this next step
uh when we have tricator Trail we
instantiate the
concrete differential Trail for e0 and
E1
however
after finding the
concrete differential trails
we only fixed the difference in four
positions
namely in the input output of e0 and E1
when you fix the difference in the input
output of e0 and E1 you can compute p
and Q using a using the existing tools
and you you can take the clustering
effect into account because easy run E1
are short enough
in addition you have the input and
output difference for the s multipur in
the middle so you can compute its
probability using VCT framework fpcd
framework or you can do it
experimentally
we do it we did it mostly experimentally
because the probability of em is large
enough in all of our applications and we
can easily compute this probability
using experimental approach
let's discuss about one of the
applications of our
uh tool
this simple comment represents the usage
of our tool it receives only three
integer numbers
which specify the length of each part in
Sandwich extinguisher for example assume
that you want to find a 23 round
distinguisher for Warp
6 10 7 is a good choice because
the full the legs are fully efficient
for warp is 10. so it's best to choose
the length of the middle part
uh 2b10
and running this command takes 20
seconds on a regular laptop what you
receive is the boomerang distinguisher
it's a specification and a rough
estimation of its probability
this tray represents the round function
of warp uh
we applied our two to war
and in this animation I want to show you
how our method works we propagate the
difference in opposite way
as you can see the dense part represents
em
and the sports Parts represents e0 and
E1
here the length of em is 10. as you can
see only three Sparks comes into effect
all of the other spices in the middle
are just uh ineffective you know we can
bypass all of them for free and
the policy of middle parts is large
enough to to compute it experimentally
it's my 2 to the minus 4.5 58 you can
just uh experimentally
um measure it you can compute it on
regular laptop
so
um
this is a summary of our results for
work the best previous distinguisher
covered up to 21 round of Warp
but we discovered a 23 round
distinguisher which again has a much
higher probability
we proved that distinguisher by two
rounds but take into account running
this command takes only 20 seconds
on a regular laptop because our model is
the simplest model we don't go through
the Beats level because we believe for a
strongly aligned Cipher you don't need
to go to the through the Beats level
if you want to find a good boomerang
distinguisher
award-wise model is quite enough
and we come to the end the star end of
the start where I would just like to
thank you for your attention before I
finish let me just say that uh our tool
is publicly available in this guitar
repository in the combat repository
during this work he also developed a an
open source tool which is a Xbox
analyzer and it can be used to
encode the differential linear or
integral properties of Sparks and it can
be used as a sub-module of Xbox class in
sagemath thanks I hope it will be useful
in Q was saying do we have questions in
the room
yeah thank you for your talk so you said
that for highly aligned Cipher you don't
need to go to the beat level uh can you
explain this a bit more I mean thanks
for your question
um
let me see if I can find a picture maybe
this one
beats well to this question you know to
find a
to find a good Boomerang distinguisher
what you need is actually
um
finding a good truncated Trail not a bit
wise differential Trail
because the leather switch plays the
whiter role it's the it's the strongest
uh switching effect in Boomerang
analysis
uh so if you take it into account you
can find a nearly Optimum distinguisher
and it is uh the thing that you can
model in a worldwide uh MLP or
constraint programming model you don't
need to go through the wheat level you
don't need to model the DDT it's just
like counting the number of common
activist boxes
it's also the case for skinny AES craft
warp or Cliff yeah I can mention some
other strongly aligned black snipers but
it's not suitable for present gift
because they have bitwise operations
this doesn't work
but for essentially a line Cipher I
think according to previous experiences
for example comparing this paper with
the previous one or our FSA 22 paper
um we got a
even better results in a shorter time
you know it's it means a word wise model
are sufficient or strongly aligned by
Cipher
yeah I'm not sure if I I have answered
the question
uh I have a question regarding the time
uh so for example uh if you change the
number of middle rounds for example from
10 to 8 to 6 like this then while
keeping the overall number rounds same
how does your time change or the tool
okay if anything correctly you mean if
we change the configuration for example
here yeah the number of middle rounds oh
yeah while keeping the total number of
rounds the same is the time still same
for your tool or it changes yeah uh so
let's review the method it has it has
three steps right the first step is
defining truncated pattern then you
instantiate with concrete
these two steps the time for these two
steps doesn't change
uh and it doesn't matter if you get the
middle part so for example 10 Rounds or
less than or more than 10 rounds but for
the last step when you want to compute
its probability
if you uh if you if you consider the
middle part very long
what goes wrong is that you know
uh it's first of all it's not necessary
you know I mean I mean the full
diffusion of Cipher gives us a good uh
indication for choosing the length of em
if for example first you need the length
of the will diffusion I as far as I
remember should be seven or six if you
choose the middle part more than six
rounds is useless because dependency
disappear after six or seven rounds you
don't need to choose the middle part you
know do you remember we choose the
middle part to model dependency so if
you choose it longer than six rounds
it's useless
but uh
another problem is that if you choose it
too long the probability of middle part
cannot be computed experimentally
even if you want to compute
theoretically the number of involved
parameters might be very high and again
your program stuck in the
in the computation
so
I would say I would say the running time
change for just the last step when you
want to compute the probability of each
parts but for the two First Steps it
doesn't change yeah
okay thank you you're welcome
so there's one more question
thank you so yeah uh
my general question so what about the uh
result uh on twine
is there any progress unfortunately I
didn't put them into the slides but uh
uh four four clivia and warp we
significantly significantly improve the
previous results by a number of rounds
but for toying L block we just improved
the probability not the number of rounds
but I don't have the exact number
numbers in my slides but as far as I
remember the aspects of Towing and
Adblock was uh
stronger against Boomerang analysis this
is the ethicity of War
um it's it represents the the the the
s-rings of a Sparks against
Boomerang analysis you see there are for
example two uh
uh cases where
you have a lot of large entries in the
table this is some sort of weakness
because if you choose two or a as the
input of boomerang switch in the middle
you can make the most of clustering
effect you get a very high probability
distinguisher but for toying and a block
you cannot find such a
I remember but sorry I didn't put the
exact numbers for 29 okay but you're
welcome to refer to the paper I think we
have
uh discussed about this question in our
paper thanks for your question yeah
so your attack is independent of the key
schedule right it's a CL key attack
yeah yeah
so that the key skill doesn't come into
effect because but there is there is no
difference the key schedule
so yeah
our work is mostly focused on the boom
on the distinguisher part
but it can be simply extended for the
key recovery I actually did it after
publishing this work I applied this
method so on a skinny as you can see for
example in my first example here
this is just one one of the outputs of
the tool or a screening yeah I applied
it to a skinny as I climbed this
applicable to any align black ciphers
but and we extended for kirikori as well
it's not complete but it's it's it can
be extended for key recovery okay as far
as
finding the distinguisher so the key
schedule is not done yeah related yeah
so in any key schedule yeah yeah
things as long as it's a single key
distinguisher yeah okay yeah thank you
you're welcome
thank you do we have some questions
online or in Beijing
so I guess no more questions
uh I have maybe a short question
um
you you have results on warp you have a
better Boomerang distinguisher than in
the previous paper
can you explain what is different in
your work compared to the work is it
because I optimize for an attack on your
only optimize for a distinguisher or
other other parameters uh
if I'm not mistaken they also try to
find the best distinguishers beside
finding that attack but again they
I think the problem is that they try to
make the model very accurate they
modeled they they went through the Beast
levels
when you go through debut levels and you
want to compute everything theoretically
or
take the clustering fix into account you
know all of these stuff
the model the stocks in running time in
the in the running time it never
terminates so you have to sacrifice the
accuracy you have to include some
additional constraints
and
and uh due to the I think
uh
uh complexity of the resulting model I
think that uh
maybe that's the reason that
we got a better result because our model
is simple and
it's as I mentioned it it seems the
award-wise model is enough for because
let me clarify this um you know for the
middle part uh or the middle part for
example here
if you want to compute the probability
theoretically assume that there are
innocent of three s bars three common as
far as there are ten common Xbox
in the middle
if you want to do it theoretically it
doesn't work
you can drive the formula but when you
want to evaluate this formula the
complexity could be two to the 50 to the
60 can do it so we start sacrificing the
act in the accuracy and
it causes you to get a maybe worse
result
uh but if you just uh
I think
uh it's just the the problem uh the
efficiency versus accuracy problem
[Music]
maybe the main reason is that we just
compute the probability of middle part
experimentally
and we get a maybe a more accurate or
okay which is close more accurate uh
probability which is closer to the
actual probability if you want to
estimate theoretically
yeah okay thank you thank you for a
question
so thank you
according to my understanding you have
you first built uh byte the mode in a by
the layer right
in the Bible the translated model then
you find the compatible uh yeah yeah
yeah so do you find some cases where uh
after you find a solution for the
truncated model then you cannot find a
solution in the byte model it's in a
video did you find some cases thanks for
your very interesting question it could
be the case but as far as I know for
many cyphers that have this issue you
can again put some constraints in the
world level model to get rid of this in
possible
or tranquiliters for example for AES
if you
you may find some truncated trades that
cannot never be
instantiated with real bitwise ways but
as far as I know for all for as far as I
know to the best of my knowledge for
most of the strongly aligned by black
snipers we can again put some additional
constraints in the world level model
to get rid of this
impossible uh Trails tranquila Trails it
can be handled I would say again in the
world level in the world wise model we
don't need to go
through the beat level
I myself uh
no but I think in the previous papers it
has been discussed here there it's
possible I think yeah
okay thank you so let's thanks uh sign
again and all the speakers of this
session
you want to answer
I just want to add some extra
information to the previous question so
I think the main difference is is that
when we compute the probability of the
distinguisher we are actually Computing
the
so we fix each different of each word of
the site first and when uh in their work
as they are Computing experimentally the
probability of the distinguisher
they obtain a better approximation a
better evaluation of the probability as
we are not Computing the same things so
I think there is the main differences
that why there are better probabilities
as
that so thank you huge for explanation
yeah you made my life easier
okay so now it's over right
so let's thank all the speakers and we
can go to lunch