hello everyone today I will talk about
electricity analysis of the stream cycle
treco
uh
so in Asia groups of 2001 uh Alex
perukov and another published their
seminal paper one
TMG trade-off attacks the main
conclusion of the paper was that for a
stream Cipher
to be secure the size of its intense
state in bits
it needed to be at least one and a half
to two times the size
of the secret key that it's uses
this was generally accepted as the rule
of thumb until
the EFC of 2015 in which I'm Nick and
Mikhail have proposed the stream ciphers
proud
whose internal stage was exactly equal
to the size of its secret scheme
now surprisingly the disciple did not
succumb to generic TMD trade-off attacks
and was much smaller in the area
than any known streams after that point
because of small state size
now a stream Cipher is a finance State
machine
if we consider F to be the function that
Maps the internal state of the stream
Cipher too
uh to your keystream vector of equal
size then the crypto analysis of the
stream Cipher reduces to inverting this
one-way function f
at any one of the key stream segments
that the attacker has access to
uh
now the algorithm that
uhmir proposed had the trade-off curve
Mt Square Times t squared equal to N
squared
with the limitation that t had to be
larger than d square
m t and D are the memory
online time and the data complexity of
the algorithm
yeah capital N was the cardinality of
the internal State space
and the offline complexity was given as
[Music]
n divided by T so the main idea is that
in the on offline stage the attacker
chooses some random initial States
and iterates this one-way function f
that Maps the state to the keystream
so we'll have two times and stores the
endpoints in a table
in this way the attacker covers a
fraction of the set of states that the
cipher has
and in the online Street the attacker
States one of the key stream segments
and tries to see
if it is present in my in my in one in
any one of the tables
uh a typical point on the straight-off
curve is where both capital T and couple
B
uh capital N to the power to third Which
is less than n
if
denotes the cardinality of the e-space
and N equal to K we should say that the
key and the state size are equal then
the straight-off point represents a
valid attack
against a stream Cipher
so as a rule of thumb
capsule n was set to K Square
after which
it is not possible to find a point on
this curve for which
both capital P and capital T Infinity
online and the offline complexity are
less than capsule k
okay
so the main idea behind the Sprout and
similar stream ciphers which have
shorter internal state is that the state
update function required the secret key
as the input
and so
any of these maps that Maps as the sis
to the CIS
which is not possible to construct this
function f
that Maps the state to keystream without
the input of the secret key
so this made the effective State size of
the cipher
basically equal to the size of the State
plus the size of the key
which was effectively twice the size of
the key and so any generic TMG trade of
type attacks could have been prevented
however prevented
of course proud had other weaknesses and
it was attacked in a number of papers
following its publication and since then
there have been various attempts at
designing Short State ciphers
for example plantlet was a redesign of
sprout by the same authors
by removing known points of attack from
the design
however there was a near Collision
attack reported against it in the FSC of
lizard was another design presented in
FSC of 2017
and there are some attacks reports
against uh lizard in the efficacy of the
following year
atem was another design presented in FSC
last year and uh you're not aware of any
attack reportedly instead
so Draco was a design presented to
defici this year
those familiar with the structure of the
grain family of stream ciphers would
recognize this setup immediately
so just two non-linear registers of size
95 and 33 bits
and the stage is updated with the 128
bits non-volatile state
which consists of the first 32 bits of
the key and uh
96 bit IV
by extorting this bit DFT to the update
function at every clock cycle
now uh
G of T is constructed as followers
first the IV is prepended with a single
zero bit to make it of 97 bits
and the bits are renamed as x i
and
DT is then calculated as X of T mod 97
xor with K of T mod 32. it was probably
done because 32.97 are co-prime and so
it would be more difficult to construct
patterns in the TT sequence
now we have proposed two attractions
Sprout and I was very quickly thank you
to both of them
the first attack stems from two
observations
the first thing to note is that the
sequence D of T is periodic repeated
equal to the product of 32 and 97. this
is not very difficult to see since DT is
just a xor of
the IV and the key bits and
since the IV and the keep its repeating
cycles of 32 and 97 I just
therefore understandable that they will
come into sync after 32 times 97 Cycles
and so uh sequence DT will be periodic
with the
this given period
well the second observation is as
follows
we take all IVs of the form
Kappa concatenated tries and the whole
thing rotated by one bit
yeah
um
keep it fixed
for all such ideas it is very easy to
see that this 96-bit sequence
D of Tau plus 1 up to D of Tau plus 96
is 0.
for all values of star that are
divisible by this uh
by this period 3104.
uh since GT is the contribution of
the key to the update of the State uh
this essentially implies that the state
update for 96 Cycles
and in turn the keystream BET generation
from 99 Cycles is effectively
independent of the game
well the key stream is independent from
99 instead of 96 because
in Cycles 97 98 and 99 the state bits
are updated by the key
s that are updated by the key to not
take part
in the construction of the keystring but
and uh
so uh
there are a relatively small numbers
which is about 30
to um
IVs of the required form
vvv rotated by one
and so the strategy in is by is using a
chosen IV scenario and trying all
possible IVs of this form
and with v equals Kappa
yeah that is when the cycle becomes weak
algebraically
okay
so the idea is as follows in the offline
stage we try
to create tables assuming that this
stream Cipher is already in this week
generally compromised it
um
so we Generate random 128 bit States
uh generate the 99 key stream bits that
does not require
uh any involvement of the key then we
store it in an offline table
um index by the keystring vector of
course
so that it is easy to search
now in the online stage
we query keystream bits for all IVs of
this required form
and we take
for for all I that are one mod three
3104 so we extract these 99-bit key
stream windows and try to see if they
are already present in the stable or not
so if we find the match shall we
generate a few more keystream bits and
check if the extracted key is limits and
the generated engagement bits match
if not we can simply reject this
candidate and move to the move to the
next keyframe window however yes then we
can open secretly
and by using birthday bounce it's
possible to calculate that the total
complexity of this attack is around 2 is
about 114.
as opposed to Bluetooth search would
take just 128.
um
the second attack stems from another key
observation
so the idea is we take all initial
vectors for which the first 96 minus
capsule e bits are zero
and the remaining caption ebits are
some some small Vector small small yeah
and now consider some Lambda which is a
multiple of 97.
it can be proven that the 97 minus
capital E bit sequence
uh G of Lambda to D of Lambda plus 96
minus E it does not depend on the small
e
and this is not very difficult to
provide and have an improvement in two
lines as I've shown in the slide
um
but the main takeaway is that of the IV
of this form
for any idea of this form the state
update for 97 minus e-cycles
and for similar reasons keystream bits
for 100 minus E Cycles do not depend on
the idea as well and this try gives rise
to another set of three configurations
that we can explore in the following way
um
in the offline stage we try to create
tables again assuming
that the stream Cipher is already in
this week
compromised it
uh the only difference is that that this
time you have to construct tables for
all the to the power 32 key prefix
values
so we take we generate 2.96 minus
capital D
random States
and generate
is 100 minus E key stream bits
and store this spare keystring comma
state in
the respective table tab of K
uh the online stage is exactly similar
we take
all IVs of the given form in which the
first 96 minus capsule e bits are zero
and then we take all 100 minus ebit
heat stream windows and see if they
exist in any one of the toolbar 32
tables
um
and the rest is exactly similar as the
previous attack if you find the match
then you're not the key here and we can
generate a few more D string bits to
check but the generation and extracted
keys to mix match signing up the key
otherwise move on to the next candidate
uh we can adjust values of capital E and
capital G to balance the offline and
online complexities
and you've seen that for capital G is 28
and capital is 40. the three
complexities become the same and the
Civil complexity becomes actual 107.
and this is probably the best we can do
in this setup
uh to conclude uh it is obvious that uh
the main point of entry of the attack
was
the schedule function
and how the authors chose to construct
the sequence DFT
which allows us to define a very simple
one-way function over from the state to
the key stream
over a smaller uh overset of smaller
cards analogy
um my initial intuition is that a better
quiche we should fix this design
and that is all I have in this
presentation thanks a lot for listening
thank you
foreign