so this session is on linear layers
there will be three talks
and the first talk will be decomposing
linear layers by Christopher Patrick
Felker gregoriander and Sandra Orange
and Gregor will give the talk
thank you very much
is this working yes maybe yeah okay yes
so um
I'm going to talk about
designs that don't follow the best
practice maybe so there are certainly
open designs and cryptographic Designs
which where you have a public
specification where you have design
resonance
and security
arguments but there are also close
designs where for one reason or the
other not all of this is fulfilled so
maybe we don't have a public
specification maybe we do not have
design rationals
or maybe if you don't have security
analysis yeah and examples for the later
case is things that was not supposed to
be public and all only got reversed
engineered like the ga one ciphers then
Simon and spec is a famous example where
we have a public specification but we do
not have any design resonance and this
three box that we already heard this
morning where we don't have
any design rational and actually it's
even a bit more hidden what what was
done
so there are different levels of close
design here
okay so this three block just to recall
it's a Russian Standard a hash function
and I'm going to give a bit more details
because this is like a running example
throughout the talk so this operates on
the 64-bit State and where we have an
8-bit s-box which was just given as a
lookup table where you have a
permutation of bytes and the 64 by 64
binary metrics that is supplied in
atem's in parallel so this is the
specification of the cipher and we don't
have any design arguments how those
things were chosened
and
and so given such a design a natural
research question is how do we recover
structure now how do we understand where
is this Design coming from and for the
s-boxes this is well studied
um so they're very nice results how the
Xbox
was chosen I don't know but at least the
structure that's in there is by now well
understood to a large extent I would say
and for the linear layer it's not so
well studied so we don't have good tools
to to find structure in linear layers
and this is what our work is about
so we focus on the linear layer and the
idea is given a binary metrics every
linear layer can be represented as a
binary Matrix recovers Direction and
especially um
so they could be all kinds of structure
we focus on something very particular so
we certainly do not solve this problem
entirely but we focus on the question of
can we find a structure that is induced
by constructions over extended figures
so like the AES mix color
so and if we further structure this into
in three problems the first one is
exactly this given a binary Matrix how
can we decide if this actually should be
is better represented as a matrix of an
extension field
the second part is an obfuscated version
of the first one and I'm going to
explain what I mean by obfuscated
version later
and then the third one is like a
follow-up question if you then know that
is actually a matrix of an extension
field what kind of Matrix is this does
it follow some um some well-known
construction for example for MDS
matrices okay and in this talk I'm
mainly talking about this first problem
and then for the second and third one
I'm briefly motivating and giving the
results but no details no technical
details
okay so this field structure just to be
more clear what I want to do I'm given a
matrix in this example a 12 by 12
metrics and I want to know
if this Matrix could be represented as a
matrix over the extension field of
um to the four elements so that's the
question
so can I write this as a three by three
Matrix where each of these blocks
let's try to use this one so you can
stream Zoom where each of these blocks
actually corresponds to multiplication
with the final field element so of the
form gamma some power where gamma is a
generator in this finite field okay
so this is the question we want to solve
in this first part of the talk
so usually we represent a finite field
by picking a irreducible polynomial and
thinking about multiplication of
polynomials modulo this irreducible
polynomial
that's certainly the most General and
not the the most common way of doing so
but there's much more General ways of
representing a final field as a matrix
and by matrices final field Elements by
matrices
um and I briefly motivate why in this in
the in this area of uh SPN ciphers we
might actually observe things that are
more General than just polynomials
so if you consider two-round spns or one
and a half or whatever yeah so Xbox
layer linearly Xbox layer what you can
always do think of an
changing the specification
um either because it was just a reverse
engineer though because you want to hide
something is you can certainly put
a small linear layers after the s-boxes
and the inverse right after so that you
actually did not change anything and you
can do the same after the linear layer
no so we didn't do any changes to the
functionality and then to make it nice
for the round before and after you're
going to put T and T inverse before and
after and now we end up with the design
which is functionally equivalent to what
we started with but which has a
different s-box which I don't care in
this talk but which also has a different
linear layer and if I started with a
linear layer of the finite field so if L
was actually defined over the financial
field you can think of what happened in
terms of matrices is that this Matrix
this binary Matrix L was now multiplied
from left and right with block diagonal
matrices corresponding on the blocks you
have this T and T input
foreign
so coming back to the metrics
representations of an extension field if
I start with a field which is I
represented as as you know by shooting a
an irreducible polynomial what I end up
now is that each of these elements will
be left and right multiplied with t and
t inverse and they still form finite
field so I don't give a formula proof
here but yeah it's just conjugating
these three elements you still have the
same properties in just one example
though if your field elements that you
modify them this way and you multiply
you get feedback
and this means that we have to do
something a bit more clever than
exhaustive researching because even for
small sizes the number of T and T
inverses is large
so now the problem becomes given a set
of matrices binary matrices can we
decide if they correspond to fluid
multiplication or not
okay and then this set s is normally
would just be the blocks of our Matrix
that we started and it was
so we start easy we just take one
element so how can I decide if one given
Matrix of size s s times s so a matrix a
which has to be invertible but because
otherwise it's certainly not a field
multiplications I'm only going to
consider and invertible matrices is this
a field multiplication or not can I
represent this as a field multiplication
or not this equivalent
to the minimal polynomial minimal
polynomial of the Matrix a being
irreducible
okay that is basically how all this
um irreducible polynomials come into
play I'm not going to give a proof here
let's focus on the next um more
complicated case now I don't have too
well not only one Matrix but many
matrices all these blocks and I still
want to know the same question is this
field can I represent this as a field or
not so what I have to do now
um
is not only check something about
irreducible polynomials but we also have
to check if kind of if they fit together
these matrices that's the the main point
and so what we have the the statement
that we prove in the paper I'll give a
short proof here is that this is a is a
final field it's a representation of a
final field if and only if the
multiplicative subgroup
is cyclic and the generator of this
subgroup has a primitive it has an
irreducible Mini model
okay
and just let me give you a short
proof so if it's cyclic and generated by
irreducible minimal polynomial that's
exactly the Lemma before so this this
direction is clear and also the other
direction is not a lot more complicated
if you have a field then the
multiplicative group is cyclic and then
you take a generator and and this is
going to generate
um this this Matrix is going to generate
this
and this um
suffering and and by the previous Lemma
this minimal polynomial of alpha has to
be irreducible
so this is not too hard to see
and now the question is how to make this
into an algorithmic approach so how can
we algorithmically verify this thing and
the main problem is
um so maybe algorithmically checking if
the minimal polynomial Computing the
minimal polynomial is easy and checking
for irreducibility is easy so what is
not as straightforward maybe is how to
check if it's cyclic or not
okay
so how do we check if a group given by
and generators is a cyclic group or not
okay
and so there's a one Lemma which is very
nice if I have reducing again complexity
by looking at two cases first so if I
have a group which is generated by two
elements and I know this group is cyclic
then I can easily find a generator by
taking a a suitable product of those two
elements
so I can always even without knowing
that g is cyclic I can always write down
this
um this element yeah but then it's not a
generator but if it's a cyclic group
then I'm going to get a generator of the
cyclic group in such a way and now this
is just for two elements but you can
just apply this Lemar recursively to
kick out and to reduce the number of
generators in your in your group one by
one
okay
so this is the algorithm that does
exactly this so first you're you're
given this n matrices and you want to
know if the multiplicative group is
cyclic and if this corresponds to a
finite if the
the polynomial is irreducible
so you first use this algorithm to find
something which generates the group if
it's a click so we still have to check
if it's if this really is a generator or
not so this is why we call it a pseudo
generator
so this we can easily compute and then
we're going to check if all these other
matrices if all these AIS
elements in this suffering by using the
additive structure using linear algebra
to check if you can represent them
um if they are in the span of of these
things so if they are linear combination
of these powers of Alpha and if not then
we know it's not the field and if yes
then we know it's Alpha is indeed a
generator and then we test if it's a
real reducible polynomial and then if
not we say it's not the field and
otherwise we found that it's a field and
we actually computed the generator okay
and the nice thing is that up to
factorizing 2 to the S minus 1 this is a
polynomial time so that's very fast and
for the S with we are interested in so s
is basically the size of the block size
and not the block size but the s-box
size so that's all always in all
interesting practical cases be easy to
factorize
so application tools three block
you yeah it's a second or a fraction of
a second and you'll get the the field
representation
so this was actually done before so
there was like handcrafted algorithm to
check and so it actually the is just
running through it reducible polynomials
you would not find that it's uh that
it's a
um a food structure directly but you had
to transpose and okay now basically this
is more automatic and you know handcraft
needed okay so there's hidden structure
in the in the linear layout Street box
okay
so then second part was optification and
more structure and as I said I will be
very brief on this
so looking back on on the choice that we
had so now it's either the choice that
we again that happens because we are
just reverse engineering things and so
maybe we do not get the intended
representation or because we really want
to hide structure if you want to really
height structure you cannot put can of
course put much more different things so
there's no reason but all the T and T
inverses have to be the same in the
first round and there's no reason not to
put different ones after the linear
layer and and then you get something
which is much more
hidden yeah so this also is not the
field representation you know so even if
L is defined over the final field this
is not there anymore yeah and in the
paper we we explain how to
how to recover
um this field representation efficiently
up to
things that you cannot
so there's no unique representation
anymore but it's again
efficiently
and then finally
the uh what more can be said after for
example we found in this tree boxing
that there is a final field
hidden if you want what more can be said
so then we also give ways to test if
some heavily obfuscated like of the form
I just shot on this like before if this
actually corresponds to a cauchy MDS
Matrix and again because of this heavy
application it's technically a bit
involved and the details can be found in
the paper
and if you then apply this to this
Russian Standard you did see that not
only
um was it
hidden that there's a fee structure but
also it's actually a known Construction
for uh
for NDS matrices namely this kosher
Construction
and I think that's all I wanted to say
thank you very much
thank you gregar so we have time for
questions are there any questions in in
Beijing
yes no question do you have questions in
Kobe
okay I've I have one question maybe two
um so you you you you identify this
hidden structure in the street bug uh
Matrix so I guess for me obvious
question do you see any possible uh
problem with this structure did you try
to think about this
um potentially some some interplay with
the s box as well with the I don't know
much about the Xbox entrybook but maybe
there are some interplay with this
structure as well yes maybe there's some
so we did not think too much about it I
my personal feeling it's uh it's
unlikely but uh
if you certainly cannot exclude it
maybe a joint work with Leo in the
future you're looking into this but yeah
it's not
okay thank you very much
oh oh we have a question okay
um so not for your question but just on
this uh possible interaction between the
Xbox and the linear layer
the s-box is defined in the same field
so the Xbox it's nice thanks by the way
representation is in the same field as
the linear layer but I agree that at
this point
Beyond this I cannot say anything
yeah
that's the official version yes
yeah so I I my opinion is it's not I am
rather
I would be super impressed if they put
it back to end this
no no but I would be super impressed and
my feeling is I'm I don't think I'm so
impressed
so did you try same thing with cousin
Matrix
I mean that also is the same as box and
but there's already a construction given
right I know it's given
it's in a different field yeah
yes but there's I mean there's it's not
I mean there we know that is coming from
okay okay okay thank you
okay if no more question let's think can
I go again
[Music]
oh okay
hi this is
okay
thank you I will introduce your talk
okay so sorry
all right so the next talk
um is on the lower bound of cost of NDS
matrices
by I needed I needed
will give the talk online thank you
you have to shut the screen okay yeah
hi all uh this is I will be presenting
our paper on the lower bound of cost of
MDS matrices this is a joint work with
abhishekar
as you can see from the title this is
about MDS matrices in the context of
lightweight cryptography in this work we
established the lower bound on the cost
of 4x4 block MDS matrices under the
metric called swxr or sequential XR
based onwards
here is the outline of my talk I will
briefly introduce basic concepts and
then we see some preliminary results in
settling the lower bound finally we
discuss some limitations of our work and
open questions
as you all know MDS matrices are best
suited for Designing diffusion layers
because they provide optimal diffusion
matrices can be implemented using
circuits with XR Gates
and the main question here is finding
MDS matrices with minimal Hardware cost
that is requiring least number of XR
dates for the parameters of practical
interest the general form of this
problem can be stated like this
minimizing the number of XR Gates
necessary to compute a set of linear
functions this is also known as short
test linear program problem it is known
to be NP hard for this reason given a
matrix finding optimal implementation is
hard
a number of Matrix over the field after
to the power n is MDS if all its Square
sub matrices are non-singular in this
work we consider block matrices it is
the notation that we use in our
presentation M and M denote the Ring of
M by M Block MDS matrices with entries
from n by n binary matrices gln is a
general linear group of non-singular
matrices DNM is the block diagonal
matrices where the entries are
non-similar matrices pnm is the block
wise permutation matrices a block and
MDS block Matrix m in mnm is set to be
MDS if all its square blocks of matrices
are non singular
there are mainly three metrics discussed
in the literature 2s is the cost of
matrices the first one is dxr or DirectX
R it is the number of ones in a binary
Matrix minus size of the Matrix it gives
a good upper bound on the cost of the
Matrix another one is sxr or the
sequential X or it is the number of
bitwise XR operations in a sequential
program with In-Place operations that an
In-Place operation is like this given an
input Vector X1 to X N replacing x i
with x i plus x g this can be used as a
Elementary row operation of type 3 on
the input Vector x 1 to X N that's why
given a matrix M will consider
decompositions of this form where p is a
permutation Matrix these are Elementary
matrices of type 3 each Matrix
corresponds to the operation x i
replacing with x i plus x j it cross one
XR so we want to minimize the number of
type 3 matrices involved in the
decomposition the minimum subject gives
the sxr here we do not use any extra
registers to store the intermediate
values by allowing extra resistance one
may get a better estimate this is known
as g x r this is related to the SLP
problem and also it is hard so for this
reason Computing gxr for a given Matrix
is a hard problem similarly sxr is
related to Optimal pivoting using
gaussian and elimination it is also a
hard problem so Computing sxr of a given
Matrix is also a hard problem
the most popular choice for designing a
diffusion layers is four by four block
MDS matrices where the entry is coming
from GL and F2 the least cost of a known
Matrix in the case of n equal to 4 is 35
and it is 67 in the case of n equal to
8. the main question here is whether we
can get better matrices it is still an
open problem what we do in this work is
we establish that this is the best that
we can achieve if you consider the
numeric swxr
now we present some preliminary results
used in establishing the lower bound
as you know Elementary matrices are
related to Elementary row operations and
these are obtained by applying
Elementary row operations on the
identity Matrix the block identity
Matrix of order M over JL and F2 is
denoted by inm so this is nothing but
identity Matrix of order MN over the
binary field and viewing it is in a
block form there are three types of
Elementary matrices corresponding to
three types of Elementary row operations
the first one corresponds to
interchanging to rows of a matrix the
second one corresponds to multiplying
the row by a non-zero scalar the third
one corresponds to adding a scalar
multiple of a row to the another row
these are denoted by e i j e i j of a e
i j of B where a B in the case of block
matrices these are n by n matrices and
these are known as coefficients and I J
are the indices
here B can be singular but we wanted a
matrix decompositions using type 3
matrices with non-singular coefficient
matrices as you all know from linear
algebra any non-singular Matrix can be
decomposed as a product of Elementary
matrices even in the case of block
Matrix if it is non-singular it can be
written as a product of Elementary block
matrices of type 1 type 2 type 3 where
type 2 and type 3 Matrix coefficient
matrices are non singular
as you all know a matrix can have
variety of decompositions given a
decomposition
uh one can reorder these Elementary
matrices by using these identities here
you can observe that multiplying a type
2 or type 3 matrix by a type 1 Matrix
simply changes the coefficient the
indices of the type 2 type 3 matrices
but there is no change in type
coefficients similarly multiplying a
Type 3 Matrix with type 2 there is a
change in the coefficient but there is
no change in the
indices of the type 3 matrices using
these identities we can reorder the uh
Elementary matrices in a given
decomposition
using the first limit one can move all
the type 1 matrices to the left or right
are by appropriately changing the
coefficients of the uh the appropriately
changing the indices of the type 2 and
type 3 matrices so that we can get a
decomposition of this form where p is a
block permutation Matrix corresponding
to the all the type 1 Elementary block
matrices and the remaining portion is
product of only type 1 type 3 mattresses
using the second gamma we can move all
the type 2 matrices to the left and get
a decomposition of this form where p is
a block permutation Matrix D is a block
diagonal matrix which is the product of
type 2 matrices by appropriately
modifying the coefficient but there is
no change in the indices of the type 3
matrices this is the portion of product
of type 3 matrices
we can have this kind of decompositions
and given a decomposition one can easily
compute MX by applying G1 to GK at
relatively and the input Vector X so the
cost of implementing m is equal to the
sum of the cost of the implementing J1
to GM GK
the sxr cost of type 1 Matrix is zero
because it is simply a permutation sxr
cost of a type 2 Matrix is equal to sxr
of its coefficient Matrix a in the case
of type 3 Matrix the sxr of type 3
Matrix is equal to n if B is a
permutation Matrix if it is not a
permutation Matrix it is greater than or
equal to n plus one
similar to the sxr we consider
decompositions of the sperm where p is a
block permutation Matrix since its cost
is zero we want to separate it and look
at the other portion which is a product
of type 2 and type 3 matrices with
non-singular coefficients yes swxr of
the block Matrix m is minimum overall
such decompositions of this form
we can also see that given a block
Matrix and we get a variety of matrices
which have the same swxr cost Erp is our
block permutation Matrix disr block
diagonal matrix whose entries are again
permutation matrices over F2
and the inverse of M and M transpose
also have a the same swxr cost not only
that these four matrices are also MDS if
m is MDS and also they preserve the cost
swx are costs
now we discuss the main ideas
uh in settling the lower bound
in our search technique
a path of length L is an ordered list of
Elementary block matrices of type 3
ignoring the coefficient matrices so you
can view it as an order list of tuples
consisting of row and column indices of
the type 3 matrices
The Matrix generated by this path is
having a decomposition of the sperm
where we have this type 3 form and we at
take p and Q to B Block permutation
matrices and D to be a block diagonal
matrix a matrix having this kind of
decomposition is belonged to this path
or this Matrix can be generated by this
path
similarly
we can also consider this kind of paths
because a type 2 Matrix if you want to
reorder type a product of five to one
type three it doesn't alter the indices
of the type 3 matrices because we are
only worried about the indices we can
also consider decompositions of this
pump either you consider this
decomposition or this decomposition
Matrix having this this composition we
say that it is belonging to this path B
the mattress can have variety of
decompositions so mattress can be
generated by variety of paths
we want to see what are all the paths
that we can generate the same set of
matrices
observe that
in the product of two type 3 matrices
they commute with each other if the
indices satisfy this relation it has no
dependency on the coefficients if it
satisfies this relation so in a path if
the indices satisfies this relation you
can reorder these elements and then the
reordered path also generate the same
set of matrices
not only that if you have in a path if
two consecutive elements having the same
indices they can be clubbed together to
a single element so the path of length L
can be reduced to a path of length L
minus one that also generate the same
set of matrices another way of getting
New Paths to which is generate the same
set of matrices is by applying a
permutation on the indices of the given
path this is called a conjugate of the
path because we consider all the permit
all possible permutations here that
actually makes we can incorporate this
also so this way this path also generate
the same set of matrices
so using these relations we Define what
are known as equivalence classes of this
path
suppose we have two parts of the same
length the path B is equivalent to path
B Prime if it is a conjugate of a path
obtained by iterative will applying
valid exchanges on the path B what do
you mean by valid exchange if you two
consecutive elements commute with each
other then you simply reorder those
elements like that you can apply
sequence of these reorderings and then
finally take a conjugation you get the
path as you can see from the earlier
discussion these two paths generate the
same set of matrices
if B is equal into B Prime then they
both generate the same set of matrices
this way we can Club several parts into
an equivalence class and now we Club few
more such equivalence classes to extend
these equivalence classes
given a path b and a matrix generated by
this path p m inverse can be given by
this decomposition M transpose has this
decomposition and you can see that these
are related to this path
simply reversing this order of this path
you can see that this m inverse is
generated by this path and simply
exchanging the column and row indices of
this entries we get that inverse of the
transpose Matrix is generated by this
path
so we Club all these four
into an extended equivalence class the
main result here is
if you take two parts in an external
equivalence class and if one path can
generate an MDS Matrix and you can also
get a MDS Matrix using the other path
because if m is MDS all these matrices
are also MDS not only that they all have
the same cost so if you can generate a
matrix MDS Matrix using One path having
some cost then you can also generate an
MDS Matrix with other path having the
same cost so
you can if you want to search for low
cost MDS matrices it is enough to test
for only representative one
representative path of these equivalence
classes and this greatly reduces the
search technique
such complexity so we use this idea to
search low cost matrices
from the wrong address paper we know
that the smallest path that can generate
MDS matrices is of length 8.
first they actually searched for
matrices over the finite field F2 to the
power n searching all the paths of
length eight there are 12 Power 8 paths
and the best that they can get is having
cost eight and plus three so this match
is the known result they could not
improve the known matrices then they try
to search over gel four F2 or glnf2
their search complexity is huge so they
could not establish whether there exist
matrices with complex with cost less
than or equal to and eight n plus two
what we do in this work is we present an
algorithm to identify potential parts of
length 8 that can generate MDS matrices
as discussed it is enough to test only
representative parts of the extended
equivalence classes so we see that
finally there are only two such paths up
to Extended equivalence class that can
generate MDS matrices by applying some
Transformations and we see that
even these two parts we cannot generate
generate four by four block matrices
having cost eight n plus two
there are 12 Power 8 paths because there
are 12 type 3 matrices and
we want to check for potential paths
that can generate MDS matrices first we
eliminate all those paths that can be
shortened uh that means only
pass of length less than 8 cannot
generate MDS matrices so we eliminate
all those paths then from the remaining
path we consider only representative
Paths of this extended equivalence
classes then we search only those
representative set of paths symbolically
whether they can verify MDS matrices you
can check the paper for the details we
use symbolic computation uh treating
these elements as of a free algebra on
the indeterminants of the coefficient
matrices out of this 12 Power 8 paths
only two non equivalent paths remain
which can generate MDS matrices
now we take these two paths ah presented
here the representatives of those two
equivalence classes and we check whether
these two paths can generate
MDS matrices with cost less than or
equal to 8 and plus 2.
we consider the first path and a matrix
uh generated by a first part is of this
form like this and the coefficient
matrices are
given by this as and B's if their exist
a matrix with cost eight n plus 2
what we can have is only at most two of
these coefficient Matrix can be non
permutation all others must be
permutation matrices because there are
eight type three matrices uh A10 is
already fixed and only you can have
additional two so only two of these
coefficient matrices can be non
permutation all the remaining are
permutation matrices there are 36
matrices there are 24 permutations if
you want to adjust your research it's
huge task what we do is we just look at
the elements of this form like this
which are some of two monomials and we
look for all such elements in M and M
inverse observe that if
this The observed expression the
bracketed portion this is a sum of two
monomials if all these efficient
matrices are permutation matrices then
this sum becomes singular Matrix so
because sum of two permutations is a
singular Matrix if we want this to be
non-singular Matrix then at least one of
the coefficient Matrix appearing here in
this expression must be non-similar
Matrix this way we are identify which
pair of elements can be non-singular
matrices non permutation matrices and we
identify that only there exists only one
one pair of elements that is B4 and B5
can be non permutation and all the
remains must be permutations if you want
to have a matrix with 8N Plus 2.
we will then further apply some
Transformations and then verify whether
with such a choice whether we can get a
MDS Matrix even this fails in the case
of testing two by two sub matrices
so what we see is we check similarly the
other path what we see is both these
paths cannot generate MDS matrices whose
cost is less than or equal to 8 n Plus
2. so what we see is that the minimum
swx or cost of four by four block MDS
Matrix must be at least eight n Plus 3.
by using extended equivalence classes
and some Transformations we are able to
establish the lower bound on the cost of
four by four block numbers matrices
under this metric swxr cost metric if
you want to get better matrices you have
to use other metrics such as sxr or gxr
in this metric in this search Technique
we have not considered a depth parameter
by including depth parameter one can
search for
uh low cost matrices and also uh this is
we we only work with four by four
matrices if you want we can extend these
ideas for higher order matrices but the
such complexity grows drastically so we
can probably use some heuristic
techniques to search for low cost
matrices in higher order matrices
uh that's all thank you for our
attention
so do we have questions in Beijing we
have maybe just time for one question
they're the question in Beijing
okay
hello uh hello in the previous work uh
once I told the pro are they proved uh
some lower bounds or not only the MDS
matrices but also the emulatory Matrix
so I want to know if your method can be
used in The evolutionary matrices
yeah we can use this technique
okay but uh in the previous I try to use
the method in the involutely but the
effects maybe not code in the MDS in
matrices
so I think it can all that we have to do
is we have to actually take permutations
into consideration we have to insert
permutation in between so that we can
make involutely matrices because type 1
mattresses uh changes the indices of the
type 3 matrices so we have to uh this is
actually we are also looking into this
kind of uh
approach to find a low cost involutely
MDS matrices yeah okay uh I think maybe
the problem or the swxr yeah thank you
thank you yeah
okay thank you I think we don't have
more time for other questions so let's
thank the speaker again
all right
so then let's talk of the session will
be more input makes difference
implementation of linear layers using
gates with more than two inputs
this is a paper written by Kun you weija
Wang lingson
sorry young Hong fan
and the speaker will be conglu
in Beijing
you have to share the screen
if possible
19 years
[Music]
much
there are any technical issues
yep because also known everyone uh
okay it's an honor for me to present
your paper today and it's a joint work
with one without swinging final
12 from day six suspects and let's start
by start uh discussing some background
information and first type of question
for you how to apply a ciphers in
results constraint devices
yeah that's why we are interested in the
language photography
in recent years the live choreography
has become a major focus in the
cryptography Community due to the rapid
development of the library devices such
as the internal things and radio
frequency artificial types and these
devices has a limited resources in terms
of the circular size the power
consumption and the latency therefore we
have to expand the limitation to these
devices and generally speaking the
direction is divided there are two
directions now first we can design new
language primitive
that can efficient in hardware and
software efficient
and another method it's optimize the
existing implications that can Aid in
designing new parameters and the
criteria is about the power energy
support area and latency and in practice
the diffusion and configuring components
are relevant to the linear and
non-linear operations and in this paper
I work mainly focuses on the area of the
linear layers such as the mixed columns
in AES
and then we talk about the motivation
and contributions and this is the
astronaut function and the MC in the
mixed columns and if we can reduce the
area of the mixed columns we can
significantly reduce the area of the ASR
function to illustrate this point we
show the example
for example we have a terrible circuits
it requires eight extras and if white
Source requires 2D the circuit requires
16g but
for our optimization method we can get a
new circuit it only have four
extraordinates and have the numberology
so this example demonstrates that after
optimization method we can we can reduce
the area of the cipher
there are many work to optimize the
limit linear layers but most of them
focus on the two input cell circuits as
we all know the standard libraries can
support three input textures or for
input Gates so we can use multiple games
to reduce the area further and there are
two methods to do this
one method is proposed by back Center a
search circuit directly but it increased
the searching space
because as a large number of extra times
and another method is proposed by
bending control it either transforms
directly to convert the circuits using
two inputs into the circuit using three
inputs and circuits but it may require
more candidates to get better circuits
and our our paper follows this line of
work and propose the transforming
framework it can transform a circuit
using it with no more than inputs into
the circuits you engage with no more
than n plus one inputs the framework
require a graphic standing algorithm and
we can see the figure first we have a
given circuit with admin protectors and
then we use the graphic designing
algorithm to generate the file
equivalent circuits or maybe 500 some
thousands that is impossible and then we
use the framework to do uh to convert
the circuits into many new settings with
M plus one input textures and then we
can choose the best one with the lowest
area as our results and we apply the
framework to many in linear layers to
our blood ciphers such as es two fish
and Tall with two three four inputs
extra case and this is our exam
experiments which has
51 and
5500 messages the BP is using two inputs
Aggregates and the e3283 is our
algorithm using multiples of
on average the area on each Matrix is
reduced by 21 percent
and then we talk about some new aspects
for SRP problem the SRP problem is
defined as finding a solution with a
minimum number and Outsource to compute
the multiplication of the Matrix and it
has many applications such as the
optimization the computational geometry
and the operations research but it is
proven to be NP hard so no efficient
algorithm can solve it exactly and but
there are many heuristics to find the
sub-optimal solutions
but we have a new question the SRP
problem focus on the minimum access but
we focus on the low exterior it's
different so we propose the sopa problem
is as a problem with the lowest area we
use the Epsilon operation as operation
containing Epsilon to include a circuits
then given the cost of every operation
the metric is defined as the following
question using the following equation we
can find the lower area of the circuits
and then we provide two definitions and
first is the d80 addressing the cycling
graph is directed graph that has no
cycles and it's important when you cycle
because it was graphic cycle as a wrong
in Hardware we cannot implementing a
hardware and another definition is the
topological ordering it can help us to
control nodes in correct ordering and
then we talk about the graphic sending
algorithm we can see the example the
node 0 to the seven is the input noise
or the unit nodes and the following
equation represents the circuit requires
10 extra case now for example the ta01
means the nose is in the sum of the node
zero and the one and the underlying on
you know 12 is
represents the no tell in the output
values or the target value I will use
the example to show our technique first
we introduce two dimension in the single
graph is a directory graph so that it's
not a union nodes has only one
impeditions this the single graph like
the equation one it is an intentionally
used in Hardware to implements the
linear layer another definition is
extended graph in extended graph each
node can have more than one picture like
the equation two we can see the notion
is the sum of node 4 and the file or the
summer node 14 and no switching so it
cannot be used in Hardware but we will
use it to optimize our limitations and
this is the method to generate the
external graph and the graph use the
determination of the reachability sets
on the right in the table for for each
node there is at least one path from the
nose to its visibility set and then next
question is how to split the extended
graph because the external graph is
wrong in Hardware we cannot use it so we
propose a simple method we can choose
every implementation of the nodes in
extended graph we can see the example in
gs0 the No 7 in the sum or no 13 and 14
and gs31 the Note 7 is is
a difference and use our method in our
example we can generate 32 single graphs
based on the extended graph and next
we need to do some first optimization
after splitting the extended graph that
knows in different single graphs may
have different in degrees and our
degrees the L degree 0 means that the
nose is not used to generate it other
nodes so maybe we can remove it and we
will give the property to check if a
node is redundant and we use the method
in our example in the 32 grams we found
12 graphs have one redundant nodes and
two graphs have two redundant nodes and
we remove that but that's where it's had
the final result we found some graphs
are wrong the wrong graphing is in fact
circuit for the corresponding Matrix
which usually contains the Cycles in the
graph I see the example on the right in
the figure the node e node F and node T
consists of a cycle so it's wrong in
Hardware we cannot use the figure to
implement the
linear layers in Hardware so we checked
all the graphs in our example we found
only 16 graphers around and 16 graphs
are right in the right graphs we find
four graphs has a nine extra percent we
listed them and we can choose any one as
our best results and can see can be
optimized by our framework and this is
the algorithm they have it have four
steps first we need to generate the
extended graph based on the single graph
that is the image position of the linear
layer and then we need to split the
extended graph into many equivalent
circuits and then we need to remove a
redundant nodes and finally we need to
delete run graphs and we can send this
graphs can be optimized by our framework
and next we'll introduce the
transforming framework
uh before we introduce the transforming
framework we need to do some limitation
for example if we use G3 extra metrics
only two three four inputs extra case
can be used use this implementation can
reduce the searching space and then we
can do the transformation from the
equation of the left to the equation on
the right
other transformation the area of the
circuit is reduced and before we
introduce framework we have through
question we need to answer the first
question is which node can be removed
when we receive a implementation of the
linear layers and the question two is
how to remove windows when we found the
nodes can be removed and the third
question is when we found both nodes can
be removed which nodes should be removed
first and if we answer through question
the transforming framework is
has been done so we tried to answer the
questions and the first question which
note can be removed will provide the
conversation suppose that the circuit
has been if G is from xor Matrix and the
in degree and our degree of the null u
means the conversation so scenario can
be removed and for the first second
question how to remove OneNote we also
provide the proposition uh suppose uh
give a circuit with a two input Central
gears so it can reduce the circuits by
removing the nodes with algebrae and and
see the example the no U has out degree
2 and if the condition is right we can
remove you and adding two three protect
circuits and the area of the new circuit
is lower and the third question which
node should be removed first the
proposition can answer our question
suppose the upper balance and for
example if the algebra or U is M algebra
or no U unknown V is n if m is greater
than n we can remove it first remove the
node V will reduce more constant than no
U and then we answer three questions so
we propose the algorithms using three
inputs answer keys
um and then is an example using four
inputs and circuits uh if the audio is
one with the first figure and out degree
2 will the second figure and if the art
degree is greater than two we can use
the same method to do it and this is a
algorithm using four input actors and it
has four steps first we receive the
imitation of the linear layer with two
inputs Gates and then we use the graph
standing algorithm to generate many
equivalent circuits with two input
skills and then we use three inputs
extra guests to optimize the circuits
after that we need to we also need to
use the graphics linear Rhythm to
generate many equivalent circuits with
three input Central keys and finally we
use the transforming framework using
four input circuits and generate many
circuits with lower
area of the circuit so we can choose any
one as our the best friends the best
results and finally when can show the
application we apply our method methods
to many linear layers of the images such
as es The Joy tick the two fish at all
and
for example we we see the es if we only
use who inputs extra keys like the hdrbz
the error is greater than 300 and if we
use multiple Keys like the XC LBZ plus
e83 the area is reduced to
243 areas so that's all thanks for
attention
thank you
um do we have question in Beijing
yeah the other question in Beijing
I
hope that the linearly respect
mountain in Portuguese but for the Xbox
I want to know if you try to do Sim work
yeah you see as both circuits yeah
we do some work in the exports circuits
for example the buyer at all provides
the circuit in
2010 it's it's circus has divided into
three parts the first part and the third
party the linear layer and the second
part is the non-linear year we can use
our framework tool is to linear layers
using fluid protector Gates or for input
circus and we can get a little
Improvement using the multi-in
protectors but for other types of other
types of like it's like the endings or
the organs uh we live without the future
work we hope to generate a general
framework with more types of the kids in
career thank you thank you thank you
any other question
yeah there is a question from Beijing
um hello Mr Leo I just want to know uh
you know the latency is a very important
effect where we need to consider when we
design designing a circuit I just want
to know whether you algorithm can reduce
the depth of a circle you mean the depth
or the circuit yeah yeah
as you know the latency is also
important in hardware and the depth is
relevant to the lenses so I think our
can find a better
listening outside by circuits with lower
latency maybe we can see the slide
yeah uh you know first we have the uh we
we received single graphs and then we
use our graphic standing algorithm to
generate many equivalent circuits and
after our optimization method we
generates many
better searches with a lower area
and if we focus on the latency or the
test or the circuits we can also choose
one from our the many equivalent
circuits and maybe the depth is reduced
I think the method can help you
uh okay thank you thank you thank you so
much
any other question
okay I have one one question
um did you try to look at your results
uh coming from your from your your Tool
uh when you compare them with the Ros
synthesizers so if you put the metrics
give it as inputs to to one synthesizer
did you try to see uh what what uh great
equivalency it will give in the ends
like if you try different optimization
in the end did you try like hard really
uh really uh important optimization with
uh with uh with hardware tools
uh sorry I I do not quickly get your
question but you mean the multiples uh
greater than four and
or yeah so
so so when you like do you really try to
do a lot of optimization with your
sanitizer using uh like different gates
with a larger uh number of uh
we have not do this work we in first
work I will focus on the linear layers
so it only requires the actual case and
for other types of extras but the type
of other types of link is maybe more
complex and we have not ideal to do this
you know sorry my body is just that if
you use a synthesizer they might be able
to optimize your circuit as well even
though it's just a source it might be
able to potentially provide improvements
um
I think it's the
our method we can only use the some
libraries and not all the libraries
because some in some libraries the three
input sector case requires more area
than two three percent circuits
okay thank you yeah thank you
all right if no more question then let's
thank the speaker and all the speakers
of this session