all the new construction and this
section will have two talks the next
talks is the title is short
variable course from Red Key security
problem Cipher the visited and the talk
will be given by the speaker Antonio
Daniel from from France so let's reopen
Antonio fanio
good morning everyone first of all could
you all uh hear me loud and clear
yes
oh perfect so I'm gonna start
so good morning again so I'm going to
present this joint work with John Luca
Brian uh joao Ribeiro and Daniela
Venturi I'm Antonio fonio right now in
France at 3am so you know excuse me
sometime I look a bit sleepy
the wood
okay so uh brief history of this project
so this project uh
starts around here where you see my
mouse
oops
I guess now you know can you still hear
me loud and clear
it cannot leave you guys sorry I will
have to post a second
okay sorry I'm back
okay so as I was saying this project has
start around here where you can see my
mouse
and in around here we discovered about
this nice paper by uh Fair Cartman and
Manic and this paper is about the normal
level code and it has some nice
interesting uh new uh security property
from from the block ciphers from which
we they can construct on a new malleable
cost and since we were interesting you
know malleability we decided to use the
framework to you know yet another
project a different project from the one
that I'm presented right now on uh on
normal ability so we write a paper we
wrote a paper we submit it to task 21.
everything seemed too well until the
reviewer arrived the reviewers were kind
of nice and they were so nice that they
even found an attack on our paper uh and
by the way this attack was not just an
attack on our paper but it was after an
attack on
um
cryptographic Assumption of this paper
from a fair government many and so we
were here kind of in a uh you know in a
crossroad we had to decide what to do
and what we decided to do was to fix the
paper from
fkm18 and so that's what we did with the
fixed paper uh we so the reviewers she
pointed us through some other attacks to
the attack that was originally by
Bernstein in 2010 and then it was uh
extended the formalized by uh Albert
fashion Patterson Watson in 11 so you
read that these papers and we went back
to work and we fixed the Afghan paper we
submitted it again at task 22 and um
here presenting it so
I guess this is a a nice uh story a nice
story of the reviewing process
yeah by the way thanks to the reviewer
the anonymous reviewer
so this paper is about normal level code
the normal level code is an encoding
scheme so cruel and encoding scheme you
can encode a message and then you can
decode the message about correctness if
you include a message you decode the
same message and the important property
from a normal code is this normal
ability property this normal ability
property says that if you encode a
message and then there is a tampering
function that modify your message and
get a new codeword and then you try to
record the code this tilde you obtain a
message and tilde and now this message
until this either the same message of
before which means that the stumbling
function didn't do much or if it is
another different codeword it has to be
completely uncode related respect to the
original code word
so
it's easy to see that the normal level
code are impossible without any further
restriction in fact if someone
as a full power of a tampering function
that can decode the the code word and
for example for example adds to the
message plus one and then encode again
the code word this codeword will be the
message and the line is called with the
city that would be highly correlated to
the original message
so we need to put some restriction on
the kind of tampering function
and the kind of restriction that are
considered in the in the
in the literature is this uh one of the
kind of conditions that are considered
in the literature there is this speed
State model where basically we assume
that the code work can be passed in two
parts c0 and C1 and now the tampering
function are applied separately on a c0
and C1 so there is a company function F0
on c0 and a thumbprint function F1 on C1
at least two terminal functional
Independence and they don't do not
communicate
and
uh and then you know the the same game
of the normal ability and this in this
model we can construct a normal level
codes and indeed the paper of uh F uh of
uh fair cutman and many present a very
interesting uh normal code in uh in this
setting so they consider a very nice
intuitive uh scheme which based on a box
Cipher which basically say okay let's
encode a message by sampling a fresh
random key and then by using a block
Cipher as a PRP to encode the message by
you know creating a cipher text using
the block ciphers on K key and on the on
the message that we want to import
and then the decoding functions the
triviality you stick back your key and
you Decode by decrypting it
and they the the the the point of this
paper was uh by looking at this natural
malleable code what are the security
properties that we need from the Block
Cipher so that this normalable code is
secure
and the two security properties that
they came up with and that were
sufficient for the work where uh PRP
with leakage meaning appear that is
leakage to the ceiling and uh notion
what they call it the fixed related key
security
and the attack that I mentioned at the
very beginning of this talk uh break
this fixed related key security so let's
go to see this uh notion a bit uh more
uh in detail
so this notion basically says that there
is a game in which uh you know there is
the the fresh key the flash key can be
tampered and you can create a key key
tilde which is you know the thumbnail
key and now the adversary can be two
different words in the real world he
gets to play with a left Oracle in which
there is the original t and the PRP and
in the right word there is the template
key we can interact with these two uh
Oracle now a study in the in the ideal
World it can play with a random
permutation on one side and with another
random permutation in the other side now
if the two keys are the different than
the two random permutation has to be
different and also there is a constraint
on the template key so the taranteed key
cannot be too probable so another way to
say is that the function
and tampering function cannot affect too
many a fixed point
and this is a necessary condition
now that we see the notion let's see
what is the attack proposed by
bernestine and then uh formalized by fbw
11n from the uh you know that we got to
know through the reviewer so the attack
is uh a big contrived from my point of
view
so the attack should
set the pump key as the block Cipher on
the original key
executed on message equal to zero zero
zero zero or any fixed value is okay and
this is why I say that it's a big
contrived because you know in the in the
literature of actual comparing attack uh
this kind of sampling function seems a
bit you know a bit out of the the
capability of what a tampering function
can do but nevertheless in a theoretical
framework this time frame function is is
a perfectly okay function
now that we set the temperature in this
way the attack Works in two phases so
the first phase is the extract phase and
the second phase is the check face and
in the extract phase what happened is
that uh the
adversary can query is left Oracle with
the message zero zero zero zero now if
it is if the investor is in the real
world by querying it with this message
what it happens is that it will extract
from the uh Oracle the thumbprint key
instead if it's in the real world well
what happened is that they will get a
random value
then there is a second part of the
attack which is called the check
step in this check step what it does is
that now I have my key which is the
temperature Key most probably if I if
I'm in the real world and I'm just gonna
check that is indeed the thumbnail key
so I locally can encrypt a message for
example one one one with the with my key
and then I query the template Oracle to
see if what the encrypted match what
what the Oracle tells me and if I'm in
the real world this uh check will hold
with probability one if I'm in the real
the real world instead this check will
all do with probability very low so I
can distinguish between these two words
and this is this attack
so the notion of frk security uh is uh
is doesn't know
so what we did
in our work was to try to fix the notion
of fixed related key security and we did
it to two fixes the first fix is trying
to avoid the extraction step of the
burners
so the to do that we avoid uh we delete
the Oracle access of the adversary to
the left Oracle meaning the Oracle with
the original key
of course if you talk of this Oracle now
maybe the notional uh become trivials so
we still want to give information to the
adversary about the original key and to
do that we take the game we divided in
you know a two-phase scheme in the first
phase uh distribution sampler can sample
a bunch of messages which are to be
random but not uniformly random they
just have to have some entropy
uh example these messages and and then
in the The Challenger
either encrypt the messages with the
with uh with the block Cipher or you
will encrypt the messages with a random
permutation and then the second phase of
the game starts
now through to this uh this fix we know
we should assure that the adversity
cannot perform the first step of the
uh but maybe this is not enough
so what we did next is try to avoid also
the second step of that so in the second
step of the attack the adversary can
locally test if the extracted key match
the temperature
and air uh
so it can encrypt the key and then you
can go to the right Oracle And if either
the right if the right Oracle is the
random permutation the check will not
hold so what we do is that instead of
giving a role access to a random
permutation in the in the DL world in
the other word we give access to the
tampering function to the block Cipher
on the template key itself so now these
two words beside what are the the
encryption the the ciphertext have the
same Oracle access so if you want to do
a check that depends on the on the on
the on the
on the Oracle this check should
give the same answer right so in this
way we try to avoid the second part of
the attack
uh of course this uh this might be not
enough so we proposed these two fixes
oh no sorry okay yeah here I am so now
if you look at this uh fix uh we also
gain some Simplicity in the definition
because in the original definition there
was the point in which uh the constraint
in which uh you know the tampering
function cannot have too many a fixed
point and the point was that
this condition was necessary because
there was this there is another attack
in which uh you know if the tampering
function has a lot of fixed Point what I
can do is that for example let's suppose
that there is a a k k bar which is very
probable I can adjust the assume that uh
in the real world I got access to a
dampering uh to the to the block Cipher
with this uh K Bar
a key set so I can just check if this
indeed the key that I'm that I'm
worried and even if any if I am in the
real world this probability is quite
high and therefore I can distinguish
between the real world and the real
world and because of uh this attack uh
we had in the in the regional definition
we had to have this constraint but now
in the new definition we have in both
cases uh other collapses to the to the
the block Saturn with the temperature so
this attacker doesn't hold so this
attack does not hold and therefore we
don't need this constraint
okay so just to summarize and then
Tropic fixes really the key a security
notion that we put forward in this work
uh just uh you know is the very similar
to the previous one there's the Stampede
key then there is a bunch of messages
that are sampled from a distribution
this message has to be random but they
don't have to be uniformly random just
they need to have some entropy and then
the adversary can play with a tampering
Oracle and it can distinguish between he
has to distinguish if we got some good
side effects so some real sci-fi attacks
or some you know software that's made
with a random permutation
but you can see the paper for the
details
so our first result is to show in the uh
edl Cipher model that our definition
holds true so by doing that we assure
that there are no black box attack on
our definition which means that our
definition should is secure it should be
secure enough same practice
and okay so in the dsfl model we
consider this uh the same definition of
before but we also give our local access
to the adversary to this ideal Cipher
and the most important part is that we
also give access to the tampering
function to the uh to the uh with the
Earth cycle this is very important
because you know the attack of Bernstein
worked because the function had a
capability of computing the the block
side so we need to have a block cycle
dependent sampling function and in this
model we can prove security as you can
see there are some some numbers here
but I would say it's quite of a tight
reduction
okay next
now that we have our sound and safe
assumption we went back to the idea of
uh uh Fair uh kathman and Manic and we
slightly modified the encoding scheme
and so uh
to encode a message what we do is that
we put on the left side the fresh key
and on the
right side we'll do an encryption of the
message but that with some Randomness so
you have a random thing that you put on
the message which because we needed a
bit of entry in the messages this is how
we add this a bit of entry and this is
our encoding so K and the Sci-Fi text
Sigma and to the code we do you know the
trivial thing so we use the key to
decrypt we receive a message on some pad
and what we need to do is just to you
know remove this path and out
and we have a theorem to show that if
the
uh encryption scheme where if the block
Cipher is uh in public uh fixed rather
key secure then the normal level code is
secure as well and as you can see that
the uh the the the the the result is
quite tight uh and here we need to only
it was one query to the to the dumpling
protocol and one message to be encrypted
and that's it
uh thank you
uh so is there any question or comment
from Beijing
and maybe from Kobe any question or
comment from Kobe
yeah one question
okay
hello thank you for the presentation
um
so I have one question so
um Your solution is to add your
Randomness in the primitive
um so I'm Bard by the way
um so one thing we thought of when we we
saw the the issue with with the model
was to just instead of
um putting the key in the first part
split the key and for instance gamma
would consists of like a normal block
Cipher encryption with one half of the
key and the other half would be the top
part does that also work or do you see
what I mean
so uh so if you could go to one of the
beginning slides where you had the
picture
a slide four or five I forgot the number
uh maybe here okay yeah whatever so yeah
this guy so the key what happens if you
would for instance split the key in two
and one half of them is concatenated in
the gamma would that also work or
do you see yeah we we look at into this
actually uh we we ask
uhman uh and I think uh we we we
couldn't we we couldn't approve it but
uh we didn't put so much effort also
improve it but yes because this this
would be another solution right it
probably will be also a bit more
efficient because there is this notion
I'm sorry I'm not a big expert in Block
Cipher but this is notion of tweakable
uh uh block Cipher which I think would
match this notion uh better right
yes yeah it's a difference but this
comparable solution indeed yes yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah actually it would be nice
to prove it secure but we didn't manage
uh to do it secure I don't remember a
lot of the details but uh you was in in
the in the you know in the reduction of
uh
to the ideal Cipher model we've we had
it was a bit more complicated to handle
because I mean in our solution we
encrypt the key so we have kind of a
layer
more of uh protection because this key
is is a is encrypted now but yeah that
would be cool in fact
okay yeah thank you I have no other
questions
yeah thank you and any question any
additional question
maybe due to the time limitation we can
move to the next talk and give you any
question you can maybe send an email to
a speaker
so thanks
okay bye
and you can stop sharing your screen oh
so the next talk is uh SCP mode
semantically secure lens blazing
encryption
and the talk will be given by fabinho uh
Buffy from Switzerland and he will keep
the talk in quebe so this way open the
speaker sabinio Buffet
hello yeah so hi thanks for introduction
my name is Fabio Banfi and I'm going to
present SCP mode semantically secure
length preserving encryption
um
okay it's working so yes this is
the structure of the presentation I will
begin with some background and
motivation then I will introduce the
concept of length preserving encryption
slash and ciphering I will explain later
what the difference is after that I will
introduce a new scheme SCB mode which is
a semantically secure LP and in the end
we will have conclusions
so let's start with the background in
motivation so we all know that we
usually construct encryption schemes
using uh modes of operations which
transform block ciphers into encryption
schemes
thanks
um
so this seems to be has stopped working
now
thanks guys thanks so much
sorry about that so yes uh in most of
operation we usually
um have some input message which which
we assume is composed of blocks of
length n
and from this we then compute The Cypher
text which as usually some expansion so
it's going to be again a sequence of
blocks of length n plus some Lambda bits
where Lambda we call this the expansion
Factor
so a very famous insecure way is of
course the ECB mode the electronic code
boot mode
where essentially we have zero expansion
and the idea is that we simply and
Cipher every block of the message to
obtain our ciphertext so therefore again
the length of the ciphertext is going to
be the same as the one of the message on
the other hand a secure way is for
example CBC where the expansion factor
is exactly the block length n
and the idea here will be the first
sample a random block of n Bits this
will be actually what accounts for the
expansion because this is then included
as part of ciphertext so these are extra
n Bits And then for the for the
remaining blocks we use the previous
block as a pad and then we encipher the
current block of the input message
so again here we see that the resulting
ciphertext has uh is formed of L plus
one blocks
and of course both schemes can actually
be adapted via a technique called
ciphertextiling into encryption schemes
for messages of arbitrary length not
only for messages of length multiple of
a block Cipher
so let's go to motivation now from the
previous slides and questions should
actually come up naturally why isn't it
possible to have kind of both of these
nice features namely Security in the
sense of in CPS Security but also uh
zero expansion or length preservation
uh and I want to argue now that this is
actually something that might be also
useful in practice what if for example
we have the following scenario where we
have many short messages that need to be
transmitted that communication is
expensive so in more detail for example
consider a case in which every day we
have to transmit some M messages
also assume that each message consists
of B blocks this quantity will be
defined by the underlying block Cipher
now with a conventional lean CPA scheme
the resulting number of transmitted
blocks will be M times B plus 1 whereas
if we would have an encryption scheme
which is length preserving so without
expect any expansion the number of
transmitted blocks will be just n times
B so now we see that if B is very small
compared to M then the cost kind of of
the secure scheme is twice as much as
the one of uh of the skin without
expansion
so again the question is can we actually
avoid expansion but retain semantic
security
well this is something that seems
impossible but spoiler alert is actually
not
so uh for this we need to introduce
lengths preserving encryption schemes so
uh
again this seems to be impossible so
let's see why this is the case
it seems that
if we enforce an encryption scheme to
have a zero expansion then this actually
needs to be a deterministic function
which we all know can't possibly be in
CPA secure
so in fact if that would be the case
then essentially we have that for any
possible length this algorithm will be
implementing a permutation over bit
strings of length t
so this is actually something that in
reality in cryptography is actually
studied this is sometimes called length
preserving encryption but maybe should
be also uh more appropriately be called
length preserving and ciphering since
again this is a deterministic process
and it is also sometimes called variable
input length
block Cipher
but back to our question we want to
achieve more than just PRP security from
such a scheme here
so this is actually possible because we
can do something about correctness
namely we can relax it and instead of
requiring correctness of such a scheme
to be perfect we can require it to be
only computational
so in this case then obviously EK can't
be a permutation anymore on any length
or with strings of lengthy and also it
seems that it should be a stateful
algorithm
and so let's define the syntax of this
object now
so what we have is a pair of algorithms
one for encryption and one from the for
decryption they both take a beat string
as input and also some State and we'll
output again some bit string and some
updated state so we have different
states for encryption and decryption
now the requirement of these two and
these two algorithms are as follows so
for any uh key for any encryption State
s and for any decryption state t
we first of all need that these two
algorithms are efficiently computable
and also we need that again they
preserve the length so this means for
example for encryption that on inputs on
message M and some State s we want that
the resulting ciphertext has the same
length as the input message and here the
state
is something that is kept privately by
the sender it's not something that is
transmitted to the receiver
so in the following slides I will use
this notation to indicate that we
encrypt the message M under some key K
and some State s resulting in server
text C but we also then on the side
update the state s to the output state
and also importantly note that in this
definition unlike usually one does there
is no hard-coded notion of correctness
in fact this will be a separate uh
property that we will have to Define
later
so yeah let's define now security and
correctness for such a scheme where this
denotes the empty state
so for security we Define this in terms
of an advantage advantage of an
adversary in distinguishing between two
settings so in the first setting the
adversary is given access to an
encryption Oracle where the state is
updated after each query by the
adversary and in the other setting the
ideal setting the adversary is
interacting with an oracle that simply
always gives random beats as output
and for correctness we Define this again
in term in terms of an advantage of an
adversary in distinguishing between two
settings
in the first setting the adversary has
is given access to an oracle that first
encrypts and then
subsequently decrypts and also updates
the states accordingly
and in the ideal setting the adversary
simply obtains access to the identity
function Oracle
let me now show you a scheme that indeed
satisfies these two Notions
so this is called SCB
so SCB stands for secure secure code
book
and the name is has been chosen because
this can be seen as a variant or a patch
around the insecure scheme ECB
so the observation comes from ECB itself
if you remember from before the problem
actually is that in ECB
we completely lose security as soon as
some block is repeated within or across
messages
but if we assume somehow that there's uh
no block that repeats actually the
output of ECB
is indistinguishable from
random bit strings
but of course in general we cannot
assume that this is the case
so the idea would be to keep track of
the blocks that we've seen so far and
for the blocks that are repeated we
should do something different we should
not and Cipher them again otherwise we
will of course again lose security
but we should somehow uh find a way to
to signal to the receiver that the
current block is a signal that some
previous block was already transmitted
and we are trying to transmit this again
so this of course introduces some
problem namely on the correctness of the
scheme because now we want to interpret
kind of a Subspace of the possible
blocks as repetition signals rather than
as normal blocks that one might want to
transmit to the receiver
but of course we can kind of Be Clever
about the choice of this Subspace in a
sense that we can spread it as uniformly
as possible over the space of blocks
so I will show you next how to
concretely do this so the idea is that
we need to Define two parameter segment
Tower roughly speaking Sigma will affect
security and Tau will affect correctness
we also need first of all that they add
up to at most and the block size we know
we need also a key K1 for the block
Cipher itself and a second key K2 which
will be used as a pad so we further use
a compression function H mapping n bit
strings to Tau beat strings
and also a look at table s which will be
the state of encryption which Maps B
string style of length style so hashes
of blocks two bit strings of length
Sigma which will be interpreted as
counters within the scheme
and also we'll use this notation to uh
to mean either the values stored in the
lookout table under hash H or the value
bottom if no such hash has been stored
so far in the lookout table s
so then what we do for each block Mi is
the following we first of all get a hash
from h of this block
and we check whether we saw this hash
again in the lookout table s
now this check here approximates whether
Mi is a repetition or not but of course
there might be problems here because we
might have collisions in the function H
since we are mapping to less beats than
n
so if this is not the case then we are
actually guaranteed that Mi is a new
block which means that we can actually
use plain ECB normally
but we also uh so we do not only do that
we also set the counter to zero so we
initialize the counter for this
particular hash value so note for the
hash value not for the message so that's
where we have problems for correctness
and if instead we already saw this hash
value so mi is probably a repeated block
but we might also be wrong
then we have to now signal destroy the
receiver somehow and the idea how to do
that is that we simply include we
concatenate the hash value the current
counter and we zero pad this enough uh
to have a block
and then we pair this with the key K2
and we encode this value so now this
will be the current block for the
ciphertext
and after that we increase the counter
in the lookup table
so this is how encryption works
so for decryption now uh the issue is we
have to find out whether some particular
block of the ciphertext is actually a
normal block or it's just a repetition
signal
and for this so let's consider again as
before Sigma Tau K1 K2 and H
but for the state we have something
different now we have a lookout table
from Tau beats to n Bits which will
approximate kind of the inverse of H of
the compression function
and what we do for each block now it's
first of all we simply apply ECB so we
just decode the block
now what we have to do is to find out
whether
this block Mi has the form of a
repetition signal so for that we need to
see first of all are there like the
correct amount of leading zero bits and
second of all do the last Tau bits
correspond to a hash value that we have
seen before
so if this is not the case then we are
sure that this is not a repetition
signal this was really something that
the sender meant to transmit to us so we
keep this mi from plane ECB but we also
keep track of the message the block
message Mi corresponding to this hash
value
so if this is the case then CI is
probably a repetition signal but again
we might be wrong
so in this case we retrieve the current
mi from the table rather than from the
ciphertext itself
um yeah so in the paper we showed that
indeed the two definitions from before
are satisfied by this uh scheme so we
show security by uh proving that if the
block Cipher is a PRP secure uh
um block Cipher then we have the
following bound where this term comes
from kind of the things that could go
wrong that I showed you before
and the same for correctness if you
assume that H is a collision resistant
compression function then we have the
following bound where again the
additional terms come from uh the bad
events that we might have upon
encryption and encryption
and yes so let's go to the conclusions
so in this paper we introduced the first
ncpa length preserving encryption scheme
and we also use the Cyber text stealing
technique that I mentioned in the
beginning to extend the scheme to
actually handle arbitrary size messages
we also consider a variant that is
secure and correct even if cyber texts
are reordered when there are transmitted
from the sender to the receiver
and we identify also some possible
improvements for future work for example
there is a term in correctness that it's
kind of not really ideal but we believe
that this can be easily removed if in
the description we actually consider
also the counters because if you
remember from before in the cryption we
actually ignore the counters completely
uh it's it will be also interesting to
uh analyze whether the state uh growth
can be uh made better because for every
encryption and every decryption the
state keeps growing so it will be
interesting to see
um
to how can we minimize such a growth and
finally of course it would be
interesting to see whether there are
other ways to achieve better security
and correctness balance in this setting
so this is all from my side I thank you
for your attention and I'm happy to take
any questions
okay thank you would be some quick
questions
so any question from Kobe
there are two questions wait
okay
okay thanks for your presentation I
think it's actually quite a creative uh
problem about problem solution to a
problem
um I was indeed wondering you need to
get the ciphertext in order otherwise
you you screw up with a stable lookup
and now you say you also have a solution
that um
can deal ciphertext has come in out of
order this is given extra loss or or in
the security bound or in the correctness
or what's the consequence of this uh
yeah thank you for the question so
security stays uh the same and one only
needs to realize the correctness of the
scheme in case of reordering so for that
I also uh one also needs to introduce a
different notion of correctness than the
one I have shown before I do that in a
paper and then I also prove that the
bound stays essentially the same
yeah okay thank you
thank you for yeah nice talk and yeah
it's quite inspiring I think and
so you are in your scheme that or you've
taken a hash value for each message
right yes and uh yeah of course it's
it's a key idea Butana in case of the
implementation maybe uh so there's a
complete you can compare it with your
skin with an assay
building a wide block Cipher that only
have a CPA security I mean that this can
be basically possible while with faster
taking a series of the whole message
hashing into a one rock and
making some ECB or counter-like
encryption to the list of the whole
messages
so yeah of course this requires that
this means that the entire scheme is
offline so I mean that in the first
ciphertext block is already received
from the after receiving their
uh after the last print text block has
been determined so it's it's not
comparatory I'm not offensive so your
scheme is all right but if we we allowed
to do uh offline encryption scheme there
might be a
solution without
needing a decryption error so that's a
that's a baseline scheme so I I mean
yeah okay so I'm not sure I understood
exactly uh your idea so
uh maybe we call talk about this offline
really the strict thing is that I want
zero expansion right so anything that
you do seems to either require to be
stateful and also have some
incorrectness or I really I cannot see
how you can have something that is in
CPA security and land preservation and
is also perfectly correct
yes
yes but then it can't be in CPA right
sure sure
yes yes yes that's what I mean and I
thank you and the one might small
comment is uh you are using the two keys
right yeah and I think it's a it can be
reduced to one but just using some kind
of technique previous technique for
building a teacup rock cycle built on
the Rock cyber maybe there are some
additional security laws or correctness
loss but yeah it's I think it should be
possible yeah I think you can definitely
just use a prf or something to expand
the key initially and yeah yes yes it
was just for uh easier presentation that
I showed two different keys but you're
right yes thank you very much
thank you so any question from Kobe
additional location
I think no oh sorry
can you spin a second and uh discuss
what's the change in your hashing table
size for in CTS mode
if you didn't encounter mode
uh sorry can you repeat the question uh
how would uh putting this in counter
mode affect your hashing tables
how would it affect your hashing could
you
you mean the CTS yes
I was having trouble visualizing that
so you're asking how I can uh apply CTS
to my scheme yes
um
so
so I the way I did it is I just defined
uh kind of
uh the block function of my encryption
scheme so I have an encryption scheme
and I kind of separate like I I look at
the code that just handles each block
individually
and I take this now as kind of a block
Cipher and I apply CTS to this but uh
I'm not sure I can recall it exactly the
details I'm sorry thank you yeah
thank you so any questions from Beijing
or maybe from nine
do you have questions from Kobe
no more questions
okay let's thanks the speakers again so
we will have short break then we will
move to the next section
so thank you