good afternoon how are you doing had a
great lunch great well my name is Mike
bow mom and I'm going to talk about how
to use Hadoop for solving the Big Data
of security problem we have the thing is
that you hear about a lot of big data
what you can do with big data and and
the thing is what we're having now today
is a big data in insecurity we have a
log files in terabytes network traffic I
mean understand a desktop is 1 terabyte
disk space in if you do in computer
forensics and not to what malware that's
an insane amount of data and that's
where I'm coming from I'm not coming
from a big date I'm doing Hadoop and
let's see what I can do with security
malware analysis is a hobby hobbyist I
was here in 2012 and talked about my
three computers under stairs in my house
doing male reason is as a hobby and it's
been progressing from that where I'm
also spoke about how to do it cheaply
and how to make use of the data the
thing is from 2012 to now my memory
collection has grown really big and my
three computers on the bed under the
stairs is not really cutting it
because I'm moans globally correct all
the more rare and it's a lot this was
one of my sources of malware it's from
beginning of 2012 to Bob now anyone can
guess how much malware that is from that
single source how many things one
terabyte show of hands I think I can see
you come on wake up
no one thing you have a one terabyte of
malware you think it's too much yeah
what 50 is not quite that much I don't
have a son at home see still under
stairs although I want a son I can't
afford it I can't see how's it why point
8 terabytes of this phase 4 from this
single source I have 20 other sources
now if you look at the releases here one
here 18th of July 4 to 5 almost 46
gigabytes
three days later another 125 gigabytes
you can't down the line fast enough let
alone analyzing them is it 100,000
sample each of these packs I mean how do
I care can't keep up
oh I can't I need I need in
reinforcements I need help
morning were in more ways than one so
I'm looking this this is a big data
problem what can I do with big data all
looking a Hadoop that's the open source
solution for all big data problems it's
true
Rico project it is meant to run of
off-the-shelf hardware not you normal
standard PC that has its faults the
hardware dries it burns up and it
doesn't require any special networks
I have a friend he's working in HPC
sector he is talking about his 1920 CPUs
cluster he just installed
it's like 1920 course and gigabyte
terabyte of RAM and infinity band
networking all the things and it's like
okay how much it cost 5.6 million ok
I'll come back about 20 years when I
click saved all my income and I can
start looking at getting some families
refurbished so Hadoop all standard stuff
all hot standard hardware the processing
is done locally and that's important bit
because this is actually a Hadoop
ecosystem do things in the middle in a
circle or there the really important
stuff you have the HT FS the Hadoop
distributed file system it's you if you
think about raid raid fire one cup put a
file in and the hard drives is be spread
over several hard drives and so on well
that stuff is what Hadoop does but
across machines so a standard is that it
makes three copies so that piece of data
is stored of three machines then you
have the MapReduce it's the computing
power is it's actually quite stupid it's
thinking in the easiest way think grep
- word count that's Map Reduce the map
part is the grep the reduced part is the
word counts WC command
of course you can do a lot of things
with either part of them but that's it's
in a nutshell then you have all these
components around them for me I'm using
pig most of the time HBase sometimes but
mostly I'm not actually thinking about
it I'm losing PK using HBase everything
else is magic happening it's a security
a talk it's not a big data talking how
do you get a Hadoop cluster well my
recommendation if you're running this at
home get one of those prepackaged
distributions a cloud era has one
Wharton works as one there's several
others you can also rent them using the
EMR from Amazon that's really cool
really cost-effective way to do it or if
you really really want you can compile
it yourself not recommended unless you
want to actually improve the Hadoop
ecosystem itself because if you just
want to use it go for a prepackaged or
rent it
so let's talk about how to I do
malware analysis Badou well first are
using a piece of software not developed
by me this pioneer peak it have solves a
lot of these problems first of all
marrow samples are in May up in size of
megabytes Hadoop likes them larger so
what what it does is it's crazy a
sequence file this is a key value pair
where the key is the identifier they
like the md5 checksum and the value is
the contents of the Malheur because then
you have a lot of malware as one single
file then this files are batch process
on each and every node in the Hadoop
cluster they are processed locally which
means that they noticed us the
processing has the data on its own hard
drive so I don't have an additional
network i/o to consider and the output
store in elasticsearch for accessing for
more analysis for drilling down into
inter results
so what do I do with it we're doing
extracting resource information which
means everything that the P is headers
telling me I'm collecting I'm also
collecting all the the resources all the
icons of the binary something is
interesting to know that malware
developers are as lazy as normal
developers wants to find a good icon set
that will keep it will keep using it
same thing is if once they have found
I've got open SSL or some other
third-party library working on the
machine they will keep using that
version with those specific changes they
made to it and those things are things
we can look for in an example and you're
also looking at how to improve detection
rate so I'm using Yarra for that and
everything every time you're doing a
signature update you want to see how
well it responds getting a false
negatives and the false positives you
actually find what you're looking for so
that's really good to run it and rerun
the sample sample set so it is like the
workflow of Pioneer peak you have a sip
file or a local directory with a lot of
malware samples memory sample is a
malicious file don't know those that
fire is being sequenced as stored in the
Hadoop cluster in the HDFS
once that part is done I run a bunch of
peak jobs for creating hashes the clam a
be scanning to do the Jarrah signature
detection and extract all the strings
the resources whatever I want and if I
figure out tomorrow that piece
information I would like to have bro
right as a new Pig script that extracts
that information for me and rerun the
job with affinity amount of of nodes it
can be done very very quickly but I'm
getting back to that later next thing
you can do with Hadoop is doing network
analysis that one is similar to the
malware analysis person you store the
pcaps in HDFS and you run a bunch of Pig
scripts to extract the things you're
looking for
so if is you want to run snort
signatures against the whole lot you can
do that
you can do things like okay give me all
traffic that didn't have a source in
English signature you can replay the
traffic you can look at artifacts back
and forth
the workflow looks like this pcap stored
locally uploaded to HDFS across the
nodes and that circle motion is
representing all the peak jobs the runs
on the each individual node is a POF
extra signature extraction the heard
about the POF - it's actually looking at
all the terraces of connection to see
that the TTL was - for this one it means
that it's probably a Windows machine or
Linux machine or so on which was
generating the traffic you can extract
the user agents whatever you want
I mean think about the query you're
looking for you can have it
then you have the computer forensics and
that one is a more complicated it's like
you're having tons of storage you have a
fast and a normal computer it takes time
to do a keyword search this is a
multiple part process first to extract
or take the raw image extract metadata
about the raw image all the files both
about the image itself
and the files in the image you upload
that and the raw image to HDFS
then you're processing that data you got
into HP a HBase is a new SQL database
and you do an iteration you find the
first all the files and you find the
contents of the files you catalog
categorizing the files your keyword
indexes files and so on which means it's
doesn't do anything different from the
normal sloths kit software is just doing
it faster as you have more processing
power to use with it and the nice thing
is that you just need to have enough
storage around the whole cluster not on
each machine
so extracting keywords you talk nicely
documents you clustered similar objects
and you can even compare it another
image so if you have a plain windows
image you can remove all those files
from the investigation
and then you have the extraction point
where you are actually building the
report of all the data got out that's
really cool
and we got back to the log and I see
this is him the basic example if you if
you look at how to write a MapReduce job
they always have the example of doing
log analysis usually Apache logs doing a
pure MapReduce job for this is okay it's
a bit more work than writing a big
script for it which is a overlay of
MapReduce jobs it's like writing C
instead of assembler so the workflow
with doing large-scale log analysis is
that you're using flume which is another
of those data acquisition components
they push the local logs to HDFS and
normalize them then you have pic scripts
that is all this is batch processing so
you have a batch that using peak scripts
to either directly look for bad stuff or
populate the HBase database because once
you have a data in HBase you can start
querying that one for more information
it's like you you grab your pipe it to a
file and then they start looking at that
file for more information
and this log pig has restful service for
data extraction and the Seohyun actually
start using the data in your normal you
ice or sea ice so here's comes the
animation again it's quite standard
so flume push the logs to HDFS HDFS is
spreading it across the computers you
have a pig scripts extracts the data and
put them back is either back to HDFS or
in HBase and then you can create
additional pig scripts to extract more
information
so back to my my little hobby malware
analysis as I said I have my three
computers under the stairs like Harry
Potter and I'm storing my samples
locally what I need to do is my three
nodes at home they don't cut it it's not
enough computing power I can't keep up
so what I'm doing some loading the data
interesting to analyze up to s3 the
Amazon Web service simple storage
service then I using elastic MapReduce
Amazon to run binary Pig and extract all
the data and then uphold the results
back locally the reason we're doing is
is although s3 is cheap to store data
when you're talking about terabytes of
storage it's no longer cheap we're
talking about hundreds of dollars per
month
so this is that my hobby so I need to be
cost-effective and time effective and
everything so data is being backed up on
Amazon glacier and one heard about that
one a few hands it's their longtime
storage solution your uploaded is stored
on very cheap storage so you if you want
it back you don't can't be in a hurry it
will take time but you don't lose it at
least also doing using the less reduced
redundancy storage of s3 so I only have
dot nine nine and not dot nine nines
because I figure it's going to be up
there I have a local copy I wouldn't be
up there for an hour two ships of the
cost the third thing I do is I bid on
Amazon ec2 spots which means that Amazon
is having this market where you can buy
unused computing power and marquette
highest price winning wins and you can
get the computing power very cheaply
although if someone beats higher than
you I just turn off your machine but
that's not a problem because Hadoop is
built to actually be aware of that it's
actually better if they do turn it off
before the full hour because if they
terminate your machine before the full
hour of machine time is used they
believe nothing
and I don't be doing incremental saves
it's like an if I bid low enough I get
it done fast enough and very cheaply but
if if time is more important and money
easy you can buy your on demand
instances which means you pay retail
price or just bid very high price and
this the thing this is bid price is is
the maximum you will need to pay not
what you are paying so if you can if you
bid like five cents an hour you can end
the spot price is 1.1 cents an hour you
just pay in 1.1 cents
and this is getting down about my
estimate about $20 a month I'm having
haven't got my first bill yet because
this is a work in progress during the
summer my the storage node on my home
computer it crashed
I lost half my hard drives and all my
malware some in the process of
rebuilding my my archive so this is how
I'm doing it going forward
so conclusions Melbourne analysis it's
really appropriate for this kind of
setup you can do it very quickly very
cheaply and if you figure out a new way
to extract data or find a new piece of
data you want you can rerun you whole
sample collection in hours or if you
credibly missus is big enough you can
run it in one hour and a lot of machines
at Amazon I mean you could run the whole
archive at 5.6 5.8 terabyte of malware
in just under an hour but you mean
you're paying for it it's cheap you can
do it from network analysis and if you
if you're recording all the traffic dump
it to HDFS you can start re running
samples you can develop your own
signatures it's like you have you find
an exploit or malicious network pattern
and you're right to use North signature
you can run that North signature again
at all the traffic we already collected
and see if you got any false positives
or all if there are other machines that
has been attacked
same thing with a computer forensics and
here I think Hadoop is a really good
tool because you don't need ten
terabytes of disk space in each number
node
I mean you can have 500 gigabytes disk
space provided you have enough nodes
because you're the capacity of HDFS is
the disk space across all the nodes
divided by three as you have it you
storing as the same data three times
over a cluster
and for a log analysis this is the
newest part of my ecosystem and I'm
already seeing benefits of it especially
when you're talking in taking in logs
from the dynamic analysis of malware
binaries the old system calls next step
is to actually create computer learning
algorithms to to help me detect bad
stuff