my team at GU and I build systems and
policies that prevent account takeovers
in this talk we want to live summer Vale
on how we view this problem and what we
do to defend against it whether we
realize it or not our accounts are for
hijackers a rich source of monetization
opportunities starting from financial
information like bank accounts data
through personal information that can be
used for blackmail lists of our contacts
that can be scammed or fished to even
our identity when you for example work
in accounting and your boss tells in an
email to send money somewhere else which
should double gas it
these motorisation opportunities are
significant enough that hijacking
related headlines appear in news from
time to time major companies continue to
be victims of serious data breaches
exposing billions of credentials in the
process but not only companies and
high-value targets are affected in the
end the hijacking program is about
protecting regular users in this
TechCrunch article the offer describes
how the hacker got into his gmail
account logged the offer out and started
coming his friends at Google we want to
protect all users from all kinds of
threats and in this talk I like to focus
on the dominating and perhaps most
verbal form of online authentication
password authentication what I like you
to walk away with from this talk is that
securing passwords in the modern
environment requires a defense adept
system one that takes into account the
uncertainties that are inside each login
let's first get an idea of how big the
problem really is the life cycle of
hijacking begins with possible theft and
there are three main ways this is done
firstly passwords can be obtained
through date
bitches secondly passwords can be stolen
by malware in this particular case we
care about keyloggers lastly password
passwords can be fished one particular
thing all of these sources have in
common is the dam markets associated
with them hackers often want to sell the
data they have stolen to willing buyers
there is also a demand for easy-to-use
malware and easy to use fishing kills
these markets significantly decrease the
barrier of entry into the abuse world
there is no need for specialized
computer knowledge in order to start
hijacking gullible victims accounts but
the silver lining here is that because
there are markets therefore we can track
them in 2016 we have collected over
4,000 data bridge dumps with over 3
billion credentials this number is
dangerous and not only to services that
have been breached but to all account
providers this is because despite
ongoing education attempts the number of
users who still use their passwords
remain high estimates found in
literature vary from 12 to 43 percent
our own estimate puts this number at 17
percent no where is the threat posed by
the combination of the sheer volume of
data breaches and password use more
visible the number of valid Google
passwords found in those dumps so among
those 2016 data breaches there are over
67 million credentials that are also
valid Google credentials mean if our
password authentication was only about
comparing password hashes there will be
nothing stopping the hijackers into
getting into millions of those accounts
and some of these dumps were a few years
old dance of the remained valid and
valuable until we take an action on them
we also track the two other data sources
and we have evidence that they led to
acceleration of at least 1 million and
12 million credentials respective
just like these free sources differ in
volume they also differ in a success
rate so compared to a general active
Google account if we additionally know
that your password was in a data breach
then we estimate that is at least 10
times more likely that your Google
account will be successfully hijacked
this number grows to 40 times for
victims of a keylogging attack and if
you are fished then it is 500 times more
likely that your account will be
hijacked the reason why phishing is so
much more successful is because as
you'll see we collect and often ask our
users for additional pieces of
information pieces of information that
Fisher's also try to get note that these
numbers are based on hijacking incidents
we are reasonably confident about as
such are only the lower bound of what's
really happening out there so the
password theft ecosystem is private
there are tens of thousands of
credentials changing hands every day we
fight the hijackers by blocking them up
at every step of the way starting before
they even steal the password we prevent
dissemination of fishing baits and
malware by warning users about
suspicious content for example in Gmail
if the user types a click sufficient
link then save browsing Chrome security
efforts may intervene and warn the user
from visiting or providing details on
such a site hackers try to avoid this
kind of mechanism they use things like
URL shorteners in Gmail utilize already
hijacked accounts that have some some
trust ingrained in them they also
actively probe the machine learning
systems that stand behind these
protections and try to adapt to them
whenever we think that the user is at
particular risk we notify them and when
we find out that the password has been
compromised we force them to change it
otherwise the password will be
circulating in this ecosystem up for
grabs by anyone who wants to harm them
hijackers who have stored the password
need to log in with millions of stolen
password
out there just accepting the password as
it is is risky at best preferably users
would turn on additional security
mechanism that we offer things like
second factor authentication but the
truth is such opting security mechanism
just don't get adopted on a wide enough
scale less than 10 percent of active
Google users use second factor
authentication and only twelve percent
of Americans report using password
managers this is not enough but there
are good reasons for the state of
affairs firstly as you have heard
yesterday there are privacy implications
of sharing your phone with an online
service there are perhaps security
implications of storing your passwords
in one place but most importantly it's
about convenience and usability it's
perceived as an unnecessary hassle to
set up additional security from one's
account there is also a worry what will
happen if we lose our security key we
will lose access to our own account so
there's this gap security gap between
password only authentic Asian and
two-factor authentication in order to
bridge this gap we look at additional
signals available to us at login time
the signals that we look at can be
grouped into two categories the first
the first category of signals are
signals of how surprised we are to see
you log in the way you are logging in
where there's any deviation from your
login patterns the second category is
how risky does your login look like does
does it match any known hijacking
campaign or hijacking behavior or
perhaps we know that there are the
particular attacker is targeting you
this risk assessment Mahon is mechanism
has been at Google since 2011 and just
like anything security there's a
constant arms race here for instance
once we and other account providers
started using geolocation in the login
process hijackers noted that nowadays
over 80% of phishing kids collect your
location information and so
hijackers have learned to use practice
effectively such that we have trouble
detecting that they'll geo cloaking
themselves it was slowly becoming some
hijackers favorite way of fooling our
systems in the end we had to ratchet
down his importance and we even turn it
off for users that don't seem to need it
based on the past behavior we used the
risk assessment in order to decide
whether we should ask our passwords only
users for additional additional proofs
additional pieces of information and
this requests we call challenges so we
challenge our users whenever we detect
whenever we think that the login is
risky and we only challenge them in such
a way they should be able to solve it in
effect these passwords own users these
users that are not the factor rolls into
second factor of education in a state
that we call dynamic second factor of
Education that is they may still have to
solve a challenge in order to log in but
such requests happen much more rarely
and they depend not only on the settings
of the account but also on the
particular properties of the log in this
challenging part of the system is where
risk is most visible because we can
never barely be certain where the person
behind the login is the legitimate user
or just the hijacker or hijacker could
just hide really well we can also learn
never really know where the user will
not be particularly inconvenienced by
the challenge and will not be able to
solve it this risk translates to real
damage if we make a mistake
let the hijacker in he may wreak havoc
inside the account on the other hand we
are too strict the user might be locked
out of their own account in order to
react appropriately we strive to build
an arsenal of challenges so that we
always have a suitable option for a
given situation I like now to share with
you some of the lessons learned from
these challenges
please remember that while before
focusing on their weaknesses
the end goal here is not perfect
bulletproof security
the usable one we want to provide the
best security even for a basic account
the first kind of church is secondary
email verification where we send the
verification code to the secondary email
associated with the account what we
found out is that 10% of our users have
problems solving this challenge the
reasons vary forgotten password to email
or even secondary a secondary email
provided no longer existing this number
shows how costly it is for us to
challenge anyone we have to be really
careful about whom and when do we
challenge this is also the reason why we
often combine multiple challenges so
that users will choose a suitable option
for them secondary email verification is
also vulnerable to password to use it's
not uncommon for hijackers to try the
same password across multiple accounts
and use already hijacked accounts as
stepping-stones the second kind of
change that I'd like to present is SMS
code challenge in this challenge we send
a verification code to the phone number
associated with the account this
challenge is born to fishing in the
sense that Fisher's try to intercept
this code around 80% of phishing kids
try to collect it but what's more
worrisome is that there are more there
are multiple other ways hijacker can get
their hands on this challenge ways we or
the users have little control over just
like in the case I mention at the
beginning the offer of that article had
a two-factor authentication account with
an SMS code setup what the hijacker
presumably did is he presumably called
the cause the customer service at his
phone carrier and trick them into
cloning his sim in effect all the SMS
codes we sent to the user were
intercepted by the hijacker as a general
trend most successful hijackings of
valuable two-factor authentication
accounts involve breaking the SMS code
and make no mistake this affects not
only targeted hijacks but also
opportunistic ones when the data was
found in a data breach or has been
fished
as for the volume of this kind of attack
vector FTC reports that in January 2016
alone there are over two and a half
thousand phone hijackings in the United
States now don't get me wrong
SMS has its weaknesses but it still
raises the security bar especially for
Ronald email accounts
nevertheless we promote more secure
challenges like the Google prompt where
we ask the user to verify the login or
the under smartphone device the user may
still click the yes button when his man
in the middle for example but it doesn't
suffer the infrastructure witnesses that
SMS has it also gives us wider field for
maneuvering we can present additional
information to the user we can also do
things like correlate IP of the login
with the IP of the device to see whether
something fishy is going on most
hijackers are stopped at login but some
do get in and when that happens our
focus changes from prevention through
mediation
hijackers who get in usually want to
monetize by stealing data performance
comes performing in product abuse
because they want to monetize they have
to perform specific actions actions we
can monitor for whenever we note that
something suspicious is going on we
notify the user
unfortunately this channel commutation
is just too slow hijackers who get in of
the in common with a prepared script of
what they want to do
enter race against time so we rely
instead on automatic pipelines that
attack ongoing attacks consider for
instance typical things hijackers do
when they get into Gmail after they log
in they like to delete the notifications
that we have sent to the user so that
the user remains unaware of what's going
on then they start looking for valuable
information nowadays in hooey things
like bitcoins or intimate photos then
they may export the list of user
contacts in order to widen the list of
potential potential victims they may
then use the account in order to send
phishing links or scams and just before
they log out they set up filters so that
the user never find out
about the attack perhaps they can use
the account for later whenever our
systems detect an attack taking place
they block the account in such a way
that the hijacker cannot get back in but
the user by providing additional
information can and this concludes our
journey from password fact to
monetization thanks to the system I've
just described most hijackers never get
to deal any lasting damage so we see now
how passwords may seem like it's simple
and binary mekinese on the outside by in
the backend there are a complex and
dynamic system and they have to be in
order to make on.i authentication work
thank you
[Applause]