[Music]
so I'm here to talk about another
socially important issue in a time where
governments are increasingly demanding
access to encrypted data or seeking to
nullify the protection of encryption we
want to protect access to the encryption
to allow people to continue to protect
their data I'll start off by apologizing
I feel like I'm a little underdressed
for the topic I was actually gonna try
to borrow a suit for my talk but I
couldn't get in touch with this guy in
time before the conference why am i
standing up here and really wishing I
had this suit from The Hurt Locker well
I'm here to bring you a very radical
proposal I'm here to suggest to you that
we might actually want to make our
crypto a little bit weaker normally we
talk about how do we make crypto
stronger we might actually want to make
it a little bit weaker so that we can
make our systems stronger and provide
stronger protection to our users now
I'll admit the authors of this work we
ourselves are a bit ambivalent about the
idea but if you'll bear with me for the
next 18 or 19 minutes I think we have
the potential here to do a lot of good
so let's see what you think the most
famous case of a government demanding
access to encrypted data is Apple versus
the FBI I'm sure you all know this story
in 2015 after the San Bernardino terror
attacks the FBI under the direction of
James Comey demanded that Apple help
them decrypt an iPhone that at one time
belonged to one of the attackers Apple
under Tim Cook of course said no and
there was a big fight in the courts and
in the court of public opinion in the
press and this dragged on and on and it
got to the point where Apple engineers
were openly discussing the idea maybe
we're gonna go to jail rather than help
the FBI with this and the reason they
were having to have this tough
discussion was that if they provided
this special code this effectively a
backdoor to the FBI it could have been
used not only to get into that one
iPhone that was supposedly important for
the case but it also could have been
used to get into thousands or maybe
millions of other devices
that maybe weren't as important and I'm
here to propose to you that it's a
limitation of the technology that forces
this debate into a false dichotomy if
you read news articles on about this
topic you go read on Twitter about this
topic the view that you get is that we
have a strict binary choice between
these two absolutist options if you
listen to Jim Comey or Rod Rosenstein at
the Department of Justice and FBI if we
continue with strong encryption like we
have now we're gonna get into this
future where internet hooligans like
this guy in the Guy Fawkes mask are
running around harassing people causing
chaos and terrorists and criminals are
doing their thing with basically nobody
able to stop them on the other hand if
you listen to people on our side tell it
our only alternative to that is to give
in to a government that wants access to
all our data all the time and wants to
be all-powerful like the agents from the
from the movie The Matrix now obviously
these are caricatures right Tim Cook is
not really running around out there and
a guy Fox mask Jim Comey and rod Rosen
Stein don't really want to be Agent
Smith but the state of the public debate
on this isn't a whole lot more nuanced
than that I'm here to argue to you that
if those two alternatives are all we
give people we may not like the way it
turns out I like this xkcd cartoon
because it reminds us that the security
of a real system doesn't just depend on
the technology it depends on the human
factors too now I'm not I'm not too
worried about agent Smith running around
with a wrench
hitting every owner of an encrypted
device but I am a little worried about
the pressure that can be applied to the
the device makers and we don't have to
go too far back in history to see
examples where this has happened back in
2013 we had two encrypted email
providers lavabit and silent circle they
both shut down after a court order came
down for lavabit where they were gonna
have to turn over a master cryptographic
key that would have exposed all of their
users encrypted data to the feds if you
go back a couple years before that
blackberry was almost kicked out of
India in 2010
until they they caved in and they gave
the government a backdoor we look around
the world we see that right now the
situation is maybe even a little bit
worse already this chart comes from a
tech report last year from the Center
for Strategic and International Studies
they looked at laws around the world and
they found that right now about half of
people in the live today live under
governments where at least officially on
the books there are laws that say that
you must provide some sort of assistance
to recover encrypted data whether that's
key escrow or backdoors or whatever and
what may be surprising to us as
technologists is that it's not only
authoritarian oppressive governments
that are imposing those requirements
this stuff is pretty popular sometimes
so here I have some survey data from
from pew from 2014
they asked Americans what do you think
should it be possible for people to do
some activities online with anonymity
and the results are kind of mixed when
you look between sexes between age
ranges between income levels on the
whole though we see that Americans think
privacy is important but it's not nearly
as sacrosanct as it is within our tech
filter bubble and you can look at some
of these demographic results for example
among women that's only a minority of
women who believe that online anonymity
is really important as another example I
have some data here from YouGov in the
UK this is from 2015 they asked people
about what's the right balance between
privacy and security and I'll note here
when they say security they're not
talking about data security or
information security they're talking
about more like national security or
maybe physical safety and again we see
that privacy is important to people but
physical safety is even more important
and this this result holds for the most
part across party affiliation and so I'm
here to argue that if all we're gonna
give people if we're gonna give the
public policy people if we're gonna give
the voting public only a stark choice
between these two extreme options that
sounds to me like a high-stakes gamble
we might as well go to Vegas and put it
all on black
there's a huge risk that the strategy
winds up losing everything and we wind
up in that Agent Smith future so my
first call to action in my talk is that
we need to kind of give ourselves
permission to work on this problem to
think about other approaches to get out
of this low-resolution one bit of
precision binary all-or-nothing world so
wouldn't it be nice and instead of that
start binary choice if we had more like
a sliding scale or a continuum and so
you can imagine wouldn't it be cool if
we could decide exactly what level of
access we wanted to allow and we could
turn a knob or move a slider and so
maybe the far left into this spectrum we
would allow access for the government to
recover encrypted data only in the most
important like existential threat kind
of cases so the 9/11 hijackers or the
KKK or whoever we think is the biggest
threat that's the only cases we would
allow as we slide that slider towards
the other end we might allow more and
more access in less and less serious
cases to the point where maybe at some
point we're allowing access to encrypted
data for any case where we're right now
prosecutors and investigators can get a
search warrant with probable cause and
so in this model we can imagine that
even organizations that have really
strong feelings about this for example
the Electronic Frontier Foundation the
FBI even they wouldn't be at these at
these absolute extremes I'm gonna get in
a ton of trouble with this slide because
I'm kind of putting words into the
mouths of the FBI and the e FF wolf
sorry guys but you'll notice that
there's no scale on my graph here right
and that's that's int it's a little hand
wavy but hopefully you see the point and
I think taking that even further most
normal people would probably fall
somewhere in the middle and probably
closer together than we might think from
the state of the current debate so we
have a lot more in common than we think
and again it's a failure of the
technology that it takes people who are
so close and it pushes us apart to these
these extreme options that nobody would
really pick if we had our choice okay so
how do we do better well if we're gonna
try I'll argue that there's at least
three
requirements that we need to satisfy for
anything to work first and foremost we
absolutely need to have the strongest
protections against warrantless mass
surveillance this is one of the cases
where older approaches for this problem
like key escrow from the 1990s they fail
so in key escrow the idea is that every
decryption key gets encrypted and
wrapped up and stuff after the
authorities were just some trusted
intermediary but there's nothing to
prevent that authority from going and
opening up all the keys and using them
to listen in on all the messages so we
need to avoid that if we're gonna make
something work at all in this case
secondly we need to make our technology
easy and efficient for the people who
are going to use it and for the people
that are gonna develop it and build out
the systems this is another place where
key escrow fails it doesn't make a lot
of sense for me as an end-user
to burn through my battery and burn
through my data plan encrypting and
sending off all these encrypted keys
when the benefit isn't for me directly
anyway it's really for Jim Comey here
the FBI so our third requirement once
we've satisfied the the first two we can
start to talk about enabling some truly
limited access in exceptional
circumstances we we call this problem
exceptional access it should stay the
exception rather than the norm and of
course we also need to have built in
technological safeguards to to keep it
rare and we need to have strong
incentives to require due process and
protect against misuse so today I have
some early preliminary kin cryptographic
instructions that can get us toward this
feature this is probably not the
greatest be-all-end-all final
construction that we can come up with so
this is my second call to action I want
to see what this community can do to
push this area forward but today the
approach that I want to present is that
think about
so car metaphors are always terrible
right but here's my car metaphor
sometimes when something really bad
happens it's better to sacrifice the
technology and have the machine break a
little bit in order to protect the
people inside and so let's go back to
that example where the feds have two
options for getting this guy's
decryption key they've got the five
dollar wrench and they've got the
million dollar cluster suddenly that
million dollar cluster doesn't sound so
bad does it for one thing it's gonna
hurt a lot less when they use it and
secondly it costs a lot so it has a
built-in disincentive for misuse and so
let's try to take this idea and make
this a little more precise and a little
more general so for one thing maybe a
million dollars isn't enough and and
paying that cost just once isn't enough
so what we want to do is we want to
impose two separate kinds of costs on
any adversary that wants to recover our
messages we're gonna have an initial
upfront cost that you have to pay before
you can recover any messages at all
we're gonna call this capital I and then
we're gonna have a marginal cost that
you have to pay each time you want to
decrypt a new message so we're going to
call this capital m and we can the ideas
that we can tune capital m we can make
it really high to limit the number of
messages that can be decrypted we can
turn it down to enable more here we're
gonna rely on a slightly non-standard
set of cryptographic assumptions
normally we assume that everybody is
maximally malicious and our adversaries
are gonna screw us over no matter what
the cost of themselves here we're
relying on the rational crypto approach
where we assume that all parties act out
of rational self-interest so for us that
means that even if somebody has the
money in the time and the resources to
recover a key and decrypt a message
they're not necessarily going to do it
unless the benefit they get from that
message outweighs the cost of all the
expenditure they had to do to recover
the key to impose our initial cost we're
going to repurpose an attack on
diffie-hellman key exchange I don't have
to time to get into all the math of
dippy huh pardon me diffie-hellman here
but in that key exchange it works by
both parties who want an exchange key
we'll do some modular map with really
big numbers my
a big prime P the insight from this
paper from 2015 was that attacking this
construction can be broken down into a
really big upfront pre-computation phase
shown in the yellow part of the diagram
and they estimate that for a 1024 bit
Prime this would cost about one hundred
and forty five million dollars but then
once the adversary has paid this cost
they can go and break any diffie-hellman
key exchange that uses the prime P for a
relatively small cost as the parts shown
in pink so we are going to repurpose
this attack and we're gonna use it for
something good the idea is that we can
take this pre computation and we can use
this as an extremely expensive puzzle
and we can crank up the the difficulty
in the cost of it by changing the length
of the prime P so how much does it cost
well it's hard to say for sure because
the attack is really complicated and
there's a lot of different pieces of the
algorithm that you can trade off against
each other but we took the numbers and
the analysis from that 2015 paper and we
extrapolated out to Prime's larger than
1024 bits and it looks like if we set P
to be you know with between 1070 and
1090 bits we can have a pre-computation
attack that costs between one and two
billion dollars that's again billion
with a B so at that level it doesn't
really matter who your adversary is
that's a pretty substantial cost before
you can recover even a single message
just for comparison I think the FBI's
annual budget this year is about ten
billion dollars nine point something so
pretty substantial for our marginal
costs we're gonna use a hash based
proof-of-work
similar to hash cash or more famously in
Bitcoin mining so we're gonna assume
that the original application did a good
job of deriving a good symmetric key
we're gonna call that k0 ko the first
thing we do is we we take what we call
the little hash function little H we
pass ko through little H and that gives
us a string of random bits that's
substantially shorter than in the
original key then we take that we pack
it up together with some public metadata
about the message or about the file or
about whatever we're encrypting
including if possible if we have the
diffie-hellman key exchange going on as
well we include the
shared secret SW from that week
diffie-hellman key exchange and we pass
all of that through another hash
function big H that gives us a string of
random looking bits that is the same
size as the original key and we can just
plug that back into the original app and
use that in place of the original key
and so now to recover the message all
the adversary needs to do is a
brute-force search they don't need to
find the original ko they need to find
the hash the little H of ko so for
example if little H gives us 60 bits
then that's a key space of only 2 to the
60 that they need to search and to make
it easier to predict how much that brute
force search is going to cost we borrow
some important parameters from Bitcoin
so in Bitcoin mining what you do is you
do a brute-force search over a random
number and a header that's 80 bytes or
640 bits and so we make our header the
same size and the hash function the bit
in Bitcoin mining that they're computing
is a double-shot 256 so you take a shot
256 hash of of the header and then you
hash that hash again and that's your
output and we use that as our crumpled
key how much does that cost well it
depends on the hardware that you're
using to do the search and here we have
some data from the Bitcoin wiki to show
the enormous difference input in energy
performance for custom ASIC hardware
that's been developed specifically for a
Bitcoin versus say it a recent
top-of-the-line Intel CPU we're looking
at a 20,000 times difference so the
important takeaway for us is that even
if we have a nation-state adversary the
chance that they could come up with
something that's vastly better than this
is pretty small right it's very
difficult for them to outrun what the
free market can already do ok so again
how much does it cost well we took some
data from the US Energy Information
Agency
it looks like the cheapest region of the
u.s. you pay about 5.2 cents per
kilowatt-hour and so we plug that in
with our our mining efficiency and the
relationship is pretty simple right so
you add one bit to the key length you
doubled the search cost and note here
that the the y-axis on this graph is
logarithmic and I guess if you think of
the x-axis as the size of the key space
that that's also logarithmic
and I'm not here to tell you what the
right choice is the key length is but it
looks like the range between maybe 60
and 80 bits is probably the right area
to be looking so if you have this
high-performance efficient ASIC minor
and you have a key space of two to the
sixty and it looks like you can do that
search for about a thousand bucks if we
crank up the effective key length to 70
bits that gives up to a million dollars
we crank it up again the 80 bits now
we're talking about a billion dollars
again a billion here a billion there
pretty soon and you're talking real
money now so that's sort of the initial
constructions that we have for this I
don't want to claim that this is a solve
problem now but I hope this is enough to
get the debate started and to have a
more productive more nuanced more
thoughtful debate on this topic so for
example now we can think about if we
have more choices than just the binary
extremes where do we want to set that
slider how much access do we want to
allow even if the answer is none that's
very different when we say no we will
not do this is different from oh sorry
we can't and so it is qualitatively
different
there are also some technical challenges
here I may skip through this a little
quickly for one thing there are certain
targets certain people whose information
is probably always worth it for the
adversaries to go after what should we
do to help them should we can we I think
there that's an important area for
future work as another thing the math
behind the stiffie Hellman attack is not
something that the world really
understands very well yet and we need to
get a better handle on that I showed you
a puzzle that I think costs about two
billion dollars what if it's not 2
billion what if it's a hundred million
or just a couple of million finally
there's some regimes that we probably
should not ever trust with a scheme like
this because they would just whatever it
takes they're gonna crack down on the
dissidents even if that means criminals
go free and their people starve
finally you can imagine if we were to
deploy a system like this the world
governments would probably collaborate
and work together to solve some of these
big problems and I don't know is that
something that we want to encourage and
if so how do we do it this is something
we want to discourage and if so how
before I wrap up I want to come back to
Apple versus the FBI
for the people now in Jim Comey's role I
want to caution you that pushing for a
mandate for something like this before
we have time to do more research and
better understand the risks would be a
really really bad idea
really very premature on the other hand
if you're in Tim Cook's role and I think
probably more of us are in that role
hopefully we've given you some ideas
that you can use if you're worried about
a government coming in demanding access
to your users encrypted data maybe you
could do something proactively to
protect yourself and to protect your
users before we have another San
Bernardino and my co-author and I are
happy to meet with anybody in industry
or government if you want to talk about
these problems more I think we have some
time for questions and discussion
remember I forgot my suit so go easy on
me but I'm looking forward to it thank
you