you
[Music]
most of us in this room probably use
cryptography first thing in the morning
if you're like me you got out of bed and
picked up your phone and maybe browse
some websites or check your email each
of these tasks is protected by
cryptographic technology that was really
honed over decades of experience I think
what we've seen is only the beginning I
think that in the near future we're
gonna see cryptographic technology that
not only protects your data as it's in
transit over the network or is it stored
on disk but while it's in use and being
computed on itself my name is Steve
Weiss and I'm a software engineer with
the Facebook privacy data privacy team
I've spent my whole career applying
cryptography to protect people's
sensitive data I'm excited to be here
today to talk about emerging
cryptography and the models of private
computation that will help enable I
think to see where we're going we needed
to see where we've been and also who is
left behind we need to learn the lessons
of the past and make sure the technology
that we build doesn't just benefit the
people in this room but the next billion
people who come online there's a large
and growing body of people whose
experience coming online is very
different than mine was and most likely
different than yours they're people who
have never used a keyboard before they
may share a device as multiple people
and pay for Internet connectivity as
they go they also may not be legally
allowed to use the same technologies and
services that we can I think as we talk
about emerging cryptography today I want
to keep all the people emerging online
in mind now looking back at the past one
of the most important developments has
been the widespread adoption of
transport encryption meaning the
encryption of your communication over
the network it wasn't long ago that most
major web sites didn't default to using
TLS the transport layer security
protocol and that the traffic would be
plaintext over the Internet
it wasn't until 2010 that Gmail first
started defaulting to using TLS before
that unless you explicitly opted in when
you're reading your email on Gmail your
contents may have been visible to
somebody who was on the
working between you Facebook and Yahoo
followed suit several years later and
started enabling TLS by default and
we've since seen the emergence of things
like certificate transparency let's
encrypt and commercial offerings like
cloud flares Universal SSL that all make
it easier and safer to deploy TLS to
your websites the end result is that
billions of people now enjoy private
communications and are protected against
those adversaries on the network now
there were several major vulnerabilities
and fixes in TLS that in general
improved the security of protocol for
all of us these had branded names like
poodle beast or crime in each of these
cases the fixes may have been unintended
consequences so if you're a large site
you had a hard decision to make do you
stop supporting a broken version of TLS
and potentially cut off users with old
devices that can't support the most
recent version or do you keep supporting
a weak version and potentially put
everyone at risk there's not an easy
answer and I bring this point up to
illustrate that sometimes the most
secure option is not always the best one
and then we need to keep usability and
adoption mind and also realize that most
people are on old unpatched devices and
not everyone has $1,000 iPhone disk
encryption is another technology that's
come a very long way it wasn't long ago
that encrypting your hard drive was
opt-in and very fiddly and hard to get
right over a little more than a decade
we've seen disk encryption go from
something that was more or less rare to
where it's the default setting on our
most common devices meaning our mobile
phones it's gotten to the point where
even an agency like the FBI has to go to
great lengths to decrypt an out-of-date
iPhone so technology is here and it
works and then encrypted messages are
another technology that's really matured
in recent years now we've had end end
encrypted messaging clients for a long
time even America Online had a
enterprise encrypted edition in 2003 and
there's been many open source projects
out there but I think it wasn't until we
saw the widespread adoption of
smartphones that a large number of
people started using what I considered
to be high quality messaging apps in
2010 whisper systems released tech
secure and red phone which eventually
merged into a signal around 2014 that
signal protocols been adopted by
whatsapp Facebook Messenger and most
recently by Skype and is generally
considered safe and secure
I think the adoption by whatsapp is
perhaps the most impactful there's over
a billion people who are using end end
encrypted messaging today and that
rollout was largely invisible most
people didn't even know it was happening
whatsapp from a design perspective had
some hard pragmatic security decisions
to make for people on unpatched old
clients they opted to continue to let
them to use whatsapp meaning those
conversations were temporarily visible
to whatsapp because it was intended
encrypted until those users updated it
turns out their user base also switches
devices very often and in the underlying
signal protocol that means that new key
is generated and the right thing to do
from a security perspective is to prompt
users who are talking to somebody to
verify those new keys usually thrown out
of band communication channel well for
these users this experience would have
been very disruptive and also confusing
and also many these people did not have
another outside communication ban to
verify these keys so whatsapp opted to
not force people to manually verify and
made it opt-in only I think this is a
pragmatic decision and one that kind of
illustrates the trade-offs that we
sometimes need to make for a security
model in order to drive usability and
adoption I think this type of trade-off
will be most relevant in a few slides
when I start talking about technologies
like secure enclaves so what we've seen
is just the beginning in the last few
years we've seen the emergence of crypto
currencies like Bitcoin and aetherium of
darknet marketplaces on tor onion nodes
and of klepto graffiti or ransomware
like not Pecha these are all ideas that
have been talked about had false starts
going back to the 80s but in recent
years I think we've started to see them
impact everyday regular users
so I think we live in interesting times
and things are just gonna get it more
interesting and weird in the next few
years
so private computation and private
storage in my mind are things we know
how to solve we've seen this widespread
adoption where billions of people are
using it
excuse me private communication I think
the gap is computation so if you're on a
weak or cheap device and connecting to a
cloud service even though that
connection may be encrypted while your
day is being used by that service it's
visible to them
emergent cryptography can give us
technology that can make these
computations private and make our
current cloud model safer and better at
protecting your data I'm gonna talk
about some of those technologies that
are available now in the near term and
in the long run so software guard
extensions is a technology from Intel
and the core idea is that you have a
small trusted Enclave in the CPU where
you as a remote user can load software
into you'll be able to remotely attest
that your authentic code is loaded in
this Enclave through the use of a
cryptographic protocol the end result is
that you have a small trusted foothold
in an otherwise untrusted system because
that's surrounding operating system
that's running on there is not supposed
to be able to access that Enclave so
today a technologic SGX gives us private
computation you can do things like
provision cryptographic secrets to it or
process chunks of private data this is
available now so microsoft's announced
availability of SGX on there is your
cloud computing platform there's
multiple blockchain companies who are
building their technologies rooted in
SGX and signal which I talked about is
doing experiments with contact sync
discovery in enclaves that means that
you can find all your friends using the
app without their discovery service
learning who those friends are now
there's still kinks to work out namely
the security model highly trusts Intel
in the attestation process and right now
on the heels of meltdown inspector
I think our confidence in CPU
manufacturers security is probably at a
all-time low
regardless I think that this represents
the most likely way to achieve private
computation today because it's available
now and people are already using it
along the theme of private computation
and transactions I want to talk about
what's called a zero knowledge snark and
snark stands for succinct non
interactive argument of knowledge in
cryptography the concept of a zero
knowledge proof goes back to the 80s
with some researchers named Goldwasser
McCallion Rakoff and the core idea is
that if I possess a secret I can prove
to you that I know the secret without
you learning anything about it or be
able to prove to somebody else one
application of this is anonymous
payments so if Alice wants to pay Bob a
hundred dollars anonymously she can
anonymize a transaction and through the
use of what's called zero knowledge
proof sub knowledge can prove that one
she has the money and is not creating it
a thin air and to is authorized to spend
it the interesting thing about snarks is
that distinctness property that means
the proofs are short and relatively fast
to verify
so this verifier can verify a large
number of transactions fairly quickly
this makes this technology very suitable
for crypto currencies and in fact one
currency called Z cash has pioneered the
use of this technology and today is
doing tens of millions of daily
anonymous transactions using their
crypto currency since then a larger
crypto currency called etherium is also
announced that there'll be adopting zero
knowledge snarks and some of the authors
have published a new paper as of last
week with a next-generation which they
call a stark which will continue to
build on this idea now all snarks have
proven themselves for transactions a
more general purpose concept I'm gonna
talk about is called multi-party
computation this was invented about 35
years ago by a researcher named Yao and
has been the subject of decades of
research and improvements as a classic
example suppose Alice and Bob each have
a private salary and they want to
determine who may
more money to do so multi-party
computation allows them to do something
called garbling and they'll garble a
circuit that is basically just a
comparison operator and they'll do this
by engaging in an interactive protocol
and at the end of the protocol the
output to Bob will be a single bit of
information whether a is greater than B
now one thing to note is that this
version of multi-party computation is
interactive and it's one-shot so if they
want to compute some different salaries
they have to run for this whole thing
again the reason I bring this up which
is a pretty old concept in technology is
that between about 2008 and 2013 there
were many security and performance
improvements to multi-party computation
that are making it practical for more
real world problems and in fact several
startups are now working on applying
multi-party computation to solve real
problems and the next talk is going to
talk about one real-world problem that's
solved by mult multi-party computation
Google's also been talking about using
multi-party computation to share data
with advertisers but from what I can
tell from public documents they're using
a construction called homomorphic
encryption in cryptography a
homomorphism is an operation that you
can perform on cipher texts that will
yield the output of that encryption on
the plain texts so if I have an
encryption of a and an encryption of B I
can homomorphic they add those together
to get an encryption of a plus B
meanwhile I don't learn anything about
the input value a the in B or the sum I
can do the same thing with
multiplication so in this example we
could have to be these two operations
are interesting because the combination
of them allows us to build circuits so
if you can do both addition and
operation addition to multiplication we
can combine these together and
essentially build an encrypted circuit
so in this example somebody could send a
encrypted search query to a private
service and then get back the search
results which are the output of this
encrypted circuit now we've had
homomorphic encryption for 40 years but
for most of that time it was
it's called partially homomorphic that
mean you can only do one of these
operations and not the other this meant
that you could only do limited sets a
private computation
it wasn't until 2009 that a researcher
named Craig Gentry invented the first
fully homomorphic crypto system now this
first system was very inefficient it was
something like a trillion times slower
than the underlying circuit but within
just a few short years that performance
was sped up by a factor of a thousand
and it spurred other developments and
practical things like a homomorphic
encryption library called a Qi Lib now
one thing to note that's different
between this and multi-party computation
is that it's not one shot this private
computation service can serve multiple
queries based on the input by doing
different combinations of these
ciphertexts I don't really expect to see
fully homomorphic encryption used in
widespread for you know at least five to
ten years but I would expect to see some
niche cases in practice in the near
future and that eventually a cloud
service will be able to offer something
like an encrypted database that lets you
search over it by using homomorphic
properties one thing you may have
noticed with homomorphic encryption is
that it required a round trip to do
anything useful I had to get the cipher
text back and decrypt it to do anything
useful with it functional encryption is
a notion that we can delegate some
specific functionality to somebody and
allow them to compute it on ciphertexts
so in this example I might have a mail
server that I give the ability to
compute and is it spam function and if I
give them encrypted messages they can
run this on the ciphertext and determine
whether their spam but not learn
anything else so it's reminiscent the
multi-party computation and homomorphic
encryption but if you notice there's no
round-trip here this server can actually
act on this information and we know that
it's limited to just learning what we
decided to disclose to it so this
concept was first talked about in some
identity base crypto papers around 2005
and
between about 2011 and 2013 was more
formalized at that point some
constructions were proposed based on a
primitive called a multi linear map this
is still very inefficient and in its
early days but again this is advancing
very rapidly and is new this brings me
to the last concept I'm going to talk
about which is called
indistinguishability obfuscation or just
software obfuscation the core idea is
that I can take a program and obfuscate
it in a way that if I give you to run it
you don't learn anything about what it's
actually doing what the algorithm is or
secret values in that program all you're
able to do is feed an input and then see
the output so this is not the ad hoc
obfuscation that you'd see in something
like copy-protection or an anti reverse
engineering in some ways this is the
cryptographic holy grail if I have
indistinguishability obfuscation I can
build everything I talked about today so
as an example suppose I office gate AES
encryption with a fixed key if I give
that to somebody they can take this
office key today yes and they're not
able to learn anything about that key
itself they can just feed in inputs and
get ciphertext out so this essentially
gives me the definition of public key
crypto so again this is still variants
early phase
it wasn't until 2013 that researchers
proved that this was even possible to
build but I think it's a hint at what's
possible through the use of cryptography
we know it's possible to obfuscate a
program and outsource that computation
is somebody especially they don't even
know the algorithm they're computing so
how can we all benefit from this I've
talked about cryptography that we can
buy off-the-shelf today though it's
probably decades away from being used in
practice well they all all have in
common is that they strengthen the
security and privacy of outsourced
computation I think that model is gonna
be important in the future because again
invisibly protect people using those
relatively weak devices
if all you have is a some local
computation network connectivity and
some credentials you'll be able to
access these powerful back-end private
services I think one day we'll be able
to use cloud services without
sacrificing our privacy like we all have
to today so suppose we had this
technology right now every couple of
years I go back and make the same slide
by just grabbing a couple months of
headlines about law enforcement and
government people saying that they want
to regulate cryptography I think we see
a constant tension between government
and law enforcement and emergent Oh
private computation represents another
channel going dark for law enforcement
namely that they won't be able to
subpoena services for data that they no
longer hold I think if this model
becomes common what we'd see is more
targeting of those endpoint devices
so all those weak unpatched phones I was
talking about those are really soft
targets so even if we are able to build
all this and deploy it we still have to
solve all the basic security problems of
just securing your device making sure
it's updated and authenticating people
we may also see legislation that
requires services to retain access to
their plaintext data so I think it's
gonna be up to people like us in this
room to continue to defend our own
rights to use emerging cryptography and
to protect the privacy of our own data
so I'd like to thank you all very much
for listening into the Enigma program
committee for accepting this talk I'm
very excited about some of these
technologies and truly want to see them
become a reality and used in practice so
thank you all very much and I think we
have some time for some questions