[Music]
thank you for that introduction David
the important thing to note about the
introduction he just gave is that he
didn't say either of us were lawyers
because we're not and we're gonna be
talking about some legal aspects of
border search and crossing borders and
we did that on our own interpretations
and some talks with some lawyers but we
are not lawyers
second disclaimer called number one is
that our thoughts and opinions are our
own and do not reflect those of our
employers so what sort of came about
brought about this presentation this
idea it started about a few years ago
when I started to see news articles and
comments about employers asking for your
social media passwords or investigating
your private Facebook posts in job
application process prior to being
employed there and an escalated and
became part of the border crossing or
u.s. visa application and extreme
vetting process in 2017 that there's
proposals that require your social media
account access or investigations into
your digital devices as as you cross a
border or interact with different law
enforcement agencies in various contexts
so that can be really scary and thus
inside when you're crossing a border
that they're gonna require you to give
over your devices to take a look at but
if you take a look at the numbers
compared to the amount of visitors that
come in to at least the u.s. I will come
in and go out of the u.s. in one year
which is around just under four hundred
million and the actual device searches
it's really a small drop in the bucket
and I don't know if you guys can really
read it but in 2016 it was just under
20,000 device searches and in 2017 it
did go up by sixty percent but it's
still only in the thousands it's 30,000
by searches so it's very very small but
if you do happen to be one of those
unlucky people that gets chosen it's
it's really terrifying what they're
doing with these devices once they take
it behind
in a closed door button you have no idea
what's going on as you can't see so one
would initially think that if you don't
have to give over your passcode that
it's going to be fine because they're
just gonna look at the device if you
have a passcode on it and they're not
gonna be able to do much but
unfortunately the CBP does require you
well they say that we're obligated to
give over our pass codes to these
devices so that way they can take a look
and it's a little broad in the sense
that it's just not those pass codes but
just any ones that they ask for so then
the question is what are they doing with
these devices that are unlocked behind
closed doors if they're most benign well
it's not really benign but what they
could be doing is making backups and
specifically if it's unlocked
making unencrypted backup so that
doesn't really sound that bad because if
you don't really have a lot of
information on the device it's not
really that big of a deal but if it's an
encrypted backup there's actually a lot
of sensitive information in those
backups and that can include your
credentials for you social media
accounts bank accounts really anything
that you've authenticated to on the
device with the applications are
probably stored in a keychain of sorts
and this includes authenticated session
tokens that can translate into
unmitigated forever access to your
digital life which is incredibly
invasive because much more so than just
taking a look at what you have in your
suitcase as you cross the border but the
CBP did release and a couple of weeks
ago in their newly defined directive
they released and they clarified what
they were actually doing in the sense
that they wouldn't be using these pass
codes or these authenticated tokens to
access any data that's solely stored
remotely which doesn't sound so bad
but the way things do work is oh sorry
I'm skipping ahead alright so in the way
that they do that is they to ensure that
they aren't accessing it is they have
either the user or they will disable the
network access on the device before they
take it into the back room this is a
little bit misleading because what that
actually translates into is any type of
MDM or remote wipe solution
if it detects an evil Isha's access is
not going to be able to remotely wipe
the device or protect the sensitive data
that's on the device and it also doesn't
prevent future access to this remote
data if they don't delete the backups
and so the way applications work is yes
even though they won't be able to access
your social media accounts or bank
accounts if they need to authenticate
using a network any data that's been
previously downloaded with these
applications it's still going to be
accessible to law enforcement when they
take a look at it so I have it on
airplane mode and you can still see my
private message to Andi in Twitter but
as a US citizen crossing the US border
doesn't the Fourth Amendment protect me
from this type of search you know this
is where we touch in like sorry for
anybody who's not a US citizen and or
for your assistant is not crossing a US
border this this part doesn't apply but
the Supreme Court has actually ruled
that that there is an exception called
the border search exception to the
warrant and probable cause requirements
of the Fourth Amendment to conduct some
of these searches and this is due to the
they've ruled that the United States has
a need to protect the integrity of our
borders and that need overrides some of
the individual privacy rights we expect
in our day-to-day lives and it's it's
not so much that it like overrides it it
actually redefines sort of what's
considered reasonable and a routine
search or a reasonable search is
anything a search of anything that is a
common possession carried across the
border such as your luggage but also
your digital devices some searches are
not routine they're highly intrusive and
they impact the dignity dignity and
privacy interests of the individual but
so how does this really apply to the
digital devices that we carry with us
and so this was not defined by a
government agency up until January 4th
when the CBP the US Customs and Border
Protection Agency released an update to
their 2009
directive on searching of digital
devices and and now it says that it
defines what a basic search is what an
advanced search is the key thing here is
a basic search is without any suspicion
or or any reason other than they want to
they can hands-on with your device
search through it everything they can do
just by interacting with it an advanced
search requires individual suspicion by
policy and an a group includes making
the encrypted backup hooking up any
device to it to do the investigation the
key here is that exit policy it's an
agency directive it's not a law or
provide legal protections and violating
a policy doesn't give you legal recourse
usually to have to address it there
there are some court cases that sort of
conflict with the what the directive
claims like the obligation to share your
passcode and there those court cases
don't apply in the border search
exception case yet but the e FF has
brought some cases trying to apply them
to that but they're currently litigating
that process and so a big part of our
talk here is providing some technical
solutions and technical protections
around some of this ambiguity of well
you're you have legal protections
there's a policy that sort of override
some of those where there is explicit
legal justification you have a warrant
you've been subpoenaed
they have just cause for an
investigating your device we're not up
here to interfere with that what what
we're here to provide are as a technical
conversation around sort of that gray
area of what could users do to protect
themselves or what could service
providers do to protect themselves and
in that main we just want to help move
the conversation forward and so Congress
is aware of this they have proposed in
this current session a bill that would
it really make our talk completely moot
but as of well it was introduced in
April and it hasn't been any
I've been on it since which is
unfortunate but maybe this will help
spur it forward yeah the the key parts
of this is that basic searches are still
basic searches advanced searches are
still advanced searches but advanced
searches require a warrant acquired
within seven days of performing the
search so you can do still do the
advanced search in the moment but you
have seven days to then get the warrant
otherwise you have to throw up any data
acquired in that advanced search so what
protections are currently offered for
travelers when they are crossing borders
there are a few out there that are
somewhat decent in our opinion they
don't go far enough but one of them is a
one pass word for those of you who
aren't familiar when password is a
password management solution you store
your credentials in what they term a
vault which is just it's almost like a
directory of your credentials and you
get to categorize them by vault for what
they apply to and so the idea is you
create a travel vault that would only
have the credentials for services that
you need while you're traveling and so
then when you log into the 1password
site and enable travel mode it actually
deletes any other vault that's currently
on your device outside of your travel
vault which is great because that that
means that you're only exposing those
but it doesn't do anything to protect
the keychain or any other credentials
that are stored elsewhere on the device
so with Android there's multiple users
you could configure a travel user which
again they're only configured with the
applications and services that you need
while traveling but this won't do
anything against forensic solution when
they plug in and take a look to see what
else is there because the other users
and their data is going to still show up
in in that in that pool Oh gotcha here
is that you know you're logged in to
your travel user if they recognize that
you have multiple users you're just as
obligated to give access to that other
user as you were to originally give
access to your device and so it's just
more of if they notice then you're still
obligated and accept to you to make a
decision on whether you cooperate or not
yeah so again it's just a pseudo
protection Apple has an application
configurator to
is recommended but I've never been able
to actually validate this claim but it's
recommended to use this because what it
does once you have your device synced
with configurator - you could designate
what laptop or you know endpoint that
you're using to backup and sync your
device to and then any other laptop or
endpoint that you plug the device into
it will not sync with it and so some
have said that this would be a good
solution against a forensic device like
a cellebrite but again I can't attest to
that and celebrate always has a ton of
little bypasses and gotchas so there's
no guarantee that that is actually the
case so originally when we were talking
about this we were going to be building
a proof-of-concept for laptops that
would enable a more extreme solution to
protecting data but upon taking a look
at USB kill which is an anti forensics
solution that if there's any changes on
the USB ports it will shut down the
computer but you can also configure it
to erase specific files entire
directories just to further protect your
data which fit would be an extreme
solution was water we were headed but
since USB kill handles it and we mixed
that yeah we're not lawyers we do not
recommend in a border crossing you
actively delete stuff in front of a
border search agents before handing it
over that seems like a bad idea for my
non legal opinion I probably raised a
couple of red flags so the best option
when you're traveling is to use a burner
for those of you who aren't familiar
this is going to be a device that you
purchased just a cheap phone cheap
laptop that you only have configured
with services that you need while
traveling and ideally it's not going to
be exposing anything super sensitive so
the and that truly is the best option
here you wouldn't be traveling with any
other of your regular content but for
those of you who that's maybe not the
best option or you just don't have the
cash flow to do it there is the clean
device solution or as we like to call it
the technically proficient poor-man's
burner so you can take a device and you
image these devices and - then you store
these images in some cloud somewhere
whether it's Dropbox or whatever you
choose and then you wipe the device set
it
reset it to factory settings and install
only what you need then when you cross
the border if they haven't taken a look
at your device you can always just
reinstall those images it's a time
consuming process but it's it this is
highly effective and it's a way to still
gain access to all the data that you
would need on your day today without
having to make any cut types of
sacrifices but if it has been looked at
at they looked at the laptop or they
looked at the mobile device don't
install those images because you don't
know what they did they could have
installed some type of malware solution
or something on there that would enable
them to spy and see what exactly is
going on so it would just be a good
choice to just treat it as a burner from
that point on and give a new toy do new
devices once you get home yeah what care
is talking about is if they take the
device away from your presence part of
the new directive with the CBP is that
unless they have a reason to believe it
will interfere with their search or
national security concern of your
presence being there for the search you
are allowed to be in the presence of the
search even the advanced search when
it's conducted although if they're going
in advance there so they probably have
reason to believe that you shouldn't be
present for it
so while these are all great solutions
they don't go far enough
none of these truly protect you if you
need to travel with your data because
none of them will prevent backups well
maybe configurator but none of them will
prevent backups of any kind of keychain
or any kind of credentials so
specifically when I say sensitive data
that's what I'm talking about it's
something to keep it session tokens
credentials that sort of thing so we
should do better we can do better
so reiterating we're not lawyers we did
some proof of concepts here that at
least one of them may have some legal
ambiguity if you actually used it in a
border crossing action we're not
recommending you replicate this
functionality and then do it yourselves
they're more of conversational piece to
get to get things moving forward and
primarily to get the attention of
service providers or OEMs to be
proactive about providing some
technological solutions for for use
instead of all these third parties
trying to to interact with the service
or interact with the base OS to provide
the answers to these situations so the
initial one that we came up with that we
will help you releasing because it's a
little racy is the Deadman switch this
was an application that you can install
on your mobile device that would
programmatically wipe the device if it
was plugged into you know the if the
port was interacted with so it would
still enable a basic search but it would
prevent any advanced search not the best
solution it would probably be better if
they if Apple or Android could create
some kind of solution that you have a
travel mode enabled on the device and
that way the officers could still
interact with the data they could still
pull the data but they wouldn't be able
to get access to the keychain or the key
store that they wouldn't get be able to
get access to those authenticated
session tokens and to end credentials
and so yeah that's the USB kill for the
mobile situation for the mobile device
the other solution we came up was for
the cloud storage for your social media
for your different accounts that you
have access to and we wanted to go
beyond password reset so if that's what
we called the software and nicknamed it
beeper what beeper does is oolitic so
service listening on the internet that
you can send a text message to so you
don't need to have internet access just
ability to send a text message you text
a secret code out to it without the
secret code ignores your your connection
and it connects to all of your social
media accounts it changes it generates a
new password for those using dice ware
and changes your password takes that new
password pgps it to a key that you've
provided it with and then stores that
PGP password up on something like
Dropbox or other cloud storage provider
and this way you it's never written to
disk it's all done in memory on it and
then taking a step further than that it
also revokes all accounts that and
devices that are associated with that
that that platform so it will revoke
your iPhone access your laptop access if
you have browser sessions open it'll
shut those down and it gives you
plausible deniability
that you cannot divulge your access to
this and the naturality they shouldn't
need this because they've said they
won't do anything to access remotely
store
Datta anyways well this would be more of
a solution for employers that sort of
thing yeah and it's also if you've
divulged your password you can quickly
revoke all your access instead of having
to go into things and change it over and
we have a demo of doing just that I am
NOT gonna live demo this so here we have
your Dropbox it was an empty Dropbox we
connect up to Twitter which is the
social platform that we're going to demo
you go you log in we have our Twitter
account for this we type in our password
verifying that we and we know our
password and can log-in we've also
associated this this account with an
iPhone so we'll go look and you can see
the iPhone listed there on the platform
great-grand
so now I want to revoke my password I go
to send a text message I send my secret
passphrase off to the account send it it
goes and Twitter will try to do a
refresh and you'll see that the
passwords changed Twitter behaves great
and kills the session who hires me to
log back in Here I am typing it in the
same password I did type it incorrectly
but it didn't work so the password did
it we now have a file here in our
Dropbox
it's called Twitter PGP go ahead and
download that and then we'll run PGP to
decrypt it we have this really long dice
where passphrase there copy it go back
to Twitter show that copy and paste that
in that's much longer than the password
was originally that is the new password
just by sending a text message and then
we'll go verify that to the iPhone no
longer has access to this as well so
this is just sort of its own like it's
capable there are solutions out there
there should be sort of some something
bad happened in my life I need to blow a
fuse and revoke access to as many things
as possible right now as opposed to
having to log in and take all these
precautions there should be some
solution for
or extreme situations the main takeaway
is we really need to do better as an
industry at protecting the individual
user and we need to get out in front of
this instead of being reactionary if we
need to be more proactive in making
these solutions to ensure that users
stay safe yeah so it's not live yet
we're gonna have a github page that has
all these things listed out one thing I
wanted to call a particular is that last
month the e FF presented at CCC and they
presented on this exact same topic but
in a much more global context looking at
UK and European and Canadian and US laws
and walking through a lot of that
everything basically everything up until
like the technical solutions that we
talked about well and they don't have
the updated directive the directive came
out the week after their talk so their
talks outdated thank you very much