[Music]
thank you thank you for this lovely
introduction and I'm very excited to be
here today so good morning so in true
Israeli fashion I'm gonna start with a
direct question do you know this guy
some of you may be well for those of you
who don't know him this is Kevin Finster
he is a respected security researcher
that found the critical vulnerability in
one of DJI drone system now according to
the media reports this vulnerability
leaked personal information of their
consumer in true white hat fashion Kevin
wanted to report his vulnerability to
DJI and disclose it under their active
bug bounty program but at that time when
BJ I first launched their program they
had no clear technical scope or policy
so according to the reports in the media
Kevin contacted them and in private
communication they indeed authorized
that the vulnerability he found was in
scope
not only that they offered him the
highest reward for it
$30,000 not bad right not bad well then
the plot thickened DJ I also wanted him
according to the reports in the media to
sign a one-sided agreement an NDA that
he found was one-sided and left him
legally exposed when he refused
according to the reports in the media
they threatened him with legal action
under the notorious Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act well how does this sort story
end
Kevin ended up walking away from a
$30,000 approved bounty that's right a
new Tesla
that's the commitment to appreciate that
now DJI of their own version to the
story and I really encourage you to go
online and check out their comments this
is one article you can find here but for
me the important takeaway is that I
believe that this could have been
prevented if we had clear safe harbors
for white hats for researchers taking
part in bug bounty programs my name is
Damita Lazzari and i'm here to speak
with you about what each and every one
of you can do to make sure that stories
like this don't happen again so
yesterday we heard a brilliant
presentation from Casey and I want to do
an experiment here in the crowd and ask
you who here knows the turns heard heard
the term bug bounty by show of hands
come on don't be shy right everybody
this is all over the place raise your
hand if you ever accessed a bug bounty
webpage the policy is something that
looks like this Thank You Google West
people now be honest raise your hand if
you ever read the legal part of the bug
bounty not too many of you right well
this is our reality I accept is the
biggest lie of the information age and
often people don't pay careful attention
to the fine print but as I will share
with you today
we need to start paying attention if you
want this bug bounty economy to work
because this is a wake up call in
private circles in Twitter we hear more
and more stories about people like Kevin
being threatened yes also in a bug
bounty also in a coordinate
vulnerability disclosure program so what
I will show you today what I will walk
with you through is this problem
bug bounties are exploding they attract
hackers that want to play by the rules
but their wounds won't let them then we
should start to think about changing the
rules now as you have noticed this is a
terms of your stock so little disclaimer
of my own while I am a lawyer from
Israel it might have recognized that I
am NOT admitted to practice law here in
the United States and this is a
presentation in enigma this is no not a
legal advice so just a little bit of a
disclaimer so how did we get here
well the bug bounty economy is exploding
the legal market for vulnerabilities is
booming bug bounty programs frameworks
in which hackers white hat hackers
security researchers legally trade
vulnerabilities for monetary for
reputational rewards are expanding
across industries never before the legal
market for vulnerability has been stone
dynamic just take a moment to look at
those numbers tens of thousands of
hackers participating in programs tens
of millions of dollars distributed in
bounties now this is amazing this is a
wonderful shift in how we view security
researchers we now have a bug bounty for
the Pentagon for the US Army for food
chains like Starbucks for financial
institutions of traditional industries
like Western Union we are even giving
hackers flight reward mileage so they
can fly the world everything to make
them a part of the solution now I think
this is positive in three and a half
decades we have seen a transition in bug
bounties from this gimmick this
marketing thing advertisement to a
Senate bill proposing to enact bug
bounties in the Department of Homeland
Security an icon of the establishment
now this is positive and I do agree with
my sister Karen that hackers are an
important part of the internet immune
system so here's my question to you why
here inside our industry we are still
attacking friending hat friendly hackers
instead of helping them
to help us I hope by the end of this
presentations I will convince you all to
be a part of the solution but slow but
let's go ahead and understand the
problem and in order to understand the
problem we need to take a deeper a
deeper dive into the terms of use so I'm
gonna raise a few questions in this
booming bug bounty who dictates the
rules of the game who safeguards the
legal interests of the individual hacker
our bug bounties operating as the true
safe harbor they claim to be this
industry has been working for a while to
remove legal barriers for security
research but before we go to Congress we
need to make sure that right here inside
our industry contracts are enabling
white hats to do what we ask them to do
to help us so the answer to these
questions starts with taking a very good
look in the terms so I did that I read
hundreds of terms of use of bug bounties
and what I found was very surprising
platforms and companies sometimes put
hackers in legals
harm's way shifting the risk for
liability towards the hackers instead of
clearly authorizing access and creating
safe harbors some organizations if
including governmental like the
Department of Defense would commit under
contract not to pursue legal action
against a hacker that follow the
guidelines but others leave hackers
exposed in some truth situations we have
a reality where the hacker is in breach
in a de facto breach of the terms just
for doing what we did we asked them to
do now if you take a look at the terms
this is something that you will often
see programs companies they will require
hackers to comply with all laws here on
earth on Mars just comply with all
applicable laws
now this is important but if you don't
give that hacker the safe harbor then
you are really not enabling him to
follow the law that you asked him to do
in some other cases hackers might be
forced into contractual and criminal
civil liability why because the terms of
the bag bounty will also include a
reference to the general and user
license agreement now this is geared
this is the EULA is an agreement for
users so what you will find there and
I'm sure you probably are familiar with
this is this crossing
please don't test our system no reverse
engineering no copying don't do don't do
anything to the curb so if you subject a
hacker in the bug bounty program to that
general Yuliya and you prevent that kind
of security techniques it doesn't really
make much sense not only that it creates
a situation where the hacker is actually
not only breaching the contract also us
anti hacking laws in other cases the
terms might just say something like this
don't penetrate our system don't test it
here's the body for testing our system
but don't test it so this is quite
paradoxical now this is problematic for
companies this creates situation like DJ
eye but mostly what this is doing is
shifting the legal risk towards that
individual hacker in other cases we
might see a separation between the
technical guidelines so the server is
the money the rewards the important part
and the legal parts that's not very
helpful to send a hacker to an
additional contract to click on in some
cases there is no legal part at all no
legal part even in very big programs in
other cases we see discrepancies and
conflicts between the general contract
of the platform the intermediary that
runs the bug bounty that also applies to
the hacker and the specific program
guidelines now except for the issue of
discrepancy
the person who needs to solve that kind
of discrepancies is the is that huh
correct yes our legal expert that notes
all applicable laws well this is the
conclusion after reading hands of terms
what i found is while programs often
focus on a very important part indeed of
the technical scope and the money and
often also disclosure the safe harbor
part the clearer ization to access the
system is either ignored non-existing or
lacking our reality today in contractors
is that safe harbor is actually the
exception it's not a standard and
specific authorization to access the
system under anti hacking laws well
that's almost none existing and this is
paradoxical it's paradoxical because bug
bounties are supposed to be legal right
this is how we attract the talent from
the black market this is how we
collaborate with hackers we create these
safe safe harbors and we also know that
hackers care about their illegal risk so
this is a survey from 2015 60 % 6-0 60 %
of participates participants of
researcher said that legal threat action
is the reason for them not to work with
the vendor to disclose a vulnerability
so legal incentives are supposed to be
important to attract the best hackers to
attract the best talent to your platform
to your program but in reality with
returns that stand in direct tension
with a mere practice of security
research so you're probably asking why
well these are take-it-or-leave-it
contracts they are drafted by one side
the lawyers of the platform and the
company the individual hacker the
researcher he is not in a negotiation
position maybe it lacks the knowledge
right so this is why it's
to us industry researchers platforms to
work together to make sure and the men
to see safe harbor in every bug bounty
it's up to us to make it a standard so
how do we do that
in order to do that we need to first
take a very small dive into the lagoon
or landscape so I'm promise this will be
short they're with me it's not new that
the law struggles to facilitate white
hat and gray hat hacking and this is
paradoxical because more and more
regulators are asking or recommending
that you will in fact enact a
coordinated vulnerability disclosure
program or even a bug bounty but we do
have a piece of good news and this is
the good news and this is why the
contract of the bug bounty is so
important the law allows you rabbit
parties through contracts to create a
safe harbor for the hacker to authorize
the hacker if is indeed within the very
limited and careful scope of the program
in terms of technicalities in terms of
disclosure etc to say this is authorized
conduct it allows you to do so but it
requires you to use contracts for that
so the first very important insight that
this is not a legal landscape shaped
only by vague and overbroad laws like
the CFAA
this is also legal landscape shaped by
private law by contracts by boilerplate
language of EULA's of platform terms of
bug bounty terms that affect thousands
of thousands of hackers so we have a
power to change this now the second
insight is that in the land of anti
hacking was clearer ization to access
the system and consent is what matters
so in a nutshell the CFAA the Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act creates criminal
liability
sometimes even civil liability for
intentionally accessing a protected
computer and obtaining information
without authorization or in a manner
which exceeds authorized ation notice
authorization the DMCA an amendment to
copyright law also prohibits sir
convention of technological barriers to
copyright protected work so code this
includes bypassing measures without the
consent of the relations of the of the
copyright owner we also have a new DMCA
temporary exemption for good-faith
security research but if you take a
careful look at the guidelines you will
see that the DMCA new exemption also
requires that their hacker that the
white hat hacker won't violate any other
law including swat contract law and the
CFA yes so there is a relationship
between them in the end it boils down to
the language of the bank bounty terms
this is why that language is so
important to create a safe harbor so we
might have also an agency problem and
the problem is that the legal interests
of the hackers the companies and the
platform's sometimes are not aligned and
the lawyers well they think about who
pays them they might think about the
clutter client which is the company or
the platform in this situation the risk
might be shifted to the individual
hacker so what can we do how can we
change this well clearly we are doing a
bug bounty because which one attract
hackers to want to follow the rules and
if our rules won't let them we need to
change them so this is what I'm
suggesting in order to help mitigate the
legal risks of more than 100,000 hackers
in bug bounties
first of all eliminate the paradoxical
terms there is no point in inviting
hacking to your platform to your to your
program and then saying don't test our
systems that's just that that just
doesn't make any sense if you wanna if
you want to include a reference to the
EULA to the allergens you can work on it
you can do it but we need to eliminate
those paradoxical paradoxical terms
second of all we need to increase the
salience of legal terms salience is a
term from consumer law that basically
says that if consumers vote in their
feet if hackers vote in their fingers
they don't participate in bug bounties
with lacking safe harbors then the
market police's the quality of the chirp
then drafters of platforms and in
companies they have an incentive to
change the terms so this is my slogan
you can try to make a sticker out of it
hackers no safe harbor don't participate
vendors no safe harbor don't lunch go to
your lawyer ask him what's the risk of
my my crowd and platforms if there is no
safe harbor don't put it in your
platform make that exemption the
exception of a contractual commitment
not to pursue the the law the hacker the
standard and add specific authorization
under the relevant laws because that
helps negating the whole foundation for
the legal claims so it's more than a
contractual commitment not to pursue
legal action and here we have a very
important document by the Department of
Justice the division entrusted on
enforcement of the CFAA now if you're
even thinking of a bug bounty you should
know that document and they say that
clear authorization it's a guidance so
it's not binding but still that they
mentioned they're clear of thorns ation
for the purpose of the CFAA in the DMCA
that's important so you have the
language here I'm happy to share the
link with others later then we need to
push towards standardization one
language of safe harbors across
platforms across industries across bug
bounties this will create a signaling
effect when a company doesn't adopt that
language it will help raise awareness to
the terms it will reduce the
informational burden on hackers it will
also reduce drafting costs because now
you have a template you can come to your
client say well here's the template
think about it
we need to think about education for
hunters of the legal risk and simplify
disclosures and maybe even create a
reputational system for the quality of
the legal terms platforms they have a
very important role to play here they
are doing really good stuff for hackers
but there is more to be done they need
to vet the terms they need to know the
terms they need to safeguard the legal
interests of their crowd of their
hackers they can suggest to their
clients the recommended safe harbor
language and they can educate educate
the crowd and even take a contractual
commitment from their client not pursue
legal action against the hacker so we
have good news and bad news good news
it's in our control bad news there is a
lot to be done but we can do this this
doesn't require a legislature this
doesn't require a CFA reform or even a
DMCA exemption this is our control we
can change those contracts even today we
only need to think or start thinking
about that individual hacker that wants
to follow the rules but maybe it doesn't
really understand them very good or
maybe there isn't someone that helps to
safeguard their legal interest now many
of you here in the room are involved in
a bug bounty I encourage you to take
action to look at the DOJ framework to
talk with me to talk with your lawyers
and see what you can do to help change
this reality think about it for a second
the day that Kevin remember that guy
from the beginning he tweeted about this
DJI launched the most comprehensive bug
bounty policy in terms of legal safe
harbor I've seen really some pro hunter
stuff think about the power of this
community if we were able to push
towards safe harbor if we would make it
matter
just some month before that maybe Kevin
could have gotten his Tesla
thank you very much I'm here for your
question and I really enjoyed this