I'm really excited to be here today a
very interesting event and I was really
excited to be asked so I want to just
get started pretty quickly here you know
a little bit about me I think the only
thing to really take away from this
slide that he hadn't already mentioned
and I thought it was a great intro was
that I started off as a developer and
when most security folks start off in
the traditional operations roles or they
get into it through governance I started
basically building software so this
comes from a perspective of somebody who
also has helped to build security as
software at my company I run the red
team which means that I run a offensive
security team we have about 35 people in
the role of the red team and that is
pretty large for a red team which is
kind of fun also it means that I herd
cats so you know kind of getting into
this whole Deb suck up saying hats off
to it what the heck is happening in this
industry software is being built tons of
things are happening you know all of a
sudden we woke up one day and software
was eating the world right well all of a
sudden we woke up one day and agile was
eating the world this was definitely
about 18 years ago when they started to
build the agile manifesto and for those
of you who are security practitioners it
started to change your world because it
meant basically the whole world was
speeding up all our checklists were
starting to kind of become interesting
conversations had friction and this is
the 18 years of the 30 year career that
I've had that have been really
interesting because it's introduced a
lot of friction with that change really
we got to the point where compute wasn't
working we had to have cloud we had to
have all these different things that
were gonna help us to evolve and as you
can imagine cloud actually created a
whole bunch of interesting shifts we
started to see DevOps we were going to
merge Devon ops together because oh by
the way there were easier ways to work
on utility computing it meant that
Operations folks had to start to code
and so that evolution got started now we
have multiple evolutions all building
onto each other you're starting to see
that they
sically it means that we're all asked
being asked to change constantly and
evolve frequently compliance compliance
as code our compliance folks our
governance people they write lots of
documents they don't write code how are
we going to deal with that change
eventually that basically goes from pen
testing to red teaming we see the
evolution of red teams that really kind
of spawn and more and more people
basically trying to figure out how to do
red team even more importantly
traditional security has started to
evolve into devstack ops and what this
map is so that folks that don't know
what it is it's a Wardley map it
basically is something that we use to
kind of figure out what the future holds
so that we're always pushing on the most
important things at our company wordly
maps are really interesting I would if
you haven't seen them before I haven't
read anything wordly puts out a lot of
information definitely look them up so
if we know that this is what the heck is
happening you know how hard could it be
to do dev SEC ops and I will tell you
that this is a DevOps pipeline this is
basically somebody creating code they've
got really interesting mechanics of
building that code and publishing it and
a lot of these things are sorted by a
single use capability along the way what
we found out was very quickly that
security is very complicated there's not
a lot of single use single purpose tools
that actually get built in to support
code as it's being developed which has
created a lot of friction in the world
for folks that do develop software who
are trying to figure out how to make it
safer there are tons of developers out
there that are worried every day that
the software that they develop is not
actually secure enough so if this is our
world it's really complicated as you can
imagine as a security professional where
we get so many people dedicated to our
function you know we're basically
usually 1% of whatever the software
development team is so if you have a
hundred developers you have 10
operations staff you have about one
person that covers your security realm
and one person to cover all these tools
I can tell you that's absolutely unaware
there was a lot of head banging I
actually have this sign sitting in my
office it's metal it hurts a lot it
really helps a lot too
and I'll tell you I bang my head even
today and the reason why is because the
journeys not written there's no book to
go look at you can imagine yourselves
you're starting to see these things if
you're not I'm so sorry you're going to
because really soft rates the world were
all at being asked to basically build
software skills I took them on the
unimaginable which was to tell a bunch
of security professionals that they were
going to have to build code and to this
day we have about 35 people they all
code I remember trying to convert a
compliance specialist and he told me
that I was insane I said you have a year
to do it nine months later he came to me
and said were you serious and I said yes
you have three months left or you're
gonna be finding a new job so to this
day he's also helping to move the Deaf
suck-ups movement forward he is an avid
programmer and is working as a lead in
security engineering that's kind of cool
so kind of what's the maturity model so
if you can imagine like five and a half
years ago for me it was waking up one
morning and being told we need you to
make this more formulaic so that other
people can do it with you I've been
doing this for about 15 years trying to
bang my head against the agile roadmaps
trying to figure out what's going on how
to scrum work and I started developing
code back when I was really young and it
didn't necessarily transcend into this
agile world because I used to follow
these things that were really
traditional thuds of roadmaps that you
basically didn't have to think about
because everybody had every requirement
ever known to man written down for you
and when you got done with the project
it basically failed so now this agile
work comes into the place you have this
new thing called culture you've got to
figure out people skill evolution you
have to bring a whole bunch of
executives along with you it's an
interesting dynamic programs and
outcomes I've gotten into basically
figuring out exactly how I'm going to
digest a annual road map into quarterly
outcomes and get a bunch of people who
want to be innovative to figure out how
they're going to break it down which
means basically my security team does
DevOps they leverage agile and scrum we
do a lot of scrum Road
sometimes we do fast scrum and sometimes
we do slow scrum and everybody's got a
little bit of a different way of doing
things I would say we're not any
different
your security priorities so I would say
that where we are now
my actual goals for the year is get
ahead and stay ahead of adversaries no
big thing right everybody can do this
super-easy somebody out there has
already done it for us there's already
tools commercial things that you can buy
off the shelf yes sure
so the pixie and fairy dust get ahead
and stay ahead is a really interesting
big hairy audacious goal and super
interesting from the standpoint of
changing how you think about what you're
going to do so if you go to the
innovation catalyst programs that are
out there which into it really
subscribes to you find out that you need
to think differently and thinking
differently actually is approaching
problems in a different way so that's
how we got to a maturity model these are
some of the behaviors I would say that
the first early behaviors are looking
around saying well there's no roadmap
for this so therefore it doesn't exist
so I'm not gonna do it and other
roadmaps basically tell you that there
actually are a lot of people who are
subscribing to it doing this work and a
whole lot of people who have done it who
didn't know what it was labeled so we
eventually branded it so the way to
think about this and to put it into
perspective is that you have to have a
developer brain and it starts with
having a developer brain in a way that
maybe all you're doing is automating a
very small amount of work you could be
doing something as simple as making your
email move every day I like to say that
even scripters or coders these days with
a developer mindset can you imagine for
a moment what they're really interested
in and we kind of created something
interesting which was and I always I'm
kind of manipulated by the outside world
Nutrition Facts labels kind of you know
started to eat into how we were thinking
about things what if there's only one
question you really have to ask to
change the perspective of everybody in
your organization to get security built
into your software what if that question
is how many adversaries do I have and
I'm not talking about the security team
asking that question of themselves I'm
asking that question as a developer how
many average say
does my software have how many
adversaries does my application have how
many adversaries does my commercial
products that have how many adversaries
right and if you don't know the answer
of that question it's the beginning of
your journey and my mind warping way of
telling you that you now to became a dev
SEC ops specialist this question is
super powerful it gets you into things
like well maybe I'll apply funnel
techniques developers really think about
conversion in an interesting way they've
got a sales mindset I need to sell my
product to customers if I make it truly
delightful and I use things like design
for delight I'm gonna actually create
conversion well what if we're all going
about this adversary thing the wrong way
and what if we're actually gonna have to
design for a lack of delight what if we
can actually waste the time of
adversaries what if we can find out who
they are and get ahead of them and what
if we use the same techniques as our
developer brethren what if we're just
cousins and we just have a different
mindset about it so if you can imagine
you're now just gonna change your
mindset you're gonna now be chasing
adversaries so that you can take that
information and provide it back to a
developer well that's a little bit more
of how it actually operates and in the
best way imagine for a moment a
developers looking at a library and
their question is well which one's safer
which commercial tool out there provides
that answer for you easier they have a
library they're going to use they want
to use it early in their pipeline and
there aren't that many products out
there so they want to understand
adversaries as a developer I'm a
developer I want to know who's out there
where do I go do I go start surfing the
dark web how many of you security
practitioners would let me loose in the
dark web as a developer yeah nobody
right how many people think that
developers don't want to have that
information it's really interesting what
we learned was developers who know more
about their adversaries tend to fix
things even faster I used to think that
being a two day unicorn was impossible
and what I mean by a two day unicorn is
there were companies out there that were
able to get things were mediated in two
days and we're a two day unicorn
we subscribe to our SLA as we get things
done because we actually work on what's
important the things that adversaries
are going after and we triangulate that
information a variety of ways
I have petabytes of information that are
coming in and that petabytes of
information lead to all sorts of
insights I don't have any problem
getting information from developers here
you go we want you to take it go make
some sense of it developers don't have
time to go chase after adversaries and
make sense of them what they have time
to do is take your insights and your
remediation guidance and do something
with it what we learned was we used to
hack we used to guess what would
actually be interesting and today we
don't do it that way we chase bad guys
figure out what the TTP's are that
they're using weari subscribe to those
TTP's and we use a huge data Lake to be
able to figure it out we're leveraging
AI and ml how many of you want to start
doing those things it's incredible work
to do I will tell you that as you think
about the new journey you're on as a
security professional you're going to be
learning a whole lot more and it's
incredible work being able to take apart
adversaries figure out what they're
doing help your company to get ahead it
takes every bit of information you
generate every bit of information that
the product generates every bit of
information about the attack surface
that you have and a way of actually
putting that into sense for your
prioritization so you know if a
developer is trying to figure this out
there are basically three types of
adversaries basic moderate and advanced
type of adversary about 80 percent of
the average series out there from our
Intel tell us that they're mostly basic
attackers they're trying things they
don't even really try very hard they're
just spraying the internet and they're
getting information back that actually
makes it so that they get lucky if
you're dealing with lucky attackers you
can actually get better than they are so
that kind of all boils down into what is
kill chain we've all heard about kill
chain in the past with Lockheed it kind
of came up it was a white paper and then
everybody went well how do you do it and
it became complicated confusing and some
of those things now you see mitre kind
of pair in Capek you see mitre Karon
attack frameworks and what we determined
was you can have
we use this framework and determine and
actually forecast what adversaries are
going to do and to what in your
environment 80% of the time we think
that with the advancements of AI and ml
you're going to be able to do that even
more frequently you might even get to
the point where you have a hundred
percent being able to determine what
they're going to go after as it's being
published through your development
lifecycle so pretty cool stuff
converting it to human so I always say
that it's really great that we can read
that kill chain thing and we know what a
c1 is but imagine for a moment that your
CEO speaks kill chain I have a CEO who
speaks kill chain he understands
adversaries it's pretty darn cool and
the way that that happened was through
converting it to human we have this
thing called grades we basically grade
everything those be ten see 20 that's
basically how we go through and what we
give back is we give our remediation
guidance that has a grade that as a
developer you don't need to know
anything about CBE cbss or any of these
methodologies that a security
practitioner might use you just know
that that's an F and you need to fix it
within two days and so we've super
simplify it for our developer folks and
it makes it a lot easier and by the way
we're developer folks too so we kind of
like it because we don't have to think
about it follow the guidance get it done
and by the way it goes away so the other
thing that we learned was we need to be
continuously security testing this
doesn't just mean spraying and praying
and basically using any scanner out
there to be able to find what you think
it adapted acker is going to be doing it
actually means going after and using the
science of what an attacker is doing to
you what they will do to you and
leveraging everything out there that you
can get your hands on we do leverage
every scanner that we can get that's a
commercially available we also leverage
things like Metasploit we've made
modules that we've committed we're
constantly building scripts to break
into stuff we take P Oh season and make
them better and if you can imagine it
became a huge arsenal and attack
framework I think the thing that is
really interest
is that what we started to see in our
data was that we could get ahead that as
we posted stuff it wasn't necessarily
interesting to an attacker right off
that even lucky attacks weren't actually
finding things very fast and that if you
can actually figure out when something's
coming down the pipeline
you can usually forecast before it
becomes enough there is something that's
basically become really interesting to
us is that everything degrades security
is just a degradation problem you put
something out somebody gets interested
in it degrades the security of the
software and then all of a sudden you
have to do something about it
basically the notices that we're getting
meltdown and spectre and heartbleed and
all these things that come up
they're just security recalls it didn't
get done the right way the first time
you might not have the notion of fewer
better suppliers but ultimately at the
end it's just a degradation notice
you're simply fixing something that
didn't get fixed in the first place and
didn't get fixed in the first place
because somebody was unaware didn't know
how to do something didn't get feedback
fast enough and what we say in dev sack
ops is that feedback is a gift feedback
has to be faster it has to be more
reliable and it is our job as security
practitioners to make it so that the
folks that also participate in security
which is your development crowd they're
actually also getting the things that
they need and so we are basically a
service provider and on my team to the
rest of our organization so that we can
supply adversary knowledge and
information about what's happening to
applications can you imagine putting out
a security service and having it adopted
without too much friction in your
company I can and the reason I can is
because I know how many attackers are
hitting the applications and we're able
to convince very simply through saying
here's what's happening to your
application by the way adversaries out
there have recently done some
interesting things like they've changed
their tactics with sequel injection
they've gone from simple sequel
injections of one equals one to
mathematical proofs on a session by
session basis that's pretty cool
and how do I know that well the way that
I know that is that it comes in through
our information feeds and now I'm able
to talk about it with the
who are gonna have to fix it and they're
gonna have to fix it and they don't
necessarily know how so unifying
security with DevOps all these tools
that have to come back together they're
actually really interesting what we push
on with our commercial vendors is that
we want them to make them API available
we want to be able to receive feeds
through things like s3 so we can take
advantage of data lakes and data
capabilities that are out there we want
to be able to mesh data together and we
want to be able to leverage that so that
we can turn it into pearls of wisdom and
insights for developers as fast as
possible
latency in that conversion process is
not good just simply integrating these
tools into your pipeline is okay but
it's not the ultimate goal and I think
that the the thing that I'll also leave
you with is a few places to start
looking for information so one of them
was our CSO did a talk at RSA last year
and did the security hierarchy of needs
pretty cool stuff it kind of gets you
started with how a developer can start
to hone security skills because by the
way dev sock ops is a scale problem
everyone in your company makes security
decisions every day and you need a
method in a model not necessarily a
checklist to make them good at making
good security decisions so we leverage
the hierarchy of needs to be able to do
that we basically say if you hit these
five things then your application is
going to be protected against 80% those
lucky guys and it's going to make it so
that you don't have to think about
remediation guidance because you're not
going to get any problems that come in
the other thing that was really
interesting with several years ago Avera
code actually did a full stack attack
talk at RSA and this was also incredible
they talked about the cloud and some of
the issues with it it's old information
but it's really interesting from the
standpoint of how you build attack Maps
and actually how you start to
incorporate that into the development
process we leveraged threat maps or
threat models at Intuit we also use
things called attack Maps so our red
team builds attack Maps constantly and
then finally def suck-ups lessons
os if you haven't seen this it's got a
lot of detail and statistics in it
fabulous and was done by sono type they
give you a lot of survey details hugely
helpful in setting up an SDLC that
leverages dev suck-ups so I will leave
you with the last thing which is
basically you know you're gonna want to
get involved in a community start to
hone your understanding give back one of
the things that we're constantly
thinking about is how do we give back
we're in the middle of revising our dev
stickups program across several
companies and participating in pushing
more of this information and content out
so that more people can leverage it