you
who's seen this before Robin asks how do
I fix the security bug and Batman says
you should know this is basically what
happened the first time that someone
scanned one of my apps with a
vulnerability scanner he sends me an
email with this huge automated report
attached to it and I have no idea what
it means so I ask for help and he tells
me you should know so then I scurry back
to my desk my teams all like what does
this mean this is years ago and after
much researching and googling I send it
back to him we have to go through this
three times for me to finally pass all
the tests I'm like well that was hard
and he said if you were a good
programmer you would have never had any
of these problems in the first place
Wow thanks buddy and so that taught me
and that taught me a valuable lesson a
bad lesson don't ask security for help
and now that I've switched sides and I
work in application security and I
actually do security testing all the
time I know that that guy had no idea
what that report meant and he was too
embarrassed to admit it and that's why
he said that so with that let's talk
about insecurity and information
technology so yeah what their developers
do that can make the security team feel
insecure well first of all they hide
they hide stuff from the security team
they don't ask for the security teams
advice when maybe they should for
instance don't ask Tonya how to do
crypto we'll just a 64 encode it twice
no one will ever crack that sometimes
they receive the security report and
they're like we don't have time for that
or they won't let you do security
testing because there's just no time
besides hiding things and not taking
advice sometimes like they just don't
ask for advice and
it can kind of make the security team
feel a bit like chopped liver so let's
look at the other side of this Queen
what does security do that could make
developers not feel very good about
themselves well let's see
sending so when I got that report that
was really long full of bugs it made me
feel like a giant loser if you send
someone a static analysis report that's
like 500 pages long that doesn't make us
that doesn't make developers feel good I
forget I'm not a developer anymore
sometimes the security team doesn't give
usable advice so what they do is they
send a link to NIST yeah but I wanted to
know how to do a file upload securely
read NIST no that's just not answering
right and sometimes they kind of seem
like a gate like you have to get past
them and they'll had requirements to
your security the requirements to your
projects and when you ask why they say
it because security and then they don't
explain like you're a dummy and you
can't understand and it's like just tell
me why we need to do these things I need
to understand it's a lot easier to do
work if you know why you're doing it and
like we saw in the last slide or the
very first slide sometimes when they
tell developers about problems they can
make them feel incompetent when they do
it so in my opinion this creates
feelings of job insecurity in the
development team and the security team
this friction between the two teams so
I've worked at a lot of places and I do
consulting and I talk to a lot of people
and I saw this happening in so many
shops like from both sides like the
developers just basically always us
hiding from the security team and the
security team being like
I all the developers talk to us and this
friction it causes this feeling of job
insecurity and so I researched it I
started researching this a year ago and
it turns out the social scientists have
already looked into this a lot so I
didn't have to do that much work thank
you and it turns out that when people
feel insecurities in their jobs they
have this predictably bad behavior so
let's look at that behavior deviant
behavior
so if you have employees acting with
deviant behavior do you think that they
are following your processes maybe
they're not moral disengagement do you
want someone with flexible morals being
in charge of your sensitive data reduce
job involvement great I have a big team
full of uninspired IT folk risk-taking
behavior since I'm in an IT security
crowd I feel like you probably know what
risk-taking behavior is and as last ones
a bit weird reduction of organizational
citizenship behavior so that is the
positive workplace activity that you do
so let's say you are in the kitchen and
no one is no one's around you know
you're by yourself
and you're pouring coffee and you spill
a little bit on the counter if you have
good organizational citizenship behavior
what you will do is you will grab some
paper towel and you'll wipe that up and
you might just wipe down the whole
counter if there's water on it because
you feel invested in your workplace and
your job right but if you don't have
good organizational citizenship behavior
what you'll do is you'll leave the
coffee and you might think you know what
screw those other guys when people are
acting like this you know when they're
deviating from the processes you've
planned for them they're not really
involved they're not really invested
they don't seem to care as much do you
think they're making bulletproof
software I don't um do you think that
that person's gonna stay really really
late figure fixing every single last
security bug or diligently test over and
over and over to make sure that every
single flaw is fixed I don't think
they will and in my opinion all of this
leads to insecure software that is the
thesis of my whole talk and from this
point forward instead of talking about
problems because a bunch of you have
probably seen a lot of these problems
especially if you develop software or
your kin application security and we
have to fix these things and so let's
talk about solutions okay I have a plan
you don't have to read it I've read that
as soon as you put words on a screen
everyone reads it so I'm gonna read it
with you it's gonna be great so the plan
is to support the development and the
security team with processes training
and resources so that they confidently
get their jobs done and then step two
we're gonna initiate and maintain
culture change so this plan for the rest
the talk I'm just gonna dissect it piece
by piece and give you examples of things
with funny memes to help you remember
what you could go back to your office
and do start and whenever you get back
there let's go so let's talk about
processes so if I'm gonna make a change
it takes 30 seconds to do it shouldn't
take three weeks to get approval to do
it there shouldn't be 21 steps to get
your step approved unless you're
launching a nuke right like someone
who's four levels above me in my
organizational in the org chart or
wherever I work my boss's boss's boss's
boss that person should not be approving
changes that I make is part of my
everyday job we're wasting everyone's
time that person has no idea what I do
and they have no idea if that change is
gonna break something else right so
let's create processes that work so
everyone starts getting stuff done and
then they start feeling more awesome so
one you don't have an application
security team this baby will not put up
with that
the application security team is the
part of your security team that knows
how to make bulletproof software so they
know how to do security testing they
know how to do code review they know how
to teach developers about security flaws
and how to fix them right so they don't
do all the work
they help steer the developers and help
teach them to help them meet their
security goals so if you don't have an
application security team and you work
in an enterprise business you really
need one approximately 25% of all
security incidents are caused by a
vulnerable software are you spending a
quarter of your budget on application
security and if you're not maybe you can
afford an OPSEC team so you remember
that team we just hired I have work for
them already so every time from now on
that you start a brand new software
project you're going to matrix one of
them onto the team sometimes this is
called the partnership model and
basically they are going to follow the
project the whole way through and be
your go-to person for security so if you
need a test done they'll do it or
they'll find someone that does it if you
need architectural advice they will
either answer you or they'll find
someone that can review your
architecture for you and answer you so
no more guessing who to talk to this
person will go all the way through the
project with you it's so nice I've
totally worked in a model like this
where I was the developer it was so
great so I do caution though that you
cannot assign this person to 21
different projects at the same time
because then you have a bottleneck and
you've just created a problem instead of
fixing one I suggest a roll of three
because as you will see them further
slides I have a lot more work for these
people to do than just this so another
thing we can do is start security early
and do it the whole way through
sometimes called pushing left so
formalized security activities and as
part of your system development life
cycle right so no matter what paradigm
you're doing like if you're doing a
great big waterfall or you're doing
agile it doesn't matter you still have
to know what you're building you still
have to actually code it you still have
to make a plan whether it's in little
cycles or big cycles
still need to do these things and we
still need to do security activities we
just need to adjust them depending upon
what type of way you're doing to build
your software so formalize these
activities as part of your system and
you'll have much much much better
software so with that in mind security
needs to adjust itself as need be to
what the developers are doing so if the
developers are sprinting security needs
to get running shoes and learn how to
syringe right so brake security into
smaller pieces if that's what you need
to do one thing you can do is for
instance if you're doing static code
analysis I've seen it where you know
there's a big waterfall happening and
you have this three week window where
you do this big code review and static
code analysis awesome but if they're
doing agile that's not appropriate right
so instead just do one sweep and just
look for XSS cross-site scripting and
then in your next sweep just look for an
injection of vulnerabilities adjust
yourself to the developers because they
are like water they're gonna go around
you to get to where they need to be
they're not gonna stop for you or anyone
so we better catch up
I don't always validate my vulnerability
assessment results but when I do I do it
in production I cannot stress this
enough when you send results from
security testing or analysis or whatever
to developers you need to validate
everything you cannot send false
positives because when you do that you
are sending out them on a wild goose
chase it's really hard to prove a false
positive and so then you're also like
ruining their trust in you right because
they're gonna take forever looking for
this thing that doesn't exist and then
they're not going to trust the rest of
your zoltes from then on and I've seen
it create huge huge friction so always
validate the results if you have
something coming out of a security tool
and you're like that will take too long
well then it takes too long for the
developers to write they don't even have
all the security tools and training that
you have so please be mindful um let's
talk about training
I feel like mr. t is like really
forceful with the training okay so when
I when I mean training I don't mean
general IT security training I mean
training that is exactly specific to
your job responsibilities that you do
every day so not don't click that link
but you're a you're a coder secure
coding training right you do you're a
software architect secure design and
threat modeling security training that
is specific to what people need so let's
get into it do you see this guy looks
pretty stressed right that's because he
thinks he needs to know everything
there's no shame in asking for training
if you feel weak in an area or there's
some new technology and you think you
need to know if there's no money for
training there are lots of resources
online of varying qualities but some are
really good that are free or very low
cost
um you don't want to leave these things
as ambiguous or unknown right if someone
from the development team asks you a
question you need to know the answer and
if you've researched and you've done
training and you still don't know call a
professional and by that I mean
consultant because you when you leave
things as unknown or ambiguous that's
where the insecurity starts because
people start guessing slide what if you
gave security training and it was free
if you can train your developers and
secure coding and other things and you
pay for it they will all show up when I
as a developer I had enough money for a
course once every two years and do you
think I was gonna spend that money on a
security training no no no I'm like show
me that sexy front-end JavaScript
framework yeah I was not interested in
like Oh guarantee so if you provide it
either at a greatly reduced cost because
you bring someone in or you make it free
the developers will line up for it also
don't just give training one single time
I've totally heard people say like yeah
we did that we did security training
like way back in 2012
at one time no things change and so we
need to keep doing it
another thing is job shadowing or death
by fire so the next time there's an
incident bring a developer with you next
time you toss a report for developers to
fix of security bugs make someone from
your team go sit with them and fix bugs
and see how fun a false-positive is
let's talk about resources because if
you don't have what you need some of
this doesn't matter right so create
standards or documents that tell the
rest of IT exactly what you actually
want from that I don't mean a compliance
document I don't mean something that's
turn our pages I don't mean something
that no one understands I mean really
explicit clear rules like public-facing
web apps can only be accessible with
HTTP period end of role right and then
if they do all of these things they
release a pretty good app it's like a
road map it's really good give
developers security tools they just
might do your job for you I've done this
before
it's awesome when the bill comes in I
know the training cost money I know that
consultants cost money I know all of
these things cost money and then when my
hair touches the mic it makes loud
noises but when you're paying try to
remember that you're getting your
mandate done right you're making more
secure code and you're investing in your
team and you need these things but if
that's not enough just remember this is
way cheaper than a breach just when you
write that check way cheaper than a
breach
I'm gonna introduce your new best friend
this is my best friend
Oh ASP this is a group an international
group which chapters all around the
world of around 200,000 security nerds
who are obsessed with application
security it's free invite and encourage
your developers to join this community
they might get hooked and join your app
SEC team like I did now security change
now security culture change see the
happy dog okay so no more blaming from
now on it's not Alice's fault or Bob's
fault what we want to look at is what
happened how do we fix this immediately
and how do we make sure that this never
happens again
right this is called a blameless post
mortem and it's okay to fail it's okay
to make mistakes it's just not okay to
not learn from it when we do I like this
slide when you go to work if you are in
a leadership position when anyone goes
to work but especially if you're in a
leadership position you are saying an
example every single day and you're
teaching your staff what's appropriate
so if you yell at people swear talk down
to people talk badly about other teams
behind their back you're saying that's
okay to do at work so if you set a
positive example at work you're
professional at all times
what you will be doing is making your
team trust you more but also you are
setting an example for them to follow
and when you do that if you're always
the bigger person your team will follow
you anywhere so with that I'm gonna
summarize support the development
security team with processes mmm
processes training and resources so they
can confidently get their jobs done and
then initiate and maintain culture
change and with that I would like to do
a call to action to this audience
so people that come to security
conferences you know a lot of stuff
you're seeing a lot of modern things
you're seeing things from many angles
go back to your office and set that
example I know that sounds cheesy the be
the change that you want to see but it
works it really does right so I'm not
kidding right now InfoSec is fighting a
battle and I don't know if you haven't
noticed but we're not really winning
right now right like we could do better
and we are really seeing insecure apps
all the time and if we want to win we
need to be best friends with developers
we need to get everyone involved in
everyone engaged I'm fighting this
battle with us so security is
everybody's job so I'm calling upon all
of you because it has to start somewhere
why not with all of you thank you for
your time and attention
[Applause]