so I've heard a lot of people talking
about deep learning and specifically a
lot of people claiming that they're
worried that it's overhyped so I'm a
deep learning researcher and I find
these comments pretty interesting
because from my point of view I think I
feel the opposite way I think I feel
like the over hype of deep learning is
itself overhyped there's no question
there's a lot of hype in the field
sometimes there are articles written
about it that are poorly informed but
does that really mean it's over height
let's talk about some of the things
people say they're concerned about
here's one deep mining it's just the
latest fad next year it'll be something
else well it's a fad that's been a long
time coming here is the first Hardware
perceptron the basis of neural networks
and deep moaning from 1957 what you're
actually seeing in deep learning today
is the result of decades of research and
those decades of research are finally
getting to the point where they're
actually giving state-of-the-art results
so it's not so much that this thing has
suddenly popped up and now people are
talking about it but it's after all this
work people have finally got to the
point where it's working really well as
you can expect to see it continue to
improve rather than disappear
but deep mining and machine learning
they're just the same thing right or
click learning is just another tool like
support vector machines random forests
or logistic regression right well
certainly not true that deep learning
and machine learning are the same thing
in fact deep learning is just our way of
doing machine learning before deep
learning came along this is how machine
learning was done let's say you wanted
to look at these breast-cancer slides as
happened in this stanford computational
pathologist study and create a five-year
survival predictive model so in the
classic approach to machine learning
what you would have to do is come up
with lots and lots of examples of
possible features like relationships of
contiguous epithelial regions with
underlying nuclei objects and so on and
so forth so you would have dozens of
domain experts working with dozens of
computer programmers and mathematicians
to come up with these ideas for features
and then to program them and then you
would put them through a classic machine
learning model such as in this case it
was logistic regression now this
computational pathologist paper was
really successful they came up with a
model that was more accurate than human
pathologists but it took years and years
of work
kind of the classic approach to machine
learning deep learning on the other hand
combines these three things it combines
the neural network which is a
mathematically provably infinitely
flexible function with stochastic
gradient descent which is a way of
fitting the parameters of that function
to make it solve your particular model
for your particular data set and to do
it in a fast and scalable way by using
GPUs and it's only in the last few years
of these three things have all come
together to actually allow us to use
these neural networks to get steadily
out results and so rather than having to
do all of this very slow error-prone
expertise intensive feature engineering
what we can do is we can feed a totally
random set of weights into our we'll
start with a totally random set of
weights and then train them with jocasta
gradient descent and we can then go back
and see what these neural networks learn
and so this is an example from Schuyler
and furgus showing what a specific
neural network learns after looking at
over a million photos and so there are
many layers and layer one these are the
filters in layer one you can actually
draw them and see what they look like
but these weren't programmed but it's
learnt to find kind of diagonal edges in
gradients and areas of color and then on
the right hand side we see examples nine
examples of parts of a photo that each
filter has identified so when we get to
layer two of a deep neural network we
start to come up with filters that are
much harder to draw on the left-hand
side as an attempt to draw a sixteen of
them on the right hand side I think is
much more easy to understand which is
here are a bunch of examples nine
examples of a few different filters from
layer two in terms of parts of photo
they recognize and so on layer two we
can combine the edges together for
example to find something which is
recognizing honors we've got another
filter in layer two that's recognizing
lots of lines another filter in layer
two that's recognizing kind of orangey
areas that have met
sunsets so layer three then can combine
those together to find for example
anything that looks like text or
anything that looks like the edge of a
flower by layer five we've got things
which are finding the eyeballs of
lizards and birds we've got something
that's finding unicycle wheels and so in
a deep neural network these can be over
a thousand layers deep so the kind of
level of sophistication you can get when
you have to pre program your features in
compared to the level of sophistication
that you can get when you can learn
hundreds or even over a thousand layers
of features which each of which is
mortal ikut of ly more complex than the
previous one it's very very different in
terms of what it can do and it's also
much much easier to do the neural
network approach because you don't need
all that domain expertise
so a very valid concern until somewhat
recently is well big learning sure looks
great for image recognition but it
doesn't seem to do anything much else
so the first thing I'd say is image
recognition is actually really
interesting and really important so this
is actually an example of a study I did
after noticing that back in 2012 and 13
that deep learning was actually a state
of the art for image recognition I
thought well what could we do with that
so I said to myself okay well let's try
seeing if we can do medical diagnostics
better so a team of folks and I spent
two months looking at lung cancer CT
scans and trained a deep neural network
which had a lower false negative rate
and a higher false re and a lower false
positive rate than a panel of four human
expert radiologists at identifying
malignant cancer tumors in these CT
scans so I would start off by saying
like okay it's it is clear that the
state of the art for image recognition
is deep learning and it's surprising you
know how important that can be for
practical and for real practical
projects I'll also say it's surprising
how many things can be kind of recast as
a image recognition problem so for
example really the key piece of alphago
and the algorithms that have come since
then which have beaten the world
champions at playing go is really an
image recognition convolutional neural
network and specifically what alphago
did was they looked at lots of examples
of go boards you know with the which
have been played in you know actual
human tournaments and they said okay
this go board is an example where white
ended up winning this go board is an
example where black ended up winning and
basically they ended up doing a image
recognition neural network where the
thing that they were trying to learn
wasn't is this photo a cat or a dog but
is this picture of a go board where
white wins or a picture where black wins
and so they ended up with something
where they could actually predict the
winner of a go game based on looking at
the go board and
that was the key piece really to the
success of alphago and the things that
have come since then but there's a good
example of kind of turning something
that doesn't look like an image
recognition problem in this case winning
go into an image recognition problem
so in the InfoSec community one of my
students did something very similar
which was at Splunk they wanted to build
an algorithm to help detect fraud and as
part of that to detect whether two users
were the same person or not whether that
person was associated previously with
fraud and so he wanted to use what he
had learned in our course with image
recognition to do that and so what he
did was he created these pictures you
see on the screen and each picture
represents the mouse movements that this
blank system has captured as somebody
looks at a webpage and so you can see
the actual path of the mouse you can
also see the color represents the
velocity of the mouse and then the
circles represent left clicks and right
clicks and so in this case he created a
convolutional neural network an image
recognition program to try and predict
fraud based on these pictures ended up
with a fantastically successful resolve
which ended up being patented written
about written up post blank and becoming
part of their products so here's an
example of a very direct application in
InfoSec of using image recognition
but is it only useful for image
recognition well until recently it was
true that there were few if any
state-of-the-art results outside of
image recognition but that is no longer
true so in the last couple of years
that's been changing so what I'd say
works now with deep learning is lots of
different kinds of computer vision tasks
work very well state of the art results
you won't find anything better and you
can generally use off-the-shelf
libraries to get them without too much
effort
what you may not realize is also in the
it works now and when I say it works I
mean better than any other approach is
for most NLP problems for many so that's
natural language processing so text
problems for many structured data
problems the way you've got like rows
and columns of data like from a
spreadsheet or a database many time
series and signals problems when I say
signals I mean it could be a signal like
a kind of order of events of different
IP addresses connecting to your system
it could be some kind of a IOT sensor
whatever in all of these examples most
recently I find most state-of-the-art
results coming out based on deep neural
networks so I would say this was also in
the works now category but that's in the
latest research so generally speaking
you're gonna have to do a whole bunch of
your own coding and training of neural
nets and so forth to get really good
results in these areas but it's totally
possible and within the next 12 months I
think you'll see a lot of off-the-shelf
libraries that work really well for
these as well I think equally important
then is that what's not really section
and so in terms of things where I'm
seeing very few practically useful
results right now would be reinforcement
learning adversarial models and anomaly
detection there are pockets of limited
success on certain restricted research
problems but I would say that these
three areas are not areas that are kind
of widely getting state-of-the-art
results across lots of kind of different
problems particularly practical problems
this is a bit of a problem because you
know lots of people are working on
reinforcement learning sorts of people
are publishing in the area and
adversarial models the anomaly detection
are obviously very important in info
sick
so the other thing I've heard is just
big learnings being tried a few times
recently and it's just not working that
well so I would say that's somewhat true
but I think partly it's because a lot of
people in InfoSec seem to be focused on
this not ready part of the of the
spectrum and so in particular if you
look at a AIESEC 2017 here is the deep
learning session and in fact every
single example is basically adversarial
adversarial modeling and so I thought
that was really interesting that the
deep learning session at this important
ACM conference is all focused on stuff
which the basic underlying techniques
don't really work yet in the underlying
literature however the good news is at
nips which is a machine learning focused
conference rather than InfoSec focus
conference there was a InfoSec workshop
and in that one when I looked at their
session 1 machine learning in practice
really every single one of the talks was
covering stuff which is definitely in
the it works well right now section so
it's interesting to see that the kind of
the machine learning community I guess
they kind of understand what stuff works
and what doesn't and they're more
focused on let's use stuff that works
where else I'm concerned that I've seen
lots of examples of people in the
infoset community using deep learning
particularly for anomaly detection and
adversarial modeling where I'd say we
just don't have the tools at this point
so does that mean that we can't really
use steep learning InfoSec because
adversarial modeling and anomaly
detection are so important I'd say no it
doesn't mean that at all like here's
lots of examples of like basic
classification problems that you could
start applying pretty much off-the-shelf
deep learning too right now you could be
doing the OS and intrusion analysis
looking people sign up details or their
IP and session histories who sign up
details would be like structured data IP
and session history would be like a time
series or a signal analysis they both
work really well state of the art
results with deep learning for or
finding spam or phishing you could look
at the message text classification and
I've actually got a paper coming out
very soon which will be showing clear
state of the art results with deep
learning across every single
classification problem we looked at with
text fraud we've already talked about
finding similar users using structured
data and so forth and so I used to run a
big email company which I founded and
you know these were the kinds of things
that we were doing all the time at my
email company and nowadays if I was
still running that company I would
definitely be using deep learning for
all these things
so then I hear that well I'm interested
in deep learning but I can't use it
because it's a black box it needs too
much data it needs phd's it's only for
vision it needs lots of GPUs it's not
really AI and these are all kind of to
me just tired claims that just aren't
true or aren't true in very interesting
ways
so like the way that you understand a
deep learning model is you can look
inside the black box using all of these
interpretive or m/l techniques and
there's been various interpretive wheel
ml workshops recently and papers in the
end we're basically looking at
visualizing the gradients and
activations this claim you need lots of
data it's generally not true because
most people in practice use transfer
learning which means you start with a
pre trained network which may be
somebody else's share online and then
you fine-tune the weights for your
particular tasks generally speaking if
you've got about a thousand examples of
a signal you should be able to get a
good neural network and say my students
have got very good neural networks with
as few as ten examples
um it's no longer true that you need a
machine-learning PhD our library fast AI
and the Charis library now at Google are
examples of kind of off-the-shelf
libraries that curate and make available
to you most of the best practices that
you need there are online courses and so
forth and there's lots of examples now
like thousands and thousands of examples
for example of students that have gone
through our course online with no
particular background in the field and
are now very successfully applying
neural nets to their real-world problems
you might worry that you need a huge
roomful of GPUs that's really not true
on the whole the vast majority of
successful results I see now are done
with a single GPU you generally see lots
of GPUs for kind of big googly research
projects rather than industry your
commercial real world projects
you know and then we can have this whole
discussion about is it really a I or is
it going to lead to artificial general
intelligence or whatever I don't care
about any of that myself I know some
people do but it seems irrelevant to the
question of is this a useful tool that
you could be using right now to improve
your work and InfoSec
so then the last issue I hear a lot is
well deep learning sounds interesting
that I just don't know how to get
started
I would say in the field of info SiC the
key approach I would say would be
turning your problem into a type that we
already understand how to solve so for
example if you think you have an anomaly
detection problem
don't treat it as an anomaly detection
problem treated as a classification
problem in other words try and find a
couple of different classes so maybe
just you've got one class called these
were anomalies or these were interesting
security events would be more likely and
so now you can turn an into a
classification problem where you're
separating things into interesting
security events or not I would say
adversarial models why don't you just
try skipping the adversarial piece to
start with and build a model without
worrying about that and see if it's
effective enough I find most of the time
it is and then I would say work closely
with people in the deep learning
community there's lots of folks for
example on Twitter
lots of open discussion very high level
of collaboration and openness in the
deep learning community and so you
should find lots of people that can help
you
and then finally I mentioned we have a
free course online no ads no cost it's
we're a non-profit so we make this
available just because we want to help
you out and so if you go to course dot
faster day I we've got many dozens of
hours of lessons to basically teach you
how to get stated the out results in a
very code first way which we hope you
might find helpful sorry that I couldn't
be there to do this talk in person today
but really appreciate your listening
thanks
you