all right thanks everybody so today I'm
going to talk about the evolving
architecture of the web and when I talk
about the web in this presentation I'm
not talking about front-end technologies
like HTML or JavaScript or even back-end
technologies like Ruby on Rails or or
docker instead I'm gonna be focusing on
the underlying technology and
infrastructure and protocols that the
web server that web services are built
on now the web is only one of many
applications that use the hundreds of
thousands of networks that make up the
Internet and privacy is a high-level
goal that many people agree that the web
should provide ideally the web browsing
patterns of individuals who use the
Internet should be private they should
not be something that people who operate
these networks should be able to read
and infer things about we would also
like one high-level goal for browsing
the Internet is performance when you
browse a website it should be snappy it
should be responsive when you send a
request it should come back with very
low latency now historically there's
been a tension between these two goals
on one end of the spectrum anonymity
networks like tor provide very strong
privacy guarantees at the cost of very
high latency and on the other end of the
spectrum you have unencrypted and
cacheable protocols which can achieve
very high latency but have very weak
privacy guarantees so in this talk I'll
explore a confluence of events that have
changed the architecture of the web in
the way that actually makes it possible
to improve both privacy and performance
simultaneously so let's start by talking
about the fundamental protocols that
make the web possible DNS and HTTP dns
the domain name system is a query
oriented protocol that terms names into
numbers it has a tiered architecture
where users clients make requests to or
resolver who answer the questions and if
they don't they talk to an authoritative
server to get the answer
DNS is one of the oldest protocols in
wide the use on the internet and was not
designed with privacy in mind it's an
unencrypted protocol but it also has
well-defined cache semantics and this
caching dynamic where resolvers can take
answers and replay them if someone asks
the same question provides some amount
of privacy cover the authoritative
server only gets visibility into not the
clients entire IP but just the subnet in
which it comes from and not all requests
go all the way through the DNS system
but generally DNS is not privacy
friendly now HTTP this is is the
protocol that takes web addresses and
returns content HTML and and whatnot
this is a two party protocol between a
web client and a web server similar to
DNS it's unencrypted and in the
unencrypted cases internet service
providers can help speed up help provide
latency improvements by caching this
content so let's try to visualize what
the early web with these two protocols
look like because residential networks
did not allow people to host websites
from your own residential location
people tended to host the content on a
small subset of networks that would
allow it
this results resulted in a somewhat less
centralized now somewhat less
decentralized topology than we're taught
to believe in school so web sites hosted
by a single machine are on a single
location on earth
so requests to these hosts these web
sites have to travel around the world
which can result in poor performance for
people who are not actually close to
these these web services and because the
traffic is unencrypted it also exposes
your traffic to multiple geographies now
two of the major evolutions of the web
since the very early days are shared
hosting and encryption the Internet has
evolved somewhat from a somewhat
centralized but administratively
diversed
environment to a situation in which you
have many web sites hosted and managed
by the same providers and this results
in a little bit more
realization with encryption HTTP is the
protocol that provides this and this
takes the content of your information
and make sure that nobody can can read
it when it transits the internet which
is a huge upgrade for privacy but it
doesn't close all the privacy loopholes
it's also somewhat harmful for latency
because to establish an HTTPS connection
you need several round trips to
establish the shared cryptographic keys
it also breaks the ability for ISPs and
intermediaries to do caching which is
also bad for latency so furthermore with
shared hosting to support the growing
number of domains on the internet and
the limited set of IPs that are
available hosting provider started using
the same IP for multiple different web
sites now in a perfect world you could
imagine that adding encryption would
allow you to provide cover for the many
web sites who are using the same ip
connections to this IP would be
indistinguishable which would help in
terms of privacy but in reality this
doesn't work there's servers need to
understand and know which website you're
connecting to in order to present the
correct certificate and this is part of
what HTTPS works this is an extension
called SNI it sends the hostname in the
clear so recently there have been some
more changes to the way that web
services work these changes include the
expansion of HTTPS and the advent of
low-cost edge services now an edge
services are geographically distributed
networks that can act as the server for
multiple web sites and these networks
often use techniques like IP anycast
that allows the same ip to be broadcast
from many locations around the world to
serve the same content this spreads
attacks and decreases the need for DNS
to know which IP the client is actually
coming from and if you look at this
topologically you go from a situation
where you have shared hosts and these
are very centralized to a situation
where
you have these edge providers in which
the content is almost always close to
the viewer so there are fewer long lines
fewer long latency connections and also
some sites still have centralization
such as wicket Wikipedia are served from
some central locations but the
percentage of sites especially the less
popular sites that are using these
distributed edge services has grown
tremendously and this trend is
continuing
so edge networks help you gain back some
of the performance some of this latency
that's lost from adding HTTP mainly by
putting the content closer to the
visitors but from reprise of privacy
perspective DNS is still the same it
still leaks information all over the
place now one reason upgrading operating
system components is hard is the DNS is
handled much lower down on your
operating system as a client and one
idea to improve DNS privacy is to
encrypt this connection from the client
to the resolver and to do so the there's
a proposal called doe which is stands
for DNS over HTTP so depending on how
close you can get your edge resolver
that speaks DNS over HTTP can get to the
client you can actually have relatively
low latency so even with the width ona
in place
this helps encrypt your DNS traffic but
even with though in place S&I leaks the
hostname over TLS which is still a
problem so stepping back SNI is one way
in which any network that sees your
traffic that is in between the client
and the server can know which domain
you're trying to access can this be
improved is S&I a deal breaker well you
can't keep everything hidden online but
with edge services that span many
domains you may be able to hide in a
crowd now that this is a diagram of how
you access a site over HTTP 1.1 the
most common version of HTTP before the
last couple years say you have a site
called burrito comm and another site
called beans comm and you want to hide
the hide the fact that you're going to
beans comm and the both these services
are using the same edge service both
these websites
so both DNS and HTTPS put the hostname
in the clear on the network through HTTP
on sni and through dns assuming Doe is
not deployed this also leaks the fact
that you're going to both web sites in
recent years HTTP has been upgraded to a
new protocol called HTTP 2 which allows
you to make multiple requests on the
same encrypted connection in a
multiplexed way it also technically
allows you to send requests to multiple
domains over the same encrypted
connection and this is actually done
automatically by browsers as long as two
things are present first
that the certificate is valid for both
domains you're trying to access and
second that the DNS states that both
websites or both domains have the same
IP this is actually better than HTTP 1.1
for latency and privacy reasons for for
two points one is which you don't have
to make a new connection to beans comm
and the second is that sni for beans
comm is not leaked on the network but
still dns is sent for both of these
requests and it's operationally
problematic to use the same IP for many
many many different sites you often want
to split these up so that you can do
denial of service protection and and all
sorts of other things administrative Lee
furthermore this requires a shared
certificate which in this case it's
difficult to scale this up to more than
dozens of different websites so at most
you can hide or you can hide your
traffic among a small list that's limits
the size of the crowd you can sit in so
a new proposal for HTTP to that is just
nascent is called the origin frame
now what the origin frame is is it let's
the server give the client a list of
domains that are available without the
DNS lookup and you can think of this
like moving the DNS request from DNS
into the HTTP to tunnel this results in
one less DNS lookup which is good for
latency but it also helps protect the
fact that the server is exposing that it
can serve these multiple domains now
this is better this blocks the DNS leak
for beans comm and it's it's doesn't
allow you to it doesn't force you to use
the same IP for both all your web sites
that are hosted on the same place but it
does still require you to have this
certificate that covers both most places
it would be better to use multiple
certificates so the question is if you
can move the DNS into the tunnel into
the encrypted tunnel why not also the
certificate and this is where the second
proposal comes into play this is called
the certificate frame it's a new HTTP -
extension that lets the server not only
advertise through origin that it
supports beans com but it also allows
the server to prove ownership of the
beans com certificate inside this
encrypted tunnel invisible to the
network so with origin and certificate
together a server can cover the fact
that beans traffic is being served
completely essentially you can hide the
beans inside the burrito this resolves
this for this for the third and final
privacy concern and some domain fronting
techniques that you may have heard of
work in a similar way rather than using
an explicit opt-in from the server such
as the certificate frame of the origin
frame protocols like meek
I'll have the client pretend to be one
of the sect one of the other servers
that one of the other websites that's
protect behind the same edge service and
request that content
this these techniques take advantage of
the fact that some servers don't
actually checked host names against
certificates so what origin and
certificate provide is a standards
compliant alternative to systems like
meek that have less risk of collateral
damage to websites so where are we now
with these proposals well are they real
doe for example is actually available
right now on Google DNS they have an
experimental endpoint origin is
implemented in Firefox it's in the
current stable version of Firefox and
certificate is not far behind it's
currently being standardized by the IETF
so with these technologies in place it
turns out we can get parot privacy and
performance benefits in exchange for
administrative centralization so if you
remove the dns from the equation this is
this is somewhat controversial because
DNS is used for many different things
not just for routing it's used for
content restriction it's used for
censorship and it's used for quite a lot
of different opportunities in the world
and different in the security world in
particular so we need to ask ourselves
with this technology origin and
certificate which provide privacy
guarantees that did not exist before in
the web does this have some negative
consequences does this incentivize
further consolidation behind a small set
of edge services is that good or bad
does this increase performance and
privacy which is generally considered a
good thing does this outweigh the
legitimate need for external visibility
whether in the enterprise or in schools
so there's even more questions is is
this technology in existence and if it
becomes widespread will this help or
potentially be counterproductive for
censorship resilience in the long term
now I don't know the answers to these
questions but as a community I think we
need to think about them and come up
with some understanding of what the
future will be for strong privacy and
strong latency and can and this sort of
extra features in HTTP 2 so with that I
thank you for the attention and let's
open up the mics for questions