you
[Music]
so I don't Candace pipe the fed like
introduction I don't consider myself a
Fed I consider myself a security and
privacy researcher so I just thought I'd
lead off with that but what I'm hoping
to do today is help you think about the
nation-state threat actor the
nation-state cyber army fair actor if
you look at you know the evolution of
the Internet
it began with you know technologists and
then moved business saw the opportunity
they moved in pretty much everyone on
the planet is now on the Internet at
least in the modern world and what did
that attract the attracted intelligence
agencies and later nations built
literally armies operating in cyberspace
so what I'm hoping to do in this talk is
give you some tools and techniques for
reverse engineering how those factors
operate and that will help you better be
better defenders you'll see that there's
lots of opportunity for interesting
research and yeah and lots of the
information there's an entire body of
knowledge associated with military
thinking that could be applied to cyber
security that as really large is really
largely untapped but it's freely
available so I want to provide links to
that information as well but I have to
begin with the disclaimer everybody has
a disclaimer mine is this my own opinion
not those of my current or prior
employers but more importantly given
this ground that I know cyber is a meme
okay and I know that cyber is a drinking
game okay I understand
unfortunately I have to use cyber
without irony here because the this is a
real thing not when you know cyber is a
thing when there's an entire literal
armies operate in cyberspace and you
know you see the news every day the
United States just announced that its
cyber mission force was mission capable
that's like 133 teams that are operating
so in the United States Army our
military just announced that cyber
mission force was capable and
because of the power and potential of
this that you see forces around the
world standing up capabilities and we
out get into the effects in a moment
that because of that so this was me at
West Point from 2000 to 2009 I was an
information security researcher and I
look at 2009 as the birth of this thing
that is cyber and because of the
gravitational pull was so strong coming
from DC and my really the United States
government I was asked to be involved in
looking at what is this thing that is
cyber operations so I looked at that
space and realized that isn't just
information security involves academic
disciplines like math and law and
electrical engineering political science
and then I dug deeper and realized that
cyber operations touches upon economics
history psychology business pretty much
every academic and professional
discipline intersects in this thing that
is cyber operations but more importantly
it intersects with this whole realm of
military military doctrine and knowledge
the disciplines things like operations
security targeting intelligence command
and control they all intersect and that
it's those gaps that I'm hoping to kind
of highlight I only have 20 minutes so
to highlight some of those to you and
where you can go to learn more because
much of this information is out there
and freely available there's great tools
and techniques you can apply to
information security in your in your
jobs as researchers or as defenders but
also the it helps you learn how how your
adversary thinks right so this is how
the military thinks about about war and
if you look at it the military has been
fighting wars at scale around the around
the world for hundreds of years right so
how do they operate at that type of
scale and speed and that this is the
thinking that's being applied now to
cyber operations
begins at the tactical level for our
purpose that's things like engagements
think a red team engagement from our
perspective and that's like hands on
keyboard type work and much of
information security thinking is at the
tactical level we at the enterprise
level we tend to think about operations
more and and all but in general I think
many of the books much of the lot of the
thought goes into the tactical level but
these military organizations really go
beyond the tactical and they're looking
across the entire spectrum of tactical
operational level like campaign level
analysis and then strategic level like
what does it mean - what does this a
nation look like it's projection in
cyberspace that's the type of thinking
that these forces are looking at and
they have the legal authority to use
force that many that most are denied and
what I'm trying to do is to increase our
aperture and our thinking a little bit
more as well so we can better perform a
risk analysis so what how does it army a
cyber space army think about itself well
this is US Army Cyber Command its
mission statement and they conduct
electronic warfare operations
information operations and cyberspace
operations that's their stated goal so
compliant combines those three
disciplines and oh by the way there's
books freely available books provided by
the military defining all of that and
they want to allow militaries to operate
with freedom of action in in cyberspace
and deny that to their adversaries I
think that's a pretty ambitious goal
given the nature of how information
flows but but nonetheless that's how
they're thinking about it and because we
see these forces operate in cyberspace
we're now seeing effects really at the
national level we saw the Office of
Personnel Management hack which
disclosed the 100 page plus dossier of
everyone with the security clearance
virtually everyone with the security
clearance we saw the the litany of data
spells and
of them being weaponized coming out of
NSA the Equifax hack which probably
disclose the credit history of all at
least all the US people in the room and
some international people we see
destabilizing information operations
attacks in the United States and even
influence on the u.s. presidential
election this is serious business right
when we think about or we looking at
these type of forces I like this this
graphic it's from a defense Science
Board report that throws three tiers of
actors at the bottom tier are those
actors that use existing pre-existing
vulnerabilities things that are known
things you find a Metasploit and then
the next year are actors that can find
vulnerabilities so they can probe a
system and find its weaknesses and
that's where again much of Information
Security is today but as we're thinking
about the capabilities of these types of
actors realize that they can there they
can operate at that top level - if there
wasn't a vulnerability they could
potentially create one and that's a
powerful way of thinking perhaps that
could come from a partnership with a
tech Titan to put a backdoor into a
system or it could be influencing a
stant a cryptographic standard set to to
be weaker than it should be to allow
allow access at least two people with
the right tools and techniques so this
is how nation-state cyber forces think
about think about vulnerabilities
military thinking has already been
adopted usefully into information
security the kill chain and I understand
if you've been to the RSA vendor floor
and survived you the kill chain is
overused but it's still a useful way to
break down kill chain concepts or useful
way to break down the steps an attacker
might take threat intelligences emerged
from just simple indicators of
compromise to more powerful deeper
richer longer term techniques we've seen
campaign level analysis rather than
looking at isolated
incidents and mapping those threat
actors to techniques tactics and
procedures so that could be understood
and better identified or defend it
against so there is value here but what
I don't want to say is that these forces
have it all perfect either right there
in many ways by studying this space you
can get out ahead of them which is a bad
place to be if you're a defender here
there's a general general frost from the
Pentagon just messaging to the army
telling every soldier that they need to
be responsible for their own computing
systems right so they're still doing
basic blocking and tackling alongside
their attempts at sophisticated cyber
operations so here I'd like to just give
you a few techniques from from this
space that I'm describing again not
enough time to go in the depth but I'll
highlight a few one of my favorites
is center of gravity analysis it came
from the Russian I'm sorry the
oppression theorist Clausewitz hundreds
of years old but still in use today and
it allows you to deconstruct a country a
business an individual a security
conference to find ways that can best be
attacked and when you think about these
organizations they're operating at scale
and thinking very broadly so this this
is one way they can decompose it and you
can decompose your business that you're
trying to protect as an example
it begins with looking at the source of
power of an adversary let's say the
internet is or the you can imagine the
u.s. democracy right
what are is the source of power of the
United States what critical capabilities
require for the democracy to function
and then what requirements are there for
those capabilities and as you decompose
this down into the subsequent parts what
might be vulnerable so let's look at
just the internet if you consider the
Internet well it's critical capabilities
might be search hardware software
internet governance email protocols
telecom infrastructure and then you can
break those down farther right and say
well okay if you want to have hardware
you
ship boundaries and ship design firms
and transportation warehousing maybe for
telecom infrastructure you need undersea
cables communication satellites and
access to the electromagnetic spectrum
so it allows you to take this huge
complex thing and break it down and if
you're important enough or you have the
resources think these type entities this
is how they're looking at countries and
it businesses and then you can further
break that down and identify
vulnerabilities let I'll just use the
example of undersea cables you probably
have seen the news where people have
realized that undersea cables are
actually really really important
critical infrastructure and that they're
incredibly vulnerable critical
infrastructure because it's literally
cable that's laid at the bottom of the
ocean so by understanding these then you
can better to protect against them or if
you're on the offense you can better
attack and if you have patience you can
do it immediately or look to the future
just have it all pre pre analyzed in
case of vulnerability presents itself
another source
I think of information that you'll find
interesting is the idea of fires the
military thinks in terms of targeting
identifying lists of targets
prioritizing them so you can envision
these these cyber armies coming up with
lists of targets perhaps you're on them
right and then prioritizing them and
they've got a rigorous process of how
they analyze targets and and execute
against them and assess the
effectiveness if you're interested in
that I'm sure I'm trying to include
links like that book their joint fire
support tells you and if you read it and
you start thinking in the context of
offensive cyber operations you can
really gain a good picture
another is the idea of the cognitive
domain that it isn't just the physical
warfare militaries have evolved beyond
just blowing things up
they also think in terms of information
flows and influencing the decision
making of the force of their adversaries
or their adversary populations that's
the definition of information operations
to defend information systems in
influence to
it's a rich and deep area that's
incredibly relevant right now because
while we might not have a cyber war
going on we definitely have intensive
information operations going on that
manuals really available and I encourage
you to take a look at it and it's not
just this thing of information
operations acting in isolation it's also
that you can combine your ability to
break into a computer system or gain
credentials on a system in place
information or everything from
blackmailing someone to sending out fake
urgent message fake messages to US
forces in Korea right selling them that
attack was imminent it's very serious
business and there's a great article by
herb Lin at at Stanford that looks at
that and if you're interested I'd look
at this manual and I'd look at this
paper by herb lend to kind of get your
head in the game that game intelligence
you'd be surprised that there there are
many sub disciplines of intelligence and
I spent my first fifteen years in the
military doing well the first ten years
doing intelligence work in their manuals
on humans and SIGINT in imagery
intelligence and many many more
operations security all freely available
and that's one you could start if you if
you are in the threat intelligence
business you should be mining this stuff
it's gold and now there is the idea of
effects based operations that again
militaries have evolved beyond thinking
of just let's blow that thing up and see
what happens right there a bad guy bad
guy will blow it up
it's what effect do I want to have and
mapping they're like in that effect
maybe the population is unruly do you
arrest angry leaders in the community
well that could make matters worse do
you blow things up that can make matters
a lot worse maybe if you build a well
and help the schools you can calm the
population so there's a whole thought
process of the many effects you can have
through information cyber operations and
physical kinetic operations that are out
there and that's a Rand
document out that's freely available
effects based operations because it's
absolutely critical to the thinking of
these large forces deception is another
deception has been practiced in warfare
for really since the beginning and
there's rigorous thought that's gone
into how do you deceive your adversary
and that is absolutely going on today in
the information space and in cyber
operations there's companies that have
popped up over the last few years that
are focusing on this if you want to look
at how militaries think about deception
operations there's manuals out there
that tell you one thing I think is an
interesting evolution is work while this
is focused on deceiving humans we are in
the game of deceiving machines too we
want to sieve the tools we want to
bypass the censor we want to trick the
censor but if you take this manual and
you apply it to your thinking I think
you'll find interesting insights so as I
look to the future of what what this
means like where this is going I think
we're going to see every major power and
most minor powers with the significant
capability in cyberspace doesn't mean
I'm happy about it I'm not advocating
militarization of the internet by any
means but I think it's a reality I think
we're going to see a United States or
should see the United States cyber
academy as there's a West Point for the
ground forces and a Naval Academy for
the Navy I could I think that we should
see a United States cyber Academy that
focuses on growing people in the space
what does that imply perhaps a separate
military service or government service
that focuses on this I think we'll see
30 year veterans of cyber operations and
remember these people have access to
classified information for 30 years
they've gone through a series of
developmental assignments they've had
legal authority to go on the offensive
around the world on missions so we're
going to see these people popping out
before 30 years but also engross on over
30 years they're going to get increased
legal authorities to allow them to do
more and you see them the these
forces constantly asking for more
because in democracies their hands are
somewhat tied and they authorities are
given out very carefully by the
government so I think you're going to
see that and continue we're going to see
a rise in cyber enabled information
operations and that we're going to see a
combination of not just horses with
hands on keyboard in dark you know
command centers somewhere we're going to
see the rise of AI and the this operator
level teaming and ultimately AI Driven
cyber operations a little farther out so
it's serious business and useful for us
to understand what's available and to
dig in to the dig into the body of
knowledge that's out there so what are
the takeaways if you're assessing your
risk you have to think like a
nation-state cyber army doesn't mean
that they'll be that they're going to go
after you doesn't mean that they can't
stop that you can't stop them in many
ways I think you can and but it's useful
to think at that level if I could create
a vulnerability what would I do that
type of thinking that there are many
tools and techniques and in 20 minutes I
just couldn't show you them all that you
could that you could learn more about
and apply to information security and
then read a manual or a book on on the
subject to to learn more and I think if
you like information security is
conflict its combat in many ways and
there are books on this
so like map it over here's where I would
go to start the manuals on deception
cyber operations electronic warfare and
information operations
psyops on cybers the book I just did and
cyber defense review is a free journal