probably sharing the session thanks for
coming to the session we have a switch
in the first two talks of decision the
order is changed but everything is in
place thank you for the speaker for the
last minute accommodation so the talk is
going to be about secure sampling with
sublinear communication by stronger Choi
Donald
Gordon linchang Liu and Arcadia
hirokumovich and Link shank is going to
give you something
all right thank you all for coming
So speaking of secure a secure sampling
let's consider a study of a two-party
computation
so suppose we have two parties and they
want to sample some information from
some joint distributions
this actually comes up a lot in
particular differential privacy has been
started a lot where we often sample from
calcium or LaPlace and distributions and
there are also other settings that we
also want to sample from private
distributions
so there are prior Works done on this
public functions so what if the
probability itself that you want to
sample from is uh shared distributedly
across two parties
so assume each of the party has a vector
of weights and the probability function
you want to sample from is jointly
defined on these two weights as so uh
for example if the function is a l y
distance between the two Vector that
defines the L1 L1 distribution then that
depends defines the algorithm Point
problem and similarly we could have L2
and production for it and more and more
so the question is how can we sample
from this privately
well a simple answer would be the
following we let it let one of the party
homologically encrypt his Vector sent
over to the other then we can
homophobically sample from it
this is good this is easy and it works
well however it requires linear
communication
so they really really simple question
which we're asking our paper can we do
this with sublinear communication
so while we're discussion in our mind we
started a several distributions that are
common Solutions so we construct custom
linear protocol for l y and L2
distribution
however for product distribution we show
that it is impossible in general unless
you make some assumptions on those
inputs and from those products sampling
protocol we construct a two-party
exponential mechanism as well
so let's see some construct some real uh
protocols starting from L1
so remember that it's still the
two-party setting and now the
probability that the two party wants to
sample from is this L1 distribution
defined below
so how do we solve this let's take a
look at this probability function
this is basically like so given L1 is
linear this is basically like uh the the
summation between the inputs from two
parties and we see that each party can
compute exactly one of them
so while this gives out a very simple
solution
why not we just let the party one
looking at his own input example one of
the index I want based on his own local
input and probably two example of I2
based on his local input then all we
need to do is just to choose one of the
by some coin flip
so this one gives is corresponding
exactly corresponding to adding those
two probability together
and the only communication is happening
in the third step which we need to flip
a bias coin to decide which one to
Output
and that gives us correct answer with
constant communication however this is
not private the part is kind of learned
whether the final output matches his
coin toss or not
so we need to fix this
instead of let the let the party one
samples I want you to clear we let the
post party around a protocol
that our leadership samples this i1 for
party one and secret share it
similarly we can do the same thing for
part two and this oblivious sample
sample protocol is constructed with
security party computation and Apache
and this can be done in constant
communication
this time with three point inside the
fpg and decide which one to reconstruct
and operate to both parties so now rd1
no longer knows the Iowa rd2 no longer
knows I2 so with achieving the same
constant communication size but this
time this is secure this is private
great
so now we know how to do all right
sampling which is a very easy case now
let's have a look at another case L2
sampling
so exactly the same setting except for
now we are going to sample from this L2
distribution defined below
so a question will be like by looking at
this probability function of L2
distribution
we ask can we apply the tree the same
trick from L1 maybe we just do the same
trick like both parties stand for
something and open something
however remember all we can do for the
L1 is because the l y is linear but
looking at this cost terms this is
apparently not linear
and especially for those customs in the
denominator they are actually the inner
product between those two vectors and
this is how to compute we don't know how
to compute that sublinearly
so apparently what do we have for L1
cannot be working cannot be working for
L2 we need something new
well this is our new trick we call that
corrective standpoint and the whole idea
is that instead of directly sample from
this L2 distribution we pick a related
distribution which should be easy to
sample with
and I will get the index from that
distribution and then we need to correct
it back to our desired distribution by a
step called rejection sampling so the uh
the whole point is that if somehow this
distribution this distribution is
correlated with the distribution will be
desired the desired distribution then we
should be able to get the correct answer
correct output
and for the related distribution
especially for L2 case
what we want to do is to drop those cost
terms
so then we can avoid the Computing of
the inner product
that's what we want
for this probability Pi we need to
correct the index I from the previous
distribution that should be only be
dependent on the ice input which makes
this step easy to compute otherwise we
are doing nothing meaningless
so now with this intuition in your mind
let's see our actual protocol
so remember this is a distribution I
call that a related distribution which
is a distribution a unit from now and
this is exactly the distribution of L2
dropping all those cross terms of course
it's easy to stand program that's using
our L1 protocol you see each part is
just locally compute those inputs by
square their terms and this can be done
constantly
and then somehow if we can correct it
back with this probability DPI that is
the ratio between the L2 distribution
which is what we want and this
distribution a now we should be good to
go
so how do I compute this Pi it seems
hard
intuitively it sounds like it seems like
it should be as hard as just simple from
L2 directly because I'm basically doing
nothing
so let's see can we really handle that
so the pi remember the pi we want should
be the ratio between these two
distribution
and we written the terms right ending
with these two terms
looking at the left term this only
depends on the if input Computing of
this part is easy that's just a constant
number of summation and constant number
of multiplication you can run some
secure computation protocol and get that
part so how about this writer this is
how to compute and we don't know how to
compute that
however like in terms of I from the
distribution a this is constant
so why don't we why do I need to compute
that we don't have to so even though we
don't know how to compute it it doesn't
change our output we still get the
correct distribution of L2
so we can just use that part as our PI
well of course you need to adjust that
by some constant number to make it a
valid probability
so then intuitively we have a particle
for L2 and it's simple from this
distribution a as I mentioned before by
our L1 protocol is constant
communication and with this Pi we can
run this so if you can see this is the
sunshine here with this Pi we expect
this protocol to run our expected
constant number of runs so overall we
will have a constant communication
protocol for L2 sampling
and this idea can be easily extended to
any LP so for any P that's larger than
two it works this the similar way
so now we have a sense of L2 as well how
about product sampling so we should have
a talk ahead of me we will give a
definition about production the
distribution and now let me give that
first this is exactly the same setting
and we but this time we want to sample
from this distribution we call the
product distribution
so how do we stumble from that again
let's see the probability function
so we see that the probability it for
some index I being sampled that is
exactly the multiplication between this
two terms
this is exactly like the similar thing
we saw before that one party can compute
exactly locally have one of that somehow
it gives us an idea similar to L1 so
maybe we let the party one
so we use our oblivious uh protocol as
well but the post party to sample for L1
and then secret share i1 and repeat for
I2 so this time we are going to do a
equality check if i y equals to I2 good
we operated
otherwise we restart this process and
this is exactly corresponding to
multiply these two probability together
that sounds like a solution
however this this protocol has the
expected number of iteration that is one
over the inner product
so that gives us a sense that if you
want a sublinear communication you need
to have something some assumption on the
inner product yeah so we need
sufficiently large in the product to
make this particle sublinear
communication
and also since you have assumptions on
the input inherently this protocol will
have some leakage that is the inner
product as well so we can simulate that
from the inner product
so now there is another question in
general can we get rid of this
assumption can we do sublinear product
sampling in general
maybe some new trick well apparently
this time it's impossible we find it's
impossible to do that with a visual
reduction from set destroying this
problem which is uh which can be shown
that it requires at least a linear
communication to solve it
so this is for product sampling from the
product sampling so we'll see that when
it's possible to construct that and in
general it's impossible then we realize
a two-party exponential mechanism
the whole point for exponential
mechanism is to achieve differential
privacy
so assuming you have a list of items h
and the the goal for exponential
mechanism is to Output some of the hi
with the probability proportion to the e
to the power of sh here s is a score
function evaluate on H and the purpose
is to hide the individual privacy for
the individual item age
so now for two-party settings uh assume
that uh a additive score function that
is collectively a distributed among two
parties so in a word that each party can
compute a portion of this score function
and so let's say the party J can compute
the SJ of h i and the goal is now to
Output a common hi with a probability
that is e to the power of the total s
and that is equal to the e to the power
as one times e to the power S2 that's
given by mathematics so now did you say
something this part is exactly two terms
they are multiplied together one term
can be computed by one of the party
this is our product sampling right so
basically just plug our product summary
particle here you should be able to get
the exactly same sublinear exponential
mechanism for two parties
but don't forget that our protocol when
it when it works when you give your
sublinear communication it comes with
the leakage that is up to the inner
product
so our solution would be using a
differential private version of JL
transform to estimate the inner product
to fix this leakage so now we can
achieve a fully differential private
exponential mechanism in a two-party
setting and it comes with uh sublinear
communication
so that's basically all I want to split
today and uh So eventually we brought a
question about uh a secure sampling uh
security party sampling with something
communication and with with construction
we construct the models for L1 L2 and
extend to LP distribution and we show
that when it's possible it's impossible
for a product sampling and we also
realized that two-part exponential
mechanism for differential privacy and
that's all I have for today thank you
so we have time for a couple of
questions
so I have one so what if we have uh
distributions that are huge uh in terms
of the number of points but we have like
parameters for them like suppose you
have parameters of a gaussian
distribution somehow shared between the
two parties if they want to sample from
it and does your Technique help us how
to do it or is it the easier question by
any chance I think it depends it's more
like a different question like so for
this type of question it's more like the
probability to sample some points has a
sort of fixed probability but
distributed amount of party it's not
like a specific of a specific version of
distribution like calcium or LaPlace
actually the Opera Works down on this
type of question but very few work
activated and find any on this type of
work even though we only like focus on
like L1 L2 LP distribution as defined on
those two inputs well of course you can
generalize it to any different function
so for example as you ask if you have a
large gaussian distribution
and those inputs are just like those
parameters are just the inputs from post
to party that should be the same problem
but that would be a huge like much
harder than the one I showed today so
basically if you can somehow find a way
for example some there are a bunch of
distributions that you can like apply
our technique of the get around like a
corrective uh sampling magnet technique
then maybe you could do that but other
than that there are tons of
distributions you cannot do sublinearly
okay
what happens if you're willing to
um compromise and get a distribution
that sort of close to the L1 or 2
product anything like that but not
exactly
so uh uh I'm sorry the output
distribution you want it to be within
some statistical distance of your target
distribution but it doesn't have to be
exactly the same well in our like in
this model we are more focusing on the
distribution that is exactly that
distribution so so if your customer is
asking about whether we can do the
distribution that is closer enough to
distribution
so I guess the answer should be yes
because that's more like the you're
still changing the function app so
remember our distribution is defined by
the function of those two vectors so
think about this similar case I just
randomly wipe away some of those inputs
that give us a roughly closer enough
distribution so if that match your
definition about close enough that
should work but whether that can achieve
sublinear it still depends on Case by
case
what is your rejection probability when
you do the effects uh that's a so for
rejection probability that should be y
minus the pi I mentioned so the pi would
be the probability that you accepted
that index you sample from the helper
distribution
thank you very much is there a reason to
believe that this is the best possible
uh
for L2 so there is isn't there is no
test so basically that gives us constant
expected a constant number of runs so
that would be fine well you could always
adjust it by some constant like divided
by 2 divided by three depends on your
need so that doesn't matter however like
for the product sampling even though I
didn't call that rejection sample you
still need to run that
many many iterations and the expected
number of iteration as I mentioned
that's one over the inner product so
basically you could
today that you need to trade off between
the
the probability for rejection
like
to get better
communication
and that's inherently that implies to
have strong requirements for the inner
product or something like that thank you
very much so we need to move to the next
talk I mean which was thank you very
much less thanks to Twitter again
thank you very much so as I told you the
order of the first two talks are
switched so we're gonna have Nathan now
Nathan dear
so while the speaker is setting up let
me tell you that Nathan's paper
is awarded the best young researcher
award and
and let's give it a give it up for the
speaker is is everything okay
let's wait till
electricity
don't press the last button okay you can
also use the arrow keys okay so as I
said this is the best young researchers
award let's uh give it up for him
yeah type computational and
distinguishability balance for product
distribution by Nathan uh yeah please
thank you very much for the introduction
um so the general theme of today's talk
will be about generalizing statistical
bounds to the computational setting
so a famous example in this setting just
to give you a general idea of what we
are going to do is just so Lema
so here uh what we have statistically is
that if we have two distributions d0 and
V and D1 such that we're going to draw a
random bit B and then draw from DB and
give it to an adversary asking him to
correlate the sample to back to B
its ability to do this is bounded by
Delta
so if I have this then once I repeat it
4K times once I give him K independent
samples and ask him to correlate it back
to the store of the bits
his ability to do this is at most will
decrease exponentially by K2 Delta decay
so this holds statistically and it's not
very hard to show using uh the
definition of statistical distance but
computationally it's more involved
because we actually need the
constructive proof this proof this proof
using statistical distance is not
constructing and computationally we
actually need to talk and to show how we
take an adversary against the Cake store
and transform it into efficiently into
an adversary against one instance
now another comment that I want to make
here is that
usually we expect to have some slackness
here some computational errors so
we may not be able to construct exactly
a Delta an adversary with Delta
correlation instead we may only be able
to add a construct an adversary with a
Delta minus Epsilon correlation
and we can make this Epsilon as small as
we want by paying with the running time
so we in general we also carrying these
types of of reductions about the trade
of we may care about the trade-off
between slackness and running time we
will get to it also later
okay now this was your solemma what is
the bound that we are going to
generalize
so uh it's the direct protocol bound
let's say that I have two pairs of
distributions X1 and x0 with distance DX
and y1 and Y 0 with distance d y
now what we're going to consider is the
distance between x 0 y 0 that is uh two
independent samples from X zero and Y
zero against two independent samples
from X1 and y1 okay so we draw a bit and
either we give the adversary to samples
from X 0 y 0 or X1 y1 now it is not hard
to show in fact it's it's very
fundamental using a simple hybrid
argument
that the distance will be at most DX
plus d y
however it turns out that statistically
it is full of crore knowledge in
probability theory that you can show
that this bond is not typed and you can
actually show something tighter which is
tight
the bound that is DX plus d y minus DX
times d y
okay so this is the type Bound for two
products if you try to uh use it again
and again in order to get the Bound for
a k product what you get is that if the
distance between X and Y is d then you
get at the distance between the K
products is one minus one minus D to the
k
which is Diet instead of D times K which
can be even larger than one
okay
so what we are going to show is the new
uh direct and uh simple proof of this
type bound with a very good parameter
with very good parameters that is very
good trade-off between uh the slackness
and running time in in the case of uh
non-uniform in the non-uniform setting
we also generalized in the uniform
setting but with was parameters
so before we get to that uh why is this
bound important I mean when do we care
about it so for example if it is
negligible in case polynomial then
there's not that much of a difference
between them so we may not really care
about this
so really the case where we make where
the difference may be more important is
when did times K is large
and just to demonstrate to you uh such a
such a case I will shortly talk about
amplification of weak oblivious transfer
before that I just want to emphasize
that we all already know how to amplify
awake of the protocols computationally
but I'm just going to present it so you
can get a sense of what types of
settings these bound is used
so we completely transfer amplification
originally proved statistically by uh
the Killian and salvale and then
um generalized to the computational
setting by Wars Lego
um works as follows so we have and we'll
call T the Central Security and civil
security are maybe constant instead of
negligible and we want to amplify them
both to negligible the way this works is
using an interchanging application of
two operations we have one operation
that amplifies sender security
adjustment at the expense of civil
security and another operation that
amplifies receiver security at the
expense of sender security Now the point
is that in each of this operation the
sore the applicant the amplification
behaves like xor and the degradation
behaves like a direct product
okay why is that so let's let's look at
for example the operation that amplifies
the center security so what we do here
is secret share the the database of the
sender into into K instances so its
Security will be Amplified like xor
meanwhile the receiver's Choice bit will
be constant throughout the Decay
instances so the security degrades like
a direct product because we use the same
bits in all the instances
so here uh it's important to actually
use the tight bound because otherwise
you will not be able to get to amplify
the full range of parameters otherwise
there will be some non-trivial OT
protocols we go to protocols that you
will not be able to amplify to
full-fledgedy
okay
before we get to the actual adversary I
want I need to mention a few related
walks so first of all uh molar and
sorrow show how to get a computational
generalization of the coupling technique
in uh and you do this using
hollenstein's tight version of the
hardcore Lemma so once you have this you
have a general a general tool of uh
a moving statistical proofs using
coupling to the computational setting so
you can also apply it here because we
can improve this the boundary Dimension
using coupling and so you can do this
and it works and this is also uh what
the volts like you're used but this
advantage of this is that this is the
adversary is somewhat more involved and
you get worse parameters worse trade-off
between the slackness and the overhead
also uh and I will talk about parameters
in a moment also there is a paper by 11
Robin that works specifically on this
bound however their focus was uh mostly
on on allowing it to work when there is
interaction on allowing for interaction
and not on improving the parameters
so about the parameters
so for some parameters for example if
the distance between the K products is
expected to be upper bounded by constant
then what's going to happen here is that
instead of increasing the circuit size
by one over Epsilon Square the verb
Epsilon is the slackness
we will only increase the circuit size
by log of net
so this is I think something interesting
here that's often in this in this
setting I mean
the the heart problem Etc
usually uh the overhead is polynomial in
one over Epsilon where Epsilon is the
slackness but here we get something kind
of unique we force for a large range of
parameters we can get exponentially
small slackness with only polynomial
overhead
so this is something a bit unique that
happens here
okay so I talked about Simplicity and
efficiency now let me try to demonstrate
it and look at the actual adversary
so the way it works is like is is like
this just a reminder what we get is a
distinguisher c between x0 y0 and X1 y1
and we want to construct either a
distinguisher between x 0 x 1 or y0 y1
so the first case the simple case is if
we are able to hard code some value of x
this is right now the number from
setting if you are able to hotgode some
value of x into C and get a good
distinguisher between y0 and y1 well
done
this is a simple case now the more
interesting case is what happens if this
hard coding doesn't work
so in fact what you what we can show is
that if the hard coding doesn't work
then the following is a good adversary
as a DX distinguisher between x0 and X1
so how does it work we want to
distinguish between x0 and X1 we get
this input a value X we want to know
where it came from
what's going to happen is that we start
from an initial guess B okay could be
zero could be one anything or anything
and then we keep repeating the following
we take B and we sample for YB
then we use this sample together with X
and then put it and fill it into C
C gives us the next guess and then we
continue to repeat it okay if you think
about it you can also describe it using
the following Markov chain
now this adversary well it's unbounded
right you can't actually run it so you
have to stop after T times so what we
actually want to get is the stationary
distribution
what we get in reality is just the
distribution after these steps
so if you want it 40 steps you will not
be able to reach the stationary
distribution but you will get very close
to it and of course you will need to pay
for this distance with this likeness
this is where the slackness comes in the
more time you put in the marker chain
the closer you get to stationary
distribution and then the less likeness
you need to add
okay
so this is really the adversary I think
it's it's pretty simple
and the reason and let me just try to
uh quickly describe the main idea
I'm not sure how much time we have left
okay
so I'll try to go over this quickly I
won't be able to go into details
but the idea of the proof is that we can
actually use C to build the
distinguisher for this to build the iron
amplifier for distinguishers between x0
and X1
so let's say that a is such a
distinguisher and a is not good enough
the advantage is less than digs
so if you take this distinguisher and
put you get next you build a new
distinguisher you get an X you apply a
you get the guess B of A now you take
this V and you use it to sample from YB
and feed it into C together with x
so what you can show is that after this
step
the difference between DX at the end the
current advantage of a will be
multiplied by d y
okay so we want to get the X we get
something with Advantage it is smaller
than x and what we can show is the
difference is multiplied by d y which is
smaller than one
so you do this again and again and again
and the difference keeps getting
multiplied by d y and this way you get
very very close to the x
okay this will be so the the the uh the
approach will be to start with the
trivial distinguisher that is output
zero and then keep repeating this step
over and over and over again until we
decide to stop depending on what
selectness we want to achieve
now the reason why this works the reason
why we actually get this amplifier is
because of the assumption that the C
elects is not good enough for every
choice to fix deduction you can actually
look at these four distributions and
we know that that the distance between x
x 1 and y1 and X zeroy zero is at least
the advantage of c and we can use this
assumption to bound the distance between
the top two and the bottom two and then
what you get is that there's enough
distance left for these two
distributions at the center uh which
basically says that uh I want I can do
the computation right now but it's not
very hard if you actually subtract from
the advantage of C these two uh these
two differences you can show that what
you get is an adversary with the
advantage that is better that is closer
to BX by at least the multiple of d y
okay so this is just a drawing to to uh
to demonstrate that right we start from
the distance the X from the X we start
from zero and we keep multiplying it by
d y so we get very close to DX
and for the difference we have to pay
with some slackness so the more time we
put in the closer where to DX the less
likeness we have to pay
and the last slide
um as a it's it is actually a
straightforward Corollary to arrive at
uh at the K products bound after you get
the isolated case that we've just
mentioned and for this bound you can
still preserve the good rate of between
uh slackness and the overhead of the
circuit size
uh in addition to that we also show that
these uh these ideas also generalize to
the uniform setting it takes a bit more
work but the general idea Remains the
Same the only disadvantage is that in
the uniform setting you no longer get
this good rate of this logarithmic
trade-off between the running time and
the between running time and the
slackness because intuitively you need
to use sampling and testing and in order
to sample and test within accuracy
Epsilon you need to work uh with respect
to one over Epsilon so this is
intuitively why the good rate of no
longer is no longer maintained in the
uniform setting and that would be all
thank you thank you very much
let's take the questions why the next
speaker sets up any questions
so I have one you mentioned something
about the sequential setting does your
result you think potentially generalized
to apply to interactive protocols or you
think it's kind of inherent to one
message
logarithmic overhead particularly
um so I think it uh
I didn't think about enough so I also uh
sorry I've asked this
is oh yeah
okay so uh
I didn't really uh completely think
about it I do think that because of the
nature of this uh I mean I know that
yeah solemus is uh generalized to the
case of interaction I think this should
already also be the case here because in
some sense I we don't use the rewinding
I think that was the problem
but I haven't completely verified it I
do think that it should also be you
should also be able to generalize it to
allow interaction
so I do think it should work thank you
so there was a question or yeah but it
was very high level but you said it's
very unique yeah this logarithmic
Improvement I guess yeah for their loss
so you don't have a sense which if there
are other applications of the hardcore
level whereas people vote
um no in fact I mean it's not like we
it's not like we replace the hardcore I
mean that column could be used in many
places and the other in the other places
we don't we don't know how to improve
only this one and I don't and I don't
know if you can also improve it in other
places I try to think about it but I
something something is just different
there I don't know I don't exactly know
how to point out the what's what is it
but I try to think about it in other
contexts for example your Sonoma and I
couldn't really see how you could
improve it to also have this trade of uh
in other settings
oh yeah uh yeah yes yes true yeah
thank you very much for the great talk
and the results
so the next two talks are shorter
they're technically soft marriage so the
first one and we will take the questions
about most of them at the end of the uh
both talks so the first one is secure
non-interactive simulation from
arbitrary joint distributions by Hamid
drizzle I mean for asconi Hamilton and
hi nicoyan and hamidraza is going to
give the talk
foreign
thank you for the intro introduction uh
this is a joint work with my advisor
hemanta Maji and my colleague I
so it's nice secure and interactive
simulation was introduced recently in
your clip
in essence Alice and Bob they want to
simulate a joint distribution uh
U UV which we call it a target
distribution using n independent samples
of another distribution X Y which we
call it Source distribution
and
so more specifically suppose uh
suppose uh Alice is given x n Bob is
given by n and such that x y and x y n
is like an independent samples of their
Source distribution and and if we want
to see whether there are reduction
functions FN and GN such that when
Addison bar they apply those reduction
functions on their uh samples marginal
samples the distribution of the output U
Prime V Prime is kilos to some Target
distribution UV and we also we required
that this uh reduction to be secure
which is like uh for Bob security xn has
no additional information about V Prime
then U Prime and similarly for credit
security we can Define it so suppose
that at least above the output M samples
instead of one sample what is the
maximum achievable ratio of the M
divided by n we call it the rate of the
essence uh
so a sneeze is in fact an information
theoretic analog of pseudo correlation
generator and it is also related to
related to other problems in information
Theory and theoretical computer science
so I use we okay in this stack I use two
notations BSS and Bs BSS is the binary
symmetric source with affiliate
probability Epsilon but instead of uh
instead of uh Epsilon I use rho which is
the Maxwell correlation and also the
same for BS we use a row which is the S
square root of 1 minus Epsilon this is
also the maximum correlation Maxwell
correlation is some concept in
information Theory it's not important
but uh absolutely is the Erasure
probability
so if this was introduced in these two
papers in your Crypt and
so otherwise how they showed a necessary
condition for instance of a general
Target distribution from a general
Source distribution uh in our paper our
Focus was in Europe it was on the
getting a list of PSS and Bs from BSS
and BSN and we we proved some results
for feasibility and rate but in this
stock uh our focus is on the case that
the target distribution is still pssps
but the source distribution is some
arbitrary distribution
and we showed that for any constant C
and for substantially large n we can see
that there is always a perfectly secure
uh sneeze or we get some C Over N in
security uh and we provided some
algorithm that we can determine whether
perfectly Securities exist or not and
our algorithm also retains the
construction in case it's such a SMS
exists for the rate we proved that any
feasible sneeze has constant rate the
rate is not zero and also we prove some
upper bound on the rate which the upper
one depends on the maximum correlation
of the target distribution and the
smallest magnitude eigenvalue of the
some linear operator associated with the
source distribution uh
but the most interesting result uh I can
say in our paper is this one it will
show that there is a source distribution
such that it's list of PSS and Bes from
that Source distribution has the
following property that for any linear
reduction uh it is invisible but there
is a non-linear reduction that achieves
the optimal rate and now I'm going to
explain so this result is interesting
because in our local paper we had also
non-linear reduction but they achieved
the same rate as the linear reduction
achieved so this is the that Source
distribution uh roller and it gets a
sample a b and Bob gets XC such that ABX
are uniform and Z is equal to ax plus b
and uh uh our uh our rate upper Bound
for instance of PSS with Maxwell
correlation half is uh this one is half
and uh the question is that this is this
rate achievable or not uh
the best known construction before our
work shows that the rate uh one third is
achievable but using one round
Communication in our work we don't use
any communication and we achieve rate ha
uh so this is the construction
suppose Alice and Bob they they give two
samples of roller so like X1 Z1 is
correlated with A1 B1 a2b2 called a
little bit exclusive so and it's output
Alice checks whether her samples are
they form a router and if that that
happens then she outputs plus one
otherwise she outputs minus one and Bob
also does the same we showed that okay
this is the
reduction functions if you use the like
minus and one yes instead of uh
zero and one and we see that these are
not linear constructions and we showed
that any linear reduction is constant in
secure
uh
and this is the summary of our work so
we showed that that there is some Epson
algorithm to design and find the
construction it's such a construction
exists and we've proved some upper bound
and lower bounds and we show that
there's not any reduction that keeps
optimal rate and we use computer
assisted search to design efficient
protocols and we prove that any linear
reduction for that construction is uh is
a constant in section
uh thanks thank you very much
I would be happy to answer to your
questions after the next talk
so let me introduce the next talks
speaker and authors so it's going to be
secure non-attractive reducibility is
decidable that's the title
by car take Bouchon
pancake Kumar misra Varun arayanan and
Manoj prabhakaran and Varun is going to
give the talk
am I Audible
thank you so this presentation is also
on uh let's say in the same model of
secure non-interactive simulation but uh
we will use a slightly different
terminology and we'll be calling it
secure non-interactive reductions or
snir for short because this is the
terminology that we used in the paper
so the main result of this talk is
exactly what the title says secure
non-interactive reducability is
decidable
so what is the secure non-interactive
reduction problem or snir problem
so we are given two correlations a
source correlation a Target correlation
uh that is the source correlation is X
comma y in the third correlation is U
comma V and we want to know whether
there is a statistical snir for securely
sampling UV given x y
more formally
we want to know whether for every
positive Epsilon
there exists in epsilon snir
that securely samples u v given some N
Sub Epsilon copies of X Y so when we say
epsilon sin IR we mean nsynier with at
most Epsilon correctness and uh security
error and think of this in sub Epsilon
as an arbitrarily large number
so uh in order to show that this is
decidable the main theorem that we use
uh states that statistical snar is going
to imply perfectness
so what does this mean so the theorem
states that there is a statistical snar
for UV given X Y only if
there is a perfect snar with perfect
correctness and perfect security
that samples UV using N Sub Zero copies
of X comma Y where N Sub 0 should be
thought of as a constant that is decided
by the description of the correlations U
V and X Y
now as a
immediate corollary of this we get that
the snir problem is decidable
furthermore if there is a statistical
resonator
then there is an algorithm that actually
outputs a perfect smile at for the same
problem
so going from the theorem to this
corollary is rather straightforward
so we can build an algorithm that takes
the description of the source and Target
correlations
and computes this number N Sub Zero
that's given in the theorem
and then it searches through all
possible
you know
reduction functions or what we call
protocols and see if there is a perfect
snir
taking X Y to u v
if there is one then the algorithm can
always output a perfect scenario and the
theorem states that if there is none
then it's in the statistical snar itself
is impossible
so uh because we don't have a lot of
time I will try to
uh give a brief
intuition behind how we show that
statistical snar is
going to imply perfectly scenario
so
um
yeah so let's start with a
so let's start with a protocol that is
an snir protocol a comma B that realizes
an Epsilon snar securely sampling a copy
of the target correlation using say n
copies of the source correlation so
think of uh D and C as the probability
Mass functions of these two correlations
jumping ahead what we are going to show
is that
these two uh reduction functions or
protocols A and B
they look only at a constant number of
copies of the C that is just taking as
input remember it's taking n copies of
the correlation as input but what we're
saying is that the protocol a
effectively looks only at a constant
size subset of these n copies
and this constant is going to depend on
the description of the source and Target
correlations
but now what this means is that if there
is a statistical snar
uh 4D using C then
for every Epsilon positive but however
small it is there is a protocol that
uses only a constant number of copies of
the correlation and gives you an snar
that is
uh less than Epsilon that has less than
Epsilon security and correctness error
but this since there are only a finite
number of
you know protocols that take n copies I
mean like the constant number of copies
of C uh and that's a reduction
this should mean that there should be a
protocol that is uh realizing
perfect snir
so so what goes into this how much time
do I have one and a half minutes so what
goes into this so we start with a
certain notion of spectral protocol that
is so a has a linear transformation that
gives you a so-called spectral protocol
a hat and we realized that this a hat is
in some sense a Fourier transform of the
protocol a itself
and then we note that this uh
this a is so that the Fourier transform
concentrates most of its energy in like
uh low degree coefficients that is it
concentrates on basis functions Each of
which depends on a few number of
variables
but then this is perfect for us to apply
a hunter theorem that says that if this
is the case then a should be a function
that depends only on a few of the uh you
know few of the coordinates of the
function itself
so we could not find a junta theorem
that works for a generalized Fourier
transform of this kind so we stated and
proved the such a Honda theorem and this
might be of independent interest
and
yeah this is how we
show that there exists a perfect snirer
for a d using C if there is a statistic
lesson here
so in conclusion we showed that
statistical snar problem is decidable
there are two interesting open problems
the first one
is about the rate of statistical snar we
it it's still open to characterize the
exact rate of statistics
and the other one would be to
think about what would happen if we
allow interactions what kind of uh
results can we get and this would relate
directly with OT complexity of a
function computation and so on
thank you thank you very much
quick questions for Ahmad razan Aaron if
you have a question for one of them
specifically mentioned it
otherwise I guess it's to both of them
questions you had any questions
I asked what for natural
distribution is like OT
um joint OT correlations do we have a
characterization of what correlations
imply them
for things that we care about
particularly say OT or is it a very hard
question so an earlier work I talked
about what are some necessary conditions
that are directly
that can be directly used to tell
whether there is a snar from a source to
a Target but then this so if we look at
this particular result itself it is
talking about a number N Sub 0 which
could be potentially really large
depending on the description of the two
correlations so it's not easy to run a
program to find this so you're sure it's
decidable but for specific cases do we
have like noise so there are a few set
of results that says that the OT
correlation cannot be realized using
binary Erasure correlation and things
like that we know some phase okay but
any other questions
so before finishing the session just be
aware that this brick is actually
shorter it's unfortunate that this time
that the brick is shorter we are ending
later than the typical time but and the
break is going to be about 15 minutes I
guess a little bit even shorter than
that any other question or otherwise
let's thank both of the speakers and all
the speakers on session