hello everyone it is our pleasure to
share our work a practical key recovery
attack on eight hundred and five-rounded
film here
in the following we shall introduce our
work from the following five aspects
travium is a beta oriented string cypher
designed by chrysotovo the canoe and
butt preview it was selected as one of
the extreme hardware oriented finalists
and it was specified as an international
standard on the rso iec
both the key size and the resize are 80
bits it contains a 280
bit internal state the number of
initialization runs is 1152
this figure shows an overview of trivial
and the sudoku of tribune is shown as
follows
the cube attack
which was first proposed by dina and
xiaomi is one of the most important
crevator analysts analysis technique
against your view
since proposed cube attacks attract
mainly attentions
and
lost good ideas such as
mobius transformation division property
and the correlation cube attacks were
proposed to improve cuban tax
in the following we shall introduce the
basics of cuba attacks
let f be n
and variable boolean function and
i be a subset of variable indexes
then
f could be written as following
the polynomial p i is called the
superpoly of i in f
a demand a d dimensional cube c i is a
set of assignments consisting of
2 to the power d
and tables in which
the variables indexed by i are assigned
to all the possible combinations of
0 or 1 while the other
variables remain and determine
then
p i
is equal to the summation of
function derived by each element in ci
note that
two evaluate pi
2 to the power d summations are always
needed
for stream servers the function f is the
polynomial representation of the first
order
key string bit on the key and array
variables
let i
be a subset of ie indexes and d be the
order of set i
the ci be a set of assignments of iris
variables consisting of 2 to the power d
and tables in which
the variables indexed by i are assigned
to the all the possible combination of
01 while the other iv variables are
assigned to zero or fixed constants
then the superpoli of rf which is equal
to the summation of functions derived by
elements of aging ci
is a function on key variable
there are two phases in cube attacks the
first offense is offline phase which is
independent of a sacred key
during this phase the aim is to find
some useful symbol police in sacred key
variables
the second phase is online phase in this
phase the task is to solve a system of
equations defined by superpolice under
the secret
key traditionally low degree tests such
as blr linearity test
and
capacity tests are used to find
balance the superpolis containing sacred
key information
fse
2013 folk and vanit use the mobius
transformation to simultaneously compute
a large number of sub cubes from a large
cube
given the truth table of a boolean
function one could compute its algebraic
normal form by using mobius mobile's
transformation
when it comes to cube attacks under any
specific key by storing the value of f
are all elements of ci
one could compute the a f f of f
on variables in i
it was noting that
much memory is needed to store the truth
table for a large cube
division property is an important
improvement on cube attacks
division property was proposed by toto
at euro credit 2015
as the generalization of integral
property used in integral capital
analysis against the bulk cybers
later the bitter best division property
as well as the three substated division
property was introduced by toto and the
miro at fse 2016
to search new integral distinguishing
for simon family
division property based cube attacks
were first proposed by total intercept
at crypto 2017
it breaks the limitation of traditional
cuban attacks
where the cube dimension could hardly be
larger than
40.
for example 78 dimensional cubes could
be exploited in division property based
cube attacks
the definition of beta-based
division property was assumed as follows
in the paper published in crypto 2015
and fse
2016 total and morrow studied the
rules of division property for basic
operations
and xor and copay
furthermore
for an around cyber the propagation of a
division property could be evaluated by
figuring out the division property of
internal states
then
the concept of division trail was
proposed
which could
propagate us through the whole around
cyber
the detailed definition is showing our
slides
at the asia crypto 2016 xiaomi series
showed that the propagation could be
efficiently evaluated by using mrp
models
but more particularly an mrp model
captures all division trails and the
solver is valid as the visibility rather
there are division trails from the input
division property to the output one or
not
based on division property one at zeroth
proposed a degree evaluation method
which could estimate the upper bound of
the degree of simple police
according to the proposition proposed by
if
there is d such that ok lambda with hemi
weight
larger than d
the division trail x superscript k
lambda does not exist
then it can be seen that d is an upper
bound of the algebraic degree of the
superpower
now we are going to introduce our work
in cuba text finding cube which would
lead to
useful super police is a critical but a
difficult task
previously some ideas were proposed to
find or construct such cubes
in 2009 dina and shah xiaomi proposed a
random work algorithm to find cubes with
linear superpolis
later in 2013 rogue and vernet presented
a method where two disjoin the small
cubes are unioned to find the linear
superpolis
when it comes to find the cubes leading
to zero sum distinguisher
selecting cubes with no adjacent indexes
and the greedy bit side algorithm was
proposed
our aim is to construct the good cubes
for recovering linear superpowers
to achieve our aim we find the
inspiration
from grade data set algorithm
namely
our solution is starting from a set of
cube variables indexes and
extending it to a large candidate cube
indexes
then there are two critical problems to
be solved
first
how to determine a proper set of cuban
variables indexed by i
second
how to extend i to be a large candidate
cuba indexes
we shall first introduce how to solve
the second problem
we propose a two-stage method to extend
i
the figure shows
an overview of our word measure
more specifically
steep ie variables and gentle array
variables are picked in
the two different stages
in stage one every time add a steep
array variables to decrease the degree
of superpoli as fast as possible
in stage 2
to make the degree of super bowling
close to 1 we pick up a gentle array
variables in
each iteration
now the only left problem is how to
determine a good data cube set
note that the output function of a
trivium is linear which is shown in our
slide if a cube of c has a linear
superpoli then it is very likely one of
the six terms
come to contribute
the linear superpoli and the other five
terms contribute to constant zero
namely we shall only focus on one of the
six internal states bits appeared in the
output function
take the first one as an example
according to the fig feedback function
of trivium it could be expressed as
follows
our idea is focusing on the two degree
term english expression
more particularly we choose a state of
cuba variables indexed by i and search
some of its sub-cubes to find a cube
with linear superpolis either in the
blue internal state or the red one
such cubes
is determined as a starting set cubesat
then the problem turns into how to pick
up a proper internal state from the
sixth internal state speeds in the
output function
since the output function is a summation
of six internal state beat
the superpoli of i in they could have
taken
apart into six ones
note that
a linear superpoly usually has only one
term say p i is equal to k j
one of the six super police is equal to
k j
hence for a given r
it is necessary to predict the key with
a large success probe success property
such that a linear superpoly in vr
implies a linear superpoland in skr
in our paper
skr is called the preference bit
to predict the
preference bit
our main idea is to predict the number
of terms in the form of ti times kj
which are called weak terms
in the sex internal
state bits
however it is difficult to make such
prediction directory
our solution is exploiting the feedback
function of trivium to predict
the number of weekly terms iteratively
we shall take s94
as an example
the feedback function of s94 is shown in
the slide
that we ks be the number of weekly terms
in s
the number of pre terms in s is denoted
by v s
then
the number of way k terms in s94 could
be predicted as the
equation at the bottom of our slides
the key point is to predict the terms in
red
considering the property of boolean
function we predict that the number of
weaker terms as following
finally we use the equation in red to
predict the number of weighted terms in
s94
based on the above method we proposed
algorithm 4 which could iteratively
predict the number of weekly terms
so that the previous bit could have been
predicted
another contribution of this paper is to
improve the mobius transformation
as mentioned before the advantage of
mobius transformation is that it could
compute a large number of sub-cubes from
a large cube simultaneously
however the weakness is that much memory
is needed to store the truth table for a
large cube hence our aim is testing a
large number of sub cubes from a large
cube simultaneously with reasonable
memory
let f be a boolean function on variables
our idea is breaking the original mobius
transformation into a two-stage one to
recover a part of a f of f
in the first stage we calculated g0 g1
to g 2 to the power q
minus 1 and keep a part of their
information
in the second stage we recover lf of f
according to the capital information
algorithm 5 shows the details of our
improved mobius transformation
the memory complexity of algorithm 5 is
consists of two parts
first
the size of s
is 2 to the power n minus q
and so it costs
to the power n minus q bit memory
second for h j the size of sfj
is t and so it requires 2 to the power q
times t bits memory totally
when t is much less than 2 to the power
n minus q
the memory complexity of our improved
the mobius transformation is much less
than that of the original mobius
transformation
with all
with all the above measures we make
application to 805 round trivium
first
the preference bit to find the linear
super poly is
as 66
second we choose
cubes of size 22 and use mobius
transformation to find
a proper cube i1 as our start cuba says
in the first stage we
we extend i1 by adding steep array
variables and we obtain a cube of size
in the second stage we start with
iceland and keep up four variables
as such that the degree of superpolis
are less than 4 in the last iteration
finally i4 of 5
40 is a candidate and large cube which
is given in the slice
together with some other candidate cubes
we find more than one thousand cubes
with linear super police and the output
of eight hundred and
five one trivium
there were
38 independent and linear superpolice
what's more we also find the 16 linear
superpolis for 806 rounded film
these are a part of a linear superpolis
of
round trivium
these are a part of linear superpolis of
806 round tribute
we summarize the key recovery attacks
onto view note that
the previous best practical attack is on
784 rounded trivium
proposed by 4k and bennett
in this report the best practical key
recovery attacks are improved 21 rounds
to
805 random film
what's more we apply our method to 800
rounded to film where a candidate cube
of a size 43 is constructed and the two
sub-cubes of 42 with linear superpolis
are found
now we
shall make a brief conclusion of our
work in this paper we introduce a new
algorithm to construct the good cubes
and apply it to 805
longitude
more specifically a new algorithm to
construct the candidate cubes
the preference bit and the algorithm to
predict it
and
to improve the mobius transformation
more presented
hopefully
we believe that the new algorithm could
also be applied to you like cyphers
thanks for your attention