hi
i'm going to talk about adaptive
security by deletioning attribute-based
encryption
this is joint work with richard goyal
and brentwaters
so consider we want to do public
encryption in a large organization
where everyone can send a secret message
to another person by encrypting the
message with that with respect to that
person's public key a naive way to
realize this is just let everyone
publish their public key in a directory
however this approach may be very
inefficient when we want to send a
message to a group of people we need to
encrypt and send a message to each of
them
suppose this group of people actually
have some common features for example
they all work in the same research group
or they are all under or above some
certain age we can probably just send a
message
a encrypted message to
the people with all this feature
that can decrypt but others without this
feature cannot
such a notion was formulated as
attribute-based encryption in these two
papers the high waters 2005 and
goyu pandey sahib waters 2006.
in an attribute-based encryption scheme
every user has an attribute
as an nb binary string
and we have policies which can be seen
as boolean functions that take in n-bit
input
these boolean functions evaluate on the
attribute and output
zero for reject and one for accept means
the attributes satisfy this specific
process policy we want to deploy
to issue keys
we run setup to generate the public key
and the master secret key
using the master secret key we can
derive secret keys associated with
different attributes
and to encrypt we use the public key
and
we incorporate respect to a certain
policy and the message we want to we
want to put into the ciphertext
the policy can be like decrypters must
be or graduate students and it's
expressed as a boolean function of
attributes as we mentioned before
and only users with the secret key
associated with attributes where this
policy would evaluate them on them to be
one can decrypt the ciphertext
and the rest cannot
and this formulation above is often
called ciphertext policy attribute-based
encryption
since the policy the functionality is
embedded into the ciphertext
there is also a dual formulation called
key policy attribute-based encryption
that invests the policy into the secret
key
and the attribute into the ciphertext
and both of these have constructions
that have a lot of applications
and for both of these formulations we
also have two levels of simatic security
requirement
called adaptive security and selective
security
so adaptive security is actually what we
usually want in practice and it's also
called full security
the challenger generates uh in the
security game the challenger generates a
public key
and the master secret key it gives
public key to the adversary the
adversary can then make queries
uh for secret keys corresponding to some
attributes he chooses
and for
for polynomial many times
this procedure can be seen as the
adversary
uh corrupting a bunch of user keys
and this uh this query stage can happen
again after the challenge phase
uh in the challenge phase he sends in a
policy and a two messages of his own
choice but this policy must be one that
none of the other attributes he has
queried before or he will acquiring that
the query phase after challenge phrase
like none of these attributes he will
query will satisfy this policy
and the decrypter that encrypts one of
these messages randomly with respect to
this policy the adversary gets the
cipher text and he's not supposed to get
guess which message is encrypted
this definition even though natural is
in fact not easy to realize
therefore
people actually turn to a weaker
security notion called selective
security
adversary in the selected security game
the adversity has to first send in the
policy wants to attack on before it sees
the public key
and this uh in the full security happens
in the challenge phase where the
anniversary can see the public key can
make queries and then he chooses the
messages and the the policy and here
here has has to sending this policy
and before he even sees any public
parameters uh everything else every
other stages stay the same
and many of early works would
would first try to build this selected
security and later works move on to
range adaptive security
next we can look at the line of works
that try to build a secure abe
we look at both group assumptions and
lattice and both selective and adaptive
security
so as we mentioned uh early works first
of all selected security uh in terms of
group
constructions these already works uh
built selective security from bilinear
defeat helmet
and later uh there was this well-known
new system technique introduced by
waters
and the adaptive security was realizing
these later works for policies in nc1
and they're based on different types of
decision or group assumptions and and
however uh the reliance on decisional
assumptions seems to be inherent uh when
using this technique whereas in these
early works uh that only have secure
selected security
uh we can actually build from search
assumptions
moving on to the lattice side uh these
works realize selective security for
latitude from lattice for circuits uh
however it was not until re uh recent uh
two years that we finally know something
of adaptive security from lattice and
just to mention here this buoyant
certain scheme was actually uh actually
head attack uh
in last year but we would uh we would
leave it here because it will be
actually useful
uh when we talk about looking forward
when we talk about our construction
and uh so the reason brexu we mentioned
uh was suffering in 2000 2019 realized
the adaptive secure abe from lattice
even though the functionality uh
realizable is only a subset
functionality it is a a step towards
adaptive security and it's a different
approach from all past approaches
we therefore ask the question can we
expand this approach in some way to make
that security hold for more general
cases
okay in our work
we simplified and expanded the framework
of
realizing adaptive security following
sudbury
2019 paper
we show that uh
in a simplified framework we can
instantiate
the adaptive secure a b for subset
functionality from both search
by linear assumptions and lattice
and we can make the whole framework more
clear and understandable
what's our high-level approach
a hell of a project is just combining uh
two building blocks
uh
in an interesting way the first building
block is selected secure key policy
attribute based encryption with a
property that we call deletable
and we just require this uh underline
key policy scheme
scheme to be selective secure
but it needs to be for nc1 circuits
um
which we already have from some previous
papers we mentioned
um
and we will talk about what deleted for
property means and how we can realize
that from previous work
the second building block is a
constraint prf with deletion conforming
property we'll also talk about that
later and together with these two we can
realize adaptive secure ciphertext
policy abe
okay now let's go to our first building
block
deletable abe will demonstrate
deleteable property as follows
given a ciphertext which is
uh an encryption of a message m to an
attribute x1 and we can view the
ciphertext actually as
a bunch of blocks a composition of
a few blocks and then we can perform a
algorithm called delete on the
ciphertext
this delete algorithm will take in the
ciphertext and the set of indices
it will delete the blocks in the
ciphertext index by this these indices
in this set for example 2 and 4 here and
we just take away block 2 and 4.
in fact the number of blocks is equal to
the length
of the attribute
and each block is actually just
associated with one bit in the attribute
so we can take a look at this delete
thing the other way around by looking at
the attribute first we can perform this
algorithm called restrict that basically
just remove some beats in the indices
uh in
and indicating this is they set given
and then we we can probably replace
these places with a special symbol like
bot
and then we have this encryption
procedure that can encrypt with respect
to an attribute
that might have some special single bot
and will still give us a valid cipher
text
and
uh after we said we see these two
different approaches of doing deletion
we actually uh we we say that we they
are actually indistinguishable once you
get a cipher text
so
that basically means whether we encrypt
we first get encrypt and then we perform
deletion on the ciphertext by removing a
few blocks or
whether we first
just remove a few bits in the in the
attribute that encrypt this uh
this uh deleted attribute where we can
get another cipher text and these two
cipher text should be indistinguishable
we call such
uh we call an ap scheme with such
property are this delete procedure this
remove uh restrict actually restrict
procedures here
uh and also there is a
distinguishability uh property they such
an abe will call a deletable abe
and now we get to our second um
building block is this constraint prf
let's first look at uh a usual
constraint prf what properties do we
have
so
a constraint pif has constraints to the
randomness property
so given an original key of the prf
which we call the master secret key here
we can constrain the key
with respect to a function f the prf
would evaluate correctly and normally on
the constraint key
when the inputs satisfy this
functionality f that we constrain would
constrain to
however if an anniversary is given a
constraint key is not able to evaluate
the prs
and inputs that do not satisfy the
function
more formally he cannot distinguish
evaluation on these inputs using the
original master secret key
from any uniform random values
and here we only need single key
adaptive secure
uh pseudorandomness
and
another property we need is called
adaptive key simulation
that is we let adversary choose a
function f adaptively adaptively and uh
there's a procedure called keysim to
generate a simulated key for the
function f
and
it would give a simulated key
indistinguishable from the constrail
constraint key
that procedure only needs to know this
procedure key theme only needs to know
function f
and the
security parameters and
and input output size of
of the prf and no need for knowledge of
any secret key information
so therefore this procedure can
basically be done by anyone given the
encryption of f and this will be needed
in our encryption
data only our construction
okay and now we move on to some special
properties we need for our our
construction to conform with our
framework we call deletion conforming
pif
uh so firstly
we can constrain that when we constrain
the master secret key we in fact just
need to remove
some blocks in this key according to a
set of indices so this would probably
remind you of something we just talked
about
the deletion uh uh the restriction on on
the on the attribute that we can just
keep uh that when we give given a set of
indices we just remove some attributes
uh some some beats in in that attribute
and this here will do the same thing to
the mass secret key
but how how do we know how do we know
what indices to delete how how it is
created for f and we actually have
another procedure
that that is
that takes in the description of f and
it would just output a set of indices
that uh that to tell that tell us what
what to delete what indices we should
remove from the master secret key in
order to to realize the constraint
functionality for f
and secondly uh
we need a a scientist special evaluation
procedure
that is we can evaluate the prf on a
heart coded input x
using a special circuit evaluation this
takes in
a circuit hard coded with input x and
the prf secret key as input it can be
constrained or it can be the master
quickie an output
a correct evaluation uh
as if you do just if you do just using a
normal pif evaluation on the same key
and the uh
and that value x
now we can build our adaptive secure
ciphertext policy a b scheme
from these two underlying
building blocks the deletion conforming
constraint prf and deletable key policy
abe
the first way we can start by talking
about the keychain algorithm
of our ciphertext ciphertext policy ede
our kitchen algorithm takes in a master
secret key which is just composed of
prf secret master secret key and the
deletable abs master secret key
and to derive
a key for attribute x we first compute
this prf evaluation on x using the prf
master secret key and we get a value we
call t
then we run the underlined in turbo a b
is keychain
with respect to the foreign policy just
recorded this is a key policy v so uh
the t derivation
uh algorithm is respect to a policy this
policy f x t takes in a secret key
looking forward this secretly will
actually be a constraint a prf key that
we will generate
and it outputs one if we have this prf
evaluation using the hard-coded circuit
of x
on input of the secret key s k
i'll put something that does not equal
the t we computed period that we
computed previously
and uh we'll put zero otherwise
and then we need to encrypt the message
uh what do we do to encrypt
well we just uh we're taking the uh the
policy f
and we can compute this simulated key
using the prvis key simulation algorithm
and recall that this can be done by
anyone
because it only needs the description of
f and security parameters
and after we get the
the simulated key we just encrypt the
message in the underlying deletable abs
encryption with respect to this
attribute
of the simulated key
and to decrypt it's simple we just run
the underlying deletable abe decryption
using the secret key associated with
that previous
fxt we talked about we get such a secret
key and we can decrypt
and it's probably not very obvious at
first sight why correctness would hold
varsity
we refer the orders to check the details
in our papers and take uh effective use
of this noncluding properties
of the prf
simulated key and the real master secret
key
to show security we basically hybrid as
follows
so in our first hybrid
we switch the attribute used during
encryption from the simulated key
to a real constraint prf key
so recording our real uh
encryption we need to
do something uh we need to encrypt it to
uh to an attribute and that we can
generate by anyone because this is a
public key encryption procedure and we
can just run the key simulation uh on
appear on the function f
however in our hybrids we can switch it
to a real cons uh constraint procedure
on the master secret key uh with
function at f
and these indistinguishability will just
follow from the key simulation
property of constraint prf
and secondly we use the restrict
algorithm to to perform the
uh the constraint uh
constraining functionality thing on the
master secret key of pif and we have
mentioned this uh before that in our
deletion conforming constraint prf these
two operations are actually just
equivalent
and this is just
basically removing a few blocks from the
master secret key uh
using the the set of indices that we we
need to remove for f and that would just
perform the functionality of
constraining master secret key to f
and finally
notice that here uh in the previous two
hybrids we we perform this uh
restrict or say removal on the master
secret key
which would give us this attribute that
we want to encrypt to
and then we encrypt respect to this
constraint key
attribute
uh and in the final hybrid we switch the
order of deletion
we first uh
uh just uh normally use uh we just uh
normally encrypt with respect to
attribute that is the master uh secret
key of prf without any constraining
using the deletable abs encryption
and then we run delete on the ciphertext
using the indices to delete for f so we
can still
you know take taking f we can still just
generate this set of indices and that
wouldn't disturb
that wouldn't really affect anything we
can we can do the division
on the master secret key or we can do
the same deletion on the ciphertext and
then this follows from deletion of
indistinguishability of deletable abe
and finally
we can uh
we can actually use this to break the
selected security of deletable abe and
suppose the adversary can break the uh
the adaptive cpa security of our a b
scheme in the final hybrid
and we can use it to break the selective
sap security of the underlying deletable
abe
and finally how do we instantiate our
building blocks the first thing is
deletion conforming construing prf
we can realize it a subset functionality
just following the construction in these
two works
and secondly for deletable abe
uh we can uh uh realize that from from
uh from uh some different sorts of works
uh we can actually modify the following
schemes
into a deletable abe scheme
into divisible a b streams for the group
side we can
modify the gpsw
2006 paper which uses the search
assumption on bilinear groups
and for the laddie side we can do both
buoyant thirteen and bgg plots fourteen
even though actually recently as we
mentioned there is what was this attack
on buoyancy paper
uh but that came out after the first
draft of our paper and we just we still
leave this example in our paper just for
the illustrative purpose to see how the
deletion
uh how the deletable abe would work
and uh regarding uh related works
actually
besides all these passwords we already
mentioned there was also a concurrent
work by katsumata nishimaki yamada and
yamakawa that extend the functionality
of sabari scheme into an inner product
functionality and they also follow
the same high level approach as the
subreddit scheme
finally is our summary
with adaptive constraint prf adapting
secure constraint prf and selective
secure a b
we can realize that that is secure abe
but the policy is just a subsystem
constraint which follows from the policy
we can realize for the constraint prf
and we need the abe to be deletable but
we can build such a be from a bunch of
assumptions both
search bilinear and lattice
thank you that's it for our talk
please refer for more details in our
paper