hi my name is michael rosenberg and
today i'm presenting results for my work
on blind signatures with john katz and
julian loss
let's get started
first we define what a blind signature
scheme is
we start with the intuition that blind
signatures are like digital signatures
except the signer learns nothing about
the message that it's signed
the security property is formalized as
blindness and essentially means that a
signer who blindly signed two messages
can't tell what order they were signed
in even if given the full transcript
message contents and signatures later on
the next security property is similar to
one in digital signatures
a signature scheme is unforgeable if
given access to a signing oracle the
adversary can't produce a fresh message
signature pair i.e one that the signer
hasn't seen yet
the problem with this definition in the
case of blind signatures is that every
message signature pair looks fresh
because all the messages were signed
blindly
so the standard version of
unforgeability for blind signatures is a
slightly different notion called one
more unforge-ability or omuf
this game just counts message signature
pairs
a blind signature scheme is one more
unforgeable if an adversary who makes l
many calls to a signing oracle is unable
to produce l plus one distinct message
signature pairs
to provide motivation we note that there
are real world applications for blind
signature schemes
they have appeared as a primitive for an
anonymous fair exchange mechanism for
bitcoin as well as for a cryptocurrency
imagined by david chalm called ecash
which is actually the origin of the idea
of blind signatures
our paper begins by observing a gap in
existing efficient blind signature
schemes
we look at existing schemes and note
some of the common caveats
first the blind snore signature scheme
is only proven secure for
logarithmically many signatures
in addition it was proven last year that
it is completely broken for more than
log of two kappa concurrent sessions
where kappa is the security parameter
another observation is that other
schemes supporting polynomially many
signatures rely on non-standard
assumptions including the code
diffie-hellman inversion assumption
the one more rsa inversion assumption
and the algebraic group model
finally there are some blind signature
schemes which don't provide concurrency
at all
in light of this overview we aim to fill
a gap in existing blind signature
schemes
specifically we wish to construct a
blind signature scheme in the random
oracle model using standard number
theoretic assumptions that is provably
secure after polynomially many
signatures and with arbitrary
concurrency
we achieve this goal by constructing a
generic transformation that transforms a
blind signature scheme supporting
logarithmically many signatures to one
that supports polynomially many
specifically our transformation operates
on blind signature schemes which arise
from algebraic hash functions with
certain homomorphic properties this is
expanded on later
secondly we make no new security
assumptions
thus after transformation the only
assumptions necessary are the ones that
come from the underlying schemes such as
discrete log rsa or factoring
finally the schemes that this
transformation outputs support arbitrary
concurrency
our transformation does come with
caveats however
first the communication complexity
depends on how many signatures have
already been computed
this can be improved however to just
being linear in the number of dishonest
users who were caught being dishonest
we explain what this means later
the second caveat is that the estimated
group size necessary to achieve 128-bit
security is approximately 5000 bits
to begin describing our transformation
we start with a transformation due to
poncheval
we start with an ordinary three-round
blind signature scheme
in ponchaval's case it is the blind
okomota snore scheme
the signer initiates the protocol the
user blinds their input sends it to the
signer to be signed and then unblinds
the signer's output
ponchovalle turns this into a six-round
protocol by introducing a cut and choose
sub-protocol
let's examine this in detail
the transform changes the underlying
scheme as follows
first the user now commits to two sets
of random coins
this is the randomness that's going to
be used to blind their message
next the signer picks a commitment at
random to leave unopened the other must
be opened
next the client sends the opening
and finally the signer checks the
opening
if it was valid it completes the rest of
the protocol as in the underlying scheme
if the opening was invalid then the
signer aborts the protocol and then
halts forever refusing to sign any
future messages
we call this tear down because it can't
be recovered from
in the real world tear down would amount
to updating the signer's key pair every
time a user is caught cheating in the
protocol
what does this transform set out to do
pontrevol's proof strategy is to reduce
the security of the underlying scheme
which recall can only handle
logarithmically many signatures to that
of the transform scheme
since the transformed scheme is supposed
to support far more signatures than the
underlying scheme there needs to be some
way to bring down the number of
interactions an adversary can initiate
with the underlying signer
to do this pointrevolt defines a
simulator which can simulate the signer
in the new scheme as long as the
commitment to the randomness was
honestly computed
so as long as the user is on as the
underlying signer doesn't need to be
called
the way to check honest computation is
by having the user make two commitments
and open one of them thus a cheating
user gets caught with probability one
half each session
does this achieve security for
polynomially many signatures
yes it does the reduction goes through
and we get a log one more forger
there's a neat proof that does this by
showing that if a potentially dishonest
user's execution tree with the transform
scheme has polynomially many leaves then
not too many of its branches could have
been pruned i.e it could have only
cheated logarithmically many times hence
the log one more forgery
so
since the number of cheating attempts is
logarithmically bounded after
polynomially many interactions and since
blind okamoto schnorr is shown to
support logarithmically many signatures
punjab concludes that the transform
scheme supports polynomially many
signatures
some downsides of this scheme include
the fact that it doesn't permit
arbitrary concurrency
rather it only permits parallel
execution which is a weaker notion
also this requires a full teardown for
every caught cheater which can be
annoying and costly to implement in
practice
finally this transform is not generic
ponchovalle only states the transform in
terms of the okumuda schnorr blind
signature scheme
we now introduce our transform by
starting with punchavals
our scheme doesn't diverge from it too
much
the first detail of our transform is
that its structure depends on the number
of sessions that have already been
initiated
in this sense it is stateful
we denote the session number by n
in session n the user commits to n sets
of random coins rather than just two
then
the user picks an index i which will be
the commitment that is not opened
the user opens all the commitments other
than i
and finally the signer checks all the
commitments
on success it signs just as before
on failure it only aborts rather than
aborting and tearing down
this means that the signer can continue
signing future sessions even if cheating
is detected
we now compare this to the original
point of all transform
first remember that we can only afford o
of log kappa many signatures in the
underlying scheme
the goal of both ponchovall's and our
transformations in their security proofs
is to limit the number of such
signatures
previously the probability of a user
getting away with cheating was one half
in each session
if a tear down weren't enforced a user
could cheat linearly many times which
would potentially break the underlying
scheme
thus tear downs are necessary
in our transform the probability of a
user getting away with cheating is 1
over n in session n
without using teardown the expected
number of times a user could cheat is
logarithmic in the number of sessions
they initiate since this is a harmonic
sum
also importantly we prove that with high
probability a user can't do much better
than the expected value so they can't
escape the logarithmic bound
since we've logarithmically bounded the
number of interactions with the
underlying signer we conclude that our
scheme is secure for polynomially many
signatures without tear downs
we now compare concurrency
recall that the panchaval transform only
permitted parallel executions which is
weaker than arbitrary concurrency
in particular with parallel execution a
session cannot advance faster than its
predecessors
with our scheme the only state is the
session number n
so if n is atomically incremented across
sessions the harmonic sum from the
previous slide holds regardless of the
number of concurrent sessions running
thus we achieve arbitrary concurrency
we also prove that you can do better
than incrementing every time
in fact we show that it suffices to only
increment n when a user is caught
cheating
finally we compare genericity
as mentioned before punjab's transform
was only defined in terms of the okomoto
schnorr blind signature scheme
our result which builds on ponchovall's
transform also generalizes it to any
blind signature scheme built on an
algebraic hash function with certain
homomorphic properties
we refer to these as linear function
families in the paper
examples of blind signature schemes
built on top of a linear function family
include shnoor okamotoshnore
fiat shamir and okomoto gyukiskate
that's it for my talk
thank you for your time