welcome everybody to asia equipped 2021
my name is alexis obenko and i will be
talking about convexity of division
property transitions
theory algorithms and compact models
enjoy
first i would like to provide a quick
high-level overview of the work
the work studies division property which
is a great analysis technique for
symmetric ciphers
there are many variants of division
property and this work focuses on the
earliest and the most widely applicable
one
big based to subset division property
also called traditional or conventional
division property
it was introduced by todo at eurocrypt
2015.
the contributions of our work include
new theoretic insights such as closed
links of division property propagation
with graphs of analyzed functions
which lead to one of the key results a
new compact representation of division
property propagation suitable for
modelling by sat solvers
in addition we describe new algorithms
for computing propagation tables and
compact representations in quadratic
time improving previous cubic time
approaches
as a proof of concept we studied the
super sbox model of led which was
impractical by previous methods and was
challenged in the recent work of their
best and
now i'm going to introduce all the
relevant concepts required for the work
including division property working with
the partial order or bit vectors and
formalization of division property
consider a cryptographic primitive built
from iterations of a simple round
function for example a block cipher or a
stream cipher
in integral clip analysis we want to
know whether the multivariate polynomial
expression of an output bit of the
primitive may contain a chosen monomial
of the input variables
if the presence of the monomial does not
depend on the involved secret keys
we obtain a distinguisher from a random
function which can be used to attack the
primitive
the core idea of division property is
very simple
in order for y0 as a function of x
to contain the monomial x0 x1 x2
there must exist a sequence of monomials
in the intermediate states
such as at each step the product of
functions defined by the output monomer
contains the input monomial
for example here the product of the bits
of w with indexes 2 and 5 as a function
of that may contain the monomial that
won that 3.
such a sequence is called a division
trail and each step in it is called a
division property transition
usually division trails are searched
using such or smt solvers or mlp
optimizers
in this work we focus on studying single
step transitions in depth
in particular we aim to find compact
encodings of possible transitions into
such solvers
this process is often called modeling
a notable difference with say linear or
differential trails is that here the
distinguisher holds only if there is no
division trail
otherwise we cannot conclude on the
existence of the distinguisher
i will now introduce some definitions
related to the partial order on bit
vectors that are used extensively in
this work
the order is defined as follows we say
that a vector u is below or is equal to
vector v
if for each bit position the respective
coordinate of u is smaller or equal than
that of v
on the slide you can see the partial
order graph associated with a set of
four bit vectors
here edges go upwards and one h
corresponds to flipping one zero bit
into a bit equal to one
then the partial order can be
reformulated as follows a vector u is
below or is equal to vector v if there
is a directed path from u to v in this
graph
monotonicity and convexity are defined
with respect to this partial order
a set is called a lower set if there are
no edges going from a non-element to an
element of the set
the upper set is defined analogously
extreme elements which are maximal for
the lower set and minimal for the upper
set
form a compact representation of
monotone sets
for upper sets extreme elements can be
viewed as patterns with wild cards and
ones
for lower sets the patterns consist of
wild cards and zeros
they can be seen as vectorial upper or
lower bounds
a set is called convex if it has both
lower and upper bounds
in other words it is an intersection of
a lower set and an upper set
since we aim to model transitions for
say assad solver we are interested in
modeling this monotone or convex sets
quite naturally an upper set can be
modeled using a monotone dnf disjunction
normal form
where the number of the clauses is equal
to the number of the minimal elements in
the set
for example the first clause here
corresponds to bit vectors with the last
two bits equal to one
and all such vectors are included in the
considered set
alternatively an upper set can be
modeled by cnf formula conjunction
normal form it requires to consider the
complementary lower set the size of the
formula then is defined by the number of
maximal elements in the complement
it is worth noting that the compact
representation is not always really
compact in addition the gap between cnf
and dnf representation can itself be
huge
however on practice there is a
significant chance of large reduction in
size of the representation increasing
modelling possibilities
finally a convex set can be trivially
modeled by concatenating the lower and
the upper bounds in the cnf form
this method however doesn't work with
dnf formulas notably and perhaps
counterintuitively due to higher
dimension the upper and the lower bounds
can intersect as is shown in the example
on the slide
here the vector 1 0 1 0 is both minimal
in the complementary upper set
and maximal in the complementary lower
set
this phenomenon introduces some freedom
into modeling we can choose for the
elements in the intersection whether
they should be removed by an upper set
or by lower set
i will now briefly recall formalization
of division property
at crypto 2016 buran canton introduced
parity sets as another view of division
property
simply speaking parity sets capture
which products of bits sum to one over
the given set
total's division property of a set can
be defined simply as a lower bound on
its parity set
here upper closure simply means the
smallest upper set containing k
it can be shown that the parity set is
basically equivalent to the algebraic
normal form of the set's indicator
function i recall that indicator
function is a boolean function equal to
one on the elements of the set and to
zero on the known element the set
in other words it represents the set as
a function
so using this link we can conclude that
division property simply defines
vectorial upper bounds or monomials in
the a f of the indicator of the set
recall the division trails i mentioned
when introducing division property for
example in the trail here i said before
that we know that the product that one
that's 3 may contain the monomer x0 x1
x2 for some key k0
to handle the secret keys being stored
between the round functions in a more
simple way
we can relax the propagation rule to
allow smaller products of z to contain
larger monomials of x
then we can ignore the secret keys
for example we consider this transition
valid if
say z1 instead of z1z3 contains x0 x1 x2
x5 instead of just x0 x1 x2
where we consider only the function f0
and no keys at all
this manipulation introduces the
monotonicity aspect because we can now
add or remove variables from the
products which is equivalent to flipping
bits in exponents
now i will describe new insights into
division property transitions including
new characterizations leading to compact
representations and also exhibiting
explicitly convexity of minimal
transitions
first recall the definition of the graph
of a vectorial boolean function which is
simply the set of all valid input output
pairs of the function
one of the main results of this work
provides new characterizations of valid
division property transitions in
particular it turns out that the set of
varied transitions through f
coincides up to negating the input part
with the division property of the graph
of f as a set
it is an interesting connection between
the division property of a set and
transitions of such division properties
in addition it draws attention to the
extreme elements which are minimal
elements of the parity set of the graph
or alternatively transitions u to v with
maximal u and minimal v
moreover thanks to the nf formulation of
division property
we can deduce that this extreme set
coincides again up to some negations
with a set of maximal monomials in the
nf of the graph indicator function
this link is in particular interesting
due to a recent work by carla deriving
new methods of degree bounds based on
the degrees of the involved graph
indicators
i will focus on the extreme set of
transitions highlighted by these
characterizations as it will play the
role of the compact representation
and that's exactly how we define the
compact representation which due to its
utility we shall call the division core
so the division core of a vectorial
boolean function is simply the set of
minimal elements of the parity set of
its graph
equivalently it is the set of
transitions with maximal u and minimal v
with the first part negated
alternatively it is the bitwise negation
of the set of maximal monomials in the
nf of the graph indicator
i would like to emphasize the difference
with the notions from the literature
since it may be confusing
classic propagation of division property
focuses on transitions which are called
minimal or reduced which only require
that the output vector v is minimal for
every fixed input vector u
the idea of considering every possible
input vector
comes from the table based modeling
method
first the table of all transitions is
computed where for each input vector all
possible output transitions are
enumerated
and then this table is modeled by an
appropriate method
here we instead
avoid full enumeration of input vectors
and record only constraints in some form
which is achieved by considering
transitions with a maximal input vector
u
a simple formulation then is that any
valid transition should be equal to or
lie above of some vector from the
division core
the compactness here is associated with
the fact that we consider the set of
minimal vectors
i remind that it doesn't have strong
guarantees on the size but provides very
reasonable results in practice at least
if compared with the enumeration of all
input vectors
finally i recall from the beginning of
this talk that extreme sets lend
themselves naturally to cnf or dnf
modelling and so does the division core
it is notable that solely from the
division core we can deduce the full set
of valid transitions or the full set of
minimal transitions
even more division core contains
information about division transitions
through the inverse of the function if
it exists
this highlights completeness of division
core as representing the behavior of the
function with respect to the traditional
division property
one last bit of the theory covers
minimal transitions whereby minimal i
mean the usual minimality under a fixed
input vector u
these transitions are important due to
their utility in modeling where we want
to reduce the search space as much as
possible
if we look at the full set of possible
transitions
invalid transitions form a lower set
and redundant transitions form an upper
set
it follows that minimal transitions form
a convex set
it has both a lower and an upper bound
therefore we can model it by cnn formula
by removing the redundant upper set and
the invalid lower set
however
due to the high dimensions involved the
covering of non-minimal transitions by
an upper set and the lower set is not
unique we saw that already on the
example from the convex set where the
maximal complementary lower and upper
sets actually intersected
on practice
we noticed that removing the maximal
complementary upper set
usually has more compact models in this
case
these side parts are removed twice
by the lower bound and by the upper
bound
while this is a simplified picture it
nicely conveys the idea
all these sets and the extreme parts can
be computed from the division core
i would like to emphasize that here the
minimal set is defined by considering
each fixed vector u separately
while in the figure we consider the full
set of transitions this is precisely
what allows to obtain more compact
models
here are examples on model size for some
s-boxes
for s-boxes we consider modeling the set
of minimal transitions precisely
in the table you can see the number of
minimal transitions in the set and the
size of the cnf representation using our
methods and also using optimal modeling
method the quine mcclaskey algorithm
we can see that our representation is
about twice as larger than the optimal
one
the problem with the optimal one is that
it doesn't scale well obtaining even
sub-optimal results using the quan
mclasky algorithm quickly becomes
invisible for larger s-box sizes while
our method scales reasonably well
notably we observe very compact
representation for heavy s-boxes that is
those having most high degree monomials
in their output bits or in small
products of output bits
for example the aes s-box has quite
compact model
misty s-boxes however have algebraic
weaknesses which was exploited by todo
in the attack on full misty and so have
more complex and less compact structure
of transitions
for larger s-boxes i focus only on the
number of constraints necessary to
remove the invalid trails
redundant trails can be removed
imprecisely by much smaller formulas
such as cardinality constraints
we can model super sboxes with variant
success for example strong leds super
sbox can be modeled by about 300 000
constraints
while weaker midori's super sbox
requires 2 millions
for modern sat solvers it may be still
in the feasible range but it really
depends on the exact setup
an interesting case is the heavy linear
layer of led which is based on an mds
matrix
it was the source of complexity in the
work by derbys and
it can be modeled by just 30 000
constraints using our method
finally merely as a proof of concept
we managed to model a randomly generated
32-bit s-box
as i mentioned before heavy s-boxes tend
to have very compact representations
which is nicely illustrated by this case
where we need only three thousand enough
clauses to model all valid transitions
the compact representation is practice
oriented so it is necessary to
understand how to compute it and work
with it in practice
to this end we propose an elegant
algorithmic framework capturing all the
necessary manipulations
the key algorithmic component we use is
the slide generalization of the classic
anf computation algorithm or the fast
fourier transform
these algorithms transform an array of
size two to the n in quasi-linear time
the basic function we use called
transform takes an array of size two to
the n
which can be the two's table of a
function or a set's indicator vector
and transform it by two elements at a
time
such that indices of these elements
differ in exactly one bit the parameter
f of the algorithm
is a two valid binary function described
in the manipulation
depending on this function we can obtain
many useful bit oriented transformations
the function sort up which source the
first element to the second one
corresponds simply to the merbus
transform that is the classic nf
computation
sort down which stores the second
element to the first one computes the
parity set of a set
this transformation is particularly
important in view of our theorem
which links the set of division property
transitions with the parity set of the
graph of the function
or up and or down simply compute the
upper closure and the lower closure
respectively which are the minimal upper
or lower sets containing the given set
finally less up which replaces the
second value with the n naught of the
inputs computes the set of minimal
vectors when called after the upper
closure
similarly we can compute the set of
maximal elements
again all these algorithms work in time
and times to the end
using these algorithms and our
theoretical insights we can reduce a
simple algorithm for computing the
division property propagation table of a
function
which improves previous algorithms
mainly due to the non-heuristic mean set
step
as a result we can compute all relevant
sets for an s-box in quadratic time
while previous algorithms were cubic
in addition this framework can be
implemented very efficiently in a bit
slice fashion
finally i will briefly mention our
application to led unfortunately
while compact modelling greatly expands
visibility of modern division property
we couldn't find other interesting
applications with large s-boxes
led is a lightweight box cypher
published a chest 10 years ago
best integral distinguisher is on seven
rounds due to who one guang who used an
smt solver to model the linear layer
precisely for the first time
i recall that with our method we can
modulate with cnf directly
recently their base and applied
ad-hoc dividend trail search using super
sbox models of ciphers and linear
combinations of bits and the input and
at the output their method was not
practical for led due to its complex
linear layer
therefore the question remained open
whether the super sbox model with linear
combinations can find h round
distinguisher or not
our compact models for led are rather
large but reasonable and fire well with
modern sat solvers such as kisat
the eight round model for a fixed linear
combination is solved in about one
minute
we exhausted all linear combinations but
found no 8 round distinguishers
therefore one has to go beyond this
module to find them if they exist
here we can see an example division
trail for led
the first column in the first transition
covers a subset of all possible linear
masks alpha that correspond to a
constant component at the inputs supers
box
similarly the first column in the last
transition covers a subset of all
possible linear masks better
that correspond to a considered output
component
we found that all possible pairs of
masks alpha beta can be covered by 255
different columns on each side
this means that all combinations can be
checked by running the start solver
almost 2 to 16 times
which is quite a lot
on practice we found that a small set of
discovered trails is sufficient to cover
all possible pairs
so that assault solver has to be run
only a few dozens of times
to conclude please look for more results
in the paper and check out the code
repository which has convenient
implementations of the described
techniques
there are still many interesting
problems left such as compressing cnf
models into compact mlp models or using
more advanced techniques to find or
prove in existence of an 8 round
distinguisher for led
and of course we hope the new techniques
will find more applications
thank you and i will be happy to answer
your questions
you