greetings
in this talk i will be talking about
gladius
our lwr based hybrid cipher which
supports fast distributed decryption
this is work by gran kong myself baron
maran and professor nigel smart
so
securely distributing decryption means
that
several distrustful parties want to
jointly decrypt some ciphertext
and
the way you do that is by secret sharing
the key among the parties so each party
will
hold a secret shot of the secret key
and by that you can define
some access structure so for example if
you have a
threshold then it means that
any subset of at least the parties can
use the shares and recover the secret
key
so those are the qualified parties
and on the other hand less than tea
parties
uh can't use their shares in
any way so those are the unqualified
practice
so the parties with the shares engage in
a protocol
which implements the
decryption functionality
and
since they are
they don't trust each other the
communication has to be secured
so intuitively this means that
the protocol should be as secure as the
pre primitive that it implements
so for example if the
underlying encryption scheme is in cca
security means that
an adversary was given access to the
decryption oracle
shouldn't be able to distinguish between
cipher texts
without processing
the secret key
and similarly
at the level of the protocol the
adversary
that controls some unqualified party and
is given access to the decryption
oracle
coming from the functionality
shouldn't be able to distinguish between
cipher texts without
possessing the qualified parties shares
so we want to construct a public key
encryption
for which we can implement the
decryption algorithm
using a secure protocol and we want to
do that efficiently
so we start by
fixing some requirements from the
underlying primitive
so the public encryption should be
insisted secure
should be pass quantum
and
should be able to encrypt messages of
any length
so
what we are really looking for is an
hybrid construction
so in an hybrid construction it is not
enough
to design a fast distributed decryption
for the cam part only because the cam
part is embedded in a larger
circuit and the other components
might be quite expensive for
for distributed computing
and
indeed
it has been an open problem for quite a
long that of having uh and on hybrids
constructing constructing and hybrid
um
having the
the wall decryption circuit optimized
for multi-party computation techniques
in this paper we tried to solve this
problem
so
the most famous hybrid is that from
grammar shoop
it combines a chem
and a them into
a public encryption
key generation is
that from the can
and to encrypt a message
you first generate a small session key
you encrypt you encapsulate it using the
can on the public key
and this will form the first cipher text
while the message is efficiently
encrypted with the demo component using
the session key
and this will be the second
cipher text
with that decryption is quite obvious so
you first encapsulate k
from this ciphertext and you will use
the session key to decrypt the second
ciphertext and get the message
so
we get
in cca security
if we start with ncca components
and we are able to encrypt
messages
of
any length because we can
simply
use any
symmetric
key cipher in a mode of operation
the problem it comes when we try to
distribute the decryption algorithm
so everything that involves the secret
key needs to be implemented as a secure
protocol
so
we start by securely computing the
capsulation
and the result secret key
is
should still be kept secret
and this means that we also need to
implement a secure protocol the
decryption of the dam
now this last step is the problem
especially for long messages when you
are using
um
i don't know aes in a mode of operation
uh the decryption under general
multi-party computation techniques is
quite expensive
so it would be great if we
avoided this last step
so
the native idea
is
to just simply
release this the session key
make it public
so that we can perform the decryption
over clear data so no need of any
uh secure protocol
what i mean is that once we get
the secret shinky we just
reveal it
so we can perform the decryption
uh over clear data
and
yeah the problem is that there is an
obvious cca attack because an adversary
you get
the challenge so you want to start c to
star
then forms this
cipher text c1 star c2 where c2 is a
completely random ciphertext
and
he queries the decryption oracle on this
ciphertext which is allowed because it
is different from
the challenge
so let's look let's see what happens on
uh
when it requires
the oracle so the first component will
be correctly decrypted by definition
and
yeah
following our strategy the
the the session key will be really
revealed
and
yeah the second component probably will
result in an error because it's random
some something completely random so the
adversary high probability will get
the valid session key and an error
message whatever the second component is
so we will just use the session key to
decrypt the second
challenge and get the full message so
security is completely broken
now
our
our hybrid our proposal comes from
is the result of trying to fix this um
security flow
and yeah this is what we
propose our high reconstruction
again we are combining a public key
encryption with a symmetric encryption
uh
it's very similar to claroshope
and the difference is we are using a
secure hash function here
so after generating a session key
encapsulating it and
after the encryption of the message we
authenticate the session key using this
hash function so we are linking k to the
second cipher text
as a result we get an additional cipher
text here
the effect of this on the decryption
algorithm is that
we will need to
perform
a verification of the hash
so
if this uh verification passes
namely evaluating g over c2 and k will
produces the third ciphertext
then we will
reveal we will broadcast k along with
the message
otherwise we will return just
an error message
probably you
already guessed
that
by using a hash function this way
we are basically preventing the previous
attack
indeed
if the adversary follows the previous
strategy so by submitting something like
a challenge and other random stuff
then with high probability the
verification here will fail
and
the adversary will get nothing
so the only way for the adversary to get
the session key
is either of course submitting the
challenge but this is not allowed
or
by finding a collision in the hash
function
so the previous attack
is prevented
also notice
that
by placing on a hash function here
and authenticating k
here
we have the following advantage that we
don't need the randomness from our
public encryption
and indeed we can just use a
deterministic public key encryption
well it should be
still
secure enough just to prevent some brute
force attacks on the first ciphertext
so the right
security notion we are interested in is
one-way cpa
so putting everything together we are
able to prove that
leaking the key this way
is still it is secure produces something
secure namely
if we start with a one-way cpa
deterministic public key encryption and
a one-time ncpa symmetric encryption
then we will get
a public encryption which is in cca
secure in the random oracle model
now let's go to the
protocol
secure protocol that implements the
distributed decryption of this hybrid
so this is a picture that gives you the
idea of what should be performed in a
secure way
um so everything that involves the
secret key or
the session key
should be done securely so these
operations are marked with threatened
so
first we decrypt the first ciphertext
using the secret key the result is the
session key which is still secret which
is then passed to the
hash function g which will
verify that the session key comes from a
valid encryption
and if this verification
passes then we are able to
leak broadcast the session key
and
pass it to the decryption and execute
this decryption the clear the
decrypting the second component the
ciphertext don't get the message
now
in order for
this to be efficient as a secure
protocol
we basically need two things
evaluating
efficiently g over secret data
and
evaluating uh performing a secure
protocol efficiently for the public
encryption
so the first
requirement is
can be easily met by using any
mpc friendly function
as a g so
the only thing that is left to do is to
find a good candidate for this public
encryption
so we are
also presenting we are also proposing a
second hybrid
uh which is exactly
the same as before except we now add two
more hash functions one here
and one here producing a fourth cipher
text
and also
we will need to redo this hash functions
evaluations in the um
in the decryption
so
if we do so then the previous statement
holds in the quantum random oracle model
the reason for this is quite technical
and you can find the details in the full
version of the paper
also we can
provide a
general distributed
[Music]
circuit for the decryption of the second
hybrid
which is
similar to the previous one except now
we need to
implement as a protocol these two
additional hash evaluations
so they need to be evaluated over the
secret
session key
so again for
so everything is
almost exactly as before
and
the only things that need to be
implemented as secure protocols are the
decryption and the actual evaluations
for those we can use again npch
functions
and for this we need to find a good
public encryption
for which we can do the encryption
efficiently with a protocol
so
um
what is left to do
is to
find
a public key encryption which is
deterministic
but still one-way cpa is secure
also
we would like it to be
quantum because if we plug something a
pub a public key encryption which is
spot
quantum based on post quantum
assumptions in second hybrid then we
will get
[Music]
we will get
the
in hybrid public key
encryption which is also what's granted
so
the standard way of
having um
of getting a
deterministic public key encryption is
by de-randomizing a probabilistic
encryption
and
there is a technical encrypted hash
which basically takes a
probabilistic end
cpa
public encryption and gives you
a deterministic one-way cpa
public encryption
so
basically you
replace
replace the randomness
with the hash of the message
and
to get the one-way cpa security you
have to redo these operations again in
the description
so um this is
basically what the
what one of the
variants of the
come out to
transform us
and
so
again we have a problem if we try to do
this in a
distributed way
and the reason is that
this message in our case is going to be
the
session key which is still secret at
this point so
we would need to re-evaluate the hash
function over secret data
and use it as a seed
for the randomness of the
encryption
encryption which has to be computed over
the secret session key
so
especially when
the encryption algorithm
is
using some uh weird
probabilistic probability distribution
then this operation is really expensive
for general multi-party computation
techniques
so
i hope you are convinced that this
approach doesn't really
work in our case so
we would like to find something that
doesn't use
randomness to get security
so one operation that is intrinsically
secure intrinsically
random
is the rounding map
so for two integers p and q where p is
less than q
you have this rounding map that takes an
integer and
scales it by p over q and
approximates it by the nearest integer
and this hides the lower bits of the
input
if the input is sufficiently random
then this map is
basically one way
so
we have something that
doesn't need additional noise or
randomness to
to be
one way to be secure
and that's perfect we want to base our
encryption on that
luckily there is an assumption based on
such constructions which is related to
the learning with iris problem
and guess what the name is
learning without its problem
so
here instead of having a nice
linear system you have a
rounded linear system
and the basic
version of the decision learning
surroundings
says that
for a secret vector and the public
matrix this rounded matrix by vector
product looks indistinguishable from
a completely random vector
then you also have the
decision ring lwr
if you
consider the same problem over
polynomial rings
and the decision module lwr
if you are considering
adding more structure and considering
matrices of polynomial rings
finally you have to search under your
problem which says that
it's difficult to retrieve s from many
lwr samples
so on top of that we are able to
construct our
public key encryption
so
um
it's really simple
the encryption so is probably it is
deterministic
and this comes from the fact that we are
base
we are basing the encryption directly on
the rounding map
so you see that we don't need
any we are not using any randomness
and
the
decryption is quite fast
for
distributed techniques cause
and the reason lies on the fact that we
are using lwe
techniques constructions in the key
generation
now
what is left to do is to argue the
one-way cpa security
and this is just a combination of the
search on we
here
because
this is
saying our
public key is indistinguishable from
a pair of random matrices and the search
lwr
which is basically the fact that the
encryption
is
our encryption is a one-way map
so we are done
on to summarize
we started with the problem of finding
constructing a public encryption
for which we could do
the decryption
um
in a distributed way quite efficiently
so as i mentioned this problem reduces
to that of
considering hybrid cyphers
and so
we started looking at the chromosome
hybrid which was the problem
of requiring one to evaluate
the decryption of the them over the
secret session
this operation is costly
for
uh in in a distributed way
also it requires
ncca components so quite demanding
so the idea is that we leak
the session key
before doing the decryption so the
decryption then
becomes
just an operation
over clear data so there is no need for
any secure protocol
and
we we are able to do that without
consequences securely so we can lick the
key securely because we are using
um hash function
as a
authentication
on
for for this for the session
also this hash function is useful
because we can
use minimal
assumptions for our
public key encryption we just need a
deterministic public key encryption
so what we get
at the end is a very general transform
that takes
um a deterministic one-way cpa public
encryption with a one-time ncpa dam
and gives you a
ncca public encryption in the random
oracle model
we get full security in the quantum
random oracle model if we had two more
hashes
finally we are able to
show that it is possible to
construct
a public encryption which is
deterministic still one way
secure
based on the lwr assumption
so we are basing encryption directly on
the rounding map
which basically is
avoiding us doing
expensive randomization procedures
so
putting everything together
we get
the first practical
post quantum public encryption
for which we can
implement the decryption using
a secure protocol in
[Music]
in an efficient way very efficiently
so this concludes my talk if you have
questions about paper please
feel free to contact me by email
take care