hello everyone um today we're gonna
present the improved programmable
bootstrapping with larger precision and
efficient arithmetic circuit for tfha
this is a working collaboration between
me ilaria lottie damian li
jean batister fila and samuel tap
the four of us today are gonna take care
of the presentation
so before we start uh let's see a little
overview of what we're gonna present
today so the presentation is gonna be
split in five major parts we're going to
start with a
introduction of the tfh schema an
overview of the tfh schema then we're
going to present our improvements um
which are the pbs mini loot the bfv
product into tfh and the ypbs and then
we're going to finish with some
challenges and conclusions
okay so before we start talking about
tfh um let's understand what is the fhe
so fhe stands for fully homomorphic
encryption
and it's a new technology allowing to do
computations over encrypted data every
encrypted messages
so in the slides you're going to often
see the messages encrypted inside
a box this as instance in the slide a
little blue box with a
with a lock on the bottom this means the
encryption and the message is going to
be x and y in this
in the slide
so in practice what happens in
homomorphic encryption is that if we add
the homomorphically to ciphertext or if
we multiply homomorphically to
ciphertext the result is going to be a
new ciphertext encrypting the addition
and the multiplication of the original
messages respectively
by combining addition and multiplication
we can possibly evaluate any function
and the type of messages we can treat in
homomorphic encryption are values we can
have bits integers real messages
so the most annoying part in homomorphic
encryption is what we call the the noise
growth um to be more clear what happens
when we encrypt them is that we add some
little amount of noise this little
randomness that is measured in the
slides with um with this little
thermometer and when we start uh when we
encrypt
the noise is very very small however
when we start computing homomorphic
operations the noise grows and when we
do additions and linear combination the
noise is
grows a little bit however when we do
multiplication and non-linear operations
uh the noise grows faster and the
problem is that if there is too much
noise and especially if the noise
reaches a limit a certain limit that in
the slides are going to be is going to
be um indicated by this horizontal red
line in thermometers then we risk to
have an incorrect decryption
um
thanks uh for us
there is a technique called the
bootstrapping that allows us to deal
with this noise growth problem
and the tfh the scheme that we're gonna
use today has a bootstrapping so the
bootstrapping of tfh is very special
as any bootstrapping it allows to reduce
the noise inside ciphertext so in
particular it takes an input what we
called an lwe ciphertext we're going to
explain um
in a few slides what it is
um there is a noisy and
by using a bootstrapping key which is an
encryption of the secret key originally
used to encrypt the x it will evaluate a
decryption circuit and produce a new
cipher text
of the type lwe as well
with less noise inside so in practice it
refreshes the ciphertext noise
and the boost tracking of tfh is even
more special because at the same time
that he reduces the noise is also able
to evaluate a lookup table
so the result is not only going to be
the same encryption of the same message
with less noise but an encryption of lo
ol of x
where l of x is the position
corresponding to x the input inside the
lookup table so the result is going to
be l of x with less noise
so this technique is actually uh and in
the in the rest of the slides we're
going to often call
this
technique pbs for programmable
bootstrapping
um before we try to understand how the
bootstrapping work let's uh um let's
check what are the ciphertext using tfhe
so first of all what is an lwe
ciphertext
well
lw ciphertext is a tuple a b where a is
a uniformly random vector and b is equal
to the inner product between this
uniformly random vector a and the secret
key
and then we have an addition of the
message rescale to a certain
to a certain delta uh and the error so
the error is generally a gaussian error
um
sampled with a certain variance and the
variance is going to be indicated in the
thermometer
um
the lw cipher texts are very nice
because they have homomorphic properties
and especially they are homomorphic with
respect to the addition and in the
general multiplication
in tfh we not only use the lwe
ciphertext but we use also two other
cipher texts
the first one is a wrinkle we cipher
text which are homomorphic with respect
to the addition and the constant
multiplication
and ring jsw cipher text which are
homomorphic with respect to addition
constant multiplication and
multiplication as well so this means
that when we have two ring adjustable
use ciphertext we can multiply them
together and the result is going to be
our ingestable ciphertext containing the
product of the messages
there is an additional operation in tfh
that is largely used which is called the
external product and it's an operation
between a ring jsw cipher text and a
wrinkle we cipher text
and the result is going to be a wrinkle
we cipher ciphertext encrypting the
product of the messages
okay so now that we saw um what are the
ciphertext in tfg let's try to
understand how the bootstrapping is done
so just to summarize what we said before
we're going to have an lwe ciphertexting
input quite noisy
we're going to take also an input a
lookup table that we want to evaluate
and the bootstrapping key that in the
case of kfc is a list of ring jsw cipher
text
we're not going to see the details
because this is not important for the
comprehension of the presentation
the output
as announced before is going to be again
an lwe ciphertext this time encrypting l
of m
with less noise
so what else what is the operation that
we evaluate during bootstrapping well we
homomorphically evaluate the decryption
algorithm of the lwe um encryption and
the decryption algorithm consists in two
major steps the first one is the
computation of b minus a times s which
by solving the equations i should show
you before uh gives us an output delta m
plus the error and the second step is a
rescaling and rounding allowing us to
retrieve the message m
so in order to better understand what is
coming next it's important that we we
visualize uh what is the lwe input so
delta m plus the error so you can always
imagine it as a list of bits where we
have the message that is put in the most
significant bits and the error that is
in the least significant bits and in
this presentation the message
is gonna um
it's gonna
get uh values between zero and p minus
one
okay so um how does the bootstrapping
work so we have a first step that is
called the modulus switching
which is a step of switching from the
modulus queue which is the original
module of ciphertext modules and a
modulo to n which means that we are
going to select
the log to n more significant bits
inside this homomorphically of the input
so what happens in practice is that by
selecting this to n
log to n more significant bits um we're
gonna preserve them as such because the
message is in the most significant bits
and if the error is not too big before
entering the bootstrapping then the
message will also be preserved after
module switching
the second step is a description of the
lookup table inside the polynomial
v modulo x n plus one
in which we're going to put the sum
redundancy so uh what does it mean it
means that
if the vector you're seeing in the slide
is
a vector representing the coefficients
of a polynomial modulo x n plus one
we're going to have a multiple
repetitions of the elements of the
lookup table so we're going to start
with many repetitions of l0 then many
repetitions of l1 and so on until lp
minus one
and then the third step is going to be
our rotation of this uh polynomial um of
the delta m plus error position well
delta m plus the error are gonna be the
result of the module switching
so we're not going to check into detail
uh this step this is performed in tfhe
by using a loop of external products
and um the final result of this
operation is a wrinkle w encryption of
the same vector rotated
and
the what happens after the rotation is
that the coefficient uh the were
associated to l of m
are gonna move to the first position of
the vector and then the last step was
going to be uh what we call a sample
extraction which consists in extracting
the first element of this polynomial
into an lw ciphertext and since so the
first element was l of m
then um is we're going to obtain an lw
encryption of l of m with less noise as
expected before
okay so the tfh boost wrapping similar
very a very powerful actually is a very
powerful tool but unfortunately has some
limitations
and the major limitation is due to the
fact that we work modular x n plus one
so in order to be more clear what
happens when we work modulo x and plus
one so we have polynomial of size n of
with n coefficients and the since the
rotation um modulus n plus 1 is of order
2n
what happens is that it exists a sort of
imaginary part
of size n as well which contains exactly
the same elements of the first part the
first n elements but with a minus if
sign in front of them
so what happened is the following see if
the most significant bit of our message
is equal to zero
during the rotation we're gonna find an
element inside the first
n coefficient so an element of v
uh and the result is gonna be exactly l
of m
however if in the the most significant
bit of the message is gonna be equal to
one
after the rotation the result is gonna
be in the let's say imaginary part and
so the result is not gonna be l of m but
minus l of m instead
so if we want to always have alabama as
a result uh we have to know the first
and most significant bit of the message
and especially in general uh we're gonna
fix this more significant beta to zero
and we're gonna try to keep it equal to
zero all the time and this is actually a
a big limitation
so in this paper what we try to do is to
overcome this limitation together with
other tfh limitations
um in the rest of the presentation uh
you're going to see our contribution so
we're going to start with uh what we
call pbs mini luto which is a technique
allowing us to evaluate several lookup
tables per bootstrapping on the same
input
then we're gonna see how to use the
bfv-like multiplication into tfh to
improve the tfh techniques
and this was especially possible thanks
to a tight noise analysis
and finally we're gonna see what we call
a wall pbs which is a pbs without a bit
of padding
which is the technique allowing us to
overcome the limitation i just described
about
the most significant bit
set to zero
so now we are going to have a look on a
new method which is called bbs miniboots
and allows us to evaluate many functions
into one single pbs
first we're going to introduce a new
tool which is called generalized
strapping
and it will act on the module switching
which is the first step of the
bootstrapping
so in the usual strapping
the first step required to shift from
ciphertext which is encoded over qubits
into ciphertext which is only encoded
over two m bits and that the frame we
obtain after this module switching
contains the most significant bits
so the idea is to add more degrees of
freedom to this step
so first
we want to choose the position of the
most significant bit which will be
retained after model switching so
for instance we define new variable
which is called kpa
and this kappa in this example is
defined to two
so in this case after module switching
this means that we have shifted from two
bits from the most significant bits and
so that if our message encrypted was
only originally defined as m prime
concatenated with m after the module
switching will only have the encryption
on n since we have shifted from two bits
we can also define a shifting which is
negative so that the kappa is negative
this means that after the modulus
switching we'll add some random bit
as the most significant one
in the frame which is retained after the
mod switching
in this example we define kappa as -1 so
this means that we want to shift from
one bit after the modulus q so that
after the mode switching we'll have
random one random bits as the most
significant bit
the second approaches uh is about
shifting from the right side but in this
case we'll define what we call a right
padding in this case the idea is to have
some bits that we will unsure to be
equal to 0 after the model switching
this is defined by the variable theta
and theta will represent the number of
bits which are equal to 0 after the
model is switching so in this example we
define theta as two so that after the
model switching the two least
significant bits are now equal to zero
we can combine with these two approaches
so that in fact this offers us the
possibility to choose the frame which
will be module switch
so with the kappa we shift from kappa
bits and with the theta we ensure that
the last theta bits will be equal to
zero so that the frame of the middle
switching is now up to our choice
the first application of this uh
generalized strapping will be in the pbs
mini leads
so just for recall in the pbs normally
we have one pbs for one loot and that at
the blend rotation state we are going to
choose the correct case of the loot
which will be evaluated meaning that we
want to obtain l of m depending on the
encryption of the message m
now if we apply the general bootstrap by
defining just the theta and theta will
be equal to one this means that we here
we represent what we obtain after
modulus switch in the plaintext version
so that the last bit will be equal to
zero and we are sure that
this offers more possibilities to encode
loots now we are able to encode two
lookup tables instead of just one as
previously
why is this possible because now we can
use the value of this list least
significant bit to select which lookup
table which will be chosen so for
instance if we say that the significant
bit is equal to zero we will select the
first lookup table so l0 so that after a
sample extract will be obtained lw
ciphertext encrypting l0 l0 of m
if the last bit is now equal to 1 then
this means that we are going to select
the first the second lookup table so
that we obtain the encryption of l1 of m
another view of the pbs magnitude is
then that using this parameter theta we
are unable to evaluate 2 to the power of
theta function
with the cost of only 1 pbs and the cost
of two to paracetamol extract however
the sample extract is almost free so
that the cost of a general spps and the
evaluation of many loots is the cost of
only one pbs
this offers the multiple instructions
single paradigm to the bbs
these methods are
however some drawbacks in fact we
require that the message are small
enough since we are restricting the less
bits after the switching to be equal to
zero
and moreover the more we increase the
value of theta the more increase the
probability of having here or after
after a pbs
so now we're gonna focus on the bfv
product
in the context of tfhe
so what is
the uh product alabia v
it's pretty simple you have two ring lw
ciphertext as input
and you compute a tensor product between
those two you end up with a larger
cipher text encrypted with a bigger
secret key
and what they do in bav
they
add this
key switch to go back to the original
secret key
so in this presentation we're gonna call
the tensor product followed by the key
switch
ring lwe product
we
had to work on the noise formula for
this operation
in order to prove that it's
possible to use it in the tfhe context
in the tfhe context we have
a small cube the the integer modulus for
the ciphertext
it means that we cannot have
really big amounts of noise so we had to
work on this formula
and we did it in a generic way meaning
we can have a different kind of secret
key distributions it can be binary
ternary gaussian or anything else as
long as
you can provide the standard deviation
and the mean of the distribution
so we were able to use that
ugly formula
and prove that we can compute some level
multiplication in tfhe
for instance we
we can see that with the message
precision of four bit we can have eight
levels of multiplication
so uh to to use it in tfhe we have to
convert uh lw ciphertext into ringlw
ciphertext indeed in tfh we mostly work
uh with messages encrypted as lw
ciphertexts so we're gonna use this key
switch
converting
our input messages m0 and m1 into
constant polynomials
uh encrypted in wrinkle w ciphertext
then we do the tensor product n key
switch
we end up with a wrinkle delay
ciphertext encrypting m0 times m1
and to go back to lwe we simply compute
the sample extraction
so now we're gonna see how this
uh bfv product in tfh can be useful to
overcome uh the legacy click property of
the programmable bootstrapping
so we're gonna start with this toy
example we consider ciphertext
encrypting this plain text with a zero
in the most significant bits
and
this lookup table l
when we do the regular programmable
bootstrapping we end up with a cyclotext
of the message l of m
if now we look
at what would happen if there was a one
in the most significant bits
we end up with minus l of m and that's
that's exactly what we want to correct
a way to do that is to compute
what we call the sign
so we use another lookup table
it's a constant lookup table
and
if we go back to this plain text with a
zero in the most significant bit we end
up with an encryption of one
if we now look at what happened with a
one in the most significant bit we end
up with a minus one
and it's easy to see that if we compute
a multiplication between
those two
we end up with what we wanted which is l
of m in both cases
so how to build this warp pbs
we start with
a ciphertext encrypting
plaintext without any bit of padding
we start with
pulling a bit
which is random because of the way we
encrypt with lwe
and we apply the little trick we just
showed you in more details
we're gonna see what it is
you start with this
ciphertext encrypting a random beta
followed by your message m
you compute two pbs's one for the lookup
table you want to evaluate and one for
the sign
and then you use the lwe multiplication
we described
and you end up with the desired message
l of m
so there are two pbs's to evaluate here
and
we see that we can
factorize them into one using the team
19 trick but there is a price here you
add a little bit of additional noise
if the message is
small enough you can use our trig pbs
many loot and also evaluate
for the price of one pbs only
those two
lookup tables
so i'm going to present another way to
achieve a programmable bootstrapping
without padding
so in the version damian just showed you
we use
the lwe multiplication to correct the
sign
of the random bit in the msb of the
message and here we use
another technique
so we still have
an encryption of a message m as input
and we want to obtain the evaluation of
lookup table l
with m
so the lookup table l is representing
in the bottom left of the screen
and so we don't want to work with this
huge table we want to work with look up
table twice
as small
so
first we are going to break apart this
lookup table into two lookup tables l0
and l1
so now we are going to see how we can
use l0 and l1
to obtain this encryption of l of m
so at the beginning we have our
encryption of the message m
and here we
call
beta the most significant bit of this
message and m prime the rest of the
message
if beta is equal to 0
and we evaluate
the lookup table l0 on m prime we obtain
the evaluation of the lookup table l on
m
and if we have
beta equals to 1
and we evaluate l1
in n prime
we will obtain
the lookup table
of m
so now how
does this work in fhe
so at the beginning we have our
ciphertext of our message m
we
and at the end we want uh to obtain the
encryption of the evaluation of the
lookup table
so first we are going to perform the pbs
with the first look up table
to obtain
the evaluation of our local table
at the sign
up to a sign
we also are going to perform a bootstrap
with the sign lookup table
as
with the first version of the bootstrap
without padding and
the bootstrapping with the second lookup
table
then we are going to add some offset to
the to the sign
and perform an lwe multiplication
and we all we do the same thing for the
second lookup table with the sign and at
the end we are going just to sum
everything
so here we use the
we use beta the msb of the message
to select uh between l0 and l1 the two
lookup tables and also to correct the
sign at the same time
as with the pre president previous
version
we have a layer of pbs so we can use
either the
sim 19 tbs trick
or the pbs menu we just introduced
and we can
as there is
two multiplication lw multiplication we
can use an lwe square
which consists of an lwe multiplication
with both input
[Music]
that are the same
and the complexity of the lwe square is
more or less the same as one of lwe
multiplication
so now we want to compare the complexity
of a classical pbs and the two version
of the bootstrap without padding we just
introduced
so we are going to look at pbs working
on pivot
message
so for a traditional pbs you will need a
pbs for p plus one
bit so p bit for the message and the
plus one is for the the row padding you
put in the most significant bit of the
message
for the first version of the bootstrap
without padding you will need two pbs
for p plus one bits
so the p is for the message and the plus
one is for the random padding
we added during the module switching
for the second version ah sorry and we
also have lwe multiplication
for the second version of the
bootstrapping without padding we need
three pbs but only for p bit because we
don't need any padding
and
two lwe multiplication and three
editions
so
we can see that the warp vs1 seems to be
always
to cost more than a
traditional pbs
but it really depends on the context
for
the comparison between waptbs
2 and a traditional pbs
what about
parallel complexity how does it
compare
so
each layer of pbs became just
one tbs and
if we have two multiplication we have
one multiplication so the interesting
take on
this slide is that the algorithm we
introduced are easily parallel
and
with the help of
parallelization the complexity
are quite
close to the one of the traditional pbs
so now it's the time to conclude this
presentation and to um so i will begin
by by summing up the contribution we
just
presented
so first of all we showed you a bf like
multiplication in tfh
then we introduced a way to evaluate
several lookup table at once with the
pbs menu mentioned
and finally we introduced two ways to
build a bootstrapping without padding
the wallpbs one and the what pbs2
if you look at the at the paper you will
find more contribution
you will find a generic entire noise
analysis of each
introduced fhc operators
you will also find a way to
build an efficient circuit bootstrap
using the pbs midi route
you will also find an efficient
algorithm
to split ciphertex in chunk
using the warp dbs
and using this
splitting in chunks you can
easily build a large precision bootstrap
and to finish we also introduced a new
approach for get bootstrapping and we
extend it to arithmetic circuits
so finally i'm going to introduce some
open problems that
still need to be solved
so first of all we need to take a look
at the fft because for the tensor
product we need a high precision fft
next we want to
experiment with hardware implementation
as
it will be easy to parallelize
everything and to play with the
precision inside the fft
we also want to find alternatives to
the bootstrapping without padding we
just showed you because of the noise
growth
in those algorithms
and to finish we want to improve
the lwe to glw keyswitch because as of
now it's a huge part of the complexity
of the warp pbs
thank you for your
listening