hello everyone my name is christiana
kuhn and i'm a phd candidate at
karlsruher institute of technology today
i'm happy to present to you our paper
onion routing with replies
this paper is joint work together with
dennis rofeins andy rob and thurston
strophen
let us first start by thinking why we
need onion routing in the first place
one goal of onion routing is to provide
relationship privacy so to hide who is
communicating with whom from the
adversary
and this is a very important goal just
imagine alice contacting a web server
that only offers information about a
specific disease
like cancer or depression
then it is highly likely that alice
suffers from this disease and
information that we much rather keep
hidden from the adversary
now if we want to realize the skill of
course alice cannot send her message
directly to the receiver because the
adversary is likely to be able to
observe this and even further we do not
trust the receiver and the receiver
might be collaborating with the
adversary
so instead we need some kind of
indirection and for this we are using
onion routing
onion routing employs multiple relays
between descendants and receivers of the
communication
and the message from the sender will be
encrypted in multiple layers
with one layer for each relay so that
once it goes to the network each relay
will peel off one layer of this packet
which is also called onion because it
consists of this many layers
now if the onion routing scheme
is working correctly then the adversary
cannot link onions
before the relay to the ones after the
relay
and this ensures that as long as one of
the relays is honest the adversary does
not know which sender was contacting
which receiver because he does not know
how the onions are linked in this case
in our example
the adversary would be able to observe
that alice is sending the grey onion and
he can even link it to the blue one
because he controls the first reeling
but then from the blue one he would have
no clue
whether the next onion is going to be
the green or the yellow one
um once the honest relay is done with
the processing so at this point
we unlink the sendness from the
receivers because the of the honest
relay and the adversary cannot
revert and link onions before and after
the honest relay
now it is really important that we get
this unlinking of the onions before and
after the honest really right and
therefore we are interested in
constructing a secure
onion routing packet format
now a packet format can only
be
preventing the linkings of onions that
are based on the packet itself of course
there are more dimensions like the
timing of the onions or traffic patterns
that are important in practice to
unlink senders and receivers but they
cannot be solved with a packet format
and instead on a foreign
and there are orthogonal measures that
can be applied but for now we are
interested in providing a secure packet
format
and solving this challenge first
for this let us look at how onion
routing packet formats typically look
like and they typically consist of a
header and the payload
the header contains the routing
information as well as key material for
the relays but the header is encrypted
in multiple layers in a clever way such
that each relay only learns the
information that is absolutely necessary
to do this one step of the path from
this one processing
the payload on the other hand is onion
encrypted
in the sense that well the first layer
will be is
there for the first relay the second
layer for the second relay and so on
so if we look at this example of the
blue onion first of all the outermost
layer of beheader is encrypted with the
public key of the first
relay so the first really can remove
this layer and sees that the onion needs
to go to the second relay
next
and the first relay will also remove one
layer of encryption from the payload
thereby it
gets the second onion the green onion
and now
the second relay will remove one layer
of encryption from the header to realize
that it has to send the onion to the
final receiver next and one layer from
the payload and thereby the encrypted
payload finally gets sent to the
receiver and the receiver can
remove the last layer of encryption to
see the included message
now one interesting thing to notice
about most onion routing packet formats
is that they protect the integrity of
the header for every hop on the path but
the payload integrity is only checked at
the final receiver
and this fact that we only check the
payload integrity at the very end
enables dangerous attack the
malleability attack
the malleability attack assumes that the
adversary controls the first relay and
the final receiver and wants to link the
sender to the receiver and thereby break
relationship privacy
the idea is that the first relay will
notice when the victim sends a message
in this case alice sends the grey
message
then the first relay notices that the
zoning consists of the header and the
payload but it will further modify the
payload and change a bit in it
um but we'll leave the header as it is
and process the onion
just as it would
process any usual onion except that now
the payload has been modified
now the next honest relay
will not notice that anything in the
onion has been modified because it only
checks the header and the check for the
header goes through
then this onion will be processed
further until it finally
is ending at the receiver and at the
receiver we can now notice that
well the message does not look like we
expect expected to there is no english
language or a typical
pattern in there but instead it's only
random bits
now this helps our adversarial receiver
to notice that this onion must have been
modified before and of course it is
highly likely that this modification
indeed was the one of our adversary that
just changed alice's message in the
beginning and therefore alice was
contacting this receiver and the
adversary learned who is communicating
with whom even though there is an honest
relay in between
now to prevent this attack for the case
where ellis just wants to send a message
to the receiver
we can simply
add some protection for the payload
because alice knows the message of the
payload she can pre-calculate how the
payload has to look like during each
part of the path and then she can
explicitly authenticate the payload with
a message authentication code and this
would lead to the fact that our honest
relay will drop the modified onion
because you can now realize that
somebody tampered with the payload and
in the result
the message of l the onion of ellis is
not being sent forward anymore and
therefore the adversary does not learn
to whom this message was actually
addressed to
now this works for the case that alice
wants to send a message to the receiver
but what happens if the receiver
actually also wants to reply
therefore we first have a look at how we
in general solve replying to an
anonymous sender
therefore we need to build repliable
onions and repliable onions in principle
look like normal onions but additionally
the sender will construct the header for
the backward path
so the
sander will pick the relays for the
backward path as well as the keys that
should be used during this backward
communication
and then this header is included in the
payload of our onion such that the
receiver then
gets to retrieve it as part of the
payload that he gets
um and now he can use the header
um together with the reply that he
actually wants to send and just has to
attach
the new payload to it
so basically the sender is already
constructing a back envelope for the
receiver even though the receiver cannot
read all the details of the
back envelope because the information of
the reply path is hidden in the header
such that only each relay learns as much
as it needs to learn to then forward the
onion until it's back at our original
sender alice
now if we want to make sure that our
onion routing scheme is actually also
secure for replies we do have one more
requirement we require that replies and
requests are indistinguishable except at
the center and receiver so any
intermediate relay dealing with a
with an onion should have no clue
whether it's a
request from the sender to the receiver
or a
backwards from the receiver to the
sender again
we do this because there might be use
cases where only very few replies exist
and then of course the set of candidates
that have sent the reply is very small
and having very small
so-called anonymity sets
is dangerous for the users because then
the attacker could do
more attacks or use additional knowledge
to exclude
users from this set so we want our
requests and replies to be
indistinguishable
however we of course additionally want
to protect the moleability attack
but if we want to protect the
malleability attack we need to make sure
that we protect the payload um for
requests from the sender to the receiver
now if we want to have this request
replying distinguishability this means
we also need to protect the payload for
reply messages
um but protecting the payload for reply
messages is actually not as easy as for
requests
because now well our center cannot
pre-calculate any message authentication
codes for it because
the sender does not know how the reply
will look like so he does not know how
the payload on the reply path has to
look like
on the other hand we can also not have
our receiver generate such
protection measures because the receiver
is not trusted in this use case so
we cannot have him
know how parts of the onion will look
like
once they are closed at the center again
because otherwise the receiver would
just wait for us to send her request to
him
and then
send his reply back and recognize his
onion even though
he never modified anything just because
he added parts to this onion that he can
then
add the
relay clues to the center
recognized again and therefore he will
know which sender
a sent to request and to which then his
reply just went
um so we can't do this um explicitly but
instead we need to find some clever way
to protect the payload and we look and
therefore we look for something like
implicit payload authentication
and we found two ways to do this and
there's two ways to implicitly
protect the payload are the basic ideas
behind our secure repliable onion
routing protocols
and the first way to do this is by using
snacks and the idea behind this is very
easy
let us just prove that everybody does
everything like they should
so the sender will prove that they
actually generated the fresh onion and
the intermediate relays will prove that
they faithfully process the onion and
the receiver will prove that they
generated a
reply on you
now of course on that this proof states
is that the onion that we just see is
either a fresh onion or a faithfully
processed onion or a reply onion
now of course we cannot only trust in
this single step being right but we need
to make sure that we actually build an
authentication chain until back at the
very center so we do not only show that
um the onion that we just see is the
um result of a faithful processing of an
onion
but we will show that it is the result
of the faithfully processing of
an either already faithfully processed
onion or fresh onion or a fresh reply
onion so that we can always be sure that
our authentication chain goes all the
way back until the center in this case
now how we actually do this and make
sure that we link this proofs is a bit
more involved which is why i would
kindly refer you to have a look into our
paper for more details
but what i want to tell you now is the
second way of how we can realize
implicit payload authentication for
onion routing and it is by using
updatable encryption
updatable encryption originally comes
from a very different setting it's
actually about um databases and cloud
service so the idea is that you store
your data of course encrypted at some
cloud server and now you want to change
your key
so you want to update all the source
cipher text from a node to a new key and
of course you would like to do this in
an efficient way so you don't want to
really resend all the cipher text but
instead
and this is what updateable encryption
does
you generate an update token such that
then
the cloud database can update decipher
texts on their own without learning any
information about the including plain
text or the used keys
and now there is one more very
interesting property that is
updated that some updateable encryption
schemes have and it is plain text
integrity
plain text integrity says that
well an adversary is not able to
generate a cipher text
that decrypts to a message
unless he trivially knows about this
before so of course he trivially knows
all the ciphertexts that were in the
cloud server
but other than that he cannot come up
with new cipher texts that actually
decrypt two messages
um with our um
with a non-negligible probability and
this is really interesting for us
because this means um he cannot tamper
with our payload
and we use this
in the this way for onion routing so in
a very uh different setting than the one
it's
originally been proposed for and we use
um updatable encryption in the sense
that we applied to the payload and our
payload needs to be updated with update
tokens at every relay
and as soon as it was modified the
update will fail because of the
plaintext integrity property
so let us have a look at this in a bit
more detail first of all our sender that
we trust generates all the keys and
tokens and of course knows all of them
then she starts by encrypting her
message with the first key using the
updatable encryption encryption function
um
and she sends this as the payload of the
onion and includes the update tokens and
the header of the onion
but only in a way such that each relay
only gets to see one of the update
tokens so the first relay will get the
first update token
the first relay will
use the update function of updateable
encryption and update the plane to
update the payload from key one to p2
now sadly this relay is adversarial so
the adversary knows that the gray and
the blue onion actually belong together
but now there's an honest relay and the
honest really also gets an update token
that only dishonest relay can see so the
adversary does not know this token um
and that's the important thing now the
honest really of course updates um the
payload again
and the adversary does not know that
this green onion is the outcome of the
blue onion it could also be
any other onion that he observes at this
relay at the same time
because
he does not know the update token that
if another update token would have been
used the other onion another onion would
have been the outcome
now we continue this way until the onion
arrives at the receiver and for the
receiver we want him to be able to
decrypt the message so we have to tell
him the fourth key
but nothing more than this with this he
can decrypt the message and he will not
notice that this key four actually also
belongs to key2 earlier
because he does not know the second
update token
additionally we give the first to the
first key
for on the reply path to the adversary
so that he can
um on so that he can use the updated
encryption function to encrypt his reply
as well and of course we include the
update tokens for all the relays uh
again in the backward header in a way
such that the adversary does not learn
them or at least not the ones of the
honest relays
and again
um
he will
be
sending his onion and with the payload
encrypted under the first backwards key
and the other onions will
always update the backwards key to the
other keys that alice has chosen but at
the point of the honest relay the chain
that the adversary can follow breaks
again because he does not know the
second update token for the backwards
path
and therefore he cannot link it over
this honest relay which is exactly what
we wanted
now if the adversary decides to modify
the message before the honest uh relay
pay the plaintext integrity guarantees
that the honest relay realizes and the
updating of the payload will simply fail
and the onion will be dropped at the
honest relay if he decides to modify
after the honest relay it is not much
use for him anyways because then he just
does not get the request but also
doesn't learn anything from it
now of course we need to ensure that we
did not include any other ways to link
onions before and after the honest relay
based on other attacks than the
malleability attack
and we do this in our paper but
technically it's very similar to earlier
work so there has been earlier work
that does not support replies as well as
concurrent work that does support
replies that does support replies but is
not secure against our malleability
attack so we indeed propose reusable
security properties that now are
protecting against emolliability attack
and support replies
and we do this technically very similar
to what has been done before by
proposing an ideal functionality in the
uc framework and then deriving game
based properties from this functionality
and finally of course we prove that our
protocols achieve these game-based
properties
but if you're interested in details i
would refer you to our paper for now i
want to summarize the talk so we have
learned about onion routings of the
dangers of the moleability attack
for the relationship privacy
we also learned that preventing the
malleability attack and at the same time
protecting replies in the sense that we
want that replies and requests are
indistinguishable is a challenging task
because it requires us
to
find a way to implicitly authenticate
the payload
um
which is a challenging task but we found
two ways to do this and the first way is
by using snags and proving that every
relay and every sender and receiver
actually
did the processing correctly
and the second way is by using the plain
text integrity property of updateable
encryption and thereby applying
updateable encryption in a completely
new setting where it hasn't been applied
before
and with this i would like to thank you
for your attention
and of course invite you to have a look
into our paper for more details