hello everyone my name is taiga hiroka
in this talk i talk about contaminant
encryption without admission represented
public key attribute-based and classical
communication
this work is going to work
first remy explains the prior work
secretary key encryption with
authorization was introduced by
broadband and islam
in tcc 2020
in this prim tip there is a thought
hydration security in addition to the
functionality of significant encryption
this content primitive works as horrors
first a sender generates a classical
secret key
then she generates a quantum ciphertext
and sends it to the receiver
if he receives a secret key
he can detect the ciphertext by running
a decoding algorithm on them
on the other hand
after she sends a quantum ciphertext she
can check whether he there is a quantum
cipher text correctly
if she wants to derive the quantum
psychotics she requests him till there
is a psychotics
after that she receives a classical
certificate which guarantees that
she deletes the ciphertext
then she checks whether this certificate
is correct or not using secret key
when correct even if he receives a
secret key
he cannot obtain the information message
m correctly
in gtb this is what certification
security guarantees
muah homari satellite duration security
is defined by the security game
between the challenger and adversary
first the challenger given the secret
key
anniversary generates two messages
and sends them to the challenger
the challenger decides bit b and
generates the ciphertext for the message
m b
and sends it to the adversary
the adversary generates a classical
certificate and sends it to the
challenger
the challenger runs verification
algorithm on them
and that puts top or about
the battery receives the secret key
and outputs b prime
we say that the encryption scheme is
that hydration secure if it satisfies
this inequality
where this stop means that the
challenger out could talk
this is what saturation security
guarantees
we mark that
this functionality is classically
impossible
in other words if the cipher attacks is
classical it cannot achieve such
hydration security
this is because adversary can copy the
classical ciphertext
they construct this prim tip using bb-84
states
for the ease of explanation i explain
the construction where the sender sends
only whole qubits
first season is a random classical bit
string as a secret key
after that she randomly generates a
computational basis quantum state as
horus
then
she operates at the mouth gate on them
according to this crosscarpet string
after that she encrypts the message n
using the information of bit values of
computation basis
state where
it is a hash function
and this cell corresponds to this zero
and this one corresponds to this one
are the quantum cipher texts of the
construction
then she sends them to the receiver
we remark that if the receiver has a
secret key
he can obtain the message m correctly
this is because the secret key is
information of basis of these quantum
states
therefore he can obtain 0 and 1 by
measuring these quantum states in the
computational basis
but he can decrypt m by computing h of
zero and one
on the other hand if she changes her
mind and the there is a cipher takes c
request to him to measure all these
quantum states in damage basis
the next receiver measures all these
quantum states in the domain basis and
obtains the cross-cut bit string
where rr random classical bit
then the receiver sends them to the
sender
then she checks whether this certificate
is correct or not using secret key
when this certificate is correct even if
he receives a secret key
he cannot obtain the message m correctly
this is because he has to measure all
these quantum states in the normal basis
in order to make her accept with the
high probability
since even the unbounded malicious
receiver cannot distinguish the basis of
these quantum states if he measures the
computational basis state in the demand
basis
this quantum state collapses to the
random classical bit and he can no
longer obtain the bit values of
computation basis state
their construction has disadvantages as
horrors
first their construction is limited to
the setting of one time secret game
encryption
which means that one needs a same secret
key to run the encounter with algorithm
and to run the decoding algorithm
and the key cannot be reused
it is problematic in some cases
second in the construction
the sender needs quantum operations
third in the construction duration is
privately believable
which means that the sender needs a
verification key kept secret
in their construction
if the verification key is revealed the
merchant's receiver can obtain both the
correct certificate
and the message
in our work we have improved these
disadvantages
as horrors
more homely results of our work are the
followings
first we have constructed public
encryption without hydration from
industry secure public encryption and
one-time secretary encryption without
violation
second we have constructed
attribute-based encryption with
satellite vision
assuming the existence of post-quantum
indistinguishability obviation
and one-way function
and one-time secret communication with
certification
third we have constructed public
encryption without hydration that uses
only classical communication
this is constructed from industrial
secure public encryption and the
assumption that running with errors
problem cannot be solved efficiently by
a quantum computer
this construction is secure in the
contaminated model
course we have constructed public
encryption with publicly buildable
satisfaction
that uses only classical communication
this is constructed from one shot
signature and extractable witness
encryption
but for the time constraints in this
talk i talk about this
and this
first i talk about public encryption
with such hydration
we have constructed public encryption
with satellite duration using public key
encryption and secret key encryption
with statistics as a building block in a
black spokes way
but for the ease of explanation i will
explain specific construction
idea of our construction is very
standard
to encrypt the secret key
using
public key encryption
first
a sender receives a public key
and generates a secret key
which is same as this secret key
then using this secret key she generates
a quantum ciphertext
at the same time she also encrypts this
secret key using public encryption
these are the ciphertexts of a
construction
then she sends them to the
receiver note that at this point if the
receiver has or obtained the secret key
he can't get the message n correctly
this can be done by decrypting this
ciphertext using secret key or public
key encryption
and using this secret key on this cipher
text he can put a message m correctly
on the other hand if she changes her
mind and wants to drill the ciphertext
she requests to him to there is a
quantum ciphertext
and she receives a classical certificate
which guarantees that the receiver needs
a ciphertext
then the sender checks whether this
certificate is correct or not using this
secret key
when the certificate is correct
even if he receives a secret key of
public encryption
he got obtained the message aimed
correctly
i explained the injected proof
because the secretary of state
encryption with such hydration is
encrypted by public encryption
this ciphertext uses for the receiver
therefore in order to make her accept
with a high probability with a high
probability
the receiver has to measure all these
quantum states in the demand basis
on the other hand once he measures the
computational basis state in that mod
basis he cannot obtain the beat barriers
of computational basis state
even if he receives a secret key on
public encryption after he met this
quantum state
therefore our construction is also
secure
this is an intuitive understanding of
our security
but for the homework proof we have to
construct a protocol
using receiver non-committing encryption
instead of public encryption
technically this is the most important
for work of public encryption without
hydration but for the ease of
explanation i skipped the whole proof
if you are interested in the hormone
proof please read our paper
now i finish the first part
then eyes are the second part there is
saturation with classical communication
in the third hydration explained so far
the sender needs quantum operations
in this work
we have improved the disadvantage and
have constructed certification that uses
only classical communication
in this work we have used noisy traffic
quality functions f and injective
trapped function d and public encryption
to construct a protocol
these functions are constructed from
reliable assumption and have some
cryptographic properties
using these properties a classical
sender can generate a quantum state in a
receiver's register
in another shell
idea of a construction is to use f-type
function
and g-type function
instead of directly sending
deviator states with quantum channel
first i explain how to use
nodegeotropically functions f to
generate a quantum state
a classical sender fast generator
trapdoor and noisy dropped across the
functions f and sends it to receiver
then the receiver generates a
superposition state and coherently
evaluates echo bags
since noisy drop to quality functions f
is 2 to 1
if he measures the third register in the
computational basis he obtains this
quantum state
where f of 0x0 and a hover one x1 as
measurement outcome y
if he measures this quantum state in the
computational basis this quantum state
collapses to the classical bit string
0x0 or 1x1
on the other hand if he measures this
quantum state in the demand basis this
quantum state crosses
to random classical bit string e and d
where e and d satisfies the following
equation
intuitively
once the receiver measures this quantum
state in the computational basis the
quantum state crosses to zero or zero
zero or one x one
therefore he can no longer obtain e and
d that satisfies this equation
this intuitive is formulated as adaptive
hydrocarbite property
which guarantees that the quantum
polynomial time receiver cannot obtain
both
this
and this at the same time with a
probability more than one half
and the adaptive helicopter property can
be amplified as proven in these papers
next i explain how to use injective
traptor function d
injective trapped function g is
constructed from readable assumption and
has some cryptographic properties
write knowledge of docu functions f
a classical sender candidate quantum
state in the receiver's register
first
the classical standard in
and function g and sends it to the
receiver
note that from the property of injective
invariance of the function g
the quantum polynomial time receiver
cannot distinguish
the function g from function f
this property is very important for
construction of sate hydration
and then
he generates a superposition state
and coherently evaluates g of x
since a function g is injected if he
measures the third register in the
computational basis
the sender obtains this quantum state
where g of b and x is equal to
measurement outcome y
if he measures the quantum state in the
computational basis this quantum state
corrupts this to the classical big
string b and x
on the other hand if he measures this
quantum state in the damage basis
then this quantum state prophecies to
the random classical bitching r
now i will explain our construction
again
in another shell idea of a construction
is to generate quantum state using
f-type functions and g-type functions
instead of
directly sending bb-8 whole states with
quantum channel
our construction is as well
first a classical sender receives public
key
and then generates a classical bit
string
where zero denotes the g-type function
and one denotes the f-type function
next she generates g-type functions and
f-type functions according to this
classical bit string
at the same time the sender generates a
trapdoor
now she sends the functions to the
receiver
the receiver receives the functions and
generates these quantum states in his
register
remember that in order to generate these
quantum states the receiver measures a
third register in the computational
basis
the receiver sends the measurement
outcomes to the sender
at this point she can know the post
measurement content state
using top door
on the other hand the receiver does not
know the post measurement quantum states
therefore this process is as if c
primary generates the quantum state
in the receiver's register without
quantum channel
then she can enter the message m
using the increments of b1 and x1
as horrors
where h is a hash function there is
other quantum random oracle
at the same time she increased the
location of functions using
the public key
then sends them to the receiver
these are the ciphertexts of our
construction
now
i check a construction satisfies the
correctness
if the receiver has a secret key
he jump the location function by using
this secret key
and this ciphertext this ciphertext
by measuring this content state in the
computational basis he jumped a v1 x1
correctly
therefore he jumped in m by computing h
of b1 x1
then
explain how the deletion algorithm works
after she sends the ciphertext
if she changes her mind and wants to
delete the ciphertext syllabus receiver
to measure all these quantum states in
the damage basis
and send the measurement outcomes to the
sender
where r is a random classical a bit
and each e and d satisfies the following
equation
and then she checks whether each end
satisfies this occasion using drop door
when yes
even if he receives a secret key on
public encryption
he cannot obtain the information message
m correctly
now i will explain intuitive proof of
our security
in our work to improve the security we
have introduced a new property of the
noisy drop tropical functions which we
call the
carton cheese adaptive hardcore property
intuitively catalan cheese adaptive
hardcore core property guarantees that
the content polynomial time receiver
cannot obtain
this that satisfy this occasion and this
at the same time
if you admit the captain to adaptive
hardcore property we can prove the
security of our construction in the
quantum random oracle model
because this cipher text is encrypted
using public encryption
this is useless for the adversary
on the other hand from the content is
satisfies this in this equation
he cannot obtain b1 and x1
because
h
is random moroccan
if he cannot obtain v1 and x1
he cannot obtain the information of
plaintext m
therefore a construction is secure if
you admit the carton choose adaptive
hardcore property
finally i will explain the intuitive
reason why our cartoon choose adaptive
hardcore property holds
in order to obtain emd
that satisfy this occasion he has to
measure these two quantum states in the
demand basis
on the other hand he cannot distinguish
these quantum states from this quantum
state
therefore in order to obtain this ent
he needs to measure all these quantum
states in the normal basis
on the other hand
if he measures this quantum state in the
normal basis this quantum state
collapses to the random classical bit
string
therefore he can no longer obtain b1 and
x1
this is an intuitive proof of our
capital and choose adaptive hardcore
property
in this talk i explained an intuitive
understanding of our results by showing
the concrete construction without
details
if you are interested in more formal
results please read our paper
then i finish my talk
thank you for your attention