a good number
of 35s
so welcome everybody to the mpc session
of asia crypt 2021
once again online but close your hearts
and i'm your co-chair
bernardo david and my other coach here
is sophia kubov
maybe you can introduce yourself sofia
i think you did a great job introducing
me i'm sophia
good so let's get started with the first
talk which will be
on homomorphic secret sharing for
multipartite and general adversary
structures supporting parallel
evaluation of low degree polynomials
and rio riguchi will be giving the talk
for us uh please
share your screen and go ahead
okay or can you hear this slide
yes we can see your screen and hear you
just fine okay uh thank you for
introduction uh my name is raygucci
today i talk about the paper titled
homomorphic secret sharing for
multipathetic and general advantage
structures supporting a parallel
evaluation of low degree polynomials
this is a joint work with koji nuita
secret sharing um uh is an important
building block for a multi-party
computation um as in standard secret
sharing it has a sharing algorithm which
takes a secret access input and outputs
and shares then the privacy requirement
is specified by the adversary structure
delta which is the collection of subsets
a such that the shares in a reveals no
information on the secret x
homomorphic secret sharing has
additional algorithms called evaluation
and decryption algorithms i suppose that
any input players generate m shares from
their private inputs and send them to m
servers
then each server locally runs the
evaluation algorithm on function f and n
shares it receives
finally an output player collects all
the outputs of the validation algorithms
from servers and run the decryption
algorithm
whose output is supposed to be a value
of the function f
in this work uh we consider three kinds
of adversary structures the
the first the simplest case is the
threshold advances fracture which um
which tolerates any collision of that
most t servers
on the other hand the most general case
is a general adversary structure which
has no limitation on the adversary
structure delta
finally a multi-party adversary
structure lies between threshold and
general adversity structures
specifically
suppose that the subset of m servers is
partitioned into l parts p1 to pl
roughly speaking in a multiparted bus
structure uh whether a subsidy x is in
delta or not is uniquely determined by
this vector which comes which counts the
number of servers in each part
then multiplied advanced structures
include various kinds of non-threshold
adverse structures such as weighted
threshold a hierarchical and
compartmented advanced structures and so
on
there are several homophobic secret
sharing schemes for computing
polynomials um
of degree d at most p
first information theoretically secure
schemes have been proposed for a
threshold of multiparted and general
advanced structures
however their adverse restrictions must
satisfy a condition called a type 2d
which puts a strong limit on adversaries
corruption power
on the other hand there is the most
powerful homomorphic secret sharing
scheme tolerating the maximum corruption
threshold however it must assume a
narrow class of cryptographic
assumptions
related to lattices
recently
two schemes have been proposed which lie
between these uh two extreme cases
uh first they can be obtained from uh
moderate assumption of homophobic
encryption for a degree k polynomials
second and they can tolerate um
wider class of adversary structures than
type qd um the the condition um they can
they must satisfy is uh called type qdk
for example in the threshold case a type
qdk means the threshold is k plus 1
times larger than the upper bound of
type 2d
our work also follows that direction of
research
first based on homomorphic encryption we
propose a novel moving secret sharing
scheme for multipath adversary
structures of type qdk
the share size of our scheme is only
polynomial in the number of servers so
our scheme is more efficient than the
previously known general construction
whose share size is exponentially now
so furthermore our scheme can tolerate a
multiplied advanced structure so it is
more general than the threshold
scheme in addition we also show that the
these homophobic secret sharing schemes
can be extended to homomorphic secret
sharing for symlody operation which
means that they can compute a single
polynomial on l different inputs
simultaneously
and the overhead in our share size is
only logarithmic in l so it is um
more efficient than the naive solution
of simply running l computations
independently which results in overhead
proportional to l
as a drawback however our the adversary
structure of our scheme must satisfy a
stronger condition which we call type qd
kl
but it is still wider than the
information theoretic bound of type qd
technically we use the notion of packed
secret sharing scheme for example um the
previous scheme can tolerate the general
advanced structure but does not support
power evaluation on the other hand the
pack the
share size of practice secret sharing
scheme is only logarithmic in
the number of evaluations however it you
can only tolerate a threshold advanced
structure in this work we propose a
novel way to combine these two schemes
and as a result we obtain a homomorphic
secret sharing which not only tolerates
general adverse structures but also
achieve share size logarithmic in the
number evaluations
at this is the end of my talk uh please
see here for the details that's all
thank you
thanks rio for a doc
do we have any questions please remember
you can ask questions on zulip on the
link that gavin posted on the chat here
or feel free to unmute and ask your
questions on zoom right now
so there doesn't seem to be anything on
zulip
yeah
uh so let's thank uh rio again uh for a
start and
i'd like to
to
ask one uh one question here you
mentioned that there were previous
constructions based on strong and
stronger
um
assumptions
and then
and then now you have a weaker
type qdkl class but you can get security
assuming k
uh
homomorphic encryption what class of
assumptions can you build that uh
primitive from
oh uh
um
our scheme can be obtained from um any
homophobic encryption scheme so uh
homophobic secret sharing a harmonic
encryption can be obtained from um
several cryptographic assumptions such
as um
um defeat helmand and in addition to all
lattice lattices
um
yeah okay
so it generalizes to both lattice-based
and number theoretical uh assumption
classes that's uh that's interesting
um do you have anyone has any other
questions
so if you have any further questions you
can always use zulip and i would ask all
of the presenters to keep an eye there
and answer anything that might come up
later let's uh proceed to the next
presentation thanks again rayo uh i
would like to proceed now to the
presentation on improved single round
secure multiplication using regenerating
a paper by mark ospal ronald kramer ivan
dungo daniele escudero
and ciao ping shin and daniel will be
presenting for us
please share your screen and you're
welcome to start anytime you want
yeah hello thank you so much for the
introduction so you all hear me fine
correct
yes we can hear you
okay perfect thank you
so thank you for the introduction
bernardo uh as you mentioned my name is
is is danielle and i'm going to talk
about
this paper with markup spell runner
crammer even dan guard and chopin ching
so
first let me
mention what our setting is we have a
multi-party computation with n parties
we have
we label them by p1 or 2pm
and we assume that we have two
corruptions where
n is going to be to t plus one so is the
honest majority setting with the maximum
corruption threshold
and we are going to use a brackets with
a subscript d to denote basically linear
sequential scheme
with threshold d
and
the problem that we're considering this
work
is basically secure multiplication so
given two secret share the inputs x and
y
how to obtain shares of the product x
and y
and this is an example of a very typical
multiplication protocol if you have a
shared triple a b and the product of a b
where a and b are random
then the practice could execute the
following so basically
take the shares of x subtract a and then
they obtain
some value d similarly they obtain some
value e by max masking y and then
they're going to reconstruct
these values d and these values e and
then they take certain a fine
combination that can be checked the
results in the shares of the product but
the point is that they need to
reconstruct in this process
so
for the reconstruction they have two
options
so one can be that
all parties send shares to each other
but in this case the communication
complexity will be quadratic in the
number of parts because everyone talks
to everyone
but the good thing is that it will have
only one round
and on the other hand if
all parties instead send shares to one
single party that's a p1 this party
reconstructs a secret and then sends the
result back then the communication
complexity will be linear now but it
will have two rounds
so the question that we explored is
whether or not we can achieve secure
multiplication using only one round
with a communication complexity that is
strictly better than n squared
and unfortunately we cannot give a full
answer we cannot either provide a an
impossibility result because like the
problem actually seems quite challenging
if you need openings during the
multiplication protocol then it's true
that you will go to n square but maybe
there are other approaches
that will get you seven square
but
we have a partial result towards this
which is
that there exists a protocol to securely
evaluate not one secure multiplication
band but many secure multiplications or
at least a batch of them that depends on
the number of party
where the communication complexity of
each one of those multiplications like
when you one more ties or divided by the
number of multiplications
it is sub n square
in
the detroit communication becomes a
seventh square
so
as a
bonus of our purple also works for galwa
rings which are generalization of finite
fields and also integers modulo powers
of a prime
and another interesting thing is that we
are
confusing at the first work making use
of regenerating codes in the context of
npc explicitly so these tools are very
useful or
seem very useful for helping
optimizing reconstruction but it was
quite hard to find out like a concrete
application for them
so just to give you an idea about how
this result is obtained
consider
the existence of regenerating codes
studied in this work by griswami and
voters in stock 2016.
so if we have this result say that we
have a shared value x
basically you can find linear functions
that take big vectors or big values and
turn it into small values
and certain scalars such that this
linear combination here when you take
all these compressed shares and multiply
them by their scalars then you're going
to reconstruct the sequence so basically
you can reconstruct the secret by
sending smaller shares
so if you want to reconstruct the share
value x in one round
you can instead of using the full shares
you can use the small shares
and compute the upper linear combination
and now the communication complexity
will be n squared but
if you count the number of elements in
terms of the elements in f2 then
basically this brings you down to
sub-linear and square but this is just
the start of the story
several problems will appear so i'm just
gonna close over them very quickly but
at least give you the idea of some of
the challenges
so the first challenge is that
you definitely don't want to have
multiplication or lifted to the end
because uh
in the previous slide i had that m is
about log n so this structure is going
to grow with the number of parties and
you would like to have something that
that is constant for the computation and
for this we can use reverse
multiplication friendly bearings in 30
user crypto 18.
but
doing this naively will not work because
the techniques from this work that i
just cited ccxy18 will not work in our
setting because it will add an extra
round
so in our paper we introduce a novel
encoding mechanism that also might be an
independent interest
that will improve this paper in several
aspects including reducing this extra
round
also we have problems with active
adversaries and we also show how to
address this using the pre-processing
from turbospeeds but instead of using
for communication improvements we use it
for security purposes i'm not giving
details of course i encourage you to go
and check the paper and the full video
to to see how this is done
and finally uh
rmf is over galwa rings because
everything i have said so far is for
fine and fuel so rmf's over colorings we
do have them they do exist
but we generalize the theory of
regenerating codes to this setting
and we actually give a new
characterization of the concept of
repairability in terms of the dual code
the previous characterizations did not
um
did not have these press this
did not look like this
and then we give concrete instantiations
over colorings which is the case of
interest for us
and that would be my five minute stop
thank you
thanks for the talk danielle uh do we
have any questions i don't see anything
on zulip yet uh if anyone would like to
ask a question by audio please go ahead
i see a
raised hand here from sofia or
instead of clapping
it's a clapping hand oh nice thank you
thank you so
i actually have a question i i i see
that clearly it's a more theoretically
oriented result and quite an interesting
one but uh is there any hope that the
constants hidden in all of the
asymptotic notation are actually nice
enough that we could apply these
techniques to concrete settings or uh is
it still in a in a purely theoretical
setting
so this question in terms of in terms of
constants the constants are actually
quite nice like when you see this thing
here the constants that will appear here
basically come from
the rmf the reverse multiplication from
anybody we use and the overhead of this
thing will be something like between
four and five so
i mean it's it's not really that bad
what i think is not that
practical is that i mean this is sub n
square but but in reality is this number
here which is n squared divided by log n
so i think
we break the barrier of the n squared
but if you have two protocols one takes
two rounds and it's linear communication
complexity one the other one takes one
round and it's almost quadratic it's
soft quadratic but almost quadratic so
it's probably more efficient to use the
linear one but we hope that we can keep
studying this problem and bring down the
complexity of one round multiplication
hopefully to linear although i have no
idea how to achieve this so i think this
is a very interesting result because it
breaks the career but i don't know how
to get it more efficient
well thanks for the answer and let's
thanks danielle again for his
presentation
we'll now proceed to the next
presentation on garbling stacked and
staggered faster k out of van garbled
function evaluation a paper by david
heath vlad kolezenkov and stanislav
piccini i guess it is stanislav who is
presenting for us
please go ahead and share a screen and
feel free to start your presentation
thanks for the introduction uh can you
hear me and
see my screen
yes we can hear you just fine and see
your screen
perfect so thank you again uh i will
talk about our paper garbling stock and
staggered faster chaotic and carbon
function evaluation
and this is going to work with david
heath and bart kolesnikov and we work at
georgia tech
so now consider a server and this server
offers a suite of services to clients
and
suppose that these services have privacy
concerns for both the server and the
client
and as an example suppose that a
telehealth company offers services that
screen concern patients for a variety of
medical conditions represented as
function zero through n minus one
and
the patient may apriori know that a
number of medical conditions are
unlikely to be the source of her
symptoms so the patient may only wish to
be screened for
k health conditions out of the possible
end
so the patient really wants to evaluate
k out of n public functions to which the
patient has some private inputs
so i emphasize that the patient knows
which k functions she wants to evaluate
and in this talk i present our chaotic
construction and this construction use a
concrete improvement over the
state-of-the-art constructions
so the construction is garbage circuit
based
and
i repeat that in our construction
alice's k-choices are known to her
i will start by presenting why a naive
garbage circuit solution to the chaotic
problem is not satisfactory
and an important point is that the
garbler should not know
nor learn which case circuits alice will
evaluate so he garbles all n circuits
compiles them into a single string and
sends the string across the wire to
alice and
i emphasize the descending of the
circuit guard buildings which i will
refer to as the material is expensive
in fact
this process of sending the material is
traditionally considered the most
expensive part of the garbage circuit
protocol
but in crypto 2020 david heath and vodka
listening off introduce dark garbling
which reduces precisely this bandwidth
consumption for one out of n circuits
and this work showed that it is not
necessary to send a garble link for each
of the n circuits
in fact it's a physicist to send a
single material of length equal to the
single longest garbling among the n
circuits
and while it is communication that has
been traditionally viewed as the garbage
circuit bottleneck start garbling really
changed the status quo and
garbling itself consumes significant
computational resources
and in many settings it is now
computation that becomes the bottleneck
so the start garbling technique can be
generalized generalized to arbitrary k
and while the communication improvement
is preserved that is the communication
cost is proportional to k rather than n
naively extending this technique to k
out of n circuit incurs factor k
increase in computation
so meaning the computation grows with k
so there seems to be an inherent
trade-off between computation and
communication with the current
techniques so stat karbelling reduces
communication consumption but it also
increases computation consumption and
this trade-off forces us to choose
between either communication and
computation which is not desirable so in
our work we ask whether we can have the
best of both worlds
that is can we pay communication only
for k materials and still incur
computation on the order of n and we
answer in the affirmative
and central to our idea is the fact that
material is viewed differently in each
technique
so in the garbage circuit traditionally
material was viewed as a collection of
encrypted truth tables
the key idea of star garbling was that
the material should instead be viewed as
a bit string and this idea enabled to
manage these materials with natural
operations such as bitwise xor and we
take this idea further and instead view
the material as an element in a large
color field and as a result we can
perform linear algebraic operations on
the material
so i will now
very briefly present the three
constructions at a high level and on a
small example where n equals 3 and k
equals 2. so again in the hour
scarborough circuit the guardball
garbage all three circuits concatenates
them into one string and sends the
string across the wire to alice
in start garbling instead of sending m0
m1 and m2 separately the gabriel adds
these three values together using xor
and here is where we have one in terms
of communication because we do not send
m0 and one and m2 separately but instead
send their sum and then importantly
alice needs to be able to unstack the
taken materials star garbling describes
how this can be securely and efficiently
achieved
uh i will not get into it at this moment
but since k equals two we need two
stacks so note that the material in
stock one
uh
those materials are different from those
in stack zero although they represent
the same functions and this is exactly
where the computation costs proportional
to k times and garblings comes in as new
materials are needed for each of the
case steps instead
we would like to reuse the same end
materials across the stacks which is
precisely what we achieve in our stack
and staggered construction
and in this slide i showed the two
stacks in our stack and staggered
construction note that m0 and one and m2
are same across the stacks that is there
is a total of n materials and while
stack zero is the same as in the start
garbling approach the materials in stack
one are multiplied by hours powers of
two before they're added together and
now it should be believable that this
multiplication provides some additional
information that will enable alice to
bit by bit and stack the taken materials
and since we view the materials as
elements in a galois field we can
multiply them by these different powers
of two which simply adds zeros and
shifts each material within the stack
this means we can pick our linear
algebraic operation such that everything
can be implemented with simple bitwise
xor
and hence we obtain high performance we
shift
we simply shift each material and xor it
into a stack
and these simple stacking operations are
far cheaper than the garbeling
operations as a result we obtain
performance that matches computation of
the standard javascript circuit approach
and communication of start garbling
and in summary so the key contribution
is that we improve garbage circuit
evaluation of k out of n functions where
the k choices are known to the garbage
circuit evaluator
we retained the start goblin
communication complexity
while simultaneously retained the
computation complexity of standard
garbage circuit approach
and thank you for listening and i'm
happy to answer any questions
thanks for our presentation stan uh if
anyone has any questions uh i would ask
you to actually put it on zulip because
we are almost out of time for this lot
so
uh i will actually ask that we proceed
to the next
presentation and then
please leave your questions on zulip and
i'll ask stan to also watch tulip and
answer anything that might come up
our next presentation
is on
better security efficiency trade-offs in
permutation-based two-party computation
a paper by yulon chen and stefano tesaro
and the presentation will be given by
you
so please
share your screen and start the
presentation when you're ready you
hello so can you see the slide
uh no we can see your face but
sorry
let me try it again
um
okay
now i hope that's uh you can see the
slice yes we can see your slices okay
thank you so this joint works with
stefano de sado
so as you already heard from the last
three
presentations that muti party
computation is one of the hottest topic
at this moment but do you also know that
um protocols such as ot extension
schemes and double circuit actually make
have heavy use of symmetry key
primitives
so that means this talk is actually more
about the primitives that are actually
used in the protocol instead of the
protocols itself
um so actually one of the common
denominator in those protocols is
actually a special form of hash
functions and this type of hash
functions is an often remodeled as a
random oracle but um
also um yeah i used to hash 128 bit
streams
that means that
the traditional three hash function is
too large
for this type of applications
because sha 3 has a large state size it
will lead to low performance
and that's the reason why currently
construction is based on fixed key
are used to improve the performance
however the big problem here is that
many of the existing protocols actually
use
an inefficient and sometimes even
insecure hash functions so the fact that
those insecure hash functions are used
means that um
the protocols just
yeah don't
get the
claim to security so that means
protocols will be insecure with those
insecure hash functions
so and besides
there are several notions needed for
different types of protocols
and that makes that we need different
constructions in order to satisfy
stronger version of notions
maybe one explanation about why this
problem is hard what we want here is
something that's called coloration
robustness but that means um yeah you
can find it back in the full version of
the presentation
on youtube so keep in mind that we are
dealing with something that's called a
hash function so hash function means
that no destinated secret key inputs
that
means that here the only randomness
comes together with the message inputs
and there's nothing we can change about
it and we can not just obtain this type
of hash function under traditional
symmetry key primitives such as two
global blocks
this problem is however related to a
classical
symmetry key problem which is a related
key security for xor
so um the first
security call and um quick ball
correlation replacement hash function
was actually this triple mmo
construction proposed in smp in um by
goal at all in
last year so we can see that
construction makes
two permutation calls to uh object um
for public permutation and then we can
see that the security achieved by this
um transaction is
this type of typical birthday bonds of
security which um p is the number of the
evaluation to the underlying primitive
um
permutation and q is the number of
evaluations to the entire construction
and um the
problem here is that this construction
so this um yeah it was shown by this um
one of the follow-up work by the same
elders or more or less the same elders
and it's crypto loss here
and the security achieved by this
construction is actually inefficient
when the newly used security is
considered reason their voice that's mp
is usually a very large number and now
the fact that we considered new the user
case cubic
also become large so while the second
term is still not so important for the
practical applications the the first
term is very um yeah i would say
it will be very painful for the um for
the practical applications due to the
mute using skill and setting
so the authors also introduce the
following construction which just make
one call to an ideal cipher here this
street t serves us um
the inputs key for this i o cipher we
can see this is a bond that i choose by
this construction and here b is actually
the number of um
and the
construction queries per um
of percent reach it's this b you just
need to remember that b is usually a
very small number for d and scalable
circuits and yeah because this
change and this sphere depends the
construction is very and provides
sufficient security for the user setting
but the
limitation of the construction is that
this
transformation makes uh assumption that
ideal cypher
and exists in practice which is too
strong assumption for practice
and for example assumptions like random
oracles but it was also broken by um
for example in those um
md5 constructions or something like that
and so i do cyber construction is
actually something that's more or less
um from the same level so that's reason
why we start again so the main
contribution in this work is and the
following construction it's actually
makes um
again two permutation posts to a pi one
and so one permutation called two taiwan
and one permutation called two i2 and
this construction is called the feed
forward permutation three permutation or
the fpdp transaction you see that this
construction looks very similar to
that's previous and
yeah tmmo construction but the only
difference now is that instead of feeds
forward from the output of this um first
permutation we should feed forward here
the inputs
so this small modification makes a big
improvement while the second term is
still the same which is not important
for the
ot and scalable circuits applications
the first term improves for um a factor
of and square root of q
and c again b is very small for and of
the h covered circuits and is equal to
the number of construction products i
tweak and we do request those uh three
t's are chosen by nice combinatorial
subsets for example random subsets we
can show that we can we also present a
small od protocol in our paper that's we
can do that a priori and fix the tweaks
so we proved the security for distinct
and uniform random messages
and but the same results can also hold
for arbitrary input message and if we
replace m by um this
m
financial multiplication with the three
t so just introducing one extra
financial multiplication we can get a
much better result
and we prove um the results say um both
for independent i one and pi two also
indicates when pi taiwan is equal to i2
both cases and the construction
achieves this security bond
and um just because this improvement of
square root of q makes this
reconstruction sufficient for the
multi-user setting
so this is uh um yeah at the end of my
presentation and um more about more
details about that you can find it's um
in the on the full version of this paper
or um just on the on on my full vote
version of the talk only print so and
thank you for your attention
thanks for your presentation you
do we have any quick questions
looks like
we also have silence on zulip
so
i have one quick question uh i saw that
you have uh some uh analysis some
self-contained analysis of ot extensions
um could you get a similar
efficiency concrete efficiency as the
constructions that are based on just
using aes with a fixed key or something
like that
and yeah that's a very interesting
question because we i i discussed with
my goal of about that so um so actually
what can be done is instead of um
implementing this phi 1 and 5 2 as a
real um permutation we can also choose
for example to implement this um
taiwanese on the first five front of a
um fixed key a s and this pipe was the
second five front of aes but i also
talked with a colleague who is doing
symmetrical analysis um yeah he taught
me probably uh we need more rounds for
this for example and six or seven rounds
for each but and in that case i think um
there are really the real crypt analysis
needed for this um construction to make
sure we do not use too less front and
make the um yeah the on the line
primitive actually insecure so that's
actually my opinion but that's probably
something for the future work
okay
thanks for the answer and thanks again
for a presentation
so now let's move on to our next
presentation
that's going to be about two-round
adaptively secure npc from isogeny's lpn
or cdh
which is a work by navida lamati heart
montgomery si car patranadis and pratik
sarkar
the talk will be given by pratik who has
already shared his screen so please go
ahead whenever you're ready
hello
hi everyone so my name is pratik and
today we are going to talk about
a two round adaptively secure mpc from
misogynist lpn or cdh so this is a joint
work with naveed heart and shikhar
so today we are going to talk about
secure competition i will consider the
two-party setting so there is a party
bob and there's a party alice they have
private inputs x and y
so they want to compute a function f on
their private input x and y so the
parties compute the protocol which is pi
and the output the protocol output which
is product pi of x comma y
so the protocol should satisfy two
properties first is correctness function
output should be same as protocol output
and security uh the pi should not leak
anything about
the private witness
okay so and uh
yeah so the uh the first few protocols
for two pc were presented by yao gold
like mikali and viva mikali roger
and this uh thing um
2pc has applications in
privacy-preserving machine learning and
blockchains
so today we are going to talk about ot
so it's a very simple primitive
there's a receiver and sender so the
receiver has inputs v and mb i mean b
and the sender has inputs m0 m1 and the
receiver obtains mb as output
so the receiver should not know what is
m1 minus b and the sender should not
know what is b
and so this primitive of ot is complete
for secure computation
and we also know that ground optimal ot
enables round optimal secure computation
it also has other
uh applications like private server
intersection and interactive zero
knowledge
uh but in this work we aim for
constructing
adaptively secure ots which are secured
against malicious corruption of parties
and
we aim to achieve uc security and this
is the strongest corruption model and
the strongest security model in mpc
so let us briefly focus on
the
literature of adaptable secured mpc so
we are going to talk about non-ear
models where
the party okay so in the adaptive
setting the parties can get corrupted
during after or beginning of the
protocol at any time during the protocol
execution so it's a very strong model
and here the simulator needs to uh
simulate the view of the party
even when the parties are corrupted uh
during the protocol so we consider the
non-eurasian model uh where the
simulator cannot erase the states of the
parties
so in this work it was shown by
gurgaon's eye that you cannot obtain um
a constant round mpc protocol in the
plane model with black box simulation so
that's why uh there are two works uh
which construct from non-black box
simulation techniques uh they construct
constant round mpc protocol so this the
second work is going to be the next
stock given by mac
and in the setup string model uh there
were a few few works uh which
constructed linear round protocols
starting from the work of clos uh
and then uh the work by hazai and um
they constructed the first constant
round protocol from public key
encryption with oblivious ciphertext
generation
um so that is the minimal assumption
required
and now uh let us focus on the two round
setting so we know that two round mpc is
round optimal in the crs model so in
this model uh there were a few works in
from io
uh starting from
uh the cgp and gp 15 papers and then uh
the work by behind muda at all
constructed the first two round
adaptively secured mpc
uh from standard assumptions like ddh
lwe and qr without io in the common
reference string model and in another
work
we constructed
adapted to secure mpc from ddh in crs
mode in common random string model
so let me uh go through our
contributions so in this work we show
that uh we can construct adaptively
secured mpc from a very weak primitive
called riot in the crs model i will
define riot in the next slide
and then we constructed riot from cdh
lpn and isig isogenes in the crs model
so these were not known
and
as a result we obtained the first two
round malicious adaptively secured mpc
from cdh lpn and isogenes in crs model
and as a side result we also construct
the first non-committing encryption
scheme from lpl so i will just briefly
go through the results uh
so let me first define what is riot so
it's an iot iot is is a
indistinguishability based security ot
protocol that
is secured against static malicious
corruptions riot just adds a
sampling property where the receivers
other protocol message can be
obliviously sampled
so
we show that uh using this riot and a
bunch of primitives you can construct rs
iot so in rs iot you can also
obliviously sample a sender's ot
protocol message that is uh yeah
and then you can construct these
primitives from one way functions
next we show that
from rx iot you can build something
called semi-adaptive ot which is like a
intermediate step to adaptive secured
mpc
then again we show that from rs iot you
can obtain something called trapdoor
simulator pke
and using the result of cdmw you can get
augmented nce so
um using just riot you can get till nce
and then by applying the result of
benmuda at all uh we obtain adapted
secure mpc
and finally we show that you can
construct riot from cdh lpn or group
actions and
yeah that's all
so concluding we construct uh the first
two round maliciously secure adaptive
mpc from riot so to end with two open
questions
what is the minimal assumption required
for this riot primitives
and what is the minimal assumption in
general required for to round adaptively
secure mpc protocol
thank you
thanks for a presentation pratik
do we have any questions
okay
i do have a question uh here uh what is
the relationship between uh iot or riot
or is iot and
say standard uc security can you compile
from one to two to the other or
do you need more tools
right uh
so uh ucot is stronger but in this work
because you need simulation
extractability right i mean you need to
extract the party's inputs uh so the
work by benmuda at all they actually
started off with ucot and that's why you
cannot
build that from uh lpn
uh like they start they require they
started off with ucot with some sampling
properties and that's why you cannot
build it from
lpn cdh or isogenics so that's why we
reduced it through this riot primitive
which is game based definition along
with some receivers amplitude probably
so essentially we show that uh these two
are equivalent riot implies uc
or adaptable security ucod in that sense
like our work shows that right
okay that that was uh basically my
question uh thanks do we have any any
other questions
so
thanks again pratik for a presentation
and we will proceed to the final
presentation of the session on reverse
firewalls for adaptively secure npc
without setup that's a paper by suvra
deep chakraborty chayaganesh mahak
pancholi and pratik sarkar again
but this presentation will be given by
mahak so please mohawk share your screen
and
start whenever you're ready
um
just a second
can you see this
yes we can see your screen
okay although we can see the
the bar on top i don't know if you can
maximize those lights
uh
it's okay though yeah don't worry we can
see those lights it's just a minor
detail we can see the slides just fine
just just go ahead
okay
well
hi again i'm going to talk about reverse
firewalls for adaptively secure npc
without setup
um let me first talk about mpc in the
classical setting
so suppose there are two parties charlie
and lucy and they want to compute a
function f on their inputs x1 and x2
and they want to do it securely by
securely we mean that lucy who is
corrupt here should only learn about the
output and nothing else about charlie's
input
so in classical setting charlie and lucy
would run some secure two pc protocol
and exchange some round messages and
towards the end they would be able to
learn uh f of x 1 and x 2.
and in this process the guarantee is
that
lucy will not learn anything about
charlie's input except for whatever is
revealed from the function output itself
but it is important to note that the
security guarantee crucially relies on
the assumption that the honest parties
execute the protocol honestly
that is charlie's computer has honest
implementation of the protocol
but what if this assumption is not valid
so in this work we consider
[Music]
uh
again
lucy is corrupt here but now we think of
charlie having an uh tempered
implementation
so this is this this machine is tampered
by the adversary before charlie gets to
own it
so what can happen in this case is that
instead of sending the correct message
prescribed for the protocol a tampon
implementation can just output some
sequence and so there is no privacy
and this type of leakage is called
exfiltration
um
but note that a tampering is slightly
different from an actual corruption here
the adversary tampers a machine in the
beginning and once it's owned by charlie
the adversary cannot arbitrarily control
or see the internal state of the machine
so the question we ask in this work is
can we design an mpc protocol such that
we get some meaningful notion of
security even when the machines of
honest parties are tampered by the
adversary
in general the answer is no
but with few assumptions we do get
positive results
in particular in this work we assume
cryptographic reverse firewalls are rfs
once again charlie's implementation is
tampered here but now there is a
firewall which is a piece of code that
sits between the implementation and the
outside world and its job is to sanitize
all incoming and outgoing messages
so that nothing important is leaked
we want that the
rf preserves the security notion of the
underlying
mbc protocol and this is called security
preserving rsp
and we want it to prevent the tampering
from leaking any sorts of secrets which
is called exfiltration resistance
and one of the objectives while
designing the rs is to keep its
operations very very simple so that the
code can be tested and verified before
using it
moreover it's not like we're shifting a
thrust to the rf as we do not allow the
rf to hold any of charlie's secrets
um let me talk a little bit about the
previous results before i talk about our
contributions
so this notion was introduced by marinov
at all
in europe 2015
and in their work they gave a
construction for a 2 pc protocol along
with the turret that is secure even in
the face of tampering however the
construction works only for passive and
static corruptions
where passive corruptions means the
corrupted party uh
corporate bodies need to follow the
protocol but try to learn something
extra from the transcript
and static corruptions means that the
adversary corrupts the parties at the
beginning of the protocol execution
then chakravarti at all uh extended this
result to multi-party setting and to
active corruptions where active
corrections means that the corrupted
parties can now uh arbitrarily behave
arbitrarily arbitrarily and not follow
the protocol
however this
construction assumes a
common reference string or a crs and
that is a setup assumption
um
so in this work we ex we further
strengthen the result to active and
adaptive corruptions
where adaptive corruptions means that
the adversary can now corrupt honest
parties even during the protocol
execution
and moreover we remove the assumption on
crs and our final construction is in the
plane model
finally to summarize our results
we introduced new definitions for the
adaptive case
because the older definitions did not
suffice for this setting
we give a new implication for uh between
exfiltration resistance and security
preservation
and this is a very interesting result
because uh the prior works conjecture
that these two results these two notions
might not be related but we show that
they indeed are for simulation based
security
and as mentioned uh we give a new
construction that is secure against
adaptive and active adversary and secure
even when honest bodies machines are
tempered
um thank you and you can find more uh
details on our paper which is on the
apron and um on the extended top
thanks for talking
uh do we have any questions
if someone wants to ask questions on
audio please open your microphones
otherwise we do have zulip that is
looking a bit silent right now
so start with a
with the question maybe it was my
misunderstanding or maybe we even talked
about it but i'm not clear on whether
the adaptive adversary is allowed to
adaptively tamper with the honest
party's machine after the execution has
started or not
so what is the case
it is adaptive corruption so the uh
in the beginning the
the adversary would have tampered on its
bodies but later during execution it can
corrupt these already tampered parties
also in which case it would
start controlling the parties from that
point onwards but we would want
uh that before this corruption happens
nothing is revealed
we don't really we don't say much about
what happens after corruption
okay
uh and
what tools do you need to build these uh
reverse firewalls for this very strong
case of a adaptive secure npc can you
build it from the same kind of tools you
use for adaptively secure npc like
non-convenient encryption and so on
adaptively security or do you need
something else for the
so we do use some of the standard tools
we use and adaptively secure uh
commitment scheme
um and we so so we our general
construction is it follows gmw uh
compiler approach
and so all the building blocks the
commitments came the zero knowledge uh
protocol that we use all of them have to
be adaptively secure
but finally to make it uh work in plain
model we do we do assume knowledge
assumptions
okay
thanks for the explanation
uh do we have any any more questions
so i'd like to thank mahak again
and uh now since we have three remaining
minutes i'd like to open the floor to
anyone who would like to ask any
questions about any of the
the presentations we had
i guess not so
finally i'd like to thank all of the
presenters and all of the authors of the
papers in the session and of course also
thank you all who attended our session
and a special thanks to kevin mccurley
who once again helped us set up the
whole infrastructure for those online
conferences
thank you all and i hope to
see you later in the social hour and in
the remaining days of asia crypt 2021
have a good day
and i believe the social hour is
starting in two minutes
so
if you haven't noticed in the program
there are four different rooms for four
different languages hopefully that
covers
the whole spectrum of necessary
languages
and uh
the the rooms are hosted by people who
speak those languages so i invite you to
go and
mingle with some of your other
cryptographer friends
thanks everyone
thank you