you're ready to go
all right
so welcome everyone
uh for the test award test of time award
ceremony
of asia group 2021
so the test of time award
of the iacr
is given yearly for each one of the
three iacr general conferences so one
for your crypt one for crypto and one
for azure crypt
uh and it's given for a paper that has
had a lasting lasting impact in the on
the field
so
uh we the eligible papers are
asian group from the papers from the
same conference
15 years earlier so
this year eligible papers for asia crypt
where
the papers
of azure crypt 20 2006
uh and we chose among all of all those
papers
um one which had a particularly lasting
impact
uh on
the overall field of cryptography so the
selection is done uh by a committee uh
that that changes each year
consisting of two members
uh appointed by the board of directors
of the icr as well as one representative
one of the program co-chairs from each
of the three conferences
so this year the the the
selection committee chair was willie
maurer uh together with nigel smart uh
as appointed by the board
and um francois xavier standard for your
crypts uh chris spiker
for uh crypto and myself for asia crypt
um so submissions for next year are open
so nigel put
a link so
if you want to nominate a paper to from
2007 you are you are free to do so um at
the the link he uh put on the chat
um
and so okay so
um so
as as i said we
um
uh closed so you can nominate papers we
closed nominations
um
in uh in february
so but we we didn't we weren't limited
to nomination so we can choose
ourselves and in this case it was
important because we actually received a
very small number of nominations but
anyway so we looked at all the papers
and decided on the most impactful ones
and
we selected um
uh in this case
um
uh a paper by um jen scott uh from asia
group 2006 uh titled uh simulation sound
music proofs
for practical language and constant
science group signature
and this paper was selected for
constructing asymptotically optimal
music proofs
and group signatures without using
random oracles
and paving the way to practical
constructions so
congratulations jens
who is uh attending this session
um
thank you maddie
congratulations
okay um yeah if i can say a few words um
so so this is um
work that i did when i was a postdoc at
ucla so i would thank um it's a high
rather stropski for hosting me and it
was a very productive time so we had
several papers on how to do
non-interactive zero knowledge based on
uh pairings
um and and this particular paper i also
want to thank the selection committee
for for digging it out because there
were several papers we wrote and i guess
this one slipped a little under the
radar but it's actually a paper that's
really close to my heart so i'm very
happy that the selection committee kind
of found this
paper and gave me the award for this
paper
um
so so the history is that uh at that
time we saw like figured out how to do
non-interactive zero knowledge
for pairings and and to start with that
was for like on a on a gate by gate
basis bit by bit basis
um
but what you really want is efficient
zero knowledge right and if you're
paying the overhead for doing improving
things gate by gate or bit by bit then
that's very expensive
so so the purpose of this paper is to to
show that you can really do
non-interactive knowledge directly for a
language which is practical which has
direct makes direct sense in a
cryptographic scheme
and the particular cryptographic scheme
was group signatures
um
so so
with these new non-interactive knowledge
techniques based on pairings and you can
now prove directly things about group
elements that you know you're doing an
exponentiation you're multiplying a
couple of field elements and and things
like that
um and that allowed you to do group
signatures
with so like non-interactive zero
knowledge proofs but then what not based
on the random oracle but so like
standard uh
model
um and which had a constant number of
group elements it was a huge constant
and it has been improved since uh i
think we're talking about hundreds of
thousands of group dollars but it was a
constant so it was so like a language
which was uh
practical it really has like the kind of
things you want to prove directly right
but it was a theoretical practical
result so to speak um
i want to note that uh i was not the
only one noticing this so there were
also in parallel uh works by uh brent
waters and javier yen that also did
group signatures and also had some
interesting results with the constant
size group signatures
and at the same time and so might also
have some discussions with with brent
about that but back in those days
so but um yeah thanks very much i'm very
honored and very happy to receive the
test of time away
okay congratulations again
um
if there are any comments please speak
up otherwise
i will
um
[Music]
um yeah express our congratulations
again to jens and move to the
program shares report
thanks maddie
so i i didn't show it by the way but but
uh i believe all the awards for for um
for the conference including the test of
time awards should be at some point
framed and sent uh by mail to the
authors hopefully
for to the awards
yeah i actually hope to be able to
to deliver the the award in person to
ends
son
but
yes
thank you congratulations
thank you michelle
okay should i move straight ahead into
the report then
perhaps
might as well
yeah okay so so this is the report from
the
program chairs so
uh hwai wong and myself
um about uh
the organization the scientific
organization of airscript
so
some highlights
we had the most submissions ever
and also the most
accepted papers
and i believe
we also have one of the mo the top
numbers of registrations
uh for asia crypt maybe uh last year was
was more
um although in practice because of um
um of
virtual or
organizations in practice uh we we
noticed that the attendance in sessions
is not actually breaking records um
so hopefully we we will soon go back to
um
like at least hybrid organizations that
uh
um people can um participate in person
and uh have devote their
attention to the to the to the
conference without
having uh meetings all day
that disturb them
um
so one change
we decided to make is to have a larger
program committee
so since we accepted we were expecting a
relatively large number of submissions
and
and from maybe a
um a broader
um
set of area areas
we wanted to broaden also the expertise
of the of the pc so
we invited more members to pc than usual
so we assembled a pc
um of 74 members
which was uh i believe fairly diverse in
terms of
expertise
academic seniority and geographic
geographical location and and to some
extent
as we could gender
so
um so this this this larger pc allows us
allowed us to
assign
uh smaller than usual number of reviews
to pc members so each got each one got
15 reviews
um which some
of which they could um
um
uh
delegate some uh to external reviewers
so we got the help
of uh almost 400 external reviewers who
contributed to the review process
so
that's a
bird's-eye view of what the the program
committee looked like so
in terms of gender we had
we were um
72 percent mail
uh in terms of uh geographical location
we had uh 14 uh percent
uh
in
um americas so mostly us and canada but
also some
uh latin american countries
and
um
43 percent each of europe and the asia
pacific region
so um
like in terms of location as well
um the the program committee was
relatively diverse
so
how the review process went um
so we as i said we had the 341
submissions not counting duplicates or
invalid submissions
um actually we
oh sorry
um that was a typo here so we had 200
something submissions so okay so
um so the the review process as usual
for icr conferences was to stage so with
a rebuttal phase
and so we decided also to have early
rejection so papers that um
really didn't seem to have any chance of
getting accepted um
after the initial review round uh where
received an early rejection decision so
this this was um about 100 papers so 200
something and i think it was 263
something like this submissions advanced
to the second round
and 95
were eventually accepted
so
some
got minor revisions and after
the the pc could check that the
revisions were implemented
um they were officially accepted to the
conference and this this gave
so 27.9 acceptance rate so we are one
percent up
from last year
um
so as a rule uh submissions received at
least three reviews and at least five uh
four papers that were co-authored by a
pc member
so
unfortunately there were on a handful
of papers that received less
reviews um almost always due to
coverage related difficulties on the
part of the reviewers and so um we
apology
we apologize to the authors of those
submissions uh for
um not being able to find um reviewers
on time for their submissions
and so as usual so pc members were
allowed to submit up to two papers and
one
if the paper was single author
um so we had
we put together um unfortunately i
believe a great program
uh that consisted of uh
andrew yao's uh distinguished lecturer
yesterday two invited talks so um
[Music]
casually sacco
a couple of hours ago and you
tomorrow
so
the pape
we decided for the first time for an icr
um virtual conference to have parallel
tracks
um
so
the 16 technical sessions were divided
in in those parallel tracks
with short life talks and q a so
about five minutes for each talk
and you have longer talks on youtube
so
we didn't yet receive specific feedback
but
my impression is that this uh parallel
track format uh is working pretty well
so um
please let us know if you if you like it
that way or um you prefer um
um single tracks even though and this
becomes um
a pretty long conference because of the
number of accepted papers
and so the the award paper
uh the award papers so
were presented on monday in a plenary
session so
they didn't get into parallel tracks
so you have one ramp session coming soon
uh right after this session
and um
there are there are three social
awareness in the program
uh including
language specific rooms
on we had one on monday and there's
going to be one
tomorrow as well
so
many thanks to the volunteers who
accepted to host those social hours
and this was organized by the general
chair uh by the basin idea
from
last year's asia crypt so i believe
that's the uh only
um uh
uh the only uh virtual conference where
we had we have those language specific
rooms so far
so some
silly statistics as usual so
this is the
um
the the
time of first submission of uh
of the the papers of the conference so
if you look at submitted papers you can
see that
we had
24 hours before the deadline we had
about
uh submissions
and this grow this grew to
340 within the last day
um
so the last uh the latest submitted
papers was actually six minutes after
the deadline because we decided to
um
especially because um there were there
was some confusion
about um
about um the fact that the
uh the the deadline was at noon utc
instead of midnight we we left a very
small
bit of slack
in in what how we accepted so
fortunately so we didn't have to accept
it so um
those there were actually three papers
that were submitted after the deadline
none of them actually got uh accepted
and the last latest accepted paper
though was submitted nine minutes uh
before the deadline
so
as you can see there's a
there's a small blip in the number of
accepted papers towards the end
even though um
actually most most of the papers
submitted very late
uh were not eventually accepted
so this is a wall cloud for the
submitted paper titles
so
we we thought that
new byzantine tests of fully linear
encryption was something representative
and then this is the accepted paper
titled work cloud so something like
tight security of universal quantum mpc
um so we'd like
to thank uh many people about this
conference so all the authors of the
submissions all the conference speakers
um the program committee and external
reviewers we especially thank uh
kevin mccally and k mckelly for
basically running this virtual event and
they have done a tremendous amount of
work uh to make it happen
um uh
we thank django our general chair
uh the ram section chairs who
will be running the event in a few
minutes
uh chichanok uh transaction soup and kwa
our invited speakers and distinguished
lecturers
andrew yao kaze sako and
zhang jian bao and springer for the help
putting together the proceedings
session chairs uh social our hosts
moderators and so on
uh who we mostly invited on very short
notice so um many thanks to them
and of course many thanks to all the
participants thank you very much
and
since it's time we can
move on to the ramp session now so the
floor is to
the ram session chairs
chicha no can hook