yes so we will start the session
advanced encryption and signatures
the first
presentation is public key encryption
with flexible pattern matching
[Music]
so
please go ahead
thank you very much hello everyone
so
first just to recall that uh public key
classical public public key encryption
ensures the privacy of traffic between
users
but if the receiver wants to use an
intrusion detect detection system so a
service provider who
analyzes the traffic to check if there
is malicious activity
then he can only give the secret key to
him and it breaks the
the end-to-end encryption
so in searchable encryption
if the service provider needs to search
for some pattern w
he can ask a trapdoor to the receiver
and with this trapdoor
he can see if the pattern occurs in the
traffic but he learns nothing else
okay
so now what i want to show you is that
the use case we are looking
at is very different from
the one of existing of some existing
solutions namely
uh symmetric searchable encryption
so
if we compare the the case where we are
rooting emails
emails
can be
associated with keywords naturally
like the words that appear in the object
field
so they are indexable data
uh and in deep packet inspection so if
we look directly in the traffic it's
like it's a stream
that may or may not contain some pattern
so in the first case uh
the the server who is looking for males
with some keyword is just performing an
equality test with the keyword attached
and in our case he's trying to find a
pattern that can occur at any position
in the stream
here the dictionary of keywords can be
set before setup
but here the the patterns that are
filtered evolve to to get new virus
signatures
and
a pattern can even be searched in
something that has been encrypted before
we chose this pattern
for forensic search uh for instance
uh so we we we give another name to our
special case and we we we name it stream
encryption supporting pattern
matching so just a loop a quick look at
the kind of pattern that we can have to
to search so this is a
list for some
version of snort
which is an ids an intrusion detection
system and we see there are many
patterns um
and
we see that they have very different
lengths uh
quite short but very different lengths
and so uh some solutions uh try to
to get back to string equality so there
they break the stream into strings of
fixed length
so
for instance here uh
in blind box uh if we
if we choose a sliding window of four
letters
uh
every four consecutive letter will be
encrypted into one ciphertext element
and we can give trapdoors
for only keywords of of length four so
for instance we can give a trapdoor for
hosts
and the service provider can learn that
host is in there
but hostile has a different length and
so
it won't be encrypted at once and we
cannot give a trapdoor for it like that
so one
possibility would be to to encrypt
everything for each length but we have
seen that the patterns have very
different lengths so this is very low
efficiency
and a third possibility would be to
break hostile into host and tile and to
search these two
but now the service provider learns more
information he can learn if tile is in
in it
and we have seen that there are many
patterns so if we do that for every
pattern we get a lot of extra
information for the service provider
uh
the generic solution we we are not
really interested in them because they
are very costly so we wanted solutions
that are more specific to our problem
and there are there exists uh two papers
that use bilinear pairings
and the second one is really adapted to
streams but they have two limitations
first both of them are on a rely on a
very
strong assumption that is interactive
and their public key depends on the size
of the alphabet and patterns use byte
strings so there is a two to the eighth
factor
and so we address both this problem by
providing uh two schemes uh the first
one is really efficient uh
and it
reduced the size of the public key by a
factor two to the fourth and it halves
the size of the ciphertext of the
previous solutions and the second scheme
also has removed the dependency on the
alphabet size
and he it's the first one that uses a
static assumption for security
yeah that's that's it for me thank you
um
and
any question is welcomed
thank you
so uh
no question on sleep chat
if some you have some question or
comment
please
write down on drip
or zoom chat
so i have one naive question
so uh
what is the next
direction or some open problem
of your work here
so uh the security that is proven for
all these schemes is uh selective
security
so we are looking for adaptative
adaptive security
if possible and uh another thing is that
we are using bilinear pairings and it's
still
costly uh for
real-time computation
so we are trying to find
lighter
lighter solutions also yes okay thank
you so
uh
for adaptive security so
uh your scheme use batting appearing so
usually such kind of uh
public encryption scheme can be
leveraged too by using a
dual system encryption framework so you
tried it already
so yes we we are looking at these
solutions and um
so the the the first uh papers that that
we see they don't provide directly a
solution for it uh
because the the
[Music]
uh the security that we are using uh is
the adversary can make a lot of queries
for trapdoors in it uh so it's it's a
it's at least
very much more complicated than identity
based encryption or stuff like that
uh so we are looking uh for more
sophisticated things and
and we'll see if there is something that
works yeah i see i see
that's a really nice uh
way yeah yeah
yeah very
nice
yeah i see i understand
the
technical hardware
okay so any other question or comment
so we have no
uh no more uh comment so okay i'll
return to the next
so uh
jeffrey you so
can can you make a presentation here now
oh
okay okay okay
so the next
uh talk
uh is uh title is
adaptive security via
deletion in attribute-based encryption
solutions from
such assumptions in barina groups
by
lishav goyal joffrey liu and brent
waters so a presentation given is will
be given by uh jeffrey liu so please go
ahead
okay uh just give me one second um
okay
um
okay so i'll talk about that to security
by deletion attribute-based encryption
and this joins this is john ward with
richard goyal and brent waters
so everyone see the present presenter
view do you mind sort of just
already okay yeah just just uh
yeah sorry let me let me share once
again um
let me share
okay
um
uh is it good right now good okay
okay okay
cool okay so okay as we know av was
first formulated in these two papers and
in a b scheme we
uh every user has attribute as nb binary
string and we have policies as boolean
functions
uh the two issue keys we first generate
the public key and master secret key and
we derive
uh
uh and we uh when we encrypt we can uh
use a master secret key we can derive
secret keys associated with different
attributes and when we encrypt we
encrypt using the public key
and policy
and only users with the secret key
associated with attributes that these
policies evaluate on them to be one can
decrypt the ciphertext and the rest
cannot
and this format uh this formulation is
called ciphertext policy b specifically
since the policy is embedded into the
ciphertext and there's a also due
formulation called key policy ab where
we embed the policy into the secret key
and both of these formulations and we
have two levels of semantic security
requirement
in most papers uh
papers will discuss these two levels and
what we usually would want in practice
is of of course the full security also
called adaptive that adversary first
sees the public key it queries a bunch
of secret keys associated with some
attributes and
then he sends in a challenge policy and
the message to messages adversary the
challenger encrypts well the messages
with respect to this policy and the
adversary is not supposed to guess which
message is encrypt encrypted this
definition even though natural but uh
it's in fact hard to realize
uh in most cases and people often turn
to this weaker notion called selective
security first
if they are not able to prove adaptive
security and in this case adversary has
to send in
uh the policy uh the challenge policy it
wants to attack on before it even sees
the public uh keys
um the if we look at the line of works
that try to build a secure abe
so starting from group assumptions this
already works but selecting security
from bilinear decay helmet
and later on there was this dual system
technique introduced by waters and we
could realize adaptive security but uh
the real uh reliance on decisional uh
bilinear assumptions seems inherent in
these
uh
in these works in in these techniques
and whereas the earlier selective
security schemes can actually be built
from search assumptions
and uh um moving to the lattice side
these works uh realized selective
security from lattice but it was uh
uh always it's been been a long time
before we we finally had something of
adaptive security from latis
and there was a recent breakthrough in
2019 by separate
it realized that definitely secure abe
from lattice even though the
functionality was in fact a
subset functionality it is a step
forward towards
uh adaptive security and it's different
from our past approaches
so and we therefore would ask can we
generalize this approach
to make adaptive security hope for more
general cases
um okay in our work we simplify and
expand the framework of realizing
adaptive security in february 2019 and
we we showed that the the simplified
framework can be instantiated from both
search bi-linear assumptions and
lattices
and we will still stick with the subset
functionality
and our high-level approach is combining
two building blocks the first one is a
selectively secure key policy a b with
deletable property and it should shoot
for nc1 circuit
and
the second building block is constrained
prf with this deletion conforming
property together we can realize that
adaptive secure and cipher text policy
ade
and uh let's quickly go over like the
properties we need so what's a deletable
abe so basically we have two approaches
to perform deletion
uh the first one is uh we can remove
certain blocks
uh on the cipher text according to an
index set and the second one is we
remove certain indices in an attribute
replace it with like a special symbol
for example bought and we we can have a
valid encryption procedure that encrypts
such as cipher text and we get a cipher
text that is indistinguishable from one
that you where where we perform the
deletion
over the ciphertext
and a second building block is a
constraint prf we know that in
construing prf we can constrain this a
secret key
according to a functionality so that you
can only evaluate uh on the on par on
the inputs that
satisfy this functionality
and here we need additional property for
the constraint prf oh sorry uh we can
actually constrain the uh the prf by
just removing certain blocks from the
master secret key uh similar to what we
did for the attributes
and here uh we we can uh given
functionality f we we should be able to
know which blocks we should remove
and another property is that we can do
this uh
evaluation on the prf with some
hard coded x uh hard coded x
and uh so due to time uh restriction i
won't going to talk about how i complete
uh com how we combine these two building
blocks to give us
fully security let's just briefly talk
about how we instantiate these building
blocks and
the uh the audience can refer to our
papers for details on the construction
and to to instantiate division
conforming constraint prf it's not hard
we can have such a constraint prf with a
subset
functionality following these two works
and for lattices we have uh like uh
sort of more more choices um sorry for
for deletable a b we have more choices
and instantiation
we can uh for the by linear group site
we can modify the gps w uh 2006 uh
2006 paper
uh
the one using a search assumption and we
can turn that into deletable and uh for
the lattice side we can turn both of
these two constructions into a deletable
a b scheme even though some of you might
know that there was recently attack on
the buoyant searching scheme but the
attack came out after our first draft
and we still leave the example in our
paper as just for illustrative purpose
on how deletable abe works
and finally uh there's also concurrent
work by kasumata nishimaki amada
yamakawa that extend the functionality
of subreddit scheming to inner product
and that's everything for this talk uh
thank you
so any question or comment
oh
i cannot find any comment or
question on
zurip or
the chat
so
uh i i have one naive question so com
work
uh your work uh what is a main advantage
of your work with compared with their
work
yeah we expand the the the framework of
uh
uh of the submarine scheme so in summary
scheme it's a it's using this uh very
specific properties of it uh like
overalls using this uh it is
specifically over working with the bgg
plus 14 lattice-based construction but
in fact it can we can abstract the
properties out and it is actually a more
generalized framework with like certain
abe and uh and certain and certain
constraint prf and uh
and for that kind of abu we can actually
fit we can actually fit some other
existing ab schemes uh into the
framework
and uh and i think for the the the
customer at all work and they
uh they yeah they they do expand the
functionality and but they they follow
they sort of follow this very specific
uh lattice-based construction uh
as in the suburbs scheme so yeah it's
not uh a very abstract uh it's like a
more like non-black box use
uh extension of the work right
[Music]
yeah i see i see so one uh advantage is
uh uh security from uh
uh computational program uh okay thank
you yeah yes uh yes so we we can have
fun
yeah we can have security from
computational uh group assumptions and
uh right
okay so any other question or comment so
no comment thank you very much
and okay thank you okay
next talk
uh
next
uh talk uh the title is bounded
collision abe for uh
turing machines from ibe
uh zeo says uh richard
well
little ones side and brentwood so this
shop will give a talk go ahead
thanks a lot for the introduction and
yeah today i'll tell you how to build
attribute based encryption for the
uniform model of tuning machines
from
general assumption of identity based
encryption in the bound collision model
so just let me quickly recap
attribute-based encryption so java did a
great job of telling you about attribute
based description but i'm going to be
switching things around a little bit so
let me just redo it again
so attribute-based encryption is a
fine-grained notion of encryption which
allows finding an access of
over-encrypted data
so it can be pictorially instead using
the following picture where we have two
parties alice and bob where alice has
some private data m and it wants to
share this private data m corresponding
to the people who satisfy certain
attributes
so bob has a secret key alice has a
public key and alice basically encrypts
her message under these attributes
now suppose we have a third party
charlie and charlie here it wants to
recover the message m as long as the
policy that charlie has it satisfies the
set of attributes the attributes could
be i am say age people over age 25 can
be here the speakers have text
so that's one example and uh one way to
solve this problem in order to enable uh
charlie from decrypting this particular
site text charlie can simply send the
soft text over to bob and bob can
decrypt the search text authorize
whether check whether a child is
authorized or not and send it back
but this is not very efficient because
you have to perform interaction
attribute based encryption allows a
non-interactive and a very efficient way
of solving this problem in which you can
come up with some partial secret keys
called predicate secret keys for the
function app such that given this
predicate secret key you can perform
decryption on its own
so the advantages of attribute
description is that it allows this
finding access over encrypted data you
can choose when to release encrypted
data and it solves this problem without
outsourcing and even when bob is offline
charlie can perform this decryption
so a little more abstractly as uh you
already saw the previous talk we have a
setup algorithm and generates the master
set republican secret keys using the
master public you can encrypt any
message for the attribute string of your
choice recall i'm switching the
attributes and policies in the previous
talk you saw policies being interpreted
in the soft text here i'm going to talk
about attributes being incremented under
cytric so it's like a dual version of
which is called these uh the key policy
uh version of attribute based encryption
so that means in the key generation
algorithm we take it and put a policy
and gets a secret key and finally we can
combine the side effects and secret key
to recover the message depending upon
whether the policy was satisfied or not
on that given attribute
present inside that cipher text
and for security as you saw typically
the intuition is that the adversary
should not be able to learn anything
beyond that it can learn by performing
decryption so suppose adversary is given
aside text and a bunch of many secret
keys as long as none of the suited keys
none of the policies associated with
secret key can satisfy the underlying
attributes the message should be hidden
if you can satisfy the attribute then
you can run the decryption algorithm and
learn the message otherwise it should be
completely hidden and what's more
interesting about attribute description
is that attributes encryption really
depends upon the class of policies that
you can build it for if the class of
policy is just empty then it's basically
the public encryption but depending upon
how expensive the class is you get more
interesting applications typically the
models of computation that has been
discussed or have been done so far for
attribute description can be split into
two categories the non-uniform and the
uniform classes with the non-uniform
classes we have boolean formulas and
circuits but the problem with that is
that the attributes that you can encrypt
have to be of fixed size you have to
declare that this is the length of my
attributes whereas in the uniform
classes such as deterministic finite
automata turing machines ramp programs
etc you can handle potentially unbounded
length attributes
so basically the main difference is that
in the non-uniform setting you have a
separate key for different length
attributes whereas in the uniform
classes you have one single key
that can decrypt potentially factors
that encrypt different varying length
attributes
so in practice uniform uh model of
computation is much more useful for uh
attribute-based encryption
and uh so far we've seen that there has
been tremendous amount of progress in
trying to build attribute description
from a wide variety of assumptions such
as pilot maps learning with others
multimedia maps and much more
and one commonality for all these
positive results is that they require
specific algebraic assumptions to enable
attribute-based encryption
and even further
there seems to be a gap between the
feasibilities that we have for the
non-uniform models as well as the
uniform models typically from the
non-uniform models it's easier to use
algebraic assumptions to get feasible
results but for uniform models we still
don't know a lot for example we don't
know how to get collision resistant
attribute-based encryption for securing
machines in the uh from a standard
assumption uh if you don't want to go
via the route of obfuscation for which
we have construction from well-founded
assumptions
but going forward
the question that we ask in this work or
the under consideration is that is there
always a gap between uniform and
non-uniform models or can we actually
get the same feasibilities for the
uniform models as well and in general
can we also rely on general assumptions
non-algebra exempt are not algebraic
assumptions to perform this
instantiation
and in this work we show exactly the
following we showed we built an ab
scheme for curing machines which is a
uniform class from identity based
encryption which is a general assumption
in the bound inclusion model
and the two theorems we show in this
work is that starting with ib you can
build a non-adaptively secure a b scheme
with two collisions and you can also
upgrade this security to adaptive
security if you start from if you work
in the random oracle model
and one caveat of our results
is that although the encryption
algorithm can take us and put unbounded
length attributes
the runtime of the turing machine that
can be run on those attributes has to be
declared during encryption time so the
attribute length is unbounded with the
turing machines which you can run on
that particular attribute that has to be
a pretty mounted
and as a consequence we also saw we also
were able to uh propose a fine-grained
simulation security for something called
gobble grams as it was an important
ingredient construction
now just trying to explain our result a
little bit better let me explain what
the boundary collision model is let me
just recall it so this was the security
definition that we saw before the
bounded collision model says that the
security holes as long as the number of
corruptions of keys that the adversary
can do is bounded is at most some a
primary para decided parameter q
and as long as you don't corrupt more
than two keys the security still holds
and we although this is weaker
than fully collusionist
model it is very interesting and has
seen many interesting applications and
it turns out in the landscape in the
bound collision model is already very
interesting for the non-uniform models
we already know that a b for circuits
can be built just from public
integration the minimal assumption
but it turns out all prior constructions
for a b
for any uniform models even in the
bounded collision setting they need
specific algebraic assumptions so
there's huge gap for
your non-uniform model it's just public
encryption is enough but for uniform
models it's not clear and in this work
we precisely show that algebra is not
needed for uniform models and you can
start from general assumptions if you're
working in the bound collision model
so at a very high level our construction
for attribute-based description proceeds
in three steps in the first step we
design a attribute-based encryption
scheme for tv machines in which we only
corrupt allow one single key
the second step we show how to go from
single corruption to boundary corruption
and then we show how to upgrade
non-adaptive security to adaptive
security in the random oracle model so
combining all these things we get both
of the results
and during the lack of time i won't tell
you exactly how to do it but let me just
quickly summarize so the step two
follows by standard combinatorial tricks
for amplifying completion bound but as
in the third step we rely on a very
simple non-committing encryption uh
scheme that be instantiated in the
random oracle model and show that this
particular non-interactive
communicate non-committing encryption
scheme can be used to upgrade security
now the step one is where a lot of
technical ideas came in and
in the interest of time let me just
summarize them very briefly so the
intuition is as follows to build an a b
scheme with one single key corruption
we work as follows the scifix is going
to contain t garblings where the t is a
time bound of the clearing machine that
can be run on this particular soft
text each garbling is going to perform a
computation step of the curing machine
so the ith cobbling is going to perform
the ith tubing machine step
and it's basically going to output the
labels for the the i plus one at the
goblin
and the labels are actually encrypted
under certain identities which
correspond to the tuning machine
transitions when you go from the ith
step to the i plus one extent
and secret key
for a particular turing machine is going
to be the identity keys for the ib
system for the appropriate turing
machines tuning machine state
transitions basically giving decryption
i will run uh the first problem that's
going to give me an encryption of the
wired labels for the next coupling
and those
encryptions can be recovered depending
upon my state transitions
that's the high level id and i invite
you to look at the full version of the
paper or just the full paper to see how
we execute this
we're just throwing in a little more of
details what type of goblins do we need
so it turns out garbled circuits could
be enough could be sufficient but they
lead to quadratic blow up in the cyclic
size if you just
use them naively
and we show that using carbon ramps we
can make it linear much more efficient
and the point is that in gable ramps we
have a persistent memory database and we
have different ram programs so that's
why we can take out this ram this memory
to encode the database to the to sort of
encode the turing machine state
in kabul circuit you have to pass the
the steering machine state uh
during each ram program which we try to
avoid
and in this paper we propose a new
security definition for garbled ramps
which we call iterative simulation
security and basically the point is that
in the standard notion of security all
ram programs for the given database have
to be simulated together at the same
time
but in this work we show that the
simulation still works if you simulate
the programs some of the programs and
compute the rest of the programs
honestly
then still we can get interesting
simulation security properties and this
is very crucial for our proof since we
have to simulate things step by step and
we can't simulate things all at once
because we work in this unbounded model
unbounded attribute model
and yeah please look at the paper for
details i'm trying to conclude in this
work we provide the bounded collusion
attribute-based encryption scheme for
turing machines from ibe
and he proves provide security in the
adaptive and non-adaptive setting in the
random oracle understanding assumptions
and uh this is the first uniform model
attribute description scheme in the
bounded collision setting from general
assumptions which does not rely on
algebra
showing that the gap between non-uniform
and uniform is actually uh
is not that big at least in the boundary
collision water and we also provide a
new fine information security for
garbage ramps which we show can be
instantiated from prior works by a new
security proof
and just trying to conclude with some
interesting directions for the future
work a very natural question could be
can you actually do the same for
functional encryption can we get
function encryption procuring machines
in the boundary collision model
or can you also remove this time bound
that we had in the encryption algorithm
and can we go beyond can you improve
adaptive security without relying on
random oracle modules
and recently there has been some other
bounded collision models which are
called the dynamic collision model model
and we actually extend our results for
eb for tuning machines in those dynamic
model as well
with that i would like to conclude and
thanks for listening and i'd be happy to
answer any questions
okay thank you very nice talk
so any question or comment
oh
i cannot find
so i i have one naive question so you
you say at the end of your talk uh the
challenge is
to
leverage to adaptive security without
london molecular model and
uh
i think uh in the
uniform uh computational model turing
machine
so maybe uh uh selective
uh the gap of selective security and
adaptive security is
more
large and because uh that in the key
policy type
uh
abe
so
the main advantage is
any language uh any language attributes
can be handled but if uh selective
security we consider selective security
so the first as the first of the game we
should uh declare the challenge
attribute so the
maybe the hardware is very
get low compared to the non-uniform
model
so uh
maybe the hardware is large gap is raj
is it right
so that's a great question that's your
key but uh it's possible but i don't
think that might be the case the reason
is follow is the following reason is
that even right now we proved something
stronger than selective security we
proved non-adaptive security in
non-adaptive security
the uh the only restriction is that they
should not be any post challenge
secret key queries
so
you do not have to declare the challenge
attribute at the beginning of the game
all you have to do is that the secret
key queries must be made before uh
seeing the challenge uh uh ciphertext
so you actually don't need any
information about the challenge text the
property is that we have to hardwire
certain computation inside the challenge
side of text and that's why we need to
make those queries before
so
i think uh this is uh i haven't spent
too much time on it but i suspect that
we should be able to use checks from the
adaptive security of goblin uh gobble
circuits uh literature where we use
these uh pebbling techniques to prove
adaptive security and i think those
techniques have already been used to
prove adaptive security for abe in the
binary literature and i think those
ideas can also be used to prove adaptive
security by a more fine-grained analysis
of our construction because we right now
work in a lot of these abstractions if
you open up all the abstractions do
everything from first principles and
have a very very fine-grained proof
video use these pebbling structures to
put them tricks in a nice way i think
you should be able to get to adaptive
security as well i'm not saying it's
immediate i think it's feasible but
there
this needs to be more research done in
order to solve that problem okay okay
thank you very interesting but we have
no times we should switch to the next
talk thank you very much
yeah
it's to next talk
so i will
share the
next three talks uh this is xingi huang
from uh fujian normal university china
our next talk is
digital signatures with memory type
security in the multi-challenge setting
and it will be presented by ning ning
are you here
yes yes okay great great it's your turn
yeah
okay
hi everyone my name is
and i'm glad to briefly introduce our
work due to the signatures with
memorized security in the
multi-challenge setting to you
and in our work sorry in our work we
consider memory type reductions
researchers usually measure the quality
of a reduction by its running time and
success probability or advantage
uh i've heard how they observed that
memory is also a valuable computational
resource and should be considered as a
measurement for reductions
so they call a reduction memory type if
the overall memory consumed by the
reduction is approximately the same with
the memory consumed by the adversary
and especially independent of the
adversary
and one
sorry
one interesting setting in this
direction is that
is the multi-challenge a strong uf cma
security or the msuf cma security of
digital signature scheme
different from classical single
challenges security the adversary could
submit multiple forge queries throughout
the msuf cma game and wins if at least
one of the
forgery is valid
and without considering memory single
challenge security tightly implies the
multi challenge security
however albert hall and one method shows
some impossibility results for msuf cma
security the memory is considered they
show that certain black box reductions
from multi-challenge security to single
channel security or to some
computational problem must be known
tight with respect to memory or time
so our work shows some good news
and we focus on finding which properties
of reduction are sufficient to achieve
memory tightness
and keeping the impossibility results
about
blackboard reductions of albert hall and
volunteer in mind we decided to consider
non-black box reductions and a weaker
security notion which we call the cma-1
security
and even in this setting we still face
the main challenge that the reduction
needs to distinguish fresh forgery from
replayed message signature pair
without using memory
so our first step towards solving this
problem is that we define a special kind
of non-black reduction which we call the
canonical reductions
and the idea of a canonical reduction is
that the reduction r deals with a single
challenge adversary a
and simulates a signature for a in some
deterministic way
and then the check for the final forge
query can be done by comparing the sigma
star with the simulated signature for
the message m star
and in this way the reduction r does not
use memory to store any signature
message signature pair
however canonical reductions are still
restricted in many aspects for example
it only deals with a single challenge
adversaries
and it is still not memory tied because
it it needs to simulate a random
function
and it only works for a weaker security
notion which is the cma1 security
instead of the normal cma security
and despite of these restrictions we are
able to use canonical reduction together
with a memory type pseudorandom function
to show a good result more precisely if
there is a reduction r which proves that
some signature scheme sigma prime has s
uf cma1 security
then we can build another reduction r
prime which proves that sigma prime has
memory type msuf cma's one security
and this is this result is nice because
we can go from single challenge setting
to the multi-channel setting memory
tightly
however we are still in the cma1
security case
and to upgrade the security from cma1 to
cma we take our second step
more precisely we choose an additional
nonce
of length 2 lambda and sign it together
with the message
we are able to show that the new
signature scheme is ms-uf cma secure if
the original signature scheme is
ms-ufcma1 secure
and this transformation preserves
also preserves memory tightness
so we achieve our goal via these two
steps
and to instantiate our approach we only
need to construct signature schemes with
suf cma security and show some canonical
reduction r for such schemes
and we are able to instantiate our
approach and get a concrete memory type
ms uscma security signature schemes
as you can see in this table we get
three fully tight signature speed
by fully tight we mean that they are
tight in terms of memory time and
advantage
and the three of them are a lossy
identification based digital signature
scheme and a variant of the rsa foodon
hash scheme
and the variant of the
bunin lin shattermanski
and the cost to achieve full tightness
is a two lambda expansion in the
signature size
and to summarize our work we propose we
propose a generic approach in getting a
memory type msuf cma signature scheme
and then we instantiate our approach and
get three digital signature schemes with
fully tight ms-us-cma security and our
results do not conflict with the
impossibility results by alberto or
vanetta because we can cook with these
lower bounds
since we focus on a special kind of
non-black box reductions which we call
canonical reductions
and a limitation of our work is that the
memory type signature scheme we
considered regardless of fully tied or
not
are proven in the random oracle model
so we think uh getting a memory tight
multi-challenge secure digital signage
scheme in the standard model is an
interesting open problem
so that's all from my talk thank you
very much i'm happy to answer any
questions
thank you lee so
any questions for the speaker
okay let me check
okay so i
have one simple one simple question
it is about about the
uh the
practical meaning of this uh kind of
digital signature so which kind of
scenario would
need these
digital signatures secure in the
multi-challenges setting
a very simple example
yeah thank you very much and uh i think
practically the uh the number of forged
queries for a practical adversary is
unbounded the adversary will always try
to force signatures
and a single challenge security
without considering memory single
challenge security tightly implies the
multi-challenge setting
and i think uh memory tightness uh has
uh
uh has some impact for
uh practical usage because uh in
practical world the number of
the number of forge attempts by the
anniversary is unbounded
okay
if there's no more questions so thank
you link so we'll go to the next talk
okay
uh the
the next paper is uh compact adaptively
secure fe for attribute where he starts
painting and the speaker is effort
okay
hi everyone i'm tapas from iit kharagpur
i'll be presenting your paper compact
activity secondary for attribute
rotations from kailin and this is joint
work with buddhist from entity research
so in fashion encryption there is a
setup authority who generates a master
secret key and a master public key using
master probability one can encrypt a
messaging and computes the ciphertext
city now a decrypter who wants to
decrypt the ciphertext city requires for
a functional security corresponding to
this function f
and the central authority will now
compute a secret kskf using the master
secret key and gives this to the
decryptor so that the decrypter will now
uh decrypt the separate city and learns
function of the messaging and nothing
else
so in this work we construct encryption
scheme for attribute rotation
functionality introduced in agw 20. so
in such a scheme message is divided into
two parts one is the public part first
one which is x i and the second one is
gi which is the private part so the
functionality is as follows the function
of the message m is equal to summation
over i f x i transpose g i and now say
this i is
not a pyramid bounded in the setup then
we call it environment slot scheme
so to get an idea about the importance
of this sort of functionality i will
discuss some special cases suppose if
outputs a fixed vector then it will
imply inner product function encryption
or ipfe and if z is a payload and a
feasible and function then it will be
attribute-based encryption
and thirdly if effects is of the form
white terms gx then it will be attribute
based inaccurate function encryption
recently explored in acgu20
so in agew20 they proposed a few for
attribution functionality with some
interesting features
the first one is that their scheme
support unbounded slot and the weight
functions are abb's or arithmetic
branching program
and their ciphertext size depends only
on the size of the private part of the
message and the security is based on
killing or mdds assumptions which are
known to be standard assumption however
they prove security uh only in the
semi-adaptive simulation security model
and we know that it is not a realistic
model
so uh it seems that c selective security
is weaker than semi-adaptive and
semiadoptive is weaker than adaptive
security however due to gkw 16 selective
security is kind of equivalent to
semi-adaptive security and known
customization from semi-adaptive to
adaptive security requires the
underlying symmetrically sql functional
encryption to support general
functionality so due to this fact egw20
posed open problem in the paper to
construct a fee for attribute rotation
functionality with unbounded slot for
evps to compact ciphertext and
adaptively simulation security based on
standard assumptions
so before going to uh discuss our work
let's uh see some previous works and
challenges in solving this different
problem so in the right hand side sorry
in the left hand side of the screen we
see that um some of the existing abe's
which are presented in the context of
partially attribute hiding setting first
two schemes are semi-adaptively secured
whereas the last one by duty uh
they they were able to prove this uh
adaptive simulation security for uh what
the policies are abps and in the right
hand side we see some functional
encryption schemes uh for different
functionalities the last two uh
fees are semi-actively secure whereas
the first one is uh adaptively secured
only in the indistinguishable base model
and lastly in a series of work we see a
functional encryption scheme for
interpreter functionality uh which is
proved secured in the adaptive
simulation the security model and
it supports unbounded collision so what
you can see that is that uh achieving uh
adaptive uh simulation security with
unbounded collision for function
encryption is really a challenging task
and till now i think we know it only for
linear functions
so in this work we present adaptively uh
simulation secure function incubation
scheme for attribute detection
functionality where the weight functions
are ebp
first we present a one slot scheme then
we uh convert it to a unbounded scheme
with a small caveat which i will explain
in the next slide our still support
complex ciphertext
meaning that the ciphertext size will
not grow with the multiple occurrence of
a particular attribute in the wait
function and also uh the security is
based on standard keying assumption and
from the technical ground we extend the
ll 20 framework from a b to a three ah
that means from payload hiding to
partially attribute hiding setting
so i will now discuss it uh our
a very
high level overview for a few scheme
so we consider two cryptographic tools
first one is the arithmetic key
governing scheme aka in short akgs which
is an information theory tool and it is
a particular type of randomized encoding
and the second one is function hiding
inner product function encryption which
is a computational two line in short i
will call it ipv so firstly using akgs
and ipfe we construct a one key one
ciphertext secure
one slot one f scheme in the uh secret
key setting and then we convert it to a
full-fledged one slot fes game in the
public key setting however for that we
require slotted version of the ipfe
next to convert our one slot 1f scheme
to a one slot one extf scheme which is
again in the secret key setting and it
supports single key and a single
ciphertext so what is the xtv
functionality so in this functionality
secret keys are generated for a function
f and effector y and the ciphertext is
computed for a public vector x and two
private vectors a z and w
and during decryption we learn f x
transpose j plus y transpose w
the next step is to extend this one slot
one extreme scheme to a full fledge one
ex one slot extf scheme and the idea uh
that we have used is the same as the
idea that were involved in the previous
transformation that means we need
slotted function of the ipv
and finally ah we use the transformation
of agw 20 with a little modification ah
to convert the one slot extp scheme into
an unbounded slot scheme
uh in our onslaught if you scheme uh
adversary can query any polynomial
number of secret keys both before and
after the chinese cipher text however in
the unbounded slot scheme the adversary
can query only a priori bounded number
of cipher text ah before the status
cipher text however uh after the chinese
effects it can query any polynomial
number of uh
secret queries
so yeah so this is a open problem to
construct this unbounded scheme with uh
poly poly uh security in the adaptive
security model
thank you and for more details please
look into our paper
and yeah i'm open to any question thank
you so much
do we have any questions for the speaker
okay so i got one one question for you
so
talking about the like performance of
the
algorithms like do we have have you ever
done some uh
experiments or to run run the algorithm
on the normal pc how is the performance
yeah
yeah this this work is completely based
on bi-linear pairing and i haven't done
any sort of implementation so i i will
not be able to tell how much run runtime
is and all
yeah okay okay okay that's fine so this
is completely the theory can work
[Laughter]
i haven't done it
from
the point of view of theoretically right
okay so our last talk is uh posting the
security of brian signature schemes and
the speaker is michael so michael could
you please hear the slides
michael are you
are you here in the room
okay is michael here
boosting the security of blind signature
schemes
and speaker is michael lawsonburg
is michael here
he appears not to be here
yeah yeah yeah
so
shall we close the section or shall we
keep waiting
uh we could wait a couple minutes but
okay i don't think he's been here at all
and i think he's on the east coast so it
would be 7 a.m
okay
i think it's unlikely he's going to show
up
okay
perhaps it's best just to close the
session then
okay
okay so
i think we have a
down the job so
this is a station of the advanced
security and digital signatures yes
thank you