okay so uh can i start
yes
okay
uh
uh so welcome to the session of quantum
security i am atino hussain
and we'll serve as the session cheers
with andreas harrison
this session has seven talks
each talk is given five minutes followed
by five minutes to runways
if you have any questions on the talks
please write them on the journey chat or
the chat or zoom
and so the first talk of this session
is on the non-tightness of measurement
based reactions for key encapsulation
mechanism in the quantum random oracle
model by how don't you
finish
okay
we saw your slides for a moment there
okay actually
uh if we have any technical difficulties
on showing us right i would like to over
you to the last of this session
are you able to share your screen
okay let me try again i'm sorry
okay
it looks good
you should do it in full screen mode
right
yes
okay okay i'm sorry
and i'm talking about the paper on the
90s of a merriment based reduction for
camp in the quantum realm local model
this is a jungle with the dream
fundraiser and the gym
the quantum cryptography is to design
classical cryptosystems that remain
secure for a quantum adversary recently
nissa launched our pqc project and
published a cover proposal for pke
signature and cam in particular more
than half of the submissions are camps
in this submission they first construct
a cp's qrpke anderson use a generic
transform called the physical model
to build a
cc secure cam we usually call such a
transformer by f4 in short i feel like a
generic constructions are based on an
idealized model called the random oracle
model
uh in a quantum world where improving
post corner security
and when you already needs the quantum
renault model where the adversary can
call the red marker with a quantum state
typically when proving uh
security of
our scheme when usually construct a
reduction that runs anniversary as a
subroutine to break the underlying
harder problem
in the random work model improving the
industrial ability when you only use a
quite basic reduction that use a high
quality from the adversary to break the
underlying hard problem
such as improving the effort transform
the reactor team br oep and so on
in the quantum renault model the quantum
counterpart of coil based reduction is
called environmental based reduction
that measures our query from the
adversary and they use the outcome to
break the underlying heart problem
reduction is called black box if it
mainly uses the adversary's input output
behavior
well
non-black box reduction requires the
knowledge of but versus the internals
for example adversary codes
header reduction with the smaller
tetanus and tennis gap are desirable for
practice
for iphone consortiums from standard cp
assumptions test reduction can be
achieved in a black box manner in the
random local model
however all the quantum render model
reductions are handheld and most of them
are measurement based
in particular the current black box
reductions have a quadratic security
loss
although these uh although these
quadratic security laws can be avoided
by a number box reduction uh that
reliance uh let us
newly introduced technique called the
marijuana measure that
part of this technique can only apply to
reversible adversaries
well the current black box reductions
can cover arbitrary adversaries this is
quite different from the results in the
random local model
where our linear security loss can be
achieved in a black box manner
the
quadratic security loss erased from the
usage of the volume to hiding technique
the way to hide in technique is an
essential technique to prove to prove
quantum security of a crypto system it
gives a reduction from a such problem to
a decision problem
recently several works tried to improve
the tennis of the webinar hiding however
as in the case of apholectric camps the
tennis improvements are only restricted
to the fact of the of reduction loss and
the quadratic securities still exists
a natural question is that for every lag
camps and the under the hiding technique
is the quranic secular loss avoidable
for environment-based black box
reduction
in this paper i will give a formal
affirmative answer for the above
question forever like a camps which you
we should environment based the black
box reduction from breaking the standard
the cpu security of the underlying gpu
to breaking the cc security
and the resulting cam will inevitably
incur quadratic securities
such a impossibility result can also be
extended to the chinese limits of the
general general
black box around the heading
main techniques is that we first
construct a specific quantum adversary
that breaks the cc security of the
resulting camp by acquiring the random
vocal with a well-designed quantum state
and serving a
discrimination problem between two
quantum states
the advantage of this spec
of this basic adversary is at least
square root p p is a positive real
and using the metal reduction we show
that an environment based on black box
reduction that runs its basic adversary
as a subroutine to break to break the
standard swiss gold here of the
underlying cheeky url now we have around
the atmosphere
combining these two points we can get
our results
this is a short summary of our work
okay okay
uh thanks for listening
thank you for the talk um i don't see
questions in the chat
i is there anyone that has a question or
wants to unmute
otherwise i think we're already a bit
ahead of time so uh
maybe
we proceed to the next talk
okay same uh thank you again for uh
so i would like to move to the next talk
the next talk is redeeming reset in
differentiability and applications to
post quantum security by mark gendry and
mark chandlery religious group
mark please
all right
can everyone see my slides
yes
all right great
um
so in this talk will be about
indifferentiability
uh indifferentiability is a
strengthening of indistinguishability
which is used when you're trying to
build
one idealized object from another here
i've diagrammed
the case where you're trying to build a
random oracle from a random permutation
p and p inverse
called an ideal cipher
our goal is to justify that the
resulting construction that we call c
is in some sense as good as an ideal
hash function also called a random
oracle and in differentiability is a way
to formalize this goal
indifferentiability can be seen as a
form of universal composability for
idealized objects
and indeed malware at all show that
indifferentiability composes well and
also that interdifferentiable
constructions are as good as the ideal
object
in the sense that it implies security in
what are known as single stage games
single stage games are games making up
most of cryptography where a single
adversary interacts with the challenger
because of these nice properties proofs
of interference ability have become a
popular way to justify the security of
cryptosystems such as hash functions
for general multi-stage gains
unfortunately plane and
differentiability is insufficient
multi-stage games are those like kdm
security deterministic public encryption
leakage resilience and so forth
where there are multiple
adversary parties interacting with the
challenger
for these kind of games we instead need
a strengthening of indifferentiability
called reset and differentiability which
looks basically identical to plane and
differentiability with the important
difference that the simulator in the
definition
is required to be stateless
but there is an analogous
theorem by wrist and part at all that
shows that
if you're
if you are able to have a stateless
simulator
then
you get composition and security in
multi-stage games
unfortunately reset to differentiability
has some limitations
the main one being that something called
domain extension is impossible
so domain extension is taking any small
domain ideal object
like a small compression function
and constructing a large domain object
such
as what you would do with merkle dam
guard
or
the sponge construction is also a
version of domain extension taking a
small permutation small ideal
permutation and constructing a
large hash function
as domain extension has been one of the
main applications of indifferentiability
this strong the strong impossibility has
more or less led to recent
indifferentiability
being abandoned with
relatively few subsequent works in the
area
so our starting point for this work is
two observations
first we observe that domain extension
is not always necessary
for example when using a random oracle
to construct
say deterministic public encryption
if the size of your messages are bounded
then it turns out you only need a fixed
domain random oracle
the second observation is that basically
nothing is known about reset
indifferentiability beyond the
impossibility of domain extension
prior work somewhat surprisingly didn't
even establish whether you could
shrink the domain take a large
ideal hash function and construct a
small ideal hash function
now this seems like it would be trivial
but it turns out that doing this with a
stateless simulator is actually not
obvious
um other interesting open questions
include whether you can build a fixed
size random oracle from an ideal cipher
and vice versa
so this leads us to our work
where we give a handful of new results
on reset and differentiability
first we prove that
domain extent
sorry domain shrinkage
is in fact possible with reset
interferenceability
using
the obvious construction where you just
sort of pad out the domain with
with zeros
and then hash with the bigger
hash function
to get a small one
[Music]
we also investigate the natural approach
to building a random oracle from a
random permutation
where you first pad the input and then
truncate the output you can think of
this as the sponge construction for
a single block
and we show that as long as the sum of
the input and output lengths
are at most the block length of the
ideal cipher that you get reset in
differentiability
on the other hand we show that this
restriction on input and output length
are necessary and by giving an explicit
reset indifferentiability attack
if the input length plus output length
exceed the block length
of the permutation and this is in
contrast to the plane and
differentiability setting
where basically any non-trivial amount
of padding and truncating will get you
security
then the final
result is basically showing that all of
our
results lift to the quantum setting
and why this is interesting is that
reset interferentiability is actually
very amenable to quantum proof
techniques and previous quantum and
differentiability results required
sophisticated quantum machinery
on the other hand we don't need this and
our proofs are relatively accessible
and as a consequence we give
we show that ideal ciphers in particular
give random oracles
which was previously unknown quantumly
even if we were to ignore recent
interpretability so even under plane and
differentiability this was
not previously known
right so that's all i have thanks
thanks a lot for the talk
are there any questions in the zoom chat
i don't see any um
wait a second
if there are some
insulip
so to this point um i've had one
question maybe i didn't manage to read
the paper yet but uh is the idea to
essentially reprogram the
the permutation or
yeah so um
uh in my longer slides i i i have it
diagram just so there's there's a couple
uh here let me actually here
so there's a there's a couple
um bits that are needed so first so for
domain
shrinkage
um
basically what we need is a way to
simulate the the part of the domain that
we're truncating and we need to be able
to do this without state
and basically what we show is that you
can
kind of
steal part of the
the random oracle that the simulator has
access to
and use that as sort of a um
it's kind of a state that you is
immutable
um
and so we show how we can actually
essentially get if the simulator has
access to a random oracle that you can
simulate additional random workables
additional
ideal permutations or whatever you need
in order to you know fill out the domain
and then for
constructing
uh random articles from ideal ciphers
what we need to do is what we basically
do
is we need to allow our stateless
simulator
to be able to um
you know answer
the
permutation queries and apparently also
the inverse queries
and
the way we do that is we
we simulate in the permutations in a way
where
in this um sort of the junk part that we
are throwing away
we actually encode
using more ideal ciphers and random
oracles and whatnot we actually encode
information about the input in the
stateless way that allows the simulator
to know how to invert it
um
and then our
[Music]
sort of barrier or impossibility here is
sort of
essentially what it shows us that that
is necessary that the only way you can
simulate is if you can encode the
the input
into this trash uh bits that you throw
away and that gives the
the desired inequality
i see
thanks a lot sir there's no question
anymore in sudip then i would say we
continue to the next talk thanks again
thank you
okay then i'd like to move to the next
talk
the next talk is franchised quantum
money by uh basker robots and mark
chandra i hope my pronunciation is
correct and the
vascular robots ready that looks
are you ready
hi
uh so my name is bosker uh
and today i'll be talking about some
work that i did on quantum money with
mark sandri
okay so
we are interested in studying uh quantum
money which seeks to use quantum states
uh to create uh basically unclonable uh
banknotes
uh this is not something that digital
currency could achieve classically
uh but thanks to the no cloning theorem
we at least have hope that it's possible
using quantum information
so in particular
the
banknotes or the money scheme that we're
designing
should have two properties
the first is unclonability this means
that if an adversary is given and
banknotes they shouldn't be able to
produce
uh n plus one banknotes that all
pass verification and look like valid
money
um the second uh property that we want
is called local verification
this means that it should be possible
for anyone even an untrusted user
to verify the bank notes without
communicating with the bank or any other
trusted third party
during verification
so we call this local verification
because there's no communication that
needs to be done to a
far off
trusted third party
so
in particular
the field of quantum money has been
interested in public key quantum money
in which there's a single public key
that anyone can use to verify banknotes
locally
so i'm interested in studying the
quantum money problem because it seems
foundational to the study of unclonable
cryptographic primitives
uh in recent years there have been
proposals for a variety of unclonable
primitives
such as copy protection copy detection
etc
and these constructions generally use
techniques that were originally
developed for quantum money
and so my approach is
by developing really good techniques for
the quantum money problem
uh hopefully they'll generalize and
allow us to construct a variety of
unclonable primitives
uh any questions so far
i don't think so
cool
so the state of
public key quantum money is uh there
have been a variety of
attempts
to construct public key quantum money
over the past decade
um but none of them have
sort of succeeded in constructing public
key quantum money from well-studied
assumptions
there was a
recent line of work that constructed
public key quantum money from
post-quantum secure i o
but of course we don't have
constructions of that from well-studied
assumptions
so this work
takes a slightly different approach
we'll define a new form of quantum money
called franchised quantum money which is
weaker than public key quantum money and
easier to construct
but it achieves the two properties that
we care about
which are unclonability and local
verification
previously public key quantum money was
the only primitive that achieved those
properties
so the fact that we can achieve this
without meeting public key
is
surprising
the main idea is this so in public key
quantum money verification is done using
a single public key that anyone has
access to including adversaries
in franchised quantum money anyone who
wants to verify a bank note can get a
unique secret key
to use for verifying banknotes
so
this means even an adversary could
request a unique secret key
and the scheme would remain secure
so every key can be used to verify every
banknote
and the security guarantee that we'll
give is as long as you keep your key
secret
nobody can fool you
um into accepting an invalid banknote
to
i guess to illustrate the difference
between these two definitions
if you leak your key accidentally in the
franchised model
in other words if you make your key
public the security guarantees no longer
hold and it might be possible for an
adversary to create a fake banknote that
looks like the real thing when you're
using that key for verification
any questions
i don't think so yet
cool
also people in the
in the call feel free to to ask as we go
along
okay
so the um construction that we give i'll
just summarize it at like ten thousand
feet
um basically
when we try to construct public key
quantum money the problem that we
generally run into is
the verification key also gives the
adversary enough information to
counterfeit successfully
so our approach is to take this
verification key
split it into lots of pieces and then
give each verifier one piece of the key
so in our construction even having a
single piece of the key
is sufficient to verify the banknotes
but because an adversary given one key
doesn't know any of the other pieces
it's hard for them to create fake
banknotes that will fool verifiers using
one of the other pieces
in a little bit more detail our
construction is based on the proposal
for quantum money from hidden subspaces
so
the master key would be a description of
this
subspace which has n over two dimensions
and in our construction
each franchised verification key is a
small number of dimensions from that
subspace
and so each verifier just gets a small
random subspace from the hidden subspace
finally our construction requires a
collusion bound
so this means that uh we guarantee that
our scheme is secure but only if uh
like the number of colluding adversaries
is uh o of square root n
um
what we find is that if if multiple
verifiers are dishonest and if they
collude and pull their keys together
uh they can learn quite a bit about the
master secret key
and if there are
more than square root n of them they can
learn the entire master secret key
um
so
the collision bound is a barrier to
making this construction practical but
we believe it can be
improved and even eliminated in future
work
cool that's it
any questions
thanks a lot
um
do we have any questions i don't see any
in the zoom chat
and sulip
there's also nothing yet
so maybe in the interest of time we move
on because we still have port clocks i
think
yeah i think so
uh so if uh
if you have any talks on the talks uh if
you are sorry if you have any questions
on the talks please uh write them on
your lipsense or the attack on zoom
and so next i would like to
move to the next strokes
the next talk is
quantum computational
predicate binding commitments with
application in quantum zero knowledge
arguments for nlp by jung yang
and the junior religious
please hi hi thanks
so first let me share my screen
okay
okay uh
can you hear me
yes hi can i hear you and i can you see
he was right
okay thanks okay let me begin
my name is ji yen from china university
and the title of my talk today is
quantum computationally practical
binding commitments with their
application in quantum zero knowledge
arguments for mp
okay
so let me first state my our main
results
we know that from quantum secure when we
function we can construct a quantum bit
commitment
that is in particular computationally
binding
however we know that with the general
quantum binding the committed value is
no longer unique it could be a
superposition
so
it's natural to ask uh what happened uh
if we compose quantum bit commitment in
parallel to commit as gene which is
typical in application
we ask what binding property can a
resulting quantum stream commitment
scheme that satisfy
is
is it useful in applications
this question has been opened for
almost two decades
and in this work i will make a first
step towards answering these questions
so in particular i will prove
the following so-called computational
practical binding property
that is any polynomial time boundary
center cannot open commitment in two
ways third to satisfy two inconsistent
predicates at respect respectively
and this is the first nontrivial quantum
computational stream binding that is
both useful and can be instantiated with
the minimal complex complexity
assumption
and if we plug quantum bit commitments
in bloom's zero knowledge protocol we
obtain the first quantum material
knowledge arguments for mp solely based
on final secure runway functions
but with soundness error at one half
and the main technical part of this work
lies in establishing these computational
practical binding property
okay this is our main result and now let
me introduce two important concepts that
are introduced in this work
namely patent predicate and stream
practical binding
they are motivated by the soundness
analysis of bloom's protocol
but we believe a layer of independent
interest and generally enough in
elsewhere
so a patent for a patent predict uh
first first gene to satisfy such a
predict predict it should exhibit a
certain pattern somewhere
and i will not remark that a weakness
might be needed to compute the pattern
or where it locates in polynomial time
for example i will consider a bloom's
protocol that qualifies final
verification induces two particles
p0 and p1 corresponding to the
qualifier's challenge 0 and 1
respectively
for the practical practical p0 a pattern
is just
just a whole stream
that should be like in photographs of
some permutation
with the sunnis is just a permutation pi
a silica selected by the plural
for the plastic political p1 the pattern
is n1's let it form an n cycle and the
witness is
the location of a hamiltonian cycle
these two predicates are in consists
consistent when the input graph g is not
hamiltonian
by inconsistent i mean they are disjoint
no string can satisfy both of them
simultaneously
now with pattern predict project we can
define practical practical binding with
respect to p0 and p1
namely
if a center can open commitments so that
the reward value satisfy p0 with
probability 1
then it cannot open the same commitments
so that the reward values satisfy p1
with a non-negligible probability
here we highlight that
now the word value could be a
superposition of exponentially many
genes with general quantum binding
or put it in some quantum formalization
we needed to show that accepting
subspaces p0 and p1
that are introduced induced by particles
p0 and p1 are almost orthogonal
up to any polynomial time realizable
unitary that does not touch the
commitment space
and we say practical binding with
practical binding with respect to any
pair of inconsistent predicates
and the main technical difficulty lies
in
in establishing practical binding one
needed to try to avoid the potential
exponential blow up of error that are
incurred by this superposition of
possible exponential and many genes
and by our our technique we actually
failed to prove a full practical binding
but that are
generally enough for our applications
okay okay uh that's all what i want to
say thanks for your listening and uh you
can questions are welcome
thanks a lot
are there any questions
so maybe when we wait if people
add a question also for the the previous
speakers please check the chat every now
and then um to see because there's at
least one question for the first speaker
um
that you could still answer in the chat
then
um
by the way you're still sharing
so okay
now you're showing the chat what's
actually good
okay
um
okay but i don't see any question right
now then
i would say we move on to the next talk
thank you again
okay thank you
thank
you
okay
let's move to the next talks
and the next talk is
quantum encryption with certified
deletion registered
public key attribute attribute-based and
classical communication by tiger hiroka
takashi yamakawa
and tiger hiroka
are you ready
yes can you see the slide
yes i can see your slides and i can hear
you yeah please stop
hello everyone my name is taiga hiroka
in this talk i talk about quantum
encryption without hydration represent
public key attribute base and classical
communication this occasion to work with
stomach
monkey and takashima
first let me explain the prior work a
one-time secret key encryption with sat
hydration was introduced by broadband
and islam in tcc 2020.
in this primitive there is a
certification security in addition to
the functionality of one-time secret key
this security unit guarantees a
following
first sender generates a secret key
and generates a quantum ciphertext
and sends it to a receiver
after she sends a quantum ciphertext if
she changes her mind under answer there
is a ciphertext she requests to him to
delete the ciphertext
and she receives a classical certificate
which guarantees that he deletes a
quantum ciphertext
and then she checks whether this
certificate is correct or not using a
verification key
when correct he cannot obtain the
message name correctly even if he
receives the secret key of this
ciphertext
the construction has disadvantages as
follows
first the construction is limited to the
setting of one-time secret key
encryption
second in their construction sender
needs quantum operation
third in the construction direction is
privately believable which means that
the sender needs a verification key kept
secret
in our work we have improved improved
these disadvantages as horrors
in this talk i talk about quantum
encryption with saturation where the
sender is completely classical
in our construction we have used noisy
trapped rocky function f and injective
trapped function g to construct a
protocol
these functions are constructed from lw
assumption and have some cryptographic
primitives properties
using these properties a classical
sender can generate a quantum state in
the receiver's register
in a nutshell idea of our construction
is to use f-type function and g-type
function
instead of directly sending bb a throw
state with quantum channel
now first i explain how to use f-type
function
first across carcinda generates f-type
function on trapdoor and sends function
to receiver
the receiver generates super position
state and coherently evaluates f4 waves
if he measures the third register in the
computational basis
he obtains a post he obtains a
measurement outcome y and the
post-measurement quantum state
if he measure this quantum state in the
computational basis this quantum state
collapses to the classical bit string
on the other hand if you measure this
quantum state in the normal basis this
quantum state collapses to the random
classical string e and d that satisfies
this equation
noisy drop down closely function f
satisfy adaptive hardware bit property
which guarantees that quantum polynomial
time receiver cannot obtain both
this
and this at the same time use the
probability more than one half
and you know in your construction we
have used the injective drop to our
function g in addition to this function
first a classical sender generates
function d and drop down on the sensor
function to the receiver
note that from the injected imbalance of
this function g
quantum polynomial time receiver cannot
distinguish this function from this
function
this property is very important for
construction
then the receiver generates
superposition state and coherently
evaluates g of x
if he measures the third register in the
computational basis he obtains a
measurement outcome y and the
post-measurement quantum state
if he measure this quantum state in the
completion basis
this quantum state crosses to the cross
carpet string on the other hand if you
measure this quantum state in that
amount basis this quantum state crosses
to the random classical bit string
now i explain a construction note that
this construction is not formal
construction if you are interested in
the homework construction please read a
paper
first a classical sender generates a
random secret random classical string as
a secret key where zero denotes g type
function and one denotes
f-type function
then she generates these functions
according to this classical string at
the same time she didn't extract over
and send them to the sender a receiver
receiver generates this quantum state
and sends the measurement outcomes to
the sender at this point she can know
the post measurement quantum state using
measurement outcomes on the trap door on
the other hand he can't know the post
management quantum state from the
property of these functions therefore
this process is as if a classical center
generates this quantum state
in the receiver's registers blindly
then she encrypts plain text m using b1
x1 as a horse where it is a random
oracle
after she sends this cipher text if she
changes her mind and wants there is a
ciphertext she requests to him to
measure all these content states in the
demand basis and receive the measurement
outcomes as a classical certificate
then she checks whether this e and d
satisfies this equation
when yes
he cannot obtain the information message
m correctly even if he receives a
location function which is which is us
which is a secret key of this ciphertext
analog in order to prove this
construction security we have introduced
a new property of these functions
which we call cotton cheese adaptive
hardcore property
it is relatively straightforward to
previous security from this property
therefore i skip it
instead of that
i explain an intuitive understanding of
this property
cotton choose adaptive hardcore property
intuitively guarantees that when each
end satisfies this equation quantum
polynomial time receiver cannot obtain
b1 and x1 even if he receives the
location functions after he obtained e e
and d that satisfies this equation
and i'll expand the intuitive proof of
captain choose adaptive hardcore
property
in order to obtain this e and d he has
to measure these two quantum states in
the normal basis on the other hand he
cannot distinguish these functions
therefore in order to obtain this e and
d with a high probability he has to
measure all these quantum states in the
damage bases
on the other hand if he measure this
quantum state in the normal basis this
quantum state collapses to the random
class carbide string and he can no
longer obtain b1 x1 even if he receives
a location function
this is an intuitive proof of our carton
choose adaptive hardcore property
now i changed my talk if you are
interested in more homage these results
please read our paper thank you for your
listening
thanks a lot for the talk
are there any questions
so we've got nothing on soon
so how long uh answer catherine's
question on the chat but i also don't
see new questions there
then i would suggest we move on
thanks a lot for the talk
uh so i'd like to think uh again for
uh the previous talk
and i would like to move to the next
talk and
the next stop is
tight adaptive reprogramming in the
queue room
by alex b gullo
and kathleen hoberman and andreas
harrison and christian madins
and kathleen i think cousin hoverman's
village
yeah hi everyone can you see my slides
and hear me fine yes i can hear you and
i can see your throats yeah please start
okay great thanks
yeah welcome to my talk about adaptive
reprogramming and the quantum random
oracle model
and before i dive into our results i
will first sketch the motivation of this
paper
the motivation was
random oracle model programmability
which is a nice property of the random
oracle model that allows for simple
proof strategies and
the strategy is as follows we argue that
if a random oracle has not yet been
queried on a particular pre-image x
then the oracle value can be chosen on
the fly by the game
and if we do so cleverly um
we allow the game to be simulated by a
reduction that then does not have to
rely on secret knowledge like for
example a secret key
but unfortunately the random oracle
model does not suffice to argue quantum
security
which is why it was generalized 10 years
ago
in a way that allows quantum access to
the random oracle and hence allows to
argue security against quantum attacks
in classical networks
but with this generalization
there comes some challenges for example
any query to the random oracle might
contain a pre-image x with some
amplitude
and this might not be trivially
checkable because checking would mean
measuring and hence altering the state
and
potentially derailing the attacker
so an important question is can we
adaptively reprogram in the quantum
random oracle model
and our results are in a line of work on
this question and a comparison will be
given after i have shown you what we
found out
so our result is a reprogramming toolbox
and i'll first sketch the simplest case
of reprogramming and then afterwards
show how this result can be generalized
so what we consider is a distinguisher
tasked with distinguishing between
quantum access to the
general random oracle h0
or access to its
reprogrammed version h1
and the game goes as this we have a
distinguisher run in the reprogramming
game
in the first phase of the game
it will have quantum access to the
oracle h0 that is not reprogrammed
and at some point it will issue a
reprogramming instruction
in the game we'll pick
a pre-image x and a random oracle value
y uniformly at random
and set the reprogrammed oracle to map x
to y and coincide with h0 anywhere else
afterwards the game will forward the
pre-image to the distinguisher
and in the second phase
the distinguisher has either access to
h0 or the reprogrammed version h1
and at the end it has to output a
guessing bit to indicate to which
oracle it believes it had access to in
the second phase so classically it's
pretty easy to see that the
distinguishing advantage can be upper
bounded in terms of the number of oracle
queries in the size of x because
to have any distinguishing advantage
whatsoever the distinguisher would have
had to query h0
on x in the first phase
and our findings are that quantumly
there exists a similar bound
and still we have this fraction of
number of oracle queries and size of x
but we have to consider square root and
also multiply by a small factor
however this bound is tight
as we have found a matching attack which
will be sketched in the youtube talk
and now i can sketch how we furthermore
generalized this result
so the first important generalization of
course is that we want to reprogram many
times not just once
so we pick
several reprogramming positions x12 xr
second important generalization is that
we now let the distinguisher determine
on which positions uh
we will reprogram
by
telling the game the distributions
according to which the positions will
have to be chosen
and the third generalization is that
those distributions come with some
additional site information
that is also forwarded
to the distinguisher
to compare with previous results
so no none of the previous work
considered any distribution that was
anything else but uniform
and
yeah clearly this also means that the
distributions did not offer any side
information
and to compare the bounds i just
conf
considered the uniform case to keep
things
pretty simple
so what we see here is that our bound
improves by a small factor and more
importantly it also improves by a factor
of square root of q
and with this toolbox at hand we can
also
we were also able to give some security
proofs in the quantum random oracle
model
so we improved
on previous work on vhm signatures and
the message compression routine of xmss
because we now have this toolbox that
allows for conceptually simple proofs
and um also is a bit tighter
and we also gave the first proof in the
quantum random oracle model that the
hedge future mere construction is secure
against several fault injections and
one's misuse
and with that i want to conclude my talk
and i'm happy to take any questions
thanks a lot
nice talk great result
are there any questions for catskin
so i don't see any question in the zoom
chat
i also don't see any question in the
sulup ah now there's a question a
special question
thank you for your time does the bond
get worse in the non-uniform case
um
yeah a nice question the answer is no
this will also be presented in the long
version so let me go back to the slide
with the branch
yeah so here we see a fraction of q over
the size of x and
one over the size of x represents the
uniform distribution
that i picked
and what we would consider instead if we
go to the non-uniform case would be the
maximum probability of any of those
distributions hitting a particular
element
this is all that changes
okay
is there any further question
uh if there is no question i would like
to ask one question
uh so i think i think about uh the
uh bound for no uniformities uh maybe
i'm sorry i may
miss something but so
do you also get as a tight one for
knowing your informal case
um i'm not sure so we didn't approve
tightness overbound for the non-uniform
case we only proved it for the uniform
case i think
and do you think uh the uh
interesting things about uh concerning
about
tithing is for non-uniform case what do
you think
you are not so much interested in
uh no sorry it is not so interesting to
study the titans for non-uniform case
i think that's a very interesting
question it was just out of the scope of
this paper because it was already very
long because we had to include all those
uh security proofs
okay thank you
maybe i can add that
i would expect the non-uniform case also
to be tight
and i think it should be possible to
prove that by reducing it to the uniform
case via some kind of asymptotic
equi-partition property
so by taking
many copies of the non-uniform
case
oh interesting thank you thank you
thanks a lot then uh yeah i guess we can
move on to the next talk
okay i'd like to move to the next talk
the last talk of this session
and the next stock is qcb
efficient quantum central authenticated
encryption by retirement power
saving
and mariana
for the introduction and for listing all
the quarters so that i can
jump straight into the top
okay so we begin with ocd3 which is a
very popular
authenticated encryption mode
and it is
it just uses these offsets which are
calculated based on an iv and the block
number and it uses these offsets with
the ecb mode which is highly
parallelizable and this makes it very
lightweight and it's a great one
authentically encryption mode which is
which means it just uses one block
cipher call for message two
so we begin with this and we want we
want to examine
how it
stands up against against a quantum
adversary but unfortunately there are
results already that this is not quantum
secure because there are many periods
for instance if we encrypt the same
message block
twice
and then it saw the cipher text and this
becomes a periodic function of the
message block because
the iv part of the
offsets cancel out cancels out and this
since the period is constant here we can
use siemens uh to recover the
period which is delta 0x or delta 1 and
from that we can do a force easily
and this is just for this differing part
but on the tag part as well
there can be attacks because if we just
uh
we just if we just calculate the tag of
the empty message and with the
same associated data blocks
repeated twice
then the
tag becomes a periodic function of the
associated data block with a constant
period and again we can use symbols so
these are known results
but we are interested in direct one
property of
ocb3 so here we try to examine how we
can fix this fix these weaknesses over
cv3 and still get a great one
authentically encryption mode which is
secure against the quantum interest
so the first idea is that maybe the
offsets are bad because in ocb3 the
offsets consist of uh something from the
a component from the iv solving the
components from the block
and this means that when you exit the
offsets on two successive blocks on the
same iv the energy component gets
cancelled out
but we could modify this and we could
take for instance uh
offset which is i dot ekiv and then this
ig does not cancel out when you xor it
over two blocks
but
but unfortunately there is a stream on
best attack that still works on this
because if you take
one single message with the same id and
then
the same if if you repeat the message
each message block twice like in one two
three four and so on and then if you
take the xor of this ciphertext they
have the same
period and then you can use uh something
like assignments to sample vectors which
are one of
these periods and then you can extract
enough data to solve for ekf
so this does not work and this leads us
to believe that
the main problem in ocb against the
quantum adversary is the open the offset
path
and so we want to modify it in a way
that
these
data on iv and block number is still
used but not as offsets
and so we move on to qcb
and where we
do some kind of domain separation so
essentially we use tweakable block
ciphers
and this was an idea used already in
something called decibit which was used
in the security group for ocb3
but here we see that if we if we process
the tweak in some other way
not using
these
offsets then we can get the good quantum
security of this construction so this is
the qcb it's essentially the same
construction except we have strapped out
the offset part and put everything into
a quick which has the ivd block number
and something for domain separation
but for processing the authenticated
data but
for processing the associated data we
use something else we use the iv as a
inside the tweet for the
block cipher calls for processing the
associated data and this is something
different
from ocb3 where the iv is not used for
dd
but
this
as it turns out to avoid quantum
linearization attacks it is necessary to
use this check
and so this is what is broadly called
qcb and
for the
tweakable block cipher we want something
that is secure against the quantum
atrocity
and if we assume a perfect
quantum security on the
dbc then we can show that this is also
very easy if you have secure
authenticated encryption
but then we explore further we try to
explore uh some
actual tbc which can help us instantiate
this uh ucb
and for this and there can be several
devices for instance there is a
dbc with three block cipher calls for
divisible by asuyama and iwata but
we want to use something that is great
one
because
otherwise our construction is no longer
a report on the block cipher
but we found that the key
tweak insertion dbc but the week is
simply xor with the key actually works
quite well for a purpose
but
there is a caveat that we could not
prove ideal tbc security on the key
driven session and we had to make the
modification that the tweaks have to be
non-adaptive
so that is a modification and by the way
in this model the tweaks are also
classical
and that is a common use case and we use
that here so the tweaks are classical
and non-adaptive in our group and with
that we can show that our qcb has these
goals where
these popular notions of privacy and the
unforgivability are used for privacy we
said it's intune cpa but with the
modification that the ivs are either
random or specified in advance and this
is to take care of the modified security
of the tbc
and for unforgivability we use the bonus
on the notion
where but with the modification that the
ivs are either random or specified
networks and with these modifications we
can we are able to prove the security of
qc
when instantiated with the
key tweaking such
pvc
okay and that is the main result of the
paper
and there are several open questions for
which we can explore like
whether
we can show introduces here security
whether we can define it properly and
whether we can show it and whether we
can use the more recent definition of
blind unforgeability
and
whether we can show the full tv security
of the key tweaking session
and finally whether we can say anything
without the ideal cycle
and the full function is found on ebay
then
there is also a longer version of this
talk on youtube
thanks for your attention if you want
thank you vita um
are there any questions
so i know it's quite early for uh people
but
if there is no other question
i have one so i'd like to ask a question
so
if
uh so uh in your
uh work uh so you assume nouns are
random or specified in advance right
yes
uh so what happens
uh sorry
so what happens if you uh repeat the
announce or announcement is chosen by
advantage uh is
uh both of privacy and authenticity uh
broken
immediately
um uh no so if the nonce is uh repeated
then
then there can be problems they're not
proof doesn't work at all and
if the nonce is not repeated but it's
not declared in advance it's chosen
adaptively adaptively then
i mean we have a hunch that this is
still secure but we could not prove it
because we could not prove the
security of full ideal tbc security
for the tbc
but you know the non-slippy thing is
probably we did not show an attack but
our proof relies heavily on the fact
that the nonce is not repeated
okay thank you
um maybe i can also ask a question um
thanks for the for the target
um
so i was wondering whether um
you think your proof techniques are um
are fit to prove blind affordability or
whether you um whether
other like different techniques are
necessary
so our proof techniques are somewhat
more ad hoc than we would have liked but
the
i mean
in these proofs what the impression we
had was that
there are still no standardized
framework for
making these proofs so some some people
are trying to standardize the database
method for instance which would give us
some sort of counting proofs which can
be put into a standard framework but
here we use some somewhat ad hoc
arguments for the proof so
uh yes for that that may be
generalizable to blind unforgivability
but for that our main problem was
i mean we could not
clearly define how define the problem or
we were not sure how to use them so the
so what i'm trying to say is that the
proof techniques we use were not very
generalizable
okay thanks
okay
i guess
thanks a lot for your talk um
and that was the last talk in the
session
so i think we got
about a 30-minute break now we're even
three minutes early and then there is
the test of time award happening at
10 past the full hour wherever you are
it will be a bit later earlier
than for us
then have a nice day and
see you in half an hour