the general chair of the conference
i hereby announce the opening of asia
cup 2021
asia cup had been in
annual physical events and year 2019 and
moved online last year and this year as
well
due to the corvid 19 pandemic
the number of attempt lease have been
steadily increasing
and reached the peak of 792
last year so this year there have been
561 registered participants
as of rome yesterday utc
and as i just checked that this number
has increased to 590 just now
so among which
180 are student participants
the participants come across from five
continents with majority from europe
asia and north america
here shows a further breakdown by
country with more than 10 participants
this year china has the maximum 77
participants
the conference is organized over five
days so from today to friday this week
with approximately 4 hours per day
starting from 8 am utc
different from last year we will have
parallel technical sessions this year
each technical session consists of live
five minutes presentations of the papers
which are grouped by topics followed by
a q and a parallel panel discussion with
the speakers and the session moderators
so the conference will also feature
invited talks
a ramp session and language specific
social hours
it is our greatest honor to have
professor anju yao to give the iacr
distinguished lecture this year at asia
cup
his talk is entitled with probabilistic
reasoning in cryptography and machine
learning
there will also be two invited talks the
first simulator talk will be given by
kazuo sako
entitled cryptography for a secure
privacy respecting and fair society
what more can we do
the second in-minded talk will be given
by
ee
entitled landing parity with noise
constructions reductions and analysis
the first technical session will feature
the three award papers
there will be a ram session shared by
chicharrok
and
hua when on wednesday the summation
deadline is tomorrow
6 pm utc
there will be three social hour sessions
out of which number one and three will
be organized and language specific
with chinese rule led by ue fung guajang
english room led by
mido nandi odankaman and sherman cho
japanese room led by
masayuki abe
yu sazaki
and rain
fueno
korean room led by hyundai lee and ji
hong shou
please follow the iecr code of conduct
during your participation mute your
microphone are not speaking and use your
real name
you may refer to the portal application
as your main source
questions are welcomed on tulip or
vapoli during the q a
and feel free to reach out
us by emails if you have any questions
we are thankful to our sponsors with
their generous support we are able to
waive the registration fees of many
students
presenters this year
special thanks go to the program coaches
maddie tibochi and huashongwang for
their hard work to select the papers
and come up with a fantastic program
special thanks also go to kevin mcclee
and k mclee for handling all the
technical aspects of the conference
organization
thank you
we are thankful to many others who
offered help that includes
michelle abdallah the isr president
isaiah emergency committee
the conference advisor sanning and
joseph pipsig isa distinguished lecturer
and you young
united speakers
kazuei sako and
asia crypt steering committee program
co-chairs committee and reviewers
session chairs ramp session chairs
users speakers attend lease
and last but not least zhen zhenbao for
help in the organization
we wish to welcome you in singapore in
another time soon and i hope you will
enjoy this program
thank you
now i will handle the control to the
program coaches to start the technical
session on the award papers
okay so thank you very much uh zhang
um
and um i i'd like to join joe in
welcoming everyone to
this uh this year's asia crypt even
though we can't do it physically
um so should we start so should we start
in five minutes for the for the
award session is that correct
in
i guess from 15 right
yeah i see three minutes but okay
30 minutes