yes my apologies it does take a second
no problem
please go ahead
okay oh welcome everyone to round
session me sister institutions
we are happy to share this um azure
crypt 2021 ramp session
so for further run session we have a
couple of talks coming up
and as a
general guideline the speakers will have
about one to five minutes to present
their talk and then
um we'll move on to the next speaker and
we'll introduce each of you
before your talk so please be ready to
to share your screen and to unmute your
microphone
and uh
with that uh let's move on to to the
first half of the ram session
which is about summer school in post
quantum cryptography and the talk will
be given by peter
hi can you can you see my slides uh
maybe like this
yes yes we can see it fine
okay thank you so i'm going to talk
about the summer school in post quantum
cryptography which is uh
happening next year in budapest from the
first to the fifth of august
so budapest is uh it's a fun nice city
with a lot of activities you can go
hiking you can go caving we have thermal
baths which uh date back to the 1500s we
have really cool pubs and nice
historical monuments
uh we are not on the seaside hence no
seafish but it's a nice place to ride
the bike under the rainbow and spot
beautiful falcons on top of the castle
hill
the last one is not actually true i just
wanted to make a pun with the
the
signatures uh lattice-based scheme as
well
um
finally we we also like to stay true to
ourselves and and budapest has some
truly remarkable gems
as you can see on these nice pictures
uh so a little bit of details about the
summer schools so it will be in the last
four five days uh you have we'll have a
lectures and exercise sessions lectures
in the morning exercise sessions in the
afternoon we'll
cover uh
many aspects of post-quantum crypto
lattice-based cryptography codebase
cryptography multivariate cryptography
isogeny-based cryptography and quantum
computing and this is mainly targeted at
master and phd students but of course
like early researchers are also also
welcome we have
excellent in life lectures
um
from who are all experts in their in
their fields
and uh so and and
the the web page of the the summer
school is not quite up yet but this will
eventually be the the working web page
of the school which hopefully will be
operational
uh in the next week or two thank you
thank you peter
next talk uh
will be given by claude
martindale
is on happening in bristol
claude are you ready let's stay yours
yeah
i'm just sharing my screen
okay hopefully you can see that
yes you can see your screen
great so i'm afraid i haven't got any
beautiful puns like peter but uh i'm
also advertising um
some some nice events that you can come
to
so this one is is very soon
um
uh so there's the isotony based
cryptography school that's so soon that
it's in summer 2020 and then it was in
december 2020 and then it was in
december 2021 and now it's going to be
in spring 2022.
um
and in between we had a an online event
uh last summer which uh perhaps some of
you have already come to so this is
almost 100 sure going to be a hybrid
event um
where you can either attend virtually or
in person
very likely according to international
travels you're
only going to be able to attend in
person if you happen to live in the uk
but the good news is that for all you
wonderful researchers living in asia
that that means you don't need to fly
across the world to to come and listen
um so if you're interested in this then
uh that's happening pretty soon
and but if you think oh but all i wanted
to do was come to bristol then you're in
luck because you can still come to
bristol next summer you can go to
peter's school in budapest and then
while you're in europe you might as well
come to bristol the week after
and come to
ant's algorithmic number theory
symposium uh the 15th edition of that
which is also going to be in bristol
and is co-located with the
internationally renowned uh bristol
balloon fiesta and this is a picture of
the bristol balloon fiesta so um if the
number theory or gets a bit too much you
can look in the sky and look at some
beautiful balloons instead
um
so if you want to submit a paper to ants
then uh you've got until the 25th of
february to come up with an idea like
how to spell february correctly for
example
um and submit that to the paper
to the conference so i hope to see you
all in bristol in uh
in the summer and perhaps virtually or
if you're lucky in person in february
thank you very much chloe looking
forward to your summer school in bristol
let's move to the next top the next talk
will be um
um
somewhat uh technical talk with the
title on the technical flaws in ccc
white paper episode three
slash n the talk will be given by
muhammad please the floor is yours
do you hear me
yes we can hear you and we can see your
screen yeah
can barely hear him can you speak up
louder or boost your volume
no we're getting quite a lot of feedback
[Music]
if you're using an external microphone i
believe you should
try something else
okay
uh
um
[Music]
oh
um
[Music]
is really hard to understand anything
okay so we can move to the next talk and
maybe let's come back if he can uh
manage his microphone but you really
should try a different microphone that
one just does not work
okay so the next talk will be delivered
by our president michelin abdullah
michine please
all right
so
so i want to use this opportunity to
thank uh some of the people and also
recall some of the
awards that were given
by the acr
this year
so
for that we start just briefly recalling
that
we we had the program the icf fellows
which recognized outstanding asean
members
for their
professional technical contributions to
the field
so this year uh
the fellow selection committee
was composed by ronald kramer from um as
the chair uh ponjo kim from uh kais
ana this is
so first i would like to thank uh
thank the selection committee for their
job
as we know the selection committee is
actually independent of the board and
they're the ones responsible for
selecting the chairs and this year
we had uh
five uh
five new fellows
that were inducted so craig gentry
judo lindell jose piepcik
so if
this uh
like illuminations uh were due at the
end of the month so it was a bit
for 22 they were it's already passed but
if you if you have intentions to
nominate
people for
future years
please don't forget the deadline
sorry here
so
in earlier just before the run session
started we had the test award test of
time award
which recognized the papers with a last
impact view
impact on the field and in the
particular case of asia crypt
we had
papers that were selected from asia
crypt
and this year
the committee as uh media mentioned
already was formed by julie mar as the
chair nigel smart which will become the
chair for the upcoming year
uh chris park chris pikert
representing uh crypto 2021
uh francoise via standard representing
eurocrypt 2021
and mediterrabushi
representing as a asia crypt 2021
so thank you a lot for your work
uh on this committee and as you know uh
as we just heard from jan's girls
uh a short time ago
uh
he was the winner of the
of the asia crypt 2021 test of time
award
and uh congratulations once again yes
uh
for your award
and as i said like a
plaque with
the test of time of what will be
delivered in person to you
so
and now i would like to have
actually acknowledge the work of people
who have
made
asia crypt 2021 possible
so
for that i would start first
with uh
media thibushi
which
as uh in asia crypt 2021 program
co-chair
so the certificate of appreciation reads
uh that uh the acr recognized uh
meditative for his contribution to the
international association for
cryptological research
and the field of
cryptology research through the role of
program chair of asia crypt 2021
so negin i don't know if you would like
to say a few words
um okay so thank you very much uh for uh
giving me the the opportunity of uh
of running this conference and um
thanks a lot to
um everyone as i said who contributed to
it being a successful event i believe
thank you very much
all right thank you
next i would like to thank uh
uh welcome juan
for the
uh
the second asia group 2021 program
co-chair
uh to
in recognition for uh
his contribution to uh
to the acr in the field of cryptology
research through the role of program
chair of asia crypt 2021.
yeah we'd like to say a few words
okay hello hi everyone okay thank you
for yeah and thank for everyone who made
the
contribution to make this conference
very successful okay yeah thank you
very welcome thank you for your work
uh
i also would like to take this
opportunity to thank uh jian guo
for his role uh
as the asia creep 2021 general chair
so as the certificate of appreciation
reads
with the acr thanks uh
zhang guo in recognition for
his contribution to the iecr in the
field of cryptology research through the
role of general chair of asia creep
2021.
john
would you like to say a few words i
think you you are connected there i
didn't very double check
yeah i'm here
thank you misha
so thank you for the
support for the chance
to me to organize this event
it was very unfortunate that we have to
have this conference online
but i hope uh we will be able to see you
soon in singapore
in yes
soon yeah okay
thank you jim it wasn't it's quite
unfortunate that uh this could not this
event could not be held in person
but uh
hopefully in the future years will
things will be
back to normal or as close to normal as
they can be
and uh hopefully you're gonna have a
chance to
go to singapore next time
thank you
so
uh i also would like to use this
opportunity to
uh thank the ram session chairs uh
chichanok in kong
uh thank you a lot for you your work
since you're gonna have the the
concluding remarks that i will let you
perhaps would like to see a few words
already now or
later during the concluding remarks
i can say a few words i know thank you
very much for
giving us this opportunity to to share
this wrong session it's really a great
pleasure to do this thank you very much
thank you michonne
all right
thank you both
and finally i just
like to thank kevin and kay for
working as the conference
virtual conference administrators
uh it has been uh great working with the
two of you
and you you have done a great work thank
a lot for your help
i don't know if you would like to say a
few words is up to you
uh it's 3am or 4am and i am not
articulate but i really appreciate the
thanks that we get every time
all right thank you
and thank you kevin let's get back to
traveling
yes
so
with this this concludes
my talk on acknowledgements and uh
recalling the awards thank you everybody
thank you michens mohammed are you can
you try again
yeah how about my voice now
yes it's a little bit better
go ahead
okay thank you
all right uh sorry today and
uh so this is the third episode on the
technical source in cccy people
and just be able to recap of what we saw
in the last two episodes that was um
[Music]
confidential computing is neatly defined
there are all the technologies that you
should be disabled for instance
uh multi-party computation and motion
detection or not and has multiple
competing definitions
[Music]
and what is more
interesting here is additional
perspective
is also a part of confidential
and on the second place that is um
completing definition of the terms that
is fiction and multi-party computation
you all know that
encryption is formally defined for
instance with that
as well as multi-party computation is
also defined
so what is maybe this privacy preserving
computation uh term
and what we see here
or what we
[Music]
a general um just like your competition
and it does not have a specific
um
uh meaning assigned to it or
and it can be perceived differently
let's say depending on the privacy goals
that you have functions as an
execution environments given by the
converging and it's like this so i
believe three parts of it an environment
that provides a level of issues with the
following properties the first one being
the data confidentiality
and uh unauthorized entities cannot view
data while it is
and i haven't read here the terms which
are quite big for instance a level of
assurance what is this level of
assurance how is it layered
unauthorized entities what exactly they
are and for instance data is
these three properties for instance are
also satisfied by the adjacent and hence
this definition does not immediately
characterize
and what we also claim is that this
security definition is incomplete
meaning that uh again from gas and
lender definition of security it should
have two perspectives two fundamental
points
um that is
from attacker's perspective perspective
what constitutes a successful attack
and secondly a threat model which is
completely missing in the 63.
um there are some rules like
environments which expanding it means
specific execution environment
environments and it's not used as a
synonym of what one might expect
and for instance here in the white paper
it seems together with the tvs and it's
not defined even in the references
and uh
one
theme specifically is hardware based
social execution environments as i
defined it as i described that in the
definition is dependent on
particular-based specification
environment so it's very important to
define what they are and contrast it
with this software virtualized
education environment however in the
white paper there is no clear definition
and from the figure we see that the
hardware preservation environment
has no overlap with the software
procedure environments which means that
both of these entities should have a
very clear definition
and um
they should be really described and it
has actually legal implications as well
as
uh technical implications meaning that
some of the proceed execution
environments can be
uh split out from the confidential
operating such as aws
so it really needs to be
defined what exactly this specification
is
these are the key references and thank
you very much for listening and i hope
to see you in the next
you muhammad and um with this uh we
conclude uh this year's ram session
um
seriously i think uh we all missed the
physical
ram session at asia crypt
last time we have it was two years ago
in kobe
there was a lot of talks
why bsn fund
and i believe that we all have to make
it again this year in taipei
thank you honor speaker and thank you
everyone for being here see you bye