ah they've got to record it
go ahead okay welcome welcome to the
session on enhanced pke and time lock
puzzles
so i'm stephen galbraith and i'm one of
the co-chairs and uh yong jin zhao is
the other co-chair and aaron do you want
to share your screen you can you can
start your talk on
cryptographic assumptions and hidden
order groups
yeah thanks for the introductions our
work is called untimelog cryptographic
assumptions in abelian hidden order
groups and it's a joint work with
mark stephens
um so an abelian hypnotic group is a
finite abelian group such that it is
hard to compute a multiple of the order
of the group and preferably we want to
be able to sample such a group without
the need for a trusted setup
some applications of inorder groups are
verifiable delay functions cryptographic
accumulators and zero knowledge
arguments and perhaps the most
well-known examples of hidden order
groups are rsa groups and imaginary
quadratic classrooms
imaginary quadratic class groups have
historically been less studied than rsa
groups in cryptography but they have the
the benefit of not needing a trusted
setup whereas rsa groups do need a
trusted setup
on the other hand if we sample a random
imaginary good on a class group
it's not always going to be cyclic and
we have no efficient way to check if
such a randomly assembled group
is cyclic and so this motivates the need
to study computational problems in
abelian groups of inorder and not just
cyclic groups
and then with respect to multiple
some
multiple randomly sampled generators
and so the contributions of our work are
to formalize and study this abelian
hidden order group setting
um and so we proposed generalizations of
the standard model algebra group model
and strong algebra group model and we
adapted the definitions of cryptographic
problems to suit this billion hidden
order group setting
and the main changes here are that at
the start of a computational game
um a group is sampled randomly from some
group family and then n random elements
are sampled to be used as generators
um and then adversely receives at the
start of this game
an explicit description of this group
and this random set of generators as
input
in the algebra group model adversaries
need to additionally provide an
algebraic representation of every output
group element in terms of input group
elements and in the strong algebra group
model adversaries need to expose the
circuit of elementary group operations
so multiplications and inversions that
they use to compute output group
elements from input group elements
and then
the main part of our work is to study
relations between cryptographic problems
in a billion groups fit in order in
these
three computational models
so before giving an overview of the
reductions that we've shown let me
briefly introduce the computational
problems that we studied so we studied
various order problems of computing
either the group order or finding some
element of low order
then various root problems when it first
you had to
compute the root of
either a self-chosen challenge element
or some random challenge element
to repeat the squaring problem
and
various generalizations of the discrete
logarithm problem and computation of the
helmet problem to
abelian groups
and so in this
picture here we see an overview of the
reductions that we've shown in our work
where the green cells indicate new
results
and inside the cells it shows the
computational model in which we've
shown this result
the yellow cells indicate partial
results which are conditioned on some
extra conditions holding up
and the red cells indicate that no
generic reductions
can be shown for these problems
and so if we look a bit closer the main
chunk of new results that we've shown
are reductions from this ammo problem
the problem of computing multiple of the
order to
all of the other computational problems
that we study
and then composing these new reductions
with
no reductions from the other problems to
the multiple order problem we obtained
sort of this whole block
of problems which are um essentially
equivalent to the problem of computing a
multiple of the order
in these respective computational models
and so
uh and moreover we showed that uh in
cyclic groups within order we can obtain
the exact order
of the group from a from a d log
adversary um which is kind of a a
folklore reduction which which may be
known before i think um but we
give some exact analysis of uh success
uh probabilities and and running time
for this uh for this reduction
um
so because most of the results we've
shown our reductions from this multiple
order problem to some other
computational problem and to briefly
outline the
uh what this reduction looked like
so the idea here is to obtain n linearly
independent relations with respect to
system of generators of the group from
an adversary solving a given
computational problem g
and here with a relation i mean some
integer vectors such that if you
if you raise the generators to
the components of this vector we
multiply and multiply them we obtain the
identity of the group
um and then if we succeed in doing this
the determinant of the system of
relations is going to be a multiple of
the group board
so the challenges to show these
reductions are well of course to extract
relations from an adversary solving
an instance of this computational
problem and then to randomize the
instances of this problem and call the
adversary multiple times such that it
succeeds with independent and identical
success probability on each instance
such that it succeeds on n instances
with visually large probability and such
that and successfully extracted
relations will be linearly independent
with overwhelming probability
and if you want to know more about the
details of this reduction i want to
refer to the full first full recorded
version of our talk or to the full
version of our paper which is up on
eprint or you can find in your
conference proceedings
and for now i want to thank you for
listening and if you have any questions
feel free to
ask them
that's a great really nice talk aaron
and i just suddenly realized my
fundamental mistake is i haven't pulled
up the zulu chat um
is anyone have anyone looking at that
are there any are there any questions on
the zulu
no there are not
okay good uh is anyone in the room what
a question
i actually have a
question okay kevin
you mentioned two examples of these
hidden order groups the class group and
the integers modulo product issue primes
are there other candidates that are
known
yeah
these
um uh jacobians um
right if i said correctly hyperlypic
um
i think steven published a paper about
this last year that's that's that's a
hilarious question kevin that's like
it's like i asked you to ask that
question or something
no it's just like literally wrote a
paper on that recently
yeah
no it's it's really it's a really
interesting point it's one of these it's
a classic example of one of these things
that happens in cryptography where we
have actually a really small number of
candidates for something that's actually
quite interesting
um
is that the only other candidate that
you know
class groups is the same
yeah
uh i also had a
question now and it was around
you talk about the
exact
computing the group order exactly and
the multiple
the computing the multiple order
one of one of the things we have
actually is estimates for the size of
the group so i mean the rsa case
you know zn star the order is almost
very close to n
and and for advanced group we have some
kind of bounds related to this
discriminant so does that help in any
way you to understand when you do when
you've actually finally got the exact
order because you can use these bounds
to help um
to know that you're finished
yeah maybe but the difficult thing with
these um sort of things are especially
for um
well if we look at sort of the problems
that also reduce to this multiple order
problem
then the adversary then if we want to
make a reduction from the middle order
to that uh problem and this at first you
can just work in some strict subletters
of the of sort of the whole relationship
letters of the groups that can always
multiply the relations by some some
integer multiple um
and so we can always obtain
sort of a larger multiple of the group
order and i think well the adversary
could technically also do that such that
it stays within these bounds but it's
still a multiple of the group order um
but maybe maybe if the bands are tight
enough we could could do yeah but it's
probably a small you could probably
factor anyway the time's up so a bit of
movement
so if you want if you want to stop
sharing the screen yeah thanks for that
really nice talk nickelodeon do you want
to start setting up
yep thanks very much yeah of course
our screen
cool and uh
so
so the next talk is on this uh
thing i find hard to pronounce a
stroller boss or something like that
that's correct i'll let you introduce it
so
hello everyone
my name is nicolas lambro
and today i'm going to speak to you
about castrolabus a universally
composable time log encryption scheme
this work is a collaboration with mr
apinis and tomasza harias
so first i'm going to give you a briefly
introduction into the concept of time
lock encryption
so what's time loop encryption consider
the case in a voting where a voter
encrypts the vote by using an encryption
algorithm and a public key the result is
an encrypted vote
and then
by revealing the secret key everyone can
retrieve the initial message
so but what happens in the case that the
secret key is not revealed
we have fairness issues because no one
can reveal the initial message and
specifically in self-styling protocols
so now consider the same case but
instead of using a common encryption
scheme i'm going to use time lock and
instead of a public key when i use time
t the result again is a cipher text and
after t time t has been reached everyone
can use
the decryption algorithm provide with
the time proof a time proof is a proof
that actually the time t has been
reached and retrieve the initial message
so regarding the related work on that
field
the existing times of
the existing construction of tle
they are based on arithmetics for
example
the repeating squaring
on hash function
repeating hashing witness encryption
by using boolean algebra
or centralized constructions which
mostly are based on public
infrastructure
and the generalization of all of this if
we provide a mechanism of verifying the
the solution of
the time proof that i refer earlier is
the verifiable delayed functions
so regarding the security definitions uh
all of the security definitions uh in
the literature are game-based and
specifically they assume that the
adversary operates in a concrete time so
we cannot argue we don't have
composability arguments because
time lock has not been studied in the uc
framework
where the adversary operates in an
asymptotic time
there is a work recently published in
eurocrypt it's called tardis a
foundation of time lock puzzles in uc
framework
it has many similarities with ours but
despite that there are also many
difficulties
many differences i'm sorry
the first is regarding the modeling
in tardis they assume
that
a message can be retrieved after some
computations
has been done in our case a message can
be retrieved when a specific time has
been reached where we believe that
actually captures more natural the
concept of time lock encryption
the second is the guardian the
generalization
in tardis uh they can only capture a
time lock encryption schemes based on
computational puzzles
in our case we can capture all of the
mentioned constructions
the second is that they cannot model an
adventure that possesses an advantage
over the decryption time over the honest
parties
in our case we capture such scenarios uh
by by parameterizes our functionality by
a leak function and this is useful
because there are constructions for
example based on bitcoin and due to the
selfish mining the adversary possesses
advantage and still this construction
are useful and the last is that the
entirety of the construction they
they provide construction is it is based
both on the radom oracle and the generic
group model in our case it's been it is
based only in the radha miracle
so regarding our research contribution
we define the concept of time-lock
encryption in the uc framework
by defying an ideal functionality the
ftle
we capture privacy
a delay where uh we're actually in the
delay we assume also that the encryption
takes some time
correctness and finally leak because as
i mentioned the adversary might possess
an advantage in the decryption time over
the honest parties
of course ideally the leak function
should be equal to the identity which
means that the adversary doesn't possess
any abundance
and of course there were challenges on
defining the puzzle based on uh
a puzzle-based uctle protocol the first
is that all of all of the messages in
the time then constant of time local
encryption are eventually open
so
a simulator
must
encrypt a fake message let's say and
after a specific time has been reached
the simulator needs to equivocate that
message and open it to a real one so how
is possible the solution is to use not
committing encryption
uh in the rather moral model
the second uh problem is that the the
tle has a concrete nature but we need to
start in the uc framework where the
model is asymptotic so for that
the puzzle solving
should should not be executed locally
because else any puzzle could be just be
solved in just one round so for that we
use the random morally
and the second is that this access to
this oracle should be restricted for
that we introduce the functionality
wrapper as in similar works
this is the extended construction of a
time lock encryption as you can see the
second argument this is where exactly
the simulator can equivocate to the
correct message because there is a call
to the miracle
uh so uh
we linked
a tl construction with that with our uc
definition by introducing a game based
this is actually called the q security
and informally states that it is hard to
reverse a challenge message before the
time comes
we don't capture we only capture one
awareness and no semantic security
but
with the equivocable extension that i
refer earlier is enough for having a uc
realization so we have the next theorem
that says that a tl construction that
satisfies q security uh
actually can you serialize our ideal
functionality fdle
so now i'm going to speak about
astrologers so astrologers actually
combines two very basic ideas of mahmoud
data and specifically
the puzzle that mahmoud provides but
instead of spreading or spreading the
secret across all the puzzle we just
hide it in the last short operation of
the random oracle call
and actually the secret is a key a key
of a symmetric encryption of symmetry
encryption of
of our message uh
similar to the to the reverse that all
construction so combining these two
ideas the puzzle for mahmoodi and the
symmetric encryption that also reverse
uses we have a stroller
as you can see it is it is in the random
molecule model
it is public verifiable without any
knowledge of any trapper information
and also the pathogen generation is
efficient without requiring any
knowledge of any trapper information
because it can be parallelized and
disproportionate to the number of cpu
cores in reality in the uc framework
there's no cpu course so
regarding the security of astrologers
astrology satisfies the q security but
the question is is to security enough in
a standalone
setting
uh
the the answer is no because as i said
it
there there's no any cement it doesn't
provide any semantic security guarantees
only stresses the one wayness of the of
the construction so for that we extended
uh our game-based definition and we give
it a neat cpa style flavor but in in a
time-long setting and
astrologers satisfies this
uh regarding our future research
direction
so first is to improve the scalability
of a stroller boost because now the
positive generation can be parallelized
and proportional to the number of cpu
cores but unfortunately in practice
still it's not very efficient in example
an application like voting so for that
instead of using a cpu we can use a gpu
where
the number of course
are many more
but the architecture is totally
different so it needs proper bench
marking and last
is to enhance enhance and scroll a boost
and make memory hard in order to resist
the hardware acceleration
where help us to predict let's say the
correct parameters when setting the
puzzle difficulty we can use ideas from
the balloon housing paper
in order to predict the correct
parameters but still it needs a proper
benchmarking because also the position
generation should be
should be efficient
uh these are the reference and thank you
for your attention
thank you very much it's very nice
quick summary of a quite complicated
paper um
i don't see anything on the zoom or on
the chat has anyone got
any questions at all
yeah so i guess my my question was uh
you you touched on it right at the end
about the
the
the fact that the person setting the
puzzle or doing the encryption
uh can can you work in parallel whereas
the person who's solving the puzzle has
to kind of compute these hashes in a
serial way um
so i mean
why didn't you do something
referring to the previous talk why
didn't you do something using like
repeated squaring or these kind of
things where
yes
so first of all uh
in order to so in uh first of all in
order to study uh
the reverse construction in the uc
framework we
were needed to work also in the generic
group model so you know it is let's say
it's not bad but it's it's a let's say
a bigger
assumption you know instead of having a
construction that's based only in the in
the random oracle one this is the first
limitation
uh so yes so i can see if you want to
base it on hash functions exactly you
know only has functions you know without
the general group model and the second
is that the because because reverse has
this problem of setting the difficulty
of the puzzle because they they have
discovered many attacks due to the
hardware accelerations they there are
more sophisticated algorithms that can
actually solve uh reversed uh you know
uh doing the shortcuts and actually can
solve reverse puzzle much faster uh we
believe that uh
if we enhance uh a hash function it it
would be more easier that than trying to
enhance let's say the the arithmetics
and the algebra behind reversed uh
construction
okay
cool right we better move on to the next
talk and we have to try and keep on time
so yeah thanks very much klaus for your
talk thank you and do you want to stop
sharing and uh
um i'll hand over to my coach here to
run the rest of it hi everyone this is
yonji and i will be sharing the rest of
the talks
so may we have our next speaker wang yi
presenting the paper titled
identity-based encryption for fair and
limited applications defining
implementing and applying
re-randomizable rcca secure ibe
okay
uh yes can you hear me
yes sure
okay
thank you for introduction
uh welcome to this talk about
identity-based encryption for sale
anonymity applications defining
implementing and applying randomizable
as i say secure ibe
me1 and this is the joint of work with
rumor
huang jiang ting niim
1 and the motif
in this talk you may consider the
applications of fair anonymity in the
same in a scenario of anonymous
communication when someone abuses the
anonymity services for illegal
activities we hope there is a trusted
authority that can revoke the anonymity
of malicious users
obviously identity-based encryption is a
natural candidate for such a setting
in ibe the key generation center can
check any separate tests generated by
the users and play the role of trusted
authority
apart from the fair anonymity the other
properties of such anonymous
communication put some extra constraints
on the underlying encryption scheme
first the scheme should support the
randomization of server tests so that
the server can hide the connections of
incoming and outgoing cipher tests
second
server tests should be anonymous and do
not reveal any information about the
identity of receiver
third
the encryption scheme should be secured
against the active attacker who can
probe the server with malicious server
tests
the combination of those constraints
points at randomizability receivable
anonymity and rcc security
in particular the rcc security is a
meaningful relaxation of cca security
for public key encryption and it is
compatible with randomizability
so we can study how to achieve those
properties in the context of ibe
simultaneously
here are our main results
first we define a new security notion
called anonymous idrca security
in fact gentry has defined the notion of
anonymous idcc security already
it is a combination of receiver
anonymity and idcc security
the only difference between anonymous
idcca and idrcc security is the
decryption oracle
specifically the decryption oracle of
anonymous id rcc security with output
replay when the diffusion result is
equal to the challenge plaintext m0 om1
to build a randomizable ibe with
anonymous idrcc security we start from
the gantry ibe
and consider its variant by modifying
the vector beta
into vector mu
then we apply this variant to the double
strand paradigm
the string the strand eid1 can be used
to randomize both eidm and itself
correctly
however this cryptosystem does not
satisfy anonymous idrcc security
because the adversary insecurity gain
can guess the plaintext and the
re-encrypted strength eidm with it
and verifying the guess by during the
equation oracle
so we have to restrict the itemization
of ciphertext by perturbing the
randomness in the first strand with
extra
z0 and z1
however adversary is still able to
randomize eidm with public parameters
identity and the plain text
so we mask the validity checking part
with the secret value u
and encapsulate u with another two
strings
now there is only one way to randomize
the zero test
and we can prove that this construction
is anonymous idrcc secure
finally we apply above ibe to build
universal mix net with fair anonymity
first the trustee authority plays the
role of key generation center and
generates secret keys for users and
mixed nodes
then the senders generate package by
encrypting message with symmetric
encryption and our ib scheme and upload
package to the bulletin board
then the mix now take turns to decrypt
several tests
symmetric server test and randomize ibus
have a test in the
package finally the receiver can equip
the package and retrieve the message
compared with previous universal mix net
our identity-based universal mixnet
achieves fair anonymity and enjoy
enjoy stronger unlikability and provide
more covert communication for the sender
okay that's all thank you
thank you very much for your talk
is there any questions from the audience
if anyone has any questions you can also
raise it through the
zulic link sent by kevin
can anyone hear me
can anyone hear me yes i can hear you
okay maybe one quick question
um so in your security game um
does the adversary get to choose the
ids and the message
before having access to the decryption
oracles
yes
so in this sense is it selectively
secure
it is
yeah this is stronger than selective
circuit secure
the
adversary can access the key generation
key generation oracle and because the
identity identity under the plan text is
provided by the adversary and not by the
challenger
okay i see thank you very much
okay thank you
okay um we are okay let's
invite our next speaker
so
we will have our
yeah fourth talk
simulation based by selective opening
security for public key encryption
it will be represented by young rupang
yes please go ahead
thanks for the instructions
i'm looking at today i'm going to talk
about how to define and construct the
pte scheme with bioselectable visibility
this is based on drawing to work with
screenshot 204 and jia world
so a pke scheme consists of several
results namely the traditional reserve
which produces a pair of publicly and
secret key the equation algorithm which
includes a message with a public key and
the declaration algorithm which
decreases some text to recurrent message
with a simple key it's correctness
requested the declaration can always
recover the correct message from only
security that
generated some text
and it's security requested that the
author can learn any information about
the message from the sort of text this
can be defined by requires that those
threads will have you simulated
sorry
sorry uh is there any problem
i guess you can proceed
you can you can just go ahead
okay
so this can be defined by preparing that
those
uh wheel can be simulated by simulator
that takes nothing as input
okay so a pk scheme is usually deployed
in the particular sector that is there
are many senders and many receivers
each receiver has only publicly and
super key and the sender sends a message
to the receiver by including the
messenger with the results
public key so in this case it's coming
that some senders and receivers may be
corrupted and the adversary can learn
their interest dates
in this case it's simply accessible to
practical messengers that are sent by a
corrupted sender and messages that are
received by a crafted receiver while we
still hope to protect messengers that
are transmitted between authority users
especially when the correct messages and
account messages may be written the
picky scheme with this throughout the
curriculum key is not to have selected
and in literature we have formally
started the central select open security
where only the centers can be crafted
and the receiver's leveling security
where only the reservoirs can be crafted
however we have not formally started how
to define the construct pte schemes with
by select for open security where both
the senders and the receivers can be
corrupted
so
in this work we formally initiate the
study of bioselective open security for
pke schemes and are resulting through
four parts
first we give a formal definition of
selective selective open security for pk
schemes the definition follows previous
simulation business definitions of
central selection security and that are
receivable to open security except that
those three this new definition can
craft the centers and the
receivers simultaneously
we then give a construction of piggy
scheme
with bias electrical
is a rhetorical model
in particular we showed that the simple
construction of key scheme from a key
encapsulation mechanism and the welcome
pad is already by selecting working
secure if we derive the masking key of
the one time pad
from the encapsulated key of the chem
scheme we are running morocco
we also consider a weak notion of a
selective open security that is the
adversary has to choose its
attacking type
i've seen the public keys
the definition is
weaker than the standard by selective
open security but it is still strictly
stronger than the sender selective
principality and the receiver selective
open security actually it implies the
requirements that
a piggy scheme has both the single
selective security and the reservoir
selective of this pretty
okay so finally we give a construction
of picky scheme with big bi selective
open security
to achieve this goal we
present a new printer called key
equivalent boost server and instantiate
it from either the dde transaction or
the dc assumption within a
general construction of key scheme with
weak by selective open security for this
new printer
okay so for some reason we are not able
to cover all details of our results uh
if you are interested please uh watch
the oncoming youtube or with our people
for more details that's all thanks for
noticing and
to
thank you ruben very nice talk
any questions from the audience
the zulic chat is also quite quiet
um
okay i have one question for you
europang
in your security definition you follow
the simulation based paradigm i'm
wondering if it is possible to define an
ind based security notion
for this bi-directional selective
opening
uh yes
uh uh
we have uh the
vast electrical security for uh either
your id based set here but uh there are
some restrictions in the definition uh
in the center
uh senator secretary i'm going to do
serious requirements of the case
so
the research here is that we have to
restrict the mess distribution uh
submitted by the doctor that is in a
simulation based uh definition we don't
have to restrict the message
distribution submitted by the grocery
but if you consider the anti-beast you
have to
give some
artificial restriction on the massive
diffusion so the
personal laser i think the idp
definition is a bit uh artificial and we
prefer to have a simulation-based one
and also
a simulation-based security is uh should
be stronger than the imdb
security
so
that's a strong uh that's a stronger
definition and it seems more meaningful
to construct kiki scheme with a stronger
security
well can you formally prove that the
simulation base is strictly stronger
than the ind base have you tried to
exploit that
uh i'm not sure if uh formative formal
uh reduction exists uh actually it
depends on the
type of the
definition
so in some cases uh the uh the
simulation based uh definition can't
imply the individual's definition
because at all seriously the two
definitions has different powers
but uh
uh actually uh
if we have some uh digital definition it
is possible to prove that i think
okay great answer thank you very much
any questions
from others
well if no then let's thank rupang again
and welcome our next speaker
okay shall we have uh
heinz hindsight
yes presenting the yeah presenting the
cam with tight enhanced security in the
multi-user setting impossibility results
and optimal tightness yeah
please go ahead
okay thanks for the introduction hi
everyone i'm shaihan this is a joint to
work with shanghai and daoku let me
directly start with the general overview
of key encapsulation mechanism
we consider two users alice and bob
alice generates her public key and
secret key and with the public key of
values bob can produce an encapsulated
key k and a cipher text c
the alice can use the secret keys to
recover the encapsulated key from c
this way alex and bob establish a shared
encapsulated key
cam has many applications
for example in constructing public
encryption
authenticated key exchange protocols etc
in real world scenarios there might be
many users each of them generates their
own keys and each two of them might
communicate and send many ciphertexts to
each other this is a so-called smart
user setting
in this city our adversary is able to
see all users public keys and all cypher
tests sending over the public channels
moreover a powerful adversary may even
crack some users and obtain their secret
keys sk1 sk2
and may obtain some keys encapsulated in
some ciphertexts like they like the k1
and k2
the security of cam asks the the
unreviewed key the unreviewed
encapsulated key under uncrafted users
to be sued random
such a strong yet realistic security is
formalized and enhanced security in our
work
to prove the security of camp a
commonwealth is using a security
reduction
which turns any adversary a breaking
camps security into an adversary b
solving some hard problem
and if the security loss factor l of the
reduction is a constant then we call cam
has a tight security
it is desirable to have tightly secured
cam however starting from the similar
work by coral
badger adore at eurocrypt 16 showed that
touch security under adaptive
corruptions is impossible to achieve if
either secret key has the key uniqueness
property or secret key has key
randomization property
and by the existing impossibility
results
uh this rules out some camps on their
tights
tights security on the corruptions like
the air gamma cam
however many
well-known camps including the grammar
shoot and crossover decimate cam
their secret key has neither key
uniqueness nor key randomization
so determine determining whether tetanus
impossibility holds for such cam schemes
needs new techniques
and in our work we introduce a new
technical tool called kemp's rank
first we study the equivalence of secret
keys when
they are used
they are used to encapsulate a set of
cipher text x
for a pair sk and sk prime
they are
decap equivalent with respect to the set
x if for every ciphertext in x
this calculation using sk equals the
calculation using sk prime
with this relation we can partition the
secret key space into many equivalent
classes
in particular for an element c1 in x if
x defines small equivalent classes then
x set minus c1 then we call this element
c one is an independent element in x
otherwise that x defines exactly the
same relation with x z minus c one they
will then we call c one is the dependent
element in x
so starting for from every ciphertext
set x we can drop all dependent elements
without changing the equivalence
relation it's defined
and in the end every every elements left
are independent ones and we call the
resulting subset x prime of x and
independent steps
so for set x it may have many
independent sets
it may have have many independent
subsets x prime and we define the rank
of x and the size of the largest
independent set of x
by taking x as a whole ciphertext space
we define the rank of k
and it
also equals the size of the largest
independent state of ciphertext space
with the notion of rank we established
our new impossibility results by mental
reduction
namely as long as cam has a polynomial
rank then it is impossible to achieve a
tight enhanced security and the security
loss is as at least linear in the number
of users
then we apply our impossibility results
to many well-known camps by showing that
their rank is polynomially bonded for
example the rank of the cramship camp is
two
and the rank of crossover deathmatch
camp is no more than four
therefore the enhanced security of these
schemes inherently suffers from a linear
security loss when reducing to
non-interactive assumptions
from a positive side we also show that
this linear security loss is achievable
by giving two reductions
and this together with our impossibility
results show that for camps with
polynomial rank the linear security work
factor for enhanced security is optimal
to summarize
in our work we define the realistic
enhanced security for cam and we
developed a new technical tool called
kemp's rank to identify a class of cam
schemes for which impossibility of test
reduction holds
and finally we show the linear security
loss is achievable and optimal for camps
with polynomial rank
for more details please have a look at
the longer video and our paper imprint
thank you for listening that's it
thank you very much enjoy a very nice
talk
any questions from the audience you can
just anneal yourself and
ask questions
the
yeah i actually yeah i actually have a
question
um
so can you give
any kind of intuition
as to
why i mean my understanding of the rank
is it's something to do with equivalent
private keys i don't
really understand any kind of intuition
why the number of private keys should
have an influence over the multi-user
security of the
of a cam do you have like a like any
kind of simple thought where to think
about that
um because uh we will prove the
impossibility results by the mental
reduction and we define we propose a
specific adversary a star star can
utilize
this this property to
uh to
to if to bounce the security for boss
and
in particular the anniversary will
randomly choose one of the q ciphertexts
to to change the ciphertext one of the
queue change server tests
and uh
the probability that the chosen
ciphertext is a dependent one by our
notion camera rank is bounded by uh
the number the rank of cam over the
total number q so if the
point the rank is a polynomial then we
can always choose the number of
ciphertext q to a larger polynomial so
that's this
so that's this
question is a
sufficiently small
i guess maybe i was thinking almost of
the other way around um i mean
it seems
it seems like um
if you have if you have lots of
different secret keys
um
i mean it almost seems worse right i
mean if if i have if i have lots of
public keys and it turns out that lots
of people's secret keys can decrypt a
cipher text to me that feels like a
weaker a weaker system but you're you're
saying there's actually strength
they're saying somehow it gets stronger
by having more secret keys or something
i'm not sure i understand
yes
so it's okay i should just read your
paper
[Music]
i think i agree that it's
counter-intuitive though
great discussion um any more questions
from the audience
we still have one or two minutes let me
erase the naive question
you prove
you you show that you can apply your
lower bound to many existing cam
mechanisms right
yes so i'm wondering whether the
existing proofs of the security of these
camps actually meet your lower bank
originally these games are approved in a
week you know
a weaker model than we considered in our
paper in our paper we consider a
a strong security model so in the strong
security model
uh they cannot achieve the tight
security reduction
and for some of them we proved that for
example the air gamma came and the of
the game proposed by hoffens and jager
they can achieve this lower bound and
this is the ultimate optimal
security loss
but the other camps we don't know
whether they can meet this lower bound
right
am i understanding correctly
yes yes
okay i see thank you
thank you
okay if no more questions then let's
thank
hansha again and welcome our last
speaker in the section
yeah can you please go ahead
yeah
our last talk will be hierarchical
integrated signatures and encryption
presented by
yeah yeah
and
oh
are we
do we have lost shanyu
i couldn't see him in the chat room
can you see my slice
yes yes please make it full screen
okay wait a minute
okay
can you see the slides now
yes yes please
okay uh thanks for the introduction and
hi i'm very happy to present our paper
entitled the hierarchy integrity
signature and encryption this is a joint
work with shanta and yuan
as everybody know public encryption
signature will host primitives that are
typically used simultaneously to secure
communication but the subtle point is
that
when we use public key encryption and
signature together we need to concede
join the security that is the ef cma
security for the signature component
should hold even in the presence of an
additional decryption oracle while the
intc security for the public encryption
should hold even in the presence of a
signing oracle
but basically there are two principles
when using public encryption signature
together
that is key separation and key reviews
the key separation protocol but the key
separation principle is using
independent independent kps for
signature and pub encryption
the advantage of key reuse is that the
joint security is immediate and the
construction
is off the sea off and it also naturally
admits individual key sql which is a
vital property to achieve a balance
between user authenticate authenticity
requirement and society's auditing
requirement
the disadvantage of
key separation
key separation is
the key measurement complexity get
doubled and also the certificate cost
it also completely complicated the
design of high level protocols
while the key reuse
principle
is using the same key pair for both
signage and encryption
we refer to such a scheme as integrity
the signature encryption called ise for
short
the advantage of key reuse principle is
it reduces the key measurement
complexity as well as the certificate
cost
it also helps to simplify the design of
high level protocol
but the disadvantage of key reuse is the
journal security is not immediate and it
does not naturally the meet individual
key escrow
well as discussed above we are facing a
dilemma between key reuse that brings
performance benefit and key separation
that supports individual kiosks
an interesting question is can we enable
individual skill mechanism
while retaining the merits of key reuse
to address this problem we propose a new
cryptographic primitive called hierarchy
integrity signature encryption
in hrc a single public key service both
verification and encryption key while
there is a hierarchy between sonic and
the decryption key the sending key sk
served as a master secret kind can
derive a decryption key used only for
decryption in a one-way manner as to
security will require strong joint
security we require the idc secure
security for the pk component remains
even in the presence of a signing oracle
why are the ef cms security for the
signature component remains
even the adversary get to see the whole
decryption key rather than merely access
to a decreasing oracle
next we presented two generic
construction of hic
our first
his construction is from identified
encryption the main idea is to apply the
null transform and the chk transform to
why i identify encryption simultaneously
we're attacking the hudder is that the
decryption key for the identity space i1
should be shot that means we need a
succinct representation for all
securities for identities in the
iospace
to solve this problem we propose a new
cryptographic primitive called the
constraint ib for prefix predicates
which in turn can be
built from
binary tree encryption
well our second general construction of
hic is from pke and
i z kpok the idea is to correct a
hierarchy key structure by one-way
function
uh we first pick a random bit string as
the sending key then maps sk to run
misra and
then
run the public key encryptions key
generation algorithm with random start
to generate the public key and the
decryption key
where the encryption component of hrc is
simple which is the same as the
underlying public encryption to correct
the signature we use general purpose
public coins they communicate through
knowledge of sk with respect to the
public key
next we describe an important extension
of iec with global scope property
nowadays large-scale collaborative
working apps like us
such as slack is getting popular one
hand the employer may have the right to
get access to all private communication
for various reasons on the other hand
employees need to be assured that even
the malicious employer
cannot slam them by forging a signature
for fabricated communications
where is thus further expected global
property that
that means there is a super key that can
decrypt any subtext around any public
key while the signature remains secure
even in the presence of a such civil key
to attack global escrow property for his
in a general commander we first attacked
the tour to revisit global escrow
public encryption
we formalized the definition of security
nurses for global escrow public
encryption and gave two general
constructions
our first general construction is from
is from any public encryption and idk it
could be viewed as a new application of
the celebritated noise transform beyond
the ccs security
our second general construction is from
any three-party non-integrative key
exchange the idea is that let's ask
center generator tpr himself to send a
plaintext to a receiver with public key
beta
the sender first generator temporary
keypair pk alpha s k offers
by running a three-party ike in his head
the rest of the construction is simple
combine previous results we obtain a
technology roadmap
of global escrow hisc we can freely take
any pace from the
lyft node to the rhythm
to construct a global hisc
i lost the wingmaker comparison between
c
cp cpk isc and global
global escrow hrc from stable we can see
that the global hic not only enjoys the
benefit of key reuse but also support
richer functionality such as individual
and global key escrow
the experience
the experimental results demonstrate our
global hic schemes have comparable
efficiency with the most efficient
combined public key scheme and enjoy
compact key size as well
as a bi-product we also obtained the
most efficient global
public encryption to date which beat the
best previous scheme was
attending to certain times
speed up
well
let's summarize our talk in this work we
propose a new notion called hic our
notion has a sweet balance and thus
reconcile the apparent conflict between
king separation and key reuse it can be
used as a dropping replacement of pke
plus signature in any scenarios that
require authenticity confidentiality and
auditability simultaneously and the both
user and authority will have incentives
to deploy we also extensively revisit
the global sql public encryption
our result indicated a new application
of neuron transform
and establish the nervous connection
from three-part and ike that's all thank
you any questions
thank you join you for your great talk
any questions from the audience
if no then
let me ask one question
hi chang you define your his e in a way
that
the signing key can derive the and the
the
the decryption key is it possible to
define the other way around namely the
decryption key derived the signing given
in the world yes
yes thanks for this question we indeed
concede this during notion as the end of
a paper
that is the decryption serve as a master
secret key while it can derive uh
sending key in a one-way manner the
notion could be useful in applications
where
the privacy of messages of utmost
importance why is the sending capability
need to be delegated
yes
but why do you choose this particular
direction first instead of the other ah
because
for the time being i we found it hard to
find uh
good applications for the new for the
durian notion but this notion
uh that is the sunny case of utmost
importance
is uh has run the widely
usage for example in the cryptocurrency
because
in most applications the
the signing capabilities also
is always of the first priority should
be protected
uh okay thank you very much for your
explanation
okay
well if no questions from the audience
then
we'll call it a day and thank you very
much for joining this section
thank you steve for co-chairing the
session with me
yeah
thanks for the authors
yeah thanks for all the authors
have a nice day
great okay
what do we now do now kevin just