hi my name is jan nasim and this is a
talk for asia group 2021
presentation
titled snaky ceremonies
this is a joint work by marco kovis mary
mahler and mikhail vocal
let me start you by reminding what are
sick snacks
this
this stands for zero knowledge succinct
non-interactive argument of knowledge
and the idea is that we want to prove
that some statement x
which is public and some weakness w
which is private
satisfy a certain relation
and
from security wise
we wanted to satisfy knowledge soundness
this means that prover who is able to
convince the verifier
should know a witness w
and we want zero knowledge
which essentially means that the only
information we leak
is that x and w are in the relation
and we don't even
reveal the witness here
and finally we want succinctness
which essentially means that proof size
is independent of the size of the
statement and the size of the witness
smallest snark so far
or at least one of the smallest
is uh proposed by krotz six uh inscribed
in 2016
and it requires a complicated trusted
setup unfortunately
which has
made it very difficult to use it in
practice
so what i mean by this trusted setup
um essentially we have here a prover
a verifier
and some trusted central party
kruger knows statement and witness and
verifier knows only the statement
and then in the beginning of the
protocol the trusted party
will generate what we call a common
reference string
so this is a
a bit string for from some very specific
distribution
and he gives this to both approver and
the verifier and then prover can use
this
to construct an argument and verify
again use this to
either accept the argument which means
he believes it or he will reject it
there are essentially two flavors of the
common reference string
there are uniformly random strings
which is completely uniformed around the
bit string
or there are structured reference spring
which is anything besides the uniform
random string
and uniformly random string we sometimes
call a transparent setup
because it's
uh
it's relatively easy
to obtain a uniformly random string
from some natural resources
which means that
we essentially don't have to trust it
anymore
we can obtain it by you know
picking for example
certain digits of pi
or or some other
natural source of randomness
unfortunately protocols based on urs
are less efficient
and then you have uh
protocols with structured reference
string
here the
setup is much more complicated
and we don't have as good ways of
generating this
structured reference string but the
protocols are much more efficient
so in case of structured reference
string
the trusted part usually does something
like this
it first generates the trapdoor
then he applies some function destructor
and this then generates the srs
unfortunately anyone who knows the
trapdoor can completely break the
protocol it is actually by design
of the protocol that this is possible
essentially this trap door is used to
prove that the serial knowledge property
holds
but it accidentally also can break the
soundness properly if someone actually
knows this
which essentially means that in most
applications
a single party should not be able to
generate the srs
because
otherwise
i mean we really have a centralized
trust in the system
which for example in the blockchain
setting
is not really acceptable at all
there have been several
proposals how to solve this
uh one of the earlier proposals was to
use multi-party computation
so here the idea is very simple we
already have a bunch of multi-party
computation protocols
uh the trapdoor can be shared between
different parties
so each party will generate
generate its local trapdoor
then they runs a multi-party computation
protocol
and the final output is an srs
uh where
f is applied to a master trap door
where the master door is some sort of
the combination of the individual
trapdoors of each party
and typically you get a property that if
some fraction of the parties is honest
then the final trapdoor does not leak
and the srs has a correct structure
unfortunately it's also quite
inconvenient if you want to run this but
a large number of parties
because they have to be available
throughout this whole protocol which
might take quite a while
and
also multiparty computation protocols
are not that efficient if you want to
run it with huge number of parties
which you would perhaps in a blockchain
setting
so in response to that yes there have
been proposed some specialized
multi-party computation protocols which
are a bit more efficient
but they are still quite cumbersome to
use in practice
another possibility
which is a little bit better
is known as updatability
so these are essentially specialized
snarks
where the multi-party computation
protocol has only one round
uh what do i mean by this
um
now we basically have
that each party
generates a pixel trapdoor
[Music]
and the first party will produce some
srs and some
proof of update raw one
the second party will just update this
proof and
generate its own update proof so this
update proof is something just to verify
that it was done correctly
and so on
and these in these protocols we only
rely on one honest party
and in order to verify the final srs
you just need
the very last srs and some all of those
intermediate update proofs which are
typically short in those protocols
and there are now many works in this
model like sonic and marlin and blanc
but in general they are a little bit
less efficient than the non-updatable
snacks
so it would still be interesting
to kind of
uh
make those non-updatable snacks also
updatable in some way
[Music]
and finally there is a solution by
which is a player exchangeable npc
um
the basically the idea is that in these
types of protocols
the trapdoor doesn't have to be
committed
in the beginning of the protocol
and instead they use a random beacon
which is like an extra body in the
protocol
and
then in each round of the protocol also
this random p comparison participates
and we can kind of
we're just assuming that this random
beacon
behaves
correctly it produces some random
numbers for us
and
yeah
the output of the protocol is kind of
the same as in the
[Music]
usual npc protocols but what is nice
here is that the parties
can
be different in different rounds of the
protocol
so now we are not anymore relying on the
fact that the same party
is available in the first phase and the
second phase of the protocol
so this is a lot more
convenient if you have a lot of parties
in a multi-party computation product
called especially in the blockchain
setting
and now this uh protocol of power
gap is on the myers this was used quite
extensively
for example with the zed cache protocol
aztec protocol file coin semaphore loop
ring and so on
with quite some success
so let's look a bit more closely what is
this random beacon here
idea of the random beacon is that
uh
after certain time intervals it will
produce us a new random number
um
and why it's useful in this previous
protocol is that we can basically use
this
uh
previously unknown random number
to randomize
uh this current state of the srs
unfortunately it is quite
complicated to construct secure random
beacons
there's a heuristic approach which
has been
used in this blockchain world which is
that
you just take a hash
of a relatively recent blockchain block
and you now say that okay this is my new
random
output of the beacon
this is only a heuristic approach if you
ask actually want to do it securely
then it's a
very challenging problem
so ideally we would not want to use a
random beacon at all
so what is our contribution here
firstly we propose a security framework
for non-interactive arguments
which
uh
have a ceremony protocol so this is a
product called for setting up
the srs
and you can kind of see this as a
generalization of the notion of
updatability if you're familiar with
this one
and then we propose a simplified version
of crop 16 ceremony
[Music]
essentially a simplified version of this
bowie gap is a myers protocol
which does not use a random beacon
so we completely eliminate this
assumption
and finally
we give a proof of security
in a mixed model of algebraic group
model and random oracle model
is technically quite an advanced
security proof which we will very
briefly go over as well
so let's take a look of that security
framework of our
proposal
so snuck with the ceremony
firstly we have our approver algorithm
and the verifier algorithm as usual
but the srs is now split into
independently updatable parts
srsu
which we call updatable srs
and the
srss which is a specialized srs
the idea here is that srsu
is independent of the concrete relation
that we are trying to prove
and the srss already depends on the
relation
then we have an update algorithm which
is used to update the srs
it takes in
the previous srs
a set of update proofs
and
an index either urs
depending on which part of the servers
we want to update
and then it produces
a new version of the
srs
and an update proof for that srs
then we have an srs verification
algorithm
which takes
as an input and srs and the setup update
proves and either resets it or rejects
it um
yeah so what does the model actually
look like
uh
basically we do updating in two phases
so
first
we update the universal srs this is the
srs without
a specific relation
and it goes as in usual updatability
model so the first guy updates and
produces a crew
and so on
then
we finish the universal updating phase
and fix the srs
the universal srs
and now
we have let's say some relation that we
want to use
and we take the srs
which is
universal
and we generate
initial
specialized srs so this is a srs which
depends
on the relation and we start updating
this
and as you see here
this part is in the first place and
second phase they don't have to be the
same
so from
updatability perspective we sort of
argue that
there's actually not much difference
if you work in this type of updatability
model
where you fix the universal srs at some
point and then
go on with the
specialized srs
or
you just have your usual notion of
updatability
and the final srs
is just a conjunction
of the final updatable srs and the final
specialized srs
and from the secure device we want
completeness
in two flavors actually we want update
which essentially says that okay so if
you have some srs which verifies
and we make an update
then
also this updated srs will verify
and we also have prover completeness
which is
essentially the usual notion of
completeness in an interactive
zero-knowledge protocols
that
okay so if the srs verifies
and the honest prover generates approved
then also the verifier accept the proof
so these are just some properties to
guarantee that our protocol even makes
sense
then we
require optic knowledge soundness
what this one says is that for every
efficient adversary a
there exists an efficient extractor
such that if the adversary outputs
a
statement x and some proof pi and it
verifies
uh then the extractor
is able to extract the witness
from the view of a so this is all the
internal knowledge that the adversary
has
uh
and
yeah so
you can
extract the business
and the srs here is generated by
interacting with the challenger
so
essentially what we allow is that
the first ways of updating
adversary can request the challenger
to update his
srs
and by the end of the universal phase
adversary will submit some srsu together
with some update proofs
such that at least one of those update
proofs
was generated by the challenger
so essentially there has to be one
honest update
and the second
phase works basically the same way
so now we have some srsu already fixed
adversary can
request updates for
specialized srs
and by the end of the phase he submits
some srs a specialist srs
and update proofs such that at least one
of the updates was done honestly by the
challenger
uh and then we borrowed the notion of
subversions or knowledge
uh which was invented by the lara hooks
power and skapuro
and the idea there is that
adversary is allowed to pick any srs
and
a set of update proofs such that
they verify
and in that case
there must exist an extra efficient
extractor that can extract
a trapdoor from the srs
and this trap door can use
to simulate
uh proofs that are indistinguishable
from honest proofs
so yeah this is our security model
uh
okay
so now
let's
go and check what this
uh ceremony protocol of quote 16 roughly
looks like
so uh grout 16
as i mentioned before it's dark with one
of the shortest proofs so far
and we can split the srs into universal
universal part in the specialized part
uh here this g
is generator of one of the
bearing groups and h is the generator of
the other pairing group
and x is some integer
which is a trapdoor so x alpha and beta
here are actually a tractor
and the specialist srs
kind of looks something similar
but what we can notice here is that
there's universal srs
has essentially
monomials in the exponent
whereas the specialized srs
does not necessarily have monomials so
here we see some much more complicated
polynomials
but essentially what we when we update
this is that
in the first srs
let's say if we want to update this
element
an updater we pick some x prime
exponentiate
um
let's say this element with x prime to
the power of y
and then the updated element will look
like such
so this x prime x is now
the new trapdoor x
and if you want to update the second
phase
then already x alpha and beta are fixed
and we're only updating delta
so update we pick some delta prime and
uh again exponentiate
let's say this element for example by
one over delta prime
which means that now this delta here is
updated
um
and beyond that
we also need to include the update proof
which essentially allows us to verify
that the updating was done correctly
so what this proof contains is
in case of x for example trap door x
it will have g to the power of x times x
prime
[Music]
g to the power x prime
and h to the x prime
so x prime is this new trapdoor here and
x
is the previous tractor
and then we also have a proof of
knowledge
for x prime
this is something which we need for a
security proof
uh
and the verification looks something
like this so
e here is a pairing operator
and we can kind of verify this that this
g x
x prime was computed correctly by
running this function for example
and then we also verify
the proof of knowledge
so this proof of knowledge is actually
some very specialized protocol i won't
go very much into details here
um
but so far the protocol that i've
introduced is
essentially the same as the
bowie capisson mayas protocol
but here we somehow already are
deviating a bit we are requiring
stronger security properties
for the proof of knowledge
part
uh
[Music]
what we essentially prove in the paper
is that this proof of knowledge
has to satisfy zero knowledge
and the very specific flavor of
soundness
which will have
straight line simulation extractability
so this is a very
strong notion
of soundness
and in addition
the soundness
adversary is allowed to
ask from the challenger a group element
as we can see here where x1 to xn is
some secret value
and f with some polynomial chosen by the
adversary
and additional
additionally we can
we allow the adversary to query the
random oracle
and we prove this in the model which
combined random rocket model and the
algebra group model
as right group model i will introduce
now
so yeah let's look briefly
what is the
our uh security model and
the security proof
i will give some very brief overview
of our main security proof
but before that what is this algebraic
proof model
so here we have an adversary and the
challenger
and in
algebraic group model
the challenger can give us some group
elements and whenever adversarial puts a
group element a
then he also has to output integers
which are a linear
representation of those group elements
what i mean by this
is that a
has to satisfy
this type of relation
between the elements that he has
received so far
and now
the juncture can send us some new set of
elements
and again with adversary outputs
some group element b
then he has to also provide integers t1
to dm
which again satisfy this type of linear
relation
but notice here that now
uh b can depend
both the elements that were sent in the
first round and also
the ones that were sent in the second
round
but this is what we assume from the
adversary
so essentially this is a restricted
model of computation
is forced to output something that you
would usually not force
but this has become very
uh widely used in the very base setting
and additionally we assume a random
oracle
where adversary can input some
bit string x
and in return you will get a group
element y
which is a random group element
and our security of our main result
depends on q1 q2
discrete logarithm assumption
we're basically adversary will be a
random
exponent set
and send these group elements that you
see on the screen
and now the adversary is
supposed to find
an integer set
which is the exponent
so it's the usual discrete algorithm
assumption
but uh
adversary gets more knowledge than usual
and the statement of our main theorem is
that
if 2 n minus 1 2 n minus 2 discrete
logarithm assumption holds
and we work in this combined model of
algebraic group model and random rocket
model
then
we achieve update knowledge soundness
for the ceremonial krog 16 snack so this
is cross 16 snack
together with this
updating protocol
and notice that here we don't require
random beacon which is one of the main
results
or main achievements of this paper
oh yes and the n here
stands for
the number of multiplication gates in
the circuit of the relation
so i will very briefly go over
of a high level strategy of our main
security proof
and this will end this talk
so essentially the idea is that okay we
pick some algebraic adversary a
and then
we will construct an extractor and this
extractor
will
[Music]
output specific
coefficients
like this algebraic representation
coefficients that i showed before
which we claim that will
now correspond to the witness
and our rest of the proof will actually
be we will be arguing that this output
of extractor is indeed the witness
the
views are several games
[Music]
game zero is the original optic noise on
this game with adverse array and the
extractor that i just described
and
so
if
gear5
is the
setup update proofs
in summon phase 5
then we call the critical query to be
the last
honest update that is the update timing
by the challenger
and in game one
what we will try to do is try we will
guess
the index for the critical query
before the beginning of the protocol
um
we don't know despite i guess
and uh
basically if we guess it correctly
then the challenger
will on the ice
i guess
query he will not update
the srs proposed by the
adversary but he will instead generate a
completely fresh srs
which is
unbiased and
he will instead simulate the update
proof
so now what this will guarantee for us
is that
the srs from this point on
has not been
up to this point has not been biased at
all by the adversary because we
generated it freshly
um
and we will use the zero knowledge and
straight line simulation extractability
properties
of this protocol knowledge
sub protocol
to show that these two games are
indistinguishable
and then the algebraic group model part
of the proof will look something like
this we define a polynomial q
in
the trapdoor variables x excel by expata
index delta
where
if you
apply
basically the trap doors at the point
at the index guess
that
they will be zero exactly when we accept
so this q is essentially some very
complicated polynomial
which depends on the verification
equation
all the intermediate srs states and
random oracle responses to the adversary
and also the agent coefficients of the
adversary
but it will have this property that it
is zero
exactly when
v accepts the proof
and now the proof will branch into two
parts in the first part
we say okay suppose that this polynomial
q is not zero
then we show that we can do a reduction
to this variation of the discrete
logarithm assumption
and
if it is zero
then
we show
[Music]
by arguing the structure of this
polynomial
that whatever the extractor outputs is
actually the witness
so this is a very technical part of the
proof
but it indeed seems to work out
so so much about this proof and this is
this was the by far the hardest part of
this paper i think it took us
a couple of months to get this proof
correct
um
[Music]
but yeah so the main takeaway helped
this paper
even non-applicable snacks
can be updated if we allow it multiple
phases
and this seems to have very little
different
difference in practice if you have
only one phase updating or two phase
updating
however
what is actually important is that those
one-phase updatable snarks
are also universal typically and by
universal i mean that the srs does not
depend on the relation
and this might be actually much more
difficult to achieve
but there is actually a protocol called
mirage
where they do modificate 16
to also obtain universality
but this is already quite a big
modification i would say
but if you apply this paper together
with the mirage then you can get a
version of quote 16 which is both
universal and updatable
so yeah thank you for
listening
you