welcome everyone to my presentation my
name is pratik today i'll talk about our
recent work on two-round adaptively
secured mpc from isogenes lpn or cdh
this is a joint work with naveed from uc
berkeley and visa research with hart
from fujitsu lab
and shikhar from eta zurich and visa
research
today we will talk about secure
competition we consider the two-party
setting there are two parties who have
their private inputs x and y they want
to jointly compute a function f on their
inputs
to do so they run a protocol pi on their
inputs and outputs the protocol output
the protocol should satisfy two
properties mainly it should be correct
that is the function output should be
same as protocol output and the protocol
should be secure that is the protocol
should not leak anything about the
private inputs besides the output
the works of yao gold wright mikhail
victorson beaver mikali rogoway
presented the first few protocols for
secure computation
since then secure computation has found
numerous applications in
privacy-preserving machine learning
blockchains and many more
in this work we consider the primitive
of oblivious transfer or ot
it is a two-party protocol between a
receiver under sender
the receiver has an input choice bit b
and sender has two choice
two messages m0 and m1
by performing the ot protocol the
receiver obtains the message of his
choice ot security ensures that a
corrupt receiver should not know the
other message
m1 minus b and the corrupt sender should
not know the choice bit b
this simple primitive suffices for
general secure computation it's complete
we also know that round optimal ot
enables round optimal secure computation
hence in this work we focus on obtaining
round optimal ot protocols
ot also has other applications like
private set intersection and zero
knowledge
and in this work uh we want to achieve
universal composibility security uh
based on canadia's rank entities model
so we are gonna focus on uc security
so let me briefly recall the security
properties required from our ot
protocols firstly the corrupt receiver
should not know m1 minus b and the
corrupt sender should not know
b
to get simulation based security we need
probabilistically polynomial time
simulator
sim such that it can extract a corrupt
sender and a corrupt receiver's input
given the trapdoors of the setup stream
or some extra power
we model the security of the protocol by
considering a ppt algorithm simulator
the simulator interacts with the real
world
adversary algorithm to create an ideal
world adversarial view
given access to the functionality we say
that security holds if the view of the
adversary in the real world is
indistinguishable from the view in the
ideal world where it interacts with a
simulator sim
we also consider adaptive security which
is the strongest security model in the
setting the adversary can adaptively
corrupt any of the honest parties before
during or after protocol execution
the adversary obtains the internal state
of the honest party upon corruption in
such a case the simulated honest party
view has to be opened consistently to
the honest party's input when the party
gets corrupted in the ideal world that
is non-trivial and really hard to
achieve and that is the focus of our
paper and we also consider malicious
corruptions where the corrupt party can
arbitrarily
deviate from the protocol
so let me briefly discuss the current
works on adaptively secured mpc
protocols
it is known that
constant round adaptively secured mpc is
impossible from black box simulation
duty guard against high
so the works of gurg at all and the
recent work by chakravati at all
construct constant round adaptively
secured npc protocols from non-black box
techniques
in the setup model the works of kennetti
at all and subsequently choi atoll and
gara at all constructed
linear round protocols using the gmw
paradigm
the work of hazai at all showed that
public key encryption
with oblivious cipher text
generation is the minimal assumption
required for adaptively secured mpc
however this protocols are not
round optimal so the focus
in this work is to obtain two round mpc
which is adaptively secure in the setup
string model
in the setting there are a few works
which used io
uh and finally there are only two works
which construct uh two round adaptively
secured mpc
from
standard assumptions the work by ben
muda at all
constructed it from ddh lwe and
quadratic residuosity in the common
reference ring model
the recent work by kennedy at all
constructed uh
uh the same construct achieved the same
result from ddh in the common random
string model
but these are like only three
assumptions that we know from so we ask
the question whether can we construct it
from more assumptions
so we focus on constructing
uh
the mpc protocol from other assumptions
so we demonstrate that a two round ot
with indistinguishability based security
and uh something called oblivious
receiver
message sample ability implies
a two round adapted to secure mpc
so we call this ot primitive as riot
and this is a very weaker ots primitive
compared to adaptively secure ot
and then we built our iot from cdh lpn
and isogenes so this yields the first
two round adaptedly secured mpc protocol
from cdh lpn and isogenes in the
malicious setting and in the semi honest
setting uh we considered the first
uh two-round adaptively secure mpc
protocol from lpn and isogenes uh ben
muda at all constructed it from cdh in
the seminar city
and uh to be more specific uh for
isogeny so we construct it from group
actions uh which can be instantiated
using the sea side and the sea fish
assumption
as a side result we also construct the
first non-committing encryption from lpn
in the setup string model
so let us briefly go through
so let me briefly go through the
techniques
let me briefly recall the security
properties of indistinguishability based
ot
firstly the receiver corrupt receiver
should not know
m1 minus b and the corrupt center should
not know b so this can be modeled as we
can see here
that suppose
the receiver's choice bit is 0 then it
should not distinguish between
a sender's message when m1 is 0 from a
case where m1 is 1
and for the sender
for a current sender
it should not be able to distinguish
when
the
receiver's choice bit is 0 from the case
where the receiver's choice bit is one
so this is iot or indistinguishability
based ot next we will add sample ability
properties for the sender and the
receiver message
so
we will consider the ot protocol in the
crs model where
uh the setup string consists of the crs
and it is generated along with the
trapdoor so the trapdoor will be used by
the simulator
uh
which we will see later
so firstly uh let me describe receiver
sample ability property very qui we
require that there exists
a probabilistically polynomial time uh
algorithm ob1 which obliviously samples
a receiver message pr okay
so now a simulator can honestly
construct a receiver message using the
ot1 algorithm
and the simulator can claim that this pr
on the right hand
right hand side is obliviously sampled
in order to do that it needs to give a
randomness for the
like uh randomness which is consistent
with the oblivious generation of pr
so we require another algorithm inv
invert one
which
uh inverts the randomness
of the
like
simulator which was used to generate the
actual ot message and it gives out
randomness which is consistent with the
oblivious sampling of the receiver
message
and the two distributions of the
receiver message and the sampling
randomness should be computationally
indistinguishable and that is the
receiver sample ability property
next we need
sender sampleability property we require
that there exists probabilistically
polynomial time algorithm ob2 which
allows obliviously sampling a sender
message ps corresponding to bit 1 minus
w
the adversary provides m0 and m1 as
input messages and the algorithm is
parameterized
by the adversary's chosen branch
1 minus b
now a simulator can honestly construct a
sender message using the ot-2 message
algorithm
the simulator can claim that it was
obliviously sampled
and in order to do so the simulator is
required to provide the sampling
randomness which he obtains by using the
inv2 algorithm so that inverts
the
senders honestly generated senders
uh message randomness into a sampling
randomness and the two distributions
over the sender message
receive a message and the sampling
randomness should be computationally
indistinguishable by the center sample
ability property
so these are the two
properties that we need
and we denote an
indistinguishability based ot with
receiver sample ability as riot
and we denote an indistinguishability
based ot with both sender and receivers
ample ability as rs iot
now we will discuss our techniques in
the crs model we start off with our iot
we show that riot with a few other
primitives imply rs iot these primitives
are equivocal and obliviously sampleable
gobbling and obliviously sampleable
commitment scheme these are all
instantiable from one way functions in
the crs model
our work also shows that rs iot suffices
for trapdoor simulatable pke and crs
model
next we construct semi-adaptive ot from
iors iot
equivocal commitment scheme and
oblivious ampliable gobbling and trapdos
immutable pke
combined with the result
of cdmw we also get non-committing
encryption from trapdoors immutable pke
which can be obtained from riot
finally we apply the result of blpv to
get an adaptively secured mpc protocol
from our iot
finally we show that riot can be
constructed from cdh lpn and group
actions in the crs model
so let me briefly go through the
building blocks
we require garbling schemes a garbling
scheme consists of three algorithms it
takes an input a circuit c and
randomness r it outputs a garble circuit
gc and the encoding table en
the encoding algorithm takes an input
the encoding information and input x and
it outputs encoded
input a capital x the evaluation
algorithm takes a
garble circuit and the encoded input and
it computes the output y
correctness of gobbling ensures that y
is same as c of x privacy of the goblin
scheme ensures that the encoded input
does not leak anything about the in
private input x
this is captured using a ppt simulator
which outputs a garble circuit and the
encoded input given the output y without
knowing what is x an adversary cannot
distinguish a simulated carbon circuit
and a simulated encoded input from an
honestly generated one
we also required equivocal goblin
property where the simulator generates
the simulated carbon circuit and the
encoded input then later on it gets the
input x and it has to produce the
encoding information and the goblin
state so given these information and
adversary cannot distinguish
these from an honestly generated one
such goblin schemes are instrumental for
adaptive security and they can be
constructed from one-way functions as
shown by kennedy at all
finally we need oblivious gobbling
schemes here an obliviously generated
garble circuit
always outputs y and can be sampled
using an algorithm called ogb algorithm
with randomness r
and there exists a randomness inversion
algorithm which outputs randomness r
prime
such that an honestly generated carbon
circuit with randomness r can be shown
to be obliviously garbled using random
randomness r prime
the difference from equivocal gobbling
is that the adversary does not get the
entire encoding information since the
garbage circuit is supposed to be
obliviously garbled and there is no
encoding information when the garbage
circuit is obliviously gobbled
and
the work by lindell at all
obtained oblivious goblin schemes from
one way functions
next i will talk about commitment
schemes in the crs model there are three
algorithms the setup algorithm generates
the crs and the trapdoor td the
commitment algorithm generates the
commitment c to message m using
randomness r the verify algorithm
decomputes the commitment to check it
the commitment should satisfy binding
and hiding properties
uh finally we also need oblivious sample
ability property where an honestly
generated commitment can be claimed to
be generated obliviously by inverting
the randomness so oblivious and we know
that oblivious available commitments can
be obtained from one way functions due
to an hour at all
now i will go through our
rsiot construction from riot
we will try to construct our rsiot
using an oblivious available goblin
scheme oblivious available commitment
scheme and riot
the receiver commits to its choice bit b
using randomness r to form a commitment
c
it computes riot receiver algorithm
using the bits of r as choice bits
the sender gobbles the circuit
cir so the circuit has hard coded inside
it the commitment c
a bit e and a message m it takes in
randomness
r and outputs m is c is a commitment to
bit e using randomness r
now the sender will garble this circuit
cir
with e c
and m e as hard coded inputs right and
um he
runs this for both e is equal to zero
and one
this way the sender computes two carbon
circuits gc0 and gc one which encrypts
m0 and m1 within it
the receiver should be able to evaluate
gcb correctly and obtain m b if c is a
correct commitment to b using randomness
r
the sender also computes ot sender
message using the encoding information
of the gable circuits so the receiver
gets the wire labels corresponding to
the bits of ri
the sender sends the garbage circuits
and the riot sender messages
now the receiver decrypts the wire
labels for gcb corresponding to
randomness r it evaluates gcb
to obtain mb
indistinguishability based security for
a
receiver follows from riot receiver
security and hiding of commitment scheme
and the sender security follows from
binding of the commitment scheme uh riot
center security and privacy of the
goblin scheme
uh also we can see that this protocol
satisfies receiver oblivious sample
ability because it follows from
oblivious sampling of commitment scheme
and receive your oblivious ample ability
of the iot messages
however
we cannot argue sender oblivious sample
ability since the sender is committed to
the riot sender messages
even if we use the oblivious
goblin scheme
instead of a regular goblin scheme here
the adversary can distinguish
since the encoding information is
committed
inside the riot sender messages
if we use equivocal garble circuit then
the output of the garble circuit needs
to be set at the time of the goblin it
cannot be changed when inverting the
randomness and hence the riot sender
messages will again help in
distinguishing and obliviously sampled
send a message from an actual one
so we have to modify
uh the
previous construction so in the new
construction or the our final
construction the receiver algorithm
remains the same
the sender algorithm now consists of two
levels of gobbling
the sender gobbles the circuit cir
the circuit cir has hardcoded inside it
the commitment c and the bit e
it takes in randomness r and some
message capital t has input and outputs
capital t if c is a commitment to bit e
using randomness r so this is the outer
gaba circuit
there is anoth there is an inner global
circuit gc prime
that is going to encrypt the sender's
message
uh m so it takes an input a commitment c
prime randomness s and a message m
and g c
uh e prime
uh outputs m if c prime is a commitment
to 0 using randomness using some
randomness s so this is the circuit cir
prime
now the sender computes a commitment to
zero
using randomness and it computes the
encoded input
for c e prime in gce prime as te
the sender computes the outer encoding
of te and sends it to the receiver it
also sends the inner encoding of
sc and me to the receiver
the sender also computes riot sender
messages on the ri
bits
ri bits of receiver
the two inner gaba circuits
and the two outer garber circuits are
also sent to the receiver
now the receiver decrypts the ot
messages to obtain wire labels for ri in
gcb
it has obtained the wire labels for tb
already from the sender's message
it computes
gcb like the outer global circuit
corresponding to bit b to obtain
t b which is the inner encoding of c
prime
b
right
and it evaluates the inner
gcb prime
on tb and the inner encodings of
sb and
mb to obtain capital mb
so we can
again
uh claim that receiver oblivious sample
ability follows from oblivious sampling
of commitment scheme
and uh also from the receiver sample
ability of the riot protocol this is
similar to our
previous construction
center oblivious sample ability follows
from oblivious sampling of c prime
equivocal cobbling and oblivious
amplibility of the inner garble circuit
so here we require equivocal gobbling
property from the outer global circuit
and oblivious sample ability from the
inner gap circuit suppose the receiver's
choice bit is b which can be obtained
from distinguished dependent simulation
to obliviously sample the sender message
corresponding to bit 1 minus b the
sender obliviously gobbles the inner gc
prime 1 minus b and provides obliviously
generated encoded inputs instead of
correct inner encodings for branch 1
minus b on the carbon in a
in a garbage circuit one minus b
if we use the linear pincas construction
then these are random values instead of
uh obliviously generated encoded inputs
so now an adversary cannot distinguish
between an honestly sampled send a
message from an obliviously sampled one
since in both the real and ideal worlds
the outer double circuit for one minus b
branch always outputs a bot or a junk
value
this holds true even if the adversary
obtains the outer goblin randomness due
to
uh
due to the equivocal property of the
outer garbage circuit
so the simulator can claim that one
minus b branch was obliviously sampled
and this trick of two layering of
gobbling allows us to obtain uh
rs iot from our iot
for more details i would suggest you to
check our paper
uh so
let me summarize
uh what we discuss so in this talk we
just saw this construction that is
highlighted for the rest of the
protocols i would refer to the paper
in this work we constructed two round
adaptively maliciously secured mpc from
riot and instantiated riot from cdh lpn
and isogenics
to end with an open with two open
questions what is the minimal assumption
for two round maliciously secured riot
or more general
what is the minimal assumption for two
round adaptively maliciously secure mpc
protocol
thank you