um when the keep lives kick in or layer
2 protocol pulls it down in that case
but you know be if you can work out
certainly to your advantage there once
again another part of BFD is you have
the village specify a minimum thresholds
where you could basically say that what
are the minimal thresholds of that you
want to operate at and from there it's
continuously negotiating what those
timers are going to be that the routers
can support so it's not like a static
number and you basically specify you're
defining a enabling this on a bgp paper
group for external peers or whatnot you
just specify the minimal thresholds that
you want to operate at and the protocol
will negotiate and continually negotiate
what timers you can safely operate at
and then once the failure is detected it
could then will that session down so um
you know typically with bgp neighbors
you can already by default specify keep
lives and what interval on a per
neighbor basis with this you could
probably do the similar here but it
works out on you know exchange plan of
where if they're participants people
with different thresholds of what they
can operate on the routers people with
different kind of routing engines and
route processors you know so you can set
just a threshold and then it will
negotiate higher as as configured
another one where another instance where
you can run PFD is an MPLS space
specific with LDP you can use this for
essentially path verification although
you can't really use it to actually
reroute or you know trigger any kind of
action in the router because with LDP
you're relying upon your lgp there IGP
to tell you where to route but what it
can do is it can at least provide some
sort of liveliness detection to say for
a particular fact that has gone down and
notify you that at least in you know
syslog and whatnot so it does provide
you ability to see when an LDP based
path is no longer reachable this is
pretty useful in you know certainly LDP
networks especially if you've run into
issues with LDP black holdings can
typically pick it up for you
another capability with LDP is it allows
you to do ecmp so within your network
you can have a path branch out to
multiple paths across the network and
with BFD here I can use
nation of LSP ping and traceroute to
discover the entire ecmp tree to the
destination and it could create a BFD
session for each individual path and
then transmit the packets along and you
can bring up the sessions there and a
quick little picture of that is shown
here where in this case you have two
individual BFD sessions on two diverse
paths that have equal cost the next one
um covers em plus with our our via
rsvp-te LSPs in this case you can use
BFD on individual our feet our three p
LSP that's established and one of the
things that you can do here is because
you know the LSP takes one single path
is you can actually enable bft on a
given LSP and when the LSP fails you can
actually you know take some actions at
that point so let's say you have a given
destination router you have an LSP - you
could build multiple paths there and
enable BFD in each individual one and
you can say well if PFD is running once
LSP across the network something fails
well then you can trigger that the
standby LSP will take over rather than
relying upon something else happening
the network such as getting our to be
message back at the head and saying that
the path is gone or waiting for CS if
you have to run and take a different
path in this case so um it really gives
you a nice little if you you know have a
given destination you want to verify
that you can talk to it you can use be a
fee to really trigger and detect if
anything's broken along the on the path
another capability although I haven't
really seen this one employed is that
you can use our BFD in the
point-to-multipoint
LSP scenario and the only reason you
know perhaps why anyone want to do this
is you know point-to-multipoint LSPs are
typically used for distributing video
content and things like that across the
network and in those cases you are
already having some sort of additional
constraints on you such as rapid
reconvergence
so you've got faster route enabled
bandwidth reservation sometimes and even
explicit routing to stay on SRL G free
path so in case where you're probably
doing point-to-multipoint there's
typically a reason for it you're
carrying some that's somewhat important
DF D can be useful here to detect a
failure as well another case I've seen
is deploying I'm not sure
if anyone has implemented is that you
can actually run it in the pseudo
airspace so when you're building either
you know ethernet layer 2 VPNs layer 2
circuit pseudo wires from appointment to
different end points you can use BFD in
this space to actually verify that
connectivity works and and well
obviously there's no such thing as a
free lunch and there are some caveats to
actually using PFD and the two main ones
at least that I've seen is that it does
it can have high resource demands on the
router depending what kind of robber you
have out there and what timers you're
using as well as it doesn't really have
any visibility and layer 2 protocols
specifically bundling protocols so
Ethernet bundles things like that go on
the first one the resource demands
obviously you're running BFD you're
running this instance on either line
card or raw processor it's firing off
pretty frequently the more sessions are
going to add the more it's going to you
know utilize the resources on our given
router right not only that but each
individual vendor you know can put their
own stipulation when you create a PFD on
an interface where they'll put a minimum
transmit receive interval where you may
have it enabled you may want to select
you use lower timers but those software
has been you don't essentially
instructed to say don't I know you're
doing it on a bundle interface your
minimal minimum interval has to be at
least 250 milliseconds so even though
you want to run it lower you may not be
able to just because the vendors put
some sort of control into it in that
case another thing is you know where
you're going to run BFD iran's you know
it can either run a distributed model
but depending on the protocol it may run
off the route processor just because
it's not directly associated with any
physical adjacency so if you're running
it on ibgp sessions or you're doing in
an LSP it's got to come from a
centralized location on a router which
means it's it's ending up on the wrong
processor in the end anyways so you know
the raw processor is doing other things
could be doing bgp could hold all the
sort of options you know that it's you
know it's something that you would be
concerned about and you know the main
thing here is that you need to test your
platform before you do anything here
whatever you're going to deploy you
definitely want to stress it and put
some load on to it to see at least if
you know you're able to break a be a few
G's
see in this case and you know there's
lots of ways you could do this there but
definitely you know I want to stress
that you should definitely should test
the stress test your box there's a lot
of ways you can do this you can execute
a lot of regex commands on the raw
processor itself you could try to
simulate a denial of service attacks
such as if you wanted to see what a
lying heart can handle well make the
long card CPU work a little bit harder
you know sent packets the TTL expire on
its and options do whatever you can
right because when you actually end up
deploying this you're going to see a lot
of different things in the wild that you
just may have no thought would come up
and you definitely don't want PFD of
either pulling things down accidentally
in production regarding what kind of
values are safe to try one popular one
that here is you know 300 milliseconds
minimum transmit/receive intervals the
multiplier of 3 which gets you just
barely below a second so it's
technically sub second in that case and
probably seen a vendor documentation
they seem to recommend that value as
well and some of them but once again you
should probably try some particular
value that you're safe with and then you
can work down from there in any event
that it's still better than what the
alternatives are which is relying on
your existing timers or even cranking
down on your existing timers or you have
to you know maintain that across your
network and then if you have different
kinds of equipment out there different
route processors and you have to set
different values for different boxes
it's still an improvement than what you
know you may have today um the other
caveat that I mentioned was PFD and link
bundling and one of the things here
that's kind of a an issue is that if you
do have multiple things so layer 2
bundle if they worked at layer 3
generally when you're building in that
cross let's say an IP adjacency it
doesn't know that there's you know 4
links 10 links or whatever's really
underneath so when those bf descends how
this datagrams it's typically going to
you know treat it like it would any
other packet that's going across a link
right so layer 2 hash it's going to say
okay I've got four interfaces you know
this packets going out on number two for
example it's not going out through all
four although there's some
implementations reportedly that that can
do this but it's only going to go out
through one and the response is only
going to come off
other interface in that case and well
the problem with that is well that in
that case what would happen is let's say
it's going on the interface that just
happened to have gone down well do you
want to clear the entire bundle is down
at that point just because boy I'm an
individual member link failed you
probably don't want to do that so it
can't really can bite you in that
scenario a lot of it is dependent on you
know the PFD implementation on the
router for example you have a layer to
link bundle go down by the time it sends
out the next Datagram it could have had
already rehash the layer two bundle and
send it out on a different interface so
it you know it can perhaps work around
the inefficiencies of the way that the
layer to hash from that fact that BFD
lacks ability to look inside of layer to
bundle back on this one obviously is
somewhat of a show show show stopper
given that you know layer to link
bundling is pretty popular with and by
ten geeky links you know 40 gig is there
but you know 100 gig is still far along
the way so you know the fact that this
doesn't really work all that well in
layer 2 bundles can be a bit of a
showstopper
what would be kind of neat would be if
you have the capability for BFD to fork
on individual member interfaces and
operate on every single one and then
send it back but of course if you were
to do that then you have a different
additional BFD sessions to have to worry
about and then that's going to impact
your scaling as well
on the conclusion so a few different
notes here routers do still have faults
in the forwarding plane and you know we
ride you where you can actually have a
fault and you know I hope you can remain
up but the line cards just do not
forward and I know in 2008 there are at
least pretty to large events that did
happen where routers just you know oh I
see a Jason sees remained up but packets
were just not forwarding through the
boxes and you know could take anywhere
from minutes or hours in some cases for
people to really realize what was going
on you know the default hello keep a lot
of timers that you know some protocols
have today they're still too high a lot
of people don't adjust them
and you know it's unfortunate but a lot
of people don't know all the knobs and
the preacher have the time to really
experiment and see what works
you know BFD kind of says it's a little
bit of a shortcut to say well don't
bother playing with them just go to this
it's a standardized method the sessions
are implementations pretty much well
support on most vendors today just you
know you don't have to worry about
tweaking it you try this as an option
you know on the issue of the link to
layer to link bundling issues it'd be
great if you know there was a way that
you can actually get be a fee to work in
this environment and given that you know
and by 10 gig is probably going to be
with us for still quite some time and by
40 gig if you're doing it 768 and
whatnot you're still gonna have the same
problem there too
the other issue is definitely always
remember to stress test your equipment
you know not one size fits all when it
comes to some of these configurations
regarding you know just holding a lot of
different operators who do run BFD today
it seems that you know of all the ones
that I've listed the only two that
really are popular are using it in the
ebgp space and using it for IGP
adjacencies but outside of that I don't
really seen anybody who's actually used
it in you know the MPLS environment you
know some minimal stuff with a OAM to
use it for LDP paths to really notify
when black holding or things like that
occur but it seems you know the ebgp and
I to be adjacencies are probably like if
you're going to play with it that's
probably the first place to start and it
seems to have worked
ok and some people's networks today but
you know there's a lot of people pairing
here there's a lot of people exchanges
it'd be interesting to see if you know
people said hey you know we went to this
whole md5 thing and that was a pretty
large group effort that a lot of people
you know went through they'd be
interesting to see if a lot of people
would go through kind of a similar
support of hey let's err enabling VFD in
the I exes and see how things work out
and in a widespread manner at least to
find out what blender is it works out
well with and what numbers has a lot of
data out there there's some you know
supporting if people are running this
today or how well it's been working for
them and that's pretty much about it I
don't know if there's any questions
comments