okay yeah the audio they're welcome we
have a very full tutorial so let's get
started this tutorial is presented by
two instructors first Kevin no Berman
has been in the industry for almost
three decades and in the peering
coordinator community for over a decade
and as for me my name is Bill Norton and
I have been working with parent
coordinator zh for the last 10 years or
so so we heard a couple of the internet
gray beards you can laugh and applaud
now ha ha ha Kevin and I have assembled
some material intended to provide a
high-level overview of the topic of
internet pairing along with some
on-the-ground experience that should
prove illustrious of the fearing
coordinator job this is pairing 101
let's get started but first bill tells
me I have to introduce him with an
amusing story this guy sits down at a
bar and hears a voice say hey I like
those shoes he turns around but no one
but the bartender is around he hears the
voice say I like your shirt he looks
around again but no one else is in the
bar he hears the voice say like your
haircut too he looks around and still no
one else is in the bar he calls over the
bartender and explains what he is
hearing the bartender smiles and
explains it is the peanuts they're
complimentary ha ha ha Bill let's get
started ok I tried something new maybe
it's in perfect okay thank you very
what today Kevin and I have put together
a presentation that is really appearing
101 talk at the end of this talk you
will understand specifically what the
definitions of transit are what the
definition of Internet peering is and to
some extent some of the evolutions that
we've seen endearing ecosystem
particularly between the tier ones
tattoos and content providers over the
last five years or so we split this up
into essentially four sections the first
section will be introducing to you the
definitions used in the trade for
internet transit and Internet peering
then we're going to go on and apply
those definitions and the will in fact
be a quiz to begin test the definitions
in your mind one of the things that are
found in delivering this material over
the years is it very easy to sit there
and listen and maybe pick up some of the
stuff but until you actually are asked
questions and have to process in your
mind and then regurgitate and answer
back does it actually get firmly into
your mind then Kevin will take over and
talk a little bit about some of the
non-financial the more really down on
the ground type of experience level
expertise that he's accumulated over the
past couple of decades doing this stuff
and if we have time is anyone here
interested in talking about internet
exchange points okay a couple folks why
I could talk to internet exchange points
for hours and if there's time we could
do that here if there's not time then
let's circle up somewhere and open up a
conversation among those who are
interested in talking about that stuff
so Who am I who's this guy bill Norton I
initially worked at at merit networks
for 11 years Betty shared an office with
me remember way back then and during
those 11 years one of the things I was
tasked with doing was coming up with a
business case and a business plan for
fern and off for this event question was
how do we get this thing funded do
registration fees and all that kind of
off after 11 years of merit I finished
on my MBA and went to help find Equinix
my official title was co-founder and
chief technical liaison and in that role
I worked with the peering coordinators
to help facilitate their interaction so
a lot of the data that you're going to
hear today comes from the nine or so
years of experience that I had working
with the peering community at equinix
probably most people know me from the
internet white papers that I've authored
with the community that are really a
public source of information about
peering and internet operations and how
that all works back in May of last year
I retired I cashed out my stock and just
before the collapse of the economy so it
actually timed out about right but first
I think so you know where I'm coming
from let me say a few words about the
the internet white papers that are
freely available for you to to download
one thing i noticed back in 1998 was
that there were lots of documents
describing protocols and specific
hardware technologies and how those work
routing algorithms and convergence and
that kind of stuff but at that time
nobody had documented the peering
process how does it work how do you find
out who to peer with how do you choose
whether the period at exchange points to
use point-to-point circuits and that
kind of operations activities so I took
it upon myself to ask some of the
smartest people in the world like like
Ren provo and Dan Goulding and Patrick
Gill well avi Friedman and a variety of
folks and I documented what they said in
the form of a white paper and over
lunches I would walk other folks through
that white paper and see what they said
and Randy Whitney would say that's kind
of how it works we need to modify this
revenge fuller would say you know a
Genuity we don't actually look at that
we look at this so through a series of
stepwise refinements over a period of
100 walkthroughs the white paper evolved
until it pretty much represented the
mindset of the community for a
particular operations topic so I did the
same thing again
and again and again with different
operations issues that people thought in
the internet circle that we all travel
in were critical issues to to document
things that had never been documented
before so all these white papers are
freely available there the taught at
universities around the world you can
search for my name William B Norton and
you'll find all these things popping up
at university websites and session to
free download them take a look at them
there's a lot of knowledge really cold
from the field here in these white
papers so I encourage you to take a look
at those so let's take a look at the
very first one the very basic
definitions of appearing in transit
first understand that of course the
internet is a network of networks and as
such an Internet service provided by
definition cells access to the global
internet so must himself get connected
up to somebody who's already attached to
the global Internet he does that in at
one of a couple ways there's a service
called transit which is defined as a
business relationship whereby one isp
purchases access to the global internet
typically a metered service