big round of applause please thanks
yeah I'm Ethan I'm a PhD student at the
University of Washington and this is
work with Harsha who just graduated from
u-dub and it's now at UCSD Vijay is at
University of Minnesota and then Arvind
and Tom are my advisors that u-dub so
Tracy so it's the most widely used
Internet diagnostic tool you can use it
to check up at destinations reachable if
it is you can see what the route taken
was if it's not you can try to figure
out where the routes broken you can
check if the paths longer than necessary
so maybe there's some path inflation due
to some out-of-date local perhaps
something like that going on at
University of Washington we use trace
route map the internet we have a system
for predicting performance we compare
ISPs a couple years ago I was at nanog
when it was in Bellevue and I talked
about a preliminary version of my system
called Hubble which detects black holes
and reach ability problems so you know
if we're gonna consider what it means
for me to be able to reach some web
server there's this path from me to the
web server that's the yellow path shown
there and then there's also the path
back and trace routes a great tool to
measure the path from you the yellow one
but you know it doesn't really give you
the path back and what I quickly
realized working on Hubble is if the
problems on the forward path then we can
get a pretty good idea of what's going
on but if it's on the reverse path and
we're pretty much flying blind I'm only
getting part of this story and that's
really been limiting my work similarly
you might want to understand the paths
of the traffic that's coming back to you
so we were talking to people to major
website and they had clients in a set of
prefixes in Taiwan who are experiencing
latencies of more than 500 milliseconds
and that was even though they were being
redirected to a data center that was
nearby in Southeast Asia so the people
from the website suspected that the
problem was sort of an indirect reverse
path but they have almost no visibility
into the reverse path they need a way to
measure the paths from their clients
back to their network so that they can
diagnose and address these performance
problems and then at Richard's
traceroute tutorial on Sunday he said
that asymmetric paths are the number one
plague of trace routes and similarly
that the reverse
closeted itself is almost invisible so
you know reverse path information is
really useful for most of the same
reasons this trace reality but if you
want to get the reverse path from D you
have to actually run trace route on D so
one solution that we have is we can use
public trace route servers that's great
but there's only a few hundred of them
so if there's not one in the destination
that you care about you're sort of out
of luck you can maybe mail the mailing
list ask someone for help maybe someone
can issue a tracer up for you and often
we have to fall back on assuming that
there's symmetric routing which is
basically never true so none of these
really work as well or as often as you'd
want and we're basically using them
because we have to not because we want
to so the goal of this work is a reverse
trace route that can work without
control of the destination so we need a
way to identify hops on the reverse path
we can't just use TTL limiting like
trace route because the destination is
going to set the detail to a normal
value and anyway even if there were TTL
expirations along the path those errors
would go back to the destination instead
of coming to us so unlike TTL IP options
are reflected in the reply so if you set
an IP option on the forward probe then
it's going to be reflected in the
reverse and you can get reverse path
information so we're going to use two IP
options the first one we're gonna use is
record route record routes going to
record the first nine routers along the
path so this is great if the destination
was within eight hops reverse hops will
fill out the rest of those slots but the
average path on the Internet's about 15
hops in each directions this is really
only going to work if we care about a
destination but it's close to us the
second option that we're going to use is
the timestamp option with the timestamp
option you can specify up to four IP
addresses and each of them is going to
record a timestamp if they're traversed
in order so the key there is that the
timestamp checks for the routers in
order so a router is only going to stamp
if its address is in the next open slot
this means that if we paying the
destination D and ask for timestamps
from D and then from our D will time
stamp when the probe gets there and then
our is only going to fill it out if it's
on the reverse path after D is stamped
so we can use this to check if hops
around the reverse path what we do is we
can guess or reverse hop by using an
internet map and there's a number of
services available out there and then we
can check between the various
adjacencies which one is actually the
one but unfortunately the time stamp
option is has even less deployment than
record route it's filtered and so in a
couple slides I'm gonna get to how often
we see them supported so we now have a
couple techniques that can get us some
perverse path information but as I said
record route is only going to work we
happen to be near the destination so
what we're gonna do is use distributed
vantage points and source spoofing to
help us get closer to more destinations
so in this case we have my computer we
have the web server I'm trying to get
the reverse path from the web server
back to me and then I have another
computer down at the bottom that I can
also use and let's say that that other
computer happens to be within 8 hops of
the destination what I can do is send a
probe from that other computer but spoof
and say that it's coming from my
computer and so the response is going to
come back to me and so I'll get that
reverse path information so spoofing is
gonna let us simulate being in prefixes
where we actually lack of presence and
I'll get more into spoofing in a second
but the key here is that a small number
of well distributed sources can support
the entire system and in the results
that I'm gonna present in this talk I'm
using 30 around the world to support the
entire system so all right I just never
gonna use spoofing probably raise some
flags so we're definitely aware of the
security issues but we think that it's
feasible to employ it safely as a useful
tool with limits on it that are gonna
keep it from being dangerous we only use
a really restricted version of spoofing
that's perfectly safe we only ever spoof
as notes that we control so essentially
we're using it like a reply to address
telling the destination to reply to a
different one of our nodes we're sending
it from one vantage point to another but
we're sort of bouncing it through the
destination in the middle so we envision
a restricted version of spoofing that's
available on measurement deployments
with a list of who you're allowed to
spoof as rate limits set on how often
you can do this and also a restriction
on destinations so far we've sent
millions of spoofing probes to tens of
thousands of IP addresses and we haven't
received any complaints so between
between the rate-limiting that we're
doing and also the fact that we only
as other nodes we control this really
has little in common with the sort of
evil uses of spoofing where you're doing
it to conceal who's doing the action
it's much more like the address
rewriting that happens at Nats when
you're writing in the address of another
one of your nodes in order to control
the flow of traffic to a cooperative
host so like I said before all we need
is a small number of sweeping vantage
points to run the system and spoofing
can be filtered everywhere else as long
as we can get through on a couple quarts
from those couple vantage points and
this is going to let us approximate
having control of the destinations where
we lack a point of revit presence we're
basically doing one hoppily source
routing through the destinations so
options are generally sent to the route
processor so lots of networks filter
them or ignore them to reduce the burden
or the potential of abuse so we want to
look at can we actually get the coverage
with record route and time stamp that we
need in order to build a system based on
them so what we did was took we used
planetlab
which is a measurement testbed with a
couple hundred vantage points around the
world we issued trace routes from
planetlab to essentially every routable
prefix and we took all the IP addresses
that we saw in those trace routes in
terms of record route support 58% of
those IP addresses are within 8 hops of
some planetlab vantage point so that
means 58 percent of them are close
enough that we can send a record route
from some planetlab vantage point and
get some reverse hops and then Rob
Sherwood did some related work that he
presented at sigcomm last year and found
that about 1% of the IP addresses that
are within in his case 9 hops of
planetlab drop record route packets
about 9% of routers don't record and
then also about 13% of routers record if
you encounter them not as part of an
MPLS tunnel but then don't record when
you encounter them in a tunnel so it
seems like pretty good coverage for
record out in terms of timestamp of all
those IP addresses that we saw about 37%
gave valid timestamps an additional 18%
replied but didn't set the timestamp we
zeroed in on the top 100 asses in terms
of the number of distinct IP addresses
that we saw and 61 of them supported
time stamping from most routers only
five of the top 100
toward it from less than 10% of the
tested routers so it seems like most of
the big a asses are giving at least some
support for these options and then you
know the the ones where we don't see
support the options are either dropped
the option might be ignored or it might
be filtered along the path so overall
there's pretty good support but it's not
universal
however we combine both these types of
options with spoofy and we can get
pretty good coverage and you'll see the
results on that shortly so we now have a
way to measure a reverse hopper maybe a
couple reverse hops back from a
destination we need a way to turn that
into a path and what we're gonna do is
exploit destination based routing so
most routing on the Internet's
destination based and so that means that
the next hop depends only on the
destination doesn't depend on the source
or on the path that we've taken so far
this means that once we know the path
from D to some router R we need to only
determine the path from are the rest of
the way back to our source we can ignore
the first part of the path using this we
can stitch together the path
incrementally and this is a
simplification with some exceptions but
it works often enough that we can build
a system around it so I've given an idea
of the different techniques we use to
build a path now I'm going to walk
through an example just to illustrate
how they fit together so in this case we
have a source s a destination D we want
the reverse path from D back to s we
have some vantage points v1 v2 v3
distributed around the world and some of
them are able to source spoof the first
thing that we're going to do is just you
trace routes from each of our vantage
points back to our source this is going
to give us an atlas of paths to the
source and if we intersect one of these
paths we're going to assume that the
rest of the path that we care about is
the same as it was along those blue
lines so we're just going to follow the
blue line in next we're gonna find a
vantage point that's within eight hops
of D that means that it can send a
record route and get some reverse path
information so in this case let's say
that v3 is within eight hops of D so v3
is going to send a pain to D with record
route enabled but it's going to spoof
and claim that the ping came from s DS
gonna get it in this case let's say when
D receives it seven of the river record
route slots are filled out
you will add itself into the record rap
and then reply to s and when s gets that
response we can see that there's now
some reverse path information in it we
know that our r1 is along the reverse
path so the reverse path looks like this
now we're going to continue that process
and find a vantage point that's within
eight hops of r1 in this case let's say
that v2 is within eight hops so v2 will
send a recorder out paying spoof as s
and let's say in this case when it gets
back to s we've learned two more reverse
hops R 2 and R 3 so we know the reverse
path looks like this now let's assume
that none of our vantage points are
within 8 hops of r3 what we do then is
consider a topology map showing router
connectivity and we're gonna look at the
set of routers that are adjacent to r3
so let's say that r4 and r5 are adjacent
r3 we're gonna use the time stamp option
to check which of them is on the reverse
path so s is gonna first check for r4
and it does that by sending a ping with
time stamp enabled to r3 and it's gonna
ask for our threes time stamp in r4 is
time stamp it's gonna get 2 R 3 R 3 will
fill out its time stamp and then reply
back and if r4 is on the reverse path
then when s receives the response it
should have our 4s time stamp in it we
can check that and when it gets back r4
has time stamped we now know that our
tour is on the reverse path and now
we've intersected one of our known paths
so we're going to use destination based
routing to assume that it's going to
follow the rest of the path in from v1
and so our reverse path looks like this
so we're able to combine together these
techniques to get the complete path and
we're also working on an extension using
some of these techniques to measure
one-way link latency instead of just
giving the standard round-trip time that
you normally get with trace route so
I've shown you how it works
the next key question I guess is how
often does it work and so we did a study
using about 30 planetlab sites as our
spoofed record route sources measured
reversed paths from 200 random
destinations around the internet back to
eleven planetlab sites around the world
if we're not able to get a complete
reverse path what we can do is issue a
forward trace route from the source to
the destination and we can assume that
the last hop on it is symmetric and then
try to go to reverse half back from
there that doesn't work we can assume
the last two hops are symmetric try
again if the destination and hosts
likely those last hops are symmetric or
at least close to it so hopefully this
assumption won't hurt us too much the
metric that's captured in this graph is
how many of the hops do we have to
assume are symmetric in order to get a
complete reverse path back the rest of
the way so it's a CDF so the way you
read it along the x-axis we have the
number of hops that we have to assume
are symmetric back from the destination
on the y axis it's the cumulative
distribution of source destination pairs
so probably the best way just to point
out the points that I have marked there
in 40% of the cases the value is 0 which
means that we get a complete path back
from the destination without assuming
any symmetry and then in the medium case
we have to assume that the first hop
back from the destination symmetric and
then we can measure the rest of the path
using our techniques so it seems like
we're often able to determine the
complete path when we can't we can
usually get it from a couple hops away
and the main limitation here is I guess
the number of sweeping managed points
that we have and then also networks that
don't honor the options that we're
sending
B I'm just giving you a path we would
like to give you the right path or a
path that looks similar to what you get
if you could actually run trace route
from the destination so we did a study
to evaluate that in this case we used
200 planetlab destinations because in
that case we can issue a trace route in
both directions and compare the trace
route from the destination to the
reverse trace out that we measure from
the source and again I'm using 11
planetlab sources so the graph here
shows the fraction the fraction of hops
that you see on that directly measured
trace route that we also find on our
reverse trace route and it's a CCDF so
to point out a couple points the black
line there is how well you do if you
just assume that the path is symmetric
so in the median case there we see that
you'll get 38 percent of the hops right
so not too great our techniques the red
line in the medium median case
can give you 87% of the same routers
that you would see with traceroute so
we're doing quite well identifying most
of the hops a big challenge though is
identifying it's hard to know if two
hops are the same and that's because
traceroute will generally give you the
incoming interface on each router record
route will often give you the outgoing
one or sometimes the loopback and so
it's hard to know which of these IP
addresses actually belong to the same
router we have some techniques that
we've borrowed for earliest
identification identify and which ones
belong on the same router but they don't
always work and so some of that gap some
of the reason we only identify 87% in
the meeting case might just be because
we don't know that the hops are the same
so to look at that a little bit instead
of considering if we get the routers
right we just looked at whether we get
the pops right where by pop we just mean
a given a s in a given City and we
basically identify pops using DNS names
so in this case the blue line shows that
in the median we get 100% of the same
hops that you would see if you could
issue trace route from the destination
back to your source there are other
reasons that we might return a slightly
different path than you see with trace
route for instance we might get
load-balanced in a different way or
there might be a path change in between
the two measurements so we issued trace
routes one day then we used to trade
shots again the next day which was about
the time scale that I was issuing the
record the reverse trace that's on we
saw about 26% of these paths change day
to day either due to load balancing or
actual path changes so between those two
stats it seems like we miss a few hops
sometimes but it's largely due to alias
issues and load balancing and this is
even in those cases where you have to
assume the first hopper to wear
symmetric another issue is hidden
routers some routers show up in record
route but not traceroute other routers
show up and trace route but not record
route there's also instances where a
destination based assumption might break
for instance if we hit a tunnel in the
middle it might not hold and then
perhaps I don't know of any cases where
options are routed differently but there
might be instance of that that you guys
can tell me about it seems like we're
doing pretty well we can basically give
you the same path that traceroute gives
you
so now showing you that our system works
pretty well and I'm going to walk
through an example of something that you
might use it for so in this case we
looked at Layton sees from planetlab
sources to those 200 random destinations
and look for ones that were inflated
based on the geographic location so in
this case we measured 150 millisecond
round-trip time from Orlando to Seattle
so that's about double what you'd expect
in one case when you might be looking
for instances like this is if you're a
contact content provider you might
detect poor performance to a client you
want to try to debug that so with
current practices what you can do is
issue a tracer you could check of it to
interact so that's what we did here's
the traceroute it starts in Florida goes
up to DC comes back down to Florida and
then goes across the walk to Seattle so
there is this detour up through DC and
that's costing us about 50 milliseconds
but it doesn't explain that big jump in
round-trip time between hops 9 and 10
from 53 milliseconds to 149 milliseconds
and so if you just add tracer at this
point you'd be sort of stuck you would
suspect that there's some problem on the
reverse path but you don't really know
what it is if you look up at hop 5 you
can also see that there's an inflated
round-trip time of 116 milliseconds but
that's not carrying through so that's
not affecting our RTP from Seattle so
with our tool you can issue a reverse
trace out and then you can check that
reverse path to see if it's indirect so
that's what we did and you see that the
reverse path starts in Seattle goes down
to LA and then comes back to Seattle and
then continues across the country
through Chicago so there's this big
detour through LA and that indirection
is causing the inflated round-trip time
that we saw in the forward tracer so it
seems like it's traveling down to LA on
internet then it's crossing over to
transit rail coming back to Seattle and
then going across the country so this
isn't necessarily a problem for instance
that might be the only place that they
pier but we've verified with a trace
route from u-dub that actually they do
pier in Seattle so there's not an
obvious reason for this interaction it
could be some out of data information or
there could be a reason that it's
happening on purpose but our tool gives
you a way to identify these problems and
help troubleshoot these inflated
latest you're seen so to wrap up Teresa
is obviously a very useful tool but it
doesn't provide you with the reverse
path information our reverse trace route
provides complimentary information and
fixes this limitation with traceroute it
could give you a much more complete
picture during unreachable 'ti I didn't
really get into that but we have some
ideas on that and actually they're going
to be in the slides that are posted
online if you want to take a look at
them after and generally we're giving
you most hops as if you issued a tracer
up from the reverse site there might be
some dead zones due to options coverage
but we think that it's a useful enough
tool to encourage supportive options so
in terms of how this affects you guys um
we're hoping to have a downloadable tool
by the right comedian in May that you
can run and then we'll let you plug into
our distributed system and get reverse
paths back to you using our advantage
points you can email me Ethernet CS
Washington DD you if you'd like to be
involved in that the coverage is tied to
the distribution of spoofing vantage
points and we're hoping to get people in
the community to host some of these to
increase our coverage so it's similar to
hosting a public traceroute server
except that our system will be the only
thing accessing it we're developing
software for that right now and the
codes gonna ensure you know stay for
eight limiting spoofing safety they're
only spoofing us nodes we control and
it's gonna have admission control
because it's all going through our
system so if you have some hosts that
you'd like to contribute we'd love to
have them and with that I'd like to
conclude and I'm happy to take questions
so I think you covered this but just to
make it more explicit yeah how much of
the source spoofing is planetlab let's
you do that and how much of that is
actually plausibly on a lot of public
networks so the MIT super project is
estimating that about 20% of IP
addresses can spoof probes there was a
discussion on nanog a while ago actually
prompted by a preliminary talk that I
didn't this where a number of people
thought that the number was actually a
lot higher than that so I think also
that we only need a few sets sites that
are spoofing and they only need to spoof
over set and reports so it's also
something that could potentially be
allowed to encourage the system because
reverse path information is useful
enough that providing the service based
on this could be encouraged so on the
one hand this audience could break that
functionality but they could perhaps
facilitate it working even more reliably
yeah yeah I think that if people decide
that they want access to this
information this is the way to get it
and I mean like I said we only need a
small number so it also doesn't have to
be like ok all of a sudden we turn off
filtering you know we have almost enough
vantage points to get pretty good
coverage already so thank you see Nick
had a chance you know we excuse me we're
all familiar with traceroute in the ways
that it in interpreting his results and
I think with the methodology here
there's all kinds of interesting
probably real edge case kinds of shark
you know where like if there's a because
you're attempting to give an address in
a packet to get a response back from an
intermediary node if that address
appears multiple places or you know
people have you know as before
exhaustion people get creative with
interface addresses and routers are
responding with different things these
probes then in turn might be putting
pockets and and then the results are
that the tool gives is going to be
potentially very very strange but I
don't think that that's today yeah so
there's certainly issues with that and I
think that I guess the best thing that
we can do is continue the sort of
comparison between traceroute and
reverse trade shot in situations where
we control it so I could do a follow-up
study using trade short survey or
something like that and try to identify
corner cases where we can actually
identify the case based on the probe
results so you know things like tunnels
things like that we might be able to
actually identify that something weird
going on and at least flag the results
in those cases okay
Anton Capello the five-nines data it
strikes me that the reason we're gonna
want to use a tool like this is
typically to debug problems and reach
ability or suspected I don't know maybe
highly congested highly multiplexed
links from content right
we're motivated to figure out what's
wrong right right things clearly wrong
could we change the last question you're
asking how some host can use to have
some applications we could stuff into
this perhaps is there a way for you guys
to extend the probe techniques maybe add
some packet frames or packet pairs to do
things like dumbbell detection in this
so that in the reverse path we were able
to see not only a here's how they reach
us and they're dumping through cogent
but they're announcing three-one-seven
that's you through you unite or someone
looks ready well appeared out but maybe
they are congested or aren't confessed
it is a question we could perhaps seek
to answer if this deployed if a
structure could support many warm more
prototype I think that's really
interesting and it's the type of thing
that we have on to think about this but
we haven't done much with and it's great
to hear that okay that's interesting
thing to look at we the only thing that
we thought about is how these ideas can
apply in situations of reach ability
problems where you can't even reach the
destination and we have some thoughts on
that but yeah definitely these are good
things to look at let it let it be a
voice for more encouragement Thanks
I am connect let's have you guys thought
about what could potentially happen in
the case this section goes back to a
discussion we had yesterday were an isp
might route traffic differently
depending on the source of the traffic
so if it came in from here versus
transit and you're doing spoofing they
might change that path depending on
where that traffic came from yes I mean
certainly these cases where destination
based routing breaks down break some of
the techniques that were using I guess I
mean it's how it's something we'd have
to look into more there might be ways
there are ways we can use multiple
advantage points to identify if you're
getting different results from different
places and we might be able to do
something intelligent about choosing the
proper one to use in different cases
that's kind of my question is this
actually accurate so we do that to to
identify when there are multiple paths
either if it's low bouncing or something
like that but we haven't looked that
much into how to characterize what the
cause of that is so we're mostly at this
point just assuming that it's um you
know hash-based load balancing that it's
not based on on where things are coming
from but it's an interesting idea to
look at it definitely Thanks