all right over the summer of 08 I chose
to roll out ipv6 on a single state for
City network it's now become larger
after an acquisition but we'll figure
out how the role extends further when
the time comes chose to do this because
the figure is easier to campaign for
everything else related to v6
deployments if this piece was complete
so quick touch on the architecture I was
dealing with for pops to court routers /
pop one small pop but otherwise it's GSR
connecting to our upstream transits is
entirely GSR and the customers are a mix
of platforms thankfully at least one of
them is going away general strategy was
v4 v6 dual stack deployment on any and
every box that was v6 capable looking at
our lifestyle going forward this covered
all the upstream most of the core
Ethernet in our two larger pops and t3s
and higher in the one pop that had a
dedicated GSR for that category of
customer so for our deployment tactics
unfortunately had no effective testing
lab available to us I do not have a GSR
do not have a super 720 in any way set
aside for us to experiment on but we do
have 2n redundancy throughout our core
layer so just push the traffic away from
one core threw it all in the other one
different commands depending on what I
GP was in use and that will talk about
the implications there coming up
scheduled to reload in 20 applied the
commands I had queued up crossed fingers
waited looks good canceled the reload
and for the most part that was what it
took for us VPN access from home came
through our San Antonio pop so I began
in San Antonio work my way through our
dallas pop worked through external stuff
in the dallas area continued through
houston and came my way back around to
san antonio and did it very
progressively one router the first day
two routers the next day and so on
sequentially that meant that the first
night was really just do these commands
blow up the router and nothing further
the second night was the next router
across a link and allows us to see if
the various protocols actually worked
and if routes through being learned
where they should be first phase covered
interface addressing and ospfv3 so once
the second router was well we got to see
an ospf adjacency get built and then the
second phase was rolling out vgp so the
basis of our configurations is our two
large pops Dallas and Houston are used
to announce our aggregate routes out of
the core layer so the second router to
get done in phase 2 allows us to see our
aggregate route get shared amongst all
the v6 capable routers in our network
assigned / 30 to you from Erin initially
made the mistake of trying to slice it
up and use way too many f's try to use
the very highest 48 in the range to do
our internal operations and that was
getting effing old use zeros it just
makes life so much easier so we're in
technically recurrent but it were almost
there yet and squishing back down to the
0 block to make things easier for
production the corporate stuff internal
addressing was the one area that I found
was the big unknown because the the
networks that already had v6 rolled out
but we're considering it their
competitive advantage and were therefore
not willing to talk about it I kind of
didn't know what to do and it finally
just became pick something think about
it refine it and then do it so for our
router loop backs missing a colon
between the f1 b8 and the pop we used
all of our pops are numbered and then
within each pop the various routers have
a particular node ID and so that the
loopback addressing basically has four
fields the 2607 f1 be a two colons and
then a pop number two node number links
within a pop are addressed as the prefix
Cohen Cohen the pop number
and then just a sequential link link ID
that we track internally and then an
endpoint ID and we use the 112 mask so
it falls on the colon boundary and
therefore there are five fields in use
in those addresses so you can begin to
recognize the difference between Aleut
back four and an intra pop of five and
an inter pop link that has six fields
and use referencing the lower numeric
pop number and the higher numeric pop
number and then a sequential link ID
running between those pops and then an
endpoint ID with a 112 bit mask so one
of the lessons learned was define
endpoint ID very carefully before you
start doing this I try to get way too
fancy by using the pop ID numbers or
router ID numbers on either end of the
endpoints and just kind of forgot the
right numbering sequence as I was doing
it for us it simply became easier to use
colon 1 and colon 2 across the board we
kept having endpoint collisions and why
am I not seeing routes and so forth but
once I slap myself and got standardize
on one and two life was a whole lot
easier going forward so our customer
assignment plan we would reserve a range
and use 112 for their lan or
interconnect link customers getting v6
would get a / 56 automatically if they
requested they get a / 48 they wanted
more than that we do it on a one-off
basis in reality no customers with these
six so there's unfortunately no data
there to use our general plan for
assigning those addresses to customers
was to divide and conquer starting off
with very middle and then kind of doing
5050 splits thereafter so that going
forward we have the maximum chance at
any one point for a customer to expand
their range should they ever ask you
later and we're dark ages but we're
using the spreadsheet for now I
understand the acquiring company has a
bit of a address management tools we'll
see what that works how well that works
for us but for now the spreadsheet
worked it's worked for us in before
going it is what it is six years ago as
we began v4 dynamic routing and finally
came into the century we started ospf
it's what we knew at the time three
years ago switched to is is a bunch of
reasons one of which we wanted to get
away from some ospf legacy issues we had
but and some other benefits however
we've gone back to ospf as part of this
process we had significant deployment
challenges because of multi topology in
is is I robley could have survived had I
gone through and deployed multi topology
it seems as though you've got to have
multi topo support from day one prior to
doing anything with v6 is is and I do
believe you've got to leave it there
permanently because it's essentially
impossible to do your v4 and v6 commands
truly simultaneously when you're adding
a new link or a new router we had major
bomb outs when we tried to put v6 if you
didn't have everything lined up
perfectly so we're back on ospf once
again and stayed with same ibgp hack as
we did and before loop backs and enter
pop links and enter pop links in the igp
everything else upstream and downstream
remaining in BGP internal services we
have none like I said my goal was to get
something out there and let everything
else kind of begin following from phase
1 our internal dns web and mail is
handled by our IT department they are
not ready yet for v6 but at least I'm i
can say i'm done and the balls in their
Court we are essentially more of a
wholesale bit mover most of our
customers your ISPs of a smaller nature
so our assumption is if they've got a
need for webmail or DNS they'll do so
within their own network and will
survive until were pushed into a need to
do so upstream transit dropped an email
at cogent said we'd like v6 what does it
take answer was not yet when we have no
roadmap for putting it out there
contacted abovenet not yet no
road map contact at ntt we'd be glad to
for some money very small increment but
I just amazingly hadn't heard that song
sung before it came as a bit of a
surprise so in the interim we've got a
hurricane electric tunnel we've got some
now some operational experience our
prefixes out there because i have no v6
dns i don't really know what to go ping
or traceroute so i'd say see random v6
addresses on mailing this post i go see
if we can reach them goes back to our
internal services so state of the packet
so far so good once we got past our
bombed-out attempts to try with is is
the transition was incredibly smooth
really just came down to 10pm couple of
nights applied some commands and routers
were happy and stable no customer demand
yet but we're still trying to catch up
to get this deployed in a lot of places
where the customers can actually use it
so i have this full expectation that you
know sales will sell it and we'll all of
a sudden have no ability to deliver it
but to the best of our knowledge the
equipment roadmap is restricted to v6
capable gear so at least going forward
will be better positioned so once we got
going it went well anyone who said there
isn't revenue to be made with v6 hasn't
picked up the phone because when I got
that call from NTT saying gladly for a
fee I realized hmmm maybe there is some
option for revenue and as an aside I can
only assume that are the availability of
these six on their transit connections
and whatever price difference there
might be is going to influence our
decisions going forward I plopped into
config snippets these are very shortened
just enough to show the global and
interface level commands that we plopped
in see other talks I've given for basis
of metric values and and you can
reference the earlier slides to find the
addressing formats this is taken from
our dallas pop which is pop number two
and core 2 which is router ID number two
and the link shown there goes from pop
to to pop 3 which is Houston it's the
third link going between those cities
and it's on the Dallas side which is the
lower numbered pop so therefore the end
point ID is a one phase to a quick
snippet of what dropped in for bgp
obviously more neighbors in this but
this is the basis and this is also one
on one of the core routers used to
originate our aggregate into our mesh
that's the ipv6 route at the bottom so
that it's available for bgp to propagate
if you'd like any further configuration
snippets from us feel free to contact me
but my goal here was really just to have
some sort of operational experience for
those of you who were looking to do this
kind of deployment and we're not yet
able to find some case studies let me
know what what kind of questions I can
answer and and I'll take questions now
Oh
Tom Daley dynamic network services so
with no internal services for DNS what
are you doing for v6 reverses because I
don't know about you guys felt like no
reverses in v4 I can kind of deal with
it reverses in v6 not having them makes
my life really miserable I my goal was
to have this segment of a v6 deployment
completed my understanding is our DNS
infrastructure currently is not ready to
do v6 like the best I can do to help
motivate that forward is to have an
operational need I told our IT
department this is coming you may have a
need for it soon I've told them it's
done you may have a need for it sooner
and it's not my power to force it
through it is what it is ok
happy hello I'm Louie Equinix so um your
nameservers can't answer in v6 could you
at least put the zone record so it can
answer the v4 i'll give that the dns
folks to deal with I my understanding is
we do have a much better or at least in
a more opps centric DNS architecture and
team post-acquisition so they may be
better position to put that out there
thanks for the presentation it's nice to
see various implementations I'm curious
if you have research to find it there's
any other outreach happening on the
system side of the world like the Aaron
community nano community ripe etc
pushing to say hey guys it's time to
started with mini v6 as well and and you
know I got that email from Aaron saying
folks you need to start making a plan
whatever plan that is you need to make
it do it do something passed it up to
management chain fell on deaf ears I
said I need to do something and the gues
parts losses for Aaron does Aaron have
an outreach program that that focuses on
system folks as well lesson maybe
somebody
so so that they aren outreach is is
right now it's been actually like I said
low barriers kind of focus a little bit
on enterprises because they are kind of
not well served by in their large
contingent the audience and and actually
I would love to hear from you in terms
of where these systems folks are how we
can actually reach up I think it might
be a really neat for Aaron or somebody
to allow for a repository of things like
scripts you know even simple things that
parse rancid configs and generate
reverse zones and comp files just a
place we can put them and go hey here's
what I've done it's really easy DNS
isn't that hard that that's already
there sourced internet so it's a
vailable in the community repository air
and put out but as a it was a suggestion
that would that we rolled out the end of
the last year fantastic thank you I in
Japan some hosting services company or
internet access subs company provide
ipv6 address automatically even the
customer doesn't form on it so I just
want to know if you have run to do the
same thing or do you have something in
mind are but if you are I mean the
reason that you don't do that or this
motor automatic assignment of v6 is part
of their service I see that on a road
map but at the time I did this
deployment I knew that the acquisition
was possible and felt that it wasn't in
my interest especially given the fact
there's limited routers in which we can
actually offer it that it was easier to
leave that part of autumn process
automation for future and I get the
impression there's now going to be a bit
more structure within our provisioning
people and from there we can make that
automatic and I'm just happy to say I
didn't have to listen to a Randy bush hi
Jay it's been missing and with the
amazing one of these speakers I just
it's like it's something's not here oh
ok I think we're good we are running