I'll be given this tutorial lessons
learned as a small network operator
things I've picked up on through various
different nanog presentations that have
made a huge difference in life as a
network operator agenda what we're going
to cover hopefully these slides are up
on the website by now overview and
background where I'm coming from basics
of our pop architecture a focus on igp
followed by bgp then mpls traffic
engineering some pointers on monitoring
and a few other random items from there
so email addresses there if you have any
questions afterward feel free to track
me down and ask whatever you'd like to
know up until basically last month maybe
even this month I was in a hybrid
engineering an OPS position for a small
telecom and isp in Texas recent we were
recently acquired so now I'm strictly in
the engineering department this in the
sense has increased the traffic that I
deal with by a factor of six so we'll
see what all changes going forward
general objective when you're doing
network design keep things simple Dave
Meyer said somewhere along the line be
realistic about the trade-off between
complexity and operational expenditures
and I simply say be realistic about your
network complexity no matter what if
it's simple it's easier for various
people to troubleshoot if it's simple
the network will scale and if it's
simple you can go to nanog and take
other vacations without a lot of stress
whenever you're doing engineering
troubleshooting or anything to do with
your network think like a router think
through what how will this router deal
with packet processing sequence how will
it forward this packet on a packet by
packet basis and then work your way
through your network on a router by
router basis as I coach knock people and
other operations staff on how to figure
out what's going on at this moment
this type of analysis comes in very key
for them so six years ago came into a
job working with for routers just one
router / pop ds3 is tying it all
together but we're doing a whopping 5
megabits to the internet over the next
three years we grew to 35 routers lots
of ds3 s200 megabits total and we've
slowed down since then but it has grown
another 50 megs at peak we're back down
around 200 recently but that's about
where we're at for City network our
internet pipes were just 41 s 2 cable
and wireless cable and wireless
statically routed to us we had default
routes everything within the network was
static and corporate offices were
getting to the internet through a pretty
scary process of NAT and those four
routers in the Pops were riverstone
which nobody knew and this was a
challenge from it from a support
perspective from a design and
architecture perspective and even bit us
from a sales perspective sales people
would get asked the typical question are
you guys using cisco or juniper and
they'd have to say no we're using
riverstone and the customer would follow
with who's that so we started planning
our upgrades after we ran into flow
routing limitations of the river stones
and everything you're going to see and
the rest of this presentation is what we
use to get us to where we are today so
we're whenever you're looking at your
router obviously any network pretty much
starts with one you might run out of
slots you might run on a memory you
might find yourself tapped out on CPU
resources as you plan to upgrade you're
going to find it you need to become an
expert on the different routers you may
select we learned very hard that we had
to become quite well versed in memory
errors on Cisco VIP tubes once we
learned them we knew whether it was bad
memory or bad VIP
we knew what had to be replaced and were
able to get past our problems so they
didn't recur and impact our customers
going forward we continue to learn about
implications of different GSR engine
revisions and continue to get bitten by
little limitations in catalyst 6500 line
cards and those wonderful concepts of
redundancy everyone wants to hear the
geb redundant Network and multiple
routers don't ensure that you've gotten
redundancy proper design using those
routers is key if you've got one router
in service and you decide to add router
to is merely a child of router one
router to is completely dependent on
router one and you've made things worse
not better so our initial design
involved a two-tier model essentially a
upper layer that handled all the
interconnections between sites and also
our connectivity up to the internet we
continue to be fed merely by transit
connections the lower tier a
distribution tier handled all of our
customer connections to some degree we
aimed for distinct routers suited for
particular connection types ideally and
this is where we're heading it wasn't
this way in the beginning one type of
router for fractional and full t ones
another type of router for ds3 and
larger ran technologies OC 3 and so on
and then one type of router for Ethernet
services so looking at our initial core
design to tie all these routers together
whether you know obviously two core
routers per city based on our redundancy
goals and then one or more customer
connection routers we use two parallel
lands to tie these together so two
separate Ethernet switches to provide
essentially backbone redundancy each of
the core routers connected to both lands
each of the distribution router is
connected to both lands and that got us
going it started in our first pop and
continued thereafter and here's a
representation of what we had so all the
different routers became
pretty much similar icons within our
model two switches to tie it together
but we soon ran into issues that the
routers because they're going through a
multi accessed apology wouldn't be able
to detect when another router lost a
link had a card fail or what have you so
there'd be time you know we have to wait
for I GP timers to to timeout and we had
not yet explored much with tweaking
those timers regardless I don't think we
could have gotten down below three
second failure detection and we weren't
real happy with that especially because
in the default case we were looking at
40 seconds of black hole until we
detected the failure likewise capacity
issues if the links from those Ethernet
switches to the various routers were
fast ethernet in some cases in gigabit
in other cases the sending router would
not know of a bottleneck going to the
receiving router if it was transmitting
on a gig link and and draining out a
fast e link and likewise we had
troubleshooting issues we had a lot of
round robin back at delivery especially
in the case of a link failure quite
unpredictable as to what the path would
be from one router to another so as part
of hardware upgrades putting GS ours in
the core we worked on transitioning our
topology so that the core router is
connected to each other so that transit
traffic had a direct path and then the
core router is connected to each
distribution router so even though
essentially all were Ethernet we were
able to treat them all logically as
point-to-point links and that gave us a
lot of gains throughout our topology so
here's the representation two cores talk
to each other everything else connects
merely to the course so now the core
routers no link state to all the other
routers and vice versa and routing
became more predictable and our queuing
became more predictable got us going
gave us what we were looking for but got
bit by another challenge then because
our upstream connections were on those
core routers so obviously we're so far
as Cisco only shop with in iOS the bgp
path selection algorithm rule number 9
says prefer the external bgp path over
the internal bgp path and therefore
inter pop traffic that might be coming
in from an adjacent pop and then heading
out to the internet would leave by the
logically closest link unless unless
another link was drastically better so
here's a representation the two routers
in the center are will call it City one
each one has an upstream internet
connection and you'll see city two on
the left and city three on the right and
traffic coming in from city to wanted to
leave by way of core ones upstream since
it was an external bgp path city two
might have originally chosen a best path
from core two but since each router is
making its own routing decision by doing
its own layer three look up core one
sends it out sup stream so here's what
we were hoping to have happen city two
through its full ib ibgp mesh had
selected core tues upstream as its
desired exit point but let me show you
here's what we were seeing as a result
the traffic coming in from city to was
instead going directly out core one and
the reason for that is core one prefers
most paths out its external path in core
two prefers both pass out its external
path in city to those core routers were
learning both paths by an bgp full mesh
and its core routers were selecting a
best path as city one core two for one
reason of the most likely oldest route
perhaps a router ID it all depends on
the individual situation so city two was
sending packets destined for that
internet destination towards City one
core one because that was its next hop
toward city one
and so as the packets arrive on City one
core one another IP routing lookup is
performed on the packet and it decides
that it's best drain point is the
upstream link rather than sending it
over to core 2 in that same city so
that's how we ended up with this
challenge and because of our traffic
patterns customer differentiation
between markets and so forth we found
this incredibly difficult tuned as we
grew we found that our upstream links
typically on two or three-year contract
terms were becoming increasingly
difficult to balance well when traffic
was coming in from another city so we
kept our two layer hierarchy but split
that lower tier into two types of
routers one for customers and still try
to break that up into connection
specific choices and then added edge
routers which hand which we're handling
specifically our upstream connections so
essentially an upside down v when you
look at an architecture redrawing our
core and edge challenge we've added in
edge routers as a separate layer from
the core and now traffic coming in from
city to arrives on core one core one can
make a best path decision both of the
drain points are external so that
decision does not factor in it probably
falls down to oldest route and can now
choose to send it to the right edge
router and go out that connection and it
was a for us a fairly small capex in
order to realize significant operational
cost savings because we didn't have to
upgrade pipe sizes just because of an
inability to tune them knowing that
another pipe might end up becoming less
used due to its term length so split the
upstream and downstream roles and remain
with the topology where each
distribution router and each
edge router only connects to the course
there was an alternate fix that we ended
up upon as a result of deploying MPLS in
the backbone but didn't know ahead of
time this would have fixed it for us had
we deployed MPLS upon the packet coming
in from the customer heading towards the
internet that inbound distribution
router would have done its own IP lookup
having full tables on hand and would
have found the best egress point and
potentially even interface and would
have applied to label corresponding that
exit point the core routers all
throughout the middle of the path would
afforded solely based on label directly
through core 1 and hopping it over to
core two and then core two would have
done it Siegrist decision and sent it
out that direction so on to selecting an
igp for choices we ruled out rip v2 it
needs to be dead we were running
riverstone so that immediately
eliminated eigrp and gave us two choices
OSPF and ISS and perhaps selfishly but
since I was the one it was tasked with
putting in some form of dynamic routing
our selection was OSPF considering that
at the time we were completely
statically routed the person who had
been maintaining the network prior to me
whenever there was a intercity link
failure would hop into routers through
back doors and console connections and
do static routes to patch around it and
inevitably through whatever magic he was
using the pick those static routes when
our internet connections came back up
those particular affected cities were
black hold again until he removed all of
his band aids so over time we switched
to is is three supposed benefits
stability on the premise that the
various hardware and software router
engineers were being very careful with
change management in there is is code
can't really say that gained as much of
anything per se
protection in that there'd be no CL NS
packets coming in from customers or
providers and thirdly as we began to
roll out mpls VPN s with a suspicion
that our customers might request dynamic
routing with us and that they might ask
for ospf to do so we wanted to separate
our customer facing VPN dynamic routing
router ospf blah from our production
network igp by doing router is is so
that people wouldn't accidentally go
into router ospf one and blow something
up when they meant to be on a vrf on
different process turns out in the three
or so years we've had VPNs that none of
our customers have requested dynamic
routing the only customer with it is us
ourselves for corporate offices and that
was BGP until recently we've now
switched to ospf the assumption is that
staff won't be blowing that up between
corporate and production and because of
a variety of reasons primarily ipv6
we've switched back did the rollout as
part of our ipv6 roll out which will be
in another presentation of this nanog
tomorrow but also chose to do it because
we had forecasted a use for gear that
did not support my sis whatsoever so by
rolling back to ospf we were able to
keep our topology and architecture
consistent typical IGP design goals that
you hear in a lot of the other nanog
talks but our consolidated here keep
everything lean device loop backs links
between devices nothing else I've even
heard of people taking their inter
device links out haven't quite figured
out what they're after and how they're
doing it but if it works for them even
better everything else belongs in BGP
it's a protocol made for thousands or
outs and it's got administrative control
and plenty of filtering capability
that's specifically not in OSP
f and we copied a lot of the work of VJ
gill and the AOL transit data network
team from their nanog 29 presentation I
believe from when they converted from
ospf to is is we use that during our
conversion to is is and copied the
metrics coming back to ospf more
recently doing so we started with a
table of metrics based on link rate and
then add a various modifier depending on
the role of a particular link so our
general table goes from 1 to 10 40 c 768
or 40 gig Ethernet down to ds1
considering that our total traffic right
now prior to acquisition is a quarter
gigabit I'm not real worried about
anything bigger than that whether it's
hunter gig 160 gig or whatever modifying
those metrics the links between cores
are metric one no matter what size the
pipe actually is on rare occasions we've
had two different sizes of pipe one a
primary one a back up so the primary
would be one the backup would be two
links from core routers to distribution
routers are 500 plus whatever was in the
table links from cortege are the same
500 plus whatever is in the table links
between cities so far our 30 plus table
value I believe VJ and the ATN folks
attn folks mentioned that they have
different levels of modifier based on
one of those links are within a region
across regions or cross continents this
will be a matter of study for us as we
move to a multi-state network
post-acquisition text link is based in
texas and pacwest being based in
california we may have to do some semi
separation between the two until we get
upstream links rebalanced and and
whatnot and as I'll highlight later in
the talk we've had to do some minor
tweaks to these landlink values based on
BGP tuning purposes considering that
one time not thinking through all the
implications here I managed to blow up
an entire pop when multipath ran all for
customer connection routers out of
memory at the same time considering it
was also the router that handled our
office it was a bad day every now and
then staff need to do modifications to
the network whether it's planned
maintenance upgrades downgrades what
have you they've all been told add
10,000 to the link cost and that way
it's pretty easy to figure out what the
link is supposed to be when they're done
with their maintenance so if we've done
some some changes and let's say there's
a ds3 that would have been a metric of
38 because it's going between cities but
for tuning purposes we may have made it
43 temporarily they know that when they
see a link cost of one or 10,000 43 they
should revert it back to 43 for
simplicity if for some reason a link
really really really should not be used
that Delta is 20,000 folks usually tend
to go Pete why is this one 20,000 and
that's enough time to say won't step
away from where you are and let's not
disturb that right now and here's why so
with the carefully engineered metric
Design we get a very predictable traffic
flow and that's good both under normal
conditions and when the link is out of
service expected or unexpected and I
diverge for a moment to say learning the
algorithm by which the router select
paths will really assist in
understanding what's going on my magic
light bulb came from the book shown
there traffic engineering with mpls and
I gave a tutorial back at 37 about
traffic engineering and in there there's
an exercise that explains both the base
shortest path algorithm and also how it
works with in traffic engineering so key
factor in the link design and metric
Design is that our distribution and edge
routers aren't as
early size to handle traffic that for
one reason or another is trying to
transit this pop so far our network
isn't big enough in a steady state
configuration to have much if any
transit traffic but we had a link outage
over the weekend as I was arriving here
in dominican republic and we were
punting all traffic that would normally
have go from houston to san antonio
through our dallas pop so that extra
traffic were it to have tried to travel
through the router designed to handle
customer t ones could have put a serious
hurt on that poor little 7206 so we want
to make sure that the traffic that in
this case is transiting quartic or link
knows where to go have the quarter core
links in dallas gone away we would have
been in a bad space anyway but let's say
those are the only two links that were
down we want to make sure the traffic
that one otherwise want to go through
them will go around the lan rather than
trying to punish our customer
distribution routers or upstream routers
so to do that the we know that the
distance within a pot going from a core
down to a disk back to a core or
likewise core edge core is going to be
at least a thousand and two because
those link metrics are always 500 plus
at least one and likewise 500 plus at
least one whereas the cost to go around
the way in is always going to be at
least sixty three since from this city
to the next city will be at least 30 11
to go from core decor and 31 to go back
through another win link to this city if
there are additional cities going around
that ring the land cost is going to
increment by anywhere from 30 to 40 per
city so in this case traffic would
rather go through 23 cities before it
would decide to go through the
distribution layer keeping us safe for
now with only four cities we're safe but
i know that we're on an expansion
roadmap and i'm very happy that i'm not
going to have to go back and recalculate
re-engineer for a long long time so
here's a representation
of those metrics not totally to scale
but you can see that the distance from
core down to distribution and back up
again is far greater than it is between
the two or particularly to go over to
another city and as our staff begins to
become familiar with this they get to
see that it truly is consistent as long
as they've got the metric table in front
of them I've occasionally given them
projects to configure a new router being
out of the network and they can
understand better how to put in the
proper configuration entries so the
event that kind of bit us that one
afternoon we have links to NTT vario in
both Dallas and Houston and based on the
BGP path selection algorithm rule number
10 prefer the route that can be reached
to the closest IGP neighbor lowest IGP
metric core one in San Antonio was
connected to Dallas and in Dallas we had
a link to 29 14 and therefore San
Antonio corwin liked to go that
direction San Antonio core 2 was
connected to Houston and we had a link
to NTT there as well in core 2 liked to
go towards houston we were noticed that
some of our dallas distribution routers
were sending outbound traffic over to
Houston to go to auntie T because of a
difference in igp metric from Dallas
distribution to Dallas core to Dallas
edge vs from Dallas distribution to
Dallas core over to Houston core and
then up to Houston edge so we tweaked
the link metrics going from Houston core
to Houston edge 1 rebalance traffic and
sure enough those Dallas distribution
routers would began doing the thing that
we'd hoped they would do and that was to
stay within city and send their traffic
out to dallas ntt however our San
Antonio distribution routers had bgp
multipath enabled and they were now
getting best paths at least if they were
headed towards ntt pointing towards
dallas from core 1 and pointing stirred
houston from core 2 so 4 40 or 50,000
prefixes we now had two entries and
those poor little RSP force all went
boom pretty much simultaneously and
considering that my desk and
all of our support personnel were behind
one of those we were kind of in the dark
until we figured out maybe that change
about 10 minutes ago was bad so our
retrofit was merely to was to leave the
Houston edge metrics the same or as
desired so that everything matched and
behaved similarly between Dallas and
Houston but to change the LAN links from
Dallas to San Antonio and Houston to San
Antonio so this San Antonio core routers
had a clear preference I think currently
it's towards Houston and wouldn't feed
the distribution routers with a
multipath mess so within BGP it's made
to scale use it we carry all of our
customer link subnets customer land
subnets and external routes within BGP
as well it's got great filtering tools
use them it'll save your life we filter
at every route ingress and route
injection point and in doing so we apply
an internal community so that any BGP
route anywhere on a network will have at
least that internal community so from a
troubleshooting perspective we're able
to figure out where it's coming from
instantly you're going to have to scale
your BGP at some point confederations
did not work well for us we started off
using one sub a s per pop when you have
one router / pop it means each router is
its own sub a s convergence was painful
because those pops would end up having
to send a full table over to the
Confederation neighbors as opposed to in
a route reflector situation where they
send only best paths and if they're
getting learning routes from an adjacent
pop that were better anyway you've got a
much simpler reflection upon BGP session
restoral so in the process of doing our
various pop upgrades we removed the
Confederations and deployed route
reflectors in the step-by-step process
and again following the suggestions of
vijay gil and 8th edn we have no client
to client reflection the distribution
and edge routers within a pop are fully
meshed
which prevent theoretically prevents at
least first layer met oscillation we are
nowhere near hitting that but I'd rather
take the future of you now than have to
go around later and race around and fix
things up so within our distribution
layer all the customer links are
redistributed into bgp as connected
routes make sure you exclude the
interfaces that are from disc to core
and we got burned on this once when we
didn't write our route map i suggest
that you don't write your route map to
exclude by interface name if the router
comes up and the VIP is not there it'll
drop out that reference in the route map
and now you had instead of denying one
interface you're denying all routes
instead use a prefix list so that even
if you end up with no interfaces
matching a prefix list you have a static
reference and you won't have this kind
of black hole likewise we redistribute
static routes in the bgp may want to
consider a prefix list there to make
sure you don't capture any private space
you might want to block and doing so
when you add a customer to a
distribution router you don't need to go
anywhere else to make sure that they're
properly routed scales very well means
that a lot of your technicians will only
have to deal with the distribution layer
and won't have to deal with much of your
redundancy and scalability bgp local
pref design this is one of the magic
secrets that i've never found in the
books and sometimes you can't even find
it in many of the nanulak presentations
you want to choose your local pref
values so that traffic goes appropriate
to your dollars knowing that transit
probably cost you money peering might
cost might not but perhaps lower than
transit and your customers mean revenue
makes more sense to send traffic to a
customer than it does to send it through
one of your transit connections and most
people seem to be using local pref to
accomplish this so our basic design
although not totally reflected in all of
our routers is that customer routes are
given a local preference before
p routes get a LP of 300 transits or 200
and any route that temporarily is being
asked to be treated as a backup to some
other customer peer transit route gets a
local preference of 50 since the routers
default to a local preference of 100 if
you forget a route map or you typo a
route map you're going to have routes
that are invisible and you're going to
go troubleshoot it and you're going to
go oops I forgot where I bombed a route
map and you're going to fix it early
rather than crashing into it months or
years later and as everyone requests
please filter your customers we do it
once on-ree in grass from our BGP
customers and we do so very aggressively
for each prefix we check that prefix
against a prefix list and against an AS
path list we allow that customer to
prepend as much as they wish we allow
them to truncate the AS path so if they
have a customer of our customer that's
giving them a prefix so we might be
seeing two different a esas in the path
will allow our customer to take over
that route for their customer and the
event their customer has some sort of
emergency so the second and subsequent
is in that path is completely optional
we tell our customers about these rules
and a whole bunch more at Turnham and
assuming they read the document which
would notice that do not rarely do they
have everything they need to know to
bring up that session without a single
phone call we also factored in no
routing capability and we do so somewhat
complete with certain amount of
complexity but the reality of it is it
gives the customer flexibility and
allows them to do a lot of stuff without
ever having to call us assuming you have
enough clue to use it will accept their
aggregate routes marked for no routing
we will treat internally as a no route
and we will propagate those aggregate
routes allowing them to do certain
tricks which we'll cover in a bit
and certainly will accept their
aggregate routes assuming no tagging or
at least no no route tagging and
propagate it normally as would be
expected we will accept any more
specific of their aggregates mark with
no route we will treat it internally for
no routing we will mark it internally
for no export so that doesn't go out to
providers and customers since it most
likely would get filtered anyway share
it all within our network we do also
accept more specifics of their
aggregates if they mark them with a
override community we treat that as an
aggregate and allow it to be propagated
out on the hopes that our transits
filter on a less than or equal to 24 bit
basis obviously that's best effort for
some verb up streams but the notion
behind this for a small shop such as
ours is that if you have a customer with
sufficient bgp clue to call you up at
seven p.m. on a friday night and say hey
i just added a customer two minutes ago
which we know is false but they've got
this new prefix they've brought from
wherever and they want to be able to
route it will say go ahead put one 1457
colon 20 on that announcement will
accept it will propagate it assuming
it's somewhere within their prefix list
and allow it to go out and hopefully
it'll magically begin working we
expected it will for at least one of our
providers based on current patterns and
allows us sometime over the weekend or
monday or tuesday to do the right thing
and get those routes added properly to
our filter list last but not least we
will accept more specific routes of that
customers aggregates untacked will
accept them well mark them as no export
because we see no reason to send them
out or propagate them internally we use
it as a anti spoof filter opening for
traffic engineering purposes a little
bit complex but it means that life is
very hands-off for bgp customers so
basic thought is the customer can
obviously announce their aggregate route
they can announce that aggregate route
and null route some specifics we figure
is the second likely case that if they
have enough clue to use no routing
remotely they can accomplish it
themselves they also have the power to
announce their aggregate and null routed
which will propagate externally and also
announce more specifics without no
routing tag for which we will forward to
the customer so let's say they have a /
20 only wish to use the 24 of it they
could announce the 20 null routed
announced the 24 to us the rest of the
20 gets black hold for them very easily
they don't have to do the other 15 / 24
s to be no routed to get to where
they're going they can do it with two
announcements and within that 24 they
could no route further specifics so it's
a very scalable hands-off design keeping
the customers offer phone lines out of
our hair here's a sample in this case
they've got a 22 of our space they've
marked it for no routing which is the 11
457 colon zero or no we accept it pass
it out to the world and no route it they
can also announced the 23 within it will
accept it share it with in totally
internally routed to the customers would
be otherwise expected as an RPF opening
and they can also announced a 24 within
the 23 and no route and in doing so
they've got a 22 with only 24 forwarded
so very hands-off if the customer has
enough clue to even no route they might
want to do this wasn't too hard for us
to write in the beginning and continue
cloning for new customers and scales
very well for us one side challenge is
that for every customer we have at least
two prefix lists one that's the exact
match on their aggregate routes another
one that's Ellie 32 to allow them to do
their no routes and their overrides if
the customer asks we will adjust their
inbound route map to inject various
tuning community communities at their
request
had customers that just don't understand
how to do a simple route map to SATA
community and will do this to get them
out of trouble going back to the
internal community design we tag every
single prefix internally the moment it
becomes a beach pier out in doing so we
identify the pop where it came in the
general requested exit handling and a
type of route so we can interpret where
it's coming from and what's being used
for one of the things that we do with
that is to use the pop of origin to
adjust med automatically it's a simple
geo routing and it saved significant
city to city land costs and Link sizing
for us design is our AS colon ABCDE
first digit is the route type customer
hours or upstream bc covers up to 100
pops so far five but we're about to add
five more as part of the acquisition d
is a high-level desired tuning 0 is
based on whatever we've cooked up
overtime to keep links balanced one
pretty much strips out any of our tuning
and goes to whatever the providers would
give us if untuned otherwise to is for
backup and seven is for maintenance and
the last bit indicates what to do from a
geo routing perspective whether to apply
meds or not so here's a sample one 1457
colon 10 200 since a is one it's a
customer out since bc is 0-2 in our case
it came from pop to which is Dallas D is
0 so we propagate it based on whatever
tuning we've cooked into our existing
route maps assuming that you know and
there's no hook out to avoid them and E
is 0 so we now knit announce it as hot
potato which is a default med in all
cities the geo routing for us is very
simple I have a suspicion is going to
grow to maybe a third tier right now
it's basically new your verses far if
that internal community matches one 1457
colon four dots and a one last digit
being one end it matches a nearby popov
virgin and bc bits we set ned to 200 if
the internal community matches one one
four five seven and then ends in a I
have a typo there no that's right if it
ends in a one but it's not matching a bc
of a nearby pop that is 400 if the
internal community ends in a zero it's
going to get med of 200 whether near or
far extending that bgp community design
develop a set of community so that your
you and/or your customers can apply to
those routes for tuning within your
network we allow our customers to do
obviously they're going to default to
customer level local preference they can
choose peer level local preference or
back up if they want to do a if they
have two connections and want to do a
customer versus customer backup or
pierre vs pure backup we tell them they
can do so using local you know meds
within that level and local preference
to get between customer and peer a
little bit more complex than using the
heavy hammer of local preference but
it's more scalable and keeps our route
maps cleaner and our local reference
count cleaner so for the simple stuff
one 1457 colon 200 300 or 400 is the
customer pier or transit levels or other
way around and of course the colon 0 for
no routing we have another set of
communities that we or our customers can
apply to routes for tuning outside our
network in in this case it's for our
upstream providers we do not you have
yet have any peers but this would scale
to those as well we can mark prefixes
for no advertise whether to one provider
or all they can set pre pens to those
providers that are independent of
whatever they might announce in to us
and they can also request local
preference so here's a diagram of our
tuning logic as it leaves our network we
filter out any other upstream routes
they have no sense going back we don't
want to be a transit provider between
our providers we allow routes from
stammers or our own flagged with
individual or global local preference or
prepend requests and this does get a
little complex to handle multiple
combinations there in if we've had any
of those requests we then hand it off to
the final logic that does the Med
selection if there were none of those
requests we allow routes flagged with
internal local preference requests and
map a corresponding external local
preference request if there's nothing
there we processed routes based on their
embedded tuning that D bit within the
internal community and likewise hand it
off for meds one of the things we've
found the hard way in the beginning is
that if a customer through communities
or other route map tuning ever requests
to be treated inside our network as a
peer it becomes essential to announce
that prefix outward as a peer as well
otherwise you end up with a certain
stickiness that if they ever fail over
to us external routing will then glue to
our transits and when their primary link
comes back up our transit still like the
route coming from us because the they
see it as a customer route they will
stick to us until the customer breaks
their link with us causing additional
pain flap dampening etc so using those
meds for geo routing we quote unquote
enjoy parallel connectivity to three
different transit providers for each of
those providers we have a link to that
network in dallas and a second link to
that network in houston so for outbound
routing we receive those providers
routes and their customers routes and
rely on the meds learn from them most
likely any other routes we learn our
peers perhaps they are purchasing
transit I'm not certain about one of our
networks regardless we zero out the meds
on anything we get that's beyond them
that's not a customer route
if they can't give us much direction on
where to send it no sense us trying to
send it through multiple links of our
own and it works well because a normal
state cold potato sending it straight
out to them you're sending it through a
preferred med value is only one hop
longer than hot potato sending it
straight at the local city and the
assumption is we know our network we
know we've done very careful igp metric
Design it's working for us we know that
we've chosen good backbone networks we
assume they've done a lot of careful igp
metric Design and so forth but we know
our network better than we know their
network we don't know what they use for
med values how significant they are if
there's a way to add to them there's
certainly no way to multiply them within
our route maps so if they're telling us
that a particular pop is better we will
use it but only on their routes and
their customers because the assumption
is the med learned is in some way tied
to IGP distance fiber kilometers some
other vector towards wherever that
particular prefix is going into their
network so if it's let's say one of
entity various aggregate prefixes think
they've got 157 229 or something like
that we know they're going to originate
it on some subset of their core we
assume that that is going to be
announced to us in dallas and in houston
with some representation of how far it
is to that particular injection point
for their customers let's say they have
a customer in atlanta we know that that
customer is most likely better reached
through houston which is geographically
closer to atlanta then dallas would be
for us so if they're giving us med it's
probably tied to that distance
some other link costs like that and
we'll choose to send that traffic
through our network to Houston to give
to in this example NTT and let them
carry it to Atlanta to go to the
customer so we feel that it's a pretty
good balance between trying to do the
right thing internally and trying to try
too hard and send traffic on funny
circles so obviously we have numerous
customers that do BGP we respect that
many perhaps even all of them have
little to no bgp experience most of the
customers that we've had that we're
doing any sort of multihoming were doing
so merely for the sake of transitioning
from old provider to us and they perhaps
had a errand assigned prefix block and
felt that it would look best on the
internet if they were announcing it from
their own a ass when in fact we know
that doesn't really matter as long as
that customer sends is just their
aggregate routes with a reasonable a s
path and they don't dump their entire
table or at least so many that it bumps
up against max prefix everything works
fine if the customer requests will apply
reasonable tweaks we've often had
customers who had a link to us and a
link to a Tier one and find that a lot
of the traffic comes in through us will
often mark their prefix to be treated as
a peer in our providers which tends to
rebalance things well otherwise we tell
them look here's a web page with all of
our current communities you can do it
with BGP route maps on your own end at
whatever hour you want to do it you
never have to call us and a few folks
who've had enough clue to try and use
that have found they've got all the
knobs they need even in us a perhaps
tier 3 totally transit dependent network
moving on to traffic engineering
redundancy especially in a small
minimally mesh network for cities for us
would theoretically need six links for
full mesh we've got five we do some
subset of regular simulations but it's
not very conducive in our
to efficient redundancy favorite quote
of mine from GI Jane to means one and
one means none if you've got two links
you can fall down to one but if you have
one link and it fails you've got nothing
unfortunately two to one means half your
capacity ins of being excess we are such
a small network that in many cases we've
got to go with 2n redundancy to have any
redundancy yuck getting around this
based on multiple ds3 is running between
certain key cities then multiple OC 3s
as we grew well mpls traffic engineering
saved our network normal igp routing is
completely unaware of traffic saturation
until there's so much traffic that those
keep alives go boom and in that case
you're in a very bad situation anyway
but it's just messy trying to send
traffic a long way mpls te enables our
routers to spread our traffic over
multiple paths including those that are
not on the shortest igp path so we've
often used call it backdoor paths
through austin and through san antonio
which were secondary pops aside from our
main dallas and houston sites and it's
done using one-way tunnels between
routers initially we had a full mesh of
tunnels between all of our distribution
routers and all of our edge routers
sometimes one sometimes two tunnels in
each router pairing depending on traffic
loads we ran very aggressive 15-minute
automatic bandwidth rescaling timers so
those tunnels rapidly reflected how much
traffic they were actually carrying and
those tunnels would then redistribute
their traffic across the backbone very
rapidly and because we often had two
three sometimes four DS 3s over the
primary path and in some cases a hundred
and twenty megabits per second maybe 140
megabits per second trying to reverse
those 40 s 3 s it was a very tight fit
it was the only way we survived but we
got squeezed because we had a customer
who set up a news server and those news
feeds would get glued to a
tunnel so our best bet in these cases
were to add more tunnels over particular
edge distribution pairs we went to for
primarily to get traffic to hash over
multiple tunnels we knew that that nntp
flow would fit to one tunnel and
hopefully almost all the other traffic
running from edge to distant dis to edge
would pick the other three tunnels which
pretty much did gave us the granularity
next necessary to rebalance all that
traffic and the flip side is that all of
our redundant capacity back up paths
longer pass what have you can usually
get used by accident because you don't
really have an easy metric as to how
much of that excess capacity or that
excess traffic is travelling around a
non shortest path wow you can end up
with quick surprises when your
redundancy just isn't there however that
excess capacity can be used during
momentary surprises we've had a few
customers still have one that just
seemed to be a bit of a magnet for dos
attacks and when they would get dust at
least the network would take care of
itself we'd use up all available
redundancy for that event but at least
we kept running and the rest of our
customers are not so severely affected
by that das attack long-term we ended up
with iOS version mismatches on different
routers and something just wasn't right
we could never get cisco tac to identify
what was truly going on but it just
wasn't working knowing that our core is
entirely GSR almost we migrated to just
using mpls traffic engineering over our
Hwang links which natively were smallest
links and the ones that were the most
likely to need protection each link gets
four tunnels so therefore if one of
those tunnels has to find a less than
shortest path away from point A to point
B only about a quarter of the traffic
over that link swings a particular time
and therefore the traffic follows the
shortest path except in the face of
congestion and so we
stay back to as close as simple as we
can predictable rarely have to explain
to people why traffic's going the long
way but it does happen every now and
then but it keeps us back towards a very
default traffic flow most of the time
changing topics to network monitoring
obviously we all have small budgets for
tools consider taking off the shelf
stuff and kind of home brewing some
tweaks and modifications on to that and
do what you can to put information in
front of your support folks you're not
in your helpdesk and whatnot and perhaps
you won't even have to share enable that
much with your NOC folks because they'll
be able to figure out what's going on a
lot quicker our analysis analysis said
there were three problems to solve right
now what is up or down that's perhaps
what you might use whatsup gold or HP
openview for analysis of what happened
when whether it's simple with syslog or
sure there's other tools that capture
that and show what's going on and then
how many bits packets errors what have
you are flowing through the network
obviously different tools to solve each
problem the two biggest things for us
for mr TG to be able to figure out what
our trends were and what our traffic was
and homebrew enhancements that really
tuned it up and make it useful for our
people and then syslog to show what's
happening right now on the network the
mr TG that we've deployed has simple
links on each customer facing port for a
cutesy network diagram a link to be able
to telnet to the CPE and a how-to guide
on how to configure our standard CPE so
that if we provision the custom report
any time during the day tomorrow morning
at 6am all these tools get updated and
created so that as long as we do it a
day before the technician would be
configuring the CPE he doesn't have to
ask anybody it's got step by step with
IP address values and channel
assignments already coded in
automatically generated there's a
diagram showing them what routes are
sent where we've had knock personnel
just capture that in a screenshot and
email to the customer when they want to
see it in a graphical manner and
likewise their syslog has a pearl
wrapper that color codes up as green and
down as read and substitutes in the
interface description value learned as
part of our regular em RTG configuration
generation so that when an interface
goes up or down the log entry has a
local meaning by showing the customers
representation so it's a little
scrunched for the PDF but you can get an
idea this is a sample of our automatic
network diagrams for a customer in one
of our cities shows the distribution
router with inner co shows that in this
case it's on router dist for interface
card s 3 x 0 t 1 number 7 and time slots
1 through 15 shows the LAN Network
mapped from distribution to cpe specific
endpoint addresses for people to
reference and then whatever the
customers network is is represented the
bottom whatever their land block or land
blocks are the likely land gateway even
though from a distribution router we
have no easy way of knowing what's going
to be assigned because some of the
customers may choose to subnet further
and then these on RMR TG page are
clickable links to give people a
translation of what / 28 actually means
so they don't have to have it printed
out and taped to their cork board next
to their desk it's always available when
they're looking at one of the most
likely places they'd be looking at a
slash notation and if by chance there's
any sort of extra admin distance
configured on the router configuration
we have a table that shows the all the
different values within a cisco iOS for
those distances and if by chance there's
an internal tag which for us the only
tags we're using is on our black hole
server we tag black hole routes as 666
but the hook is there to make it easy to
show the staff what's going on likewise
here's a modified snapshot of our log
watcher
just six Dallas is our t1 distribution
router in Dallas and the other day one
in the afternoon customer p.m. real
Realty and the location on dallas
parkway must have had a 32 second outage
another one that's about 30 seconds so
my suspicion is for one reason or
another there cpe got rebooted there the
adtran CB that we often use takes about
30 seconds at least from a t1
perspective down to up so it marked in
here that the interface in this case the
line protocol went down shows again when
the controller and the interface comes
up and second reboot of some form and so
this allows our NOC to see what's going
on on a per customer level some quick
representation of what's important and
what's not we mark loopback messages
loopback shows up in blue and ospf and
bgp messages show up in yellow simple
way for them to say hey is this
important is it not important assuming
that they're actually watching it which
can be potluck but gives them the tool
that if the customer calls in and says
my Internet's down oh yeah your t1 went
down about four minutes ago let's go
ahead and investigate and we can look a
little bit more intelligent in front of
the customer instead of having to go
fishing around and figuring out what
route are there on and look at some
other representation there so the usual
plea here at nanog please prevent bad
traffic do whatever you can to prevent
spoofing we use unicast RPF wherever
possible we have a stock inbound access
list we use on all customers there's
actually two variations one is for our
legacy retail customers which blocks
anything ospf perhaps a couple of
multicast things unless they've
requested a specific exemption which
we've never had any and double checks to
make sure that they never spoof anything
that's coming from
our interface subnets we know where they
are that way if for some reason the
unicast RPF check gets removed maybe SEF
blew up and we re enabled it but it
wasn't enough to get the RPF check
restored on the interface we know that
we're at least protecting against
spoofing that would blow up our internal
bgp sessions and so forth all that gets
blocked before it ever gets into our
network the second variation of the
inbound akal is used on our wholesale
customers our ISPs in our Colo areas and
that one's a little bit wider
considering the retail akal also blocks
the netbios over tcp stuff we take a
stance that unless they've got some
specific reason to share windows files
and Printers wide open over the internet
they probably don't want that open we
block that on a retail side but leave it
open on the wholesale side and as soon
as you've got an opportunity to work it
into your configuration highly recommend
some sort of black hole router we've
cannibalized a couple of console servers
that also work as council servers and
there are black hole triggers take a
look for our tbh and Google or whatever
to find out basic ways of doing it we've
also built a very basic but very
functional net flow infrastructure so
when we get dust we know how to figure
out at least who's getting targeted our
normal recourse is to black hole the
victim address first it's the quickest
thing for us to find in the net flow
reports figure out whether it's a very
distributed a very singular source so
will then go back and check whether the
source is singular or multiple look for
the largest attackers at least and we'll
black hole from the source and then
we'll restore the victim back to
operation so it's got minimal impact to
the rest of our customers throughout the
entire event gets our customer
completely back online as soon as we can
and starts black holing the source as
quickly as we can so that's my story
it's worked very well for us I've told
management that my goal is that the NOC
handle ninety percent of the issues
completely on their own another nine
percent of the issues with just asking
me a few questions and about one percent
of the issues that I have to say I'll
deal with it it's going to take me far
longer to explain it to you then it will
for me to resolve it it's better for the
customer to get the customer up and
running and then circle back and train
the NOC later and we've we've truly
gotten to that point and then some I
mean my phone rings quite and frequently
the only exception to how often I get
called is often on those where some
other completely independent event is
happening on the network usually on the
voice side or transport side and a
customer calls in with an IP related
question and our NOC is too overwhelmed
to handle it they'll pumped it over to
me and that's about the only exception
of getting rare calls every three months
or so if any of you here in the room or
later watching the archives are
interested in any part of our
configurations please email me and I'll
be happy to to send you whatever
snippets you'd like and this point I'm
opening up the questions anything you
want to see further I can connect in and
do some demonstrations any other
questions you've got come on up
very good