okay hello my name is Peter washer you
may know me from the peering buff as
appearing but my spare time I
handle a lot of the DNS operations over
at ISC this is one of those timely talks
where we're going to talk about
something that was very current as of
last week actually a little bit
background on January the 18th is prime
became the victim of a DNS spoofing
attack using spoof source addresses some
of you or some of us are calling it an
amplification attack because the query
is dot and that dot NS record is quite
small about 47 octet and while the up
upward referral response is a bit larger
which is up 256 octet about five times
the size so basically you're asking this
little small query and they're getting a
slightly bigger response going back to
the spoof to dress now one interesting
aspect of this attack is that the
queries are being sent to the
authoritative name servers only usually
you see something like this being it
being hit by open recursive servers now
one reason that this might be happening
is that you can easily find the list of
authoritative name servers you just look
up any number of doma a number of domain
names look up the NS records and there's
your target versus having to scan the
whole net for open recursive name
servers so this is how it would look
like you basically dig your favorite
authoritative name server for the name
servers for root and it happily gives
you the list of root servers so this
this brings back an old debate now what
our authoritative name search server
supposed to do for queries that it
possibly can't answer
because it can only answer for what it's
either a master for or a slave now these
upward referrals as we call them are bad
because they're basically useless the
resolver should have this information
already and and it already knows where
to start and where and where to get this
information from and frankly a proper
resolver should consider it consider an
answer like this be out of scope to come
back so basically gets the answer it
doesn't know what to do with it anyway
it's a scope so and the authoritative
name server should have a root hints
file and that if you're asking for just
Joe random authoritative name server you
don't know if the root hint or the hints
file but that that surfer has is even up
to date as we all know we keep our root
hints pile up to date now and then upper
referrals can lead to referral loops so
it's asking again and again and again
further on that results in basically
useless queries now the first thing that
at least I saw on the DNS operations
list and the Nano mailing list was
filter um just filter them out that we
won't give a response back and and all
will be good well that kind of doesn't
work because they can always just change
change the question so and you don't
want break and just filter out 453
because like in the case of is prime
there are an ISP they run actual
authority that they actually run
legitimate services on their dns servers
so what you need is absolutely something
that is actually within DNS scope or the
dns server scope to actually stop
answering these things because what we
really want is to basically refuse these
refuse these queries and then because of
it because if it's refused then the
offending query or the offending machine
should actually just stop
so possible solutions for this and bind
if basically what you want to do is
include additional from cash equals no
to your global options now if you you
can also do this by just doing it in the
global options and then allowing access
on a per zone basis now and note that
you can't just remove the root hints
file because in bind because we like to
be able to bootstrap it's actually hard
coded into name d so if you don't have a
root hints file it goes back to this
code that what it's hard coded in and
just uses that instead so and also I
should note that if you're still running
bind eight please stop for the good of
the internet so this is what you should
see so you dig the server and it gets
back were refused and it basically ends
up being the same size as the original
query so there's no amplification you
get one for one now for other DNS
providers for the sake of clarity or for
the sake of fairness I believe DJ v dns
actually does refuse out of scope
queries from the beginning so you don't
have to do anything for power denese you
can set this in your config bot and set
send route referral in your
configuration file if for your other if
you're using something else like nst or
nominal or anything like that you can
contact your vendor actually tried
looking for NSD and can find it so I
should give it thanks to Dwayne Wetzel's
over at the NSO arc he's been collating
a lot of this stuff or a lot of this
that's been going around and has a has a
URL beds up there where you can find
more information about this and code
snippets and things like that and then
two members of the DNS operations and
nanog mailing lists for for contributing
to the discussion that's basically it
we can take a few questions Martin leave
it from Hurricane so being protocol
correct is great and you know we're all
here because we adhere to protocols but
if i'm running a bunch of name servers
that are explicitly authoritative have
never been used as a recursive name
server someone goes and queries me for
example calm and i don't own that domain
why should I even bother responding why
should I even send a packet back um but
there are some well it depends on the
the way the client setup you may find in
some situations that the client will
still ask it wants an answer and if it
gets no answer then you're still going
to see the packets coming in but unless
is being being magnified or you know
being sent back to an incorrect sauce
yeah well in what we're saying is that
if you use refuse that if it's actually
legit or if it's doing the right thing
that should just stop it'll just say oh
I've got refused I'm not trying again
okay so that's a wonderful protocol
response so let's talk about email here
you know we live in a world where the
percentage of email is coming in that is
not wanted is far far greater than the
amount of email that is wanted if dns
goes the same way inevitably at some
point maybe your answer gets modified
again it's the protocol stack versus the
real world true and if someone wants to
propose it then we're happy to listen
okay
if you're more time for one more time
Tom from dynamic when by this is a
buying specific question when you
configure bind for recurse know and you
remove the root hints file if you were
to remove the hints file and your
recursion knowing you're running
authoritative only why do you need to
fall back to hard-coded values in the
source to prime root hints you don't
need root hints anymore in the first
place that is it a design question
that's currently what yes that's
something that's asking being discussed
okay so thanks sandy do you have a
question for this one are you just ready
okay alright well thank you Peter great