hello everyone
welcome to our presentation i am sajidu
rahman a phd student
and a graduate research assistant
working at university of florida
institute for cyber security research
center and here with me philip talley
a step data scientist at fireeye and
together we are gonna present
our work on combating social media
information operations with
neural language models so
let's begin our talk on what is
information operation
in social media so
information operations on social media
are flourished
in part because they can be conducted
cheaply have immediate global reach
and can exploit the type of viral
amplification
incentivized by the platforms and not
necessarily
social media information are inaccurate
information but
most of the time they spread division
and mistrust
and there are cases where they are
highly resourceful and they are also
state sponsored and using networks of
coordinated accounts social media driven
information operations disseminate and
amplify content
design to promote the specific political
narratives
manipulate public opinion form and
discord or achieve
strategic ideological or geopolitical
objectives
fire's recent public recording
illustrates the continually evolving use
of social media
as a vehicle for this kind of activity
on the right you can see an example
from a recent report of firearm where
distinguished
impersonators a group of active
uh threat actors they are faking online
person of u.s politicians
activists and they are sharing political
propaganda in a coordinated manner
across facebook and twitter
so this brings us this question that
what are the challenges of
detecting this kind of activity on
social media
and first there is this
uh challenge of uh domain specific
expertise identifying sophisticated
activity of this nature
often requires the subject matter
expertise of
human analysts after all such content is
purposefully and convincingly
manufactured to immediate
authentic online activity making it very
difficult for
casual observers to properly verify and
the actors behind such operations are
not transferring about their
applications too
and they undertake various measures to
hide their
uh true identity by uh by using
elaborate false personas
and adoption of other operational
security measures as we have seen before
so with these challenges now and with
these operations being intentionally
designed to disagreements
can we turn towards automation to help
us understand
and detect this growing threat can we
make it easier for the human analysts
to discover and investigate this
activity despite this
heterogeneous nature of social media and
the high side traffic
so in today's sport in today's talk we
are gonna talk about
um the result from our investigation on
how the finite data science team
works together with fire rise
information operations analysis team
to better understand and detect social
media information operations
using newer language models
before jumping in uh our approach let's
take a quick look at
how the uh what are the common
approaches available currently to
fight social media disinformation of the
information operations
so this existing work on uh social media
io
detection can be broadly categorized in
two classes
content based analysis and network or
analysis or metadata analysis
so content analysis heavily depends on
defining
the various hard-coded tools for future
engineering tasks
and most of the times they focus on a
particular type of
social media information operation
social media hire campaign
and they don't generalize well across
detecting various information operations
on the other hand language models tend
to capture the structure
semantic and contextual information of a
piece of text
and modern language models are
self-supervised and trained on
massive data sets for better prediction
and they also tend to model lengthy text
very well and skill better than
other competing feed-forward and
recurrent neural nets
so this brings to our hypothesis
that
uh fine-tuning large-scale language
models can effectively lower
the bar for generating and detecting
social media posts associated with
information operations
so uh in so as you can see our
hypothesis can be
uh breaking can be broken down into two
part first we want to see that
if we can train a language model such
that
it can effectively capture the semantic
and the nuances and idiosyncrasies of
social media contents and specifically
the social media information operation
contents
and then can we use this language model
for classification and for detection
purpose
so for that we want to look into
the state of the art language model gpt2
so in order to gpt to uh and let's take
a quick look at what is
gpd2 and how does it uh perform so well
on various
natural language processing tasks and
gpt2 that is generative free train
transformer
is a self-supervised language model
which was pre-trained
on a large web text corpus it's a
layered step it's a layered
stack of encoders and decoders and the
superintendent of gpt2
comes from the attention mechanism which
helps train on enormous data sets
efficiently and also it hierarchical
text representation
captures the semantics and enables
transfer learning
so in the here you can see a
sample generation from gpt to
medium since the p train if and this was
a conditional
generation uh where the model was
conditioned to generate
a text and the input was it's
disgraceful that
and then it generates the rest of the uh
following paragraphs
so since the p train gpt2 models dataset
consisted of
more than 40 gigabytes of internet text
data extracted from more than eight
million
reputable web pages its generations
display relatively formal grammar
punctuation and
structure that corresponds to text from
news contents from books etc and this is
not suitable and
this doesn't necessarily correspond to
the type of
social to the post that we often see on
social media
so in order to uh
to make text appear like a social media
posts with the
with the nuances or the platform
specific idiosyncrasies like
shorter length informal grammar erratic
punctuation
and syntactic works including mentions
hashtags emojis acronyms and
abbreviations
we plan to fine-tune gpt2 on another
positive language modeling task using
additional
training data so
what are the data cells that we use so
we look into
uh the 20 2016 uh
information operation uh and the data
sets
that were captured uh by various
agencies
so for we labor is four open source data
sets of identified accounts operated by
russia's infamous internet research
agency also known as the troll factory
and the data sets are coming from nbc
news agency
538 news agency reddit
suspicious accounts and also the data
set
released by twitter election integrity
dataset
so after combining these four data sets
we sample english language only social
media posts from them to users
into for our fine themed language model
and finally experiments were carried out
in fighters using 355 million parameter
retrain gpt2 model from highland phase
transfer line
transformer library and were distributed
over up to eight
gpus
and as you can see uh as opposed to the
other detailed language model gpt2
conveniently requires
minimal architectural changes uh and
parameter updates in order to be
fine-tuned on new downstream tasks
we simply process social media posts
from the above data sets
and uh we
through the free training model whose
activations were then fed through
adjustable weights
into a linear output layer the
fine-tuning objective here was the same
as gbt2 was originally trained on except
now its training dataset call
includes uh contents from a social media
disinformation campaign
we also added this end of text string
and the suffix for each post to adapt
the model for the shorter length of
social media text
and after generation you can see the
sample uh generated by
the gpt2 model and now you can see that
how
these text generations differ from the
original one that we have seen
before and now they look more like
uh the type of contents we see when we
spoke to social media they are short
here fighting
stress certainty and outrage regarding
political issues and contain
emphasis like an exclamation point and
they also contain
uh these idiosyncrasies like hashtags
emojis that positionally manifest
at the end of this generated text and
depicting a semantic style
which is regularly exhibited by the
actual user on social media
so after that we also have faced some
challenges like
since we have this multiple data sources
available and
training our gpt2 model was not cheap
and rather expensive in terms of the
computational
uh point of view so how can we select a
single data data set in an objective way
so that
the the fine-tuned language model can
generalize well for
social media disinformation generation
and also detection
so for that we look into this experiment
of perplexity
and perfect city basically talks about
the probability that the
how well the model can generate
a correct next word given
some previous uh engrams are available
and for that uh basically the the lower
the perplexity score
the better so for this experiment
we fine-tuned three separate language
models
and each all of them were trained on
their
own dataset data corpus namely
we train a language model on nbc
news dataset we train the language model
on
twitter dataset we train a language to
fine-tune a language model on
the 538 data set and then it
we we ran it and we also
each of these fine-tuned language models
were then tested against the whole
dataset from the other
hold out data sets from the other uh
data sources
available so the look here you can see
that the lowest scores fell along the
main diagonal of the public city
conclusion matrix meaning that the fine
tuned language model were best at
predicting the next word on
this data originating from within their
own data sets
and the language model fine tuned on
twitter's election center big data set
displayed the lowest perfect city scores
when
average across all held out test data
sets
so we selected posts sampled from this
data set to demonstrate classification
find units
now for the rest of the presentation
philip will continue
hi everyone once again my name is phil
telly and i'm a staff data scientist at
fireeye
so now that sajid has fine-tuned gpt2 to
generate tweets resembling i o activity
i'm going to explore how we use this
capability to design detection tools for
this
and other i o campaigns
so just like when sajid showed how to
fine tune gpt2 for language modeling
we didn't need to make any drastic
architectural changes for classification
we did need to provide the model with
the label data set so we grouped
together social media posts based on
whether they were leveraged in io
activity or whether they were benign as
sajid said the model fine-tuned
on the election integrity data set
displayed the lowest perplexity scores
so we sampled from this data set for our
positive class
for the benign negative class english
language posts were gathered from
verified twitter accounts whose posts
contain
diverse inaccurate content and alcus
content
next we process these posts through the
pre-trained model
this time we fed activations through
adjustable weights into two linear
output layers
meaning fine tuning was formulated as a
multitask objective with
classification loss together with an
auxiliary language modeling loss
we prepended posts with a new beginning
of sentence or bos delimiter token
and suffixed post with the class label
or cls hidden state token so that each
post was fed into the model
according to what you see here below
the figures show the evolution of losses
during fine-tuning and the resulting
rock curve when evaluated on the held
out test set consisting of
66 000 tweets the convergence of these
losses to low values together with a
high
area under the curve indicated a hopeful
sign that this approach could allow this
model to accurately detect io activity
versus benign activity
but can we make this model even more
useful for io analysts
to answer this question we considered
attention attention scores are computed
between all words in a text sequence to
compute attention scores the transformer
performs a dot product
between a query vector q and a key
vector k
k represe k represents the other words
that receive attention from q
the query word and might contribute a
better representation for it in its
current context and q
represents the word that searches for
other words in the sequence to pay
attention to that may supply context for
it
the figure on the right displays how
attention is computing using a
visualization tool called birdviz
vertical bars represent neuron
activations and lines represent the
strength of attention between words
blue indicates positive values in red
indicates negative
columns trace attention scores from the
highlighted word on the left
america to the complete sequence of
words on the right
the element wise product shows how q and
k contribute to the dot product which is
finally normalized by a softmax function
that outputs the desired attention
scores
so to decide to predict the hashtag
following the word america this part of
the model attends to preceding words
like ban
immigrants and disgrace these syntactic
relationships are valuable from an
analysis point of view because they can
help identify an io campaign's
interrelated keywords and phrases
these indicators can in turn be used to
pivot between suspect social media
accounts based on shared lexical
patterns
help identify common narratives and even
to perform more proactive thread hunting
so sajid mentioned some of the existing
automated detection methods
in literature which rely primarily on
large curated data sets external
knowledge bases
or time-consuming custom feature
engineering each of which translate
poorly to a more realistic
multi-campaign threat landscape which
analysts are time and resource limited
by contrast
starting out with a large pre-trained
model and fine-tuning it on a per
campaign basis
allows us to more agilely detect o
activity by giving us a head start
however some care needs to be taken to
ensure this captures campaign narratives
and not just their individual words and
phrases doing things like sampling by
topics
doing temporal chain test splits and
adjusting class balances
relative to the rarity of i o activity
give much better sense of what we should
expect
performance wise in the wild while our
work and that of others primarily
focuses on
content analysis there's also an
undeniable signal and other available
metadata
and even network interactions each which
can help add context for downstream
classifiers when stacked together
oftentimes these campaigns are foreign
in nature and can be conducted in
different languages and localizations
other than english
and in these cases we've seen success in
applying pre-trained models that are
multilingual such as burt
another concern for large transformer
models is latency
and while we're still working to reduce
this a few promising approaches such as
distillation and pruning are capable of
maintaining detection accuracy levels
while reducing the number of parameters
and time required to make a prediction
lastly it's worth noting that we won't
ever
be able to completely remove the human
element from the analysis pipeline
their initial work on the front lines is
important for collecting and initially
identifying labeled i o campaign data
for us
so in this presentation we demonstrated
how to fine tune gpt2
on social media posts previously
leveraged in i o activity
transfer learning allowed us to classify
these posts with a high auc
score and fire a threat analysts can
analyze
this detection capability and use it in
order to discover and triage similar
emergent operations
sajid show how to transfer learning
allowed us to generate credible
synthetic text with low perplexity
scores
gbt2's authors and subsequent
researchers have warned about potential
malicious use cases enabled by this
language generation technology
and our research reinforces this concern
so with that
i'll conclude the presentation and
thanks for your time and attention
please reach out with questions via
twitter or
via the email addresses listed here