[Music]
thank you again for joining us for
nanook 83
a special thanks to our sponsors
co-sponsor
premium sponsors
connectivity sponsors
beer and gear sponsors
pairing sponsors
monday break sponsors
tuesday breakfast and lunch sponsor
tuesday break sponsors
network lounge sponsor
virtual expo sponsors
virtual meeting fellowship sponsor
game sponsor
service sponsors
special thank you to our nanak members
the board of directors and the program
committee
the nanook staff
they sean
the claudia elizabeth and valerie
the developers from repsis greg and
frank
network support from line line speed
rick cohn and nick
av plus
live stream
with clarity
experiences
and meeting support from
zabria kristen and
michelle uh we received your feedback
and we are taking steps to make things
better
looking forward to an analog 84
meeting stats
in in-person registration
312. we actually had
picked up their badges here in
minneapolis
virtual registration 300
member registration 214
students that registered two
speakers 36
women in attendance uh
63 or 10
and countries in attendance 27
top organizations in attendance
organizations with more than 10
attendees
and finally um we're happy to announce
uh keynote speaker for nanak 84
uh radia porwan a fellow at with dell
technologies
radi is known for inventing fundamental
technology enabling robust largely
self-managing
and scalable link stat routing used in
specific protocols
she designed isis and similar protocol
ospf
she also invented the spanning three
algorithm which transformed etherent
from a technology that supported a few
hundred nodes within a building to
something that could support large
networks
she made contributions in network
security
including scalable data exploration
distributed algorithms despite malicious
participants
and ddos prevention techniques as well
as authoring
and the textbook interconnection
about network layer 2
and 3
and co-authoring network security
radia has many industry honors including
induction into the national academy of
engineering
the inventor hall of fame
the internet hall of fame
washington state academy of science
and lifetime achievement awards
from usenix and sitcom
she has a phd in computer science from
mit
we're very excited to be welcoming radio
to the nanak 84 stage
in february
see you in austin february 14-16
of 2022.
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you