[Music]
i'm the chair of the nano
board of directors
um this is our
our first time back thank you for
joining us both in person
and virtually
um it's been 21 months
i mean
a lot has happened we've experienced
a
world of change both personally
professionally how we do business how we
meet
uh nanook staff has um
done a wonderful job and our volunteers
are bringing a virtual meeting and we're
hoping that this experience
today our first hybrid meeting
is a fantastic experience for those of
you that are joining us online and those
in person
we have 307 people here in person that
have registered
hopefully growing a little bit today
with last minute and 198
online for virtual
to keep everybody safe we went with
protections we asked everybody that
could come today to be vaccinated
it's the best we could do to try to
safely bring everybody together and have
that in person experience and start it
again i'm grateful for those of you that
were comfortable coming today and that
you took that extra step
a special thanks to our sponsors
uh kentick our host sponsor thank you
[Applause]
our premium sponsors include erin aws
and verisign
connectivity sponsors lumen and usi
and beer and gear
we have several
drop nuts
juniper netscout and nokia precision
optical
and peering sponsors databank and dc
d6 i
read it all the time but i can't say it
apparently
um and we have break sponsors solid
optics talia carrier and arista
tuesday break sponsors charter ipv4
global
and smart optics
and lounge sponsor
i'm not going to read all the virtual
sponsors thank you everybody
and virtual meeting fellowship sponsors
thank you
game sponsor in panera
and service sponsors as well so many
sponsors um i will comment that sponsors
are the reason this meeting happened
we'll go over the financial details at
the members meeting but this will not be
a profitable meeting we don't have the
attendance for that um
but because sponsors came forward and
did this we can meet in person they are
critical to nano survival as always but
even more so in years like this
i will hand it over to our host sponsor
now abby
[Applause]
thank you very much in some ways
it actually looks a little bit more like
1996 than some of the recent
nanogs except that some of my friends
magically got older i don't know how
that happened
um
no not me i don't feel old
and actually i was privileged
while we won't see kat garinsky here i
saw her a couple days ago
in austin
both
at her side project and for dinner and
that was awesome
so forward
so welcome again um i'm excited about
things uh getting back to seeing people
seeing friends having a hallway track
it's also been great to have nanag have
kept up the pace in a virtual way as
we've all been adapting there's been a
lot of cool material
shared
cool presentations and i'm looking
forward to
this hybrid and
to us all getting back uh hopefully to a
post world at some point and having even
more attendance and more information
sharing nanag has really always been for
me and for a lot of people about
community um education sharing um
both the formal and informal um and uh
it's really something that as i've
talked with people
um it's been very helpful to continue to
have and also
something that people are excited to
evolve
so a little bit background about kentic
we are a network observability company
so
uh the people that run infrastructure
the people that build infrastructure are
typically using us to send telemetry
from their network infrastructure
we gobble all that up process it show
people things that we think
are important and then are used by
engineers to understand more deeply
what should be done and then
also
to be part of their automation
infrastructure and to give visibility to
customers whether they're internal
or external
the world is becoming increasingly
diverse especially in networking there's
the stuff that we control there's the
stuff that we think we control like
other people's paths to us which
sometimes we don't um and the stuff that
we know is out of our control which is
you know our customers use of sas
providers and cloud
and really from a
end user perspective it's all network
and it's ultimately the network people's
responsibility so our view is
getting telemetry from all those areas
is important
ultimately people need to ask questions
end to end uh where are the problems are
we under attack is there a performance
issue and then go to be able to do
things about them
our view has been
really since we started seven years ago
that it's it's a big data problem
bringing all this data in in real time
keeping it around being able to ask
questions being able to integrate it's
been great to see the industry evolve
towards observability based approaches
uh even outside the network
realm
um what's new for those um who either
didn't see me do a version of this
presentation at the virtual nanog that
we sponsored last time
is we've gotten into performance testing
so synthetic testing
we've done a lot with cloud and even
ebpf in the cloud native world
white label portals for service
providers to be able to offer visibility
down to their customers a lot with bgp
monitoring so both your own and
even some
market
observation what's going on on the
internet as a whole and then of course
programmatic
interfaces so apis sdks to use those
and a lot of work to work with other
observability providers
and then a lot of that was enabled by
kintik labs which has been open sourcing
network
telemetry translators agents to do
things like
probe networks and do ebpf host-based
observations so take a look at kentic
we'd love to talk to you
we are here
and so thrilled to be a sponsor
hello everyone my name is kat garinsky
and i'm the current chair of the nanong
program committee welcome back this is
our first hybrid conference
we had four virtual only conferences
right before this nanox 79 80 81 and 82
and 83 was our first hybrid conference
with attendees and speakers attending
both remotely and in person we plan to
continue to offer speakers the option to
present remotely at future conferences
nano 84 in austin texas in february is
also planned to be hybrid
some notes for this program we have 19
peer-reviewed presentations including
our keynotes there are currently 26
members of the nanak program committee
and we've been moderating program
sessions and networking sessions we are
a self-governing organization so we
appoint our appoint our own leadership
here i'll give you the list of all the
current program committee members i'll
pause here for anyone that wishes to
read
some program tips um again since we're
gonna be both hybrid um with virtual and
in-person attendees um reminders about
how to use the virtual chat so use the
chat tab to talk with the other
attendees um and in-person folks you're
welcome to use this chat tab from the
room as well
the q a tab is still the best place to
ask a question during your presentation
in person attendees if you don't want to
stand up in front of the microphone this
is a great way to submit questions
without having to get up in front of
everyone but there is still a microphone
in the room for anybody that is in
person wishing to ask a question by
standing up you can also use the help
tab to receive technical support
and then as a reminder the agenda and
presentation materials are on the
website so you can follow along with
slides and any additional material
provided
some additional notes the newcomers
orientation we actually live streamed
this already so if you're watching this
right now you've missed it but you can
check out our youtube channel next week
for a recap of the video
our uh woman in tech lunch will be
tomorrow we will have both an in-person
and zoom option for this
but during the general session right
before the women in tech lunch we will
actually have a related talk that will
kick it off before we break out into
these in person and zoom options
wednesday lunch everybody is on their
own so you get a nice little break
if you're attending virtually we will be
streaming the internet innovator
interviews during the lunch hours for
you to watch
some reminders our call for
presentations are always open not just
for the next nano but for the ones after
as well we usually have the next three
at a minimum open for submitting for
your call for presentations
your feedbacks on the surveys is more
important than ever please let us know
what worked what didn't work and how we
can improve this hybrid experience going
forward especially important this time
since it's our first hybrid attempt one
of monday's survey questions will also
be used during the a tuesday
presentation so please try to complete
that survey tonight if at all possible
our presenter on tuesday would really
appreciate it
the surveys can be found online at
nano.org surveys there will be daily
surveys available for monday tuesday
wednesday and there will also be a
hackathon survey the surveys will close
on friday november 5th 2021
and then i would like to take a few
moments to recognize susan forney
susan was a current member of the board
at the time of her passing and she was
the board secretary and the chair of the
recently created mentorship committee
she began attending nanogs in the early
2000's and descended twice at anag for
79 and 81 both on ipv6 related topics
please enjoy this brief video that the
folks at isuck put together last month
of susan at various network engineering
conferences and we hope you enjoy this
week's programming for nanogiddy3
[Music]
so
you