now it's at home cue
work I'll let yourself go he's professor
not
you think no lo I
minor you remember for example she was
ok hun
sufficient I'll
another forever home page upon us
through you're silly oh and I
well at least to me she made some
jaw-dropping disco shows
in this ongoing personal samples on
mules
pretty amazing I'm not always like
through Russell oh yeah and I a
this is not something something that
could be you know old house
or but nothing more the more realistic
on part two
along great okay super so kissing him
yet and his bottom Meyer
be his signed yet and
the I'm little
today I apollo
their examples and yes him
I'm I challenged on
him yep
and and member
and I'm them
yet
a big day thank you members and
and me
no then are confidential now
very popular law for packet
I only me
you know humor
Mb best do him
hi into today headline
by think me
I am they have them
I ongoing Commission
any on my
some I have my here buying books
and a bit tired lately
during the day I
bathrooms high enough
no information me old
me personal data/information
bank yeah
I am him 3 and
at the moment happy I him
a bit higher again ball
impatient not dairy
your whole medical information
with it and all him they had
so there any Myers and Norway
the modem
him hear you
any patient though
be not yeah
home cation yet
and for thing
him
but they can deliver it is not only one
me being
have users and
now be there book Anna
that you
all campers or
all L
yeah bombs
lime him
angle men no normal
work by that or anything
them yes
it Mary call me
bullet hole
and
in cuba anything him
Dayton him
all of home
and
%ah problem yes
Banyai you from home
you friend commenters same way
and yeah
you get used to buy it on by
or here every
you and them
their city because Bay bill
user by service provided by
and company here
him they
and then young people and all
and young people mean only
him
up I am
I also train station long time
and Michael okay yet
machine
Nick making here bed
thank you
I'll on
and up
problem many his
all no him
where already game
and behind you you and
I that mean you're going
trait thank you all
I was there him shem
in and there was a little on
him
me
I hate all 55 be
him
well
yeah
and then yeah environment and you
publication
indignantly any being
his me
line man how many
how many have been destroyed
yeah
I Mac I'm
0 and I what I mean are in my backpack
of course I I P
he did you meet them
to be like you only yet
I
he didn't like
I'm and then
I think
amo on my min
it's very but up
I am by Jenny is very important so
by company
operation you have an obligation
haha okay
of them on them
up
am on Leland am
me all they actually think and
and
they actually are quite from
engaged
making favourite me
pay environment any
of mental FB
all
in you he
in person I imagine
yep through and
them when it comes to the fore like
Anthony
yeah
vendors by up
holiday in Jupiter again this
that it you
I'll bombed-out
that the user and that them companies
day of make the whole relied
Anderson you
I
own many people bear it
here UN
the same category people
there cue and Paul in you have any
and that things than in
there
yeah of girls
not a very any yeah I'm are you compare
and Inc
again
should for our Meetup
view it beaten that you did
thing
man
then K
well
years old there's
KK here
him they have a
possible and then
up K thank you them I am NOT our
yet and method and they
run it the next thanks he
his have
then in the end
you can take
well there you have a user
by I'm I'm
user
you that the UK how are you
I know her us past the
and all problem
be users
physical my human
yep
are surrounding Anne
him I am
if I am
and off the ice site
him
any thank you baby
and that was being a bit more difficult
I'm and
the line here is that they yet
you are thinking
and yeah decided
me
candidate brother
I'm I have mono
map hours
and are met
on
so area them as a kid all
me its them
Bay
am
now we have me by
me off on
point I'm
hit bath
base UK that at the
I'm right
okay it well
buy anything
me I'll
10 massery
them
in you
and then
the Marlins up
him
and for the bathroom anything
I'll and
go
me
from up
open
in am
your mom in founded by
members
and I think
and biometric Holly approval
no them or
Thanksgiving
apps
left
Ali day
and
defendant
than they did
here
you happy of it your users how long day
I
fine
invisible right yeti
more be them
and I'll them
it
and holiday on you
I'm I'm I'll and all your help
it up
I'm yeah
are at and perhaps along
actually a you
get the whole
them %um like people
Columbine him gay
day made by human hearings
of hi and long
all you need a
not want you get
I year
that
%um on
and then
you have the infrastructure yeah I'll
human being
day in the go
equipment of beer nation
and almond paste story
he had call
all I'm yet
%um on
am reunion their name
day
I'm main
yet 0 year again
that all
min
him
at the half
on unplugged that the
simple
their very
and
I'll that for them
and now who'll
me
cables be
eater all
and the other back
back
there as mom that hi
him then we have to
and I'll very or all the numbers used
a a yeah
and Dr might be and
password %um
now
me you him
day being and
his yeah
them
now you're lucky users are you
all 3 and
yeah operation
room them
him
I am yeah I made me
I am
him
Nahla being
by by
that nope
and then we have a
at the
you people you
all or I'm
and then maybe get numbers
home
users
the whole the
it
old
a different answer here
here long from for old 13 answer
I'm ball
them for ahead of it
demanded
being at I'll yes
up
and
me
and then a long time and
and
the and all
often be
up there losing that
thank God that their
now them
custom no and is a min
some tokens can pray as well as that
include loss
that my then
most them
world
you
the
proven that the loath still
me
yeah like them
but up to you they have %uh this is this
per user who is the on I'm
well and now you and
it the him
high esteem to are you
on
was
implying himself
might be
wall yeah old
think they're easy now
you up yeah know it all
and
example they'll all
us yeah service else
possible behind you
you goodness up
you would miss style
yeah
them
eat chocolate and other
much more
and him
and
yeah
ended
not data there right now are be
him people
ahead
and and a
hit and
you one that they
all
and then me compare
on
three
there
and then
NBN people now I have you
yeah on
net 0 later
adding phone numbers
up so
morning or
a here
yeah
baby from again
again and is that
was this scenario also for axes and
such as: patient records were
was this axes to the hospital whose
systems
what was the the scenario this
the yes there's a place in check
israelis
yeah but then you know they have
different
yeah
people
call
our here
that you can
all
here
yeah you know happy
India name
and be yeah
more right
was a.m. me
them
you have them
3 online up I
all all numbers to I him
you know
another pro man
summer pro-gross
a yet yes questions
all yes no
okay wrong number yeah sleep