um hi everyone um my name is brandon i'm
a co-chair of the um cncf tech security
um and i'm here with andy
good afternoon
hi i'm uh i'm andy we have one more
co-chair who's not with us today and
we'll uh we'll introduce her and the
rest of the people who have facilitated
and made today possible as we wrap up
the day the ctf and set you up for the
rest of the week
so yeah i'm i'm really proud to have
recently been um
uh voted in as a co-chair of tank
security so i'm here uh resting on the
laurels of other people this time round
there's a lot of hard work that goes
into these events
we have brandon of course radnor as well
we operate on a tech lead
and sort of nominative basis so right
now we have uh the the three reputable
individuals um andres attusion pushkar
and
this means that in this position these
individuals take initiatives forwards
they propose things they help to
shepherd things through uh and we'll
look at some of the some of the great
work that people have been doing
and we have just nominated another round
of excellent tech lead colleagues uh we
have michael lieberman marina moore and
ragashra shekhar
they will come in and
help us to move forward at a greater
velocity there is so much work that
needs to be done and we really
appreciate all the community involvement
all the volunteering efforts that people
put in to help move cloud native
security in the tag forward
all right so
besides some security con that we do
well used to be called security day this
was like we started this about three
four years ago and it started off as a
single day
single track event
to now we've we've gone through like two
day we have a ctf going on alongside so
the we've really evolved this and we're
kind of growing this a little bit more
uh and we're kind of excited to see
where this can go but besides that we
also do
um
both technical work uh in terms of like
writing white papers
we we do write down documents about best
practices as you've seen in
yesterday's presentation on how to use
these
security supply chain best practices
uh into integrating into um
the supply chain pipelines in your
organizations
so just to share a few these are some of
the new releases that we had
the community has been working together
we have multiple working groups we have
serverless working group we have a
supply chain working group
controls working group
and so
these are some of the new documents that
are coming out this week for kubecon eu
so we have the
um secure software factory reference
architecture paper so originally we had
the best practices paper the reference
architecture paper really tells you how
do you go about to actually build a
secure
secure buildup
so all the links are in here the the
presentation is uploaded to chat the
code so you can just download it from
there
we have the cognitive security
whitepaper v2
which includes uh all the nis ssdf
mappings if the eo is something that
you're looking to to target and meet the
requirements of we talk about ransomware
we talk about git ups you talk about eu
regulations and all that
um we have the attack security in this
control mappings
which maps the original security white
paper to the nis 800-53
and also for those that have not seen um
the first white paper and you want to
get more like you like audiobooks
we now have like audio recording that
was done by various people in the
community
and there are lots of things coming up
the open source summit in north america
austin texas next month will feature a
new event the global security
vulnerability summit
this is an attempt to answer the
perennial question what do we do with
the backlog of cves that we're
collecting as an industry there has to
be a better way to do it than we do it
now we presume and this is an
opportunity again to engage with the
community interested and excited minds
and try and ideate something that will
help us to cut through the uh
the molasses of
of cve management as i'm sure those of
us who manage our cloud native minimum
viable security no
yeah we also have the cognitive service
serverless security white paper that um
we had a panel on earlier and so this is
currently in public rfc
so we are we are gathering all your
input to tell us like what what do you
why are you looking for in serverless
security are we missing some things that
should be talked about
um
we're also working and a lot of the
issues that you see here are new we are
starting to work on them so if you see
anything that you're interested in we're
going to talk a little bit later on how
you can get involved
one thing that the supply chain working
group is working on is creating cloud
native s-bomb guidance
right we talk about s-bomb we talk about
generating s-bombs but why are you
supposed to generate who's responsible
for generating s-bombs
and so the effort is to kind of be able
to to provide guidance on for
cloud-native technologies what should we
do
then we have the nist security controls
mapping
again looking to
help implementers and people working at
the coalface to
implement sometimes difficult compliance
or auditory regulations um this will
give us a view on on how to move forward
take advice from colleagues and people
who've implemented these kind of things
before
the supply chain best practices again a
collection of volunteers and interesting
minds
put together this paper
which is technical detail on how best to
secure our supply chains
um end-to-end looking kind of
farm-to-table uh or uh end-user device
to production
and looking to tie together all of these
nebulous concepts that we have here
the s-bomb being a key point right now
what do we actually do with these
s-bombs how do we generate them
and so what we'll do in an effort to
make this obvious and repeatable
we'll take an example cncf product
project rather and
we will put it into the secure software
factory we will apply the best practices
to its configuration to its ci cd to its
contributor framework
and give what is essentially a cookie
cutter reference implementation of this
is what we think good looks like and
then again
do this in the in a community aspect
and allow it to be then critiqued we can
all feedback and then
find a shared understanding hopefully
move ourselves forward
then some some really uh
some really interesting things here
these are some of my particular
favorites the guidance on container
breakout vulnerabilities there have been
a lot of kernel related escapes recently
we look at things like dirty pipe
very quick zero day dropped without much
of an embargo
these things require very real and
immediate remediation and we're looking
to put together a framework again to
help understand these to help move us
forward quickly and then finally
many projects come into tag security
with a request for an appraisal and
audit a security review of some
description
part of this and something very dear to
my heart is a lightweight threat
modeling exercise this looks at the the
broad question the catastrophization
what could possibly go wrong
what are we going to do about that thing
that goes wrong and then we iterate and
loop around there so that we
can apply security controls in an order
of precedence based on impact based on
risk based upon what we think this thing
will actually do
and we're looking again just to increase
the velocity and to make sure that we
can be as valuable to as many projects
as possible
with that i'd like to invite our
esteemed
uh ctf runners
lewis and james
to run us through how the ctf went today
thank you andy
hey everyone um i hope if you've got a
cluster for the ctf you enjoyed it um
first of all we had unprecedented demand
um
yeah we had we spun up over well 50
instances for users so with 50 that
meant that we spun up three clusters
each now those three clusters had
different scenarios
um each of those had five nodes so we've
just spun up over 800 vms some of them
were working as we expected some of them
may um
but yes and so to that i would like to
say first of all thank you to uh james
cp
um
if you've seen us sat outside you might
see you're like why those uh why those
guys so stressed well um yeah it's um
yeah sre on conference wi-fi trying to
manage misconfigured clusters it's it's
been phenomenal um
so our scenario is today
these were brand new scenarios uh for
exclusively for this event um we're not
going to give you all the answers right
now if you want answers come and find us
tomorrow we're happy to talk to you
about them but our first cluster was
inspired by the movie back to the future
if anyone's seen that um did anyone
reference the age of the vms that you're
using to begin with
if not come and find us tomorrow we'll
give you some more of them um the second
one that we had well and also that was
based on inception so have some fun with
that uh the next one was die hard which
is actually more like um now that's what
i call hacking volume 44 which was like
our mega mix of lots of different things
and to the next one our pastor james
thanks lewis um
so the the quiet place uh scenario was
based on
the film quiet place
uh as some of you may have found we had
a runtime detection agent
um
trying to prevent users doing bits in
the cluster so the idea was it modeled a
uh sort of more red team-tiled scenario
where you were the attacker trying to
evade any protections that blue team had
put in place
cool and do we have a scoreboard
available if not you can have a look
online
um
yes so tomorrow well the next three days
james and i well tomorrow morning james
and i um we're gonna have a lion um
it's there's not been much sleep um it's
been yes it's been intense um but we're
going to be at the booth now
we like to solve difficult problems um
if this ctf has inspired you if this has
inspired you to get started within ctfs
with insecurity
um
then please come and talk to us if you
think we could have done hard if we
could have done better if you've got an
idea come and talk to us it's all about
we just we like to solve heart problems
and so please come and discuss um
with that um did we have a scoreboard no
we don't but um oh no worries so we had
to uh you well i passed you just to
announce the two winners
all right cheers uh yeah a couple of
honorable honorable mentions at this
stage um for smarticus and skybound for
being the two highest
users
on the scoreboard and getting a couple
of flags that no one else did what are
you guys
and to that there were two flags that
weren't associated with ctf um no one
got the os flag so the os flag was um
for osint which you simply had to ask
iva james roy
what's the flag and no one asked us for
a flag so no one got that one um
so try harder on that next time and the
other one was elite flag did anyone get
the elite flag in here can anyone figure
out what the leaf flag was so we got
someone did you figure out what it was
for
i can't hear you but i think you just
said to say thank you and so is anyone
who came up to us to say thank you we
gave him the leap flag and equally more
people did and to that is the basis of
these events um everyone around here so
we've worked with lindsay as well to do
this so everyone who's been here to make
this event happen we are so thankful for
you doing this and so i i hope that
leaving for this today just say thank
you to the people who do help you out
because it means so much to them so to
that i'd like to say thank you to these
two and pass back so cheers have a good
conference
[Applause]
awesome so um
i hope everyone had fun it was a great
conference um if you want to get more
involved with cncf tech security we have
a session on friday you can drop by but
if you're not going to save for the
entire con
we have multiple ways they can get
started everything that we do is pretty
much on github
so github.com cncf
tax security
we have a mailing list check out all
issues we have weekly meetings on
wednesdays uh we are also on the cncf
slack and on twitter as well so give a
moment did i folks take a picture of
this
but all this is on the the sites
uploaded as well
uh and before we go big thank you again
to our program committee for security
con
um they've done a lot to make sure that
we get all the exciting topics we have a
good program
and of course again a big shout out to
lindsay and the events team that have
made all this happen
[Applause]
awesome if not thank you very much have
a good conference and if you don't
remember anything remember the github
url
all right thank you
[Applause]