thanks for having me uh my name is fabio
poselli i'm a senior staff engineer with
vmware
and you can find me on twitter uh which
is probably the only social media i
still use so at fabio rapacelli
today i want to talk about uh so like
the worst nightmare uh of all the public
relations departments out there which is
your company making you know national
news because of a security breach
before we get started though i just want
to acknowledge something uh like it's
great to be back in europe it's great to
be back in person i'm sure many of you
can relate with the meme up there on the
screen
and i can't wait to see old friends and
making new ones here in valencia this
week so
if you see me around stop me we can chat
it's great see everybody
back let's get down to business now um
so
do you remember uh this headline from a
couple of years back
if you don't remember this one
you might remember this one
or maybe this one or maybe this one
so the thorough wins hack uh pretty much
sparked so like this intense debate on
and exposed the importance of the
software supply chain
in a way that i've rarely seen in my
life honestly and you know i've been in
this industry for like 20 plus years and
it's the first time i see such an uproar
in terms of like you know legislation
and so like discourse around this
specific problem it was not the first
time that there was a you know something
similar to that happen actually but the
target the scale and so like the blast
radius that this attack had was
unprecedented
now it was a humbling moment for you
know for many involved in the software
development life cycle business myself
included
now look at these figures here uh
they're taken from
the synopsis open source security and
risk analysis report
made in 2022 this is made from by the
same company that
makes the blackduck scanner you're
probably familiar with
uh you know there's there's a number of
interesting findings there and there's a
link you know when you get to see the
slide there's a link to the report there
but the two metrics that uh sort of like
caught my attention uh were these two
you know look at them
that means that
3 4 of
all the code bases that were audited
which means that you know code bases
from all sorts of companies you know not
just from you know software development
companies but this is like from all
industries and all geographies
three fourth of their code base is open
source software
this means that three-fourth of
their code base is software you know
pulled in from github pulled in from all
sorts of sources
and 81 of that code is at least
vulnerable with one vulnerability now if
you stop for a second and think about
your own stack think about how deep is
your stack like all the dependencies
you're relying on you know if if you if
you look at the blast radius it can it
can so like impact your your company if
one of these dependencies get attacked
in some way and we had recently that
example i mean think about what happened
with luck for jay
you know that can make
that can make or break companies
sometimes
and there are so many attack vectors too
in the supply in the modern development
lifestyle and the modern supply s
software supply chain you know you could
have actors submitting you know
malicious code changes to the repo if
you don't have like you know strong
uh you know review mechanism you can
have you know your build platform
compromised from the inside or by an
attacker externally which by the way is
what happened to solarwinds and you know
an example before uh you can even have
you know malicious package maintainers
you're depending on like some random
packets out of the in from the internet
and this package maintainer you know
maybe out of spite or you know out of
protest sometimes and we've seen that
with the war in ukraine recently they
can either wipe out their dependency
from the face of the earth and it's not
going to be available anymore or can
embed you know
back doors even in the code
and if you don't know if you don't do
anything about it then you end up with
backdoors in your code in your shipping
code now it's obviously easy for me to
point out the problem uh the reality is
that as engineers we tend to value so
like you know velocity and you know
making progress
way more than we value compliance in
general i mean
i'm guilty of that myself
so we deal with compliance only when we
have to
which is usually uh when you have
somebody knocking on your door which is
usually the security team or the legal
team if things get worse uh back in 2017
it was the architect for
uh product at vmware
and i was dealing with license
compliance we have a large code base in
go and we had a number of obviously
number of packages there and go is as
many of you know is a at least back then
it was you can only get statically
compiled binaries so it means that you
have to like scrutiny your licenses
because some licenses are incompatible
with each other
and we're trying to make our cicd tool
smarter to like you know catch a
licensed creep early on so i built a
tool and i went to a conference in paris
called go to present it
it's still available on youtube if you
check it out
and
at the time i was saying you know
there's actually two more than 2 000
packages this slides from 2017. there's
more to 2000
packages made with go that are gpl2
license mean that means that this is
like a hat scratcher for a lot of you
know legal teams and especially in
product companies that are building
products to sell
so i can start tackling some of these
you know fundamental issues and the
software supply chain these days now
it's hard to like pinpoint to a single
solution but
you know there are ways to do this and
software builder materials is probably
not
know nothing new is concept but it's
you know it it caught a lot more so like
attention and you know in the past three
four years
uh mostly because of the attacks that i
was talking about before
and it has sort of like started
accelerating the adoption of you know
these concepts and these practices
and to me the important shift here that
has to happen is sort of like moving
away from the you know what i was
calling the compliance because you have
to
to sort of like the compliance because
you want to because you want to be
compliance because it means creating a
virtuous cycle where you know a flywheel
where you have you know there are
tangible benefits in adopting something
like this for everybody involved not
just for a legal team you know being
able to sleep at night
so but what goes inside is an s-bomb so
there's a number of competing standards
for s-bomb there's uh there's spd-x
which is backed by linux foundation
there's cyclone dx there's a bunch of
other uh standards out there but they're
not very opinionated in what goes inside
an s bomb they're just opinionated in
the in the type of like in the way it is
described but not in the way that you're
putting information inside that so right
now it's not like a common belief that
you know having vulnerability scan
results the license audit uh the
metadata on the build system that i
actually built the artifact uh all the
dependencies that are involved in so
like building that specific piece of
code that specific piece of artifact
and so like the relationship that exists
between the components that are actually
built
you know it's so like an acceptable you
know list of information to generate you
know a viable set of tangible benefits
to the teams involved and why why is
that because you can identify you know
vulnerabilities that are known
you can you know count and manage your
license which was you know my original
use case for something like this uh you
can identify compliance you know
obviously at the license and security
level because you have both information
available to you
and you can start evaluating and
quantify the risk of your software as a
whole
and most importantly it's also
forward-looking because by having a list
of all the things that you and all the
components that you have all the
dependencies that you have in your
software
it means that when there's a new cv
coming out or a new you know security
problem that to mitigate you actually
have a list of things you can go and
check on and say okay i have you know
out of the entire software state that i
have you know i'm using this library
that is vulnerable in all these software
packets so i can go and fix them and
know exactly where to go instead of
trying to scramble and you know audit
the code base when there's a day zero
out there that is sort of like you know
uh impacting you
now if you take a step back you know now
we have s-bomb in our toolbox you know
let's take a step back and look at how
that fits into uh so like the overall
security of the system now having an
s-bomb generator is great it's fantastic
but there are several points where the
supply chain can actually be attacked
now
you know securing all this is obviously
hard and it's you know probably there
are team entire teams dedicated to
fixing this problem many companies you
know vmware included
now
but how do we do that it's actually
pretty hard so there are two so like
frameworks that are so like standing out
these days one of them is the salsa
framework which was uh you know
initiated by google and so like you know
something that is you know
something that is there's a lot of buzz
around it right now and also there's
like the os proactive control framework
they can help you integrate you know
practices and automation into your
supply chain trying to leveraging the
same platform and tools that you know
your developers and your sre teams are
also using so like creating a connection
between the two and so like adding sec
into your devops cycle into your devops
practices
now work in this area is still pretty
nascent if you look at especially if you
look at salsa salsa has four levels uh
level one and two are pretty well
defined three and four not so much so
if you're a security expert if you're a
security practitioner and you're
interested in this i would suggest you
to like go check out salsa which is l s
l s a dot ave and you know take a look
because it's it's interesting stuff
uh and in closing i know i'm over time
already but i'm trying to wrap up early
as much as possible so how do you get
started today now
uh so joe joe bida is one of the
kubernetes co-founder and
there's one line that i always use when
talking about kubernetes that i really
like which is kubernetes is a platform
platform
which means it's a platform to build
platforms now
what you see up here it's a set of tools
that are available today to so like
build your own secure supply chain
platform right
i want to highlight some some of these
notable examples here but there are many
more out there so
this is not like a complete lease by any
stretch of imagination so
if there's nothing here that fits what
you need go check out the cncf landscape
because there's likely a project that is
you know is built for you
so
let's quickly look over you know what we
have here in total performs at the
station so
it which is basically authenticated
metadata on
for your software artifacts so while
you're building your software you create
at the station and then you see you
cryptographically sign them and you
basically take them along your your
secure pipeline
you have you know cartographer which is
a choreographer so like similar concept
to orchestration for secure supply chain
this works in conjunction with you know
and task executioner like you know
techton or even jenkins and then you
have six store which is you know toolkit
for automatic signing and verification
of artifacts and if you looked at the
recent you know release of kubernetes
124 kubernetes 124 is the first release
that is signed and can be verified using
six store so go check it out
uh and as i mentioned earlier there's
salsa and osp as a security framework
again go check them out uh and last but
not least oppa which is pretty famous
and i'm sure that if you're running a
kubernetes cluster in production there's
a pretty high chance you're already
running oppa or open policy agent for
enforcing policies out there it's gonna
be extremely useful also for creating
secure supply chain
i hope this was helpful and
you know hopefully also informative in a
in a way uh good luck in securing your
pipelines and
have a great time here in valencia thank
you