welcome to uh security con by cntf tech
security
um
[Music]
we're gonna have events over two days
which you probably already know about uh
so fun facts there's a ctf going on and
i did not
did we hear it back andreas did we hear
back when is what days are the ctfs
going on
okay we'll get into the c-types in a
second
uh so lewis is going to talk more about
ctfs uh there's a talk later today about
that so ctfs are a great way to get
started with stuff so if you're new here
if you want to
start learning stuff that's a ctaps are
a great way
you know we often talk about being alone
in our basement so we can be alone in
our basements together so that's a fun
thing
um
so
when we were preparing this this little
opening
section uh the organizers were asking me
i was asking the organizers what should
i talk about and they were asking well
why what do you like what do you find
interesting about security and what i
said is
well security is kind of hilarious
because there's a bunch of stuff that
um
there's a bunch of stuff that most
people don't know or don't think about
and the results are often unexpected
which is what i find humorous but the
problem is when unexpected things happen
people get fined uh there's you know
security audits that kind of stuff
sometimes it doesn't work out that's a
problem
so we need to make sure that things work
we need to be able to
think about things proactively so that
other people don't have to especially
when it comes to security
now that's
that's a bit of a hot topic here because
we often get the sense that a lot of
developers especially developers are not
a big fan of security uh and the reason
is because
there's too much going on for everybody
i'm sure all of you have too much going
on and every developer and every team
that you interact with they also have a
lot of stuff going on so
a lot of our jobs uh tends to be
getting out of people's way uh even
though our jobs are important other
people's jobs are important but we try
as much as possible to
generate less work for other people and
i think that's a very important thing so
a trend that we see emerge not emerge
but get more and more
visibility is automating security and i
find that super interesting i find it
super important because we remove the
human element we make sure that things
work by default instead of working
because we made everybody as paranoid as
we are
so there's a lot of talks about that
about automating things so uh fabio uh
who is a co-worker of mine at vmware uh
he's gonna talk about devsecops which is
one of those one of the ways to automate
uh how security works
uh we're going to hear about fuzzing
we're going to hear about uh argo cd
which uh i think there was a big
vulnerability or something which is very
interesting
we're going to have talks about policy
binary signing and so on so lots of ways
to automate things to make sure that
things work without having to make
everyone an expert in our subject matter
which i think at the end of the day is
the goal is to make sure things work
without everybody having to worry about
everyone else's area of expertise
so if you're interested in getting more
involved in this community uh i think
we often work in silos which is not the
healthiest thing in the world so if
you're interested in working more as a
community uh make sure to talk to your
peers the people sitting next to you are
the community that you should be
involved with
do talk to the speakers after every talk
about the subjects that you find
interesting everybody here is super
approachable
there's a talk tomorrow by raga in which
she's going to mention
all the ways to get involved in cncf
tech security there's also kubernetes
dash security which is a
slightly different focus but point being
talk to talk to your peers talk to the
speakers talk to everybody let's work
together as a community
so
things here are very volunteer based um
it's not traditional infosec
which has lots of pros and cons but
dude let's try to work together
everything is uh very open very
transparent
um
so i'm gonna hand it off to fabio in a
second
and
i just wanted to wish everyone a great
day here uh today and tomorrow we have
lots of really cool talks
and
and that's it there's coffee outside uh
make sure your coffee's hot i was handed
cold coffee just now and it was like
very traumatic experience uh
anyway uh it's five year ready
so i'm gonna hand it off to fabio cause
uh he has more stuff to talk about than
it was the allotted time but don't tell
anybody
fabio
all right thanks so much everyone