so you know those open source libraries
well
that kind of disappeared a little bit um
so we're going to be talking about the
unexpected demise of open source
libraries or it's going to disappear and
we're not going to be talking about
anything i don't know um so next up we
have laryntal
again
so i'm probably gonna be the only person
who's stopping you and the
after party up happy hour thing so no
pressure there
uh so yeah the unexpected demise of open
source libraries or basically where do
the where do libraries go to die or
libraries die hard all of those kind of
titles of you know us using open source
projects but maybe not knowing exactly
what's happening there
so open source has fundamentally changed
my life
as a teenager for me i was going onto
things like the linux kernel mailing
list hanging out with people learning
about open source using tools
basically finding collaboration and
communication paths with like-minded
people
and it enabled me to learn and do many
many good things i hope and just put
them out there one of those was the
projects that i actually built about 15
years ago uploaded it to an open source
page called sourceforge for some of you
who might remember it
and you know to date i've actually went
back and seen how much uh that has
actually been impactful and i've
actually seen this project called uh
dela radios as part of
the resume of some people that have
their skills and exp and experience laid
out on linkedin which is pretty cool so
it actually changed my life but it also
allowed me and enabled me to
basically improve and change others
people's life to the better so i'm glad
for open source my name is irantal i'm a
developer advocate at sneak where we
build developer first security tools
basically help empower developers to not
just find but fix security issues along
the way id is sexy and all of those
things i'm also doing a bunch of stuff
on the ecosystems of node.js and pm
open source all around so if you have
any questions on this in any different
way i'm happy to chat about it
afterwards just find me here
so talking about open source um this is
this is a pretty interesting topic and
the success of it i think i think it's
been successful so far so i went back
and found some information that was
really interesting for me one of which
was
almost half of the projects at around
nine at 20 15 on github are mit licensed
which is interesting by itself but
actually this is all the projects
everything else if we look down
specifically on things like ecosystem
language-based ecosystems like npm like
ruby python pybi things that people
store there we're actually getting to
about 90
of those projects
being used using licenses that are very
very permissive
and i think that is something that has
indeed contributed to the fact that open
source has really
been growing and advancing at a really
increased state
so
one question when we're talking about
here and you know the unexpected demise
of open source libraries is are we have
we used
so much open source that at this point
we're actually taking it for granted
and then
what happens when we do what happens
when we use open source and just consume
it it's just you know
just another s-bomb entry
so with that said i want to share with
you a few stories that really happened
in the ecosystems this one specifically
called left pad is a story of how legal
actions were driven and taken by
commercial body towards an open source
maintainer that at the end of it back in
the end of this action it had actually
caused
widespread disruption of build and
systems
impacting projects like the node.js
project like babel and other in the
javascript ecosystem so what exactly
happened there
well if we take for example uh you know
regular software development theme like
this one well there are some fallacies
there for example we have uh murray
jonathan and mina doing open source
development which is great and they're
doing also internal development
for the company and you know it's been
scientifically proved that to be a
developer and what it actually means is
essentially you take some coffee
that's right you know it and some code
goes out
and so that it you know about this one
already uh there's another thing that
has been uh we've been witnessing
recently and that is that no they use a
lot of open source packages up to 90
and you know those statistics being
shared out you know once uh and about
every time and they use a lot of those
open source packages one of them by the
way is this person called azure he's an
open source developer a maintainer of
many many modules one of them this team
actually uses so in essence
one of the fallacies is this team is not
really three people team they're like a
four people team actually many many more
people because we're using a lot of open
source packages behind those projects
behind those packages leave other
maintainers and other developers that
impact us
so let's talk about azure for a second
azure has is an npm developer you know
building stuff upon the npm registry for
javascript he has this module called
kick kik
which accidentally
is also a name of an instant messaging
application
that's pender and a commercial entity
that exists
on this kind of like a platform
and so he was asked by this legal entity
you know several emails exchange and so
on to basically give up the name and
reduce some other name just you know
give it up and uh and allow this other
company uses kik to own that actual name
that didn't really work out as you know
could have guessed so as a protest of uh
no not really agreeing with that then
npm the registry itself the team behind
it not able to actually bridge between
the two sides and eventually uh what
happened is he did not want to
get a lawsuit or any other kind of like
legal actions so went on and just as a
protest action
removed all of his modules from npm he
had many of them about 250 back then
just removed removed
any all of them and said you know bye
bye
one little thing that happened there is
there's like this little little model 17
lines of code called left pad left
padding strings
and it's downloaded just a little bit
about 2.5 million times and so when that
got removed
essentially a lot of projects that used
it as a nested dependency somewhere down
your transitive dependency tree have
actually broken up
and this is how
this story became to be how one
developer actually broke the whole
ecosystem
so some learnings from this story
first of all reinstalling those packages
all the time when you do npm install on
ci on developer machines and you go off
and fetch
you know the actual the actual artifact
like this kick module or
left pad module or something else you
want this to be a very deterministic and
you know proven uh way of doing that so
obviously one of the ways of doing this
is to put something like a caching proxy
like uh something that actually takes uh
both the fact that it also saves up not
just the fact that something could be
a network error or just be gone from the
registry for some reasons but also the
fact that you want to speed things up
and do those kind of installs really
fast internally so verdejo is an open
source
private proxy server that does all of
those kind of things it's pretty fast
basically the way that it works you kind
of configure package managers to use
that as the app stream or as the actual
registry and then that one is verda
itself is used as that
a source to which upstream are you
allowed to actually contact and bring
all of these things in so reduction is
really cool and it's a great open source
software for us to do this and i think a
lot of companies have learned this in
the hard way of using those internal
proxies
not just for speeding up reasons but
actually to prevent those cases from
happening but also the fact that
when this happened when all modules got
published this was an unprecedented
event in the npm ecosystem because no
one thought about the potential you know
threat attack that someone would
actually go and publish their modules
especially if they're so popular and
everyone use them but when they do it
just impacts everyone else so it
actually brought in npm to introduce new
limitations as if you cannot
unpublish your modules if it is popular
or used by other you know dependencies
and so on and so on so we've learned
from it as an ecosystem as well but
we've had to learn the hard way
another story is
this uh story about someone
who actually stopped their project from
being alive from being maintained
anymore just because they wanted
to be a bit more greener for the earth
so i don't know how you would feel about
it but i'm pretty sure like for a lot of
maintainers like gaining the popularity
and reputation of being an open using an
open source project is something they
probably don't want to cut in uh just
midway or as you're developing it but
for this person not so much
so meet francois he's the developer and
maintainer of this faker php library
it's essentially a library that allows
you to fake data do random generation of
data for tests things like that
it's pretty cool it's been there for
since 2011 and it has been used uh to to
be uh
an sdk for like different languages like
uh python and uh also provide different
locales like over 70k so it's like a
very very popular project
when you download it as a dev tool it's
three megabytes of size pretty you know
not that much if you compare it to like
end-to-end tools and like figure things
that you probably pull in
so this is a project it became so
popular that by 2019 it had actually
been downloaded over 120 million times
many many contributors many many
projects being dependent on it but the
thing is
at this point of popularity if something
if you wanted to be
conscious of climate change would you
actually consider the size of your
library an issue
sure maybe it's an issue for front-end
and optimization and stuff like that but
for climate change that is something
that francois really had difficulties
agreeing with and working with he did
not want to be a person who contributes
in a bad way to climate change
and he actually you know figured out
that potentially what's going on there
is about 11 metric tons of co2 emissions
just by all of those downloads that's a
lot and he said i do not want to do this
anymore
so what happens next well first of all
do we get new maintainers how does open
source work
so francois had here's as you've seen
and understood like he's been on the
open source ecosystem for a bit and he
had like really bad experience with
transitioning his projects to other
maintainers uh one of his stories is he
actually uh owned another maintain
another project called propel a php or
rm library and when he handed that off
to a friend to continue maintaining it
that friend
handed it off to another friend
which handed it off to another friend
which they ended up to another friend
that said this code base is not really
good i'm gonna rewrite this whole thing
and do a 2.0 version that was six years
ago nothing came out of it
so
he had a really bad experience and he
did not want to just you know try to
continue the project by handing it off
so he said
i'm archiving the project archiving the
github you know repository no more
releases no more issues nothing else if
you want you can fork it
you know he just added a comment
you can fork it it might be better than
faker the php library just remember it
might not be so much fun
so here's another open source dependency
just unexpectedly you know dying off
first of all excruciating maintainers i
think is a is a really good thing that
we should adopt and that relates to the
whole sustainability aspect of open
source and discussions around this and
of course you know help support the
climate change is an important thing and
it's great that maintainers and
developers are conscious to this
our last story is about how
mr m this person did not want to do any
more free work as part of their open
source packages
and i'm pretty sure there's some people
here that are contributing to open
source maybe even maintaining it so
we're all using open source projects but
how much are we actually giving back to
people how much are we actually giving
back to the projects maintainers
themselves and developers
i promise that unlike their two stories
i'll
end this fairy tale one in a positive
note
so meet mr m
they are an open source maintainer
and they have a bunch of projects one of
them is this called faker.js this is by
the way not the same project the idea is
the same but
coincidentally uh it is
it is of the same name just not the same
one different maintainers different
projects by the way different outcomes
it's pretty popular as well this one as
well is used to generate random data
used for tests and things like that but
um
it is pretty popular as well 12 million
million monthly downloads and
just like many other projects on the
ecosystem most of this work is unfunded
it's maybe sustainable maybe not but you
know no one contributes to the project
so this person the maintainer behind a
project called faker.js
went down on 20 uh 2020 and said uh in a
github issue i am not going to support
this project or you anymore uh no more
free work from me
and i think as you can see maybe a bit
by the reactions on github most of the
people actually agree with this and
support this because it's a project
that's used by you know fortune 500
companies and you know we're not that
doing that well of a job contributing
back to all the peers and the colleagues
that actually work on open source
so this was his statement and the
question is was this heard this was back
it wasn't that hard
one of those things that happened is
that by 2022 the beginning of january
this person the maintainer actually
pushed code into the repository that
essentially nullified everything else
they forced push a commit so all the
source code that existed for this faker
js php library was completely removed
only
if you archived it or forked it before
or clone it or whatever nothing exists
also they pushed a new version called
faker
6.6.6 understand that where this is
going which indeed broke the ecosystem
as well it had nothing in it but
essentially it was an empty project if
you try to use it it would fake it would
uh it would not work and so
he actually lived up to his statement
right
said no more free work so no more free
work you're not getting any of those
packages anymore question is did anyone
really care to understand that we
actually need to dive a bit deeper into
what happened here and so
faker this project if if the maintainer
actually pushes the project with you
know 6.6.6 major version
that is broken but is this actually
affecting all of us not exactly
the main
stable branch or version center range of
faker the library on npm is actually
major version 5. the way that npm works
behind the scenes is where usually it
out of fetches
minor and patch versions depending on
how you configure things
but you have to be very explicit to just
take everything in with a wild card and
people usually do not do that and you
know
good thing that they don't so the fact
that a new version 6.6 is published
doesn't really impact many many people
because the amount of people actually
use faker as a new project or
automatically get it by builds isn't
that big
so something like this wasn't really
hurting anybody even though we wanted to
make a statement as this open source
maintainer did
but here's a note
this person a maintainer on npm actually
owns many other libraries not just faker
for example callers is another important
and very uh
important to the ecosystems but also
very uh you know prolific one
and
it's so popular used by nasa
dependencies that it has over 100
million downloads a month
so
mr m actually owns both of them he's the
maintainer of both of those
so what would we do
perhaps
inject something into callers
if
1.4.0
is the latest stable version that gets
those 100 million downloads a month
if we release 1.4.1 for example a patch
version
probably a lot of automated download
tools will actually start getting this
and this is exactly what happened and
also developers at least in javascript
from what i've seen are very keen on
just getting the latest and bleeding
edge which is we'll leave it to the end
to talk about it but what's in 1.4.1 we
usually don't even look at a source code
to realize what we're getting we just
want to be at the bleeding edge want to
get the new features the new bugs
new bug fixes
well here's one of the changelogs
i'll uh
go ahead and
zoom in for for some of you
this is what was added in 1.4.1
i realized that many maybe not everyone
here are programmer but essentially by
the for loop and a case of minus of less
than infinity you can understand that
this is a denial of service
of a loop that once you include and use
callers 1.4.1 in your project the moment
that you do and this is getting used
essentially this is a denial of service
attack for anyone because nothing will
actually continue working
with your application especially node.js
being single threaded
and so on so this is what happened
now remember we talked about mary and
jonathan and mina at the beginning and
we said they are part of open source
ecosystems they are this is the fallacy
we do not understand but they are so
let's see how far this went out
well mary actually works at amazon and
she is working with aws cdk which got
impacted because it uses 1.4.1 so all of
the users who used amazon cdk have
actually had this problem coming in
remember mina he's actually working for
heroku's a cliff
essentially that also uses colors behind
the sin and if you were using that you
would be pulling in automatically
potentially this you know denial of
service attack to your application
how about jonathan he's working on jess
that's like that's like a test runner
for javascript very famous one built
from facebook or meta these days
so that's also been pulling in callers
and all of these projects and many many
more so we are very much part of open
source and we cannot deny it anymore and
all of those things are actually
impacting us so if something goes bad
there
regardless of security vulnerabilities
like projects dying or
something some some in some way getting
added some malicious code into them that
just is you know bad we are impacted by
this
let's see further out how impactful this
is so
as they later published
version 1.4.1 and version 1.4.2
you could see that really really
fast
okay in a matter of hours and days
the amount of downloads per each version
we're talking about
more than
500 000 half a million downloads within
a day or two these and 1.41 and 2 are
the impacted one so it shows you how
fast and how impactful this has been on
the ecosystem if you have been impacted
by
colors
well
let's talk about colors incident
learning what could we have done to have
prevented this well first of all if you
use a log file and don't just install
everything all the time then you have a
lot of assurances like you know a
checksum like a sha and all of those
other things but essentially it allows
you to not just get every install you
know new version december whatever that
just you know went out yesterday but
you're always getting deterministic
installs there are specific commands in
npm that you have to follow both nci and
your development environment to make
sure that indeed this is what happens
because you could still have a log file
but use different commands that override
it so like this is like a bad practice
the other thing is if that would have
happened to you and you wanted to
mitigate it
if this is a nested dependency not a
direct dependency which you can just
update if this is a nasa dependency
impacting you then you cannot really do
anything to change it if another
maintainer pulls in
for example just that pulls in colors
1.4.2 you cannot do anything to to tell
jess to do 1.41 until this feature from
npm now supported by other package
managers like yarn and and pnpm and that
allows you to specify this thing called
overrides which we used it also for as
you can see in the reference here for
the node ipc which is didn't cover it
here but that's like an another
interesting uh
protestor let's call it like that
so this is another way of doing that the
other thing that i actually want to
share with you is
there are many automated dependency
upgrade tools you know like the one you
use and see in github and there are
probably other vendors that do it the
thing is you have to be very conscious
on what you're updating we're just
talking about now about packages that
have been
harmed in or just stopped in one way or
the other but they made by the
maintainer that's not even like
an external attack vector someone taking
over a package that's like someone that
you're supposed to trust within the
ecosystem
and
all of those automated dependency
upgrade tools that you actually get all
the time updates and updates
think about for a second what if you
could have
been able to just delay the upgrade
right and so this is something that we
actually looked into
about three years ago back at snake when
i joined actually looked at many other
malicious incidents that happened and we
looked at the data frames for uh how how
much time it took for a malicious packet
to actually be known so now unless a
dependency is
needs to get a security fix like unless
this is a security fix that needs to go
in
all of those
updates that you will get from the sneak
bot for example will be delayed by about
three weeks which is what we found to be
a very reasonable time for you to update
you know just for
new features or new bug fixes if needed
automatically
but also be a bit on the safe side give
you some buffer time so you know the
community can vet it and things can you
know get uh
get uh worked out by a bunch of other
people and more more eyeballs looking at
it if the quote uh quote someone else
so i said this is going to be a
fairytale ending so what happened here
i'm going to go back not to callers but
to faker.js of the same maintainer
luckily for us faker.js on the
javascript system is a very big project
like we said many fortune 500 companies
have been using it so
the beauty of open source is that in the
case of faker.js here this maintainer of
colors and faker.js another group of
people amazing humans who came up and
said hey you know what we're going to
fork the project and it is very
influential there's like a lot to do
people use it all the time it's a very
good project and they have continued it
and provided the roadmap and everything
that they you know they updated the
documentation it actually brought a lot
of
different forks and different people who
maintain like documentation and stuff
like that aside brought them together so
they can actually cooperate on a new
place for faker js
so big shout out to this thing big shout
out to open source to everyone here is
doing that and to that team specifically
i wanted to take in uh just an example
of the metric this is from a screenshot
from yesterday you could see that from
just the last month the activity that
has been on the project has been to
close down merge 83 pull requests and
more and more so it's amazing to see
also the continuation of projects in the
open source ecosystem beyond them being
sometimes discontinued in ways that are
unexpected
so to end the kind like this the whole
stories here are going to give you a bit
more takeaways unrelated to these
specific stories
well first of all i think when
developers essentially look for packages
we use the currency of stars the
currency of downloads if i want to look
out for a package for example an http
library a client-side client library for
http calls i might go into you know a
place like npmjs and probably the one
thing that i'll use to judge is
how many downloads are there for it
actually it looks like this is a
trending up graph even so
looks like requests here this library
getting about 15 million downloads by
other users by our developers so i don't
know maybe it's safe maybe i'll use it
maybe but there are more
perspectives that we could look at
around the spectrum of what makes a
project what makes a community for a
project that are good indications that
we shouldn't
deny them so
on this one specifically request
actually got deprecated a few months
after this after this screenshot thing
so
what led to that is if we could have
looked at something that gave us more
information for example i open it up
retroactively now for example in the
sneak advisor tool which is a free tool
that you can use to like look at
packages and get more package health
information and you could see for
example we look at maintenance and we
see that it didn't have any commits or
any releases in the last two years so
yes it's getting downloaded 15 million
times but it's not really active that's
a signal that something could actually
turn bad it doesn't mean that it's bad
in internally or in any other way but
you probably do not want to continue new
greenfield projects and might want to
consider moving on to other http client
libraries on npm that are not this
let's take another example that's you
know the other side of the flip side of
the coin this is marked
a library a javascript library that
translates markdown and uh you know
converts that to html it's a pretty cool
library i've been on the system also for
a long time and it had its share of
vulnerabilities too but you could see
that many of the latest versions first
of all there are many of those
throughout 2021 and even though many
vulnerabilities are being tried to the
project they're getting fixed and your
releases are going out also you could
see the pulse on the com on the on the
maintenance side of things showing you
that commits are happening all the time
showing you an idea that again is not
bulletproof and doesn't mean that this
is you know not going to be discontinued
tomorrow but it's a good indication that
says this is a pretty positive
healthy project
whoever heard about this bomb
right
but i want to give you a different
perspective i want to lend a new
a new opinion here for you to like think
about here not just the software bill of
materials that's you know
fine like we talked about it a couple of
times that's that's okay
how about the fact that
projects are not materials they are
built by humans by people they are very
dynamic in nature they change they
evolve and so to think about humans as
materials is a pretty bad concept
i think
so how about we talk about sboh how
about we talk about the software bill of
health not just
what we use not just the vulnerabilities
of it but all those other signals that
we may have
in the project and around the project
and how it's actually being used and
consumed and does it have tests and so
many other kind of signals that we can
get into how healthy the project is as
an open source project for us to use
so hopefully some of this has resonated
with you i'm here for a bit uh thank you
for having me and you know use open
source safely it is great it's amazing
that's it
i wanted to end with a
bit of a bit of an ending here this is
the one
so
the only thing that lasts forever are
well naturally dependencies as we've
seen
and not really airmile so i hope you
used all of those when fine here and
covered in all those things
um i think it's cat videos on youtube
that's the only thing i could think of
that probably lasts forever
and so with that really thank you so
much and thank you for having me
[Applause]
any questions
all right
eager for the happy hour
not there yet not yet okay cool well
have fun people and enjoy the conference