uh thank you and good afternoon and
welcome i am actually really honored to
be out here and uh getting to present
after two years of not presenting so
welcome to everyone here in person and
everyone joining us online uh it's
actually a real honor and it's actually
a privilege since it's my first time at
kubecon and securitycon and i'm just
curious with a show of hands how many of
you folks are new to the conference
all right well it's great to meet
everyone and hopefully i get a chance to
talk to you guys all you folks
today tomorrow and this week
all right so
session today is on the
five reasons
to invest in this in the software supply
chain and securing the software supply
chain and we cover some some myths as
well as to um you know things that come
up in the context of the supply chain
that we want to make sure that we uh we
address and get into the right context
as we
um as we look at investing in this area
so just a little bit about me i
got my start in wall street i.t i moved
to the west coast joined microsoft
primarily worked in systems management
virtualization management i got to work
with some standards organizations around
storage management primarily dmtf and
snea
and i got a chance to ship some cloud
on-prem products
as well and more recently i joined the
strategic missions and technologies
group in microsoft where we focus on
supply chain and supply chain security
and so
at home i currently find myself
keeping my senior dogs from getting
annoyed by the new puppy that's been
introduced so that's always fun
all right
so with the talk all the talk this week
are on s-bomb supply chain at the
conference and just in general with what
we hear in the news and just the ongoing
and relentless relentless attacks uh
that are you know pretty much hitting
every industry
um
it's good to put it in context as to
exactly what is to gain i guess from the
cyber uh from the cyber crimes that are
out there uh in terms of cyber damage
cost
you know we're looking at
six trillion dollars in 2021 uh
potentially exceeding 10.5 trillion by
and uh as well we see the investments in
cyber cyber security also increasing uh
actually substantially from 3.5 billion
in 2014 and then cumulatively going to
about a trillion dollars between 2017
and 2025. now i put these sides aside
just to
compare the growth in both the
investments and the damage
not so much a statement on how much
should be invested to match the actual
damage that are out there
but we do know that more is needed and
faster
so let's put the supply chain in context
we hear i mean so the supply chain in
context to me covers three areas
software development
software deployment
and software runtime so we start with
the software development side uh
to me the supply chain and everything
that goes into it has to account for not
only where the code is actually being
developed when it's where it's being
checked in who's checking it in you know
are these verifiable sources are these
repos healthy you know there's a big a
big part of sorry one
yeah so there's a lot there's a lot that
goes just to making sure that the code
is authentic and the integrity of the
code itself
and that spans the software and the
underlying hardware of that development
environment
and then when we
when we move forward to the deployment
phase
now we have to make sure that we know
what we're getting is healthy we know
that we can verify the sources both of
the repositories and the issuers of the
of whatever claims you know that's where
we look at the s bombs that are being
generated we want to make sure that
those s bombs are generated at check-in
time and not after
after the build is complete
you know and we want to know that we're
actually using hardened deployment
processes especially when you're
deploying at the edge or you know
in a sovereign environment you may not
actually have direct access direct
control over the infrastructure that's
being deployed so you want to make sure
that your your processes are hardened
both in the software side and also in
the infrastructure deployment
and then once you're running this
environment and running the software you
know you're going to have drift right
unless you're investing heavily in the
automation and all the tooling that can
guarantee that
drift doesn't happen you know you want
to you you want that monitoring you want
you want that observability you know do
you have those hardened package
management tools that will get you the
the right updates the secure updates you
know um if you're if you've got your
your infrastructure team the operations
team actually doing break fix on those
environments on that infrastructure are
they producing signed scripts right
that's something that we learned as part
of deploying uh
cloud on-prem is how do you seal the box
and everything that our sres have to do
on those systems can actually be from a
trusted source in this case being
microsoft but the customer gets the
guarantee as well that whatever's being
put on their systems to initiate a break
fix is actually uh verified right so
this the supply chain primarily you know
we talk a lot about the software
development side but it does span um all
the way into the runtime all you know
through the updates and eventually into
decommissioning right we put a lot of
work especially in hyperscale cloud uh
service providers on the secure
destruction of data to ensure that
nothing actually leaks out of the
out of the data center
okay
so
let's get to the first myth
once you create your s-bomb you're
pretty much done right
well let's uh first question is what are
you describing right we talk a lot about
describing the dependencies the binaries
the docker image with images whatever
you want to or the container images you
can start there but
that quickly starts if you start peeling
that onion or pulling that thread you
know you're going to start asking more
questions right you know is it beyond
the entire package at what granularity
what are your upstream dependencies you
know what are you expecting to see in
that metadata you know uh do you have
any kind of uh vulnerability
information captured inside you know do
you have your cv scan results also in
there and there's a bunch of tools that
come along with that right not only with
s-bomb and the formats whether it's
cyclone dx spdx um ava black covered git
bomb earlier today you know but then you
get into uh the
signing of those statements and what it
actually means to be a verifiable
statement
and then the automation right the
frameworks like in total and tough tough
giving you those uh sealed updates and
eventually the observability side right
how do you get to the you know multiple
levels of of a secure environment and
the promises that you've gone through
each of those steps and you know met
those requirements and that's where
something like salsa comes in so
i like to use
i like to you know start with the fact
that s palms are typically used as an
ingredients list or the comparison that
it's the ingredients list to something
that you buy in the store or maybe you
get something on the menu but i want to
pull that thread a little bit more and i
want to use
an example
that is
from a show called portlandia
you know um and in basically two minutes
of
a couple entering a store they ask about
the chicken that's on the menu
and they you know they learn a lot of
great things like you know the chicken's
name is colin uh you know it's breed and
you know what it was fed
uh but then they start asking you know
they start pulling the thread more you
know um is it happy did it have friends
you know uh is it is the information
that's being provided actually you know
real
um is it organic right does it meet
whatever requirements of organic what
kind of organic you know and eventually
you know where did it grow up
you know who who owns that farm
you know and
the person is actually providing this
information that service provider in
that case
it's not an authoritative source
whatever they're saying you know could
be true you can't verify you don't know
if it's authentic they're just trying to
do their the best that they can to the
best of their abilities
so
in the same way if you looked at a
lettuce right you've got dna markers
embedded into the lettuce itself that if
you need to trace back a parasite
outbreak or any kind of bacterial
outbreak you know what farm that lettuce
came from so i like those kind of
examples because
it gets sorry
it gets us you know thinking more about
what else could we include as part of
that s-bomb and what other artifacts we
want to include right when we say
artifacts
sorry when i say artifacts in this
discussion i'm going beyond just the
nest palm the document but any kind of
for example measurements that are being
done on the on the code itself
you know any kind of logs that need to
be uh added or even a manual attestation
right of maybe some stl process that
isn't automated that you but you want to
make sure that it's captured and signed
by someone within the organization right
so
um
all right so then we get to the second
half of that myth which is you know once
you create the s bomb and you've got
your software captured you know you're
pretty much done and in fact what we're
seeing and you know some of the
investments that we're making actually
we want to extend the build of materials
concept and that artifact gathering and
verification concept uh beyond the
software into the underlying hardware so
you can see for example uh these the
chip manufacturing industry
highly automated huge investments in
these in these uh in fabrication you
know and you know they've got they've
got all of this nailed down but they're
really siloed because of that ip that
they carry within those within those
fabs and so you know you really can't
make any determination on the qual on
the um on the chips itself you know you
just have to trust that it's being done
right and what we've seen it recently
with nvidia is that anyone is
susceptible to these kind of threats um
if you look at system integration right
once those chips leave the fabs they get
sent to these odms you know and
eventually they get put into systems by
a system integrator you know that's
another level of building materials
right if you're in procurement you know
that anytime you order a server you're
giving that building materials to you
know your hardware vendor and you want
to make sure that what you get back is
actually that server and that it's
something that uh ideally isn't you know
tampered with especially if you're going
to a secure environment or in in the
federal space
um
so
two sides to that myth about you know
just being at one s palm and you're done
both on when you're pulling the onion on
the fractal of dependencies as ava put
it earlier today and also how deep into
the stack do you actually go beyond just
describing the software
so
uh the next question is you know you've
got the s-bomb and that's it you can be
trusted right this is a really simple
one um swamps can be modified all right
and uh it's you know the metadata that's
contained there there's really no way of
proving uh you know who generated it and
if it's something if it's an authentic
uh piece of documentation and if even if
it's verifiable so this is where we get
into you know if you pull on the collin
example right a farmer could say all
right um colin right grew up on contoso
farms and i'm signing that statement
that's a statement that i'm making about
this particular product so you get into
you know two you know the salsa example
where in this case we're talking about
attestations right where you take that
the artifact itself is the document or
the log or something else but now you're
making a statement making a statement
about that particular artifact and then
you want to make sure that it's signed
and you want to make sure that it's
something that's verifiable right and so
you get both the you know you put it in
the envelope and then you've got those
bundles of attestations that actually
describe your microservice your service
your product you know whatever whatever
you're trying to describe
in your environment okay
so this gets us to you know uh if it can
be trusted and also the integrity
so uh skit is actually a framework in an
architecture uh that has been worked on
in in
in the open community where we're
looking at how to enhance the security
of the ledgers themselves so ledgers
that you've heard on today we're talking
about you know append only
append only ledgers that are tamper
proof built on merkle trees all goodness
um what we've done with skit is actually
take that a step further and we give you
three guarantees uh both in uh when it
comes to encryption encryption on disk
encryption in transit and encryption in
use and this is where we get to the
conversation about on secure enclaves so
on the skid side and the skit service
there's essentially three guarantees
that the service itself is making the
first one is that the statements are
issued
you know by someone that's identifiable
that's authentic and though no taxi
backs is right you can't say yeah i
didn't say that so you're non-reputable
right and then the next step is to say
that those statements get registered on
a secure ledger that's immutable right
and that's secure from from top to
bottom okay
and the next one is that
the
issuers
that's right so the issuers can prove to
any other party that those claims
actually exist in that ledger with a
receipt once you have that receipt and
you actually have that you know the
combination receipt and the claim you
know that it was recorded in the ledger
and that you can actually trust what's
actually being uh put out there
now this architecture is actually built
on um confidential computing so in azure
the confidential computing vms
running intel sgx
offer that secure enclave and that's
what that's a technology that gives you
that
guarantees at the chip level that the
memory space the data is actually
protected while in use so there's no
chance of tampering while the data is
being written to the ledger itself
okay so let's quickly walk through the
architecture and just uh you know a
simple workflow
first we start with who right so we
start with the with the did uh the
decentralized identity once we have that
identity um captured the next step we
actually
can then generate our artifacts s bombs
logs whatever it is and so once i have
that that artifact next thing i want to
do is generate a statement right this is
what i'm saying about this artifact
which is what what i eventually want to
wrap into into the next step which is um
sorry
so which i'm eventually going to wrap
into a claim now i get my endorsement
from the did based on my uh my on the
identity
and i can use that to generate a claim
now the claim itself is what you know
wrapped in a cozy envelope which
includes protected headers the payload
itself which is the statement and the
signature that comes from your uh your
did
so now with that claim in hand
uh what i can do is now record it in a
ledger so the skit
skate architecture provides a skit
service provides a transparency service
that transparency service is the one
that records it in the ledger once it's
recorded in a ledger what you actually
get back is a counter sign statement
that sorry counter signature that we
call a receipt
okay so
once with the original claim in hand and
a receipt now you have a transparent
claim and the the
the beauty about this uh part of the
system is that now you can use that
transparent claim to actually verify all
the information that was put into the
ledger itself because you have a receipt
of that that the data was actually
written to
into the service uh the the transparent
service itself will guarantee that a
receipt is not given until the date is
written right so
if you have a receipt data has been
written and now you can uh whether it's
yourself as part of verifying in you
know in uh in real time or let's say an
auditor needs to go in and you know
basically run through all the
verification um for an investigation or
something else they can use those
transparent claims which is a claim in
the receipt against the ledger to walk
through all the
um
everything that they need to verify
all right
give me one second
okay
so the next one is okay so you've
generated the s-bomb and we saw a lot of
this as well as we were going through
the the executive order and making sure
that we you know we we met uh all the
requirements there you know a lot of the
folks that are actually doing this work
they don't know the details that go
behind what's you know uh what's
actually going into the guarantees that
you don't you want to make whether it's
you know the sdl guarantees or the s
bomb and everything else so
just saying that yeah i did x checkbox
done uh we know that that's not enough
being compliant uh you know is not a way
of gain of getting to be secure
um simple example is what happened at
target in 2013 pci dss compliant yet
they still got hacked a few weeks later
and even though they earned that
certificate that said that they were
compliant so this is where we get into
you know um
think uh
a way of looking at the executive order
that actually has
multiple parts that actually can
contribute to it first you're looking at
the uh
secure software development framework
the ssdf right and then from there the
supply chain risk management document
and also zero trust architecture
and gives you a way of mapping from the
eo
and through what the requirements are
you know the recommendations are into
actual practices and tasks that can be
done to meet those requirements and the
beauty about this system is that it it's
really not meant to be
fire and forget or one and done right
you do it and you want you want it to be
continuous you want to keep building
those practices so that
you know this becomes
inherent in what you do on day to day
you shift left in terms of of your test
environment and you start
these security practices from the
beginning
and
lastly
with willpower alone you can push
through those tough days i'm gonna get a
little bit more personal here but you
know uh between long hours you know
keeping up with with the increased
threats uh coming into your environment
you know there's a
winding skill gap that's been seen as
well in terms of cancellations being uh
cancellation of events you know the the
onset the pandemic you know and then
just the relentless security reviews and
audits and everything else uh we know
that there's eventually going to be
burnout right so
part of that you know is asking for help
and that's you know something that does
require a certain level of vulnerability
but it's something that you know once
you have that network of support around
you you know it's something that can
help you through those tough days you
know setting healthy boundaries at work
as well uh sometimes
it's not easy you know current a recent
survey that was done uh measuring that
about 47 of security uh admins and
operations folks you know working over
40 hours a week up into the 90 hour
range so um and
with the
cyber damages and the incentive that
these guys have that these folks have to
actually do this you know to actually do
uh damage into an environment you know
that threat is just going to continue to
increase you know and also just
understanding you know what you need to
do to recover whether even a micro dose
of recovery and obviously sleep as well
so with that i've got a few resources
that i've added into the deck itself
and that you can check off a check up
offline and that is it so i thank you
for your time thank you for your
attention and
open to any questions as well if you
haven't
okay thank you
any questions
so i have one question so how does this
align with the six store right so the
framework that you mentioned the
architecture uh so
do you see any synergies there
uh as of right now it's they're separate
but it's something that we need to also
look at and investigate uh because there
are some similarities there when it
comes to having a ledger and ensuring
that you've got you know your your
trusted your root of trust uh but as of
right now those are those two are
separate
any other question
yeah thanks thanks victor thank you very
much everyone appreciate it