hello everyone thanks for joining this
cloud native security conference session
my name is kailan ching i'm a cloud
software engineer at intel
with a focus on security and
confidential computing
my topic today is towards the hardened
cloud native cornerstone
container runtime protection from
security to privacy
i'd like to hereby thankfully tremendous
help received from my teammates while
building these contents
so firstly let's jump into the question
about our main character today
the cloud native cornerstone container
how secure it is
we may not have a direct answer right
away
but let's take a look at the container
security
from different views
let's start with the container security
risks from users view
here is the chart from a white paper of
tencent cloud in 2021
which illustrates the container security
risks that users are most concerned
about
in this chart we can find that the
container escape
which is part of the runtime security
together with the image security and
cluster intrusion are the top three
concerns raised by users
however it is really hard to address the
risks before knowing the potential
threats
a systematic analysis of canadian
threats is therefore needed
here we present the threat model which
was given by open web application
security project lwasp on docker
in 2019
the threads of containers have been
categorized into six aspects according
to owasp
kernel exploits container outbreak
denial of service
and network threats
also possible poison images and
compromising secrets
it's easy to understand that most of
these threats are happening or can
eventually lead to security risks
at the wrong time of containers
in fact the threat model of containers
can be further extended in several ways
to complete the owsp threat model
first the end-to-end flow of containers
should be considered including the cncd
phases
as well as the code and image management
where supply chain kind of attacks can
happen
secondly a stride analysis can be
applied
to more fine-graded layers of containers
where we should be able to understand
when and how spoofing tempering
repudiation and information disclosure
and so on can occur in which layer
moreover with the evolution of attacks
and varied user scenarios we should take
stronger security targets and more
advanced attacker assumptions into our
account
with this extended continuous threat
modeling
then let's take another look from an
attacker's view
how does the running container look like
in their eyes
a container can run in a vm or directly
on top of the bare metal depending on
the deployment schemes
while in this diagram there are a host
of attack vectors
for instance
vulnerable code exploits
can occur in almost everywhere the code
runs
in addition
bad and uncompliant configurations
can expose a large attack surface
also the running containers can be
connected with insecure networking
besides
containers can be using compromised
images leaking secrets and escaping from
their security boundaries
it's also worth mentioning that in some
scenarios
even the hosts i mean the hosts kernels
and os's themselves can be malicious
so with these attack surface
surfaces exposed
we are able to summarize the possible
attack paths or scenarios of containers
so firstly
the first attack scenario is the intro
container attack
where the user's applications can be
attacked by the language runtime or
libraries running within the same
container
the second attack scenario is called
intercontainer attack where containers
are able to attack each other
the third one is called container to
host and host to container attack
this is one of the most common attack
scenarios
well the fourth attack is called
container to container wrong time or
sometimes container engine attack
the fifth one is host to runtime attack
and finally we have the last one we call
it cluster or cloud attack
where attacks can be launched through
cross-host networks
after having a thorough analysis of our
enemies the next question is
how can we defend against all these
threats
so let's try to put a shield on the
containers
one first attempt is to apply the best
practices of container hardening
such as using secure mapping following
mutable paradigm and so on as suggested
by owasp
this best practice
can help avoid at least
or at least mitigate several types of
container threats
a second short can be given by fully
leveraging the container security
features
that we have so far in the container
ecosystem
the security features include the ones
applied to the images
cluster environments
demand and the core components of
containers
and to the containers themselves
let's revisit here the software-based
security features
of containers themselves for example
we have c groups and namespacing the
kernel space which are the foundations
of containers
beyond these two there are also
capability mechanisms
and cisco restriction mechanisms like
sitcom
in addition mandatory access controls
mac
can be enabled by linux security modules
lsm
it's also containing uid and gid
management and usernamespace remap etc
we can build up a more security hardened
container
what else can we try
in production runtime security detection
which monitors and reports out abnormal
container behaviors such as high-risk
systems and file tempering is usually
deployed in production
a series of vulnerability mitigations in
kernel and applications
can be utilized in parallel
note that image scanning and encryption
are two practical enhancements for
images to help raise the security bar
it's worth highlighting that
hardware-based container security
techniques
like virtualized secure containers are
regarded as very helpful
for defending against the container
escape
and for world looking trusty execution
environment-based confidential
containers appealing to address the
privacy concerns
which will talk about them further later
in this
talk with all this black magic
our container is free from security
threats today
unfortunately the answer might be a
little bit annoying and disappointing
but the truth is that the containers are
far from secure
one of the first reasons is that through
even though designed almost perfectly
but we lack security feature deployment
in real production environment
this can be due to their high energy
barrier low roi and stability concerns
and so on
the investigation from tension cloud
found out that there are still seven
percent of users are still running
without any security capabilities
which can be very terrible
furthermore some advanced security
capabilities that we introduced just now
are not yet a use
to tackle with the advanced exploits
besides the shortage of deployment
another important fact that cannot be
ignored is that the weaknesses are still
across every layer
the kernel layer
the container layer and the
orchestration layer
even in this year or the past 2021 cves
that can lead to container escape and
privilege exclamation still come up very
very frequently in the kernel layer and
the container layer
the content layer where the core
container components like docker
container d and run c are lying in
are still facing a huge number of
vulnerabilities
not only the container escape privilege
escalation but also in the command
execution their mounts and configs
even the
virtualized secure containers like kata
containers which were thought to be more
secure are found to be not immune from
some advanced hacks
well in short
the container on time security is yet
another canon mouse game
let's then deep dive into what are the
recent advances of defense security
techniques in the container world in
response to the varied requirements and
advanced attacks
in real world
inoculates and trusted process can
sometimes become malicious during its
lifetime because of bugs have been
exploited by attackers or just triggered
by or used misused by users
a series of sandboxing mechanical
mechanisms are therefore invented to
help isolate a software component from
the rest of the system
in this picture we are comparing
different sandboxing mechanisms
and we will introduce today a recently
one called landlock which has some
advantages in performance fine grain
control embedded policy and unprivileged
use
different from
a mandatory access control mac provided
by linux security module lsm in kernel
then log is the first mac available to
unprivileged processes on learning syncs
513.
landlord is such a sandboxing technique
to restrict ambient rights according to
the kernel semantic for example global
file system accesses a set of processes
to complete the limitations of the
c-comp
it also helps create a safe security
sandboxes as new security layers
in addition to the existing system-wide
access controls
so with landlock we are
also able to compose success controls
from multiple tenants for example system
domains app developers and cloud clients
it's a really interesting technique to
enable built-in application sandboxing
to protect against explorable
in trusted applications via embedded
policy
or directly against untrusted
applications
via sandboxes or container managers
the container on time is such a case
that can benefit from landlock a lot
equipping containers with landlocked is
an ongoing effort happening in the wrong
time spec and the wrong c communities
here in this diagram we are
demonstrating the schema in the runtime
spec where users can specify the lan
lock unprivileged set
access control settings for the
container process
the users firstly need to identify a set
of rules and define them as a rule set
so in general the rule set is basically
the actions or objects that need to be
handled or restricted
next the rules field specifies the
security policies to be added to
existing rule set
and pass beneath is the only supported
currently
which is an array of
the file hierarchy type rules
in each rule
users can specify a fine-grained
approach of the file's hierarchies to
restrict and the actions are allowed for
each one
a best effort control is also provided
to help the runtime enforce the
strongest rules configured up to the
kernel which is currently supported
in general unpredicted sandboxing can be
enabled through this approach
then let's take a look at an advanced
attack called crossht attack
ht here stands for hyper threading or
hyperthreads
a cross-hd attack
involves the attacker and the victim
running on different types of threats of
the same core
mds and l1tf are examples
of such attacks where an attacker is
able to steal secrets from another
co-located
hyperthread
through some set channels
the only full mitigation of cross ht
attacks is to disable ht
which is considered to be extremely
inefficient
cross scheduling since linux 514 is a
scheduler feature that can mitigate some
but not all cross hd attacks
it allows http to be enabled or turned
on safely by ensuring that only tasks in
a user designated untrusted group can
share a call
this increase in core sharing can also
improve performance however it is not
guaranteed that the performance will
always improve
so that is seen to be the case with the
number of real-world workloads
but in theory
cost scheduling aims to perform at least
as good as when have us writing is
disabled
the basic concept of course scheduling
is to allow user space to define groups
of tasks and can share a core
from this diagram here
we can observe that some tasks are
grouped together
the grouped tasks are holding the same
so-called task cookies
tasks from the same group
for example t1 and t5 can be scheduled
on the same core
there are two other rules the first one
is that never mixing on the same core
tasks from different groups
for instance t6 and t7 on the right of
the diagram will never be scheduled onto
the same floor
another one is to never mix on the same
call the tasks that one is grouped and
another one
which is not or ungrouped
some cpu threads may stay idle even if
run queue is not empty
in this diagram we can find that ta and
t9 are in this case
know that co-scheduling can also help
with some performance use cases but we
will not elaborate them here in this
topic
enhancing containers with core
scheduling support
is also raised in the runtime spec and
around c communities
in this schema users are allowed to
configure the course scheduling options
for the container
by coursegate users are allowed to
define the following operations
the create
field can choose whether to create a new
unique cookie
for the process in the container
the share to field specified the pids
that
the course get cookie of the current
process should push to
and share form specifies the pids that
the calls get copied of the current
process should prove from
all these provide support for setting
and copying cost scheduling task cookies
between the container processes
and the threads processes and the
process groups which helps define groups
of tasks that can be co-scheduled onto
the same core according to the basic
concept that we mentioned just now
the hardware software code design is
another merging advance in the container
security enhancement
that is worth introducing here in our
talk
for instance the control flow
enforcement technology
deliver cpu level
level security capabilities to help
protect against quantum malware attacks
and they have been a challenge to
mitigate with software alone
cet offers
two key capabilities to help define
against control flow hijacking malware
here we can find these two technologies
the first one is called indirect branch
tracking ibt and the second one is
called shadow stack
we call it ss
you can see from the left left part that
the ibt delivers indirect branch
protection to defend against jump or
core oriented programming we often call
them gop or copy attacks
you can see from the picture
that ibt will prevent attacks from
jumping to arbitrary addresses
and the ss technology on the right
delivers the return address protection
to help defend against return-oriented
programming we often call them rope
attacks
in this picture we notice that ss will
block call if return addresses on both
sets don't match
these types of attack methods are part
of a class of malware referred to as
memory safety issues
and include tactics
such as the corruption of step buffer
overflow and use after free
there may be widely used techniques in
large classes of vulnerable
exploits in the container world
and most recently data breaches have
been
increasing which is constantly suffering
enterprises
and regulators and customers
for containers
which are the de facto vehicles carrying
a variety of workloads today
are facing rising concerns about the
privacy or the protection of
confidential
code and data within them apart from the
security concerns
the consequently the augmented threat
model has come into being in this
context
different from the original threat model
which considers the host to be benign
and includes the host software stack
into the trusted computing base tcb
the intention of this thread model is to
prevent the whole software stack from
accessing container data and code while
in use
a new technology called confidential
computing makes it all possible to
provide isolation runtime encryption and
verifiability at the same time to fill
in this blank
with confidential computing we are able
to completely remove the whole software
stack from the container tcb
this includes the host software
which are
host firmware kernel os hypervisor which
are all out of the tcb and only the
tenant can see and modify its data
we can see that infrastructure owner
sometimes this csp cloud service
providers themselves are not even
trusted in this case
now with additional support in the
container runtime
a two-way sandbox for seamless security
and privacy we call them confidential
containers can be constructed based on
hardware based trusted execution
environment
there are in general two types of
confidential containers we can see
them in this diagram
the first one is called process based
and the second one is called vm-based
the process-based confidential
containers can be built on top of intel
sgx for example
process-based isolation is beneficial by
joining the isolation boundary exactly
around each container process
and this reduces the trusted computing
base
to some extent
in contrast the vm-based confidential
containers can be more straightforward
with the hardware will augment directly
the vm-based secure containers for
example cutter containers to guarantee
confidentiality and integrity based on
that
additionally image management and the
test station services should be provided
to firstly ensure that the container
image is always encrypted or signed
i mean the container images should be
protected in some
cases
and their post processing
is also need to be
protected
and secondly the ability to test the
confidential containers
which run on top of genuine and trusted
hardware should be guaranteed and the
workload is exactly expected
here we are unable to dive into every
single detail of the potential gaps that
the original containers need to fill in
but we list a few of them from a bird's
eye view
firstly confidential container runtimes
need to
adapt to different hardware based
encryption
they should also support attestation key
provisioning and the secure agent apis
which are
strictly limited to confidential
containers
also for confidential container images
the image service offloading layer
encryption and security context need to
be added to adapt to the confidential
computing usages
for confidential container os is
minimized tcp and unified onclick
abstractions as the top two requirements
we should also know that confidential
container orchestration and monitoring
especially for the logging debugging
error management and potential migration
vci guarantees
should also be considered by the
confidential containers
you may have the ambition to achieve a
further stronger strain model
yes indeed it should be possible
ultimately
imagine we'd like to extend an intro
container with more fine-grained
isolation
in this case for example we'd like to
only consider the sensitive data
compartment within this container and
the hardware it runs on to be trusted
where with all the others including the
libraries and references by the comp
department can be malicious
actually multiple fine-grained isolation
techniques are already available
to help this dream come true
they often have different execution of
switching overheads
so one of the
challenges here is to balance between
security and performance for different
container workloads
one example is to integrate or combine
the memory protection keys as known as
mpk with containers
this mpk is able to tag memory pages
within the containers using p keys
within
a permission register called pkru
which is provided to allow the user
space instruction to update pkru so that
letting the hardware to enforce the
isolation between the compartments
within the containers
well i think we might be
getting the right feeling that advances
of container security will never stop
just as new attack measures will
continue to emerge
the future of container security still
has a lot to explore and it's worth
checking out
that's all for my talk thanks for
listening any questions