okay so next up we have connor rogers
and ryan gibbons and they're going to be
talking about cncf best practices for
software supply chain
thank you hello everybody
um
it's great to be here at the cncf
conference um my name is connor rogers
i'm a technology leader with celegent
systems
uh
we're a branch of emphasis
and we're an aws
consultancy partner and
i'm lucky enough to have gotten the
opportunity to work with ryan after 25
years in old school configuration
management build management
release management technical management
lean
agile all this kind of stuff i get the
opportunity to work with a security team
and 3m of which ryan is a senior leader
right ryan gibbons um it's great to work
with conor we have a lot of fun together
you'll see that while we talk today i'm
part of the 3m digital science community
so 3m is yes they make the post-it notes
and all the things you're used to but we
also have a technology kind of incubator
here in in dublin while i'm in spain now
but
um i started as a developer many years
ago and
then spent
a lifetime in information security so
when they said hey
security's starting to shift left back
in development i said sign me up so we
have a lot of fun together and we're
going to tell a little bit of story that
started a couple years ago on on how our
journey has progressed along this whole
paradigm of shifting security left and
we'll get into that in a little bit but
first can i find out just what how the
audience is distributed technical or
more like program so how many folks
primarily spend their time working on
technical problems show of hands
okay and how many are more like on the
projects and programs than the resources
okay so mostly technical but scattering
a few okay thank you
okay so here's here's the situation
framing it not particularly for 3m but
just in general um they're shifting left
again and i always like to say this is
guys this is shifting left this is not
dumping left this is not a push this
should be a pole right we will need to
give developers the tools and
the capabilities and the training and
everything else they need so we can move
this responsibly and not just have audit
and compliance go hey developers you do
all the stuff now
there's a huge lack of awareness in the
software supply chain
right we've been doing
manifests and things for many many years
but some people are still kind of new to
some of these things so that's okay
we've got um there's limited guidance
it's been getting better over the last
couple years but when we started this
journey a couple years ago it was kind
of sparse you could read some dod
documents and this had some things they
were really focused on kind of
traditional sdlc type of things but but
not necessarily the tool chain so so
there were some problems um solarwinds
raised awareness quite a bit is
everybody here i'm sure
is aware salsa from google also helped
quite a bit
and uh to do this we started as i
mentioned before
big company 3m very diverse technical
environment so a little bit challenging
lots of different groups
oh and one other thing i want to mention
here and then yeah so on the security
integration little circle we have there
um we had a lot of coverage in in the
whole operate right so that's the
traditional space where the stuff runs
and in the plans they had all these risk
things you had to go through and and
architecture reviews and everything else
but as soon as it goes to build it was
like just scan your code
and that seemed really it's right that's
right um i come from lean background
release management devops better faster
cheaper better faster cheaper let's go
faster less get us out there shorter
increments
and oftentimes in my career
devops was conflicted against legacy
style security organizations
the department of no but no
ryan's focus here is improve
the security posture of the applicant
application code delivery and what that
means is not being the department of no
it means
being department of collaboration okay
and first time ever i got to work in a
devops agile way with the security team
that builds solutions okay we like this
yeah yeah that makes it so much more fun
we get to be the builders not the no
people
so
how this worked at uh 3m we really we
knew we're kind of introducing an
entirely new category of of
considerations for senior executive
leadership
so i had to be able to tell this as a
story i had to capture their imagination
i had to get them bought into that this
is a thing and we're going to need to
spend time and prioritize the resources
away from just delivering stuff to
making sure how we deliver it is secure
so 3m knows supply chains they're very
good at this stuff they've seen some
briefings from how they do it they're
fantastic
so i just needed to leverage what i
already had and of course everything in
here you have to adapt to your own
organizations but for us it was okay
they understand supply chains so
i actually use this image when cncf
released it but i had an earlier version
of this which wasn't as good you guys
know supply chain so you have materials
and you build the thing then you have to
deliver it to your store and then it
gets consumed
software is the same way this is new for
them because they're they don't didn't
know software quite as well software you
have components and code and you bring
them in and you have to compile them
together in a pipeline and then you you
know you put it into an operating
environment it's kind of like sending it
to a store so i had to use what they
understood and put it in terms that they
get and i knew i was being successful
when i started hearing about this in
other meetings oh yeah there's this team
doing the secure software supply chain
so that's how i kind of captured this
interest that we need to secure our
software supply chain just like you have
physical security controls yeah i'm i'm
an sclc guy i've always been sclc
and you've got to realize everybody must
realize at this stage you know it is a
complete software supply chain and a lot
of the components are coming from the
outside
and a picture tells a thousand words
what ryan isn't telling you here is how
diverse our organization is and how many
different stlcs we have
how many different approaches and we've
got some legacy and we've got some very
very contemporary innovative approaches
as well
and the executives
that ryan has to deal with
are many and diverse and they don't
often have a lot of time to
read the big document or take it in so a
picture tells a thousand words and
that's part of you know our knowledge
um
propagation upwards but also downwards
and that's very important in the space
that we play in yeah we had to we had to
make sure that this story was going both
up and down and so we actually had
different versions of how we would
message it depending on who our audience
was very important and we enhanced that
with the data that we had so
i mean
what is
um the critical security control number
one what's number one
you might know this one
what 20 critical controls used to be
called yeah
nope not firewalls good one
what's that
users
the user is very important to
i mean these are kind of in in all those
things but
most of
um what they teach you and the
the critical security controls is you
start with an inventory because you
can't protect what you don't know and
then you have to know both in hardware
and software inventory and then you kind
of go along
so we're like well let's follow the same
pattern i mean we're doing as a security
piece let's follow the best practices so
step number one how much code do we have
and how many components do we have in
our environment and how many build
pipelines and how many code repositories
and how many like let's let's just
identify all that
and to make it fun we kind of went to a
lot of the tech leaders and said how
much do you think you have how much how
much do you think you have how many code
repositories do you have how many
yeah so i really like this rhine leads
with vision okay but up above vision you
need something you need so many
principles and standards and that allows
you to be too agnostic okay you bring it
up to what does good look like let's not
worry about what the brand name or the
tool name or the
software utility name is we start up
there at that higher level yeah then we
can work downwards and that was a lot of
fun and so then at the end we kind of
showed how much
how many different types of technology
and how much code each group had against
each other it's nice to have kind of
healthy visibility i'll say not
necessarily competition but just like so
you have this much this person has this
much you thought you had a lot look at
this guy right and so having an
organization lover that makes him sit up
and pay attention oh how am i doing
against the people i'm having to compete
for resources with so we kind of got
into that conversation and then they
started using
what us and what we found as
part of the conversation so you can lead
with your threats and say this is the
current news this is the current hack
what's your exposure what's the
probability of that happening so you
have to have visibility and discovery of
your inventory your source code level at
your build level at your orchestrator
level at your deployment level god knows
the old uh cmdb yeah you know where has
it gone to
okay where is it on our outside and
indeed all of our internal tools are
critically important as well because
that's where the software supply chains
attacks are coming they're not coming on
your perimeter they're going inside and
they hit much more when they get out
yeah and that helps us to tie it to risk
so
um and we we built some reputation too
so where did we start
so on our team just a little bit of
context so i set the kind of general
scale but just for us we already had a
application security program we'd been
running for a while we kind of started a
new one we called it the code security
team because we don't deal so much with
the runtime environment we're just we're
all the way until you build it and then
once it's built and we secure the tool
chain and all the tests you know then
other teams are so we kind of carved our
little niche um
we'd already been
we had some resources some people we'd
already been looking at some of the best
practices so so that's kind of where we
were we weren't just starting out when
this document came so just a little bit
of context
from from where our journey goes in here
you'll see that you know we'd already
kind of started and we'll talk about
yeah so we came here to tell you a
little bit more about our story and how
the cncf helped us
and that's really the message that we're
here to give you is that there's a
really good artifact that people should
look at and read
and how
it came to us and how we were able to
leverage that yeah and how we were able
to communicate that to our organization
and we always use so while we're on this
journey so
we had started solarwinds came out and
really advanced the conversation and it
went from
my my boss and boss's boss saying so
what are you guys doing out there
exactly how does this relate to
so-and-so and then then it was like oh
solar winds right so now i was on the
table which is nice
um and then a year later we've got log
for j and everybody's like hey can you
guys come help so we've made a lot of
progress in the last year so there's
some cultural messages here as well so
ryan is a great culture leader he's got
a security vision he also has a good
security team but underneath that if
you're building solutions you've got to
have some good technologists okay so
we want to build cloud native technology
solutions that are enterprise available
for a vast enterprise so
good vision good strategy good culture
we're lean we're agile
and we got some good technologists to
put that kind of technology in
underneath the security best practices
not everybody is a security expert we
all can't be security experts
not everybody can be a full stack
engineer but we have to have some
specialists to put some meat on the bone
so we had had good people on the team
and a good good partnership and we
actually started this was our strategy
before the cncf best practices document
came out so this is we're going to show
you before and after because we um first
it was nice because it mapped pretty
well and second we made some
improvements so
we wanted to release these capabilities
so we talked about before shifting
security left is not dumping everything
on developers we wanted to build
capabilities that help developers to be
able to handle these new demands that
compliance and everybody else is putting
on them so we approached hey we're your
partners we're going to help you protect
the code in the code repositories we're
going to help you make sure you're
getting the right licenses we're going
to make sure you've got clean components
and have tools and capabilities and
repositories like we just heard from to
do that um we're gonna make sure that
the scans are done and that they're easy
and then and then get a little fuzzy at
the end we're like yeah and build
pipelines we didn't have a lot of
thoughts there yet because we were kind
of just starting that but but that we
knew that that was gonna be a big focus
we had some resources assigned to it so
this was our starting place it was great
and
it was early 2021 i started working with
ryan
he started talking to me about a
strategy and this is so appealing to me
okay it's simple and it covers a lot of
my career actually today you know but
it's very much a capability view at this
point and what are we going to do
protect our source code do some sca
scanning do some credentials discovery
use good components and then out here we
got
this big piece of securing the pipelines
yeah which we didn't have well defined
we're doing some basic things and we'll
talk about that a little bit and we were
just calling it securing our
applications
that's right that's right yeah
so picture tells a thousand words
okay devsecops what's devsecops what
does it mean across the sdlc and for me
you know it was always
can we get the code
from here to the customer as quickly as
possible was it a waterfall and then we
go agile now we can do this faster and
then in the new world okay we're taking
in these components we were always
taking customer off the shelf component
but now there's huge amounts of osf and
the attacks are coming the whole way
along here
i'm saying ryan you know ryan
you know if we're going to protect the
front door we've got to stop the stuff
coming in at the back door let's protect
our ingestion boundaries so i drew this
picture and i tried to make it
principles and standards based
and agnostic
and agnostic and we needed a map to have
these conversations because we jump in
and go okay remember this part in the
pipeline we need to start talking about
that and people would just like have the
people in the room just check out okay
let's build the map um we'll get input
from other people and uh didn't get as
much input as we thought they were just
like yeah okay that's i mean we could we
can have conversations here you've got
some major processes we didn't want to
make it too detailed and we didn't make
want to make it too high level so we
tried to find the right way that we knew
how to talk about where to put the
security pieces so
we found we developed we found we could
we could talk to the waterfall guys we
could talk to the agile guys you can
actually fit a container pipeline in
here yeah which we have yeah so this was
our our map and we have our security
services across the top this is how
we're trying to communicate to people
well how we fit in to the work that
they're doing so this was our starting
point
and then
well you know so we were discussing all
this and we're just about to launch two
of the processes
and
well joe biden uh his executive cyber
security order we better go and have a
good look at this
and i think everybody probably knows
broadly what's in there you know protect
the federal government protect the
infrastructure there's a big section in
it called secure software supply chains
and this is in response to solar winds
um
and of course then it's the s-bomb the
s-bomb i've been doing builds and
materials for a long time generally
they're in your make file or your
manifest
do you check on the other end and do you
a test do you verify so this is a
standard space desk bomb okay one that's
transferable and interchangeable and
this gave us some leverage because 3m
does a lot of business with the federal
government and other defense departments
and stuff and we're saying guys they're
taking this very seriously we need to
make sure we're staying ahead of the
game because you never want to be caught
behind where they're like i need this by
next month and you're like well we don't
do that yet
so we need to make sure we deliver
whatever it is that they look like
they're going to ask for it and i'm like
oh hey we've already got plans for these
things yeah absolutely um it's i'm not a
security guy at that stage well i am but
i think everybody should be a security
guy i think everybody should be a devops
guy it's not that guy over there is full
we're all in this game together
and it's resonating with me
and we're going
hang on we've been trying to get ahead
of this game and they're talking about
what happens next
this well two days later
two days later this wonderful document
drops from the cncf
and i'm doing my normal examination of
what's new in the world of hacking and
software supply chains the document
comes out it is a wonderful document
i read it i said to ryan i said ryan you
know we're not that far off you know
we got to put some more meat in the bone
but look what we're just after getting
here from the cncf document so
recommended reading for everybody in the
room
so what is it about and for me it's
about
principles and standards at the high
level there's really good governance
there's really good principles about
your risk environments your risk
appetite but general principles of trust
trust at every stage
and every job in the pipeline so
attestation and verification
it's high on that it's also high on
automation better faster cheaper better
faster cheaper no no
better faster cheaper and more secure
okay so that you have consistency
the investment in automation
is paid back later because you have
consistency less effort it's automated
clarity at every stage know where it
happens control that environment
build nodes as we heard earlier on
hardening your pipelines
you must be able to reproduce the build
at any time and anybody else who needs
to do it
people think often you know oh we'll
move the source code system from here to
here yeah we'll just lift and shift it
no you've got to bring the pipelines the
processes and all the builds with them
which means okay bit for bit by bite
your artifact at the end has to be the
same before and after that migration so
clarity is really important
and then of course the mfa mutual
authentication
every step of the way everybody needs to
be authorized and accessed and certified
so
that's critical okay
so what does the document actually have
in it
and lo and behold it breaks down the
software supply chain
securing your source code protect your
code at rest
okay so there's 22 good principles in
there that everybody should be looking
at
how to secure the integrity of your code
your access to your code the integrity
of your environments and there's some
pretty high bars that you would have to
meet
signing your source code with gpg and
mime keys
it's difficult for some systems to
achieve
yeah and and also in these controls that
each of the sections have or each of the
the statements or requirements there's
different levels what would you do if
you're just trying to low and this is
kind of like for public people public
repositories for medium
or moderate levels which would be more
like internal system confidential types
of things and then high which would be
missile systems air traffic control
banking phi data
okay and some of these are high bar to
achieve and when you assess that you
look at it and don't forget all the
branch protections and all those
configuration source code management 101
stuff it's all there but called out and
clear principles to remind us
next action is securing the materials so
you have your source code
and you have all your materials where
your materials come from okay so a lot
of oss and probably some cuts off the
shelf tools as well
okay so attestation sca analysis s-bombs
from your vendors
and again verification automation all
the way through some really good
practices there i think 33.
um when you get down into securing your
build pipelines
that's a great section of the document
everybody should read it on the
presentation earlier on uh securing your
build pipelines with kubernetes and
techton yeah i think they're hitting a
lot of the battles there but that you
know what we're talking about is
immutable pipelines okay so that nobody
can get in the administrator is not
getting in there and changing it on the
fly we don't want any snowflakes and we
want to have build workers that are
reproducible continuously typically now
in a container that you can spin it up
and it is
certified as well so in total is big
here big recommendation
very high bar to reach but we're going
hang on let's not let perfect get in the
way better okay it's a journey we're on
this journey three amazon this journey
digital transformation is a journey
we have to go there but don't be put off
by some of that really high level stuff
measure your risk appetite to where you
are well that's part of how we'd
recommend using this is find the ones
that work for your organization you
don't want it to be too far of a reach
you also don't want to make it too easy
so we spent a lot of time like a
moderate plus maybe this one in this one
or you know security artifacts at the
end of the build okay so you got your
build you got your manufacturer put it
in a repo okay put a checksum on it put
a hash on it promote it to your qa
environments make sure that it's the
same one with the same license and all
the same code in it that your team
actually
released promote that through your
environment do your unit test system
test integration test performance test
all your tests when you're ready to go
you might bring it closer to a target
environment
that's where it should come from just
your cd is taking it and putting it out
there and then the last piece the cd
okay make sure and we've spoken already
today about the tuf framework it's big
on the tuf framework there so
attestation
verification
clarity trust every step in the way and
then
least privilege and separation of duties
and reproducibility and automation
this is goldust this document
okay very good so conor what did you do
when the document came out well i had to
read it a few times
and actually
i read it a couple of times since i left
dublin we're both in dublin here at the
moment and this is lightroom every time
i read it i was really not i get i get a
new one and it's just going i have to
think about that again you know what are
we going to do so what do we do
but you broke it out i did i parsed it
out into clauses and i put the clauses
into categories and he's like ryan check
this out i've got this whole thing in a
big spreadsheet for you i'm like
yeah absolutely and then ryan goes
well that's amazing and that's good but
hang on how are we going to make this
work for 3m yeah because 3m has its own
culture and its own vernacular right
okay and we got to translate that into
the words people commonly use
book we had a framework okay so
it gave us a good reference it told us
where we were weak told us where we were
strong it told us some bits that we
hadn't covered
so and then we took we took those
phrases those different pieces we
simplified the language a little bit to
make it more consumable
and then we went we we kind of put it in
the controls list and i'm like i've done
this before i've done this looks like a
controls framework so i put it on the
bottom you see i put control objectives
and numberings on there and who's the
owner and evidence required and
everything else we just start filling it
out like this and and it was quite
enlightening as we went through we
started seeing a lot of patterns and
and we had some great discussions when
we came up with what evidence what would
we expect someone to give us if they
were going to meet this control and
these would be this would be targeted
more for the tool chain owners and less
towards the application owners right
so
absolutely and then you know audit
control policy these are big hammers
that you can bring into an organization
but we're a team that likes solutions
yeah okay
we do not want to leave how good are our
current solutions
uh how do they measure up against this
yeah you know
which ones how do these different tool
sets measure up against each other
because we would like to converge but
not necessarily be completely rigid and
and how not to make friends is to come
in with this real hard requirement that
there's no tool to be able to do yet and
say go figure it out right that's a
terrible position but yeah your baby is
ugly yeah don't do that we're like let's
let's find out what we can do and then
we're going to work with the tool owners
and we come to them and we're going to
say
our job right now is to make you the
gold standard for the company we're
going to try to get you up to that level
so so work with us for a few months
we're going to do an assessment of your
tool find out where we're deficient see
if we can get some items on the backlog
and see if we can get these things fixed
for the different tools that are
supporting this out there and the
natural way that conversation worked is
after they saw that initial pass they're
either oh yeah okay well that's doable
we can we can fix those things and we'll
secure this pipeline or
yeah our technology we just can't do
that
we're going to decommission this and
move to some one of the more modern ones
which is great i didn't have to be the
bad guy we're just like hey yeah they'll
admit to it you know but respectful
conversations transparent conversations
collaboration partnership really
important but we do come in with the
know-how and the show how the show has
how do you actually prove that you uh
rotate your keys yeah you know so here's
a couple examples of how we do this and
we can get into more detail if we if
people want to get it have questions
later but here's two of them i just
pulled out
one's a little fudged because i why
first i had to get this through legal
review and second i didn't have a lot of
screen space i wouldn't just put this
together so first one would be securing
your source code so are you doing secret
scanning or preventing secrets from
getting in well secrets preventing um
false positives cause problems and we're
still working on the prevention part but
we said for right now let's just make
sure we've got scanning
make sure that it's um measuring stuff
that's on and that developers are
getting these findings and it's going to
the vulnerability team too so they can
help track that that's where we want to
be for right now
um the lucky person who's the owner
would be the owner of the github or tfs
or whatever technology was doing this
and we would make sure the secret
scanner is working so i can report on
their stewardship of that technology
yeah and we're not bringing somebody
like to shine the lights into their eyes
you know we're saying
tell us how we can help you improve this
should you be doing that or is this a
service we should provide you so you can
do this right that's the approach so
second one securing materials software
composition analysis those are like your
black ducks and some types and other
things
you can either integrate black duck or
whatever tool into your pipeline and
make sure that scans happening every
time
or you just have to get your stuff like
they just mentioned from artifactory or
nexus that's already been wrapped and
approved and nothing gets in unless it's
approved and so as long as you're
pulling your stuff from that then you
meet this control so this is kind of the
approach that we took on how we get the
evidence and it depends on you know
obviously this is subdivided and there's
multiple a little bit more complicated
but the other groups don't need to see
that they just need to know we've got it
organized and it's by a person who can
actually make it also you also
interleave some of that with some
standard controls that we actually have
for logging and monitoring and
everything we also had to
move some pieces around a little bit
because we had a two year strategy and
we didn't want to go ah no it's
what we had we wanted to tin our
strategy at the top
and then have those capabilities
underneath so
for example uh
das scanning we can put that scanning
into merge clean components okay or
possibly in the qa
however sca we put it there and also
yeah i think ryan
um the building artifacts the storing
the artifacts and clean deployments
that's a lot to take in for somebody so
we crushed that into yeah
we'll talk about that in just a sec in
fact maybe i'll skip to it now
so we
i'll skip to the strategy and we'll talk
about how it helped but we took the
structure that they had and kind of used
it to simplify so
um you know secure build and deploy
became we kind of merged a couple of
those in and and now we have definitions
behind all of it like i know how to
assess people against those different
things that's your software build
materials certified build pipeline
certified delivery mechanisms all those
things and we just simplified the
strategy in general because
you know license and components were
kind of
you know they merged it in the
in the the
best practices document like oh yeah
that makes a lot of sense so it helped
us to simplify our message we aligned it
with the best practices document and and
this is really easy to communicate to
executives i can go in and say here's
what a software secure software supply
chain looks like you have these pieces
by the way here's our strategy you
implement this and you have a secure
software supply chain and they just go
boom
great what do you need i mean it's a
much easier conversation it is they they
ask us to come there because something
like log4j happens and it's so nice when
you've got this plan and i know how much
the time it's going to take
we we didn't get into this but we can
talk about um you know resources and
roi for this and the costs we've had
together
ryan deeply understands how to get that
message up there what does value mean
security costs
okay but it also reduces costs okay if
you have automated security you can
prove reduced costs
your ci your cfo may not understand stlc
and the secure software supply chain but
he can understand our supply chain and
he can understand cost reduction and
effort yeah and that's a big one so with
this one thing i found really really
helpful is to actually get good
estimates on how much time it would take
to do this manually or how much time it
would be if you can automate this and i
we actually put that into hours and we
deliver that monthly and it was really
painful at the beginning but as you do
anything you iterate on it you get
better at it and better at it so now i
can sew every month both legacy projects
we kind of get a residual because it
still helps those but any new project
that comes in i'm like if you were to do
this manually would have taken you this
long our tools do it in this much time
right it's automated and the cfos love
that kind of stuff because they're like
well i can spend money because i see my
roi here and it's it's legitimate they
have to do it either way you might as
well do it the fast easy automated way
and we're helping you do that absolutely
and remember i mentioned the old style
cmdb
that was fine when you had 20 servers
but now we've got containers with very
short life cycles so this dynamic
inventory of where is it where has it
gone to how did it get there if you have
your operations teams continue trying to
figure out what's out there and they
don't know because there's been no trail
back no audit trail
no release note with the s-bomb where
did it go to
that's your cost saving right there
so we've talked about how we only have a
couple minutes left we've talked about
how it really helped having this best
practices document come and reinforce
our strategy and how we could leverage
an industry standard and we were talking
to all these tool owners and i mean it
was just really nice in that perspective
um but i just want to end with this yeah
so
here's some advice some lessons learned
along the way
we did not do everything right in fact i
bet some of the stuff we're doing now is
wrong so if you have ideas we'd love to
hear from them
um we just we learn and we fail and we
do better next time but
we're open and transparent right we're
open on transparent we like making new
mistakes that's right don't make the
same mistakes
create these alliances a partnership
like we're never trying to embarrass
teams we always want to give people
plenty of time before the results are
published
um before anything comes to you know so
we always work with the groups trying to
get things up before
other people find out about it and
absolutely we we don't want to crush
them into a corner and we want people to
be open with us so we're very respectful
we understand their problems from a
security perspective and from a
development perspective but we want them
to acknowledgement as the first part of
that journey yeah and we've made lots of
friends along the way i mean it's this
is ultimately i'm convinced a culture
change it's a culture change for how
developers do their work in a lot of
cases for how managers prioritize the
work and for how people pay for software
i mean there was a paradigm especially
in some of the acquisitions where it's
like hey we're just going to do
um you know we're going to do things
really agile we're going to use all free
software and it's going to be super
cheap and we don't have to pay for
licenses that way we could just be fast
and we're like um
okay well show me how you meet these
requirements with this thing you've
cobbled together over a weekend
and so if you're gonna meet all these
security requirements it's better to use
on one of the items on what we call the
paved road right if you use this
technology and this component management
and this pipeline and these things we
will do your
compliance stuff for you because it's
all already automated if you do it by
yourself i'm gonna need all these
deliverables all this evidence to show
me that you're doing it and so it kind
of restricts
um
to people adding risk because they're
doing it on their own way a little bit
and and also gets more engagement in the
big processes because if those aren't
working for them they need to give that
feedback so we can add the features and
so we don't come in with the policy
framework and say no no no this is wrong
we'll come in with a paved road okay we
build solutions and we go how about this
way over here look you know this is the
way it works and guess what leaders lead
those who want to follow we want
everybody to be security they'll come
with us there will be an ugly tale
perhaps but guess what
you know policy will harden as we
improve behind us
and then you know we're making it easier
for developers to do the right thing and
not as ryan says dumping to the left
yeah we're not dumping to the left it's
all about people
um these are professionals they want to
do what's right if you show them the
right way to do it we've found that they
just love it they're very grateful for
hey good thank you for letting me know
exactly what was needed giving me the
tools to do it all right i haven't found
anyone in 3m that's like nah i want to
do things insecure like nobody says that
they're they they say well i'd like to
do that but i'm getting all these
business pressure right so we can give
them some air cover by talking to their
executives and making sure that they've
got the air cover and and also well what
you're asking to do is really really
hard can you help make it easy yeah we
can do that
and if you do that we've found that we
have really great results and it's been
a great journey and conor is legitimate
this guy
he's fantastic it's been a pleasure to
work with him and when he's done helping
us you guys should be lining up at the
door to get
help i just want to say it's a pleasure
to be on the stage here i can talk techy
and he can talk leadership it's a
pleasure to work with him but most
importantly to say thank you to the cncf
yeah great document
[Applause]
i don't know how much time we have if we
have time for questions
or you can
talk to us after it doesn't matter
i could probably get one okay one
question
i guess they're talking after they're
talking to us after then
don't talk too fast connor
ryan comes from utah but he's his inner
irish man is coming out that's it i'm
not even allowed to kiss the blarney
stone because i can just go i was gonna
wear my hat up here anyway thank you
thank you