uh
[Music]
me
all right um yeah good morning everyone
um
very happy to be here um thank you marco
for inviting us
for me this is actually the first in
person conference in uh two years so
with a lockdown and all so it's just um
yeah really nice to be doing something
like this again
um yeah so today we're going to be
talking about guide to cpg
and so this is all about creating graph
queries that you can use to to find
vulnerabilities in binary code
and
yeah i'm presenting today with claudio
who's here
and yeah
nico who also works at our company he
unfortunately is not here today but um
yeah
he did a lot of work um on this as well
so i would just like to mention that
um yeah a few words about
us and about
this talk
so in our day jobs as
marco
already said we work at a startup and
we're building
automatic vulnerability discovery so
we're in static analysis uh meaning um
yeah we we actually uh write programs to
look for bugs in other programs that's
essentially what we do
and um
the uh content that you're going to be
seeing today is kind of a combination of
what we do at our work but also just a
hobby project
and this was a hobby project that
claudio started he thought that it would
be really fun to take apart
some routers that you would find you
know like consumer grade routers stuff
that you would find at home
and so we took a look at the d-link
routers
and turned out to be a pretty juicy
target so there's a lot of stuff in
there and you'll see a lot of that stuff
um as well today
um yeah and it was just a great
opportunity to test out whether our
stuff really works and of course finding
out where it does not work so that we
can
go ahead and improve that
and so today i mean this is a talk
mostly about methodology how would you
approach such a target
but we'll actually also look deeply into
the bugs that we found
as well as um into how we exported them
uh so overall everything that you're
seeing today i mean this is not
commercial stuff this is open source you
can download all of this and you can
play with it
this is very important to us um so it is
um from a technological point of view uh
something that we also um use in in
products um but yeah we have a huge part
of of it that we make available to the
community
and the platform is called yearn
on yearn i o
and the idea is to create a bug
counter's workbench over time so
something that you can use during your
code audit
that will support you in reading your
code
and that will also support you in in
creating exploits for it
um this is actually a quite old project
at this point um it started off in 2013
um it was just me at that point and
yeah it was mainly for research
and the initial idea was to create a
fuzzy parser so that's a parser that's
like very robust
regardless of whether you have a build
environment or not it will somehow
translate into syntax trees and from
there on to control flow graphs and so
on
because i was doing research on like
pattern recognition for vulnerability
discovery and so in that setting you
can't go ahead and configure build
environments for like a thousand debian
packages or something like that um you
know to get your experiments running so
you need something that's a bit more
robust and initially it was that fuzzy
parser um today it's become more of an
interactive programming shell for
vulnerability discovery so you import
code still with robust parsers then it's
available in a graph database and you
have a query language that you can use
to
then explore your code
it's it's based on scala i realize
that's not very uh popular in the
vulnerability research community uh it's
actually a very pretty language i hope
you will agree after the talk and we do
have the ability to script this with
python as well at this point but yeah um
you know scala is cool
just wanna say that anyway at this point
uh we can not only analyze c and c plus
plus uh but also java javascript
and then at some point we went more
towards
byte code analysis so jvm byte code and
lvm bit code
yeah and eventually binary which is what
we're speaking about today
there's a query collection that you can
check out you know just a bunch of
queries to get you started um so that
kind of turns that whole thing into an
automated scanner but i just want to say
i mean we're not really about um at
least in this open source project we're
not about building this um you know
scanner that just gives you the bugs and
that's that it's more about building a
code exploration platform something that
you can actually use during your audits
more in the style of let's say um you
know ida or ghidra or something like
that
unless in the style of a yeah a linter
or automatic scanner
all right um so it works pretty well on
source code
we've seen that in the past so here's
one of those typical queries
here we look for an allocation
and inside that allocation
we perform arithmetic
and
then we look for a mem copy
and we check that that allocated buffer
actually
goes into the first argument of that mem
copy
and then we make sure that
yeah there's a
there
there is
something in the amount that we copy
that's not equal
to that arithmetic expression and so
that is something that uh
yeah leads to heap-based buffer
overflows a lot
and we used this query in 2014
found a buffer overflow in the automatic
updater of vlc
used the query again in 2020 and i found
another one right
same quote more or less
different instance but you can see you
can kind of generalize there and have a
query ready that you can fire
years later and it will return box again
and so then the question is what do we
do if all we have is binary
and we've looked at that question before
so if you've followed our work over the
past years there used to be what's
called bjorn so binary yearn
and that was based on r2
but the experience was not comparable to
what you have with source code
essentially what we did there was we
imported the disassembly and started
writing queries and realized oh wow this
is actually
not you know you can't just take
something for source code and then
import a binary and expect similar kinds
of results and so the main learnings
for us at that point was uh were that uh
well it's it's hard to adapt these
approaches to binary it's not trivial
and the other thing is that uh it's it's
um we actually spent quite a bit of time
before we realized that so it's actually
better if you have a platf if you have a
target available and while you're
building this you're already trying it
out
just a few words about how source code
in binary is different so in source code
often you have a vulnerability
like a good candidate point that already
concentrates itself in a single uh
statement like for example if you have a
string copy here a strn copy and you see
that okay they're actually using the
length of the source buffer um for for
the copy operation that's already pretty
indicative of a buffer overflow sure you
want to make sure that you do some uh
data flow analysis to actually ensure
that you can get to that point stuff
like that but that's already very
indicative or for example this typical
malloc bug width times height where you
have an integer overflow that then leads
to heat baseball for overflow or like a
truncation here where somebody says into
len and then assigns a string length to
that to that variable and so syntax
trees are already you know quite
powerful to describe that and then you
can do a data flow analysis to kind of
uh narrow in on that
all right for binary uh you know you
have a call site and you see okay
something's been called and then it
tells you well the arguments are a1 a2
and a3 and you're like okay
thanks sherlock uh you know this is not
very useful for us is it so
reconstructing these arguments uh is
crucial
another problem is that you don't really
have variables anymore like variables
actually you know the programmer's
telling you what he's doing with that
memory location that's not the case in
binary all you have is
memory locations and registers and so a
huge part of what you need to do is
recover these
high-level
variables
there's a good paper about that where
they call that abstract locations i just
put it here on the slides you can check
that out later if you like
yeah the good thing is what changed
between 2016 and now is guidra
was released
and guidera just has
apart from having a good disassembler
it has an amazing decompiler and
decompilation actually deals with these
topics that i just talked about it does
approximation of local variables uh
intra procedure recovery of arguments
within a function
and even recover some control structures
and so the idea was why don't we not
just make available disassembly
i mean that's good but why don't we just
use the decompiled code and feed it into
our robust parser i mean we have that
parser right so let's try that
and yeah that was actually that actually
turned out to be
a really good step to take
so get rid of cpg extends yearn uh
it imports the disassemblies you can
also import the decompiled code we do
both today and what you end up having is
a polynomial time inter procedural data
flow analysis for a binary which with
gidra you don't really have you have an
intra procedural uh reaching definition
uh analysis with gitra and that's that
it's still highly under development but
we're developing out in the open so you
can check it out
and now uh yeah for our target
so
this was
the first time i started doing iot
security so i didn't know exactly what i
was doing almost at all but i tried to
go ahead and
pick something that is interesting
um and
the way
the targets these targets were chosen
were basically just like go to a major
router manufacturer website
and see which products are on the main
page and pick one that is like
um
more expensive on the expensive side
like around 100 bucks 120 bucks
and one that is more mid-range so maybe
not something that your grandma would
buy but you know your sister maybe or
something
um and the other uh consideration was um
whether the firmwares were encrypted or
not
from the get-go and in this case they
were both encrypted so that means that
not a lot of security researchers uh
looked at it as much as for farmers that
um aren't
um so these are the two targets the drx
1860 and the dr842v2
and there are both release date 2021 so
they're fairly recent uh still on the
market still on the
on the web page of the
provider and after the targets which
were chosen um and if you want to do
something um like this yourself
basically you have to purchase a couple
of tools
so for example here you see
a voltmeter
and a uart converter
a uh
analyzer is an analyzer for this and a
couple of wires um and basically
when you have all of that you're ready
to go all of the tools cost around 120
dollars or if you don't want to spend
the money you can just go to your local
local hackerspace and they usually have
all of this for example in berlin at c
base they have all of this on and you
can use it for free
um so after all of the that is done uh
what you have to do is to solder the
stuff uh you solder a couple of three
wires in this case um in
one of the router in in the uart port of
the router and just all the three wires
in the connector and then you connect
connect them both and then you're ready
ready to go
if you are as bad as soldering as i am
you can also do
uh go to your local
provider of
like a computer repair shop and they can
do this for you for very cheaply this is
berkai from berlin
from computer handy shop
he's watching right now hello bad guy
and he did he did a wonderful soldiering
job much better than the one i i could
do
and just to see how it looks like when
your soldering job is very poor
these are
on the bottom there you see all those
glitch chars
and those are the things that you see
when either the wires are bad or you set
the incorrect baud rate on the
connection
yeah so this is uh this is the whole
setup um you have you have the uart
connection like with the with a good
uart connection in place you have um
uh you can just connect via screen and
then you get in most of the cases you
get the root shell not
in all of the cases like some of the
newer devices have like some protection
mechanisms or a password in place but
you can get around that uh usually
pretty quickly with some tricks in uart
uh sorry u-boots or
um yeah just like trying stuff out
so
when you have all of this
and you have a root shell basically or
what you do is you just go in and you
try to look try to understand the system
a little bit how it works obviously the
first thing that you want to do is just
to look at how is the web interface
shown right how the that when you go to
the admin panel of the router uh what's
uh what is the thing that is serving
that um traffic
and here um it's just basically
there's in one of the targets there's
like one old school cgi program uh dpd
and basically has a couple of
lua scripts as a configuration and um
which point to two binaries like in
one of the devices and um
one of the binaries is used just one
time in the
html of the admin interface which means
that that's probably an abandoned
library or a lib or a binary or a binary
that has been forgotten there
so that makes it a much more interesting
target and a target to look at
so
now you have the binary like you have
like one of the interesting binaries and
then um in my case um i just started get
gidra and the yarn shell at the
same time
and started to look into
the target a little bit more closely
all right
so yeah the first thing that you want to
do is you want to kind of map out the
attack surface so what's the code that
actually needs to deal
with the data that i can provide as an
attacker
and you'll see a query in a moment but
you know let's be honest here there's a
lot of tools that you can use to do that
you essentially want to look at the
external functions so what are the
library functions that are being called
and so we did that for uh
the two binaries so for the two
different devices
the first one
first binary was called
u mtfw from that uh more expensive
router
and um it actually it uses lip c like
very rarely uh to do string handling
file operations and memory allocations
so that's nice i mean there can be
memory corruption in that and it's a web
application you know don't forget that
for http uh it is very old-school it
uses get end so environment variables
to uh to to get the http request data
so extremely old-school stuff
then for the other one this is actually
the cheaper router but it's not as
old-school
so these guys also use lip c functions
for string handling file operations
memory allocation but then they have a
library called mongoose that they use
for http uh
for all handling of http really
including web sockets they have a json
library called jansen we didn't really
look into that much and there's an
internal rpc library called djr
rpc api we also didn't look into that
too much um you'll see we didn't have to
look very deep actually
so i'll just talk about that cheaper
router for now and then claudio will
talk about the more expensive one so for
the cheap router um i mean
we just talked about how it gets all of
it http data via mongoose and mongoose
functions all start with mg mg
underscore so the first thing that you
can do is kind of like list all of the
different calls to mg functions just to
get an idea of um you know how do they
how do they receive attacker controlled
data and here you see there's a function
called get header which yeah as the name
would imply get some data from an http
header then you have git cookie that
gets stuff from cookies pretty center
stuff and then what you can do is um
yeah you can you can dump out
all of the
decompilations all of
the decompiled functions
of methods that call one of those mg
functions you can just dump that to a
file that's pretty nice that means you
can scroll through it and you actually
get a good idea
yeah of of like the the first responders
in in in the http chain right
um
and then you know as you as you try to
automate this um
you can just mark all of these functions
to then use them later
so here's a query that we use that
essentially says take all the calls to
mg functions
and go to the methods that they're in
and then just start walking the the
calls the outgoing calls um and only
take the internal ones and do that ten
times so you're just kind of expanding
into the code and along the core graph
and you're just marking this you're
saying okay this is attack surface right
so with all queries that we show now
we're just going to filter uh to only
look at these functions so you're not
looking at the entire binary you're
looking at the functions that have
something to do with the http handling
directly or indirectly
um yeah and so here was our first square
query really and it's super simple and
the fact that we found something with
this is a bit problematic
so the only thing we do here is we say
okay look at look at string copies strn
copies and mem copies and then look at
the amounts here all right the amounts
are in the third argument and uh they
should not be
literals
it should not be a constant amount that
we're copying because otherwise um you
know there's probably no buffer flow in
that right
and then look at the first argument
that's the destination of the copy
operation and uh it should be a stack
buffer right so stack buffer constant
size but a non-constant amount that we
copy into it and the last thing is just
it should be part of the attack surface
right which we marked with the previous
query
and that's it um
and so you can already see the ability
to inspect arguments here is really um
important otherwise you could not do
this thing here now the nice thing about
this query is this is exactly the kind
of query or
that we would run on source code right
the only thing that's a bit different
here which we would need to clean up to
have the exact same query is that thing
here with a stack because here we're
saying okay gidra has nicely marked this
as a stack buffer so here we we would
really need to say it's a local variable
that is an array and stuff like that and
so this is just shorter but this is the
only thing that keeps you from running
this thing on source code as well so
exactly the same query
um yeah and so we ran that and
yeah there was immediately a buffer
overflow that we found um so this is in
the websocket data handler and you can
see here um they're looking at the
packet it's called param3 and if it
starts with an init and then they're
going to go into this block here and
then they take the rest of the packet
and they just copy it into a stack
buffer and they really don't mind how
big it is this is the amount that they
copy so yeah you just overwrite it and
the nice thing on this device is also
that
uh i mean from an attacker's point of
view is uh they don't have any stack
cookies or canneries or anything like
that so you really just overwrite the
return address and can you know start
start exploiting this
uh yeah there were really just two
results right and this is the second one
and uh this is in a code that is in a
quality of websocket data handler so
also a function that you can reach with
your uh
websocket packet and here's the second
buffer overload it is also extremely
simple right you have a stack buffer
here's uh the uh what you control here's
uh the size of that and there you go
another um exploitable bug right um yeah
i talked about how we have the
disassembly so that's pretty nice what
we could now do is extract gadgets for
our exploit because what is a gadget
right a gadget is really just
a sequence of instructions that ends
with a red right and so we could say
okay um give me all of the uh yeah walk
backwards through the uh control flow
graph like five times in this case and
um yeah just dump that to a file again
so that gave us gadgets that we could
use and we selected a few
and you can put all this stuff in
scripts and then uh yeah there are year
on scripts which are just scala scripts
really and you can then reuse that every
time that you want to dump gadgets uh
yeah and this this works across
platforms as well because we map return
um to yeah
from different platforms to the the same
intermediate representation
yeah and
you know
you can also write
binary experts in scala if you want to
right so here's my binary expert in
scala
it contains three gadgets it's not a lot
of magic that we need to do fix the gp
make sure that a0 points to somewhere um
that we control um yeah and then call p
open right and you can see here um i'm
actually passing in a shell command
which is just echo the string owned into
tmp lul and um yeah that's what we used
as a proof of concept to show that we
can actually write
an arbitrary file on the device as root
and then we send that over via websocket
and that's that
and yeah this is a 100 stable exploit
luckily
because
they
map the
n-web
base image at a fixed address every time
yeah it's a remote root exploit because
that n-web thing that web interface runs
as a route
so yeah it's pretty much everything that
you want as an attacker right you can do
whatever you like um
yeah
that's that yeah
but that was really simple if you think
about it right i mean we didn't even
need data flow analysis which is a bit
of a pity so we we looked for more right
so we then looked for um typical uh
directory traversals and so we were
looking at f open calls and somewhere on
the way in the data flow we want to make
sure that there's a string cat so a
concatenation
that's pretty indicative usually means
okay they're just putting strings
together and you can specify dot dot
slash and break out right and of course
again in the attack surface
also two hits
both of them are directory traversals
but that was not all actually when we
tried to exploit this we realized
there's another bug in this and you know
we wanted a directory traversal but we
got more like a heartbleed style bug
which which is really funny actually so
here's the code for that uh i'll try to
speed up a bit
um so
this is the function concat endpoint
it's a it's a it's a function that just
reads an arbitrary file off of the
device and on each line is another file
name and then it will read all those
files and put them together and send
them back right and you have uh you have
directory traversals in both of those
file opens um
now the funny thing is actually that um
yeah
as they try to write that file back
um
they will
call f open here and if you specify a
binary to read files from like these
lines
then very often you'll get back a an
empty line
so then this thing here f open by the
way if you if you call that on a
uh
directory then this actually succeeds
you get back a pointer you just can't do
much with it right and then there's an f
read operation here that they call on
that
and the f read uh
they're not checking for the return
value right so this f read will fail
which means this buffer here ptr which
is just some pointer onto the onto the
heap
uh it will be uninitialized
and then they just write that back to us
right so that's what it looks like you
just say dot slash dot dot slash and so
on bin ls right and then you get back
memory and you run it again and you get
back
different memory right so typical hot
bleed style kind of bug
all right and then audio
yeah
so for my bug
this was um
yeah it was i i don't know
to be honest it was a little bit
disappointing uh that the
the bug that they found so i definitely
wanted to have a bug in my hand that is
has a
high impact
um and i searched for a lot um and you
know just because i've just started up i
i wasn't really sure how to do it where
to do it and so so there was a lot of
trial and error involved but at some
point i just stumbled upon this bug
and i talked to a couple of people about
it and they were like
okay this could be pretty bad
and also i found out that this is the
kind of bug that
router manufacturers have had
you know problems with for a very long
time and it was very surprising that
this is still going on like hard-coded
credentials
so what's the bug
um here the mtfwu
binary of that more expensive device
is um
getting this is the git right the
compiler output right so this is i this
is how i started and um
afterwards i'm going to show the query
so the get m
parameters here calls receive
data from the outside and specifically
three get m
values are important
http cookie http http act and http auth
here
if you look inside this function this is
the main function
you see
at some point
there is this string fw upload which
looks like firmware upload so it could
be something with the firmware and here
we see now the string size of firmware
is too large so that's very probably
okay it's a firmware upload mechanism
inside the
admin web interface
um and if we look further down here
further up we see that the var
ivar5 controls
the
uh this this call right
so either five comes from the a eight
eight f zero function so the return
value of eight eight uh f zero and the
this eight eight f zero so it should be
some kind of authentication mechanism
right
and and the funny thing is it's it takes
three uh variables here it takes pc r3
which is the cookie and i've checked the
cookie was indeed some kind of a
mechanism um
authentication mechanism by just
checking the web requests that were
being sent from the admin interface but
also um two these these two which were a
little bit efficient because we already
have an authentication mechanism and why
is it another auth right so why is there
a second
getamp here right and also the
even weirder uh thing was
this act here
and this act is actually the variable
that is being string compared over here
so
we have this action string that goes
inside the authentication mechanism so
that doesn't make any sense right
um so let's look at the authentication
uh
function here ajf0
and inside of it uh there are
three interesting things so first of all
we see that the
first parameter here is only checked
that it starts with the string uid
equals
and the first parameter of this ff 88 f0
is pc bar 3 and pc r3 is the http cookie
and the http cookie is exactly the value
that is being used for normal
authentication but in this case it's
only checked for that it starts with the
string uid equals
so that's that's a bit weird and
looking further down in the function we
see another very weird thing is that the
return value of this authentication
function which controls the firmware up
update mechanism
is
taking the value from string compare of
its second parameter with this stack
buffer and the stack second parameter pc
part 2
was this auth string
and this odd string is compared with
this stack buffer which is also a little
bit weird and the stack buffer is just
one line further up
this is passed into another function
eight four before together with
parameter three and parameter three is
pc bar one act so the action mechanisms
so this is
very very weird and if we look in eight
four before a little bit closer we see
there's a lot of things going going on
here but we see mostly that we have this
s printf call to the third parameter
which means and this s printer of course
has a format string with a hex value so
it's it spits out a hex value of pb var
3.
so that means that somehow this
parameter three is transformed through
to a hex value of pb bar
three
parameter three from pb of r3 so this
means
that
the actual
the http cookie value that is usually
used for authentication is completely
ignored and instead the authentication
of the firmware is a basically a
transformation a hex let's say it could
be md5 we could replace this this this
function with md5 whatever um of
of the other parameter act
so
actually
it means that if you pass in a value for
a a random value for http cookie that
starts with uid equals and a hash value
of uh hp act
um
act that equals the http auth then you
can upload um replace the firmware of
the device
so this is not like a typical hardcoded
credentials vulnerability where you just
like string compare two things or where
like whereas there's an actual string in
the binary but it's a little bit more
hidden inside the code
okay
so
um let me show you the query
so um
this is just like a step-by-step guide
how to build the query and the first one
is just like you import the code you
import the binary and after you have the
binary you can look in the graph and you
can see
all these assembly instructions because
now we're at the binary level
but we don't want the assembly so we
just take all the method nodes of the
graph
of the binary which contains the gidras
decompiler output and we concat them to
a large string with new lines and we
import that we create a source c source
based
graph from that string
so now we can run good
data flow queries on it
so
now this is how it looks like right so
we don't have the assembly instructions
anymore now we see the actual code of
the git right the compiler output
and the same thing that fabs showed the
attack surface tags um can be stored
with like this type of command so that
it's easier later to to reach those
nodes
um this is for example what you can do
if we you've tagged the attack surface
you can just like list all calls in the
whole binary because you don't want to
look like all over the code right you
can just like do this and then you know
exactly all the specific
places where data comes in
and um but now we want to write the
actual query and the way it's um i did
it i mean you can do it like any way you
want but the way i did it was just to
start at the the heart of the problem
which was the s printf call to the third
parameter so what you can just do is
give me all nodes of s print f where the
second argument is a literal that has
this x uh that matches this regex which
is uh the hex transform so it's like it
basically takes the
source parameter and it um makes a hex
transformation to the destination
parameter right
so this is s printf transform which
matches this one line
for the second line we want the 84b4
function
right which actually calls as printf
right so we want that that function to
be passed some uh to to be identified by
the query and in this case we just write
s print f transform so this is the
method that we just found and we take
all of the method that contains s printf
transforms
and then we run two data flow queries to
see if those methods actually reach the
s printf
so and and in this specific case you can
see s printf this is that call over here
and then we check if one of the
parameters reaches the source and one of
the parameters reaches the destination
of the method s printf
and we call this parameter hex transform
this is this all made up names is just
like easier to remember at least for in
my case so we have parameter hex
transform is the 84b4 function
and we go back to our bug we remember
that the 84b4 function was the fishy
function that was that transformed the
stack buffer here right
so we have
the parameter hex transform is the eight
four before uh
function so and we want to take all the
callers of this function
and we want to see if there
is a string compare
from one of it if there is a data flow
from the parameter of this caller to the
string compare
and also if there is um if that same
function that calls the the um parameter
hex transform also has a data flow to
the um parameter hex transform
so then you have both of them together
and this can be improved a little bit
but um and i mean it
it's it's it's good enough to detect
this bug so then we have the compare
transform and then
the only thing we have to say is that
okay the is there a um data flow from
the attack surface from the get em calls
to this function and did we find that
and this is the the the whole query how
it looks like
um when you run it you get
this
you get this output so you get these
three environment variables and
obviously
the next step would be to actually
confirm the bug and you can do it in
many ways the way i did was just with
ld preload where you can just write a
custom version of string compare
in this case that prints out
the strings that are compared
and then you just run this on one of the
acts which is get device info and you
get the hard-coded credentials for that
specific action that gives you the
device information and then you can do
the same with firmware upload and
firmware update and then you get the
hard-coded credentials for those instead
of going inside the function and trying
to figure out what's going on and all
those bitwise operators and whatever
and this is all good but you know it's
not super interesting because it's a
land-based vulnerability uh so you know
it's like kind of hard to exploit but it
would be interesting if we were also
remotely exploitable right so um
a colleague of mine bernhard suggested i
should try a dns rebinding attack to
combine this with the dns rebinding
attack so um this is very easy to do
also it was my first time doing it but i
highly recommend you try it out um you
can just use the singularity from ncc
group this tool where you can just spin
up an aws instance you install the
single reality server it's very easy
it's like in five minutes um you open
you know the firewall ports on the aws
instance and you have to do a couple of
configurations you buy a domain name and
then you can just trigger a
dns reminding attack and what's going on
over here is that
i this grandma's secret recipe this was
on my local computer
and
um
the browser should actually protect
against this right should actually
protect against this this this type of
thing so you cannot just like go to a
web page and the web page can request
stuff from your local machine right so
this is what cores protect
against but if you
manage a dns rebinding attack which
works like you open a web page and the
web page gives back a dns response with
a very short time to live and the next
time the browser request of the the
webpage that the customer already shows
the next time the the request goes out
the dns response is to a local address
and then with that you can actually show
a web page to um
to a person and
then
you can
send hp request to any local
ip address or of the local network for
example the router so to combine this
with the bug
we can just show
a web page to the to anyone um and with
this router and then we can exchange the
firmware on the fly
which means
it's partnered ready
all right i'm just gonna wrap this up
now so notes on disclosure we did
contact the vendor over 90 days ago in
august
gave them
an initial bug
they said
that they would forward this to their r
d team
and they would contact us uh but they
never really got back to us so we
contacted them again uh like very early
in november uh because we wanted to talk
about this and we said hey you know
what happened to our bug and also uh
here is another bug you know
if you like but no response so um yeah i
mean i'm i'm hoping that um
i mean
maybe they'll see the talk maybe they'll
fix it maybe not but um you know we
tried we really tried so i just want to
say that
so uh to conclude um
yeah it's it's really nice to make a
disassembly available in a graph
database to then query it but where it
gets really powerful is you have if you
have something that's a bit more high
level something that you would get from
from a decompiler and that's what we're
using as our baseline now and it's just
amazing how
even though this is actually from a
binary it's sufficiently
c-ish to use the exact same queries
um and um
yeah uh
the you you saw two types of querying
one is like okay i'm gonna write about
something that i think is going to be
broken in a particular way and then just
get out the box and then what claudio
showed you is he had something that he
wanted to characterize across devices
kind of create a very complex signature
that generalizes enough to use this
across devices and those are like the
two use cases that you can go with with
those with those kinds of
queries
and the reason we do this on binary
really is that the parser that we have
in yeon is extremely robust meaning you
can feed it anything that kind of looks
like c and it will do its best job to
create abstract syntax trees and control
flow graphs and these kinds of things
so it is really a parser designed for
hackers if some code fell off a truck
you don't need to start configuring a
build environment because you can't
right you can use this on whatever code
that you have and the decompiler output
from gedra compared to code that just
fell off a truck is actually quite tame
oh yeah and finally i guess yeah it's
quite scary certain consumer-grade
routers they're remarkably insecure
we didn't have to try very hard
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]