uh
[Music]
me
very good uh it's a pleasure to be back
on the conference circus
um it's been a while
many as many like
as many of you had the same experience
it's been
a long time without actually going to
on-site talks and this is a super
amazing opportunity to actually talk to
you about some of the fun stuff that we
have been doing
um
this conference is called no hat
and uh i figured well actually as we're
riding the the fuzzing
pipe train and trying to figure out if
we can
find
vulnerabilities and use fuzzing to
discover different kind of
vulnerabilities we're still wearing some
form of hat right
but this can be an arbitrary warm hat
this winter is coming and we'll see what
uh what we can do a little bit about me
i'm an academic but that shouldn't stop
you from listening to me
it just means that i'm giving you tools
while you can still find bugs with them
right so we've had this discussion a
while and
yesterday during dinner for example and
one of the big differences is if
security researchers give talk
that are primarily interested in
bug bounties they will only release
their tools whenever their
tool no longer finds any effective bugs
what we researchers do is we try to get
as much fame as possible and we want to
release tools much earlier than than
others so we do a proof of concept
we show that a new technique is actually
useful and
as researchers or as academics we have
to be poor so we're not trying to get as
many as much money out of the bug bunty
programs as possible but we're releasing
tools so that you folks can actually use
them so all the different things that
i'm talking about today are open source
you can download them you can play with
them you can figure them out you can
integrate them into your tool chains and
you should right so
just to give you a bit of perspective of
what kind of research we are doing we
are working on on three large areas in
my uh in my group and i've got about
20ish people working on on different
aspects uh we do software testing we do
mitigations and we do compartments
um compartments is like you have large
complex software you break it into small
components you do fault domains and you
try to figure out that this actually uh
makes your system a bit more secure
mitigations i'm sure you know control
flow integrity shadow stacks and so on
uh this is also an area that we're
doubling in a bit but most interesting
to you because you want to make money is
software testing and software testing is
a tool to help the developer to prune
bugs
using fuzzing to discover them and
sanitization to detect them
now
that aside right we're going to focus on
on fuzzing and bug finding and turning
stuff into exploitable crashes from now
on
i've looked around at the last couple of
conferences just this year
academic and
hacker conferences as well and all of
these top conferences have something
something in common just looking at the
program each of these conferences has
like a full session or two sessions or
three sessions on fuzzing does using
security um this is uh ndss this is um
oh sorry first was smp this is using
security and um there's there's raid ccs
was just lost
last week or this week it had two
sessions on on fuzzing so fuzzing is a
very hot and ongoing topic
now you may wonder why why are we doing
fuzzing right we've been uh we've just
heard from david that we've been doing
security for 20 30 years right
why is this uh why is this still
interesting right well
bugs are still everywhere there's bugs
wherever you look right and you just
have to poke the software a little bit
it's going to explode in your face and
crash and some of these explosions can
actually have some collateral damage and
allow the attacker to take over your
system
uh as many bugs are exploitable right
then this can result in your system
being compromised by ransomware your
virtual machine being taken over your
super fancy new electric car being
turned into a remotely controlled toy
vehicle which is fun for the hacker on
the control is not so much fun for you
sitting in the car it can invade your
physical spaces uh by turning smart
locks into uh matching opening devices
and so on
right
um going back to what what i said before
there's the difference between software
testing and mitigations we could now
put in a lot of effort into mitigation
making the exploitation of these bugs as
hard as possible but this wouldn't
help us in
removing the bugs from the software
right it would just make exploitation
harder and you hackers are clever you
will figure out a way to actually get
around these mitigations and develop
tooling and so on so it's not going to
be super effective on the other hand if
you actually use software testing to
find
all these vulnerabilities we have an
opportunity to fix
the code and actually make them reduce
the exploitability
you may remember from other academics
there's tools like
symbolic execution formal verification
and so on these are all great if your
code size is less than 100 lines of code
right if you have a little bit more
complex code than that
it's a bit more difficult right and last
time i checked and looked at our code
for example the
google chrome
um
the browser there's more than 100
million lines of code that you're
running as part of the software stack
there's no way that you can formally
verify this there's no way you can
symbolically execute it and just for
reference in code complexity because
like 100 million lines of code is really
really hard to imagine
i i have two pictures here one of them
is margaret hamilton who was responsible
for the apollo guidance computer you're
too young for that but that's that thing
flew to the moon on very primitive
hardware and they printed out the the
software stack that was running on the
system in assembly code and like if
you're generous there's about two meters
of software complexity right if you
print out the google source code uh we
have about 400 meters of complexity
uh in a high-level language so this is
much more much more complex and much
harder to assess so we need some form of
automated techniques to actually handle
this massive amount of complexity
without it breaking down
david luckily already introduced fuzzing
um i'm just gonna do it one more time
because we saw that a lot of people
actually did not work with fuzzing yet
so if you regret not holding up your
hand before i will bore you for two
minutes about how fuzzing actually works
um if you already do fuzzing bear with
me this is going to get
more interesting very very quickly so
fuzzing international you have a target
program a software under test as david
called it you run it you pass it some
parameters uh you see if it crashes
a simple fuzzer is while true you just
throw random stuff with it and you see
if it you you remember if it crashes and
the main
goal of fuzzing is
don't be clever don't spend too many
cycles don't overthink it be fast as
many executions as possible we want to
know if this input crashes if the input
crashes will set it aside and use it for
later analysis
um so we have this input we run the
program under test in some kind of
virtual environment we see if it crashes
if it crashes we store the input set the
input aside and keep it for later
analysis this helps the developer to
actually have a
witness
if you run the program with this input
it's going to crash and
you can use this for debugging to fix
and identify the bug
and there's obviously a loop right we
run the program we create new we
generate new input we run it again we
run it again if it crashes we store it
and we do this until we run out of
resources
now this is fairly dumped and this has
been like that until
2010 ish where we just do random random
changes to the uh to the input
and hope that we will trigger some more
interesting behavior
now if you use some form of information
about the program just like a note of
which kind of functionality has been
executed we know which inputs that we
randomly create trigger some kind of
interesting behavior
and then instead of
just modifying the the root input or the
empty input we can modify the input that
already triggered some some interesting
behavior before so this is a kind of
change in in a thought pattern instead
of just doing it from scratch every
single time we create an input we
modify input that has been successful
before hoping that it will be successful
again and more interesting again
right so
to make fuzzing effective
and find more interesting bugs there's a
couple of things we have to
we have to look at when we're optimizing
first our test cases should trigger bugs
so we're using some fine kind of
coverage guided fuzzing for that second
the fuzzer must be able to detect the
bugs right if it just silently passes
the bugs and doesn't really figure out
if there's a there's been a bug
triggered or not yeah tough luck right
and uh performance is key
fuzzing is a zero-sum game
uh going back to also the
the
introduction that david did using
game theory right you have a finite
amount of resources even if you're
playing this game for
an infinite amount of time at any point
in time you have a finite amount of
resources and you want to get as many
bugs out of the cycles that you have
available as possible
so it's that's what as an engineer
really really drives me right so i want
to get like i know i have a cluster of a
couple of hundred cores where we can run
fuzzing i want to get as many bugs out
of these cores as possible right so this
is keep this in mind that this is an
inherent optimization game
let's focus on the first challenge
tracking coverage
and um
the current state of the art is
gray box box-based mutation coverage
or
fuzzing based on feedback from
from simple code coverage that we have
there's a different different kind of
instrumentations that we can have and
the the overarching goals you take the
source code or the binary you instrument
it and whenever a given code area is
executed you you record it on your on
your magic map
there's different kind of coverages that
are out there there's function coverage
block coverage line coverage edge
coverage what not and
it's an it's an inherent trade-off on on
how you want to record what areas you
have executed the more cycles you spend
on recording coverage the fewer cycles
you're actually spending executing the
uh the code on one hand you may get
better information about what you're
executing on the other hand it's more
costly to collect so you'll have to
figure out some form of
of trade-off here
and when we're looking at coverage
collection the fuzzer keeps uh
like as the fuzzer is running it keeps
track of what kind of code areas have
been executed what kind of
functionalities have been triggered and
the the fuzzer keeps us as part of some
form of global coverage right and it's
it's like a map of which edge has been
executed as many times as in in my
example here right and then for each
execution the car the fuzzer keeps a
local map and if the collector coverage
is higher for the for the topmost bit
then the global coverage will update the
global coverage and set the c decide for
further mutation
right so the fuzzer is created as one
input we executed
we check the collector coverage
yeah sure we've executed a couple of
edges more time so for example the
orange edge and the
the pink edge has been executed more
times but we haven't increased enough
right so the the the highest the top
highest most bit is not going to change
so we're going to just keep it the same
let's do one more input ah here now the
the pink bit has changed uh the pink uh
counter has changed from seven to eight
so we've executed this loop more times
we've gone through the loop on the on
the right hand side and this control
flow graph more times
this is higher than the top most bit
that we have stored so far therefore
this is considered an interesting
new seed therefore the fuzzer will set
it aside and continue fuzzing with it
right
we'll store this and then figure out
what the what to do and how to continue
with it
so
fuzzing has been rather boring until
2011 12-ish until uh afl actually came
along and there there have been two
events that happened on one hand there
was the cyber grand challenge that kind
of kicked off a lot of this this
research who knows the cyber grand
challenge okay so this was one of the
darpa grand challenges darpa the
u.s defense agency
they kind of posed these large
challenges out there to humanity and
there's a
researchers trying to find a way to
solve it and the cyber grand challenge
was figuring out a way to auto
automatically find vulnerabilities and
then exploit them in in some way
there's been grand challenges for auto
autonomous driving and
location geolocation and so on and a
bunch of others and this challenge was
focused on vulnerability search and
vulnerability discovery and this led to
what i call the cambrian explosion of
fuzzers if you've
paid attention in biology the cambrian
explosion is when life happened and it
just exploded and there's all these life
forms that that that came out and we see
you see the same as all the fuzzers
there's now hundreds of buzzers at each
conference there's ten new fuzzers being
uh being proposed and all the slight
slight differences and deviations so
we've been working on actually uh trying
to categorize systematize all these
differences to help other researchers
also figuring out how they relate to
each other and what they uh what they
they belong to both on on the control
flow coverage edge but also on the data
flow coverage edge
so this will help you choose what kind
of fuzzer you want to have and also
gives you a way to measure
for a given program what kind of
feedback will be most useful
uh so as a summary for for tracking
coverage coverage helps a fuzzer to
effectively explore new code areas it's
a feedback process that tells the fuzzer
what areas actually are interesting
code coverage and edge coverage but for
example is very cheap to obtain it's
like two or three percent overhead and
precise enough in general so all the
fuzzers pretty much uh rely on a form of
code coverage there's many flavors of
code coverage with subtle differences do
check out and you may want to hand tune
but it's very easy to just set up a
fuzzer go with it and then tune along
while you actually observe your fuzzing
campaign future research so if you are
interested in writing new more
interesting fuzzers alternatives to code
coverage what is a good approximation of
code coverage for example in in areas
where you cannot really
instrument your binary think of
embedded systems think of systems where
you don't have uh
debug primitives or like
closed environments or other kind of
binaries that make it hard for you to
obtain this this information
combining different coverages and also
adjusting coverage as needed during the
campaign for example after you finish
the exploration campaign and you know
how the
how code actually works you want to go
into into an exploitation phase where
you figure out individual bugs and there
some more fine-grained feedback may
actually be fairly
fairly useful
second challenge detecting bugs
well if we would just know that a bug is
there this would be super easy right if
the bug would just tell you hey this is
the bug i'm on line 15 uh fifth
character go fix me right unfortunately
this doesn't work that that way and we
need some form of oracle we need a way
that tells us that hey there actually is
a bug
uh if you don't have source code you may
just yolo it or you could statically
rewrite the binary right something that
you get like if if your program is hack
faults
yeah that's very likely a bug right so
that's a that's a very cheap oracle if
it's egg faults or not uh you can
statically rewrite the binary to make it
more likely to segfault to re retrofit
some kind of
fuzzing or address sanitization
instrumentation into it and we'll talk
about this in a in a bit um or if you do
have source code that's the ideal case
um and i i disagree a little bit with
david here and i didn't pose a question
so you cannot really shoot me down and i
can just as a speaker now i can talk
about it that often if you do have
source code it makes fuzzing and bug
finding much easier and you can actually
spend some cycles on uh instrumenting it
with different kind of
sanitizers who knows sanitizers quick
show of hands
very few um
the cheapest way to find bugs as i tell
my students is
sanitizers yes hand sanitizer everybody
knows hand sanitizers right it gets rid
of germs on uh on your hands especially
over the last two two years right a
sanitizer is the cheapest way when
you're writing code to find
vulnerabilities in your code um you do
dash
f sanitize equals address
your code compiles and if you touch
illegal memory
you get a nice bug report that tells you
hey there's a bug over here you should
all during testing you should always
compile your code with sanitization
uh there's concurrency sanitizers or
threat sanitizers there's type
sanitizers um
logic bugs ah we don't really have
something useful for logic bugs yet so
that's a that's a nice way for you for
to to look at future research
but i don't just want to talk about
sanitizers because this research has
already been done you should be using uh
sanitization during fussing and we can
talk about some of the the the
trade-offs here but i'm happy to do that
during the break but the the main goal
or the main
issue i want to talk about is that yes
crashes are great but having actual bugs
are much better
um a fuzzing campaign produces n
crashing seeds that map to m bucks right
so after fuzzing you have n crushing
seeds and your fuzzer tells you all of
these seeds are unique bugs right but
you don't know in in essence there's
only going to be m actual bucks and
often m is much smaller than n right so
now given that you have the 7 000 uh
total crashes or a thousand unique
crashes
um
how do you distill them
into the number of unique bugs
right in this example here there were 7
000 crashes on afl 124 unique and all of
them were the same bug
right you've got a couple of overhead a
couple of orders of of magnitude
difference between the number of real
bugs
and the the
unique bugs that your fuzzer reports and
this is going to cost you a lot of
resources and if you are a bug bounty
hunter you're only paid once per buck
right so it doesn't matter if you say
hey there's more but there's more bucks
here right it just doesn't work like
that now the challenge that we have is
given n
the number of crashing seats how do we
distill them into the set of actual uh
actual books
well
one approach is we could just do call
stacks right group all the crashes based
on the on the hash of top k frames well
the issue here is that there's a whole
bunch of type 1 errors
so there's going to be duplicate bugs
that crash at different uh different
addresses and we'll uh will lose those
uh the
will will over count by about two orders
of magnitude
crash location that's another simple
estimator
so we just record the crash location and
treat each crash location as a as a
different book
the prime counter example here are used
after three bucks use after three bugs
will crash anywhere right so the crash
location has nothing to do with the
actual
actual bug that you're looking at this
is pretty uh pretty useless as well
unfortunately so both of these
approaches over count by two to three
orders of magnitude um wasting your your
uh your developer time so if um
like for 100
potential bucks you spend 100 days
analyzing them and then you have one
final book that's not going to be super
uh super versatile
so
we spent some resources
we did 79 cpu years of fuzzing
and we looked at 254 000 crashing seats
that we got out of it
that's actually a fairly substantial
number
um and then we analyzed the
the different seats it's actually great
if you have phd students they can
actually do a lot of stuff and look at
this manually so you can get ground
truth um
and the existing grouping that have been
used both over and under approximate
bugs this is bad
each bug is triggerable by a unique
trigger right like if you think about it
each bug that is out there will have
some form of unique trigger that you can
use to actually trigger the bug
and large sections if you trace the the
program execution to the bug large
sections of this execution path are
irrelevant to the crash
now if we could identify the small
sequence of the paths that is actually
responsible
for
the the vulnerability and for the crash
we could use this to identify it based
on the on the topology
so our idea that we had is do we want to
minimize the path prune all the
irrelevant sections that do not
correspond to the bug trigger and then
cluster by by graph topology to match
similar similar kind of sub-paths
and we're introducing igor for that
igors are if you if you know discworld
and um
i'm a huge fan of of the discworld
novels you should totally read them
in ank moorpark there's a
a group of igors that are helpful
servants to crazy scientists and we used
to use the name for that terry pratchett
is the author and you should all read
read his books they are they're amazing
so we're introducing igor to help us
distill all these different crashes and
the underlying pipeline looks like that
we get all the crashes in we do some
data processing filtering and then igor
fuzzing
uh and then we do graph clustering and
then we get clustered crashes so for
each of the bugs we get a cluster of the
of the crashes out there
you see fuzzing in the in the first
in the first box i'm going to spend some
more time on this on this fuzzing we're
going to do fuzzing but different
right so the the goal of fuzzing usually
is we want to maximize coverage we want
to trigger new and different bugs
for igor fuzz we don't
now with igor fuzz we flipped the
fitness function and we want to have as
little coverage as possible while
triggering the same book original
fuzzing is we want to get more coverage
and hit different locations
what we do is given a seat we want to
hit
less coverage
and the same crash and this allows us to
shrink and prune all of the code that is
not necessary like imagine you spending
hours and days trying to get rid of
functionality that is not bug relevant
this is using a machine that does that
right so it gets rid of all the the
nodes here on the on the right hand side
there's a that's a lip png example that
we triaged um
you see all the the basic blocks the red
ones are those that have been pruned um
and the green ones are those that have
been added to make they make the past
simpler and making the execution much
more much more efficient right this
allows us to get rid of large chunks of
the the pass and figuring out the
details we then do clustering
for
the the different different bugs before
our coverage decreased buzzing
clustering was a bit of a show as
you see on the left hand side it was
very hard to distinguish these different
crashes uh afterwards on the right hand
side you see distinct clusters for all
the different cvs so it is very
effective at grouping
grouping crashes into into small groups
and this gives you a way of
clustering 250 000
crashes that we had into 40 bucks
so
the
summary for for igor is it's fuzzing is
great at producing crashes when using
the right sanitizer of course but
programmers are just overwhelmed by the
thousands of crashes that we have we can
minimize the path length of seats to
enable this the similarity matching and
using our tool we group these 254 4000
crashes into 39 unique bugs and 48
clusters so it's much easier for you to
analyze 48 clusters than 254 000 seats
i i would say so check out the
the the paper the source is uh is online
versus we are currently working on a
tutorial and making it more usable for
for analysts
many of you are working on fuzzers
about two to five percent according to a
show of hands but i would guess much
more
because it's very hard for you to show
hands but if you are if you're
developing a new fuzzer for an area
right you may not want to open sources
or whatnot but you want to figure out is
my fuzzer better than the fuzzer that
already exists right is it worthwhile to
invest my time into tuning this strategy
so you want to find uh find a some kind
of metrics to compare your fuzzer to
other fuzzers
it could be code coverage could be
crashes it could be bugs well code
coverage is subject subjective it's very
hard to measure measure talk to me about
this during the coffee break crashes are
imprecise as we've just seen
and for bugs you lack ground truths
right you don't really know what how
many bugs will be in the in the code
so what we did is we created a benchmark
using real software
that allows you to test all these uh
these different uh these different
fuzzers including your foster it's very
easy to set up and then you can evaluate
if your fuzzer is actually better than
uh than other fuzzers
that just as a side note if you want to
check it out it's called magma uh and it
it contains a real world software that
you can use to to drive your uh your
your fuzz ring code
two quick notes on on some fuzzing
niches and techniques i want to mention
and some some neat areas especially as
the discussion came up
today this morning and yesterday during
during the dinner one of the areas where
fuzzing is really really really really
hard are embedded systems and with
embedded systems i'm thinking about
these small little embedded systems
where you run firmware and you have some
arm cortex m0 m4 or some other kind of
kind of constrained environment
and
the the issue there is right they're not
running an operating system they're
running on the hardware itself they are
heavily customized it's very hard to use
it's very hard to look at uh the the
firmware is task dependent there's a
metric ton of different peripherals
you would have to support and it's super
hard right there's no way for you to uh
to
to do peripheral discovery and to
actually support all these these
different systems
um
one thing all of these systems have in
common though is that they um they have
some form of hell a hardware abstraction
layer
and there's a bunch of different help
health and we use this so instead of
implementing an emulator for each
individual peripheral we implement an
abstraction layer that allows you to
hook
when an individual uh hell function was
called like whenever a half a function
is called for example you are greed or
you are right
instead of implementing the and
emulating the ur chip which would drive
us insane
we allow you to intercept and then
replace it with a five-line python
script
so our hallucinator replaces the
underlying hals and other libraries with
high level implementations and gives you
as the developer the the analyst the
opportunity to to implement these
high-level abstractions so this
transforms the re-hosting problem of
re-hosting and re-implementing all these
different peripherals and supporting
tens of thousands of devices into
supporting a dozen of health and this is
much uh much easier
if you're looking at a modern firmware
on such an embedded embedded system we
have the off-chip hardware we have
on-chip hardware and we have to firm our
running running on top of it if you peek
into the firmware a bit
right we've got the vendor hell the
platform hell and a bunch of other
abstraction layers on top of that we may
have rtos protocol stacks such as a
low level ip sigbi
peripheral libraries like sensors and so
on and then the application code on top
our rehosting uses qmu to run all the
the low level instructions and then he
finds interception points for whenever a
hardware is accessed through the hell
and you can then implement these these
hal abstractions on top of it either
running the the full stack application
code rtos um the the real the real-time
operating system protocol stacks or even
going higher and abstracting these uh
these low-level
systems as well
giving you an opportunity to intersect
and intercept the application code so in
hallucinator we do hal based firmware
re-hosting and you can locate health
functions in firmware in the firmware
address space and then use this as
individual hooks
qmu translates the instructions we trap
on peripheral axis based on the on the
health functions and then enable fine
grain introspection we just did a
tutorial for uh
for the folks at onr the tutorial is
online on the on the website using the
uh the different uh uh slides and so on
as well so you can play through the
tutorial and do some some re-hosting of
your firmware as you are you're playing
with it this is also great for firmware
fuzzing
if you if you're into that that kind of
thing
uh a second uh project i want to talk
about that we've been pushing really
really hard on also making it available
to you folks is a retrowrite
it's a tool that allows you to
statically rewrite existing binary code
for both x86 and arch 64. so you start
with an
elf binary that can be stripped you do
symbolization so you recover all the
different
different offsets and the different code
layouts
resulting in the form of labeled
assembly and then you can run a bunch of
instrumentation passes on top of this um
of this this reassembled code
memory sanitization address
synthesization fuzzing coverage or
control flow integrity and then you
compile it back down
um features that retroright already has
it is it's a zero overhead rewriter for
ar-64 and x64 so it gives you a way to
rewrite your binaries at very very high
speed and very high compatibility
fully symbolizes arm and x64 code and we
provide as i said address and it is a
sanitization fuzzing and coverage
function shuffling exception handling
basic control flow integrity and and
shadow stacks
we've got a tutorial on here as well um
the
c plus plus support is very iffy at the
moment because c plus exceptions are
hard
but we're working on that if you're
interested in using it the 60 uh the x86
version is fairly stable the arm version
is coming along if you're interested in
the arm version please reach out
we give early developer access so we'll
be very interested in working with you
on that
i want to spend the last couple of
minutes and talking about some of the
unsolved challenges that i've seen
fuzzing and also give you an opportunity
to
later during coffee hit me up and talk
about all of these different things and
would be very interested in in
discussing those and if you have
solutions please please please let me
know these are very interesting and
active areas
areas of research
first of metrics for starting seeds
right we often have it that
you have first a software before
now you have 40 000 seats
you've seen that
you want to continue fuzzing because the
software changed a bit or the
configuration change of it which of
these 40 000 seeds to use as your
starting corpus
how do you generate goods starting
corpora right
in academia papers are often evaluated
we start with empty seats but any
good analyst will spend 10 minutes to
create a set of good starting seats and
then use those to to actually jump start
the the exploration and fuzzing process
cross distillation to reuse seeds among
targets
we've had great success when we uh when
we did usb kernel fuzzing where we
found around 40
000 days in the in the linux kernel
where
um the
we fuzzed a usb target and then the
seats that we we got from there we just
replayed on on windows and and mac os
and then found a couple of odays and
windows and mac os as well with this
incomplete usb parsing
so this is an interesting way to do
cross distillation between targets and
it goes back to a bit to what david said
with the with the a b
a b testing with the different url url
lips
stateful programs and network protocols
this is a really really hard target to
look at
handling more peripherals helping
developers analyze discovered crashes
and distinguishing the exploration phase
from the exploitation phase during
fuzzing and i think we need to break
this into multiple phases where we're
using different kinds of feedback
different kind of mutators different
kind of
options there
talk to me about this during the break
or any time during the day i'll be i'll
be around
let me conclude
please join me in riding the fuzzing
hype train it's an amazing uh it's an
amazing train bugs are everywhere and
fuzzers allow you to find these bugs to
uh to then do fun stuff with them
it's easily integratable into the
development chain as an analyst you can
use it to uh to to target bug bounty
programs
the goal is that you leverage feedback
uh from coverage to find more and
interesting crashes and uh best feedback
and mutations are program dependent so
we'll we'll start or
slowly move to an area where we will
hand tune the fuzzers to the to the
different use cases
some interesting future research that
you could look at increasing usability
reducing startup costs
that's also something that we are
looking at we're providing the tutorials
and on the websites and so on um
specializing fuzzing for new
environments such as embedded systems
and then helping developers make sense
of the bugs this is what the igor system
for example uh was targeting at that's
all what i wanted to say today i hope
you have some time for questions um
thank you for your attention and
please
okay
uh
[Music]