so I'm going to talk today about a way
to use routers for not things rather for
things that are not specifically linked
oriented who wants a router raise your
hands at the hub 9 the linksys clean
Dixie so if you want a router we
happened on a load balancer as I
discovered what's the point of was using
a router for a load balancer in my mind
the point is is quite narrow it's for a
collection of services that really don't
have a whole lot of value that is all
they have value but they're not going to
have a value in the sort of scale that
you might see at Yahoo or at Google or
it folks who do you know 300 machines
behind them address that kind of stuff
kind of the idea here is that we want
local a balancing sometimes for instance
things that have relieved the want wonky
behavior such as with all of our client
libraries and windows or unix boxes we
also want to use just the simplest
things possible i like the router i
already have it why add another piece of
gear to affect load balancing so it my
concept for this generalized fast server
load balancing is simple utilize
existing structures with features within
hardware like ecmp in this case to
affect the same types of connection load
balancing behaviors as you see in more
stateful more aware more costly devices
the other important point to mention is
that if we do this in a router we
benefit by all the work gone into the
forwarding paths I can't think of a
single 10 gig layer 3 box that's not 10
gigs that way three if it can do that
why not use it for distributing traffic
to machines links are good but we can do
this with machines to i discovered so
what are the ingredients for this
generalized fast server load balancing
needs a couple things to work really
well on iOS is where I basically
implemented all of these things or this
this process and it needs three things
need to spawn stime reporters things
that do health checks this is sometimes
called IP SLA second thing we need is an
enhanced tracking feature tracking
objects were around for a long time
I am to make sure one interface could
follow them another interfaces state for
example taking down one port if any in a
wink I group went down for instance this
now can track other things like IP SLA
objects in iOS so the configuration can
solve those two things both of those are
the underpinnings for the ECM p to work
well once you do all these things you
affect this generalized fast server load
balancing concept why is this good for
us if we can use a router to affect
server load balancing and do it in a
very simplistic manner with the
previously mentioned things the track
and they round about the response time
reporters we don't have to run ospf for
bgp or whatever well as we were doing to
our end hosts which I've heard a lot
about from a lot of people that's not a
bad concept but it seems like a lot of
extra work it also seems as if in many
locations or many circumstances you
won't be able to run a roni protocol to
the device you wish to load balance the
service to so it's kind of an onstar in
some ways and I think I can remove that
with these mechanisms another good good
point about this concept is that it's
all it's all routing there's no state on
this stuff when the packet comes in
headers used create the hash the source
and destination IP addresses in cisco
ccnp case minimally affect the death
selection of the next top this is a are
cry from things that know about source
and escorts things that know about the
nature of the URL and in our case we're
not going to be concerned with those
things so strip them away use the router
how does it look effectively we have
just two pieces the normal route router
you always had and for the sake of
example we're using 10 that in this case
we have three machines we care about and
we want to say that we'd like to have
them all handle the same load for a
common address let's call it you'll see
in the later on we'll have that DC NP do
these three machines in this case what
we're doing is called direct server
returned or each machines target service
address is living on a loopback not on
the ethernet interface in that / 29 in
that access via when the return traffic
is next top to 1000 one in this example
we have this interface VLAN 100 again
director of return does the right thing
from dot 0 dot 3 episode 2 and 3 and we
basically in this
click configuration here would have
these enumerated with similar dressing
as I'll show you here so text config
again VLAN interface you always have
that response time reporters this is
kind of a simple example just two of
them we're doing our scenario based on
recursive name server pair I like the
fact that then was Oliver libraries will
try the first and fail to the second but
I don't like the fact that they never
tried the second to begin with this is
an example of a really silly load rather
loosely workload created by resolver
libraries I rather have both machines
take some of the load why not I'm paying
for the power I also prefer that if one
of them failed I wouldn't have to tell
anybody about that and wouldn't have to
have customers becoming enraged or angry
that they're waiting for a timeout to
get to the second server if we have
these response time reporters checking
two and three the actual servers here if
one goes down our following config will
track that we have track one in fact to
tracking response time reporter 1 and
response some reporter 2 now why is that
useful it's useful up to this right
right bring this part here is standard
ecmp routes are configured manually
you'll note one additional element at
the end of the route not a not a metric
or anything else or a tag but in this
case a track option we're saying that
for the destination two and three but we
have two possible next hops 10 10 10 10
10 10 10 to whatever I'm sorry the
destination address there the next house
or two and three for that particular
host we have two candidate routes you'll
see 10 10 x 10 1 10 10 10 goes to 0 dot
I'm sorry 130 like and 10 10 10 2 goes
to 3 into a light with track one failing
where those are also be expired we'd
have all the load to the remaining
machine comp out the same is true for
track two how's it look under the hood
if you do with show IP SEF internal for
that particular next top you'll for any
of them you'll see the 16 hash buckets
ultimately have themselves pointed to
two and three in the case of even
numbers of routes this works just fine a
problem that cisco has always had or
seems to have had for a long time
uneven distribution of which hash bucket
points to what next top in current code
my observations are that you actually do
see SEF resize things or recarved things
into odd members of buckets in this case
with three ballad next ops 2 3 & 4 it
truncates the 15th bucket kind of cool
finally so some examples of doing this
here's a quick test we did 2 nameservers
up pointing queries towards ns1
pseudo-random sources just a stupid
little script running through and we see
about ten percent equivalence up above
balance so yeah it works who'd a thought
some caveats obviously today ecmp and
cisco 16 paths maximally this can be
resolved by having two switches we've
done some chaining if you will where
once which has two next hops living in
the second switch each of those machines
each of those next hops then for a
machine a machine be if you will can
have multiple more parallel using few
routes so if you were to go totally hog
wild I would presume he could do 16th to
the 16th possible machines behind this
concept with two switches I wouldn't
recommend it may be a server irons good
then but it certainly is something you
might already have in the rack so why
not connection tracking doesn't really
exist if a machine were to fail from the
group say a three machine group failing
to a to machine group any distribution
you have of connections aren't
guaranteed to be sustained to the
machine that we're currently going to
because the hash buckets are going to be
recurve completely a session that was
coming in towards NS 1 or a TCP
connection to www one may not land on
two if furry fails that's a an issue but
be aware of it you also don't have the
ability to let the protocol in this case
ecmp is not really protocol but the
mechanism doesn't know at the load of
the underlying machines for an
application like recursive name server
purposes irrelevant for something a bit
more complicated whether interface to
some ERP stuff work or you could take 10
seconds or a minute might be a bigger
problem for you don't do this do
something look more elegant we call so
don't get any support in these kinds of
products for direct easy ways to
translate say a public IP on average
interface to arbitrary number of 10 dot
something machines behind it if you
wanted to use net features I guess 723
bxl whatever can do this translation
you're going to have flow over a head
for connection setup and teardown just
deal with that interestingly in this
research we discovered that on SX and SR
and newer versions of 1240 there was an
option to include in cisco ecmp
calculations layer for headers later for
portions of adam and seems to be even
more even distribution than using that
so in summary a couple things to keep in
mind just configure it do something and
show IP profit thanks one minute and if
leah leah was already on his way up
great and after Leo X Ryan Dixon