okay so this is actually based on some
ideas and some work actually did a
number of years ago never really did
anything with it because there wasn't
actually very easy to do back then but I
get access to some infrastructure that
makes a little easy this time so the
basic idea is there is this a public
exchange disappearing fabric this is
where a number of routers may be
connected to iniquitous or switching
data or d6 or any other of the dozens of
exchange is what we want to try to do is
figure out who's pairing with who on the
public exchange fabric and so what you
have to do it and it's not anything
that's not obvious but you get behind
the network that you want to figure out
who has peer relationships with others
and do Trace routes and if you can trace
route to one of the public pier
addresses and get a response you can
presume that they're their peer and so
of course you have to go find out all
these bedros blocks that the exchange
uses and you have to somehow get behind
all these networks to build this graph
so one easy way to do that is to use the
the pairing DB there's a list of
approaching 200 exchanges in there and
there's at least 125 prefixes that you
can get them which are mostly
twenty-fours but there's some / 19 s and
some 25 s and some s'mores and then you
get a number of remote hosts which may
be easier for some than others I have
access to a number of machines around
the net on different providers and as
well as the there's a nice tool kit that
you can use the script route which is
essentially kind of based on the planet
lab infrastructure and you just launched
a ruby based tools and commands and they
have everything I'll pre-built for doing
trace route and you essentially launch
your trace route using any of the
servers that are part of the scripture
out of network so you can get behind
those networks or at least a great deal
of them and then you get your traceroute
output and then you start parsing
through that and then see who's actually
cured so I did that and i just used
speakeasy because that was one of the
first ones like I
wanted to graph for this top and so I
discovered that at the five major
equinix locations this is what their
paragraph looks like so they were the
center and all the nodes that the edges
are people there appeared with now the
work that i did is maybe not exactly I
wasn't rover giris in doing this so if
someone from speakeasy is looking at
this and sees the numbers are slightly
off that maybe my name is some here and
there in fact one of the things I
discovered right away is that there
there was five that they arrived at the
green X exchanges here in North America
they list for on their appearing page
and they list for and appearing to be
those two sets of four are not congruent
so this is maybe a nice way to actually
kind of verify your configuration or
someone else's configuration trying to
find out where were people out who their
period with so then you can go further
and you can do an entire exchange
peering Ralph so if you can get behind
enough networks you can actually start
to build up to see who really peers with
who and depending if you can get in
behind enough networks and watch enough
tracer outs and do the analysis you can
you could build something like this this
is again this is a sample this is not
everyone at the equinix ashburn but it's
sort of a subset of some networks and
who they're connected to and some fairly
significant ones like 80 and hurricane
and some others and so that may be the
obvious question is then you know is
this something that we should be able to
do is this a good thing is it a bad
thing is the you know how how is this
possible why can you actually do this so
people in my experience and just looking
at this sort of tangentially is is that
the the network's we're at these
exchanges at least tend to advertise
those exchange net blocks within their
own network so internally so if you're
behind with those networks you can get
to those public addresses at the
exchange a few do seem to announce them
publicly into customers or peers for
some reason I don't know exactly why
this is my guess is that maybe default
configuration of the we just reconnected
perhaps I actually inquired one of the
networks this afternoon about why they
do that and I get so cannot answer I'm
not clear on why
but currently they said it was as a as a
service to their customers and I don't
know why any customers will want to see
the public address space that was their
answer I think they didn't really have a
lot of time to actually want to spend on
this and I don't blame them so do we
care about this you know I don't know
this is maybe just sort of interesting
but isn't necessarily a bad thing I
don't know maybe it's not so much but
opens up some possibilities for
something may be interesting to people
to work on maybe it makes some certain
attacks more possible or enable some I'm
almost done if you can you wait once i
get trial so it may be enable some sorts
of attacks may be Geographic based
attacks so in North America this may not
be such an issue because we have lots of
exchanges and lots of lots of places but
maybe for smaller markets this may be an
issue so people may be concerned about
enumeration of privacy issues obviously
this might be neat for researchers to
actually understand topology better
maybe certain exchange operators may
want to do market research maybe not
necessarily on their own exchanges but
to see how they compare to other
exchanges and maybe they were hire
someone to do surveys of us like this
you may even be able to figure out where
you actually want to go in and peer at
based on building these sorts of maps
and then lastly something Danny
Macpherson pointed out to me sort just
made it in time for the slides it's this
may enable easier stealing of transit if
you can get if someone is actually
advertising this public address space
either globally or from than their
network maybe it is set up a tunnel and
actually use that facility to actually
use their use that to actually transit
through those pairing addresses not
having use your own and so just a real
quick I'd be interested if anyone
actually thinks this is sort of
worthwhile where I should spend any more
time on this or if this isn't athis is
or if you'd want to see like the Dwayne
wessels kind of maps on the source they
can maybe animations about
you know how peering evolves over time
just made a quick show of hands is sort
of interesting maybe some want me to or
have someone actually do more of these
maps or rafts just any value not so much
okay someone have a question over here
hi Lois Lee equinix so I spoken with
some of our customers about why they are
announcing the exchange subnet and
they've at one answer which I have
accepted from them is that they announce
only to their transit customers to
facilitate a trace route that the
customer might do so it doesn't look
like that there is some kind of bad
stuff going on at the exchange interface
so that their trays alpaca to get back
to them okay well thank you this is
derived from recommendations in about
februari in 1997 at nanog I'm cited
missed the first of our case against
Randy Bush IJ this what it Louie just
described is specifically from
recommendations made by a group out of a
group of backbone operators for how to
operate at an exchange point which is to
announce the exchange point fabric down
not to pierce okay and is it may be also
useful bothering to imagine canticle
beta monitoring their thirst I mean your
network and your customers want to see
that but you don't want to enhance it
appears they should be announcing it to
their cultures some people do seem to
announce a globally in certain cases and
certain exchanges seem to be better
about it than others but thanks okay
thank