this to them are our Charter is to
participate in advanced research and try
and provide the most advanced network
that we can do the research universities
and by extension serve the rest of the
of the community so quickly go over
merits present a merits history back
about forty one years ago the three
major research universities in Michigan
thought it'd be really cool if they
could connect up their mainframes since
they didn't really know how to do it
they formed merit to do so merit during
most of its existence has been involved
with research and trying to push forward
forward networking and internet working
probably our greatest cream claim to
fame is our involvement the NSFNET with
MCI and IBM and one of the offshoots of
our work with the NSFNET was nano so in
1994 we started to sponsor nanog to get
the operators together to help make this
the internet work and that for those of
you who are interested next month the
NSFNET is celebrating its 20th
anniversary in Washington DC and el
gourmet attend we're working on that the
we've also spun off a number of
different companies many of you have
worked for merit or worked with merit in
the past so this is merits mission and
we're nanog fits in is if you look in
the second half of our mission
initiating and facilitating
collaboration and providing knowledge
and technology transfer through outreach
so so even though the most of you are
are not from Michigan and not that part
of our community one of the reasons that
the board has merit in existence is this
outreach and knowledge transfer in this
fostering community and collaboration so
is a non-for-profit this is something
that we can do in a vendor neutral
environment better than people who have
a profit motive and have to serve
serve their owners and make sure they
get a good return on investment so
hopefully you find nanog to be a
valuable experience and that it is a
little different than most of the vendor
sponsored conferences so on the next
point is where we going to go from here
say we for 13 years we've been doing
some pretty neat stuff here in nanog
we've gone through some changes
everything goes through life cycles
ideas come into existence get rare very
popular and then the environment moves
on those ideas are not as effective so
it's important for nanog to continue to
evolve to be relevant and to provide
value to you the community over the last
couple of years the nanog leadership has
focused on how to run nanog how to work
through its relationship with merit and
how to run the organization I think it's
time now for nanog leadership to focus
on a vision for the future and to where
where are we going to bring nanog what's
it going to try and accomplish how is it
going to interact with all of you
there's been some discussion of this on
nanog futures but I'm going to challenge
the new steering committee to come up
with a vision and a strategy that
American implement to make nanog more
valuable to you for them to do that
there's a number of things that have to
happen we are the North American network
operators group so I did put Johnny
Canuck up there along with Uncle Sam for
those of you from other countries you
know sorry North Americans in the name
but anyways we have a vote going on and
the you need to know who you're voting
for you need to know that candidates for
the steering committee what their vision
is what they would like to see nanog
accomplished and does that align with
what you want to get out of nanog you
also need to talk to the steering
committee themselves and let them know
what you want what you want to get out
of nanog this is a valuable organization
only so much as it serves you and if you
sit back passively and nanog isn't
meeting your needs then well it's your
own fault but we have a steering
committee we have program committee
we've got
people for merit talk to us let us know
what you want let us know your ideas
participate nanog futures and help us
make nanog more valuable and a better
organization that's more valuable to you
thanks and West before we get started in
the main program is BAE pills a crumb
Aaron I for those of you who don't know
this is one of our annual joint meeting
with Erin so we have today and tomorrow
and they are in meeting is wednesday
through friday so for those of you who
haven't been to an errand before I
encourage you to stick around and see
what the public policy process is about
good morning I have no slides and I will
not take up much of your time for those
of you that have seen the discussions on
various mailing lists the air in public
policy mailing lists the air discussed
list also some discussions on an analyst
and also ITF discuss list you know that
there's going to be very very
interesting time on Wednesday and
Thursday of this week in our public
policy meeting there are 13 policy
proposals that are on the on the agenda
most of these deal with the those topics
that have been discussed a lot of them
have to do with ipv6 current policies
for how ipv6 is managed from a registry
perspective also there are two proposals
that are global policy proposals to
attempt to look at what to do with the I
ana free pool as it depletes and also
there's a policy proposal about what
errands should be doing as the it's free
pool depletes and how to manage that
situation there's also a going to be a
panel on IP markets and would be other
discussions open mics and so forth this
we'll also be discussing particularly on
Friday in detail the proposed you should
say the the legacy services agreement
registration services agreement that we
just posted the day before yesterday or
yes I can't run which and that is
actually in response to community
request that says that we need to
address this issue so this is a one of
the means by which the board is
attempting to do so your input is
valuable and if you cannot if you have
not made plans to stay over and can do
so please do so if not our meeting as
our meetings are will be webcast and you
can remotely participate in the
discussions so for those of you that are
going to be there or can be there I say
thank you and welcome and i'll see you
on Wednesday for those of you that will
be doing remotely I'll say thank you and
welcome and I'll see you somewhere or
other on Wednesday as well so thanks