alright so for those of you who were in
Bellevue we had a pretty interesting
panel on 40 gig and 100 gig and some of
the work went on there in the standards
bodies and I thought it would be a good
follow-on to continue with another panel
talking about some of the optical
developments going on in research work
in that world in that in that space if
you will and some of you may not know it
but Drew's company do a perkins for
infant area here they started working on
their stuff quite a long time ago right
about the time the bottom fell out of
the industry if i'm not mistaken and
they actually made it through and they
got their box to market and they're
doing quite well what's kind of cool
about that is there was a lot of work
going on in the in the optical space
prior to that and when the bottom fell
out all that cool work going on stop
happening and now things are slowly
starting to pick back up and some of
that works starting to get engaged again
and come to fruition for so hopefully
we'll see some more cool stuff coming
down the pike here soon why it's
important in the internet space in the
IP space is it gives us some really cool
new tools and ways to move more bits
more efficiently better spectral
efficiency if you will some people like
that term better throughput better reach
all these new things going on so I had
Kimball the idea to put together a panel
to kind of talk about some of those
things and this is that panel and I'll
introduce our speakers here briefly if
you want to read their BIOS please feel
free to do so they're on the web I am
NOT going to regurgitate them for you to
my right your left is Drew Perkins who
from in from infant area he's a CTO
their prior to that light terra for
systems get that right right to my left
and your right is gary nickel from cisco
he's an engineer in their optical unit
out of ottawa canada not a marketing guy
so we won't have any of those here to
his left and further to my fear right
his ross saunders from strata light who
has been involved an optical
transmission system since 1992 they get
that right and i think you guys are like
this panel there's some good stuff going
to be talked about
I'm going to ask that you save your
questions till the end I do not want to
see us get rat hole between
presentations and burn 20 minutes and
then shortchange some of the other
speakers so if you all would be kind
enough to do that that would be awesome
and with that we'll let drew go first
drew you're on deck all right good
morning everybody Thank You Ted I've got
the more slides here than I should so
I'm going to be going pretty quick
through them here just a bit more on my
background I've been involved in the
internet since the very early 80s
actually was one of the first people
that the very first IETF actually and
I've had a long background in Internet
as well as optical technology but spent
most when I have a sort of layer three
two and one and on down so this is my
perspective on what's what's going on
here the next generation of optical
transport how it relates to IP so the is
just an agenda slide we talk about
ethernet and how that relates to IP and
optical transport what we call super
lame the services bonding multiple
channels together 10 gige under Giggy
and where we think it needs to be going
as quickly as possible terribly ethernet
we talked about some work we're doing on
reconfigurable IP router bypass mention
a tour thing a thing or two about
modulation approaches and then talk a
little bit about photonic integration
and unfortunately we're not gonna be
able to cover any of these things in
depth at all to the brevity of time here
but ask questions later please so we've
been doing an interesting study at
infinite we've been basically modeling
an IP network nationwide continental US
IP network from sort of top-down
starting with you know there's this much
population in these areas of the country
help now and you have these pieces
equipment to build from go to and how
would you do that and we're developing
an analysis system that does that and so
one of the first things and i'll talk
about a few things where we're finding
as weed is obviously it's kind of a
no-brainer obviously 10 gigabit ethernet
wins on router shipping today anyway 10
gige is much more cost effective than
gig pause or a 40 gig pause if you plot
these curves out basically the curves
I'm showing at the bottom here what we
do is we're scaling an IP network from
for a range of one to two hundred six
times as large somewhere towards the
left side there well maybe a third in is
sort of a terabit level where a number
of big carriers today and going out
probably another 5-10 years as a scalar
capacity and no matter how far out you
get 40 gig pause sort of never catches
up I'll say more about that so Ethernet
the future of optical transport really
appears to be Ethernet basis by far the
most cost-effective thing it's kind of a
no-brainer mother heading up apple pie
I'm sure so just sort of definition what
we think there we go IP links you know
years ago more than a decade ago yes
used to be what we call sub lambda that
means you had a lambda a wavelength
running across your transport network
and then you carved it up into TDM time
slots using sonet/sdh and IP used t1
than a ds3 then OC 3 OC 12 now finally
in the sort of towards the late 90s IP
caught up to up to sonet/sdh to optical
transport started using a whole
wavelength at a time you have the WDM
systems optical transport systems
emerged and first we start using two and
half gig wavelengths then we stepped up
to 10 then you know earlier this decade
we started to need more than a wave life
and you start having started having to
bond circuits together between a core
adjacent corn oats and your IP network
we call that super lambda we're using
multiple lambdas to to aggregate a leg
to get a composite link a link
aggregation group whatever you call
there's a bunch of terms for it
basically inverse multiplexing of your
IP packets over a number of different
lambdas to get enough throughput enough
capacity for your IP to meet your IP
service needs right so if you sort of
look at where where traffic's going and
has been doing you know a couple years
ago already we were using you know n by
where n was as much as eight lengths you
know three or two years ago or so and
this curve just sort of plots out a
couple different growth rates
seventy-five percent hundred twenty-five
percent probably the probably should
have maybe had fifty percent there but
even if the 75 percent growth rate which
may be as close to where a lot of people
were growing get out to buy 2010 you
looking at one point three terabytes per
second is that the demand the need that
you have to scale your each length
between core IP router knows so
obviously there is no nothing on the
drawing board right now and the
standards groups as far as terabit
lengths to everybody the net in
particular although that's been
discussed a bit in the I Triple E and uh
Tripoli right now is working 100 gig e
but so right now you got a bunch of
errors that are looking at putting in 40
gig lengths to update to upgrade from
their their 10 gig links which are
largely going to 10 gige at the same
time in some curves as I said before the
40 gig really hasn't cost effective but
we are getting a forex jump and
bandwidth perhaps so at the I Triple E
in the discussions of hundred Giggy that
have been going on number of carriers
have come in and said you know what this
hundred Giggy is just not enough it's
what I need today by 2010 I need
terribly Ethernet need need a whole lot
more other than that level 3s put out
projections they're going to be running
150 x 10 gig between core nodes in in
2010 and other carriers have made
similar statements so clearly we need to
to be able to keep scaling the the links
between core nodes to pretty pretty
dramatic levels of capacity and no
matter what transport technology you're
looking at whether it's 10 gig 40 gig
the hunter gig number of people are
talking to 100 you gonna wave like
you're still in any case even 100 gig
level going to be putting multiple
having to bond together multiple
wavelengths together we're living in a
super lambda world and we're going to
continue living there from here on out
all links are going to end up being
super lambda here between at least
within the core of you
wrkn even getting into the cross back
called lengths it's here to 2 or 3 links
it's no getting around that so as I said
we're doing the study trying to look at
the economics of a building an IP
network a combined I p+ transport
network the whole shooting match
basically and this pictures just this
lies are showing here you know a network
without router bypass ie each core
router is connected to its topologically
adjacent neighbor ok sort of the
conventional way to build a network
people have been doing some amount of
bypass you know for for many years but
most of the to eliminate the degree this
slide is just showing no degree at all
just pure no router bypass that's where
the baseline alright and as you do that
of course what you have is is you have
IP packets the core routers are serving
a lot of transit capacity right you know
the router is in the middle a lot of
their capacity of switching capacity is
just coming in going out again from east
to west west east whatever without being
dropped at that local site or shifted
switched to a tier 2 node there's just
going from one tier 1 link to another
tier 1 length so you're you're spending
your router's of course are the most
expensive part of your network routers
today are far more expensive than
transport equipment you pay you know
almost an order of magnitude maybe at
least half an order magnitude more per
bit per second for an IP router blade
interface than you do for transport so
if you're spending most your router on
show on switching capacity in and out
you know seventy-five percent or ninety
percent of your capacities just going in
one high-speed interface to a noun other
one from one tier one node to another
you're spending an awful lot on using
your router as a regenerator basically
so it becomes increasingly inefficient
so what happens when you start adding
router bypass to the picture right what
I mean by that is let's start building a
mesh at the at the from at the layer
three IP layer across the transport
layer so people of course have been
doing this to luminance degree in the
past most large networks do this you
know
dc2 la New York to San Francisco those
types of links but it's been very
limited because it has limited
cost-effectiveness there's a few places
that there's very high demands going
between but but not all that many so
we've been studying this and seeing okay
well if that's true how does that scale
as the network scales as we get out to
2010 and beyond and we start getting to
terabit links what opportunities start
presenting themselves to putting in IP
router bypass links to shunt traffic
directly across transport nodes and
bypass intermediate IP routers and what
kind of cost savings does that get you
okay so here you see a picture a graph
here and these are somewhat preliminary
numbers but we but they're they're
pretty much on on target what we see is
that the ability to add in IP router
bypass links increases over time as you
scale your network higher and higher and
higher so what you see on the left for
instance the very top graph each of the
each of these lines is a an amount of
savings it looks like my units got cut
off on the left side I'm sorry but this
is sort of one hundred percent is what
the network costs with no router bypass
at all and then you know as you go down
to sixty percent or whatever it is what
your network would cost as you add
router bypass links okay and and then
each line is as you add scale to your
network which is basically equates to as
the if your network we're doubling every
year for instance then you know five
years is two to the six to the fifth 64
32 times etc and then the number there
the scale the network is plotted so what
you see is that and the other thing to
say about this graph is we stopped the
plot at the point where if you add
another router bypass link to your
network it's going to get more expensive
not less and what's happening there is
if the network that we're modeling here
happens to have 18 corn oats so there's
18 x 17 possible bypass links between
corn oats and so out of the 306 how far
did you get before it starts becoming
more expensive than what you see is that
low scales it only makes sense to add a
couple which is sort of where most
networks have come
from beyond just a few lengths maybe
five they never can get more expensive
and what's happening is that the demands
between if you look at the matrix of
demand between all the core nodes some
are going to be the very high ones are
going to be more than a lambda others
going to be less than lambda and if
you're buying if you need less than
lambda but you're buying IP router
interfaces on both ends to support that
that demand you're going underutilized
and it's becoming very inefficient so
the number of times you can do that of
course scales grows as a scale the
network so even if the even if the
transport network were free it doesn't
make sense to put all of your traffic in
a full mesh configuration because you're
under utilizing the router interfaces to
a great degree and this is sort of a
fallacy if there's a lot of people have
an eyeball all optical switching model
where they assume that eventually the
networks going to scale to being all
optical switches in the middle and this
IP routers at the edge is sort of one of
the visions the industry that vision
turns out doesn't make any sense at all
you're always going to need IP routers
to aggregate traffic because that full
matrix if you plot it out there's many
lengths it's a sparse sparse matrix
where it makes sense to actually put
these things all right so if that's true
10 gig what happens at 40 gig well the
answer is that 40 gig already starts out
less cost effective than 10 gige if
you're using that and 40 gig now your
lambda is running faster which means
that the demand necessary to make that
by passing like makes sense needs to be
even greater which basically means your
whole curve shifts it's just right or
left then you better miss perspective so
it makes less and less sense and what's
going to happen is we get hundred Giggy
it makes less and less than so there's
basically a tension between the demand
the capacity of a single wavelength 10
gig 4800 good versus the scale versus
putting in these router by passing links
to where you get the most cost effective
bandwidth all right now also as you
start putting an IP router bypass links
you also create a need for being able to
reconfigure your your optical transport
network because as traffic shifts as new
sources pop up new popular website
sporting events what
her as IP peering BGP Jason sees come
and go whatever traffic shifts pretty
dramatically sometimes you want to be
able to reconfigure your your transport
network on the fly to do that so that's
something you'd like to do so a vision
in the industry right now is all optical
road ohms to be able to do that be able
to switch all optically as I said that
that will make sense for some amount of
these bypass lengths but given the
limited use of these bypass links
depending on scale it makes more or less
sense of course road ohms all optical
networks have a bunch of problems or
issues because there's no oao going on
so there's no wavelength interchange is
no regeneration there's no performance
management OMP etc excuse me and also
there's wavelength contention and
blocking because there's no wavelength
interchange going on which makes you
know routing through that network be
even even more expensive what you see is
that what our size are showing is that
there's a thirty to forty percent
incremental cost on the OEO side now if
you're using your router's as duro EO to
switch wavelengths you're using the most
expensive device in your network to do
it pretty simple transit function so
also your service becomes limited by the
wavelength path because of reach number
of rosy path through every time you pass
the road owe me a decrease your reach
etc alright we believe the right answer
is is what we call digital rodents which
are air every node is a capable full oao
and therefore full in wavelength
interchange full statistics etc but
through photonic integration technology
it becomes very inexpensive to do that
and you get at digital protection in the
optical layer as possible it's another
interesting thing that we're seeing that
historically it's been the case it has
made no sense to do protection in the in
the transport layer at once once we went
to the lambda level beyond sonnet you
know when we had sonic we did protection
in the sonnet layer well we went to
individual lambdas all protections delay
or three the most cost-effective thing
it's not intuitive but what our studies
are showing is as network scales too
much higher in a few years from now
basically it actually starts to make
more sense
to do some amount some of them out of
your protection in the optical layer
again and transport layer and we'll be
back way to talk about that more as we
study that will further so anyway if you
can do things digitally because of
because you've made oao less expensive
yet you give yourself a degree of
freedom that unconstrained you for
digital and drop right so question now
is where how we r we going to keep
scaling capacity in the future going
from 10 to 40 hundred where things going
you know there's lots of different ways
to scale capacity ur network there's a
simple tried and true approach of space
division multiplexing give me another
fiber give me another circuit give me
whatever peril optics etcetera there's
time division multiplexing just pure TDM
that's sort of been tried to go from ten
at ten we're kind of hit a roadblock
there it was tried at forty the first
generation of 40 gig stuff did n RZ it
turned out that ran into so many
problems because of dispersion
polarization low dispersion chromatic
dispersion all kind of things
nonlinearities people are now stepping
back and using fancier modulation
approaches and looks like we're starting
down a road where first thing would sort
of do a binary there's a whole bunch of
different terms like throw acronyms all
day at you but you know at the end of
the day things may very well end up much
like in dsl or cable modems or wireless
where you're going down you know big
constellations of quam and you know i'll
be surprised if we don't you know aren't
talking to qualms 2010 20 for several
years from now but but we'll see and of
course there's the also tried and true
wavelength division multiplexing so all
these things are really equivalent you
can you can get additional capacity by
doing any of these things the question
really is one of economics and so just
looking at history as a guy here what
have we seen with 40 gig those darn
expensive we didn't get the four times
bandwidth increase for four types of
costs it turned out much greater than
four times the cost right wasn't two and
a half times as we wanted right a lot of
people will in the transport industry
are now talking about hundred cape coral
am there's lots of different approaches
being thrown out that's where the
biggest one most popular one being
thrown houses dual polarization qpsk
quadrature phase-shift King approach
basically you're taking 100 Gig 100
gigabits really dividing down a 250 gig
channel sending each one over different
polarizations so doing polarization
division multiplexing across your fiber
as well as wavelength division
multiplexing each of those takes more
part in more components and then within
each quad each polarization you're doing
a qualm for basically trying to get two
bits for every symbol across your
network you're basically building a big
modem and what we're seeing so far is
that even at the 40 gig level that the
best ship available now that's been
published is burning 21 wats to do that
kind of modulation at 40 gig nobody
knows yet what it's going to take a
hundred gig but the answer is
undoubtedly much more than that so it
becomes very power hungry which equates
to almost directly to cost because power
dissipation is the most costly thing to
do but also is clear that you require
significant integration to do this
approach as well what will cost the the
I saw just last week get a conference
one vendor was suggesting that's going
to be about two and half times the cost
of 40 gig so for a gig 100 giggly at
parity on a cost per bit basis well a 40
gig is much more expensive than 10 gig
you know I we think that people are just
going to stay at 10 gig for quite some
time at least for a lot of networks so
10 gig of course infinera has been
shipping 10 gig 10 channels attending
integrated on a single chip photonic
integrated circuit as it's called since
2004 all right and we predicted cost so
that's going to keep going down so
interesting thing about pics is ten by
ten isn't the limit we've published
papers on 1.6 terabit pics that run 40
channels of 40 gig there's a lot of room
for growth there and not only are going
to need to increase the line capacity
you know a single line card you want to
get that scaling from 10 to 40 to 100
where we are today to four hundred or a
thousand you know terabit level also
want to scale your you're lying
bandwidth in finners shown some exposure
approaches publishing papers nellen pic
based what they call SOA semiconductor
optical amplifiers that
can give you a much greater bandwidth
across your fiber than today's
erbium-doped fiber amplifiers so there's
a whole lot of approaches to go from 1.6
therapist for instance to tens of
terabytes I just read a paper the other
day that and showed how to get 150
terabits across a single fiber so
there's lots of ways to get there and
summary of just say that it's pretty
clear that ethernet is going to continue
to grow up is already and going to
continue rolling the day economically we
believe at least is the interface super
lambdas here to get a stay it's going to
remain the norm and become popular it's
very important to integrate that and
optical transport has Transport has to
become much more flexible to enable much
more IP router bypass this the least
expensive way to get there and mobile
terrible lighting systems are going to
be necessary terrible end cars required
so all that's going to take massive
integration whether you're doing pure
and WD m or gdm or fancy quam modulation
integrations necessary and all that
stuff thanks
don't know where Val words you put these
people under other
good mornin thanks Ted for inviting us
to this say this conference and I must
admit I didn't understand too much of
the talks have been gone on today so
it's time to get my own back here with
some some optical stuff and I will be
thrown a few acronyms over here so
apologies up front for that hey what I'm
going to talk about now is it's really
the alternate religion to what drew has
been talking about their Drew's really
talking about basically building more
lanes on the highway and get stuck in
with the same speed whereas our religion
is much more on trying to increase the
speed on each lane so that's increasing
the capacity and each wavelength one of
the critical things is try to see if we
can engineer 100 gigabyte modems so that
they can plug into existence systems
which basically means in the long haul
network exists in tank 10 gigabit
systems so introduction for a gig market
is really just beginning to take off I
agree with what drew said the price
point is still more than 4 x 10 gig at
this point in time the Sun a steep cost
reduction curve as a volume packs up as
dope is more expensive it has been
deployed by some very large carriers and
that's that's really driven by the
increase in capacity you can't just look
if you just look at the cost of the
transponder vs 4 10 gig the economics
don't price then you have to look at a
total cost of ownership where the IP
traffic is growing so fast that carriers
don't necessarily want to be burning
through multiple d WM / belts which cost
money to buy those new WM systems to
install them etc so that's you know
that's where we are at the moment just
just in its infancy but growing pretty
fast we've driven by a lot by converged
IP networks video distribution
peer-to-peer video very on-demand all
that stuff is really scaling up and you
know pretty much most of the SMS out
there the core network will more or less
double every couple years so that's
that's very high high growth curve there
optical transport special efficiency so
this is the capacity that you can get
per fiber and the port speed coming off
the
the IPO or Ethernet switches etc hasta
has to keep pace for that growth this is
the growth curve i mean you know that
we're back again at 2000 we can pull out
the same curve again hopefully it
doesn't go the same way as a went in
2002 2003 but you know it's all been
driven by video and what was a good
growth there a hundred gag requirements
there's a whole bunch of detailed
requirements here in terms of really
just making it work on the on the
existing infrastructure so you know the
current standard in terms the long haul
network is a 50 gigahertz WDM channel
spacing and to keep most carriers happy
at least in the in the US we want a 1500
plumber or greater reach there may be
metro regional opportunities and other
national areas asia and europe where
that where the reach can be a bit less
really all of these things at the end of
they come down to you got you got to
make it work with what's installed in
the field so you can just plug this new
technology straight into existing
systems that's that's really what's
helped with get the get the 40 gig
market started as the fact that for a
gig was engineered so that you can plug
it into those existing systems which
means more advanced modulation formats
higher spectral efficiency but you know
that that really enabled it unable to
market and get going if you require a
carrier to deploy a whole new WM line
system then it becomes a tougher sale
because now there's a big cost
associated with deploying a new system
certifying a new system training the
engineers to work on a new system so
that that mantra we're trying to keep
that in mind as we as we go towards
engineering 100 gigabit systems some of
the technology considerations you've
always got a trade-off complexity for
performance and as you go to more
complex solutions it does drive up the
cost as well so you have to keep that
keep that discipline there and many of
the schemes also trade off spectral
efficiency for reach so as you go to
higher levels of coding then usually
that that involves a reduction in the
signal noise ratio and has a reduction
in the reach
another part is that you got to use
practical electronics so at the moment
even if for a gigabit we are using
leading-edge electronics processing
speed so it's the same as we move to 100
gigabit you got to build a use existing
production qualified electronics
transistor technology an electrical
signal process and in general is lower
cost and optical and so once you get the
volume up there the cost of the chips is
certainly lower cost and the optical
compensator so that's you know again
something that we've got keep in mind as
we as we engineer these solutions and
also you can gain a lot of insight from
other industries so a lot underseas
other industries have had to fight the
spectral efficiency battles before we
have an optical so you know you can look
at wireless gsm use some advanced
modulation formats minimum shift keying
HDTV and using trellis coded modulation
some advanced if you see satellite using
the quadrature phase-shift keying
quadrature amplitude modulation so again
you know high spectral efficiency there
wimax using the orthogonal
frequency-division multiplexing another
technique with a good spatial efficiency
so you can look at all these different
industries and say okay how can out you
know how can that help us out to get
higher spectral efficiency a 100
gigabits again bear in mind got use
practical electronic speed because the
optical opticals bandwidth bandwidth
poor speeders is obviously much higher
also the use of DSP is is immature and
optical communications so say you know
we can predict it that that's going to
become a more important component of the
overall design as as time moves on the
other thing is fiber non-linearity so
the there is a nonlinear effect in the
fiber that we you have to watch the
amount of power that you can launch this
is this applies to today's systems but
when you go to higher Lane raise more
advanced modulation formats that becomes
an even bigger constraint so it's not
like Wireless we're in general you can
keep jacking up the the launch power
they are we we have to we have to watch
that with with the optical domain so
apologies this is a acronym supiera
thrown a year but
basically there's a map and all
different kinds of modulation formats
and you can look at the pros and cons
here we're looking at spectral
efficiency versus optical signal noise
ratio so really to be in the zone where
we have something interests and we want
to really be in this green quadrant
ideally we want to have a spatial
efficiency of two bits per second
perhaps that enables you to deploy a
hundred gigabytes on 50 gigahertz
channel spacing and in terms of optical
signal noise ratio if you get in this
this regime of 12 13 14 DB now we're in
the regime where we can we can do 1,500
kilometres type reach so that's the kind
of design target area if you look at
some of the other options like oh okay
is basically on-off keying which is
pretty much what everybody's used for 10
gigabit and that doesn't have the
spectral efficiency or or the reach so
you know that that is the simplest
format but it just doesn't it doesn't
work for 100 gig some other formats
optical geo binary you've got better
special efficiency it would work on 100
gig grid but doesn't have the the OS and
our sensitivity wouldn't have wouldn't
have good enough reach you've got some
other formats a quadrature phase-shift
keying differential quadrature ship fish
ackee and these ones again one bit per
second perhaps they're a bit better spit
or cenar but better reach but you can't
get the special efficiency really then
you've got 16 level qualms which has got
multiple levels between it it has very
good special efficiency but you lose
some in terms of reach so you and bill
ahead the thousand kilometer plus they
preach polarization marks that's what
the PM stands for they are qpsk PMD qpsk
now we can get down to a 25 giga baud
rate so you're coding for bits per per
symbol now you've got the spectral
efficiency you need and reaches getting
there is still a challenge really to
improve the the reach we really need to
go to next generation either trellis
coded modulation or soft decision
forward error correction which kind of
gets you closer to the theoretical limit
the Shannons limit as a color on there
on signal noise ratio performance so you
know there's a lot advanced advanced
stuff required together if you look at
implementation complex the ink which you
know does translate through and to
intercourse their you know their that
you've got a trade-off between the
electronic complexity and the photonic
complexity so of course the the format's
that they're easier to implement have
lower complexity and but they don't have
the the reach are the are the spectral
efficiency so looking at these advanced
modulation formats such as PMD qpsk RPM
qpsk and let's increase the photonic
complexity quite a bit especially the PM
qpsk which requires a coherent detection
which is really something something new
in the optical domain is used all the
time and other industries but to do it
optically is certainly more challenging
there when you look at these p.m. d qpsk
p.m. qpsk the electronics is is not as
bad because you're you're down a 25
bigger baud rate which means you can use
lower speed electronics so that's you
know that that is doable from from that
side this just shows you the kind of
transmitter receive block diagram for
one candidate format here hundred
gigabit polarization musts qpsk is quite
complex i mean if you compare this to an
on-off keying block diagram as you know
there's a lot more boxes on here is it
does translate through into costs here
in this case we have a couple of
modulators here your your your
marginally in two different polarization
tributaries and your for driver
amplifiers on the transmit sizes you
know it's a bit more complexity leah a
good thing is to make it practical is
your operating at this 25 bigger baud
rate so you know effectively the driver
amplifiers are lower bandwidth than we
use today 40 gigabits because 40 gigabit
systems that are deployed they are
operating at 40 you know one bit per
symbol which is a with FEC is a 43 gig
of Audrey so the the electrons some of
the electronics here is actually lower
speed on the receive side you've got
more complex that you've got a coherent
Tector so that means a local oscillator
which is basically actionable tunable
laser and you need a face like phase of
polarization diverse receiver and to do
the the phase estimation and do the
corner protection lock synchronous
coherent detection you need an
analog-digital converter and digital
signal process and there and that is a
new chip which it is pushing the limits
in terms of the electronic speed some of
the enabling technologies that there are
that help us to get there as you can
approach this from there's two two main
tools that can help you get there one is
use modulation scheme to try and make
their higher higher speed wavelength
operate over current systems and the
other side is to use dynamic
compensators and you can do that
optically and electrically so some of
the key technologies today is an optical
tunable dispersion compensator which is
a device called a fiber Bragg grating
which basically the kromagg if you have
large amounts of chromatic dispersion in
the link you can you can basically bring
the pulse shape batch back together
again by this sharp grating which is a
it basically just do it reflects
different wavelengths that light at
different point than the down the
grating structure so this is critical as
help does it for again as likely to help
us a 100 gig as well also we have a
polarization more dispersion come
vincere PMV is they're called
single-mode fibers but they really have
two polarization modes and and in older
fibers you can have dispersion between
the two of those so yet you have to
build a combat that too to make 40 gig
100 gig work so that's another critical
technology moving on to some of the
coherent detection schemes when you have
an ATD converter then then into a
digital signal processing chip when
coherent detection one of the advantages
is that you passed the the optical phase
into the electrical domain that doesn't
happen for the direct detection
mechanisms so now when you pass that
phase into the electronic to me now you
can digitize it quantize it and you can
use a digital photo
finite impulse response filters to
combat some of the the nasty optical
effects such as PMD chromatic dispersion
cascaded their felt filter tolerance so
this is something that is going to is
going to help in the future we'll go
through this in detail but basically
that we are at the moment we're already
using the state-of-the-art qualified
electronic processes and to do some of
this is dis advanced stuff especially
the fast analog-digital converter we
really need to go to the next generation
CMOS 45 nanometer CMOS or next
generation silicon germanium bi CMOS
which is around the 300 gigahertz ft
which is the the transistor process
roughly you need a rule of thumb where
you need five times the transistor speed
five times a day our way to build make
it work so when you go down to the 4 x
25 giga board for download digital
converter has to passed it through two
samples per board which means you're up
to the 60 Gigaba bigger sample per
second type speed to make that work 100
gigabits so that but really needs a fast
next-gen electronics process so we are
at the bleeding edge of electronic speed
I won't go through all the detail here
is is on the web there if you if you
want to look through it but certainly
when you compare the different different
options here you know to a large extent
you do get what you pay for i mean if
you if you want to make it work over a
50 gig bread if you want to build a 1500
plumber or reach plus you know you are
looking at a PMD qpsk or a PM qpsk type
type modulation format and there is a
cost premium a pay for that so you know
they said that that you go you gotta
bear that in mind really if you look at
100 gig it's going to be similar to wear
for it again as at the moment where you
have to look at the total cost of
ownership where you look at okay am I
going to be scaling my IP traffic so
fast that you know I'd oh I really I
really want to be able to deploy 100
gigabit channels on a 50 Giga have
spread which effectively gives you a
neat Arabic capacity for fiber
you know if you have low capacity growth
maybe it's not it's not the right option
for you you may be better gone but some
of the options that drew talked about
but certainly you know if you follow
this growth Carver 2x per year and
reality for 100 gigabit to be mature for
all the bugs to be ironed out to be
really field deployable and I carry on
network it is probably three years out
so you know three or four years I've so
if you look at the growth curve or the
capacity by then and at least in those
highest capacity networks that we feel
they're still going to be a need for it
just to summarize the traffic growth
been fueled by video IP rich media got
the hockey stick growth curve there and
again we've got a plan on this network
traffic growth to double every two years
or so at least until 2011 knows beyond
done deploy 100 gigabit wavelengths
using 10 gig rules as feasible it does
require this very high spectral
efficiency but do have to go to more
exotic modulation formats to make it
work but as possible through these
advanced schemes where we recordin
multiple bits per symbol so has taken
the you know taking the modulation
scheme to it to the next level there
reaches sell it still a challenge we
really need to get out to that 1500
plumber or type reach really need
coherent detection and or next
generation forward error correction that
gets us guess it's close to the Shannon
limit to the theoretical limit their the
optics is is fairly easy it's fairly
straightforward at 25 gig aboard you're
not pushing the boundary in terms of
modulator bandwidth or a or a photodiode
bandwidth this is really still still the
challenges is on the electronics and on
the electronic site in terms of the
making it work I would say the optics is
still a challenge that you do need some
level of photonic integration to be able
to get the cost down a bit but the you
know the bandwidth is not going to be an
issue there one of the critical
developments that we need there's an
extremely fast analog-digital converter
our digital signal processing chip and
that'll be one of the key key areas of
development thank you
alright next and last is Gary and then
we'll have some questions I would like
to reserve five minutes of question and
answer for the panelists amongst
themselves first and the old nanog phim
of what's throw tomatoes at each other
you didn't tell me that when I signed up
for this hi Sam my name is Gary nickel
working their court writing group ID of
the Ottawa office in Canada guess my
talk bisley leads on from the top from
Drew and and Ross talking about really
the impact of all this on on writers now
I've been in cisco for about ten years
now working on the evolution of the
primarily on the opportunities and the
writers and I've seen the optical
interface speeds increased dramatically
over that time from a boc 312 when I
started to ten and just no 40k recently
but they look at that primarily to did
those opportunities have been very
simple in a couple of respects that
they've probably been focusing just
doing very short regional forces
particularly predominantly two
kilometers that's predominant because
you want to connect one box another box
within the pop or maybe you want to
connect one writer switch to a transport
box which then basically is responsible
for transporting out thousands of
kilometers across the country and again
in terms of the optical technology as
Ross has mentioned to date up to like 10
gig anyway it's been very very simple
what's called on-off keying basically
you turn the light on you turn the light
off the light on is the one the light
off is the zero and it's been very
simple now as we're looking to go to
higher bandwidth connections at 40 and
100 gig again Ross of literature we're
going to be looking at a lot more
complicated modulation schemes and then
again is Drew alluded to to try and keep
the costs under control what we think is
that a lot of those modulation scheme
will actually sort of my great and be
implemented on the writer directly so
that
can basically derive those long haul
distances directly and you don't need
additional sort of costly high-speed
shore regional visit to connect to it to
a transport box I guess I should put
this on to slide show okay so this is my
version not quite of the the growth and
not quite as visually appealing is
Ross's hockey stick but it's basically
telling you the same message a couple of
interesting bison is that people are
projecting the trophy to grow to about
11 exabytes per month in like 2009-2010
until I put this presentation together
and talk to our marketing people had
never heard of an exabyte but but a part
of the one exabyte is five times the
world's printed matter and five exabytes
is all the words ever spoken so that
really sort of puts the sort of growth
in context and then this growth has been
alluded to before is primarily been
driven by or exclusively driven by data
primarily driven by sort of applications
both legacy and new applications as we
know like a lot of the legacy
applications are actually migrated into
an IP infrastructure even things like
standard sort of broadcast sort of video
for cable is moving from a well in the
past was probably a proprietary analog
distribution technology run basically on
an IP backbone directly to your set-top
box voice obviously moving to voice over
IP then there's a whole range auslly new
applications exclusive to IP that are
obviously driving up the bandwidth and
another statistic that I heard and is
that if you do a project if you look at
that household bandwidth demands for
like 2010 do all these new services and
applications listed above that 20 such
homes in 2010 will generate more traffic
than traverse the entire internet in
1995 no Ted did mention that she be
careful staying up here because somebody
might refute that so that's certainly
did a point that I've heard and seen
presented a few times but point being
anyway there's a lot of bandwidth with
growth there so again so given all this
where does this take us to obviously
we're going to need higher bandwidth to
to address this growth and I think all
of this in the panel are essentially
saying the same thing there 10 gig
networks today a beginning to feel the
strain and if you look at a lot of the
core networks today people are actually
starting to aggregate sort of multiple
10 gig screams together to to address
the bandwidth demand between some of
these these core pops if you look at how
you address that higher bandwidth
demanders number of ways you could do it
one way you could just use l2 l3 link
aggregation aggregate multiple smaller
pipes together on the right or switch
but really you can't rely on that that's
not a scalable solution as we're going
forward there's obviously a number of
issues with the efficiency of that as we
know and probably lot of people in this
room you know that on the efficiencies
are some of the algorithms the hash or
games used to sort of aggregate traffic
at layer 2 layer 3 it don't scale very
well and the sort of throughput of those
are is not deterministic it very much
depends on the statistics of the the
bandwidth and really what that comes out
to if you look at do anything at layer 2
layer 34 x 10 gig does not equal sort of
40k so again we have to be careful when
we're doing these comparisons of like 4
x 10 verses for weeks that may not be
just a straight comparison if you're
trying to do it at layer 2 layer 3 so
the other approach and again I guess is
what drew was alluding to in his talk is
okay well have a nice big fat pipe at
Thea off the router or the switch and
then but we'll still do some aggregation
at layer 1 so run that over so multiple
lower capacity wavelengths a 10 gig and
address a lot of those sort of link
adore like issues
so that against probably got more
Molly's but fundamentally at the end of
the day that approach does not scale as
well because ultimately your DWDM
systems the ports are not unlimited okay
maybe you've got a 40 or ha like a 40 or
80 channel DWDM system in the grind
today and as Ross ministered like
typically customers want to use up those
ports as efficiently and as slowly as
possible because once you've used them
all up it's a it's a fairly major
retrofit to install a whole news or a
DWDM system so going forward and so will
it really just two is that really you
want to increase wavelength capacity
like as soon as it's viable and that
really been moving to higher data rates
/ lambda so going to 40 gig which people
are starting to deploy now and obviously
a hundred big looking a little bit
further right and again as Ross
mentioned that these must operate over
existing infrastructure we can't have to
just install a whole brand-new transport
infrastructure to be able to carry these
40 and 100 feet waves you want to be
able to run it over the systems that
were installed like probably during the
bubble times which were originally
installed to carry 10 gig / we're so you
want to run 4,800 gig of those and
ideally you want to run it with the same
performance to 10g and by that I
basically mean in terms of the distance
you can go and i think is ross alluded
to you typically out people are looking
around sort of 1,500 kilometers in that
sort of the target we're trying to get
to with some of these new high-speed
links and i can i won't go through the
news but to do that once you're talking
14 100 gig does require us to move to
some more advanced modulation schemes
and actually the whole alphabet soup
that the Ross went through that that I
won't go into into much more detail in
this talk so in addition if you look at
bandwidth scrolling it's been
essentially driven by IP if you look at
what that means the network it does
provide the opportunity simplify the
network and resolved i'm primarily two
layers a service layer that's
predominantly converging on
p and a transport layer that's really
converging on two DWDM as the providing
the connection or the big fat pipes
between those those service letter
writer or switcher nodes and again is
interesting to step back and look at
that as well because I've been in
industry for like 25 years first half of
that was working in transport transport
started off pretty as a single service
transport it was providing transport for
at the time voice and then over time it
really migrated into more about sort of
the transport network malted into more
of a multi-service entity where it was
hard to provide transport not just for
voice but obviously for get in its
various forms like ATM and frame relay
and IP and leased lines and sort of
stuffs you end up with sort of fairly
complex transport network that had a
whole aggregation they are built in to
handle the these multi services and what
I see going forward is it will actually
migrating back more to a single service
transport network where again the
transport network is really just
providing transport for IP between these
switches and routers and I think again
if you look at a little bit further
right then it makes a lot of sense to
actually integrate a lot of that DW
closely couple of two layers and
integrate a lot of that DW technology
directly onto the riders will see in
some later slides so that's just what we
call IP of a WDM again just integrating
the GTM directly on the rider the
picture in the top right is really the
present mode of operation where the bit
on the right is the the transport layer
and what I was trying to show today is
that the transport aleris or a
multi-service you've got some
transponders connected to router so you
got some other transponders at the
bottom they are connected to transport
other services so the transport layer is
predominantly multi-service and because
of that you typically of these
transponders there because the
transponders are really a multi-service
that allow you to connect the transport
layer to all the different service types
it is transporting and it sort of makes
sense to do that and that provides a
nice clean d mark between
the transport layer and the multi
different service nodes is providing
transport for but again as we can see in
that top right hand picture it there's
the dots requires the more functionality
on the transport here it does require
what I'm trying to show they're like
view from the rudder short reach
interfaces which are the little blue
boxes they're connected to the
transponder which then converts it into
a as a recovered lambda for connection
across the transport network now if we
move to the bottom picture which we're
calling IP of wdn this is sort of why
we're looking ok so the transports
moving more to so that single service in
its only providing transport for for IP
in which case then it would seem to make
then a lot of those transponders it
where they are to provide that multi
service aspect and to provide that d
mark point the value of that somewhat
becomes less and less and it allows you
to basically then move the the transport
that's fine transport into the rider it
itself what we're trying to show in the
bottom so we basically have the colored
objects directly off the router and that
truly is the sort of reducing all of the
cost because we've taken out a lot of
the assurance interfaces between the
writer and the transponder a lot of the
actual optical interconnects between the
rider and transponder and limited the
transponders themselves it's basically
living it's a lot of the common
equipment that it goes around with
actually supporting these transponders
so basically overall allows you to move
to a much simpler and we believe lower
cost network is the one marketing slider
die down a threat appears I won't spend
much time on it just other didn't say
like again this is not just chart where
we have a sort of 10 and 40 geek TW
emphasis on the router today that are
actually deployed sort of in the field
and sort of carrying sort of live
traffic and the one point that we've got
40 kg I guess deployed over links of up
to 900 plus kilometers so yeah I just
look a little bit more about 40
100 Gig technology in detail so 40 gigs
so as we mentioned rudders prefer a
single 40 gig pipe for the ligand load
balancing limitations customers that we
talk to prefer single 40 gig per second
interfaces and primarily that's because
the teacher and transport doesn't have
them in reports it's often viewed as a
fixed and some acid it's installed in
the grind it's got a certain number of
ports and people would rather turn up
sort of one port for 40 gig rather than
burn up sort of four ports and obviously
the druze point like that cost is
important in there certainly is a
balance there but what we're seeing it I
the people are prepared to pay a premium
upfront initially to for that spectral
efficiency and good example out and say
we've got both for by 10 gige actually
and 40 gig DW minute is off the rudder
but most of the interest and what most
of all were selling is actually sort of
the 40 gig card and not the 4 x 10 gig
card which like somewhat surprised me
because it is simply cheaper n you can
actually go a lot further today with it
but we're seeing that basically across
most of the customers we're talking
talking to so I'm looking forward in
terms of the modulation technology as
Ross i mentioned that is advancing
rapidly from like optical geo binary
today to sort of dpsk to maybe look a
little bit further right some of the
coherent technology that Ross was
talking about like what are the bunnies
with the coherent technology is as well
it's actually allows you to do a lot of
the processing electrically and not
optically so you basically do a sort of
an A to D convert right at the front end
your receiver and then you can actually
come and see it for a lot of these
things like chromatic dispersion in PMD
electrically which again ultimately over
time should be should be a much lower
cost solution because again looking back
in my time University typically doing
things electrically is there's more cost
effective than doing things optically so
we're ready sure that 40 gig today can
run over to exist the interior
infrastructure that's typically using
optical geo binary does have some
limitations in terms of
sort of the performance in reach but
with some of these newer technologies
that are coming on stream over the next
year's that we will be able to get 40
gig sort of meeting or in some cases
actually exceeding the ten key
performance and again just from a writer
perspective key thing there is that all
these advanced modulation schemes can be
integrated and you can drive it directly
off the router upload so then just
moving a little bit about 100 gig under
D Israel customers are requesting today
both the ITU and the I Triple E are
already taken up the effort on the
standard and number the people have seen
in this room are actually helping out
for that in the I Triple E I think
they've been working on it for about a
year now keeping us here as well I again
because this is a new standard like
we're not talking 100 gig tomorrow for
the actual height r ability to complete
the standard I think the schedule is
sort of 2010 so again when you're
looking a lot of this stuff and maybe
comparing 210d costs you don't want to
be doing it today you want to be looking
maybe four or five years like when this
100 gate technology will be start will
start to be deployed so the other points
methods are pretty much the same as
before like a 100 key rudders still
prefer a single 100 gig interface
customers who were talking to you still
prefer to see it a single hundred geek
universe basically 100 gig pro lambda
that's been achieved at 40k it's
obviously more challenging at a hundred
gigan and but again again as Ross
mentioned that the basically we can
leverage a lot of the work we we started
at 40 gig in these advanced modulation
schemes to achieve sort of a hundred
geek / wave length and width sort of
equivalent performance to 10g and again
this from my perspective what's
important is that a lot of these things
that Ross is talking about can be
integrated directly onto the writer as
well so just quickly to wrap up IP
traffic is of the continue to grow as
we've mentioned what that means is we
need fatter pipes not more pipes
we need that both with the service level
like it the writer as we mentioned you
to the ligand load balancing limitations
I also believe that fundamentally we're
going to need that at the transport
layer as well because that transport
systems do not have unlimited ports so
we have to look at continuing to
increase the speed per wavelength that
does require advanced modulation for
months that the fodder pipes were
looking at both 10 and 100 geek do need
eltima to match the performance of the
skinny pipes today and again that's
probably going to be in performance both
in terms of distance and ultimately in
terms of cost as well now we see the
network convert into two layers as
service in transport and then a closer
coupling of those two layers we believe
is the next obvious step in network
evolution and I think that okay and
that's it thank you very much
alright I'll kind of wrap this up here
for us guys up on the panel then we're
an open up to you guys like I said I
want to give the panel us a few minutes
to ask each other questions if they have
questions like we used to do in the old
days of nanog and just kind of reiterate
what they say else agree we're kind of
moving into a binary world ones and
zeros IP and transport optical and
they're all going to be the same thing
and it's a it's best for everyone start
paying attention to learn it there are
some people actually working on optical
routers as in like light and it's not
just science projects any more inward
universities there are a little startup
incubators looking at this stuff so it's
coming for real um so with that we'll
open it up drew Gary Ross do you'll have
any questions for each other or you guys
going to be nice you're going to wait
for the next I triple you mean you need
each other alive when you're not in
front of the audience or in the bar all
right they don't have any questions for
each other right we'll open up to the
audience anybody I needs have questions
for the panelists please come forward
mr. Myers over at the left Mike okay um
uh for South nice maybe you can repeat
my question um you guys talked a lot
about a physical error stuff it's an
optical panel I understand what I'm
curious to know is whether eventually
we're going to hope that we can plug in
100 Gig circuits or interfaces in two
routers which sort of means that
eventually we're going to need all three
engines that can can do on a hundred gig
we're going to need be okie chips that
can do 100 gig we're going to need l2
framing and all of that stuff at 100 gig
what is your sense the sort of a generic
question what if what is your sense
about where that technology is as
compared to where sort of the phi tech
nology is today it's definitely a long
pole in the tent there's certainly a lot
of people working on it and there are no
chips available today as far as I know
and hopefully I know what's most most of
what's out there but
I think that's their third maybe three
long poles I said that's definitely one
of them hello yeah yeah so I guess the
short answer is yes where are they in
terms of I guess I'm an engineer so I
better be careful what I say here yeah
both there's definitely drew said
there's advances in terms of the engine
technology there's obviously advances in
terms of the Phi there's a bunch of
rumors of I just to do like the shortage
interfere it's like how do we get a
hundred key short reach interface across
the office and then how do we get 100
gig across the country so there's really
there was three aspects to it I think
there's active work going on in all
three three three areas right now as I
mentioned before like this has been
worked on with the I Triple E and the
ITU I think this I think the schedule is
to probably drivin probably 2010 I guess
for that to be sort of fully ratified
and i would expect all of those three
components to be available in that by
that time frame maybe it's the best way
to put it the other component or the
other piece of that question i forgot to
ask that i wanted to ask is what kind of
power envelope is a hundred in your with
with optical is a hundred gig just a
single port now 100 gig line car going
to look like talking power dissipation
or optical power on the fiber power
dissipate our requirements and heat
dissipation on the line card that was
actually going to be my question to
these guys actually you guys I think the
target of goal is obviously to try and
do 100 gig within the same power budget
envelope as the as we have today on the
40 gig per slot because yeah exactly
it's got a head they're kind of 100 to
150 watt range but one thing I don't
agree with drew is that's not a major
cost drivers as Morris you've got to
make sure it can plug into existing
rowers and exist and WM systems and you
got a bill to cool
I mean those are the challenges it's not
that it's not the power consumption
Perseids up a big cost element certainly
a fascinating thing I think that's going
to cause some thinking going on in the
industry from my perspective is if
you're just trying to come up just do a
short reach link within a pop or
something between a router and transport
gear for instance multimode fiber ribbon
technology is going to be far less
expensive far less power and far sooner
availability than anything over single
mode over a single single mode anyway so
I just curious what's going to happen
when when people can buy multimode fiber
ribbon in interface as a year earlier
for attempt the cost will see mind you
the same thing happened with 10 gigabit
right and the problem is none of the big
carriers of their of that multi more
driven five are distributed in through
the distribution frame so you know even
though there's a big cost differences
I'd imagine it's still going to be an
issue there that you know they want to
go above the 300-meter reach and you
know they don't necessarily want to have
to deploy new multimode fiber and even
though there's a 40 gig there's a
there's a obviously a big premium there
as well I mean 40 gig shortridge
interface is a single you know cecee
deol 40 gig interface is expensive as
gary said that's why there's value in
integrating the WM on the router there
so yeah if it's not going to happen
there I'd still be surprised if those
carriers are going to go for the the
pain and investment of the Putin up
multimode fiber ribbon cable
distribution in there I think Gary can
tell you about what happened to 10 gig
though and I think has some you have
some experience on unzipping multimode
fiber ribbons at that level right yeah
again his raw soluti we actually came up
with a scheme called OC 192 VSR at 10
gig we actually did run 10 gig at the 10
gigs here at the time this is back in
1999 was extremely expensive and we come
up with a scheme of running OC 1920 bore
sort of ribbon fiber
it was significantly cheaper but again
it was not widely accepted by the
industry for the reasons that was talked
about but it did have actually did have
the advantage of driving down the cost
of 10 geek cereal because it was a much
cost much much lower cost solution to
helped all the cereal optical vendors
sharpen their pencils and really did
have the have the benefit of helping
drive down the cost of cereal 10d
quicker than might have done this we
haven't come up with that solution on a
realistically desirable deployment
distance 1500 kilometers has been
mentioned if you apply all of the
advanced technologies that have been
mentioned what is the theoretical limit
theoretical and what I mean if you get
p.m. qpsk next-generation fact you can
do more than 2,000 claw marks what is
the theoretical limit for the amount of
data that can be deployed over a 1500
kilometers fam I think 14 terabits has
been demonstrated by MTT how close is
that to the ultimate limit I mean a lot
of it will go back don't you know what's
your spine loss and things like that
because that all affects the signal
noise ratio and things but I mean
certainly yeah if you do two bits per
second perhaps you can do it Ted a bit
per band and kind of commercially
available certainly see band and people
talk about El band as well well there's
not so much of it deployed so you have
16 terabits with that if you want you to
do more than that you know now you're
getting to some sort of 16 qualms or
something like that where you know you
could potentially double that capacity
once again up to 32 terabytes but then
you'd have a reach doesn't reach
improvements to signals noise you have
to have launched power that's
unrealistic yet I mean you get one thing
when you go from PS k to qpsk quadrature
phase-shift keying you can double a
capacity and it doesn't actually heart
you in terms of second or noise ratio
that kind of comes for free but every
time you go you go beyond that two more
levels and the clam constellation if you
like now when you got more and more
levels you basically trade-off spectral
efficiency for for reach so you know
this if you want to go to higher
spectral efficiency you might have to do
something a little bit cleverer and the
optical lane system but then that means
changing the infrastructure so you know
if you deploy more EDF es you reduce the
the amplifier space and you know it kind
of looks like a submarine system fair
enough then you can you got better
signal noise ratio or you deploy some
other techniques on the optical wine
system like ramen amplifiers they can
also boost the optical signal noise
ratio so you know if you want to go to
those 1500 coma or reach and even higher
spectral efficiency you've really gotta
go do something clever over the lane
system part of our perspective though is
that spectral efficiency is is an issue
because you're limiting yourself to the
c-band if you can get yourself out of
the c-band and open up the spectrum then
it matters less how efficient you are at
least for a given for capacity level so
if you can get the S fanned open the
obin even there's much bands here then
you can start buying capacity without
having to increase dramatically a
spectral efficiency and then if you can
if there are other approaches to
modulation that have lower power then
that might equate the lower costs so
there's a very very large number of
factors that go into this equation yeah
yeah okay and when you mention the
bypass router model you didn't mention
the control plane and specifically not
GM pls mentioned so wonder that was and
purpose or there's some development
there too that was a time limit true
statement or one of those presentations
and up and I'm kind of preface this with
beware of transport vendors pitching
Rodin's and optical transport control
planes that automatically switch and do
one for n protection because what they
don't understand is when neighbor
adjacencies change and physical paths
change and what was the router ID one
second ago is an
router ID now is not protection that's
disruption be careful yeah transport
people love that stuff that'll
understand control planes well there is
it it's a whole lot of metal there's a
whole lot of work that's gone on for a
decade probably nine decade i guess but
eight years on GM pls control planes and
certainly major router vendors support
GM pls but there's a whole lot more work
to be done there I didn't even put a
single slide in as you noted here but
I've gone to multi-day conferences
solely than that yeah you might on my
panel if you did just teasing