hi everyone welcome to my talk
oh yeah and leave his tape on mobile
dangerous for the looking girl so just a
bit of a mouthful to say I must have met
um a little bit of background about how
this talk came about I went to security
a few months ago with a colleague and I
met I bumped into Andy and David you
start talking about b-sides and possibly
doing a talk and I said to them I want
to do a talk after my dissertation but
after a few beers they did persuade me
to do this talk now so anyway I helped
me out but this so quick run through
what my talks and if you bow these are a
few points that I've expanded on a
little bit it's quite steep learning
curve because I didn't really have a
talk before so I wanted to go except
it's like working on it quite a lot and
I will speak learning curve for this but
first thing I wanted to look at was why
do people actually read their devices
and I quite a lot positives initially I
thought was a bad thing I thought people
like if you've rooted your device you're
opening yourself up to a lot of
vulnerabilities but actually you can
them you can definitely make your hats
later so you you can increase the
privacy you can get liberate of a lot of
the bloatware on your device and you can
install cool themes and third-party apps
if you want to do that I mean how many
of you in the audience has an Android
device cool how many of you have rooted
your Android device so a lot of you
probably knew what you were doing when
you're rooting your device especially
here but some people they don't
necessarily know what they're doing and
they could be speedy installing custom
themes and new roms and you can't be
cool things that but you could also open
up your talk to possibly you could
probably thought you could possibly
break your device which I did experience
first time when I was testing things and
also you can see that some of the apps
won't work because in case you install a
third-party app it could be a bower and
you could open your your device up turn
more cool so first I looked at how you
actually real device so there are two
ways I found so far there were ones
immanuel immanuel way and then I saw
that you can install apps when you were
rooting your device so when I went to
root my device the device I had a
samsung Jeffrey that really rubbish that
want to do it on my iPhone I tried to
install Kingo root and one click and one
click root the one think great you had
to pay for the Kingo root it didn't
actually work on my device and I wanted
to see how you'd be able to read a
device manually anyway so I give a try
and I installed 12 recovery image so
when i went to root it I went into
fastboot mode and it still installed the
recovery image and then I ended up going
through and they're installing the
binary so I you super see although my
disc is more of a newer version that
people use and when it's a recovery mode
and still that binary and basically
installing the superuser binary can then
enable you to go out for religious tea
applications and you could do cool
things like customize your firmware on
your device or anything like that I
thought was really interesting actually
before I did the talk I thought up it
could be it could be a danger obviously
and I've changed my mind a lot on the
site if you know what you're doing you
could do some really cool things you can
improve the battery life of your device
and things that Seth had enough it's
that firstly first I set up my lab
really could be around theory it's not
enough install I didn't really notice
tearing I had a PI pi 0 which had
terrible processing power so I came to a
PI 3 B+ and worked a lot better just a
quick setup I mean I had a Peyser had
one us people and I was lugging my mouse
taking out plug in my keyboard taking it
out and I plugged my phone it was like I
can't actually run any commands on my
phone because for my phone and connector
because she didn't have enough people so
I had a USB port splitter and got that
and the whole idea behind this talk was
the fact that I've been seeing a lot of
these USB ports around charging USB
ports on my plays and buses and whatnot
and I think this is a possible attack
vector here because if you plug your
device into this random USB port you
don't necessarily know what's going to
happen so the whole idea behind this was
programmatically rooting your device and
I did feel a lot like this when I
started looking into it because there's
a lot of there's a lot of reasons why
you can't and security is actually quite
high on your devices so for example when
you plug your device in it's the USB
does USB debugging after that pop up on
the screen that comes up you have to
physically real device as well press
buttons and manual questions and whatnot
and yeah human human input is needed so
you do have a pop oh you have to press
okay and whatnot that's our that's
that's an issue so I've decided to try
and find ideas to work around that but
first I want to see what you could do
when you plug your device into it u.s.
people when it's not rooted some issue
say there's a quick disclaimer here is
that if you plug your device into a USB
for charging port if a PI was behind
this thought then what could happen and
I played around with you dev rules to
interrupt and kernel detect when a
device is plugged in I've create a shell
script to kick off screen recording
which is quite cool thing so if you do
adb shell you can scream and call your
device was quite a few ifs and buts they
would the code that I wrote here you can
see the vendor ID text the device and
keeps off the PI script you have to have
a specific vendor ID for it to kick off
in the background and always it's very
simple code and there's a lot I want to
develop on it from this but basically of
course screen and you can capture it so
it maximum is about three minutes but
you could possibly capture passwords and
you can see that's showing up there
and you could also see emails or
sensitive documents and I thought I was
quite interesting but I little that idea
that if you did plug that device and you
don't know what's happening because the
user doesn't see it necessarily you have
to make sure that the device is unlocked
and the USB debugging enabled first
actually watch well one of the issues
because the USB debugging pop-up came up
I was thinking what's a good way to work
around that so I had to play around with
a business card
device and I went through about five of
them because of all them broke but you
can automate the keyboard on the battle
pretend like it's a human interface
device and automate some of the steps so
here I've just got gif of the code
working now on the side and you can see
it's switching and pressing ok and if
this develops a little bit further you'd
be able to kind of cancel out the pop
out because imagine if you plug the
device into this USB port this runs and
it's just sending the codes and you can
automate a lot of this alright and the
pie could be something for and you could
also you could also crack passwords they
take a really long time I didn't really
try it was something I'd like to develop
so initially I had a look at third
epps as well because i was one of the
issues behind it and there was one
called a fake snap to act i looked into
you and if you were someone like a grand
mal for example they had a fun and they
installed a this app this app could
possibly with the permissions go back
network and also steal the credentials
and it used to be in the Google Play
Store it's taken down now but it's so
easy cuz this is the newbies talk you
could just download the apk file and you
could install it under file to listen
like so being a newbie that I am I
decided to try and create an apk file
using easy split which is basically pass
the NSF console and asteroid and I had a
look at trying to install that onto my
device so I used the ADB Android
debugging bridge to automate the install
on the back of the with my PI and you
plug it in and when I when I plugged it
in I actually lost the apk file I don't
know how and I checked it I tried to
understand it what an uninstall try to
install it was saying it was already
installed so if I know what happened
there but that was were the things I
think if you manage to install it and
kick it off then it would run in the
background and you'd be able to exploit
it in prerov as TCP connection with the
payload so if you imagine you've plugged
your device in and you can install the
apk file and they might click on it
through some social engineering or
possibly and attend I saw I had little
million zillion tech st. fully
understand but these can kick off in the
background if you run the ABB shell come
on
if you automated that for a basket when
it's plugged in and you develop real
kicked off that you'd be able to create
this reverse TCP capture TCP connection
to the PI and then from that SSH so he
could be like hacker in a cafe or
something SSH into the PI that's hidden
disguised and then you'd be able to
access all these files on this rooted
device for example that has been plugged
in and then would really be none the
wiser otherwise you'd have to make sure
that you've unlocked the device again
and got rid of all the popups so because
the install the apk file didn't fully
work out to ours like well how it was
this apk file actually doing in the
background so I used apktool just to
pull out some of the files of the
a PK that had been generating them SF
consoles so I wanted to see how it was
working and basically had all these
permissions and it's someone installed
this apk files like clicking yes and
granted all these permissions you
basically had a bug on your class this
is really interesting has something I
really want to look into as well so
there's a lot of ideas because I really
wanted to do some I just yeah so you've
got all these machines and I also had to
play around with the smiley files and
this tool called x2 just so I had a look
in that R and X teacher and I opened up
some the Smarty file so I could read
them in Java they're too far that
definitely will have a future
a few quick mentions but I wanted to say
with there's a lot of cool things
already out there in terms of just
storing a device I guess so you've got
the USB killer this short circuit said
itself uses your phone and kills it
completely so imagine if you're a
businessman or whatever a new plug your
device into this u.s. people and it
kills your phone that's basically
basically your life as a lot of people
have phones these days and it's Freder
as well I'm pretty sure there was a talk
on that earlier and if you've rooted
your data device for example and you've
installed Freder and you've used it to
pretend that you're not rude then you
can install third-party malicious app
and that will get all the accesses lara
break out the sandbox environment and
cause bit damage so freely could be a
nice eye patches are quite interesting
but a lot too much depending on time
yeah so I wanted to mention iOS because
I didn't play around with it's a bit of
a gray area because it's close sauce I
didn't look into the vulnerabilities of
it however there's a exploit database
for this you can find online I've got
I'm pretty sure there's a link in my
description you can come and talk about
you would yeah it's not just Android
devices that are vulnerable and part of
the futures I do want to look into this
a bit further and I'd lovely like a 2.90
of something where I've actually like
research into a lot because I didn't
have too much time to research into this
one so I'm interested in mobile malware
are we searching to that and I love the
automation size behind it so the whole
idea of this was automating the exploits
when you plug your device into the PI so
I'd like to work oh yeah that's pretty
much a joke so if you have any questions
because it might not been so cool
a little bit I'm supporting out there
please ask away because I could probably
explain better in a conversation muscle
the guy all the way in the back yeah use
the microphone probably creating the
dizzy squat device I said it looks at
such a small slide but I spent days just
trying to get this automation to work
alright plug this keyboard into my phone
as five pressing the keys I thought I
tried all to make these steps actually
the best because you can see it working
as soon as you plugged it in and it's so
satisfiying on you actually managed to
get that working and I'd love to develop
it so you could create bad USB with
these cities box just plug it in and
imagine what you could do with your
phone then yeah that's probably one of
the most other questions remember the
old days when ADB was the assembler
debugger geez I'm sorry comments
thoughts it's not a question is this
hand I swear he did do you have any boss
security I'd love to hear your thoughts
on this because as you can see it's a
very like a lot of ideas and I've still
a long way to go with this I please just
like comment approached me because I'm
really open to learning more about it so
the USB device he showed up there the
little thing was that actually like a
rubber ducky or something equivalent so
I got these did you spot devices they're
like not cough Arduinos I bought a load
of them and I love them just didn't work
because I just clearly not sure exactly
so I got the idea of a bad yet I had the
idea about USB I don't want to try and
create something enough paramount code
initially because I've got to experience
this I wanted to pull files off the
device and then move them onto us piece
it wasn't really close or I haven't
managed to get working but I did just
end up using it to send commands to the
phone and it literally works straight
away Gabe hiding in the back I need for
another 10,000 steps today just welcome
down the plane when you fly home talking
about the requirement to have the device
ID did you do anything with it
attempting to automatically identify the
device to
grab the device I'd even say a database
or something is that something you've
looked at as possible no I didn't it
could definitely be possible in my head
I thought if it was actually going to
become a working so it doesn't take the
work that's when I was testing that it's
obviously my practice having a load of
you dev rules but I initially looked I
spent a lot of time looking at gvfs and
the where it was mounted and seeing if I
could alter anything like that so when
it's plugged in if it detects a device
like that I did ibly I could definitely
look them to work I was thinking a lot
of vendor IDs but it's hard but it's
very specific to one device whereas
there are different types of devices out
there and there's different ways of
routing the devices and it's it's very
varied so yeah be something I'd want to
look into sure yeah okay the universe
the interactive the couzo the kernel and
so much sound for a thermostat
godlessness interprets it it detected
again oh so basically with the you
Devils it like it has common but it's
not it's not really a listener yes it's
a mere listener and it talks to the turn
on the kernel does that send the Kamaria
but yeah it's the device that way so
when I was testing it I run LS USB to
find out what the vendor ID was in the
product ID and then wiped it that way
and originally I was thinking you'd have
to use the vendor ID in the product ID
in the rules file so we had to kick
anything off but actually could limit it
to the vendor ID and when I was - it was
getting when I was testing it
I will you because you had to have it
unlocked and then also USB debugging
they would I was testing it and I
managed to get it to kick off the shell
script to bring up a browser so I knew
it was working
how does she do it say yeah Cecily I do
have that probably such a little better
excellent thank you very much