so yeah I'm gonna talk to you today
about my dissertation project I done an
investigation and to gpgpu enabled
failed carving and if you don't know
what that as I will explain its
hopefully so yep
I'm Corey Forbes I've recently left
Alberti the university that doesn't
exist the Northwest save the world I've
just also finished work at the Scottish
business resilience centre and I'm
moving down here to work at NWR so
that's gonna be fun yes so what is fail
coming I hope everyone here knows and
does anyone want to put their hand up if
they do actually know what failed
carving is okay maybe not then and so
fail carving as the collection of fails
on the raw hard disk because when files
are deleted they're not really like
removed
they're just dereferenced so what we do
is we drop down to the physical level
and we search the contents of a hard
disk or backing storage so the Quartier
excellently summarizes that the metadata
that holds all of the fail locations as
fragile baguettes completely weight and
when I fails deleted but when as deleted
this is still actually and the physical
death square so and you can see here
that the track sectors and are when the
death sectors and the tracks meet and
that typically holds your individual
chunks of a file and but the operating
system usually deals with us for you
the fail so the fails are broken down in
these chunks and appropriately place
them at the desk and this can be in the
two ways
you can see here which is fragmented
fails where the fails to beg to be
stored all together and as throwing
throw death it's a pain in the arse and
contiguous failure location as when the
fails all kept together and it's just
linear like lift missus quake Goods when
you're working with physical hard deaths
that have the actuator arm so the
riverboat because you just read all and
one go when it comes to tests as well
with these actuator arms and that helps
me segue into the fact that backing
storage has only recently became fast
enough that it's no the software's fault
that it's not that everything's starting
to get slow from our fail carbon
perspective so SSDs and raid technology
has helped shift the attention of these
programs back into the limelight in
terms of needing improvement so
ultimately my research question was how
fast can be header for search become our
how fast can I get the header for search
to fame these fails and to clarify the
headers and furs or unique like
identification at the start in the end
let's say this is a PDF or this is a
JPEG so Alethea helped me get a solid
answer to the question but to better
explain as just to make sure our to
figure out where the problem was I had
to break down what fail carving programs
do so it just comes down to the to house
of searching for these fails and these
header/footer pairs as well as the
actual carving but the carving can only
get so quick before you start to lose
accuracy and so the header fur repairs
is entirely
where are the searching for these pairs
entirely where my efforts were focused
so I'll quickly talk about surfing
algorithms I don't want to ruin
everyone's day here so Ballmer as what
the current tools for motion scalp will
make yourself these are two open source
CPU fail carving tools that I was
comparing against Boyer uses to rule
sets to jump through and strengthener
searching and help save time but it
requires the CPU to be fast enough I'm
not going to go through everything on
the side but as more for the video for
anyone who wants to look back on it
Boyer mer
also has two pre-compile these jumps so
it's not very fair for purpose with this
new hardware I was trying to bring into
the process and so as such I moved to a
new algorithm which is the parallel
failure list a whole Korsak it's a
dumbed down version of the apple corer
SiC algorithm which will allow our which
basically well act as a brute-force
search but for multiple patterns
simultaneously forgot to mention
actually Boyer can only search for one
string item so having the ability to
search from multiple as we're a big step
up also comes in which will see in the
results later but having this more
towards brute force search helps with
them the fact that each core of our each
computer core on a GPU is a stupid and
comparison to the CPU where it's all
fast and smart so know the backgrounds
oh the way we can discuss the
development so I made use of C++ as well
as the CUDA library to develop the
Alethea tool set but CUDA then limited
me to only be
Alti used in the video hardware so as
such I wanted to bring back the
usability at the time Matt and actually
realized and ER looking into adopting
CUDA so that would have worked well to
know okay so yeah cross-platform
development was then a big objective of
thing I wanted to get working on both
Windows and Linux so then other tool or
the other goal of course was I wanted
open source fail Carver's to be
hopefully and I wanted to be in the
leaps in compared to those foremost and
scalpel being cpu-based I was hoping
that I could proof of concept that GPU
is the way forward so for my results I
used both my personal desktop which was
running Windows and AWS instance on
Linux and I've just got less for Klara's
purposes again it can be looked at later
AWS was really useful for being able to
recreate my results for anyone to want
it to look at it themselves so you can
see here the scalpel has both the
fastest and slowest between the two
tools and specifically it's worth
knowing that the Boyar algorithm I
discussed and how it searches for only
one string at a time it was made
perfectly clear by the fact that had to
do multiple passes
thus when I was searching for all the
patterns instead of just PDF patterns
the data throughput dropped drastically
um you then compare this to ilithyia
which was a vast improvement and when
you compare PDF only to all patterns you
can see there's a lot less drop-off or a
lot less of an extreme drop-off on the
death reports so I was hoping as well
that's just taken away so
far more for future work I was really
hoping that I could even apply this to
real time memory forensics use case a
hypervisor for example could be running
a tool very similar or a repurposed
version of the final project in the
event I do implement the fill fail
carving features and it could search for
malicious files they exist in life
memory so but yeah that's that's a lot
of in terms of my slides but I'm open to
any questions or heckles hackles yeah
there's any questions I'll ask one that
so while you were doing this did you
look at the device free list not the dev
free list but there are no free list in
the UNIX systems to see if that might be
a good starting place or did you just
look at the file system raw so I was
just looking at how fast I could get a
specific process to go just looking at
fail carving yourself I haven't looks so
you just scrape the entire dr3 list off
the drive yeah
I'm specifically with my EWS instance as
well I wanted to test my algorithm more
so I even made use of RAM disks to
Lourdes the contents that I wanted
searched and it was just all but the
speed of the algorithm so and did you
look it through the bed block table as
well or did you know I was the stupid
approaches over yeah okay other
questions
now that the tough ones are out of the
way that was actually how I got started
in security doing the how fantastic
forty-one years ago yeah hello hi Sam hi
Cori
yeah I was just wondering what do you
think about the feasibility of tools
like for most implementing a GPU based
approach do you think that might happen
or do you think is
Rider but the court isn't good I held
them on github and they responded with
their attempt and I mean yeah they could
absolutely adopt it it's just a matter
of proof of concept and hopefully being
able to circulate this knowledge
throughout the sphere and it would be
applied hopefully in the future so when
you say it's not good did you mean it
wasn't parallelizable or was it not
vectorizable so they dead managed to
paralyze their results but they've also
it was as if they they're really good
computer scientists but they just
obviously aren't good parallel
performance they just didn't understand
how to do it correctly and ultimately it
just didn't work out well for them other
questions comments ideas okay thank you
[Music]