hi everyone thank you very much for
coming I appreciate attendance
especially Freya last talk of the day so
I'm going to be speaking to you about
spear fishing and we'll be looking
through a bit of a story and
understanding how fishing attacks work
and why they're so easy and why people
would actually choose these over a more
technical attack for an example so my
name is Alex arc and arcs I work for
pentest people as a senior consultant I
specialize in web application and API
technologies but I have a genuine
interest in the psychology of hacking
any sort of social engineering basically
the fun bits I'm sure all the pen
testers in the audience here love as
well so first of all I'm just going to
be going through a few common
vulnerabilities just to make sure that
we're all on the same page for the non
pen testers in the room so we're going
to be having a look at software versions
brute force multi-factor authentication
and weak passwords so software versions
are left on by default by many different
software's and these versions are often
seen as a low-hanging fruit for an
attacker it's very simple once we find
software versions we can go and look for
pre-written publicly available exploits
click and play them a lot of the time
and there's very little effort required
whatsoever and you can potentially get
root system or any kind of exploitation
that you're looking for from it so
here's an example of a server response
header that has been caught from a web
application using a talk about sweet on
here we can see that there is Microsoft
is 5.0 as I'm sure the pen testers will
point out the incredibly ancient version
with thousands of version but well a lot
of vulnerabilities associated to it so I
thought it would be a good good version
for this so software versions are not
only sent in server response headers and
web applications you can also find these
by running a port scan against the
network layer by using tools such as
nmap here's an example of an EM map scan
that's been returned that is showing the
is web server 5.0 version and we can
also see here just for jokes that
four or five TCP is open which is the
which is a service that was exploited
during the NHS wanna cry attacks so as
an attacker once we actually have a
software version what is the next step
how do we find the next way how do we
find the exploit
so CVE details contains thousands and
thousands of published exploits you can
search the software version on here and
find anything to use against in this
case the web application so as we can
see these are just a few of the ones
that have been found including buffer
overflows and denial of service attacks
once we've looked on TV details and we
found that there are exploits related to
it we actually need the code to then
compile and run and attack the target
we're looking for exploit DB is a
website that you don't have to sign up
for it's publicly available very easy to
use and it hosts code for exploits it
also hosts the a lot of the time the
vulnerable software alongside the
exploit so if anyone does really want to
try and have a little play around with
some hacking go and exploit DB download
the vulnerable software versions
download the exploit fire them off
yourself and just see how actually very
easy it is so this is a little bit of a
snippet from the Microsoft is x-point
and here we can see a snippet of the
eternal blue code the gun was used in
the NHS ransomware attacks so software
versions are incredibly easy to hide so
for example in your Apache config you
can just turn service signatures off and
your server tokens product so brute
force and multi-factor authentication a
brute force attack in a web application
scenario will typically start off by
trying to enumerate a list of valid user
names this can be done through different
functionality within the web application
usually being the Forgotten password
function or the registration function so
when we go onto an application we will
try and register an account and then
afterwards we'll try and re-register it
with the same
an address to see what the error message
is if the error message returns to us as
this account already exists then we have
a different response and we can use
automated tools online to build lists of
thousands of user names or email
combinations there are many word lists
around this really isn't much work or
much effort for any pen testers once
we've got a list of valid user names we
will then actually run brute force
attacks against the login portal against
the password sections try and get it
again there are readily available
automated tools online that are very
easy to do this so multi-factor
authentication is a second layer of
authentication after we've used our
standard username and password this is
often a screeners asking for some kind
of code that usually comes through
Google Authenticator or SMS messages
multi-factor authentication code should
be treated exactly like passwords are
not shared with anyone recently I was
doing an engagement for a pharmaceutical
company and we spoof well we did we got
their domain added - support on the end
just a nice classic and registered it
and then we sent an email to their
company saying that we have an important
security update to be pushed that will
require everyone's have Outlook Web
Access which is obviously rubbish the
majority of us but a lot of people will
fall for it so we had a keylogger on the
portal that we redirected them to from
the email and we got to director-level
accounts and pharmaceutical company
however they had multi-factor
authentication enabled so I thought I'd
take a long shot and phone one of them
and I was like hi I'm calling from IT
support we've you know emailed you
earlier we've asked you to log into this
you come back to us and told us you're
having problems would you be able to
read the code that I'm about to text
through to your phone to me please and
they read it straight away so I decided
why not try and see if I can get another
method for them to give it to me like
this so I sent a push notification
called them and said we're sending a
push notification to your phone just to
confirm it to you before we
asking you a few more questions they
press the push notification without any
argument whatsoever so we have to start
treating multi-factor authentication
tokens as passwords so as we can see
brute-force attacks is simple to set up
and execute it's only a matter of time
and computing power until we actually
get through unless there's some form of
protection the protection is quite easy
you can add a CAPTCHA you can use
account lockout policies and ideally you
should always have multi-factor
authentication enabled on logins whilst
this isn't always possible I think the
more is an industry if we can really
start pressing the importance of
multi-factor authentication then whether
applications in general will become a
lot more secure mitigates against
password reuse in in in in essence
because even if you log in through the
first layer you're not going to get into
the second so there are a lot of options
now mainly being automation Google
authentication Skater so weak passwords
passwords have been talking topic of the
security industry I guess since the
first day and there are many myths
surrounding it so take this as a bit of
a pinch of salt because it's come from
how secure is my password online so I
don't know the full accuracy but it
gives a bit of a rough idea on the
computational power that is actually
required to crack passwords so here's
your typical pass typical weak password
of the word password which will be
cracked instantly by by dictionary
attacks and very quickly by any kind of
true brute-force attacks so does using
complexity on weak passwords make them
stronger yes but not by that much you
can add more complexity you can change
things up but it really doesn't make it
stronger much stronger so passphrases
I'm sure everyone in here or most of the
people here have now heard about
passphrases at one point or another pass
phrases are multiple words with spaces
in between them and this is a lot easier
for the human brain to actually remember
in a psychological point of view because
remembering three words with spaces or
dashes is a lot easier than remembering
one word with seven hush tags for
semicolons and a couple of commas
involved it up a minimum length of ten
characters should be in place for low
privilege users and a minimum length of
16 characters should be in place for
high privilege users so here's an
example of a passphrase being used which
has now gone from instantly to one
minute to 454 billion years so the
computational mathematics behind it
shows that it will take a lot longer and
even better yet add some complexity in
there as well so now we can move on to
the main part social media spearfishing
and how to protect yourself we're going
to start off by having a little look at
the threat landscape understanding what
spearfishing is a bit of a motivation
behind it some scary facts and
statistics a case study and then how to
protect against spearfishing we are
going to be giving away some lockpick
sets at the end of this talk to people
that can answer questions about the top
sight do you pay attention and don't
fall asleep if you want free lockpick
status so let's have a look at the
threat landscape between October 2013
and May 2018 businesses inside and
outside of the US lost over 12.5 billion
dollars to email business compromised
2015 was really a massive year for
ransomware with over seven hundred and
fifty two percent increase and
ransomware families jumping from 29 to
247 ransomware is still increasing but
rapidly what is the business email
compromised so business email compromise
is a form of fraud and it plays off
natural human psychological urges so I
would send Leggett so you to spook
spoofer c-suite employs a chief
executive officer or chief operating
officer or or whatever officers are are
these days and you'd email through to a
financial director asking them to
deposit X amount of money quickly before
we lose a license for example so the
average loss is a hundred and forty
thousand dollars the owner AG lost forty
four point six million dollars from one
point of business email compromised in
2006 in 2018 business email compromised
rose by about forty six percent or
reported email business compromised rose
by about forty six percent what is
ransomware
so I ransomware payloads are usually
delivered by email a user will click a
link or download an attachment or some
form of trickery involved and the
ransomware will then encrypt all of the
files on the computer and demand money
usually in the payment form of Bitcoin
or etherium or some form of
cryptocurrency to actually unlock the
files I saw quite a lot of cases where
people actually did pay to get their
files unlocked and never got given a key
to unlock their files so what is
spearfishing spearfishing unlike regular
fishing target's individuals and
specific people it has the attacker will
actually spend some time researching
understanding the person that they're
going to attack and building a profile
you'll understand the family's needs
their hobbies pretty much everything
that they do anything that you can do to
build an overall profile there are three
main payloads and here technical
payloads which is usually ransomware or
some form of malware psychological
payloads which is business email
compromised or any other kind of do this
now because someone's emailing you from
a higher higher level accounts either or
both which is just a spoof password
reset or some form of key logger so what
is the motivation behind spear fishing
spear phishing is incredibly easy to set
up and execute it doesn't take up much
time and the rewards can be absolutely
massive we'll talk about case study a
little bit later
you'll be able to see some of the real
effects of spearfishing and how much
money it can actually make so why
spearfishing really so we've all
received normal maths phishing emails
that are clearly sent out to thousands
of people
that are written in poorly they're in
poorly written English probably trying
to sell you some kind of penis extension
medication or or something that is you
know something terrible along those
lines maybe similar
Russian mail brides as well so the
difference between these emails are they
are not obvious they are well-made they
look authentic in their correct and
crafted the URL sorry the email address
that it's coming from will not look fake
it will no longer be their valued
customer and there are a couple of other
mistakes in there that I'm sure people
would notice like regard bottom so how
can we actually start building better
emails that people are more likely to
fall for and more likely to understand
so an example that I like to use is AC
suite employee goes on holiday and post
a picture of them on the beach and they
have their hotel name in the background
so we've got on Twitter and we found
this
we found the hotel name and we know that
they were there during certain dates
I'll then send an email to the hotel
asking them a very generic question like
do you have gym facilities or what time
is your bar closed or the usual
important questions and when they reply
to you will then analyze the language
and the way the being mail response is
written to us grab the email footer and
any information that we can actually
grab from the email returned to us and
then send an email to the c-suite
employee that has tweeted picture of
another hotel
we'll be exploiting a trust relationship
here because they've been there before
they know the hotel they don't
understand why people know they were in
the hotel so our email will say we found
some high value goods in your room
please either click on this link or
download this to have a look at them and
if they are yours then we'll return
to you very quickly people naturally
will click on that they're scared that
they've lost something maybe even
they're a bad person they're thinking
can I steal something here can I say
that something was mine
in which case and it's a good thing that
we are fishing them so let's have a look
at some fairly scary facts and
statistics two-thirds of all malware
arrives by email attachments
sophisticated phishing emails facilitate
90% of successful attacks 97% of people
cannot differentiate an authentic email
from a well-crafted fake one this is a
statistic that I'm focusing on the most
for this presentation whilst the other
one show the effect of it and a powerful
of Ness of it this is showing that
actually if you write things in good
English and it looks genuine then people
probably are going to click on it so 50%
56% of email recipients and 40% of
Facebook users clicked on a link from an
unknown sender because of curiosity they
didn't know what was on there but they
wanted to know so they still clicked on
it even knowing the risks so let's have
a little bit of look at a case study a
very famous hacking group called carbon
AK who have been around for a little
while and they have stolen billions and
billions of dollars now in total and I
believe one person has been arrested but
I don't think anyone's ever actually
been charged so if we compare this to
jewelry heists of 30 million where
everyone well the majority of the tying
their courts in comparison to our hacker
stealing billions and never being caught
we can really see why spearfishing is so
good so the carbonate group attack
banking institutions and they started
with spear phishing emails once they
were on the network that run some form
of manual reconnaissance recording
everything that was tied by staffs and
video footage CCTV footage webcams that
kind of thing to ensure that they can
actually understand how everything's
working and how everything inside is
actually operating so they can try and
impersonate
Euan member of staff large sums of money
were transferred through ATM to Swift
Network and creating high value bank
accounts but here's a slide that I've
liberated from Kaspersky they were
actually the company that investigated
this attack if you add me on Twitter at
the end or go to my Twitter at the end I
posted an interview with the guy that
investigated the carbon arc attacks
really really interesting stuff really
interesting so we start off at the
beginning where carbon arc is sent is a
backdoor email attachment to a bank
employee previously they've discovered
that this Bank is running an old version
of Microsoft Word internally by using
standard forms of Osen tools such as a
Bluto or a few others that will scrape
the metadata from files online and
they've been uploaded by people from
that company so the backdoor attachment
would exploit a vulnerability in the
Microsoft Word version that would give
system access so the employees
downloaded this and they've got system
access on one computer they've sent it
to quite a few other people and they've
got a load of computers but at this
point there is no administrative
credentials to get on to the domain
controller so they used one of the
compromised computers to send an email
to the IT administrators complaining
that one of the computers that had been
infected was very slow and they wanted
them to come and have a look at it the
IT administrators came and had a look
and there was a key logger on the login
portal so they now have administrative
access and they've got complete control
of the data that they've got control of
the domain controller they own the
infrastructure that can pretty much do
whatever they want from this time so now
that you're inside a bank how'd you get
the money out without being caught or
without being caught quickly and giving
you enough time to actually be able to
get out a decent sum of money so there
are four different methods that were
used by paavana online banking so
sending money outside of the outside of
the countries to maybe Caymans or any
kind of tax haven places
payment systems inflating bank balances
but my personal favorite controlling
ATMs so they lay a bit of malware damn
that would go into the ATMs and that
hired a load of thugs to go to banks
with special cards that would trigger
the malware and spit all of the money
out of the ATMs
after reading about this I ended up
researching ATM hacking a little bit
more and apparently it's quite easy you
can a lot of ATMs you can buy a generic
default key online that allows you to
unlock them and once you unlock them
you've got a USB port not that I'm
encouraging anyone to go around hacking
ATMs but I'm just saying it's probably
easier than we think so they would go
and collect this money and then drop the
money off to whoever was controlling
them and yeah they took over a billion
dollars on this Bank I believe this one
was it was it was a billion dollars
worth of rubies or ripples that they
ended up stealing so how do we protect
against spear phishing don't share
personal information online try and keep
as much it's easier said than done we
all want to put things on facebook every
now and then
I'm sure off that we're on holiday for
example but you try and be considerate
and try and really think if someone saw
this on my social media could they use
this to exploit some form of trust
relationship that I have with maybe a
third party or maybe a something that
I'm interested in report any suspicious
emails contact the sender before you
download anything and contact the sender
before you click on any links so now's
the fun bit see who is actually
listening and we will be giving out some
lock picks for this so can anyone tell
me how often is malware sent as an
attachment yes
[Music]
so yeah according to Verizon two-thirds
of all malware arrives by email
attachments
what percentage of sophisticated cyber
attacks start with the phishing email
knighted correct how many people from
the carbonic group have been charged one
have been charged one was at risk but no
one's been charged yet what should the
minimum password length be for a low
privileged user account of course anyone
want to answer way like sorry ten
characters obviously this recommendation
may vary depending on companies company
but ten characters usually your standard
for very low privilege user accounts
that don't have easy access to really
doing any damage to either an
application or infrastructure why should
the maximum password length be here yeah
so has anyone got any questions for me
about the presentation pardon they'll be
given out some of the questions yep
[Music]
ya know if you can research a person you
can understand then yes but we recommend
to use password lockers which will be
randomly generating pass phrases for you
that's a really good point absolutely
they use pass phrases because it's all
its dictionary based but a lot of the
time the password lockers will choose
your passphrase but they'll throw some
random complexity into there and some
random bits too to break up words so
that they're not necessarily untrue
words at that point it's very question
yes this housands of people so we'll
we'll start off by going through their
LinkedIn and we'll run some tools it'll
bring sort of all the employees back on
LinkedIn and we'll start with the
obvious we get rid of the IT department
get rid of anyone technical and then
we'll try and break it down usually to
focus on employees that have been there
for less than three months or less than
two months as they likely wouldn't have
had any security awareness or fishing
training at that point but it's a matter
of just filtering and filtering and
filtering until you get down to the five
maybe ten people you'd actually choose
or then then you'll research them
individually as a person so if I chosen
to focus on you for a spear phishing
attack I'd go to your Facebook your
Twitter your LinkedIn read your local
newspaper see if you've ever fit in
there for example if you if you have
interested in football that I know
that's potential exploit point I can go
into and yeah just researching the
person is a specific individual to
understand them
non financially motivated um yeah so
yeah in in terms of complete in terms of
actual research that I've read I'm not
aware of any but I could see how it
could be used so usually when there's no
monetary value involved in a tap there
has to be something else involved in it
it could be an attacker that has a
massive ego that's just doing it for fun
but it would most likely in that case be
either a competitor or someone that
would have that would benefit in some
way of actually either knocking down
your infrastructure or getting into your
your email accounts no I'm not aware of
any research specifically yeah yeah yeah
almost aw yeah absolutely
yeah absolutely I think the only way
that we're ever going to be able to
really tackle spear phishing is security
awareness training definitely you could
potentially but the codes reset every 60
seconds if you're using Google
Authenticator
yeah I'm not entirely sure I wouldn't
know how to go about approaching that
once we Afghanistan yeah evil jinx yep
yep yes interesting follows this is the
last one giving up yeah a comfortable
amount of data to gather is until you
are personally comfortable you know that
person well enough that if you would
have a conversation with them persons
person for example you'd know ways to be
able to lead the conversations be able
to trick them and steer them it's a
little bit how long is a piece of string
in that sense because you might come
across a really really vulnerable target
a really easy target but you might end
up someone that's posted really obvious
information about themselves online that
you can use to exploit sometimes it's a
little bit more difficult it's usually
down to whether the company is doing
security awareness training or not yeah
so if if people are not reusing
passwords and I can definitely
understand the less rotation what if
you're using a 25 character password
you're only using in one place you're
100% sure it's being stored in
an encrypted format then yes potentially
but the reality is that most people
reuse passwords websites don't always
store your data and clear encrypted and
I'm sure most of people this room have
used have I been poned on one of their
old email accounts and found at least
one or two weeks that they've been in so
in a perfect scenario yes but I just
think unfortunately the human element
makes it a little bit more difficult
than just doing that to buy password
history do you mean so you don't have to
attend class I mean I guess it means
that it really depends on the company
specifically I think how their employees
are how well the any security awareness
training is affected them and how the
kind of setup is I think it should be
looked at on more of an individual case
to case basis as opposed to just
deciding straight away but I think
rotating passwords does have its merit
but that is usually because of password
reuse attacks that have been coming out
of clear text leaks and that kind of
thing so if people aren't using their
password in multiple places and they're
not reusing then yeah you can get rid of
the yeah yeah I mean they also used to
say that um complexity was more
important than length in terms of
computational power so I think
everything needs taken with a little bit
of a pinch of soul
I personally my personal view is the
password should be rolled over and they
should be changed and they should be a
policy that
is forcing people to reset their
password every maybe six months to a
year I know three months was thrown
around for a while at one point but I
think it's being increased quite a lot
now by most companies but I don't see
why reinforcing users change a password
can actually be a negative thing if
they're using a password blocker yeah in
what sense
not really I mean on a typical
penetration testing engagement where
we're doing phishing campaigns will ask
to be white listed on a web application
test when we're testing will ask to be
white listed this isn't this is in a
standard penetration test as opposed to
red teaming this is because we're
looking to test the vulnerabilities the
code itself or the humans themselves if
they're gonna click on it as opposed to
testing someone's defenses or anything
that they've got in place over there
yeah spam filters are great they should
always be used but there's no guarantee
that well I've seen from our experience
will usually ask to be whitelist
engagement through through any spam
filters but I've I've seen recently the
people have been putting JPEGs or PNG s
pasted into emails and as opposed to
having it just in normal text it's
actually an image that's insider and I
think that's one of the ways of people
are trying to bypass different spam
filters at the moment personally not to
my knowledge but if they've done it well
enough and I won't know anyone else I am
NOT I mean I'm definitely getting social
engineered a bit by the partner at the
moment so it's probably me
yes no no typically if a company's never
had a fishing engagement or any security
awareness training you'll get plus 50%
click rate and that'll get lower and
lower with the amount that it goes down
but I mean it does depend on the company
so that's not an exact statistic but
from my previous experience it's usually
roughly 50 yeah yeah I don't yeah do
that okay yeah oh they'll be really
interesting I'll definitely have a look
at that awesome cool anyone else secure
it security awareness training is the
only way to really tackle it funny and
we should try and ensure that the
languages used in emails are coming
through to us so often when you're at
work for example if you're emailing a
friend you'll use slightly different
language it's analyzing and looking for
these kinds of things but the only real
thing to prevent spear phishing is to
have a real staff awareness security
awareness training program and regular
fishing campaigns
it's definitely paying off so when when
we've typically been doing a fishing
engagement for a company will will be
three or four maybe five and we see
significant changes between each one
yeah that we're doing the fishing
engagements against so the one the one I
use an example
a big pharmaceutical company so massive
it can really vary from from small media
from small businesses small mediums to
large financial institutions last
question if there is one yes please so
one of the things that we recommend is
if you have a phishing assessment done
you watch is sure those users you don't
shame and there's no need to share not
use except if seven under training then
there's no point in fighting with fire
basically so the best thing to do one is
to show them what their actions lighter
so if we fished a you CEO say and there
are no efficient training I thought is
that you know the bare minimum
show him because of your options you
know this malicious target managed to
steal on your passport number your
credit card information the company the
crown jewels basically if the company
and they make some think a bit more and
then they start to apply a lot mentality
so their own personal emails because you
know that's why it's going to kick in
the most really yep thank you very much
thank you very much guys