good morning everyone and thank you very
much for coming oh the Middle's delight
let me move away because I can see you
know that's me with more hair with us me
who I am like Roy said CBT and a
practitioner I'm a parenting consultant
and I do lots of work with recovery
college in reading so I run workshops
for anxiety and depression panic attacks
and stress so people that are already
very stressed out and anxious so I know
when they come we'll take the rain now I
don't know how you guys are dealing with
stress and anxiety and things like that
so my agenda for today is discussing a
bit what what mental health is what we
can do to improve mental health who is
anxiety what is the stress hello long
flight what is depression and what we
can do to cope with you know one way
when we are not of weights and we don't
know what to do and we are very stressed
out and we feel that life is not going
the way we want to we want to you know
we want it to go and we envision so that
is the agenda and the alcohol for today
is that if you guys can take one thing
away from today that you can implement
that you think is going to make your
life easier different better that would
be for me the best thing ever
so I don't expect anyone to take
millions of nodes and do I'm going to do
this and I think that if you want to do
that you know go ahead and do it but
sometimes there is lots of information
that is being delivered and it's big
huge elephant if you can just take one
thing and say this is what I'm gonna
implement this is what I'm gonna do this
resonates with me and I think it's going
to make a difference to my life so that
is the outcome really office of this
session on mental health what is mental
health
can anyone say I've got a few things in
there were worries mental health
no one what well yeah we've got physical
health homework or mental health right
so when we talk about physical health we
all know what to do
right hands up whoever knows what to do
to keep up with your health right don't
smoke so much and don't drink so much
five a day no so much sword go on
exercise half an hour five days a week
right we all know when it comes to
mental health whoa what do we do
does anyone know it I didn't write there
was mental health I heard the word
mental health good to Paul but I didn't
know what it was up until I hit rock
bottom about 15 years ago I went through
a really huge depression um I didn't I
didn't know I don't know what to do to
help myself
I was stuck I was in a hole and all I
got was people walking past let's say
and say oh you're not feeling that well
Tina life is okay you know you could
good job you've got you've got husband
if just what house what's wrong with you
we are still in the hole and you're
still looking down and you're not able
to look confident you don't know what to
do so mental health good about mental
health refers to our cognitions our
behaviors and our emotions let's say a
good mental health is how we manage to
express and then with our emotions in
the blood or negative or positive and by
the way there is no negative or positive
emotions is there just emotions all
emotions are giving us something not
telling us we you know if if you go into
panic because you step onto the road and
a bus is coming well that's you know
your emotion is telling you to move get
out of the way you need to know you need
to do something right how we build up
relationships with people all depends on
our mental health right if we have
positive thinking and good thinking we
think importance and we can we can
relate to others if we go out in the
street suddenly someone looks at
from across the road always not going Oh
looking at me Oh want to kill me
oh no looking at me what do you say what
is it I'm looking ugly today it's in my
hair I don't know what is it right but
it's not healthy where you're thinking
that can lead into paranoia right you
don't go out of the house and goes into
looking yourself up so no one looks at
you
so you see understand in emotional
intelligence knowing our limitations
knowing what to do to cope when we get
into moments of the strange man so the
world is upside down and we don't know
what to do that is promoting good mental
health because you're not going through
a crisis and you're not gonna get stuck
so that is my understanding of mental
health and this is from my own personal
experiences to war you know what I think
good mental health is now mental health
problems this is a survey done 2018
stress depression and anxiety is is the
main three mental health problems that
we get to talk about and people are a
bit more open to talk I'm very very
stress at work I'm a bit anxious about
doing this on the other don't like
social situations move away I don't I
don't feel right socializing with people
I'm feeling very low I don't know what
to do with my life so you kind of you
kind of start going is pulling down the
statistics for 2018 is like 15 point 4
million working days are lost for the
year due to stress depression anxiety
now that is because we are not having
the tools to cope we don't know so it
gets to a point in which like I did I go
to my manager and I said I'm not feeling
very well and I'm feeling really down
I'm feeling very blue and crying all the
time I just don't know what to do and
then my manager would say like
says at the time you need to go and see
your GP and I go to GP and I said look
I'm feeling really blue and crying and
said yeah I know you're crying here you
can't even talk what what he said well
you're depressed here you are
prescription a month off off leave go
and sit at home and if you go you know
that you need that break but that
doesn't really sort out the program
that's it what is it living for me so
yes I was at home for month I tell you
what I did I got up really really late I
started having my first pack of
cigarettes around 5:00 in the morning
pacing up and down the corridor by about
midday 20 cigarettes were gone then I
would go and get on to my second pack of
cigarettes by about five o'clock the
second pack of cigarettes was gone and
my about compartment nine the third pack
of cigarettes was gone are they eating
anything
no had they drank anything no did they
sort out my problem no let me empty the
prison's work yes they did I was a
zombie they worked in a way right I just
pasted up along the corridor with my
cigarette wouldn't removing at one point
I just all those many cigarettes you
know worse than another right so I did
the presence helped but we need to help
ourselves as well and wait to understand
what's going on with us if we don't want
this time was going on how we're gonna
solve a problem when we don't understand
because of a problem you don't
understand you need to be able to make
sense of what is going on right so what
is it stress stress is the body responds
to the feeling on wound and many people
talk about stress later but I've got so
much work to do of course much of my
plate I've got so much you know so many
things going on there is stress about
finances health work relationships
strength to be a situation in which you
believe you're supposed to do something
but you don't know how to manage that
something you're supposed to do when you
become all stressed out right I'll give
you an example I'm driving my children
to school and I get into school gave my
child says drop me
in here and I just go but it's a card
behind I can't drop your fin here I'm
going oh
Melissa let's just rest
that's a stretch for everyone for
example we don't take it in different
ways why because we've got certain
behaviors that tells us you've got to do
the right thing the right thing is not
just in the middle of nowhere right I
need to like do it right and it's
perfect so they say as a sense of
perfectionism also attached to the
certain beliefs that we have that
whiteness stressors so relationships
cause of stress health word fluency
anything else that you guys think causes
a stress or stress you on anyone because
this is going mean children absolutely
what's going on in the world right that
is beyond our control and children I
mean they do know how to press it what
else are they we need also to be special
anyone notice sleep at night and you
come and see them on their quiet they go
oh yes oh not me not a few hours ago
when you were screaming at me and so no
yeah you are so stress um how does it
manifest how do we feel it because in in
my in my world when I talk to people
about stress translate and depression we
miss out how it manifests in the body
right when I was doing my civic training
and the rest of it it was all about you
know your thought leads to your feelings
and leads to your behaviors and if you
change your thoughts then you're able to
change the way you feel and the way you
behave
that's all well and good but I act out
before I even have a moment to think
about what has happened right so you're
suddenly going to panic mode run out of
a role you need to get away
you're stressed out or you're anxious
you don't know what what is going on
however if we start looking at both
physical symptoms we have we will be
able to then look into what thoughts and
reframe those thoughts so when I talk to
people about stress I ask them where do
you fit in your stress and something
people say oh I don't know that's what I
tell you
stress is felt all throughout the body
so you can feel your heart rate going
suddenly is is a really fast heartbeat
you start breathing from up here
some people feel butterflies in the
stomach some people fit some people feel
the face the plantain and the Jew
tightens up so if we're able to know
where the stress manifests some people
it's on your shoulders maybe get your
shoulders up to you or to your ears you
can relax a bit right so if we start
understanding first room where we feel
the stress we're able to recognize what
getting stressed out and then we're able
to put some wishes in place it makes
sense to me and I hope it makes sense to
everyone so you need to figure out where
you feel it and the thing is in this
modern world we are so fast going into
everything and anything that we are
going the with we lost our connection
with our bodies which is totally have
lost it we've lost our instant in gut
feeling with lost connection as to what
my body is telling me my body's telling
me something right behavioral
manifestations you all probably know if
you think stress no point in your life
you can't sleep you wake up in the
middle of the night you're irritable you
is not with everyone your eating habits
my you know my goal of the window you
are aggressive with everyone is not be
I'm going out there sometimes I'm going
up tonight
well you didn't say yeah I did say me
weeks ago it's on the calendar I forgot
yeah well I'm still going up tonight one
point you just you just hope enough
you're the wrong people you're just
going you know go away leave me alone
everyone is stressing me so if we can
think of a stress like a container right
I'm gonna stress is coming in cause
stress is coming in and we haven't got
evolved to get this trace hard we just
don't know how to get this trace out
then it goes into long-term chronic
stress it really depletes the immune
system we get all sort of all sort of
hard problems with all sort of IBS and
sanity and depression and Crohn's
disease sport officers and eventually
over time chronic stress will lead to a
very very over word fragile immune
system that will not be able to cope
with any parts of viruses too different
you know your body so if you're
distressed enough for a long period of
time you might find that you get colds
oh you get more clothes dude in the
window you want to find that your
stomach is upside down most of the times
and then you might get some skin
reactions pink brushes and that is
called you to what stress does to us
so there is eternally rushing through
the body that is there is cortisol
rushing through the body they are they
are if you want to call it too sick
chemicals they are there to make us act
they are there to keep it away from
dinosaur a dinosaur is just about to
eaten right is a very old alert system
with God it has been postponed three
years and centuries and millions of
years to our change because we need to
be alerted if something happens but we
don't need to be in a constant state
of simmering stress all the time and
that is what depletes the immune system
there is there is no no way for the for
the body to be able to cope with the
amount of cortisone that comes through
the amount of adrenaline that comes
through you need to release it somehow
and in our modern society in the olden
days you can go and run away from the
dinosaur well that's fine but nowadays
there is no dinosaur
I knew sit at your desk and you're
having a panic attack and you just sit
in there or you're stressed out and the
adrenaline is still running through your
body but you're not getting rid of it
we're not getting rid of it we just sit
there and we just plug it on well
because I need to get that report done
we can't think straight what happens you
can't think straight
um so what can we do to help ourselves
um they are what is called the four
pillars of well-being that was presented
back in October last year by the
University of Reading in a conference
about mental health and well-being and
the four pillars of will Venus is really
straightforward and easy and all of you
know and they just gave it a fancy name
because they need to give something um
give it a name um but it's properly
sleep good nutrition and hydration and I
mean relationships with others so having
a good relationship with others and
these exercises that is the four pillars
of one vein right if you're distressed
don't but you exercise what you should
you know you should do is recommended to
do half an hour five days a week okay
maybe we don't have to climb for another
five days a week half an hour when I
don't for sure but I can say well I'm
going for a walk but when you talk about
well it success nice to people that's
not going o exercise I need to go to the
castle oh I need to get myself shoes I
need to get myself that legging thing
that the mountain is cool work is having
one of those no I don't want to go
exercise him with one who we thought one
of those I know it people were getting
membership for the team I'm there
anything you need to go on and oh I need
the trainer's I need the soccer go with
the trainer because I don't want those
soaps that look like that and this and
that and then I need to complete the
family to do the visit to this thing and
we just make this huge
but if you say for someone to come for
lunch they go oh yeah and for lunch
that's a matter when you go that's in
your front do you want to go for drinks
oh yeah let's go for drinks
yeah they've all hang on a minute what
are we going to what is another over
there what we only gonna have what
spirits are they gonna have nobody's got
drinks yeah yeah it doesn't matter if it
was horrible nice in the world they're
going for drinks right so if we start
thinking about let's have a look at what
we can change in our diet for example if
I am eating I don't know what dollars
every day what surely it's not gonna be
good for me is it if I am drinking five
pints of beer every day there's not
going to be good if I am not sleeping
well you shouldn't have been saying we
don't sleep properly there is no
restorative sleep we go through the REM
sleep when you dream and when you have
the vivid train something you remember
sometimes so you might not remember but
the deep deep restorative sleep is what
helps the brain get rid of the toxins
that it has produced during the day so
when we here we talk when we work with
the things the brain is working the
sense of producing garbage and at night
is when everything is cleansed out now
if you don't speak properly and you go
over the day another day and another day
eventually those books in Singapore they
are going on thank you
you're not rested so so if we start
looking about what we contains and then
when we talk about relationships how do
we manage relationships so I don't know
what you guys but sometimes of you're
very stressed about relationships about
friends and friendships and expectations
people put the words right I had a
friend that all she wanted to do was to
go clubbing every single weekend and it
would be Friday Saturday and Sunday
clubbing so we would do the fried and
they started a club in and off we go and
then on Sunday I used to live in London
we used to go to the church in uh in
case cross that was open from whatever
time in the morning to whatever time I
mean you go there they give you a park I
mean
drinks will just come off from when I
Club it love doesn't matter get your
back your your disparate parts Oh
plastic back with your drinks and you
don't get somewhere and then they said
they say that huh
I mean eventually I go home and it got
to a point when I started not feeling
very well mentally I said I don't want
to go out anymore
I feel very of one of people with noise
I don't want to go out anymore oh we
used to like it yes but no I don't like
it anymore
and then it was argument and it was pain
from course and was text messages and
that became very stressful for me
because I didn't want to lose my
friendship but at the same time I
couldn't comply with what she wanted me
to do so
saying no certain certain boundaries but
you think that it is it's a compromise
let's say for both sighs it's on both
sides and say well you know I will go
out once a month with you I want to go
out or I will do this I will do that
pairings parents harmony how many of you
struggle a baby think it's tread with
perilous my parents were here over half
town for days I was happy for them to go
it was nice it was lovely to see them
don't get me wrong but um why are you
wearing that she was saying oh what
about this shirt yeah sure sure uh is it
watch watch
hmm what are you feeling your children
[Music]
are you cooking that food mm-hmm what
you're driving like that we drive on the
other side of the road bad why not
explain mmm from why are you approaching
the roundabout in the way you're
approaching the runabout
This Is England we're just doing the
other way
oh so having to say sometimes without
hurting feelings and say listen I've
been here 22 years for God's sake get a
break okay well you know you know it's a
long time you should have been used to
it but you know it's not good they were
one the best food for us but sometimes
we don't get into situations in which
you know they want us to do this and on
the other we just not happy with it
so we need to to money set expectations
and say no now what can we do to come to
mind
right why is stress okay when there is a
situation
are you certain yourself can I do
something about it right it's easy yes
why stress you can do something about it
then go ahead and do it just do it
no why stress you can't do anything
about it and I know it sounds very blunt
but the thing is when we start reliving
our past and sometimes I say to people
how present is your past right
how prescient is your past and we start
planning ahead and trying to control
things that we can't control
we stress but if we've got a situation
Elysees right okay this is the situation
of common hands
what can I do about it I can do this and
this and these will it work I don't know
until I give it a go will it not work
well if it doesn't work I'll try
something else and I'll try something
else
and I'll try something else and if there
is nothing to be done there is nothing I
can do cause regardless of what I'm
trying to do there is nothing to be done
so it's not one of these situations that
will say or what are you telling me to
give up why are you telling me not to
carry on are you telling me not to you
know to push forward no I'm telling you
to realistically look at it as it is or
what it is is that if you can do
something do it and if not be mindful so
mindfulness based stress reduction
techniques is what lately has been
implemented in different companies and
they provide a space for workers to be
able to to relax to be able to chill out
or to be able to run to in case they
have panic attacks anxiety whatever I
used to go and lock myself in the
cubicle in the toilet is there was no
place to go so under different different
ways that we can do and I know that
you've heard
probably oftentimes mindfulness and I
tell you what when I first heard
mindfulness I was like over a month of
my own says what among the world raving
I see if I'm not breathing but if I'm
not reading in bed but it's not that
type of breathing you see we've got the
nervous system has the parasympathetic
nervous system big word but it's
basically rest on digest this when you
are till now did when you online know
the age is when you're watching TV and
there is no worries for you that is not
it being calm on the sympathetic nervous
system is the amygdala is the
fight-or-flight response is you need to
get out of here is not stress is the
simmering on solitary right and it has
been proven that breathing from here
from from it diaphragmatic breathing
comes down the the sympathetic nervous
system the fight-or-flight response it
has been proven there is no way you
start breathing from here I'm your
amygdala is still gonna be a different
working that's how you come to certainly
monkeys or in the back of the head that
is constantly going on right you you it
is it is calming it down so I say if it
something to work with parents and
someone said children stress me out I
work with parents most of the times
actually sometimes they call oh my god I
can't take the silence you even hate
here I'm right here that's alright
stop stop and pick five five pick
breaths just from here from you're gonna
put your hand over Billy and just give
it a big breath in on a big breath out
I just do it two or three times a day
your brain gets used to it you bring the
strain on doing it when you run into an
emergency you bring we know what to do
isn't it when your shoelaces when your
little kid you start by learning that
you doing like this and like that and
everything is a staple nowadays you just
going to your shoelace this is like
driving
remember when you started driving
mirrors are in decay
they were indication one over oh my god
I look like a parrot not trying to
remember what I'm doing now whoever is
struggling here you know that you just
do it you don't have to think about it
so if you if you train your brain to
start doing some breathing if you train
your brain to relax if you go before you
go to play it on your samurai token I'm
gonna relax I'm gonna relax I'm going to
stop focusing on my toes I'm gonna relax
my faith I'm gonna relax my curves on my
legs and you progressively work your way
through the body eventually you'll fall
asleep I can guarantee you huh and
eventually you'll have the best sleep
ever so you need to start relaxing your
body and relaxing your mind and then
visualization techniques sometimes when
I'm stressed out of my mind I just think
where have I been in a place but I felt
really really really relaxed and happy
and a page and I just think myself lying
on a beach on each one when the Sun is
hot and I'm like oh this is nothing no
children no Christian sleepy bird on the
Sun emits no feeling at all and you can
actually recreate that so you can be in
the place anytime you want
it's all in your head and you've got the
ability to do it because you've got the
ability to relieve a horrid moment
you've had in the past why wouldn't you
use the same ability the relief a good
woman that you've had in your life
because the brain watch how with watch
is out for the negative because it's not
alert
you know alert alert Danger Danger so
for negative things the brain is not
velcro and for positive things is like
Teflon we tend to forget it
oh forget forget program so those are
things that we can do to mine one time
is an issue we're talking about work and
when time is an issue we'll let's look
at what we can do in terms of organizing
our our our word you know sometimes I
find myself doing the the millions of
emails why are you doing that
is it gonna bring you something no
really
am i dealing with things that need to be
done and they are not urgent but they
need to be done because if I don't do
them you know I'm gonna be stressed out
if I leave you finally Fabio and I'm not
planning a bail let's say until the last
minute and I get the reminder then I'm
gonna be stress not about pain that they
write they finally to arrange whatever
for work and I don't do the presentation
and then last minute I need to put the
presentation together I'm very stressed
out so one time is one time is it's an
issue that it structures it what we
don't want to do we complete those ones
aside and we can prioritize and we the
the notion of what we think is urgent
and important sometimes everything are
not important sometimes making dinner
for the children is not not important or
that then you can't fix something you
don't need to prepare a three-course
meal - and sometimes sending an email to
someone that you might of crossing the
corridor at work and say okay I have
seen your email but haven't got the one
with now to do it I will reply the
backup you had always should've
should've should've done it using the
shoes from the masked man I have to sew
when time does what we can do and when
we need to prioritize rest of the paper
is ask yourselves what outcome you want
what do I want
what when does he need to be done and
some people have some people have white
boards with planners with wit planners
and they say right that needs to be done
that needs to be done what resources do
I need who needs to be involved in here
what what else do I need
and then you just is a really really
quick step one your brain knows what to
do step one two three four five as many
steps as you need and then just go
through your list when you get it out of
your brain and you put it in paper is
when you you suddenly come visualize
what needs to be done it's not making
that washing machine just painting noise
in the back of your head and you can
actually take action in a in a manner
that is not stressing you know
stress leads to anxiety and depression I
tell you why when our amygdala when the
fight or flight response is constantly
on we're stressed all the time I wanna
make my eyes constantly going the limbic
system if you can think of your brain as
a fish unlesss are usually presented
this is your limbic system this is your
amygdala the adrenaline gland sits back
here and this is your prefrontal cortex
this what makes you Russian what makes
you relate to people in a normal manner
and it is it regulates your emotions
now when you are in a constant similar
in state of stress that is like a lid
frames up it's not proper flipped up but
that flips up a new artist working in
reptilian brain now when the amygdalae
sandwich hunt all the time was going
almost coming almost almost almost it's
like a mere cut or like a prairie dog
and it's just going that what's going on
what's going on what's going on is like
Shh there's nothing going on but that is
so unsanitary waste are catastrophizing
honest how you pee is it's not feeling
of sensation of danger unfair an extreme
extreme fear I would say but it's not
actual danger but your brain is telling
you can't throws country what's going on
what's going on what's going on sure
it's got different flavors and people
would have different ways to express an
anxiety let's say social anxiety I was
knocked in the house who liked the whole
hollow and I could not even go out and
buy milk because I had to go out of the
house and talk to the person in the
petrol station that was going to say to
me one calling the police on our freak
out say anything right there is no I
can't do that
I always say but over stay at home
you've got health entire thing what's
wrong what's wrong what's wrong I'm very
good at home fans may as well as my
husband my saying here
so I'll respond you know like the mom
who came up with the children monkey
with the with the baby so I wasn't me -
no come on here let me just take you up
but everything is okay and you've got no
lumps in here and all I'm saying there
know these know that not the other mixed
mommy
come here let me check you up check you
up right some people would take right
I'm just going like all you know school
days and I've got luck and I've got this
and luck phobias panic attack or cities
and their lessons I think just in
general um how does it represent Hey
look look at my poor little one ah nah
it's all that goes on when we're anxious
all of it goes on absolutely every
single thing because you could be
response in a way that triggers all the
adrenaline and cortisol going through so
you'll have sweat in your sweetie and
your legs become jelly you might need to
go to a toilet and suddenly it's like a
toilet you get it with children you
won't feel so sick your stomach is going
you don't know your breathing is like
hey I'm having a heart attack I'm dying
that's what I thought when I first no I
think it's in sorry I'm having a heart
attack I'm dying someone is gonna pick
me up place and take me somewhere so
what do you fill your anxiety I put in
there a fight flight freeze and faint
because the amygdala will get the
sentence but you probably have heard
fight and flight response right when you
need to jump out of a dangerous
situation but when you feel it it will
be in your body so I can tell you for
example that I feel my anxiety when my
heart starts going but I feel my fist so
I'm a fighter I would go and fight that
dinosaur my husband would say that I am
a donkey show their life fight windmills
non-stop and I would for every single
scene so I feel my fist
some people just feel it in the legs and
the legs start going oh they need to
defend me to run somewhere and some
people disturb breathing so soon so much
that they finished in the feel like
gonna faint and some people just freeze
so we're with a little girl last year
you could just literally pick it up so
so picture from there gradually taken
off so we just be like huh for one place
and another and just take huh
okay she was just like a little listen
she was so petrified to share with their
works you can serve it in this port so
some people do that well what do you see
it now you feel in your body and I don't
know whether you've asked yourself such
a question if you have ever suffered
from anxiety or stress but figuring out
where you feel it in your body will hold
here to be able to identify what is
going on with you and their challenge
those thoughts that make you feel the
way you feel so this is the the
stability Crossman and
intimately they say that you've got a
thought a little triggers the emotion
and then the behavior we put marriages
we put safety behaviors in place like I
said you know I'm not going to a petrol
station we're gonna get the bus so for a
while my journey into work was an hour
and a half when you could have been 45
minutes Chris I wouldn't go on a red bus
because red bus says I had a panic
attack on a red bus so I were called
away on the train to Waterloo and then
come out of Waterloo and guess what what
colors are the causes in London red
there is no other color so I come out of
Waterloo and I'm just walking and I see
a man because he's alright was because I
had a panic attack and I was petrified
of a red bus so then I decided to walk
over the bridge into whole wall where
the office was and back I'm just picking
the pages so we put safety behaviors in
place you see um so if we were able to
identify the physical sensation then we
might be able to challenge our thoughts
and unsee
so when we talk about challenging our
thoughts with this kind of mental
distortions that we all have right
someone has looked at me across the road
and all my gold is because they they
they hate me because I don't I don't I
make a pass through Feist and if the
worst is gonna happen and it's gonna
cross the road that person is gonna come
tell me that I'm so scared I was just so
frightened I'm walking into a cinema
social situation
in a room like in here for example a few
years ago I wouldn't have been able to
walk him and I just go oh my goodness so
many people have in your company that
wanted to never sa iyo interesting
company am I am i doing properly I would
say my story or catastrophize and we
find the words of the words of the words
that thing is gonna happen first of all
the bad thing is gonna happen it's gonna
happen to us
that's what we say it's gonna happen to
me it's not gonna be a tiny but thing is
gonna be a huge thing it's just gonna be
just horrendous now I'm not even gonna
be able to hope I'm gonna die someone is
I'm just gonna cry I'm gonna have to run
away
they filter hricko filters we filter is
black and white is either I get it
perfect or I am I'm a loser I'm a
failure
there is no grain between we filter the
positives how many times you have a
lovely day
and sometimes you know there is
something that happens and someone grows
it so how would you like oh my god it
was so rubbish you know I was in the
office and this person came over lunch
and she said that she won't be blah blah
blah done and I couldn't get it done
because I was having lunch when they she
said you do
chatter chatter chatter chatter but you
had to get meeting with your boss you
had a good journey on the trail how to
get your husband you had a good time out
with your friends you went to the cinema
on enjoy we filter all the out and we
just say no negative oh but you're not
generalizing you know everything happens
to me is the worst and everything but in
the world it happens to me right
an emotional reasoning is when we find
the way we find the way to say no but no
but so I often say that I work with
related a while back now and her husband
would come back home late from from work
I mean her mind out her husband was you
know he was unhappy he was having an
affair he was gonna leave her leave her
and the children and what am I gonna do
and this is horrendous and they cease
and you go what else can it be
have you spoken what else can it be
but we lose that mental flexibility of
bordelles can it be right or it could be
the poor man was the stress out of his
brain he was going London hours in your
face and he
comes back home late and he's tired so
he doesn't want to talk and he doesn't
want to eat because he instantly he's
too tired but we just find the way and
she we just say no no no putting 101
together on 101 is like he's doing this
because of and every time she will come
she will have a list of behaviors that
she had picked on him
that would actually confirm her hair her
dance on her husband for example Oh what
can we do right
um in a day you know one night we've got
we've got we're going to happen hobbies
the center when we're feeling calm and
relaxed of peace and if you think it's a
bit the bicycle wheel if every single
one of this Punk's is what happens
during the day right what you've got
during the day going on in your day all
the ring of the of the wheel now when we
feel anxious okay which is focus and
that on the anxiety and how much time
there is pain or do we spend focusing on
what is making us anxious I tell you for
me 90% of the time it would be
constantly in the back of my head does
it make sense now the other things going
on we don't pay attention to them one
thing I want you to do is it's a little
bit of an exercise and we might might
wake some people up from talking
toughness Network falling sleep is a
dark room anyway if you get your finger
on your index finger out go on don't be
shy
I'm not gonna bite the finger of a
promise get the finger out just put it
straight ahead of you
and then keep bringing it slowly slowly
slowly slowly as close as you can as
close as you can to your notes on at one
point you're gonna feel and if you hold
it there and you keep looking at it
intensively okay you're gonna feel that
your eyes is not hurting you're
squinting is not comfortable you lose
your peripheral vision when you think
that it's not here you can focus on that
finger you can
still see what is going on around you
it's called peripheral vision when you
think that is here
you've lost your peripheral vision is
called for your vision now what we
needed in the day just focus on that
unsightly what are we doing which is and
what is it doing when we when we are
looking at it for a long period of time
it hurts your eyes will hurt eventually
is not comfortable anymore with anxiety
this is what we do we just focus on that
particular point instead of just putting
it aside and saying right I've got other
things going on right so when you feel
yourself anxious I often say to people
the way they you stop yourself right
afoot concern when you stop yourself I
used to wear elastic band around my
wrist and whenever I used to feel
anxious I used to snap it because that
would get me out of it and realize that
I am being anxious and then I would ask
myself what is going on in here what am
I thinking what has happened that has
triggered the state I am in and that way
I can then act on it and the way to act
on it is it's in different different
different techniques and different ways
to act on it when you've got the thought
that is not a healthy thought is called
the three C's for CVT you catch the
thought which is the hardest part it's
like cutting going fishing it's hard you
know you catch the thought you collect
the evidence you become a duplicative of
your swords right you need to collect
all the evidence before you can say well
this is true or not because reality is a
sword the sword is not a fact right I
think we are all ok with that
good it's a stone now I thought crisis
our minds if we engage with it we can
aspire on down now it's a thought it
could be true it cannot be true if we
let it go past our heads as if our Birds
just don't engage just be an observer no
facade yes I had a thought but you don't
engage with it it's a different matter
if you choose to engage with it you cut
safe and then you collect the evidence
and you ask yourself what evidence doing
half of this thought through and against
what else can it be
what else can I say that I can look at
it could I look at it from a different
perspective could I look at it from a
different angle
this of a look if I've been owned about
several times before and nothing has
happened I've not heart the heart that I
can have not died right oh why would I
know
okay what is it different in this
situation that it was in the previous
situation okay yes yeah so you see that
listen when I when I put the roof on
before so in sympathy they say any
challenge your thoughts become a
detective of your thoughts however
remember I was telling you before that
you act so fast that you don't have the
time to challenge your thought that's
why I said pay attention first of all to
your physical symptoms because then you
know that you are having a thought that
is not healthy because your body is
telling you if you do that body mind
body connection right and then you can
you can challenge the thought and when
you can tell you something you say well
what other way is a more realistic way
of looking at it well what a friend of
mine say what if that what a simple
friend that has to NATO base in Ghana is
happening over on us you say to me I
what would he say to me what is a more
reasonable way of looking at this
situation so you talented another way
that I do it and I often say when I when
I run this this particular technique
with others not telling do it so much
better than we do because we others have
lost all imagination whatsoever and I
said
unsightly you're not born anxious you're
not coming out
I'm you're anxious already the same way
you're not gonna smoke on you know you
don't come out with a cigarette in your
hands right no so we learn if it's a nun
behavior we can unlearning
with one your own brain to be to be
anxious week on my of the brain we can
break those
connections so if you start thinking of
your anxiety as it is my warrior helping
me be safe
however is like a faulty car along
sometimes they set off and it needs to
be rewired
and sometimes it's telling me don't make
me think of the reason I'm used to
personalizing it and often I say you
know you can put it in the palm of your
hands and say this is my anxiety talking
to me right you start feeling anxious
actually did it in a supermarket my
husband doesn't know this but know him
in the supermarket and I I feel very
very very anxious and I was pushing the
shopping trolley and I was going to the
cashier and I was so panicking my legs
were going thank goodness a hot that
trolley because I was holding on to it
so the life of me thinking I'm gonna
faint in here and everyone is gonna
notice he's gonna be terrible and I got
to get to the cashier just to the table
to pay and they started packing but my
hands were steaming really that I
couldn't really get the things out come
on you know X I gotta fall and then
everything is gonna fall and I like foot
right enough and I put it in the palm of
my hand give it a nice tight bikinis
give it a shape give it the color give
it the name what he said I'm happy
whatever they hold on the water nowadays
I mean really really close and it's got
these rooms in here that's right
but you can talk to it you can actually
talk to you inside and say I know you're
trying to protect me I know you think
this is something but but it isn't I'm
in the supermarket needless to say
people started looking at me thinking
it used to be looked up and I was just
going right what what he said it was
like to be or not to be to be or not to
be and I was just looking like what you
want no no I'm fine I'm fine this is the
supermarket things no problem
yeah you don't in any way you want to do
but what we're trying to do in here is
to disassociate yourself from your
anxiety you are not your anxiety and say
it is something you do when you don't do
it all the time you do it sometimes so
if we can start thinking about anxiety
as something we do then we gonna stay
sane right I can do it I cannot do it
I've got a choice it's not me when I
first went very very very safe I went to
a psychiatrist and she
he said to me get used to it this is
what it is this is what it gonna be for
the rest of your life depression anxiety
that's a part of Prozac
off you go when you run out what do you
GP any okay mayor Parker um that was the
end of it and I saw mm I was okay before
I was fine for what is among a number of
years right
I know if there's something I'm not fine
and you're telling me that this is gonna
be it well no I'm not faced this has
hurt man I it has happened for a reason
I don't know what it is this number five
is something that we have done is
something that is very very good to do
because when new and answers you think
about your anxiety all the time a few
hitmen if you city is some 15 minutes
every day 15 minutes every day whatever
the rural place so I used to live in my
bedroom I stay in the bedroom I'm just
going the bedroom I was a bullet champ
sit down in the bedroom and just go
right okay timeout 15 minutes oh
goodness
it was it was so hot baby no more when I
anxious thought comes and you worry time
is finished your money a box in your
head or backpack are used to merging I
had a backpack and you tuck it in
don't worry time and all the time you
break those connections because the more
you think about your entire thing it's
like a tomato plant you're watering it
you're tending to it you're picking the
box
we're even have beautiful beautiful big
Tomatoes do you want a big tomato no
thank you very much I don't want it you
say so if you if you give you some 15
minutes I need to say this is what it is
you start breaking up those connections
and guess what happened one day a friend
of mine said let's go to the cinema
I heard them into the cinema for
donkey's years I was so scared of pain
and in a closed place with people I
didn't know you know what I couldn't do
is something hop in a panic attack and I
went and I said okay I'm gonna be a
phenomenal and I went to the cinema I
came back home and it was too late leave
me and I went or eaten gone decided
tango I couldn't get that day and over
time I did something else I was so
excited I went to the cinema
I went for the drink I went for a coffee
and then I didn't need more time anymore
because I was able to control my
thoughts I'm telling him
grounding is when you are in a state in
which you're doing a presentation like
me you know here five o'clock in the
morning I I wasn't in a very good state
of mind and it's really really really
quick and you just say okay three things
I can say three things I can hear three
things I can feel and then you go down
two things I can say two things I can
feel I can I can hear two things I can
feel anything you go down one thing I
mean you take a deep breath now what
you're doing when you're doing that when
you're anxious the your right brain you
don't think this is your brain so when
you're done choose right emotions are in
the right side of the brain and they're
just running running running like wine
and you're spiraling down now there is
no integration with the left side of the
brain which is the language the logic
the lateral side of the brain in which
you you you can make sense of things
when you start saying three things I can
hear three things I can see you're
starting getting the language the left
side of the brain when you engage the
left side of the brain that is
integration in the brain some people say
it's a distraction but in reality
neuroscience what there is is an
integration between left and right
hemisphere of the brain no I'm going to
technical with it before visualizing
depression depression is feeling blue
every day feeling sad every day feeling
worthless you don't sleep you don't need
I used to just you know smoke like I
said up and down the corridor I I
couldn't eat my stomach was in a state
I couldn't sleep either I couldn't make
sense of the world I couldn't make sense
of myself now very characteristic of
depression is that you lose interesting
things that you used to like in the past
you you don't want to do things and you
see the world in a different way now
that is overall
what we feel when we are depressed there
is no restorative sleep there is no
concentration we can concentrate we can
engage the prefrontal cortex to to be
able to you know function in the world
we can't function basically what happens
in our brain happens in your brain when
we are very very stressed and we have
like you know we explained before
adrenaline and cortisol and Wilko court
longer eco corticoids rushing through
now we've got really good chemicals in
the brain nor a not a big thing I never
want to hear that we're right helps you
be alert I'm mentally alert and active
okay but we're depressed because I wanna
meet because our amygdala has been
overworked okay
the levels go down and when the levels
of norepinephrine go down it will make
you feel a nolo me more team will make
you feel blue look at corticoids always
look and also lower the production of
dopamine and dopamine is the feel the
feel-good chemical that we have and when
we enjoy something this is what I
encounter now with kitties that they're
all of gaming on that less for night why
because the dopamine levels go up is
that reward system but when we are
depressed that goes down so then no
wonder that we don't enjoy activities
anymore and then the stress that goes
with it reduces the serotonin which is
the if in the feel-good
is the failure good chemical so we
become really depressed and then we
start developing certain core beliefs of
helplessness of worthlessness and enough
ability and we turn it on waste and one
loser I'm a failure I can't get anything
right you know me I don't fit in so we
start seeing the world ourselves on the
future in a negative way so it just goes
thrown in circles and it goes run in
circles so Buddhist is not really we
create our own environment and what he
refers to what he means is now when
we're depressed we don't get to see the
positives in life we don't get to see
the good things in life we just focus on
the negativity about ourselves the world
on the future so people come and say oh
but you know you got something to look
forward to no I don't because I am not
feeling I'm enjoying anything in life
lately and I'm not happy with anything
and I feel bad with myself people don't
love me people don't like me it's not
the case but we filter now why why we
feel depressed sometimes well this is
the current self and this is the ideal
self we all have a blueprint the order
of the world that is ruled by our
beliefs and our core essence of who we
all are as individual and unique human
beings and we've got values and we've
got beliefs I said and dreams as to the
world should be know this and this and
this is a blueprint we're all born with
it we all know that I'm gonna be like
this I'm gonna be like that I want this
in my life I want that and I want the
other now when there is a gap between
the current self and the ideas of your
blueprint that very suffer you say and
we suffer because we are not paying
attention to who we are so that we are
oftentimes
conditioned by the society by our
parents by pictures by what we should do
what we shouldn't do I'm a family man I
need to provide I need to do this I need
to do that right in my case I was a
pharmaceutical sales rep I was always
told on my parents work and a good
salary do this do that to the other I
used to work ten twelve hours a day
very very very successful but it's not
me so it was not conditioning that you
must half a salary you must have a good
salary you must have - you must have
that and it's like an onion and it's
Vegas and layers her layers that you
that you put upon yourselves ever since
we are little and we start picking up
beliefs that might not be our beliefs so
the bigger the gap between your current
situation and your radium self
the more suffering we get right um
basic human needs so what can we do so
if we start thinking about we all have
certain human needs and our values and
our actions are developed over time
according to we value the most
so some people would probably certainty
meaning that I've got a routine I've got
a job I do this every day and this is
this is me I don't like this is me as
well by the way a certainty is one of
mine I do not want to be doing bungee
jumping I am NOT adventurous if I'm
going somewhere my husband will turn I
need to plan the whole thing out what
I'm gonna eat what I'm not gonna eat
what I'm gonna go the bus fare whatever
it is some people like variety that's
the adrenaline junkie that you might
find others people that change jobs
every so often or they like being here
and there and everywhere
some people like being significant being
value for who they are and some people
say well I want to be seen as who I am I
want I want my own authenticity to be
acknowledged and to be accepted
unconditionally some people very local
connection some people value love a
growth or contribute contribution now
growth is learning is developing in
whichever way and contribution is is
giving back so when I was a
pharmaceutical sales rep when I was
being told that you need to generate X
number of millions right oh yeah it goes
against my values because my value here
is contribution I am a giver I want to
take her so but on the other hand I have
to get a good job because my mom and dad
you know you know in life with giving
you an education and get a good job get
your money have a house have children is
all this conditioning that we have so
when you start looking at what is that
you value and you start aligning your
actions and your values and your beliefs
according to that is when when you start
feeling that you can actually make a
change in your life so you can you know
you can sister what do I want to
experience more in life what was
important for me in life or what do I
enjoy experiencing in life for me will
be no fun connection and contribution I
like even some other people way I want
to be significant
I want to be valued right in in civitate
we talk about concurrent depression with
valued activities now because you've
seen that a human needs chart over there
when I talk about value that activities
you need to actually consider what you
value before you start looking at the
activities because as I said I used to
go clubbing Friday Saturday Sunday and I
used to do it and at one point I said I
don't want to do it anymore
I didn't realize why I didn't want to do
it and I didn't know what was it that
was so for me so against it and then I
realize that because I want a little fun
connection going clubbing getting
actually provide me with the opportunity
to be connected with others because when
you're in a nightclub let's be honest I
mean you can be connected so that the
solar as you're jumping then you can
have a meaningful conversation you can't
have a coefficient I would say okay I
value that I would come for a coffee
with you
so small daily changes that go according
to your values and and that is what you
need to do putting it to align with what
you really truly think and when you
reevaluate your beliefs at the same time
and you say what I must do this and you
can actually say to yourself oh his
belief is this one I must work right
when I said well no I must go if I need
to be full-time employed and blah blah
blah and I stopped to say to myself okay
who who do I believe with this one but
if my parents is not lying I'm quite
happy working you know not having to do
this whatever big corporation or
whatever it is I'm quite happy doing my
own thing so so when we can do
activities that align with with those
three points it when we start becoming
the oh yeah now to want it to straight
when you feel blue when you feel
depressed you can do it in three ways
you can change your focus like we were
talking with moving your focus move not
will when you focus on the room you can
change your language or you can change
your physiology I often say to people
that if I am to talk to myself when I
say change
when we talk to ourselves if if I am to
talk to me soon oftentimes my talk will
be oh so rubbish you're such a stupid
person what would you do that it's a
negative negative negative so for me
it's hard to be mindful and change my
language change my focus is also very
hard but physiology is something easy
for me to do now if I am to ask you here
how when someone is depressed can you
figure on in your mind how they look
what body
what would a poster do they have and you
might not have seen a depressed person
in your life but when you talk about
depression what do we what do we think
in our minds is this your cruelty now
you're looking down you're slow you your
facial features are being and son right
if you are to change if you are to
change your physiology and straighten up
and look up your brain will change I
will leave you with a pic talk we're
young sociologists social psychologists
in Harvard University called
Amy Cuddy and the talk is fake head
until you become it and she's done loads
of research and studied into how your
physiology changes your brain and it's
amazingly interesting and she talks
about how postures that you hold it for
two seconds and this is the Wonder Woman
once pulls it and you hold the footage
segments on the cortisol level goes down
and the good feeling levels goes up and
it's a very very very interesting feel
because we always said our brain changes
our bodies but our bodies also change
our brain and that is all for me I think
I've over run I'm so sorry any questions
I'll be happy to if there is any
questions so a lunch is gonna be out
there so you've got but before we go
these big round of applause is all about