thanks very much for joining us we are
the beer partners we're here to talk
about organizations that claim they
taking security seriously what in fact
they do quite the opposite and we're
also here to talk about some examples of
good practice that are out there we've
got a couple of friends so they need no
introduction themselves but they're
gonna join us in a little while around
so so we'll kick off is anybody in the
room under the age of 18 yeah okay
there's always one mental age so here we
carry a parental advisory because we do
some of it one of us does tend to say I
say all right that's just why I say okay
okay so that's why we carry the parental
advisory so there might be a bit of
swaying but the will make every effort
to keep it in context to the talk okay
if any of you start swearing then that's
fine retinol advisories out so thank you
very much meadow for the introduction
you look fantastic
would we like to introduce ourselves
we'll start with Krissy hello Christy
Morgan I'm Mike I'm John up the knocketh
difficult name you're in England but I'm
the Belgian guy I'm fat Hobbit I have
one in sweet hollow hey I'm Sean okay
thanks very much guys so you can you can
see I have two it handles all up there
and the bear farmers do have their own
Twitter account you probably see as we
do propaganda shit out from there from
time to time we had an APB bought bro
we're apt Bock for a while which really
did upset and scary people
it wasn't the intention it was hashtag
just for fun and we have a website which
we don't keep up-to-date whatsoever so
we have a website you did we have a
lesson so on WordPress when it comes to
redundant websites on ghost
I heard it's unhackable we have a slide
around that took the topic in a little
while and the websites down
so what I'll go through this and think
so are we in the real world so Chrissy
does physical security I call it closed
reception but I really didn't
necessarily know what that means
physical security and friendly hacking
you do a lot of stuff I work for an ISP
in the north of England calls an
internet so we a medium-sized
organization and I run the security
analysis team so I'm a defender I've
sent a lot of emails we'll get on to
that in a second John's of security
champion for his organization back in
Belgium so he spends a good word about
everything we do in his a defender
manager and then email irate Allah
didn't talk about the emails about yeah
yeah and he provides great in self so if
you know in who know his background its
Canadian intelligence poetry it's all
yeah so he's got a lot of us half of my
rock-and-roll stories you've got the
best stories really Sean you're a
security champion in your own
organization and Andy is a friendly
hacker a hot-shit reports ok fitting
that a certain organization has a stand
outside awkward and we try to come in
quietly but clearly that's not gonna
happen it didn't happen but if you see
any of our talks earlier in the year
throughout the first six months of the
year we do tend to discuss Facebook
quite a lot and we don't do it just
because we want to pick on face but we
do it because they're constantly in the
news for egregious practice okay so you
don't really need to spend too far away
from social media all the news platforms
to find that's Facebook of lost data
Facebook have made a really carnal
decision at the very top of the
organization around privacy and that
goes on all the time and the
the quote there that I took from an
email that Mark Zuckerberg sent to
senior execs who's way back was that
privacy is a social norm of the past and
I think that seems to be we see evidence
of that evidence in support of map and
as a consequence the current perception
is that Facebook is evil call their
lawyer came out last week and said that
nobody using social media should have
any expectation of privacy because if
they read the terms conditions because
we all do they'll see that actually they
seek our permission to do whatever they
want with our personal data that may
well be right when it's written down but
a no one ever reads the season sees we
know that Apple's T's and C's
I don't read the T's and C's in a back
pack packing our receipts Moschino stuff
but then there's a moral argument about
it and their lawyer said that we can all
go and that comes a little bit after
Mark Zuckerberg said the opposite like
you said that we should be taking
privacy and security more seriously so
the the higher echelons of that company
are diametrically opposed will each
other philosophically and I think that's
not great so when we talk about faithful
we talk about the organization at large
and it's senior executives and some of
its philosophical directions and
decision making what we're not talking
about is the security engineering and
the good people at work for the
organization of which there are many
were the guys are at that table there
those guys out there great guys yeah so
a quick show of hands and we like to do
this and who's got a Facebook account
you'd have to tell as well who it is
what is well since that's quite a few me
I've got one I use it who deleted their
Facebook account in light of things that
have gone on okay not soon not too many
I don't know how many hundred people are
in the room but that's quite low number
ten percent yes who's thinking about
getting rid of their Facebook account in
the context of hashtag delete facebook
so again not too many and I see
arguments about we get involved in
discussions about this and I think
really it's about understanding your own
threat profile the other day and I use
my Facebook to chat with mates and share
pictures and cat memes and stuff like
that but I do that on squared C if you
follow me on to it ile you'll know so
understand you threat model but also
understand that to a large extent
Facebook does not take your security
seriously as an organisation and you
guys want to comment well it's just I
have a super depressing life so I don't
exactly want to have it on Facebook not
to mention your rookies Lord oh yeah you
know I think you came under the point
and I think you know Sean said it best
what's your quote about Facebook that if
it's free is that your quote I get the
two confused to look like brothers and
I'm shit with names although that's my
cue
yeah the quiz essentially if the player
if the product is if the platform is
free year of the product is the same for
anything separate where's the simple
link tennis is here for social media
simple pornhub it's the same for every
business you are the product success is
that speaking that doesn't calm so it
turns out that actually privacy is a
pain you Mark Zuckerberg wallet because
I know if you read it in the news
recently and Facebook of put aside or
made it a profit adjustment between
three and five billion US dollars to pay
a Federal Trade Commission fine against
levy of all their practice around
privacy so that's kind of I'm realizing
that financially it will harm them
ultimately and you think well three or
five billion in the context of the value
of Facebook might not be much money but
in the old scheme of things finds we
were seeing around this book I see a
level finds at four to five hundred
thousand dollars so we are starting to
see some pretty serious financial
penalties hitting these organizations
Sean also shareholders and investors and
that do not like seeing fans issued
against companies because obviously
should at last so again that's something
that should hopefully well I'm not
advocate of trying to bury businesses
but provide incentives to do the right
thing and treats deal with morals and
that property and ethic
[Music]
yeah and also with Facebook and Google
and some of these big companies they
make this kind of money within minutes
or hours you're finding them and they
don't really care it's kind of like a
more of a outlook of how they look but
well I think we could do is perhaps
restrict them so where they've got their
ads in a certain country suppling from
having their ad revenue coming in or
stop them from being I guess within
Europe if they've got the GDP our to
fall back on so yeah okay we're about to
finish hammering Facebook but again it
goes about four point I made earlier
excuse me about their lawyer can't quite
agree with them as an organisation he's
defending the fact that they should
really be perfectly a liberty to do what
they're doing well I think to one of the
aspects of this is it's running straight
into the entire concept of the GDP are
so at some point they're going to be
showdown right there's going to be a
whole bunch of supervisory authorities
on one side and there's give me a
Facebook lawyer on the other side and
it's gonna come to a head and and it's
it's not just Facebook the the most
startling thing I heard about the other
day was that Google has written an email
parser for anyone that's on the Gmail
platform all right and what this email
parser does is it looks for evidence of
something that you bought I like a
receipt and it stores that information
away and this wasn't disclosed to
anybody using the Gmail platform that
that was going on and so we're starting
to see more and more of these ways that
your personal private information the
things that you buy are scrutinized by
these companies and then they profit off
of that information that you never gave
a right to them to sell to a third party
or to use you know to win an election or
any of those things yeah absolutely
and so we said we'd stop panning twice
booked that's exactly what we're gonna
do and we're gonna go someone else
hummed in the air or shower
who's this fella Jack Dorsey right so he
came out with a wonderfully
philosophical statement years ago about
I just want to build stuff that really
simplifies our base human interaction
but I think that was him saying that we
want to get more people connected and
that really was the fundamental basis in
what started Facebook that they're
stalking but it makes you wonder it
makes me wonder around where did that
message or that belief get lost I got
lost in profitability and shareholder
values and all that custom but again you
know we talked about masses of data
being lost they lost a Twitter 330
million records in 2018 personal data
and I wonder and I said this in a couple
of our talks whether we become over time
a little bit desensitized if the numbers
aren't in the at least hundreds of
millions and billions and squillions and
gazillions that seems to only make the
news these days but I used to work in
local authority for a large council in
the north of England and we had a root
and branch investigation if a single
child record was lost or a USB stick
with a couple of kids records was lost a
left in a taxi and that would often
result in serious disciplinary action
and that was before anybody really
understood about the depth perception
implications and stuff like that so I
care about one record if that can cause
harm or a disadvantage to individual we
try my touch on submission a little one
so Ian's got a little story to tell and
I'm just gonna push the book yeah so
first America really interesting
scenario there and actually I'm gonna
get one of my other beer fires to jump
into that huge company huge amounts of
data all of it basically publicly
available what was the vulnerability I'm
not super technical anymore I used to
know a lot about windows 2003 server
well what is it
where there's like no the I dorm was the
attack vector and essentially this
allowed you to incrementally index and
see all of those records to the tune of
what was 85 million eight hundred eighty
five mil 885 of columbian records all of
the information you would need to do
email phishing identity impersonation
mortgage transfers
any of those type of things or even
extract money using those nefarious
tactics of the immigration police are
coming for you and you need to go and
buy a whole bunch of Apple pay pay cards
in order to not get arrested immediately
so this is fuel to the fire and really
detailed information histories of
properties that you've owned and sold
like is a massive haul and and the point
that I'm trying to make about this is
that the issue did not lie here I think
with the intentions of the organization
this happened as a result of a pressured
IT environment you guys might all be
able to kind of like agree with this a
high-pressure IT environment where the
business said we're going to the cloud
make it work and the IT guys started
disabling security until it worked so
that they could say project delivered on
time and on budget let's go to the next
thing so the question really becomes as
if that's what IT did to deliver this
project the security team there's some
negligence there you know where was the
pen test where was the audit even you
know wait so this is where we're going
with this in terms of this is a business
failure and not an IT or IT security
failure
yeah the thing with that is that we see
that often if you can count you can hack
literally and you have this amount of
data and this is yeah like Froy is
giving workshops Scott is doing them as
well now this is basic security
knowledge first of all you have to you
need to have skilled people so train
them and the second thing there was a
very good remark you made that you
should have found that even before a pen
test this is security testing this
should be part of your life cycle not
not something that comes out of a pen
test event as this for the special cases
the more difficult ones but not for yeah
just incremental number that's insanity
and you should never yeah as a security
team you should never agree with that
this is basic security
yep I'm sure so I'm going to read the
top part out you can read that
yourselves but what it roughly
translates doing in our parlance is we
take your security seriously but
evidently not so if somebody hand him a
mic I'd like to welcome mr. Troy hunt
for the stage I couldn't do that I
couldn't do that not a chance
so Troy and we know a bit about breaches
but I think it's fair to say that you're
recognized as somebody that knows a hell
of a lot more than we do so what we'd
like to get is a little bit of your
insight about your current understanding
of air your current thoughts on the
subject and why you think it's heading
we're all screwed basically
hey can I give everyone stickers well
I'm here yeah plus I get to throw stuff
at the audience and it's all kind of
fence around they're all for you tonight
on so we're all screwed yeah yeah what
am i up to seven point seven billion was
it last year yeah we had a we had a
shout out listen couple of months ago we
had a something like there were three
records the human put live on the on the
earth that had been written a breach
that we knew about but we chatted about
and you said money faster lower the
number and you reckon it was probably
ten per living person on the planet and
some so I guess that the raw numbers in
heavy beam powers were seven point seven
billion records so just put in context
as obvious there's not that many people
there are sixteen records that's me
because I'm in Dropbox and LinkedIn and
stuff like that so you know that's sort
of part of the front like one person
ends up propagating their data at
multiple times over and then in terms of
unique email addresses owns about four
billion or something and and that's kind
of weird too because in my mind I don't
know if are there four billion people
themed a Larissa's how many people on
internet but two or three or something
some number of billions but then like
you end up with multiple email addresses
so the various data have a been pined is
my work email address and my personal
email address we both need OB database
so you end up with multiple email
addresses multiple instances and then we
see a lot of data breaches as well this
is serve a lot of crap in them like a
lot of fabricated addresses particularly
some of the data aggregators like I
later I think was something like you
know let's say it was Apollo to i/o one
of these aggregators it just takes a
whole bunch your data from different
places places like you know when you
sign up to that survey to win the cruise
and then you wonder why you didn't win
the cruise but you've read the terms and
conditions beforehand it was like we may
take your data and sell it to people
none of you read that wait there's no
cruise this is the thing what they take
your data and then they aggregate it in
the seller and one of the interesting
things from some of those data breaches
is there's people on ever been poned who
work in organizations they get domain
search results so they'll you know
they'll work for Acme core and I'll load
something like a polo and they get this
email which is like here's all the email
addresses that were in Acme core on your
domain and they're like but I don't have
sales at marketing at and a lot of these
organizations just fabricate these
addresses so of that sort of four
billion unique email addresses is also a
whole bunch of junk in there as well so
[Music]
here's a really good graphic and I kind
of know this exists because you used it
in your coronis UDP our briefing do you
go so personally I find this really
impactful at work or what I'm doing
talks internally because everybody I in
my organization has probably been in at
least one of these things you want these
blobs that we see Twitter I mentioned
earlier that 330 million Marriott hotels
then you're in there right several times
probably but it's impactful diagrams
it's using them yes it's a really useful
tool to highlight the problem and I
think it's you said Troy you know is it
getting any better
no it's not in fact it's getting much
worse right so I got a correct John
something he said before Twitter didn't
lose their data they they made a lot of
backups of it
they're never gonna lose it now like if
they lose it legitimate job I'll restore
it for them yeah if anyone's to say this
this is from a site called informations
beautiful so if your google informations
beautiful data breaches and it's kind of
cool like that the bubbles are animate
and stuff like that
I doing some media stuff this morning at
the the other conference and though like
you know a data breach is getting worse
so yeah because there's lots of really
good reasons well they're getting worse
so number one there's like more data
than ever before like we've all seen
stats about how much information humans
create like every day well you know
we're just creating a lot more of it the
cloud two-hands the cloud has kind of
made the whole thing a lot worse as well
insofar as it's so easy now for anyone
just to stand up anything publicly
facing so there's so many data breaches
we've seen now which is like MongoDB
elasticsearch Amazon s3 publicly facing
without authentication because you know
it's easy right and logging turned off
so you don't even know who might have
got it yeah that's the other painful
thing let my so time out they only know
when it's like I tweet and I go hey does
anyone have a security contact anyone's
like this isn't gonna be good alright so
we're seeing all these data breaches in
IOT
so I writes one jeez a few weeks ago
with with Ken Munroe as well about
watches and and that was ID or - so
watches where you could track your
children because that sounds like a
great idea doesn't watches with GPS is
to track your children and you can make
calls to the API and just increment the
number and pull back another child or
reposition a child or set yourself as
the parent of the child so that you can
then call the child and the phone has
got like zero interaction that's fine
the watch and has has actually has
anyone got one of these you've got like
a kids tracking watch so no I don't want
to admit it now cuz you know but always
wonder like what's the point they're
getting the watch for the child because
if you're gonna kidnap the child
wouldn't you just take the watch off
them yeah and I appreciate this sounds
like I've thought about it way too much
and then you could do stuff like if
you're the parent you can call them and
it will automatically answer because
what if I imagine like what if someone's
kidnapped the child and have tied
up and put them in the back of a van and
I can't reach it to answer like how
fucked up is this we have to get to this
point there's far too much okay all
right so the kids watches the cloud
Patino got a cloud pit no good
so cloud pits are connected teddy bears
and the know what could go wrong so they
exposed all of their MongoDB data
publicly space and without a password
and then they had all the kids voice
recordings in a publicly facing Amazon
s3 bucket with obfuscated names but all
the metadata to the file locations was
in the Mongo and it's it's all publicly
facing and we like we didn't have
recordings of children before in that
fashion like I remember when I was a kid
if my parents wanted to record me I had
to like get up a tape player thing and
the microphone and all that and now it's
like a kids in their bed just talking to
the teddy bear and it's on the internet
so like all of these are just
compounding that the prevalence of which
data is collected and then making it
easier to expose and we're getting into
more places yeah great
ok so we talked earlier about the
consequences of these data breaches and
hacks going on and equifax are now the
chickens are coming home to roost with
Equifax and they've had a lot of value
wiped off their organization in yeah so
that this one was really interesting so
we saw two congressional reports and as
well as a report in the UK on Equifax we
saw the CEO of Equifax hauled in front
of Congress which doesn't really look to
be very fun at all and then the most
interesting thing happened suddenly the
bond rating company went after them and
lowered their credit score and this this
was really interesting because it's the
first time it's happened it's first time
a bond rating company has lured a credit
score as a result of their spend to
clean up the horrific breach because I
think they're now closing it on or have
exceeded a billion dollars one point
four billion point four billion in costs
associated this breach so finally the
real financial realities of data breach
were felt at now being charged as a
higher risk client to
or even more money to fix your shoddy
security so the other thing that's very
interesting is when you're a giant
company you try to sell your corporate
debt to other people and the amount of
money and interest that's paid is based
on your credit rating and now they're
risky so it's even more expensive for
them to sell their corporate debt this
will put a really interesting spin on
the cost of data breach if now we see
the credit markets reacting negatively
which will truly impact the share value
as you can see in the company right
there
so really interesting just we're going
to see the bond market wake up and go oh
you know what shoddy cybersecurity is I
shall now be punished yep agreed and the
last part is the first point you made
that Moody's downgraded them from Sables
and additive now that's the kind of
behavior you see happen to countries
okay that's so that's that's pretty bad
shit okay
yep I just want to add one thing so when
you take into account that as well as
the cost those cost of them this all
resulted from a simple fix was just
updating the patchy struts so if you
look at it from that point of view it
wasn't like something major that would
take months and months to fix this was
something really trivial in a sense not
always that trivial but in terms of
spent to fix it you're not talking
minions yeah leave it yeah agreed
okay so we'd like to pass the mic sir
mr. Scott helm and welcome into the
station
[Music]
[Applause]
Thank You Troy we'll be seeing you again
in a few minutes all right thank you
Scott now what we'd like to do here is
allow Scott to share some of his
insights around the encrypted web and
the ongoing battle that is encrypting
the web so he's got some fantastic
insights I'm sure he'd like to share
with us and Shawn's got some interesting
opinions he'd like to share back but
we'll make it clear we're all on the
same side so Scott yeah so the encrypted
web thing for me I think like the number
one point always comes right to me if we
were to redesign the web today and I say
like we could go back to square one and
start this again from the beginning
would we just have quite default
encryption would that be the the stance
would we be like oh hey you know we
could have the option of HTTP and HTTPS
and I honestly think that if we were to
rebuild it now and and reset to zero we
just start with an encrypted network
because that would be like the smart
choice so I think you know what we're
doing right now is essentially fixing
that kind of design flaw in the
beginning that the network wasn't secure
and that was largely based around the
trust we had so who's who can go back
and think of the web like way back in
the early days why into the late 90s no
test the room now haiti's okay that's
right
so like wait it was a small place right
like things were very different back
then it was a very trusted environment
we had like the internet phonebook where
you could go look up an IP address and
see people's like name and actual
physical address and who they were and
now I have toasters and scales in my
house with internet connections and
we've just gone like this full
revolution away from what the
environment originally was so for me
this is not you know where we're
deploying HTTPS so like protect people
to which it does but we're deploying it
to fix the original issue that we didn't
have encryption in the first place
there's no scenario that I can think of
where deploying encryption make
something worse nor is there a scenario
that I can think of where it won't
protect you against at least something
so we continue to remove barriers we've
got things like let's encrypt with free
SSL you can get certificates for no
financial cost now just the minimal
technical cost and the performance
just been completely washed away you
know maybe like late 90s early noughties
we could make the performance argument
but nowadays the cost is essentially
zero and actually most of the time we
can go faster on HTTPS than HTTP web
apps so for me nowadays this is just
kind of a given we need to like this set
the clock back to zero and say right you
know we just need to go and crimp the
whole network and then we can start
worrying about like all of these just
wide variety of attacks that we could
get rid of it but while we're trying to
do that right we have this kind of
argument okay and Shaun you've got a
real honest in geology so what is this
about
yeah this was about trust if I and wire
did they made it to the slides just
because they jumped yeah they quote
tweeted sweet I did with arguments and
tweeted it was about some company we had
their lesson crip certificate expired
and I quote we don't say ok automate all
things make sure that this doesn't
happen there's automation so you don't
have to this doesn't have to happen and
then if I hold it he'll start okay
Melvin let's say infographic about the
false economy of certificates and also
that the be8 British Airways Act was due
to certificates we all know that British
Airways Act was due to third party
compromise and Sean yeah literally I
tweeted a lot I mentioned some people
and Chung ripped all their arguments
yeah that a tear them apart so yeah so
one thing I think is really important
when you try to get security in that out
is give the route information try be as
honest as possible if you try to market
something join put out false information
and that's kind of what they were doing
there that there was a lot of things
that were saying will compete completely
inaccurate I mean the headline there is
Oh good example with BA it was a
JavaScript
absolutely nothing to do with the
certificates and that thing just really
browsed me up I mean that comes back to
our point earlier where we need to do
things morally and ethically so your
business on the things that it can do
rather than false information yeah yeah
if I may chime in the thing is my
opinion at least if you call out
companies for this kind of behavior I
think that's a good thing why because
other people who maybe don't understand
all technical details they will just
believe them one other important thing I
often see is that support employees from
companies get called out and even get
abused online and then that's that's not
cool honestly that's not cool you can
you can be not okay with something a
company does but always think what the
person was just doing the the Twitter or
the other support and that's that's
important to see don't be a dick okay
can I just like yeah reaffirm that point
so I go quite a bad reputation online
for being like MTC a anti certificate
authority because I'm constantly holding
things like this apart and and it's not
I'm not like anti CA or like Rage
Against the Machine or whatever people
say is this what you kind of picked up
on now it's that they're they're
spreading this information someone will
read that and believe it essentially
because it's like well why would this
organization why in this infographic
especially if it comes from a thought
leader so yeah it's this you know that's
the reason for me like this is why I
spend so much time on this especially in
the CIA ecosystem pulling these things
apart and just breaking it down to
technical points not because I don't
like them I mean I don't like them
because what they've done but not
because I have some inbuilt dislike so
you know it is about correcting these
facts okay if somebody mentioned
unhackable earlier so yeah and it speaks
to the point about making bold and in
substantiate claims about the security
posture of your product bit 508 out are
all products that were destroyed
rather than publicly by n chess partners
represented here by handing over there
so you wanna say a quick few words about
mr. shitty I've gotta make southern yeah
yeah don't claim shit's unhackable
basically as the that's the TLDR but
essentially fire was was endorsed by
that's kind of here it was it was said
to be a super-secure unhackable Bitcoin
wallet and within about well they will
agree about a day it was torn apart by
tyranny date so at under tyranny and
cyber Gibbons on the Twitter sphere at
Turkey apart and basically went through
all the claims that I had said like
always got limited viewing I can go and
I can see it's a dollar so that's the
bullshit and oh it's a super secure
device actually they took out a part it
was using media tech which is like a
really cheap Android device that was
bill chef is they said it wasn't a phone
it had SIM card slots hopefully not
telephone and would wash it and then on
to Pandora and some of you might have
seen I was on the BBC Drive my rate book
are let me not go fucking Google it's
great for one day the BBC took us to an
interview that we got to hack shit
basically and essentially Pandora were
claiming that they had an unhackable car
alarm because who wants to connect their
cars Internet and make sure that yeah
yeah I'm gonna speed things up just a
little bit so Beth I did repent a bit
and we like that the tweet was kinda
like yeah we fucked up right
don't use unhackable and then last week
this came back with the same sort claims
we've spent a lot of time there now on
their 37th CTO CEO somebody and they're
making the same bold statements again
just just don't do it so the good news
is that there are people out there doing
good things and there are organizations
that actually give a shit and they do
honest keeper our privacy enough a day
security on the web
so passwords do us with our problem and
they remain a problem and there will
remain a problem for a long time and we
see lots of novel alternatives passwords
but from a usability point of view and
I'm thinking about my mum who's 80 she's
not gonna get beyond a username and
password and for many people in a
similar sort context yes so we have to
espouse responsible password management
I think first and foremost we do have to
have the MFA discussion and we do have
to press organisations that can support
NFA to roll out as an optional tool for
users that are aware and familiar and
savvy enough to implement NFA for
themselves and we should encourage those
users to implement NFA ok so that's my
take on it any other good points just so
it doesn't help when the bigger firms
actually don't make whole job easier so
they put password length restrictions
for example Microsoft and even some of
the big ones that like Microsoft may
even produce patents when they're
actually generating a password for you
which is something not very good and
when it comes to the two-factor
authentication as well they're actually
when it comes to shared email boxes if
you've got shared email boxes in your
organization make sure that you can't
log in to office 365 because guess what
you need two factor authentication on
those also sometimes and the pickle
could I say so she doesn't read aren't
help in are they yeah I mean the hi by
the fact that well we've got sprawling
software architecture implementations
are huge and it makes it really
difficult but what makes life really
difficult for our organization is when
that date is looted to the tune millions
and millions of accounts well it could
be implemented so it's just one more
thing on passwords an mfa using things
like password manager and something I
really love to see more often as we're
both well within North
UTF tokens photo because not only do
they the help prevent against the the
password weak passwords and and that
kind of thing but they're also going to
help against things like fishing google
there's
for all the employees were UTF tokens
and to date I think this is for true not
one of their employees have suffered a
fishing success for fishing the tent so
these are some of the things that
organizations that are that do care are
doing so they're running things like
responsible disclosure policies and show
hands who's familiar with the security
dot txt standard okay it's quite a few
people so it's the deployment of a
simple text file onto your web
application that points somebody that
finds a book to how to tell you about it
in a responsible fashion it's a really
simple thing to do you'd have to write a
lot of policy around responsible
disclosure you just have to put
something out there that guides
somebody's to tell you about it and if
they do tell you about it then it's kind
of incumbent on you to fix it if they
cared enough to tell you and not to hack
you that I think you need to care enough
to so to turn that book around severity
based on severity
craphead and not withstanding leave me
alone but yeah be clear and make it make
it really easy for people to gain such
so we've got a slide dedicate to our
newest bear farmer miss Christy Morgan
and that's around looking at the
researchers yeah so and I recently did a
talk around this so it's just a very
light high-level couple of the points
there are some international standards
that are there to actually help
researchers but these international
standards out there like the ISAs
they're very much aimed at the companies
that they're written for they leave a
lot of room for what is a researcher
supposed to do when they come to a
company and things don't go right
one of the more reports rather than
standard that I found was sir in America
now those guys are really good
if you eat their report that they've
done around responsible exposure
coordinated disclosure you'll find that
they've actually written it for the
researchers because we need support and
advice and help be backed up there's
some changes in the law I know some of
the NCC guys we're trying to get a lot
of people talking about the CMA
Acton sin if that can be changed at all
when I've spoken to some other
researchers they've said that we have to
be quite careful because when they
change the law they don't always change
it in the best for our own benefit
always and yeah I mean appreciate if
someone's knocking on your door and tell
you you've got a problem no I like them
in and speak to them is far too often
I've got researchers coming to me now
and telling me basically these guys
being pricks to me all that just goes to
me and you know it's not not really fair
is it I just want to add something
because I've had this time and time
again where you afford something as
Chrissy said yeah they get radio silence
or no response sorry a response but then
a guy silenced all and companies need to
realize that researchers coming to them
with these findings is not a criticism
of that company
everyone has forced take it on as a good
thing you've not ended up in the media
for the wrong reasons
fix it work with the research give him a
thank you doesn't always have to be many
a simple thank-you goes a long way and
doing that will help strengthen your
relationship with that community and
make things better for your company one
less thing on that as well we've
actually seen companies recently the
hard breaches and deal with the
disclosure and then the fix so well that
they actually come out looking good like
the one that the one example that always
sticks in my mind was cloud fly with
cloud leads and you know that first CD
owned company if you aren't familiar you
can read the details but that that could
have been like a devastating issue but
they just dealt with it so well and
transparently and quickly you know
actually you know what okay I don't mind
using this company because I know when
things eventually do go wrong they're
gonna nail the fakes so yeah I think
this is really important sorry so I'll
just kind of say done this test on a few
other venues right if you've heard of
the Equifax breach majority of room he's
heard of a discuss breach are only a
handful yeah I just want to add one
thing about this because the saddest
thing in the world happened as a result
of irresponsible disclosure so I don't
know if you followed on Twitter the
sandbox escaper
saga other
I would say angry possibly mentally ill
person who dropped a series of zero days
that were easily weaponized into very
serious malware at the same time calling
out the FBI and the American government
I feel like that was a giant cry for
help and it was a very sad moment in
irresponsible disclosure because doing
that in that fashion to me is
essentially like trying to get the US
military to carry out your suicidal
wishes we have a precedent for this a
different dude by the name of trick who
is with team poison and started a little
something but they called the cyber
caliphate who took a selfie in front of
a recognizable landmark and was
vaporized by a Predator drone so even
though the paper said this is like the
first time so many blah blah know if you
do the history and you understand what
is at stake
you're responsible disclosure can lead
to physical violence at security
conventions we saw that one we saw and
possibly your untimely demise
just just to be clear the the physical
act at the conference that didn't the
passenger three responsible disclosure
yeah but then they were irresponsibly
hit in the face
I believe this all right we got we got
15 minutes left okay just them fix you
stuff all right so do pen testing and
test you processes test you people don't
be afraid to get into external auditing
done yeah don't be afraid to get
Authority and to come and talk to you
about what you need to do to be a better
organization a quick view people with
the tools and the knowledge and the
expertise to carry out repairs and do
the right things design and build stuff
securely to begin with so these guys do
the half you sell first stuff which is
something that Troy conceived many years
ago that got me an application security
in the first place and I've been quite
public about that you're running courses
right this year okay so Glasgow London
so see so
you wanna know more about that very
important you can't blame people if they
don't know that applies to whether
you're a software developer network up
designer network engineer or an operator
on a sweater again okay
let's just be clear about how Ivan pwned
everyone in the room is probably being
pwned how many in the room should gun
show of hands has proved it by using
this application yeah self validating
that I think it's fair enough so till
there are stickers around Troy managed
to throw them out at people better than
we threw our swag out at Leeds lost
somebody also now down a bit now I
thought you're here because you want to
get involved in the community you want
to talk to people though fighting the
same battles you're fighting have the
same anxiety the same aspirations that
you have you wouldn't be here if you
want to learn new stuff or you want to
interact with people that are on the
same side as you so that's really
important sharing information hmm a
breach isn't an if it's a when some of
you will work for organizations that
have already been breached but you don't
yet know about it okay so don't live
under the Troy might dot don't live
under the misapprehension that never
happened to us because it will and when
it does it'll feel a bit like that okay
so your organization but it's important
that you don't panic it's important that
you've prepared so it'll feel like that
in everyone's head and we do all fuck up
right regularly but there is a little
toolkit that you can you can use to help
you through so again it's about planning
it's about Incident Response so it sets
it there is a bit of an analogy around
the bereavement curve when you've had a
data breach and that's something that
Troy's written about spoken about don't
blame the other guy you probably failed
which allowed the attacker to succeed
that's more often than not the the
scenario that we that we find seek
support so again if you've got a cert in
your country in the UK we have the NCIC
very capable bunch of people that move
on
leaps and bounds in what they're
available to do what their capabilities
are in recent times go out through the
authorities so the ICO okay you need to
notify these guys anyway you've got a 72
hour window from discovering a breach to
notify the authority and if you are a
Tele telecommunications company or your
process data is that kind of wake you've
got 24 hours that's not a long time to
get your information in order and go out
to your wrist and your data protection
authority but when you do notify your
ICO or equivalent they can actually
parachute in some really clever people
to help you out to help you through it
to help you with the the PR the incident
management getting getting right
messages and for the public don't be a
talk talk okay so what happened to
figure it all out do your analysis do
your forensics speak to people don't
blame people yeah just engage the right
people and understand what the problem
was because if you understand you've
learned a lesson and you can introduce
it the right controls the right
technology the right processes right
where nasteria leave it happening yeah
and take it on the chin because it's
happened and move on and you'll feel
better
and you and your customers and you users
will feel better as well so we've got
nine minutes left I'm going to just
quickly blast it so North High drove
they were a great example of an
organization that really you messed up
but they did everything really
reasonable in that power to keep
messages going out to shareholders to
customers to people that cared they side
channels on Azure websites it was really
in the scheme of things it was a pretty
cool response they did a good job okay
who knows what one of these is hey
that's mine my next question was hands
up who's got one so there's a backstory
to that and well talking about stories
[Laughter]
we hear that the the cock cam has a
particularly good resolution and you
took a few pictures that you didn't
share so but yeah I mean cock I'm going
back to this they was for research
purposes of course
yeah they had had a problem and again
twittery actually Cameron Rowe got
involved but they handled it really well
in fact the diversity this company very
quickly and then online course oh well I
see those guys I'm gonna have to do this
again so sorry
alright so in talk very briefly about
sandbox escaper earlier on so we won't
revisit that example but what we need to
do is make it clear that you know you
don't just drop 0 days on the we're not
because you pissed at the world there
are different ways you can go about
getting you issues dealt invented that's
what this community tends to be all
about and in doing that if you do choose
to drop a 0 days then you are opening
yourself up to a lot of criticism and at
the Center for law enforcement to be on
the case and in tricks case vaporized by
Tennessee yeah that's kind of extreme
don't make false claims so if you think
your products in hackable just think it
somebody like Ken Monroe all the guys at
PT PR and you see any also works PGP
there are other firms other than PT p.m.
thank you for your sponsorship PTP
thanks for providing us an unlimited
supply of material for our talks you
just need to be clear the beer farmers
site is not unhackable think very long
and hard before considering daxing
people whose privacy and anonymity
they'd rather have preserved I'll leave
that hanging I heard that I heard that
it's a little bit of respect the end of
the day we're all here I like to think
the majority was a here because we care
so when people having a bad day or
saying things that are at odds with your
opinion then just come with that slack
and I'm guilty this as well so you know
you just need to be a little bit more
mindful of people and accept if you
punch a cat then all
Cave everybody daxing you for that yeah
they recorded it on video and then they
arrested the Doyle douchebag I was
awesome not punching the cat that wasn't
awesome no it was a bad thing it's
arresting the douchebag yeah I was a
training course recently where a
colleague of mine came out with
something he'd heard which was very
individual but you meet they're having a
personal battle or more that you know
nothing about and I thought that was
really an important point I took it was
the most valuable thing I took from the
training course because it's right don't
judge people and don't assume everyone's
having a good day so we've been the bear
farmers see you the bar but wait hang on
we did an encore at Leeds because all of
us were their original fibers so does
anybody recognize this golden cab
nope one or two babes Yeah right so we
were busy at the mapping last year
looking at all the shit that had been
happening on the Internet of the people
that were talking shit on the internet
some of the events on the Internet
and we came up with a retro wort and a
couple of people that receive those
awards here with us today and we're
gonna hand out those awards so we'll
quickly flick through because longer
five minutes and there are only two of
them here but Simon Smith the Australian
cybersecurity he invented cybersecurity
in Australia he's bigger than toys on
he's bigger than Troy hunt he's quiet
much more quiet than trying on Scott you
won the most cultivated hairdo award and
car and snow and I've got Barrett car
we've got a gauntlet at the golden
hairspray that cost me 12 pounds 15
boots in Manchester and Andy likes to
talk about his car what color is your
car right fucking blue right fucking
blue and but Scott without you he's got
a better car than you are keeping with
that and in keeping with gold am i yes
some map so I have bollocks
pelvis fluffy nice and I expect to see a
picture of those on Twitter in your car
on your rear view soon as I get home
okay so cowbell end of the year that's
for standing a water thing until
foreseeable times HotList app was the
bit fire clip so while it's still
available to buy on Black Bull pier the
hacker collective mistakenly known as
cyborg isn't a sniper Gibbons also
sometimes somehow called
over soft I did read out probably could
sell but it was a bunch of people and
attorney overstaffed tautology
yeah butch colleges in the room is right
there nice dogs really get some really
clever people who took took a bit prior
to task in demonstrate that you could
play doom on I try think that that was a
cool thing I saw doom up the info center
ox time sells a book called infoset
Rockstar but running is ecommerce site
over HTTP DCI was fixed it it is fixed
it even even redirects now right anyway
fingers in their ears Dave Winer we've
avoided the term anti-vaxxer and so I
just said it their fees on some bloke
but he's got very strong opposite
opinions around the encrypted web and
while you were doing that Cambridge on
let's go
bear in mind this was January so they
were still in the news Zuckerberg
Marriott because they really did lose a
lot of data my date and finally the
golden cowbell Award which was in our
opinion worth
issuing to Troy because in our opinion
not just because he's here because we
did say in January long before we got
him to come join us but we think it was
individually a lot you know mall and
many in terms of furthering the cause of
information security both for
individuals and for businesses so for
that Troy step up open this box and show
everybody what we bought for you watch
out front row
since we're out there honey takes a
broomstick you clean up well
yes it's outrageous okay bring it again
congratulations guys
thank you very much