it's an honour for us to be at the
activity this year this is a conference
where we always wish to come Gabriel and
myself we come from more Romania from
Bucharest so yeah thank you for for this
opportunity we're gonna tell you a story
about how we hacked a car today
essentially about how we hacked
Gabriel's car but before we start I just
want to ask you how many of you have
cars or drive cars oh no ok how many of
you have cars who are smart ok two hands
are those cars smarter than you do you
think probably right yeah that's the
world we live in nowadays so smart car
forensics and vehicle weaponization this
is the the title of our talk today but
before we start I just want to introduce
ourselves to everyone so this is Gabriel
Gabriel used to be a game developer he
joined the security industry a couple of
years ago and he became quite popular in
Romania for being the public
transportation hacker because Gabriel
two years ago he managed to create this
electronic ticket for our public
transportation system in Bucharest with
which he could have unlimited access to
the transport unlimited travel you know
like an unlimited card but not for your
phone it was actually a nice story for
the Romanian community because Gabriel
responsibly disclosed this vulnerability
to our local transportation authorities
they thanked him for that and they
actually fixed the bug you know quite
timely manner so we were actually
surprised by by their answer so yeah
that's Gabriel for myself I used to do a
lot of malware research and cyber
espionage research in the past ten years
so analyzing all sorts of apt at one
point I decided I want to take a break
and move over to the more you know
Internet of Things car hacking area but
what I can tell you about myself is I
really have have a real passion for
security like many people think that our
job looks like that like bored guys just
sitting in front of their computer but
in reality I'm sure all of you know the
adrenaline rush that you get when you
analyze
some new malware or exploit or
rediscover a new a new zero day so I
think it's a it's a really cool job and
the really cool industry we have in
community
just a quick shameless plug if you're on
Twitter
that's where do where we do everything
so please make sure to give us follow me
I'm not a fake account I promise yeah
Gabriel's account looks like a fake
account so we're trying to fix that but
yeah smart cars just to get us started a
little bit of an introduction to
autonomous vehicles like you know we
went from the back days when we would
use a horse and the carriage to where we
are right now where we have some sort of
automation in our cars that we use and
we're heading to a future in which our
cars would be fully automated and
they'll be able to drive themselves
while you're reading a newspaper which
is something you know ironic right but
yeah I think you know the automotive
industry divides this evolution into
several levels from 0 to 5 right now or
something in between level 2 or 3
depending how sophisticated your car is
so you still manually drive it but the
car has some autonomous functions like
smart city brake or you know keeping the
lane or following the car in front of
you especially for the for the newer
models but the main idea is that at one
point or another we're going to get to
level 5 where the cars need to drive
themselves fully and in order to get to
level 5 what the automotive industry is
doing is starting to embed more and more
smart devices in a computer more smart
devices in our cars like we used to say
that our cars nowadays are essentially
computers running on four wheels but in
reality a car doesn't have just one
computer a car has multiple computers
that are all interconnected and
essentially if you manage to get into
one of them sooner or later you could
totally palm the car so of course this
is why this area is very very
interesting
now yeah a lot of people have asked us
have asked us in the past why did you do
that so one of the main motivations
behind that was
Charlie Mira hack that happened on the
Jeep I don't know about 2014 if I
remember right three years ago four
years ago that was a big hack because
after Charlie Miller and and the other
guy John valasek hacked a Jeep
what Jeep had to do was to recall
100,000 cars if I remember correctly so
that was a huge hit for them as a
company like as an automotive company
having to recall thousands of cars
that's gonna impact your profits right
so they basically managed to put a lot
of pressure on the driving on the driver
behind the wheel so they turned out the
wipers they turned on the lights and at
some point they even managed to flood
the engine or something like that
and that's a big security failure right
there essentially what we realized is
that whenever a computer gets infected
we don't think of very bad consequences
I mean yeah sure maybe you have to
reinstall the operating system or do a
disinfection routine but nobody's life
can get hurt in most of the cases with a
computer infection but when we're
talking about cars we're talking about
human lives which are at stake and I
think that we need to understand the
problems that this industry have and
solve them before something bad happens
so let's get down to the details I
really really really like to tweak
whatever devices I get my hands on when
I got my Android I started flashing
custom runs roms on it when I got my car
I started trolling forums for ways to
change my background or to I don't know
just add the new app or something like
that so while digging around I found
some people who were actually able to
gain SSH access to their car and I said
yeah why not let's see what we can do
with that what we can what I can work
out so after digging around a little bit
more
I found the specs for the motherboard of
the infotainment system which is
basically just a free scale processor a
random Linux distribution it's got the
GPS soldered onboard so you can't
actually move it you can disable it it's
always there all right
receiving info from the satellites and
spoiler alert logging your position even
if you didn't buy the navigation package
so the car has GPS it's cheap just
cheaper for them to ship the results the
same one gig of ram a Wi-Fi module a
bluetooth module and revolutionary USB
debugging technique that we're gonna go
into and using that USB trick we decided
to get into the car put that SSH daemon
about of which we discovered a few
slides back and get in so we essentially
divided our project into two parts first
one first part was we try to do
forensics on the car's infotainment
system to see how much information an
attacker would be able to extract if you
would be able to get to have access to
that infotainment system and then the
second part the vehicle weaponization
part was when we tried to see what an
attacker could do with the system of the
car yeah so for getting in we use the
USB trick thingy remember the times when
you inserted a CD in your drive and the
author on that in would order a certain
script to be executed right that's the
same thing that's going on on my car
right now so whenever I insert a stick
it looks for a certain file and if it
finds it there then it's gonna execute
that bash script yeah and using that I
disabled iptables because your car has a
firewall why the hell not you know we
run sshd and we just got in we could
login with some dummy credentials that
we found that doubt from some service
guys and we started exploring the file
system and while digging around I found
some dot SQL files those are basically
just SQL dumps of a certain database and
when the file name is contacts that SQL
this is what you find those are the
number there are names of my contacts
and if you scroll a bit a little bit the
right you're gonna find the phone number
as well and looking around the file
system
I found another SQL file which contained
all of my call history and that's how I
found that I should be calling my
girlfriend way less often and my mom
yeah let's not forget about my mom
digging a lot a little bit more
I found this does it look familiar to
you can anybody guess what it is yeah
it's a list of addresses so my GPS was
logging my favorite point point 8th and
my correlating them with my favorite
point bees and making the list of routes
to help me just to type punching the
destination more easily while also
leaking a lot of data this is just a
strings dump that I did on that binary
blob so no encryption whatsoever the SQL
files again were not encrypted we also
found the voice profiles a lot of info
about how I was basically trying to use
the voice control in my car vehicle
status how aggressive I would be driving
and stuff like that how much I would be
braking and a directory listing for my
phone so that's basically means whenever
I would be plugging in my phone in my
USB port of my car then the car would
start crawling the filesystem and
indexing any media files it would find
even pictures so for example if I used
telegram then it would index that I had
a certain download folder in my telegram
folder and yeah whoever would have
access to it will also know what attacks
to use against my phone as well and it's
funny because I actually had this talk
at a local conference in Romania and
some guy who actually worked on
developing that came to me and basically
confirmed this
yeah the feeling that we got by doing
this part the smaller the forensics part
on this important system was that these
embedded systems in cars they are
developed by very good engineers but
there are engineers who never develop
something that is connected so for many
many years these embedded systems worked
very well as long as they were just
inside the dashboard of the car without
any kind of USB ports internet
connection Wi-Fi Bluetooth all of these
new things that we want and have so at
one point I'm sure what happened in
their company like their managers came
and said hey guys we need to connect
these infotainment systems so they just
took whatever they had and they just
added the connections and this is why we
are where we are and actually if you
talk to people in the automotive
industry you will realize that their
production process is you know very long
and very complex one but about security
they only started thinking in the past
two or three years some of the brands
some of the brands I think they only
start thinking about now they are
thinking about safety things such as
airbags abs stabilization systems but
they never try to test their cars you
know with with the community such as
such as this one so this brings me to
our second part of the presentation the
vehicle optimization part and
essentially we tried to see what kind of
attack scenario can we think of by just
using the tools that were present on the
on the on the car such as by living off
the land because that was a full UNIX
box equivalent to a computer that we
could use so what we did was by using
the same sshe access that we talked to
you before we essentially deployed a
script that would use cron for
persistence to keep itself alive and
this script would use a binary that the
developers left on the car to search for
open wi-fi's on the network on on the
premises we would also use the GPS
module to constantly plot coordinates
where the car is and of course whenever
we could find an open Wi-Fi and connect
we would connect to our own server and
upload these this this data essentially
achieving a situation which you know the
car is worth driving by itself driver is
just driving around town and and the car
is plotting all of the Wi-Fi networks
there and all of this is happening just
by inserting a USB stick inside the cars
USB port that's it nothing else nothing
more so yeah so we have to explain this
to our managers and it's much easier to
draw a picture it's worth 1000 words so
this is the area where Gabriel lives and
those are like the Wi-Fi networks that
were plotted by the car itself now we
wanted to do a live demo of this to show
you exactly how it works but we talked
with the organizers of activity and they
told us it would be a little bit
difficult to bring a car on the stage so
yeah what we did was we recorded a video
which I hope works yeah we don't need
sound it's just some engine sound but
essentially what we did this is the
dashboard of the car and we made the car
system show up a pop up every time
there's a new Wi-Fi network in the area
that the car can connect to by the way
this pop-up is made also by a binary
that was left there by the developers
the binary is totally not used by the
car so it's there for like development
purposes but still it was there actually
this was the feeling that we got that
the the car's infotainment system was a
was not a production-ready system it was
a development or staging system where
they were hoping everything would be ok
so sorry about the quality of the video
our roads in Romania are not the
smoothest but yeah this is our
successful demo so thank you very much
I started presenting this kind of stuff
to the media and starting raising
awareness and at one point one of the
reporters asked me can you just put a
pop-up in there that shows that you've
got around somewhere for your car and I
were like oh man that's a really great
idea
when you spend 20,000 euros on a car
then actually paying 500 euros just to
make it work again it's not that much of
a bad deal you know for a for your
computer at home you just wipe
everything and that's that but for your
car well it's like a barque bargain you
know you can even increase that sound to
about 5,000 euros you know so these are
the kind of threats that were gonna you
expect to see more and more when it
comes to cars especially when you think
that you've had blue Bourne the
Bluetooth vulnerability in the last year
that actually affected a lot of devices
and funnily enough the car is not
affected because the Bluetooth library
is so old that it doesn't have the bug
yeah and I started digging around a
little bit more I considered I don't
know breaking the can or making the car
break or stop or do some kind of funny
stuff but there is another approach that
people have been missing in the last
year's why attack from the inside when
you can just attack from the outside
after world the can bus just pushes the
data that it receives from the sensors
to your car if you find a way to break
those sensors and this is the exact same
problems that some people are having
right now on a forum that's dedicated to
battle robots basically so Robotics
Challenge and somebody is trying to use
an ultrasonic jammer in order to jam the
ultrasonic signals from the distance
sensors of his enemy robot and people
what people kept discussing that and it
seems like this is actually doable it
can definitely be done there is no issue
with that and you can make your car stop
because of something called city brake
smart assist so whenever my car would
find something in front of it it would
just break and if you don't allow you to
move any further until you have cleared
the obstacle in front of you and you can
actually jam those
transonic sensors or the lidar for
examine this Pacific example with really
cheap gear and make the car stop using
its tracks and just to add you know
insecurity in this community wheel is
when I will receive a new technology
always think of ways to break it or ways
to to trick it and I would like to see
this attitude more and more in the
engineers classic engineers area or
classic software development area
because what's happening right now with
the cars is we're putting so many
sensors in them but nobody's tricky is
thinking of how easily those sensors can
be manipulated everybody's testing the
sensors only in real-world conditions
without thinking of the fact that that
those real-world conditions could be
simulated by an attacker to achieve a
scenario in which the car stops when it
shouldn't so what happens when you
actually have to buy really expensive
gear just to be able to do that because
that's what those Chinese hackers did
they bought like 50,000 no five hundred
thousand dollars worth of equipment
which is mostly a signal generator to
generate the radar reflection and the
mixer in order to up it up to 60
gigahertz or something like that and
yeah it's really expensive to do it
right now
they did it with stealth why they had a
lot of gear maybe this is available to a
nation-state espionage campaign or
something like that but this is exactly
what they said about SDR in the past
this in order to do the same stuff that
you do is a blade RF or whistle hack RF
you had to have a whole cabinet of
devices and interconnect them in order
to get final yet a to decode something
like a GSM signal or anything like that
but it's getting cheaper and cheaper and
we're gonna see what the SDR was for for
radio waves we're gonna see the same for
radar or for even other kind of pair of
shenanigans and our message here is that
you know car hacking is not necessarily
something very complicated and it's not
something expensive if you want to get
yourself into that it's actually a nice
hobby of course the risk is you can
break the car actually when we did our
experiment last year we managed to break
Gabriel's infotainment system but
luckily the car was still in warranty so
we just went to back to the dealership
and told them like no the lightning
struck the car they actually believed
that so yeah I guess we were lucky so
there are some risks but you know
getting a blade RF is a couple of
hundred dollars and you'd be surprised
of how many things the automotive
industry is overlooking right now if you
if you look at the cars around you so
yeah if you want to start car hacking I
encourage you to do that get in touch
with us we'd love to share you know our
opinions and our experience and so just
to wrap this up a couple of conclusions
that we took and wanted to share with
you after this project our main worry
here is that the automotive industry is
not really thinking about the privacy of
the drivers of course when you're the
only driver of your car maybe you don't
care that all of your personal data is
left persistently and unencrypted on the
car's infotainment system but with
things such as car sharing programs or
corporate car fleets that are being
shared by the employees inside inside
the company with these things becoming
more and more popular especially in
North America and in Europe I think that
we really need to think more about our
privacy because how many of us actually
think that when we connect our phone
with Bluetooth to a rented car just to
listen to our favorite song songs then
all of our data is being extracted from
the phone saved in the car and left
there for the next driver to access it
so I think that the automotive industry
should address this these issues now of
course this is something not new for us
in the security world we always know
that whenever there's a new technology
coming up new ways in which that
technology can be attacked or in which
that technology can be abused are also
showing up the thing is we want to
evolve and we want to evolve in a you
know secure way and actually while
discussing this project with some people
we got this idea like
the automotive industry has a very good
history and track record when it comes
to physical safety so whenever you buy a
car it comes pre equipped with all the
best safety measures like it runs pre
equipped with ABS with airbags with seat
belts you start like with a computer
when you buy your computer and then you
go and buy an anti-virus and the
firewall and install it the comm just
the car just comes with everything pre
equipped and the industry actually has a
very good way of regulating itself you
know we have crash tests that can test
the the the safety of the cars so why
wouldn't we have cyber crash tests for
for cars why wouldn't we evaluate as an
industry in a very transparent and open
way how secure are different info
systems I mean I would love to take that
factor into account when decided what
new car to buy and lastly before we end
I just want to brag a little but it's a
story that I think I think you need to
know we got some pretty good media
coverage from this project so first
there were like security publications
that wrote about our hack places such as
motherboard or decipher or the register
which are really good new sources for
the InfoSec community but you know we
realize that inside information security
we're all living in a bubble because we
all agree with each other that
everything can be hacked and that
everything is vulnerable and whenever
there's a new vulnerability showing up
and the new hack showing up we
congratulate each other and we pat pat
ourselves on the back but this this
knowledge and these messages rarely
leave our echo chamber rarely leave our
bubble so this is why we were quite
happy when Forbes decided to do a piece
about our hack because Forks have some
more
you know mainstream audience so we
trying to break the security bubble and
then we became even more happier when
the some car magazines such as car bars
and drive mag I decided to interview
with us and write about this hack
because I think that there's a big you
know division between the security
industry and the automotive industry and
we like to talk about these things at
security conferences
but I'm not sure how many automotive
engineers or people are here is there
anyone who works with cars in this room
okay I think I see two or three hands so
yeah I think we should do presentations
like this and projects like these also
in places where it's not just about
security like for example at car auto
shows or trade shows for for the
automotive industry and just generally
try to break out of our security bubble
because that's where these messages need
to go to the to the whole world and to
the whole industry
so with this being said I'd like to
thank you very much for paying attention
and if there's any questions so this is
where we're here for yes or no thank you
[Applause]