hello activity thanks for having me this
is my first activity and first visit to
Budapest in my talk I will show you how
to hunt for security vulnerabilities in
web application built with adobe
experience manager
it's a popular software for making shiny
websites used by high-profile companies
web applications built with adobe
experience manager is a long phrase so I
will use a web apps term instead some
words about myself my name is Mihai you
I came from Russia
I do bug hunting on bug route and hucko
on platforms on back road I'm in top 20
I do security research and was
acknowledged by many well-known
companies sometimes I present results of
my research on different security
conferences also I have a full-time job
I worked for Ingram Micro cloud as
application security engineer but just
before the conference I decided to join
Kronus company as senior security
researcher so why this talk as I've
mentioned adobe experience manager is
quite popular choice among high-profile
companies here you can see some
well-known companies that have public
bug bounty programs or vulnerability
disclosure programs and that use adobe
experience manager
I used service called what runs and that
service gave me a list of about 10,000
domains that have adobe experience
manager running on them for about six
thousand domains main site was running
adobe experience manager on URL HTTP the
main name or HTTP 3 w dot the main name
you can see here that I am is quite
complex it has many layers in the
architecture and the attacks face is
quite big the rot 26 known CVS exist
our I want to especially outline three
Apache projects or open source projects
that form a core of am the Apache helix
Apaches link and Apache org GCR Apache
Felix is used to manage so-called osj
bundles all functionality in a is packed
inside OSGi Apache Felix gives us API to
manage content repository and also gives
the ability to expose so let's from OSGi
Apache objects are is a Content
repository everything in a VM is stored
as properties for some nodes in reserve
and all not a shape tree structure
starting from GC our root node this year
I discovered new exploitation techniques
and security vulnerabilities in a.m. and
it's perfect time to share my findings
here I want to give special thanks to
Jason Mayer who helped me with am
license and also shared some nice
thoughts with me I want to mention some
previous work on this topic in 2015 I
found authenticated remote code
execution in
web application during I participated in
a bug bounty program same year I made a
talk on pitch this conference in Moscow
that describes techniques I used in 2016
Peter Adkins from England made a very
nice blog post about getting our see on
signed out live comb web application
that belongs to Microsoft not long ago
a renowned bug hunter from Sweden France
rosin on Safety conference give a talk
about his experience with hacking AM web
apps I highly recommend looking into his
presentation and finally Jonathan Bowman
wrote a very nice blog post explaining
how he found an XSS on Philips dot and
outside just a side note all mentioned
vulnerabilities in my talk were
responsibly reported to resource owners
or Adobe product security incident
response team and I hope they're fixed
now first I want to show you how a.m. is
commonly deployed in practice what is a
dispatcher
why is dispatch is so important for
security of a.m. are web applications
and more vital question how can we
bypass a.m. dispatcher in common a.m.
deployment scenarios there are three
main components also instance publish
instance and the dispatcher also
instance is placed deep inside bacnet
it's not visible from the internet all
content is published on also instance
and through replication mechanisms is
propagated to to publish instances and
the user communicates who is
publish instance through AM dispatcher
but there can be additional components
that sit between user and AM dispatcher
for example of application firewalls or
Citians like Akamai or CloudFlare em
could be deployed on-premise or in the
in the cloud like AWS physically AM
dispatcher is a module for web server
Apache o is one of the purposes of AM
dispatcher is providing health security
frontier it filters out unwanted
requests that don't fit security policy
and prevent them from reaching publish
instance in theory is stated in the
official Adobe documentation AM dispatch
is an extra layer Inlet am security
however we see in practice that it's
only one layer the truth is that a.m.
admins rely on M dispatcher heavily and
no one can figure publish instance
securely and install updates timely and
it's very good for for bug hunter
bypassing AM dispatch fails to talk to
those insecure components on publish
instance and this way upon the whole
application in my arsenal I have four
methods to bypass AM dispatcher
the first one is CV from 2016 it was
disclosed to the public in the blog post
made by Peter Adkins it still works
quite well because as I have said admins
are too lazy to install security updates
and the second one was discovered by me
this year but just before
conference Adobe reached me and asked
not to disclose details because the fix
is not ready yet
so I'm sorry for that but of course I
will disclose all technical details
later
the next method multiple slashes works
sometimes against Viet dysplasia
policies and final method set aside
request forgery is a universal weapon
for dispatch a bypass let's discuss how
to bypass the dispatcher with CV here
you can see minimal dispatcher policies
that was recommended by Adobe before CV
exists
this policy is too restrictive usually
you extend it by adding additional rules
that allow custom requests policy
contains rules that are applied
sequentially to the request and what's
important to know that the last rule
that matches the request is applied rule
can be of type deny or allow if none of
the rules match the request default deny
rule is applied and blocks the whole
request here we can see is the remaining
rules of the policy and so here is a
bypass it's stupid this simple I should
say if we try to access query builder
JSON servlet on road beam query builder
doe Jason our request will be blocked by
the dispatcher but if we add slash a dot
CSS or slash a dot HTML to the end of
the URL we can access a query builder a
Jason servlet without problems and what
the hell let's try to analyze the logic
of the dispatcher when we are accessing
Road in query builder
we are blocked by rule zero zero nine
zero it's as was true that matches our
quest and it blocks all incoming
requests we're URL ends with a dot jason
when we add slash a dot CSS to the end
of the URL last rule that matches our
request is zero zero forty one that has
a low type this is how it works
of course adobe fixed this issue and
issued new minimal dispatcher policy now
row zero zero forty one that should
allow access to CSS or JS files is
changed now the dispatcher looks for the
real extension in the URL and not for
the last singles this makes sense of
course morals of the new policy and the
last ones now if we are trying to access
wrote bean query builder da jason all
been query builder da jason a CSS the
request is blocked because now this
patch looks for the real extension
however found a way to bypass the fix
but i can disclose details now sorry in
some cases we can bypass weirdly
configured dispatcher by aging multiple
flashes so if access to slash it's you
know jason is blocked we can try three
slashes at cidade jason and sometimes it
works magically and set aside request
forgery in some component on publish
instance allows to completely bypass the
dispatcher and later i'll show you some
examples of Seraphin our ability side
skull this year that are suitable for
dispatcher bypass so to wrap up
I am dispatcher usually is the
the security layer and there is a
message to bypass it and access
vulnerable components on publish server
now let's move on and discuss how we can
quickly separate smelly am web apps from
secured ones on the first step we can
try to access roads presented on the
slide if we get JSON in a response that
contains properties or values that have
such words as GCR or slink
ocq we are facing with a web app for
example several Twitter subdomains are
run in adobe experience manager when we
access slash dot JSON we see a JSON
response with properties like GC are
created by when we access slash dot X
the JSON we suggest in the response that
contains values like GC our content or
CQ page and there's a clear indication
of running am value plication
additionally we can try to access some
servlets that are usually left exposed
for example we can try to access like in
state a servlet all background tests
solid so you can see that when like in
state a servlet is exposed
we observe authenticated equals false a
string and when background test servlet
is exposed it runs ten cycles of testing
routine and outputs the results
everything in a.m. is stored in the
content repository that represents a
tree structure and that's important
and you feel like dumpster diver when
you are trying to find some
we'll detailed of this huge and messy
content repository during happen testing
what gyms can you find any sorts of
secrets like passwords for databases or
online services encryption keys secret
tokens production configuration private
information of users like emails
telephone numbers home addresses etc and
also valid logins for a.m. users why
does this happen because a.m. admins
rely on a.m. dispatcher heavily and
don't configure access controls for
content repository I've counted four
built-in a.m. Soviets that are suitable
for retrieving content from this er yeah
default gets all it a query builder
Jason and Fitz outlets and gql search
servlet the first one is the default get
servlet it allows to get user not with
its properties for your convenience it
supports various selectors and formats
of data for example I select tidy
allowed to get formatted output select
infinity allows to get in one request
properties of the current dresser not
and all its children instead of infinity
we can use some numeric value from minus
one to infinity this value determines
the the depth minus one is equivalent to
infinity format rest allows to retrieve
files that are normally stored inside GC
our data property of the share content
no
for example when we are accessing wrote
slash dot I did dot thriller Jason we
are getting formatted Jason that
contains no notes or and they're Pro
purchased starting from the root note
with depth three usually I use following
approach for grabbing data on the first
step I get information about direct
children of of the root node and but in
some cases listing for the cell root is
prohibited if so I try to guess well
it's not names common names are content
Etsy war and whom on the second step I
start to traverse GCR and dump not
properties when that selector is a lot
we can get the whole subtree of GTR and
one get request that's very convenient
some common places to look into children
not of it see usually contain various
secrets like database connection string
with passwords encryption keys and so on
children not of apps system config and
apps something config usually contain
passwords children notes of war may
contain private information as it
belongs to users and children knots of
whom
can contain contain profiles for AM
users with hash pad passwords and
normally properties like GG are created
by Jessie our last modified by CQ last
modified by of any not contain login
names for AM uses here is the real case
example from bug bounty program it was
possible to pull database connection
string and database password without any
authentication this information was
taught in child nodes of HC reducted EPS
config node i bypass TM dispatcher by
just painting slash a dot HTML to the
URL and this submission was rated as
critical the second and third servlets
that are suitable for the CR exploration
are query builder JSON servlet and query
builder feed servlet they support
various predicates for searching that's
very convenient query builder Jason
servlet returns information about DS
arnott and it's all its properties
however query builder fit so late
returns information only about not
a--not properties but now might we can
extract properties using blind binary
search here you can see how to access
query builder jason servlet and query
builder hit solid on this white I
collected searches that often rescue me
and give me quickly security box in
private bug bounty program I a search
through GC are using a query builder
feed so late and found a.m. production
configuration in a zip archive
full of passwords submission was rated
as critical
in another bug bounty program I was able
to get access to users profiles through
query builder JSON servlet and to grab
Cemil tokens and hashed passwords
example from a Twitter bug bounty by
searching with query builder Jason
servlet I found not that was writable by
anonymous user and additionally post
requests allowed so I was able to upload
this video file with JavaScript and have
persistent XSS on Twitter subdomain that
by bypassed Twitter security content
security policy with search shown on the
slide you can get login names for AM
users having valid logins you can try to
brute-force credentials and those extend
your access to am further I'll show you
how to brute passwords in a right way
when access to default gets so it is
prohibited but query builder adjacent
servlet is not locked you can use query
builder JSON servlet in default get
Soviet mod using presented search
strings gql is a simple full-text query
language Shakeel search soviet allows
allows to search through GCR using this
language this soviet returns only not
without proper chests as it was with
query builder json servlet however again
we can retrieve properties using a blind
binary search here you can see how to
access a gql
search solid and one example of the
search
query that query allows us to retrieve
names of child not of its you note now
let's look how we can access how we can
get access to AMS some user for getting
valid usernames we can use default get
servlet or query builder Jason servlet
we have already discussed it how to do
it and additionally a M has default uses
with name's Edmund and also user admin
is the king of a.m. he has full access
to everything and default password is
admin and it's really mystery for me but
I'm facing with many applications I
built with a that have default admin
credentials also user has desire right
privilege for not content and has
default password also and the good news
everyone
am supports basic authorization without
any brute force protection that's insane
I think like in status Soviet is a
convenient way to brute force
credentials here you can see that when
credentials are wrong so it returns your
string of chiquita equals false
and it returns string authenticated
equals true and credentials are valid
and we can see how to access this Soviet
here is the example from adobe
vulnerability disclosure program I found
a am on subdomain of adobe.com
with default admin credentials and I was
able to access system console from there
I could install a backdoor OSGi bundle
and gain remote code execution another
example is a LinkedIn owner ability
disclosure program I agree
to user names using default get Soviet
and then try to brute host passports
with like login status so late for my
like for my luck I was able to find
several uses with easily guessable
passwords and I finally access sir XD
console as internal LinkedIn user now
I'll show you some Universal ways to get
our see in a double experience manager
now I know to Universal ways to get our
see the first one is by uploading
backdoor OSGi bundle the second one is
by uploading backdoor GSP script to EPS
node to upload or J bundle you have to
be admin and have access to wrote system
console bundle bundles I have made
backdoor J prefer of concept for am of
version 6 point 2 4 the second way you
should have write access for apps not
and the ability to create new content
with slimport servlet my osj but door
appeal she works for a in version 6
point 2 or in the newer version versions
if you need back vector bundle for older
version you can generate skeleton
project using shown maven commands and
then back port back backdoor solid
across from my project to the newly
created skeleton or J bundle has begged
off servlet that execute arbitrary shell
commands are passed in CMD parameter
servlet is exposed unrolled
beam backdoor dot HTML let's see a quick
demo so we are cloning repository with
OSGi backdoor
it has jar file with osj bundle and we
are trying to upload and install it
so we see that bundle is installed and
now we can run arbitrary shell commands
by navigating to to URL it works another
way to get our C is to upload a gist B
script you should take following steps
you should create note with name RC not
and the properties link resource type
with value RC type then you should
create note ab c type and upload HTML
DOJ's P script to that note finally you
are navigate to wrote RC naught dot HTML
and have the ability to execute
arbitrary shell commands
I created a shell script that automate
describe steps let's ease demo
we are running script and pass three
parameters to it the first parameter is
URL of am web application the second one
is username and the cert is user
password it gives us URL and now if we
open this URL we can execute arbitrary
shell commands now I will present you
technical details for Sarah site request
forgery vulnerabilities I found this
year the first one is a serif in
reporting services proxy servlet adobea
sciencv ID for it
it worked for all modern a.m. versions
through this as serif you can send get
request to arbitrary URL and what's
notable that a serif allows you to see
the full response a serif can be used to
lick secrets from internal network
services like metadata service in AWS
you can also use this a syrup to bypass
AM dispatcher and Yuko you can always
exploit Sara phrase as reflected XSS and
you don't need to worry about excess
filters in browsers this is how you can
access vulnerable reporting services
proxy servlet now let's see some
examples in create bug bounty I am was
deployed in AWS I was able to leak
Amaral credentials using a seraph in a
reporting services proxy servlet another
example with a seraph i was able to
bypass a.m. dispatcher and access
secrets from child nodes of it see not
direct access to it see was forbidden
but why a seraph I was able to access
publish instance on
local host and port for five all three
and exfiltrate secrets from HCM in Adobe
VDP I wasn't able to leak anything
sensitive with the Seraph I just
exploded reflected XSS here it worked
perfectly in Chrome by passing from XSS
filter another vulnerability reported by
me is a serif in Salesforce secrets of
lat
Adobe assign CID for it
this is serif allows to make post
requests to arbitrary URL and see the
full response it allows to link
information from AWS from metadata
metadata service in AWS because metadata
service doesn't differentiate and
differentiate between get and post
requests and of course we can explore it
as Sara has reflected XSS which is how
we can access vulnerable our Salesforce
a secret servlet and real some real
examples I found subdomain on adobe.com
with am deployed in AWS this am had
vulnerable salesforce secrets outlet and
i was able to lick em role credentials
this is how we exploit this is Seraph as
reflected XSS I also found the Seraph
insight catalyst servlet that allow us
to send post requests blindly to the
arbitrary URL but adobe decided not
assigned GID for this vulnerability
what's interesting about this sheriff
that you can inject arbitrary headers in
the request through your life injection
and you can even send get output or
delete requests via HTTP marbling
technique I'll show you later how to
escalate this as serif
remote code execution here is how it
works
we sent get request parameter data
center is vulnerable to a seraph in
parameter username year-11 direction we
can specify additional HTTP headers with
how you can access vulnerable side
catalyst servlet this is another serif
that is similar to a seraph inside
catalyst soviet again add up decided not
to assign cid for it here's how it works
we send post request a parameter
analytics notes over is vulnerable to a
seraph this how you access vulnerable
also provisioning servlet and it's
possible in some cases to escalate
described blind as serifs to rc4 am 6.2
running on apache GT i was able to get a
remote code execution it works if
accumulative fix pack seven is not
installed on am if p 7 was released in
mid of 2017 in a yum there is a tongue
topology topology is used for
replication and topology connect a
servlet in default installation is
accessible on localhost only if we can
send put request to topology connector
we can join the topology of course why a
seraph we can do it and when we reached
apology connect a servlet on publish
instance we joined the topology and
reverse replication exit II edge agent
is created automatically and reverse
replication engine tries to replicate
notes from our malicious a
so our our to publish instance this way
we can upload back doe JSP script to EPS
node from malicious a.m. so on publish
instance and gain remote code execution
let's see how it works first I'm trying
to check that not his name RC not
doesn't exist it doesn't exist we are
observing access lock on publish
instance and now we navigate to this
long URL in the browser
in excess log we see that put request
was made to topology connector now we
launched our malicious a instance and
waiting for the connection from our
publish instance we see the connection
and now we should see that not with name
RC not was created by replication
service now we can navigate to the URL
and execute arbitrary shell commands
yeah it works
let's explore briefly some possibilities
for accessible abilities in am
applications there are many ways to get
XSS if you have rights to create you
notes you can create new user not and
upload this Vigi file here to get an XSS
as I've previously demonstrated hold to
beat a bug bounty if you have no rights
to create you notes but have an ability
to create new properties for some not
you can create new property with HTML
text and site there are several
exercises in as we as we have files
reported by Franz Rosen you can find
technical details in his presentation we
see M debug field was previously
vulnerable to XSS and additionally
plenty of built-in servlets of I am
returns return an escaped HTML from use
the input in JSON response and sometimes
it can result an XSS first two variants
gives you persistent XSS the rest
reflected XSS but we will look more
precisely at the elastic success variant
I found suggestion handler servlet it
reflects prayer input parameter in this
new response without escaping it's not a
vulnerability on its own however often
a.m. is configured in such way that
content type of the response is
determined by file extension and the URL
so by aging slash at a dot html' to the
URL we can get reflected diseases so it
was a floodgate XSS submission for
private bug bounty program denial of
service attacks are very funny for a em
web applications because in practice
it's very easy to cause gos using only
several requests in a row there are
plenty of ways for that you can see in
the example that in one request we
forced a.m. to return same 700 megabytes
JSON and formatted it took about six
minutes from am other tricks for the
sake of completeness I used them couple
years ago they will rarely work today
but who knows
external job post Soviet was vulnerable
to untrusted enjoyed civilization Bach
in all TM versions it takes file
parameter and passes it to object input
stream read object call let's see how it
works we generate gos payload with two
called
OS gos and sent generated payload to
external job possibility in file
parameter we see the error in the
response that tells us that there is a
problem with Java heap failure to
allocate required memory another thing
is XML external entity a vulnerability
in web dolphin limitation I discovered
in 2015 you can quickly spot if a web
doc is enabled by said ascending options
request or making get requests to the
roads Eric's
repository and I created a hacker tool
set to automate security testing of a
Bub's toolset includes several scripts
it will be published on github shortly
after the conference as mean to a hacker
implements many checks and tries to
bypass AM dispatcher and the sole folks
thanks for coming
[Applause]