I'm Roberta Norman I'm a security
researcher at fourth point working in
the a special investigation team and I
would like to share one of the recent
investigations and about the title so
the four key theory when you hear the
four key as a kind of a verb what is the
main Association you have so usually
it's television with our high definition
because that's something from the past
couple of years there is eight capes
Tier four K something good but that's
just one thing the second one is good
old cash because you are usually saying
that it's it's four thousand or like 4k
and the third one is something kind of a
retro thing called a 4k demo so I'm not
sure how old you are here but this is
something which goes back to probably
their 80s or the 90s and it was
representing a very short piece of code
doing very fancy graphics on computers
and thankfully it is still not extinct
but a little bit more on that later
so couple of questions before we we
proceed how many of you can actually
understand assembly code hands up don't
be shy okay that's reasonable
so how many you are actually still
writing assembly code that's more tricky
hands up because I know that you are
might be doing still share codes right
okay that was that was the ticket part
so it will be likely a bit of
higher-level but I was trying to also
include some assembly level stuff mainly
for for you guys who are still coding
okay and how is it all connecting to the
talk so is it a present or the past as
you can see that's a POS terminal and
it's a kind of a bad play with the words
but let's see so there was a you depose
discovery that was by us at first point
early this year that was basically a new
piece of Bo a smaller family wasn't
really
during or anything what we haven't seen
before the novelty was or one kind of
Novell feature that it was using DNS for
data extraction compared to other
methods DNS and data extraction over DNS
is not really that new but there weren't
many POS families utilizing it before
and we only had a couple I can handful
of samples of that then there was the
pinkeye story it was almost at the same
time it was by security researchers they
were finding a small piece of POS
malware according to them it was between
four and six kilobytes in size and the
interesting bit there was that it was
using kind of clearing houses for
storing the all the stolen credit card
data and also they were claiming that it
was using that the very famous double
XOR encryption as much as we can
consider that of our own encryption and
the pinkeye study goes back to a little
bit of the past so when we were reading
about the story and that is a small
piece and it's a POS there were kind of
small bells ringing so it's it's very
much looking like there is the old tiny
post / Abaddon posts more other
resurfacing or might be a new iteration
of that or just kind of ideas were lost
for that or whatever but that was very
very similar and last but not least its
Joker's - some of you might know the
name so it's a kind of famous site for
selling and trading credit card data and
the owner or maybe there are multiple
owners they are kind of pure product of
their work and just recently they were
claiming that they were hacking into
merchants directly and they are
responsible for a couple of recent
breaches Brian Krebs was having a very
nice summary on them and and also kind
of a fake Joker's - side so that
is going to kind of add up at the end
about the investigation so we were
basically just starting to collect
samples we were not really expecting to
have too many because from the previous
experience with Judy Post and other POS
mother it was usually just a handful of
samples what someone can gather we
started to collect those samples very
early this year and as of today we have
more than 1500 unique samples of course
they are falling down into a couple of
different categories but when unique it
is of course it means that it has unique
and the sample size is whirring between
two and seven kilobytes but it's as the
title was saying it's mostly about four
kilobytes and the major rate of them
seemed to be downloaders the real
payloads few and far in between and
that's kind just to play with the
numbers I can say that the real payloads
were probably less than 40 samples total
so that was a little bit suggesting that
it might be a staged approach first
about a couple of obfuscation techniques
I'm not going to tell kind of which part
or which module had what techniques I
was more like combining all the
techniques is collecting them here so
these might or might not be all used by
the different samples the cool the kind
of cool push Office keishon is a very
simplistic one I will have a nicer
example for that and and explaining
their fake API calls nothing new there
kind of having fake code fake API names
the code is not being executed the
execution is jumping over all those fake
API calls janky instructions as having
the usual knobs LEDs or any other fake
extraction mask again it's jumping the
execution is jumping over from down in
port by hash once again kind of an on on
old features or old technique
changing equal resources that's very
easily done the same about randomizing
the the vs version info there are no
real on T debug or on T virtual machine
or sandbox tricks probably that was not
needed there is almost always very
simple encryption layer on top of that
the compiled executables and it seems to
be applied after computation I will
explain later why and in a couple of
cases there is some AV process names in
the blacklist so there is the extensive
black and white listing by these modules
the AV names are there not to make
execution stop but basically just to
prevent those protests cease to be
opened and there is an example of the
first kind of cold
push off discussion I know that it might
be challenging to see it's actually if
you are running or jumping the gun and
and loading the sample into idea Pro
this is what you get that's kind of your
entry point but you can see on the
screen there is a a load library there
is a gatos address and there is a create
new tags but basically you cannot really
see any any parameters being passed or
anything which is sensible so that's the
case when you are a little bit fast and
you are using ID by default for
everything if you go back to a very nice
old-fashioned hex editor that's the same
code the ones who are reading writing
assembly can see that that's actually a
e8 that's a call that's the same entry
point here you can see that there is the
anti DLL there is there are just
privileges API and there is a nice kind
of odd name for a blue tags on the last
line so that's just an example of very
white make sense to use different tools
for the same task so the kind of the
first component the downloader and I
would kind of like to refer to it as a
tiny loader because that's also
something from the past and we are being
sure that this is the same family or
derivation from that one the downloader
is always having an additional
encryption layer you can imagine that as
a kind of a short acts or decryption
loop that's usually added at the entry
point or score close to the entry point
and it's just decrypting the additional
code nothing too complicated it's very
basic Association technique so you
cannot really see the internal command
content by just using the hex editor
that a node that is supporting do LC to
IP addresses actually there is a little
phobia laziness on the side of the
developers because most of the samples
are only utilizing one and even if you
are using if you are using only one they
are having the same constants in the
code so they were not cleaning up the
code to have a version where it's two IP
addresses or have one it's always
flipping back and forth but basically
they are using two or four times the
same constants and that's not a very
easy and convenient way for them the
main purpose for the share code sorry
for the download that is to retrieve a
shellcode and execute it I'm going to
talk about that next later the share
code is also encrypted saying X or B is
the encryption nothing overcomplicated
and due to the share code and due to
their the structure of this the dollar
is capable of running any custom share
code what you would like to do or
executor normal P executable there are
suggesting that date might be using it
for other operations than their own but
we've been dealing with one type of
share codes during your investigation
about the situation at roses the IPS are
usually lasting for a period of time
that means that a couple of months or
some older eyepiece might be coming back
whatever is changing those are the ports
so if you are looking at samples in kind
of in a timeline fashion then we could
see that ports are changing likely by
one increment or by two increments
those campaigns are kind of dying off
every second day or every next week and
just a new one arriving with the same IP
address but a new port so about a little
bit about the share code I said the
shackle is being built up from multiple
fractures when I'm saying share code and
when people are thinking of share code
you are thinking of something very short
or and and very basic functionality just
a couple of hundred of bytes this is
slightly different here so this is kind
of the hugs dump of a sort of first
level share code as you can see this is
not that tiny it's not really readable
but there are lots of API names there
are some interesting strings what
happens in reality is if the downloader
can connect to your c2 and the
connection is established it's sending
data there and then trying to retrieve
something so and retrieving it's only
downloading like a couple of hundred
bytes per each Ram and then that's
already a share code and some additional
data so like one piece of couple of
hundred bytes is going to build up this
whole piece by copying the rest of the
content to a certain memory location and
then giving back the signal that yeah I
need another piece of this this one is
probably after like six or seven piece
collected together once it was complete
the execution is being passed over to
that it's pretty much just resolving
those API names and also having
processed blacklisting or process
filtering that can be shown a little bit
in a more readable form here so it's
basically kind of easy to see a certain
system process names only using like
four characters for those and if those
processes found then those are being
skipped if the process is not on the
kind of blacklist then that's going to
be
they're downloaded and the share could
has a certain way of interaction so it's
it's not like the download that is
passing over execution to the share code
and then a share code does whatever it
wants the share code can also give back
information to the Davo there so after
the kind of thoughts is blacklisting it
was gathering all the process names on
your computer then passing that back to
the c2 in a list and if you are nice
victim then you get something back as
for the second part so this is once
again being built from fractures and
this is actually a full download their
share code so that story is not ending
here because this is capable of
downloading something unless you are
also receiving an additional IP address
a port or fine name and or an actual URL
it wouldn't do anything for you so if
you are not one of the targets they are
looking for the next check would after
this what you are getting back is
basically a nice sleep of couple of
minutes then a nice tip of couple of
hours and then I on I sleep of couple of
hours and it goes on so it wouldn't
really exit from memory but it would be
just waiting for for another command or
maybe that they are trying to send you a
different type of payload so the next
model is discount it's basically it's
having two times they are both very easy
pieces of code and basically the type a
is just collecting the running process
name so it's a small executable looking
at looking through over your process
names and basically making a list of
that it's trying to open all the
processes if there is an error there is
a flag of EOF like for fail they were
changing it sometimes for whatever
reason if it could be open then it's a
low and then it's building up a list of
all the process names and the flags and
sending back to another situ so
basically it's very easy mapping of your
running processes Tybee is a little bit
more complex but just a little bit more
and it's more targeted so Tybee is also
having a huge list of POS process names
and it's also doing some additional
tricks like getting the name of the PC
and also doing a network map that's
actually usually think of simplistic
that not view for that and also doing
the same process walkthrough but this
time it's only looking for processes
from the POS list and that P was list is
this so to understand or put it into
context you have to know that there are
six characters for comparing one process
so they were not really bothering to
have the whole long process names here
why would that be needed they are only
comparing like the first six characters
of every process name if we do the math
because actually I know the size of that
that means that that list contains over
300 actually 327 POS names so that's a
really an eye-opener because in reality
if you are going for a new business as
if you are kind of buying a POS terminal
and all the hardware and software
related for that you have one POS system
running there are no trial versions of
this software so it's not like if I'm
asking you to collect me like the the
top 10 simplistic graphics editors on
the net you can easily kind of grab
those install those check what
percentage they are using here it's much
more complex because you need to spend
money and invest money or you have to
start mapping a lot of networks and
looking for process names so this alone
indicates that whoever is behind this
these modules and these campaigns they
are they were not starting it today or
the week before but likely doing it for
a couple of years or more and then
finally the POS model itself a little
bit strangely but
maybe not that strange it is not
utilizing any encryption basically if
someone is reaching or a piece is
reaching this point then they are almost
very sure that they are a couple of
target solid that's likely a POS
terminal there is no analyst sitting in
front of the PFC most of the time there
is no heavy installed or anything like
that why would they be hiding anything
in the in the binary they could be
applying the very same simplistic axes
or they decide not to do that
the main point the purpose of this
module is but overall the kind of old
other POS moreover we are doing it's
tracking and collecting the track 1 and
track 2 credit card data from memory
and using then that sending those to the
C to the previous model can also kind of
quantity a black and white list as seen
before in the feeder share code and with
the letter scout sometimes they have a
short list of POS names sometimes they
have a longer list sometimes they do
also have a black list for processes not
to be opened and sometimes the internal
kind of combining the two it's always
different having said that it's the
basic memory scraper that is still so
minor maintenance going on on a code
level I'm going to show an example for
that and it's actually a multi-threaded
memory scanning so whenever one process
is found to be interesting and it's
either not on the black list or it's
included in a varieties that's going to
be opened and the new thread is going to
be started and all that data is going to
be scanned or whatever and whatever the
accessible there is the example for
track 1 and track 2 data so whoever was
not dealing with Pugh has probably never
seen these this is basically what goes
through on the wire then you are using
the old-fashioned magic mode magnetic
stripe card payment so as you can see
this is kind of plain text no encryption
nothing else all the vital data needed
to complete another transaction is there
so if you can steal that you can kind of
clone a card or use that data for other
transactions and this is what's actually
being extracted from running the POS
module before encryption the previous
model is using a basic XOR before
sending that over to the situ but that
just for likely for the DLP and other
system so they are not flagging the
traffic as credit card data as you can
see I wasn't using the very same card
number but basically it's attracted to
data and there is a process name listed
what was my test be us and the hittable
which was nothing sort of fancy it was
actually a notepad and I was pasting
that just for memory scraping purposes
and then one bit of evil evolution from
the POS part so on the left you can see
that this is part of the the memory
scanning procedure there is a memory
read after the memory read there are
certain checks and on the bottom you can
see byte compares those are basically
looking for digits so it's likely three
four five six those are the usual digits
for your credit card that's that's just
kind of distorting numbers there is a
whole lung of parsing code beyond that
point so looking for all the specific
and and special characters from the
previous slide and validating it all but
this is where there was actually some
improvement so on the right you can see
the very same code except that there are
five more conditions and actually it
seems that by just reading memory either
it's running on an exception sometimes
or the timing is key because on the old
sample on the LAT one that's was from
like January or February this year they
were almost reading like 400 kilobytes
and then having one millisecond of sleep
that's not really a long one on the
right they do that a lot more frequently
so likely they are testing this and a
lot of systems and they are trying to
find
- so it's not resulting in an exception
it's not having any memory reading
problems or anything like that
beside this minor change the right hand
side sample is very recent it was from
September and porcine coded everything
else is the same so basically what the
usual operation our workshop for them on
the left we can see that there is the
Scout that would be mapping all the data
and all the processes what that they can
they were not converting that or or
compiling that into x64 there was no no
reason the key it was always static in
that case for for all the samples we had
from this year the port number was those
two that was also not really changing
and it's only a very few IP addresses
they are using for sending back the
processed data so in their
infrastructure they are trying to
distinguish which data goes to where
it's there is kind of an overlap but but
they are trying to distinguish the
different functions then of course if
there is a good candidate that is going
to be a downloader the downloader there
is no encryption it's actually the brute
forcing of themselves so the top layer
the encryption is not having any key
stored there is no need it's just doing
a D word
brute force which is very fast on
current CPUs and then it can decrypt
itself it's using many different port
numbers as I was stating that the port
number is frequently changing and it's
using almost like ten different IP
addresses or that that was from this
year and then finally you have the POS
it having also an M key for the
encryption for data sending back to the
C - it's multi-platform it's always
using that very important umber and it's
also a connecting to a very few ones and
then if you get the credit card data
than they do the cash out and the whole
cycle goes back to the beginning as you
could see from all the the P
process names it's likely a lot of
cycles likely a hundreds or more of
evolution and constantly looking for new
possible targets constantly mapping pcs
and having a good understanding of who
is a good candidate and who is not so
what the problem is here first there is
a the software side of things and this
part is starting with POS ready 2009 and
POS 37 so those are Microsoft platform
names you can probably guess that P was
3 2009 is XP based what a surprise P was
37 is Windows 7 based one problem is
that people are still using the old our
POS platform and we've pretty much done
how secure XP is the other is that no
matter what you use soon they are going
to reach end-of-life they are already on
the extended support and the deeds are
next April for POS early 2009 and
sometimes October in 2021 for the
windows 7 based one then a problem is
that what we could learn from past
experience that often there are remote
access applications being pre-installed
on POS terminals so that's not really a
surprise
imagine your average IT administrator
they don't want to kind of walk down to
all the POS terminals updating whatever
software is running on them especially
kind of imaging something big in the
United States which is nationwide of
course they have moved to IT stuff but
doing that from a central location and
easily and conveniently updating
software that's always good
the problem is sometimes they as the IT
people sometimes they forget to change
default passwords or use the same
password for the whole country white
stuff and that's just providing an
additional attack surface the track want
to data
lacking an encryption you could see that
it's kind of plain text there is nothing
more there the
you track tree which is kind of the EMV
base what I'm going to talk about later
that's using three deaths RSA and AES so
they were thinking ahead of the problem
are the years back
but this is what it is we are dealing
with legacy systems here and for last
that's additional third-party
applications might be running on the POS
so in a couple of instances there might
be an SQL Server on an equivalent and
imagine that if it's storing historical
data and that's loaded into the memory
then you are not just dealing with
actual transactions being stolen but
also something from all those historical
data if the post creeper is going is
able to grab the data from the memory
and then we are switching over to the
hardware side of the problem so it's the
old debate magnetic stripe via CMV which
is in the chip amp attempt in terminals
actually MV is not a new standard but
something old it was already
standardized originally in 1993 and for
so it's it's almost about 25 years ago
and these are the thinking of encryption
back then at least the basics and it by
the way it was standing for
europay MasterCard and Visa I'm not sure
if any you still remember what Europe a
was not likely that that's also
something blast from the past another
thing which is might be a problem but
the liability shield so bank's a little
bit got fed up with all these that
people were easily stealing credit card
data and of course they are the ones
trying to ensure the money I'm trying to
be responsible for for whatever was
stolen people going to the bank hey I
got any kind of card fraud please give
me my money back because I can sort of
prove that it was stolen from me so you
can see and understand that they were
fed up pretty easily about that so they
wanted to change that and so they did in
the EU it was 2005 and the first of
January
when they were having that the new laws
for this in the u.s. it took an
additional ten years it was just the
years ago so at that point they were
kind of moving all the responsibility
from bank to merchant and the merchant
is being responsible if there is any
kind of known EMV transaction happening
and there is a fraud also there's a
human factor we are lazy people I can
say that we like to easily just find the
card we don't want to enter a PIN code
especially that's true in the u.s. sorry
guys one possible solution here would be
that they are switching over to
contactless payment because that's also
kind of a convenient way but that is
only happening in the past years and
still switching over to anything still
involves money as they have to replace
the terminals and the software and if
you think of nationwide that can be a
lot of money a couple of an all-animal
is before I am closing it up so when we
were having a look on at all those
samples and and we were doing the
investigation something kind of stood
out that they were very quickly closing
down the ports and changing to new
campaigns but sometimes you are lucky
and there are very old IPs and ports
being kept open so I wouldn't say it's
really a Field Op sack it's just kind of
a bit of a laziness or maybe they were
overloaded with with all the different
targets and the work but that has
sometimes helps you to actually have a
living connection and retrieving the
share code also we could see a very
similar downloader actually downloading
what was an act XM rig minor so that
there are a couple of differences it was
using scheduled tasks for persistency
but the assembly code loader was very
similar and sometimes they were using P
a compact which is a very basic
executable Packer that seems to be a
spin-off I wouldn't say that these are
the same people but actually crypto
mining and cryptocurrencies were a big
thing in the past couple of years so it
wouldn't it wouldn't be senseless
you say that they were extending their
activities and for the last that was
just kind of the strangest one and
that's the server IP arranged so whoever
was working with the server around
somewhere before might know that the
server is looking up a very big list of
c-class IPs for any kind of c2
communication or the possibility of that
and that means if you try to look for
Hansford data and your actual IPS from
this previous campaign are falling into
that range you run into an awfully lot
of sir Berek kind of samples and that's
just making your investigation even
harder as a conclusion so it's a 4
kilobyte usually assembly based
application purpose-built it's very easy
to borrow ideas from us such small
executable you are not dealing with any
kind of library and high level language
code and library stuff it's just the
pure user code it's also very easy so
you can imagine if I want it to rebuild
the same on a source level it's 4
kilobytes it's not taking more than a
couple of days top and I am rebuilding I
have a source code I do whatever I want
with that also it's true that you don't
really need massive amount of code to
implement basic functionality kind of
purpose-built for just doing a very
basic thing telling exploitation of POS
systems is unfortunately still happening
due to the reasons I was just discussing
with you all the hardware and the
software issues combined together making
it possible and there is a problem with
software driven update chains so it
seems to be reasonable that some teams
are also utilizing hacking and either
getting to a computer which is a
software delivery chain which is taking
part in a software delivery chain and
using that to spread all the downloads
to all the previous terminals or they
are hacking the remote access tools
already pre-installed and using
credentials to get into
companies that way and that's where we
can connect back to the Joker stage
statement that likely stealing that many
data on that level is not possible in a
different way a couple of thanks to guys
helping me and a couple of organizations
I was using the graphs I wasn't talking
about the chance because it was just a
time I'm going to share the slides and
I'm also going to share I OC is you know
upcoming blog post all the samples the C
tools and new taxes and whatever be
forgetting questions and thank you very
much for your time I am here if you want
to have questions in person or by email
at a later point thank you guys
[Applause]