place ribbons still wants to reverse
them okay do it then okay folks whoa
that's loud for those of you still in
the room from the last session we do
have a session starting like right now
another session for Egret so you're
welcome to join us although we'll
probably force you into taking notes so
if you're here for Egret you'll start
here in just a minute
I feel like people should not be allowed
to sit I cannot on all sides like I
think I think I think we should I think
we should be friends with each other and
kind of cluster in the middle can you
guys you guys come be our friend over
here it's just weird soul get started
like 30 seconds after somebody
volunteers to take notes when we get a
job or strap wow I'm overwhelmed I'm
sorry roger is going to join virtually I
believe he's going to try if that's
possible
don't everybody volunteer at once for
Jabbar scribe and not taker can somebody
take some notes source christer that I
was looking at you because that might
make the meeting faster oh yeah just try
and capture the sense of what's going on
in a room you know title of the
presentation and what's being talked
about right for major topics do we have
a backup note taker so we can merge the
tune it's not a hard job it's just
something to do keeps you off of email
well the meetings going on so welcome to
Egret ietf 86 five why is it ah the
slides are wrong it's ITF 96 and we are
not in bonus eras Roger if you're
listening thank you so I'm our cleanser
co-chair Roger Marshall is attempting to
join us virtually if he hasn't already
doing this is the note well hopefully
you've read this and you understand that
contributing how to contribute to the
IDF and what your responsibilities are
in this area our agenda today we're
going to talk for about five minutes
bashing the agenda so if you see
anything up here you don't like we're
going to hear from Brian on data only
emergency calls validation of locations
around playing changes and extension to
return complete and similar info now we
took those three documents and actually
put them in working group last called
this week but we thought it would be
good to get let Brian state what he's
in the latest changes doesn't believe
you just updated him recently so he's
going to talk about those updates and
then you'll have comment had the ability
to comment in here and then of course
working group last call please you know
review them intensely in comment on the
list what I mean will capture your
comments and here is treat image you
know working group last comment then we
have two presentations from Randy and
in-vehicle emergency calls and an
American II call and those will probably
take the majority of a time and then we
got a few minutes at the end it's an
hour meeting so is there anybody wants
to throw rocks at the agenda no okay
document status additional data related
emergency calls in the RC editor Q we
talked about next generation vehicle
initiated emergency calls on Pan
American we believe they're real close
ready to go to the iesg there's been a
lot of comments on the lists in the
authors and in those commenters are
working those issues out now and we'll
just that shortly and these are the
three documents that when we started
working group last call this week on and
data only emergency lost extensions in
validation of location so milestones we
move those out to November our
aggressive schedule was March but we
moved those out to November and while
doing that we discovered an error they
were listed on the milestones the ich
all right the pan-american II call in
the in-vehicle emergency calls are both
listed as informational I believe
they're in the drafts as standards-based
we the chairs believe that was just a
error on our part we fat fingered that
when we put them in originally if
there's anybody has causes any pain for
anybody please let us know in other
words if you thought those drafts are
going to be informational and now we're
we've announced they're going to be
standards-based if that
cause you any concern please speak now
or on the list like shortly Brian
Rosalie the intended status on the
documents has always been proposed
standard so this is your problem please
fix your problem but intended the
intended status on all the drafts has
been for post ads right in I'm taking
the blame for that I'm just stating if
that's causing anybody else any grief
please speak now or forever hold your
peace so if you can just ask that
question on the list and give people a
couple days in case they they have
anything to bring out but otherwise
we'll consider it a mistake and we'll
fix it okay so if we could capture that
insight that the chairs will send this
issue to the list question so these are
our milestone updates if anybody has any
comment on that that's weak sent that
message to the list also in hopefully
november two thousand sixteen is is good
we'll talk about the working group
probably at the end of the speeding a
little bit about the status of egret and
where it's going so Brian Rosen those
are good if we get reviews those are
good if we get that's true so let me go
find Brian's presentation here which one
you doing first date on your name enough
time for these slides hmm um so data
only is a way to send a message that
contains all the information you would
find in an invite and use this when
there is no real time media there is no
difference between sending and invited
some emergency call and something and
message is an emergency call except that
you wouldn't have SDP and set up a
session with with with media so the
example here is an alarm right an alarm
goes off you send the message it's got
all the same data that would be an
invite gets routed like a any other
emergency calls
you're in service SOS and the and the
request-uri and are out that you get
from a lost server and and a route
header and it does exactly the same
thing but it doesn't set up a media um
there's a request to deal with a
statement about privacy mainly that
privacy for emergency calls and that
would apply to data only emergency calls
is subject to local regulation and
they're in many jurisdictions there are
regulations that basically reveal or
tell you that that certain information
that normally is considered private is
at least shared with emergency services
people so that is actually a meaningful
statement you need to make sure that
that's in the concern in the
consideration so I put that in um there
was reference to a draft that I put in
that lets you do an update to additional
data we haven't worked on that draft for
a while and I decided to just take it
out that was just the easiest thing to
progress this document eventually want
to get back to that because some data
and specifically the data that you're
using a message alarm data would be the
example may in fact change over time we
have another way to do it you can send
it by reference and then repeatedly
dereference it so we have a mechanism to
to do that but a push mechanism is
probably better but I don't need to
reference it I don't need we don't need
that mechanism to make this useful and
tying the to the dress together is
probably not a good idea so I just took
it out just deleted the text and then I
needed to make changes to conform to the
the syntax that we have in the final
version of additional data i was using
some earlier syntax and i fix those
those are the changes we did do a
working loose last call on but there
there was not a really a large amount of
review um and I didn't make changes so
the chairs agreed well the chairs
decided that they would just rerun
another last call which is fine and and
that's what we that's what they did so
we we would appreciate a few reviews i'm
going to get the
guys to refute to to do some reviews
we're going to deploy this in the nena
architecture of x generation 911 so this
is going to have many interoperable
plantations reasonably soon I think and
I would appreciate anybody taking a look
at it and and give me any feedback
questions this one's pretty simple and
and and fairly mature it's been around
for a while have to deal with a lot of
these little details making sure exactly
how things are right but it's it's
actually a pretty simple mechanism how
many people are following the draft read
it keeping up on what's going on ok
again plea for review I'd really
appreciate it if people would take a
look at it wouldn't take you long so
it's not a long draught ok ok sit for
data only oops similar or similar while
we get two slides in this one
so similar gives you a way to return
location information on a fine service
response so this is used in two
circumstances one if you if you have a
valid location but you're missing some
information that can occur when you send
enough information in the location
information on the lost request that we
can uniquely identify at the location
but you may not have supplied enough
information that that we really like you
to have in the location that you send
when you when you send that location an
emergency call a great example would be
you have a arm you have a street or for
which there really is only one such
street with the right Street house
number and everything else everything
else is the same but you've misspelled
or or in some way mangle the city name
another great example is that you you
you you don't include the county or the
a two-armed level information the the
911 authorities are they I'm sorry the
emergency call authorities really would
like to have all locations have that a
to information and but you've given us
enough information you know there's only
one city with that name in the state and
and we can supply that information back
so it's complete it gives you a complete
all the fields that we know about that
location you in that circumstance you
have sent a valid location in so you're
going to get a route out but there's
there's information that we know and we
want to be able to return it to you so
you can save it and send it in the
emergency call um the the the second use
is when you send an invalid location so
this is when you send a piece of
information in but we cannot vote
uniquely locate you in them in the lost
database you don't get a route in this
case you get an error and you get a
there's three lists of valid invalid and
unchecked and you you know the
individual elements of location
information are put in one of those
three thanks so in this case what we're
going to provide
with is a valid location that is a maybe
you meant this so this is a piece of
helpful hopefully helpful information to
a user who's entered the an incorrect
location um we do the all the documents
for all of this say that it's highly
desirable to validate the location
before you have an emergency call right
you want to make sure that your location
is valid before you have to go and get a
route for it so this is going to get
used way in advance when you first get
your service you put it in an address if
you put in an address that we can't
record we can't validate you need to
figure out what the valid location is
and we're going to give you helpful
information give you a a valid piece of
information that said maybe you meant
this it's exactly the same mechanism
it's just a way to return location
information in the fine service response
of a lost query next we have had several
reviews on this document and I i have
updated the comment in response to those
reviews one of them was quite extensive
extensive review and regret and gave me
several very very valuable comments
which I believe I have implemented
virtually all of them I'm going to have
that reviewer who's not here a damn
backs look to make sure that I've done
the right thing as part of working group
last call but this has received a lot of
interest from the nena guys they're real
everybody is very very interested in
this and the mechanism is good for that
and that everything's all right so we
would again we'll get a bunch of reviews
from them but anybody in the room who's
willing to review it this one's a little
bit you need to know lost pretty well to
kind of understand this is doing but if
you if you're familiar with RC 5222 then
then there the draft is actually fairly
short but if you don't understand lost
you'll you will get lost reading this
document yes yes yes had to say that
right so working group last call is
actually started i wrote i heard the
slides before they actually issued they
working group mascot which is great
which is unusual easy does it ten
minutes be yeah all right exactly yeah
it's right I had him several days
anything at smile but I I again I the
the mechanism is actually very simple
but it it's it is something that could
use some more review okay and finally
well any clower people paying attention
to this graph yeah we do it's mostly the
meaning we need reviews right working
group last call yeah that process we're
asking people to review it see if they
agree with the mechanisms defined and
actually look for editorial nits if you
don't like you know that stuff for your
keen on that stuff we do need people to
review these things so is there anybody
volunteering to do help us with a
working group last call Dale hit that's
all I will get a bunch of reviews from
from from the nena guys they want this
pretty bad so I can fashion Minh get
them to review it
and finally we have planned changes this
one is a a mechanism to deal with the
reality that the data in the lost server
changes slowly over time an easy example
is they build a new road in a town and
we've got to add that that piece of
information another example is that a
part of a of a run at what we in the US
it's called an unincorporated community
it's an area that is not in a city but
near a city and the city expands its
boundary to take that area in we call
that annexation there are other terms
used in other countries but those
changes are an actual change in the
address the address changes because
instead of having the name of the
community the a four-level be you know
like the county name or some
neighborhood name it changes to be the
name of the city so what was valid is no
longer valid that's a planned change
these kinds of changes happen on a
schedule they say at midnight on this
date these things will change yes and
drug since they were in a city here but
25 years ago had a lot of plan name
changes yes indeed it did we're in a
city that had an are quite a number of
planned changes thank you and um so um
that that mechanism is so that that
happens um today the only way that we
have to to have to communicate issues
like this is that there's this statement
in in phone bcp that says you should
validate periodical you should
revalidate periodically so that you have
a valid location every once in a while
you should check to make sure that it's
still valid that's a really lousy way to
handle a plan change um the the way this
so the whole mechanism what
that revalidate is a pull mechanism what
this draft proposes is a push mechanism
it's a way to say I'm going to tell you
that these locations will become invalid
at a certain time or will change at a
certain time and the way we do that is
that we we save a URI in the lost server
that we poke if you if a changes is
going to be made so when you do a
validation request you can supply a URI
that you or I can be saved in the lost
database and whenever that location
changes that you are I that you provided
will be poked to tell you that that
happens it's all optional at the server
the server can have lots of control or
what you are eyes it will or won't save
you are not guaranteed that your eyes
you give it will be saved you are not
guaranteed that you can give them you
know there's limit on the size of the or
I can only have one of them for a given
source you know there's lots of limits
on what this this does so that it
doesn't overload anybody but the the
normal case is that there will only be
one two or three maybe you are eyes
against a given location of a finite
size um the other thing it does is it
provides an input variable called as of
that lets you ask the server will this
location that i gave you be valid as of
this date and that's a way to make sure
that you can create that when this plan
change happens on a known schedule that
you can validate ahead of the change
that your proposed new address will be
valid as of the date of the change so
you can you can that you'll get this
notification that says this is going to
become invalid you know five days from
now you can three days from that
location you can say well what if I
changed it to this as of you know five
days from now found four days from now
would it be valid and then the the
server can say yes well as of that day
it will be valid you asked me about it
today it's invalid in five days it would
be valid um so um the the draft has been
around for a while we did adopt that as
a working group draft
um and the so so I have issued a 0-0 of
drafty crit it's again a fairly simple
mechanism but if you don't understand
that lost works once again it's pretty
hard do basically just adds this uri as
an input parameter that you can save
gives you an object that you can send to
that you are I to tell you that as a
change has been made and gives you this
as a thing that lets you say will it be
valid as of a specific date this is a
real problem encountered by real
implementations that they know they're
going to have and it also deals with a
fact that we discovered in
implementation which is that because
phone bcp says periodically revalidate
the number of transactions on the lost
server that are revalidation is two or
three orders of magnitude more than the
number of other operations on the law
server so the law servers has to be
scaled much much much larger just
because of that periodic revalidation
we'd like to turn that pull notion into
a push mechanism so that we can reduce
the load on the law sir it's really the
validation part of the sir so that's the
deployment experience tells us we made a
mistake periodic revalidation is causing
a lot of load that we didn't anticipate
and we would like to turn that mechanism
around make it push so we have not had
very many reviews on this I'm asking for
a bunch of reviews once again I will go
to the nena guys because they are the
ones with the problem here but I
appreciate people people looking at it
and give me some reviews yes Randall
Randall gallons so I did look at the
draft but it was a while ago and I I
don't remember a lot about it so
refreshed so the intent of the way this
is going to be used is this going to be
used by
random clients out in the world every
time they want to know what
infrastructure to infrastructure kind of
view it's the less operator will to use
this so and then it'll be some kind of
security language in there about you
know not allowing the saved you are I to
be a source of malware spin and that
kind of stuff I mean it as well I mean
it's just a URI so you you you don't
retrieve anything from that you are you
only you only do a post to that your eye
right but right ozone to let any
arbitrary person give you yeah there's
there's you should look at the text the
security the security considerations is
an important part of this particular
document and and I've tried to think
through make sure that we can't you
can't get a malicious you know it helps
that you can only post right there's no
no data you're getting back but
nonetheless you could get a you know you
could get a an error you know it could
be no we know where you could cause some
innocent party to be sending out sure
that's why they're you limit the number
right so that you can't do it's not it's
not a way to do an application attack
you will you will poke you know you will
try to push a piece of document to some
things yes the the you you would like to
know who who is requesting this you have
there occur you would like to have you
should have a policy and I pretty sure I
talked about this i maybe i'll have to
go back and look at what i wrote about
this but the identity human your actions
that the server should reflect the
identity of the entity who's asking for
it but the any idea then this is
infrastructure infrastructure but
they'll be one of these potentially one
of these safety or eyes / requester /
location for saved validated address
right but but think about as again Anna
practical thing that the number of
Lissa's with the same address is going
to be you know one two three it's how
many surely so your says providers there
are four that address you've got the
equivalent of the of the M sag and
you've got some large number of
addresses in there yeah and so you're
going to have some number of these for
every single validator address oh yeah
yeah I mean but that's again in the in
the scale of databases that's that's
pretty small as long as there's really
only three of them right if there were
5,000 of them per record then maybe it
would be a concern and and and there is
definitely advise about you know
bluemont how many of these you handle
any other questions or comments I think
I'm done reviews again same with this
there are three easy drafts to read we
put them in working group last calls or
asking for people to review them and
obviously we'll go to the list with that
also
this one first Randy you're next is this
one first oh you can't see that kidney
huh maybe if I do this and look for the
screen is okay so actually version 10 of
the e comment was published today so
that is now available the major changes
since version 7 which was the last real
big revision in order to align with some
work that went on in 3gpp the MSD is now
transported using asn.1 PE are encoding
which is a binary encoding it's not no
longer in XML and furthermore there's a
mid call to normally Andy call the
vehicle sends though the MSD in the
initial invite and then the piece app
sends a response acknowledging that in
the reply to the invite and normally
that's it but there are cases where a
pset might want to request an updated
MSD mid call so the way that happens is
the piece app sends an info message to
the vehicle and says please send me an
MSD before the text said that the
vehicle would send that reply MSD in the
reply to the info now the vehicle sends
a new info message with the requested
MSD in it the info package template was
filled out with some more text added an
example that showed info and then one of
the other big changes is that because
the econ draft creates the mechanism
with this control object and so forth
that's reused by the car
ashcraft there were some items in the
metadata control object that were used
for car crash that were not necessary
for eCall so by request those were all
moved out of the e call document and put
into the car crash document as
extensions so that's and there are a lot
of editorial changes and I can go on to
the next slide which helps about where I
got comments from yes so we get a lot of
comments from the number of people I
want to thank all of them we had a lot
of editorial changes resulting from that
and then the big technical changes that
i mentioned before I want to thank
Christopher especially for spending a
lot of time I think we've got things in
a really good shape now next slide yeah
so there's really just to open issues
remaining one is a related to where I
mentioned just a second ago about moving
the stuff that wasn't directly needed
for eCall from the Eco document to the
car crash and one of those is a
capabilities element that gets sent from
the vehicle to the piece app to let the
pset know what the vehicles capabilities
are so the pset will not request
anything that the vehicle does not
support so there was a suggestion to
move that capabilities object back into
the e call document but make it optional
so that if the vehicle does not send a
capabilities object it means its
capabilities are the minimum set
required for eCall in the e call
document but then the car crash would
then make the capabilities mandatory the
other open issue is about the use of
about the info package registration
right now the e call document says that
the e call outside the info package I
can be used to send a body part a mime
type that's listed in the emergency call
data set and so there's been some debate
about whether that's legal / the info
document if it is legal everything's
cool if it's not legal then we have a
few options one option is that
one option is that we require because
the purpose of making this registry
instead of a list of static list is that
the way this gets extended is that we've
seen right now for eCall we have MS D
which is the data set from the vehicle
to the peace app for for Penn you're
being II call in North America we have a
different data set beds so potentially
other regions as they start coming up
with implementations of this general
mechanism will start defining their own
data sets and if we want to do that we
want to make it as easy as possible for
them to simply define the mime type for
this data set without having to go
through a lot of work published an RFC
and so forth so one option would be that
we require a new info package
registration that would include
everything in the earlier ones for every
new mime type that might get deployed in
a different region another option which
is kludgy ER but avoids the legalistic
argument would be that we don't use info
we use reinvite or options or something
like that but some other sit message
that doesn't have the legalistic
restrictions a third option is that we
define and this is all so ugly and
occlude but perfectly legal I think you
define a a mime type that that says
multi-part emergency services data and
then put a parameter in there and what
you do is you just only for info you
just take your actual mind type and cram
it into this multi-part as an extra
wrapper around it so that the info
package only has the one mime type it's
horribly ugly but it would get around
the wording of the info package
restriction so there you have it
christer and Krista Homburg yes first of
all I also like to thank you for we've
given a lot of comments and things which
came out from tree TPP other comments
that you had and things are going very
smoothly but as you say there are there
there are few open issues I think
there's one more issue than this also
which was raised by my colleague which
you're discussing offline was this usage
of Content ID and and and and and call
in forward but I think but that's the
main issue is this in for and and i'll
try to be short but I mean we had this
previously we had this legacy info
before we did in four packages and there
were a lot of problem with that people
use it for all kind of things there were
no real semantics associated with it you
didn't really know what people supported
and what they were going to do when they
receive is so so we define the info
package which has all the semantics and
and one thing which just info package
does say is that you define which mime
types are associated with which this
info package now the way it's done here
in equal is a different instead of
listening these mine times it says that
you can use any mind x mm I'm pipe which
exists in this specific I on our
registry so whenever people want to use
something new they don't need to define
an info package they just add stuff into
this I in our registry and that is my
main issue because I think first of all
it cydia mean we don't know in the long
run what people are going to put there
as long as they can justify it somehow
being in you know emergency related and
another example or I also think it gives
a bad precedence I've given example I
will give it I don't know it's the best
one but assume that someone registers a
nympho package for transporting you know
game online game information and they
create iono registry for online game
mime types
we start getting all these games 10
games hundred games 200 games they all
define their own mime type and they all
put this into the saints registry and
use the same info package so i think
it's it's it's a slippery slope and a
dangerous way to go so my suggestion is
really and i think that this original
intention of info package when you need
something new you define a new info
package i said here earlier you
mentioned RFC but that's not true you
don't need an RFC to define a new in the
package its specification required and
an expert review so you can define it
whatever you want maybe any you know the
Chinese Americans whatever they they
find is it can be done and so an info
packages rrrr Chi in that sense so I
really think that should be done we list
explicitly the info packages and these
are my plans you use and nothing else
also what's important to think that this
is not only about the mine finds another
thing which we have in the info package
is a section where you need to either
define or reference a specification
which describes how this info package is
used and that of course includes how the
mime types are used so now assuming that
you're adding a new mime time to this
registry which coming into this info
package you would also have to update
this add a reference to the
specification which now describes the
usage of this mime type and so on and
maybe it could be doing something else
maybe it could affect some of the other
things which are in the in the info
package rate whatever we have I mean we
don't know so then you would have to
update the info package and there is
really no procedure for updating the
info package the actual template that
has been provided to Anna there is no no
mechanism for that so my suggestion and
I have said offline I am willing to help
whatever I can do to do that is we
define this info package we call for
ikura cars crash sorry they we define
our another waiting for package we can
use similar name no problem we can even
it's a lot of copy paste we can do and
then for you know
Asia whoever needs they do in their info
box I think that's a clean way is the
way you know exactly what it's there you
don't need to go and look in this rigid
tree where there's something new stuff
there even though and so on and I think
that's a generic way to do it I know
that there is this capabilities in this
specific case there make an instant that
we have done so we can know what
supported but I don't think that's way
we should go that individual info packet
is start defining their own inclination
a mechanism that not what we should do
there is a common negotiation mechanism
which you when you send your invite you
include this receive info header field
which name stain for package if I
support this in package and I know which
mine pies are associated I everything is
good so I really think that i strongly
think we should do that here also sorry
for for you know yes got it thank you I
I again I didn't want to come up here
and say that I don't afree I really
appreciate the work that's been done i'm
really thankful for that I think we'd
love got done a lot of progress but this
is the main issue where we unfortunately
are not on the same page Prime rozum the
when you add a new block of data all
we're doing is adding a piece of data
right it's a hunk of XML that we're
sending between the entities right we
need to decide what level overview is
appropriate to add a piece of data using
the mechanism for providing if we decide
that specification review is the right
level a specification requires the right
level of documentation to add a new
thing then adding to the registry should
have specification required if we decide
that that's not an appropriate level of
documentation it's too much overhead for
the for the kind of information that we
have then maybe we go back to just an
expert review by requiring that you were
doing a new info package you are
demanding that you do specification
required that might be what we want but
it isn't a decision that we're making
it's just you got to do it that way
because that's what
nation what when m.phil says it is low
overhead we can build a template that
says to do a nympho package you know
filling these blanks done so it's not a
huge it's not a huge amount of overhead
specification required is more than you
know a review and other things you got
it some well if you read the definition
of standards required it's a lot more
than just document required Krista I'm
not talking about standard required what
maybe I remember the definition maybe I
remember the definition of specification
required wrong but my what I what what
what is needed is there needs to be a
publicly available document which takes
per trigger account because the expert
reviewer needs to you know look at this
it doesn't have to be an RFC it doesn't
have to be an opposite exactly so yeah
classification just means specification
you have it there in front of you yes
it's not a standard does not have to
have consensus just has to be written
down yeah I mean how does sleep yeah
right so but but all I'm Sam and just
for reinforcing the same time who's
going to repeat it right we need to
decide what the level of control that we
want / adding another hunk of data if we
decide that specification required is
appropriate great let's do that by
pushing my requiring info we don't get
to make that we get to make it stronger
right we can say and adding something
that a registry takes more than
specification required I don't think
we're going to do that but we could but
we're stuck at the minimum level of
specification report which may or may
not be appropriate I happen to think
it's not appropriate but we can we can
we can make that decision independently
however I am not in favor of playing
games with the the sip info package RFC
right if if the SIP guys say no you
can't do that he's right you got to
specify what mimetypes going the package
that's the end of the story we're going
to do it
and just are in my pain for a point of
interest the chairs are trying to
solicit help to look at that and decide
make that decision to outside of this
community right Robert good yeah and
Ryland yeah I have a lot of sympathy for
krista's points here I think the reason
we did all this work to come up with
with the new version of info with the
info packages rules to prevent the kind
of proprietary explosion of the use of
info which info wichman didn't
interoperate and I feared if we add
these ad mimetypes our outsides of the
control of the actual package that
effectively you've got different
versions of the same package that aren't
going to interoperate as Brian said I
think we can make this a template you
can be very clear we put that in the RFC
this is the template if you want to add
add a new a new usage then this is how
you do it this how you create the at the
what you would put your specification
you just fill in the blanks so if I can
actually just play devil's advocate for
a moment I think I very well understand
the concern that you guys have about the
reason there's info package and the
reason requirements and how allowing us
to do this could potentially create a
slippery slope that allows you know the
game people to to just go hog-wild with
completely different types of data with
completely different semantics and and
so forth and that would be a mess but
just to play devil's advocate if I was a
game designer trying to do that sort of
thing I could easily do that with info
now several different ways I could
define one mime type and just say this
mind pipe contains XML or JSON or
whatever and then I put whatever I want
in there that has wildly different
semantics and sizes and rates and
everything else yeah this is uh on this
is hummus yeah i think the case that
Krista are provided here sort of de
bourrée seems a little bit constructed
I'm like the fact that you come up with
gaming the gaming community is is is
no no it's like it's like is this a real
concern like literally the gaming
community of writing sip applications
and then putting stuff in for emergency
service to must be kidding right now
he's not saying they would use emergency
services you're saying they oversee I
said that they would define dated would
define their own iono registry for
gaming mimetypes and they even then they
would one have one single info package
which points to that registry and then
everyone starts putting these these mime
types into the same registry and it all
gets associated with one single info
package I'll eat I didn't say that they
were going to use the emergency iono
registry but they were going to
dosometing sim similar with their own
owner registry basically allowing you to
have one info packager then people can
start adding adding adding mimetypes
internet that's what I want to avoid and
and of course you know anyone can define
an XML type which is very flexible on it
we can't prevent that but I mean but but
I mean that's not a reason for us to do
you know the wrong thing just by saying
yeah but someone else could do this but
you know we do we should do what's right
and and you know that's over sure but
but see if the reason to make it's the
reason for us to do something in a more
difficult way which isn't the semantics
that we want is to prevent us from being
a precedent for somebody else to do the
wrong thing even without us being that
precedent people who want to do the
wrong thing can do the wrong thing Chris
I don't think it's easier because even
in even if we would move forward this
way there will be a lot of text needed
we need text either an update to RFC 68
is 86 or something describing how this
is done yes you can create these
registers and all these things and and
we need rules how it's done how do you
update the info package there would be a
lot of work not for you maybe because
this would be maybe for me so I I think
that they finally news effect is really
the easiest way to do it
you need to write a little text but then
it's done and it's clear and no one has
any any you know it's no ambiguity as
also so just a time check we get like
six minutes and he's got to be get
through this one in that six minutes
video d of my working with 3gpp as well
and I also support krista i think if we
create a precedence here I mean when we
looking at the SIP protocol in 3gpp
there are people who look if there are
any holes where they can sneak something
in what you're doing here and I'm not a
fan of that at least not when I'm here
in this meetings so but first from big
to bed no I I just think we should go
along the lines that the sip info
protocol a message was intended to and
we had long debates in 3gpp as well how
we can use info we are very restrictive
in this usage and I hope we can also be
that here and not open some doors debts
maybe even if somebody wants to misuse
info on cramster feeling like I said
there's plenty of ways to do it they
don't violate the letter of the RFC so
and rollin well I would hope that the
expert review of the info package would
at least catch some of those if it looks
like you're just basic regni generic
container to stuff in whatever you like
means gear up said in 20 PP we could
create a nympho package called free to
BP application and just like for
everything in the future and I have to
come back to ITF again this is not what
we want to encourage so and I don't
think it's really that hard pretty much
we can fill out the whole template in
the RSC as a registration template and
you just need and identify you just need
to fill in this bit in this bit and this
bit we will have to we'll have two
examples right one for equal one for
wonderful car crash and it shouldn't be
that difficult well but the issue isn't
with what we do for eco and car crash
the issue is what does the next region
that might need that good so ms t is one
set of data in North America Ruiz
beds which is a pretty flexible set of
data but what happens if China or
Australia or Saudi Arabia or some other
region or country decides they want
something that isn't quite beds they
want their own data set so what the RFC
with the documents say now is well you
define a mime type of you add it to the
registry and everything else is exactly
the same so can I say in addition to the
mime type you're going to have to have
specification for the info package which
is Brian points out the case of just the
doc requires it I'm sorry specifications
just the document that's all it is
publicly available document and
following that template so we provide
them a template and we identify okay
here fill out your own stuff fill out
your own stuff it doesn't seem that it's
a huge piece of documentation and
basically we want good documentation so
we can implement that thing without
having to go for all kinds of hoops and
hurdles in order to find out what it is
yes free successor so sorry Saudis will
have to define their own info baggage
and I don't think that's an issue and I
mean no matter what is gonna I assume
they're gonna document it sound wearing
some documents right so so no matter how
it's done there jit they're just not
gonna send an email to iono and hey here
is our mime type and then it's not
occupant anywhere I mean it and I don't
think even I don't know what the ITF
procedures for registering new mime
types are but I would assume that that's
not gonna pass either just someone
saying please please register is my time
without any indication what's in it so
they will have to define any info
package day you know write it down and
it's it's it's not that difficult I mean
it's not that too much information that
you need to provide the the real the
real stuff is is how you use it and that
they will have to define it somewhere
else and the expert review of it look at
that and and day for package template
with reference to that everything is
good okay so let's get through this real
quick sure that one I want to buy Mike I
want my five minute to the skirt okay
well actually there's this really very
little say on this um you know it's just
a mirror of it I mean the stuff that
came out of he call was moved the econ
metadata control object was moved in
here
there are a lot of editorial changes and
I think that's it so once we decide
whether we're moving the the
capabilities object whether we're
leaving it here or moving it back into
eCall so it forms like part of the base
pack for extension here that's really
the only open issue that affects this
document Brian Rosen in the interest of
fairness I just looked up the
registration requirements for mom type
and it's more onerous than specification
required well it depends correct it it
depends on well write it depends on
which tree we allow right and well it's
right it we probably need to specify
that if we allow it to be in the vendor
tree re if we if we have comments please
use the mic if we don't have comments
and we're done here thanks Randy oakdale
one quick ones got to be quick well what
I was saying to the microphone and rylan
again is at least for public safety
applications in different regions I
would hope they would be at the vendor
tree I'm sorry for public safety
application isn't like car crash I hope
they wouldn't be in the vendor tree
right right absolutely not and
particularly because what we're really
talking about here is as various not
just public safety we're talking about
vehicle initiated emergency calls and
we're talking about region specific data
sets for them car manufacturers would
probably want to implement this all of
the regions in the same vehicle so that
the vehicle just knows what to send
based based on where it is you wouldn't
couldn't do that in the vendor tree you
wouldn't want to Brian Rosen so so
that's a comment to change the text to
say that it's too late but we should
have probably done that with additional
data and having said that its
specification required from a recognized
standards organization
so I think we actually have an out on
that though because it's not just that
you have to register a mime type but you
also need expert review for the IANA
registry ability okay thanks Randy so
we're going to go back to what we talked
about originally which was basically the
document status so we have we have no
individual drafts hanging out there
targeted at egret right so nobody has
submitted anything for a while we have
these five drafts that are on the screen
that are there three of them we called
working group last call this week second
working group last call in a couple of
those okay so we're getting to the point
where our work is winding down and when
we submitted the request to have a
meeting at IETF 96 there was 25 meeting
requests more than they had space for so
my point I'm getting to is we're almost
if we don't start wrapping up some of
this and winding down and keep asking
for meeting slots we're going to start
doing the IETF a disservice by you
taking a meeting so awkward and there's
a work group that really does need to
meet so I'm couraging people to review
the working group last call documents so
we don't have basically don't have to
meet you know in Seoul I mean that a
alyssa is going to you know overpower me
in any way shape or form but we got to
get through these issues that between
and the car crash and II call I think
those are not insurmountable issues I
think if we pay attention to those in
work through it we can get those
documents done prior to to Seoul so I
mean that's that's from a chair position
that's what I would like people to to
start working on um Brian Rosen I I mean
I certainly agree with with what you
said
we put November down for you put
November down and I'm hopeful that we
can meet that um but I think we had
November a couple years ago on it yes i
understand it depends on reviews it
depends on reviews i'm going to work
hard to get reviews so that we can do
those things but i do believe that we
that there is more work to do and that
more work is a result of deployment
experience that works we're having I
know at least two things that we want to
do um so I you know they can be done as
individual drafts we can do it you know
we can leave the mailing list open I
understand all those kinds of things but
I think it would be good I think it
would be better to leave the working
group open for a while that's two to do
these those additional pieces of work
okay that's like thanks for the warning
obviously what we have to view is
submission for dr. Graf's is what we
look at so i think i mean i would hope
that all of these documents are with the
IHG before the next meeting of the only
the gating factor is that this is small
group of people who need to review all
of them are the likely candidates to
review all of them but that would be my
expectation for this but i think the
other thing about this group is that
there's very little overhead in keeping
the group open and keeping the mailing
list and just having it sit there if
even if there's no work for a while
there's no reason to close it if it for
this particular topic it seems like
things might pop up now and again and i
think that that's fun we don't we can
sort of be in dormant state and that
doesn't cost us anything so that would
that would be my recommendation is after
we get through the rest of these that we
go and go into dormant state and then
people can always bring the list with
new things as they come up and if you
know a year goes by or something and we
change our minds we can we can close the
group or just keep the list or we have a
lot of options sorry that's a nice
addition I think my point was more
around taking precious precious minute
time our meeting time at them you know
what the meetings for face-to-face you
know when II when this should be done by
them in general working group who's all
of his documents are in 200 last call
doesn't usually meet
unless there's like comments come back
from ASG so yeah I don't want to be
discussing info packages and November
and salt well we need to go to the list
but yeah we we're trying to get some
expert review on that but so that's
that's the chairs piece for the people
that made notes are you subscribers to
the Egret list do you ok so I'll get
with you as soon as we to get the notes
from you so Andrew I'm just one comment
on the slide mark preach previous
working requirements for like service I
think it is the same service eco sorry
for the ecole just a comment on the
wording of the slide ok it really is
there isn't the IETF eco and if they
disappoint the chief mate and the free
to be p equal there's a single service
well but no where we Alyssa aren't we
still holding this draft until we get
hard requirements or if we ever see
requirements on a 3gpp well I think his
point is just that we basically did this
for that for the service being developed
in 3gpp we wrote the draft here for that
so it's just one service but I mean I
guess the time but I'm assuming the
timing on that is like we basically know
everything like if we resolve these last
couple open issues we can go to a group
last call and go to ITF last column that
will be okay for a 3gpp is that correct
I think so just one thing we have a
meeting where we have a meeting next
week and we have two more meetings one
of which clashes with the sole meeting
to get this done for release 14 so okay
but it's possible that new new
requirements will still be popping up
from 3gpp in November well but still I
mean you're gonna speak yeah
I think to work is gonna is already
pretty stable as far as a 3d BB work is
concerned obviously they reference and
we have all this open issues and I know
they have a meeting next week so they're
gonna be they're gonna be but i think
it's i said it's it's there no main
issues i mean we we found issues that
previous meeting but they'll have those
have all been taken care of say things
very much went much smoother than it
thought so okay so but you you remember
the original idea we were going to run
it through IETF last column before
Alyssa hit the pub request button we're
going to check practice see if there's
anything else we needed we hadn't
covered from 3gpp perspective so I mean
we can still follow that but if you know
something that says we don't have to
deal with that any more than you know
please it please let us know okay I
wouldn't say we're quite that right now
but I guess we could also initiate as
well right we could we could VA's to ITF
decreed from free to be p.m. so we think
this is good now so don't hold it
anymore or if you're waiting one out
since then uh sir communication and
we'll we'll get back to you okay we we
are officially three minutes over it's
invites is opening up and there's going
to be free food and beer so I don't want
to stand back thank you everybody
oh thank you