so anyone cares for Java or anybody on
the jabber
okay so our plan to start so this is a
week working group make sure you're in
the right room so because it's Friday so
I want to keep into time okay my people
is waiting and our responsible ATSDR
probably on the way so unfortunately my
culture robot could not make to burning
his time this is not well you probably
have reduced the hundreds times and any
warranties to take minutes okay anyone
tears for to see if there's any people
on the chapel
Matthews matthias could you help with
the chapel are you on it I or anybody on
the javelin sure okay thank you thank
you what's your name by the way okay
very good I actually have a warrant here
for their minis taker we sound away but
sing for the general part is ok for his
absence Carrie uh yeah we had we hand
out the the blue sheet he's on the way
please sign okay our responsibility is
coming great so this is status of the
walking group document we have right now
on the desk so recently published the
iCub to minimum nation guidance which is
obviously 7815 and also we have the L
week co-op over senator document which
is in the Absinthe you and we have not
document related to co-op in plantation
which half has been discussed many times
over the years but now the state has has
been inspired I talked with materials
yesterday and he said he some plan about
some update of this document recently
and we have done a document about energy
efficient invitation guidance which he
has has gone through the walking group
last core but there was a silence during
the last call so I cannot say that they
are saying consensus about this document
right now so we are still waiting for
more views and probably we can click OH
but the other walking the blast call for
this document if we really laid it and
we can have the sufficient view of this
document here in the process and we have
another good document about the POS
implementation and we can speak spout
waiting for the authors to if they have
interest or they still sink this useful
to continue so that's pretty much on my
side and so we have four for talks today
lister hill and also in the agenda so
because it's friday i really hope every
presenters to be on time precisely
because otherwise people we are playing
me so yeah that's kind of on to the next
the first presentation callous ok hello
my name is carlos gomez and i'm going to
present this initial version of the
draft and title tcp of a constraint node
networks and from UPC and I took at and
my coiffeur is don't cook off from the
University of Cambridge so first of all
let's take a look at the motivation for
this draft at this moment we have a
situation where several application
layer protocols are being used for the
Internet of Things for instance we have
the coop the constraint application
protocol was originally designed / UDP
however there is currently a co-op over
TCP specification being developed and
then actually the main reason for this
copper over TCP draft is the need to
overcome middle box problems then on the
other hand we have HTTP two and even
HTTP one that one which are also being
used or considered for the IOT and other
application
layer protocols such as MQTT are also
being are also in fact deployed in the
IOT and all of these are using TCP as
the transport layer protocol so TCP is
being aureus or will be used in many IOT
scenarios however it has not received
much attention yet and in fact it has
been sometimes actually very criticised
so the main goal of this document is to
offer simple measures to allow for
lightweight TCP implementation and
suitable operation for constrain node
networks well this work actually is
related with more than one working group
for instance this is related with core
which is the working group which
specifies co-op and its related
framework also TC p.m. which defines the
DCP maintenance and minor extensions and
also this working group which has been
actually suggested as the home for this
draft I understand that at some point
we'll have some discussion or
confirmation about this so on the actual
content of the draft first of all we
should take into account each other
typical characteristics of constraint
node networks which is something that is
well known in this working group and
actually it's defined in RFC 7228 so
constrained nodes are devices which
typically exhibit significant
limitations on processing and memory
which limits the complexity and the
implementation footprint of the
protocols being used then there may be
also significant limitations on energy
resources which means that the messages
involved in communication and the size
of those messages should be reduced as
much as possible
then these devices typically use low
ceilings which means links with high bit
error rate that's mostly because
typically wireless technologies are used
but also sometimes there are other wired
technology is quite common in some IOT
scenarios which however are also harsh
and offer some high bit error rate such
as power line communications with regard
to the network topology in some
scenarios we may have star networks so
that this ends up with being a single
hop communication scenario between a
constrained device on and the Rooter for
instance and in some other cases there's
a mesh or multihop deployment so let's
take a look at the several
recommendations about how to use TCP in
these environments as per the current
version of the draft so about the
maximum segment size we have that ipv6
requires support for 280 byte packets
however many of the link layers which
are used typically in constrained not
networks offer very reduced linklater
payloads such as tens or hundreds and
red lights so this means that in these
cases another tation layer such as six
lo pan or six law is used however these
ensures that package of a size of 180
bites can be actually transmitted or
received through these links however it
is not so clear that support for packets
of a greater size than this is still
allowed still a nibble so the idea is
that in order to avoid IP layer
fragmentation this document indicates
that the maximum segment size cannot be
greater than 12 hundred and twenty bytes
and in any case it shouldn't lead to an
ipv6 Datagram size exceeding
180 bytes for these kind of links then
about the window size at this moment the
draft states that stopping wait
operation has to be used this is because
quite often they have been comments for
instance in remember in the coil working
group that for the end-to-end
reliability mechanism for co-op we
shouldn't reproduce let's say the
complexity of of tcp however the result
has been a stocking wait operation by
default in coop so this seems to be
accepted by the community which is
dealing with this protocol and the
related environments so the idea was to
say well possibly the same can be
achieved with with tcd so based on the
feedback that we've received so far it
seems like okay maybe it's better to
maybe recommend or explain which are the
benefits of stopping wait but maybe not
forbid other options so then another
matter is how we can enable the stop and
wait operation if we really want to use
it another section focuses on the RTO
algorithm so in this case what is
currently in the draft is that we
actually recommend the use of the same
algorithm that is being proposed as some
advanced mechanism for co-op actually
that's because we have experimentally
evaluated which is the performance of
this new algorithm which is called Coco
and we have compared it with other
algorithms such as the one in RFC 62 98
and many others and we believe that it
performs very well in this kind of
environments so this is why we are
actually recommending its use
some of the features of this mechanism
include her in addition that this is
based actually on RC 62 98 it also
includes using with our titties a
variable back of factor and eating
mechanism and deterring so this has
shown to lead to good performance in
terms of pd are settling time after a
burst of messages and fairness another
aspect is about the lifetime of TCP
connection so in the draft we currently
state that the TCP connection should be
kept open as long as possible well
actually there's some indication in a
quantified terms which is that if data
is going to be sending out in the next
two hours then the connection should be
kept open the idea is to minimize the
overhead of establishing new connections
then the other hand we have that
keep-alive messages lady use may be
supported by a server and in in the
scope of constrained scenarios this may
be useful to clean inactive state for ya
in active connections state for devices
which have memory limitations however
the keepalive timer cannot be set to a
value lower than two hours so this
actually some issues such as it doesn't
guarantee avoiding middle box problems
because sometimes the bindings and the
state kept the middle boxes is released
earlier than two hours so the
alternatives might be okay maybe we have
to anyway establish TCP connections
frequently or maybe application layer
heartbeat messages can be used also
based on the feedback that we have
received something you should take into
consideration is TCP first open this
would have the benefit of embedding data
already in the syn packets when a new
connection is established
however we have to make some detailed
analysis here because this week a fast
open involves negotiating a cookie which
has to be updated relatively frequently
and then also the cookie has to be
included in the same packet which also
increases message size so we really need
some detailed analysis here okay then
there is the mechanism of explicit
congestion notification which we
understand that may be used in
constrained node networks at this moment
the draft was only allowing stopping
wait operation however as I mentioned
before probably in the next version this
constraint will be released or relaxed
the idea is ACN can be useful to trigger
congestion control mechanisms earlier
than maybe after the expression of the
RTO or earlier than waiting until the
reception of three duplicated
management's and even in the case of
having a single segment window it's
still useful to to trigger congestion
control measures then a consequence of
the original stopping weight approach
that was enforced or is currently still
enforced by the draft it is that then
there are several options which would
not be used or wouldn't make any effect
such as windows scale TCP x times
selective acknowledgments however we
have that for the the next revision of
the draft based on the feedback we have
received probably since options 0 1 and
2 have to anyway be parsed then we may
phrase in a different way the
approaching in this regard saying that
we may ignore or an implementation may
ignore
options that are not really wanted and
if any way stopping weight is not going
to be the only option then maybe some of
these options might be relevant such as
for instance selective acknowledgement
finally are with regard to explicit loss
notifications this is something which
could be useful to distinguish whether
loss is due to congestion in the network
or whether it is due to corruption this
would be useful here because we are
dealing with low ceilings in constraint
node networks however this remains
mostly as experimental work it hasn't
actually been widely deployed and hasn't
been really standardized maybe 80 f so
there are several other items we should
take into consideration for future
revisions of the draft one thing is to
clarify the scenarios we are considering
for instance a major scenario coming
actually from one of the main motivation
items for the draft is to explain that
we have sometimes a constraint device
which may want to communicate with some
unconstrained device on the internet so
we need to detail which other
implications of this scenario then
something which has been suggested is to
consider delayed acknowledgments which
is the role of this mechanism in this
kind of scenarios we need to analyze
whether we can benefit from this
mechanism in which way and I think that
especially in the context of the L week
working group this document we
understand that it should collect
experience from implementation and
deployment of TCP in constrained node
networks it would be great to know if
people have had experience if something
has been has been wrong what has
happened so what is working well what is
not and it would be great to be able to
collect this
of valuable information in this document
and also there is this overall common
about the approach of the document by
which probably we should be more
flexible and even possibly removing
maybe part or maybe even all of the RSC
2119 language so also we'd like to thank
a lot everyone for the great feedback we
have received from people in this
working group also in the core working
group and also in TCP and so thanks a
lot everyone yes thank you guys has cast
Bolin um that's all I think it's really
good thing to have a document like this
so I think it's good that this work has
been started I think that the document
could be a little bit more explicit with
respect to the situation that we often
have a very asymmetric situation yet I
mean it's not the links that are
asymmetric it's the implementations that
the twins are asymmetric so one question
for instance that comes up is is there
anything that a less constrained
implementation can do to help the
constraint implementation other example
on the MSS side the the constraint side
may know more about its fragmentation
properties and may for instance set the
NSS 250 and would be interesting to see
what happens in particular I'm in ipv6
um one DJ may be at the start of your
slides we often forget that there is
another IOT particle that is being used
on TCP which is xmpp yeah so we
shouldn't be forgetting that room um I
think that's all that in German okay so
I realize a cut line so and also make
your comment short thank you Alabama
inria aqueous customer I think it's very
interesting and required to work and i
was wondering like a couple of years ago
there was a draft about TCP header
compression i think it was into a
6lowpan group and i was wondering if you
have considered like you look at this
old draft or if you've considered some
other mechanism for header compression
well it is that if the tcp had a
compression document was let's see in
progress or alive probably this document
would report that i don't know if the
approach should be different i know that
there's this draft relatively yeah which
has been inactive for a while and i know
that there are people who are interested
in maybe reviving this kind of work so
then I don't know which should be
exactly the relationship between this
document on that document but yeah I
agree that having TCP header compression
would be absolutely beneficial and just
one small comment I don't know if you're
aware but there's ongoing work on a TCP
implementation in right so actually the
main author of discipline patience the
room so maybe that could be thank you
for you kill babies yeah that would be
great and if you have any kind of
feedback or who may just discuss this
kind of stuff will be helpful things
Carolyn I think this is great work too
um I had comment a question first my
understanding of RFC 2460 and this
remains in the best version is that
nodes this is not something we've talked
about a lot but it says that nodes have
to be able to assemble an MTU of 1500
octets after fragmentation so I just
wanted to point out that there may be
some constrained implementations that
actually support an empty of that size
so please don't limit yourself to 1280
you know keep that 1500 number in mind
my question was going to be about
running code I just heard the gentleman
from riot speak I would mention that
there's already TCP implementation in
kontiki I don't know if it could be
lightened up you know using this you
know using your technique
but you'd be really interesting to take
a look at that ya think hi my name is
Michael Scharf I'm speaking here is
share of TC p.m. but in general I think
that is an interesting document probably
this is the right working group to
document how to implement a subpoena
lightweight way and see value in doing
that I don't see any value in changing
the TCPS back in this working group here
you're invited if you see see a need to
change anything with beyond what the TCP
specifications low then I think this has
to be home in TC p.m. we are open to
such work but I think you should stay
within the limits of the TCP
specification which gives you a lot of
opportunities but you should please stay
within the limits and if you change the
protocol please come to TC p.m. yes
absolutely so I can't agree more ok
suresh krisshnan Eddie had so I'm
skipping the mic cutting so so like
specifically like slide 12 like doesn't
belong here so there's something you
need to do and as logistics right stuff
and slide 12 but for example right like
so it doesn't belong here so it needs to
go but as logistics point so if the
working group decides about this
document and we're going to get a
shepherd from like transport somewhere
so media here they promised to get us a
stripper from transport to get this true
so it gets the kind of review and one
more thing that would be nice to do is
like do frequent sing cups of tea CPM so
probably like every other meeting cycle
or something like go back to tease p.m.
show what's the stakes and if there's
anything open just keep the stuff sing
so we don't get a late surprise in the
iesg at the end nice car look no way
tonight tiny sauce thank you thank you
yeah we can discuss on minis yeah
next one will heat
thanks n so I have a lot of slides I
will try to go through them quickly this
was our trough documenting our
experiences with public key cryptography
on small devices so by small devices i
mean really small devices devices that
have 8-bit microprocessor and three to
five kilobytes of RAM we basically
wanted to see three things first what
kind of libraries are available for me
as a developer so what kind of trip to
libraries I can use second thing that we
wanted to see was how hard was was it to
actually use this library so what is it
the days of a day of work or or it
required more hacking and and the third
thing was what kind of performance we
can get with these libraries that that
already exist so for all my measurements
i use this Arduino mega bored which has
a 8-bit microprocessor so the first the
first thing that we did was use RSA and
no surprises there for a reasonable key
length the performance was pretty
undesirable and it was it was very slow
so if you look at a key size of 20 48
bits which is what you would assume or
probably even bigger the execution time
for for modular exponentiation and
signing with the private key was
actually pretty slope so then then we
looked at libraries that support
elliptic curve digital signature
algorithm bear with me for a couple of
slides and I'll explain why we were
focusing on ecdsa and not some of the
other other algorithms we found for
libraries that that support ecdsa for
small devices so relic my Chronicle
wisely when tiny CC there's also matrix
SSL and polar SSL but there are more
focused for 32-bit devices and we wanted
to run our code on 8-bit devices so so
we didn't get any numbers from from
those libraries ah this is a
off to give you overview of some of the
numbers that we measured I don't know if
all of you can read back there but the
important takeaway is that in less than
3 kilobytes of RAM you can actually do
signing operation in less than a second
and for one of the course which is Sir
curve you could actually do ecdsa
signing in in less than 300 milliseconds
so it was actually 261 milliseconds at
the library had actually implemented
some some mathematical optimizations
directly in assembly so this goes to
show that if you are really a persistent
enough you can get the numbers really
down some of the cookers there were
there on the previous slide are probably
not recommended anymore so something
like P 256 or crypto forum is now
specifying the edwards cup 255 19
something like that would be probably
more more sensible to you to use on this
all devices we found some numbers for
the same Arduino mega bored for signing
it was 1.4 seconds and for verification
it was two seconds which may not be
ideal in all scenarios but bear in mind
this was on a 8-bit processor so we had
the discussion in the ACE working group
about the lighting use case and it might
make sense to just use a 32-bit
processor because it's cheaper to
actually get them and in the lighting
use case you you don't actually have the
problem of energy harvesting or low
power supply you have all the power you
need so now I come to the slide why we
wanted to measure ecdsa in particular
and basically we wanted to see if we can
develop a full-fledged application where
a sensor device is not a co-op server
but a co-op client and basically it
sends signed updates to a proxy and this
proxy would then serve data on on behalf
of the sensor so the proxy registers the
resource to the resource directory and
the client any client that is interested
in the date data does a look-up on
well-known core gets the location of the
proxy and then then gets the signed
updates from the
so basically you do end-to-end data
authentication from from the sensor to
the client even though there is an
intermediary in between and we had the
same discussion yesterday in core or
this kind of object security is kind of
very helpful when you have
intermediaries in between so we
implemented the co-op client and all the
crypto stuff we did JSON web signatures
we represented the keys has JSON web
keys we implemented the proxy and the
resource directory on x86 machine and
I'll just show the important numbers is
like it was possible to do all of this
including sorry the network layer UDP
everything in less than five thousand
bytes of RAM so this goes to show that
if you really put some effort into it
you can get the numbers actually quite
quite minimal implementation so what we
learned from this is of course our
platform was unnecessarily restrictive
so normally you would choose something
like a 32-bit ARM processor or something
more powerful but our point was that if
you can do on such a small device of
course you can do it on 16-bit and
32-bit processors faster and as is now
well-known it actually costs you more to
turn on the radio and send and receive
messages than it costs you to do the
crypto so it would make sense to choose
the right platform that can do the
Crippler that is needed yeah there's no
good reason to choose platforms that
don't provide sufficient computing so
this was the implementation part so what
we implemented the whole application the
client and everything and then we have
the guidance part or so to say we
discuss some of the trade-offs and in
the in the draft we currently have
discussion about symmetric key vs
asymmetric key and of course a lot of
people have this belief that symmetric
key crypto doesn't scale which is
somehow a misconception because cellular
network authentication which is one of
the largest deployed cryptographic
security
deployments actually does use symmetric
keys however we don't believe that scale
should be the important deciding factor
it's actually what you want to do in
your application so if it's it might
make sense to do this asymmetric crypto
prescience at the beginning to do the
key exchange then derive a symmetric key
and use that however if there are
proxies and intermediaries or the
connection is very shortly so think of
if you are using a phone to open a door
lock you might actually want to use
something like data object security so
we have some discussion on trade-offs of
doing security at the different layers
of course link layer is good and useful
but it can be problematic because it's
it only protects the first hop and many
of them use group keys so if if the key
gets compromised you can have all sorts
of problems then we have IP 2nd Para the
network layer and our favorite TLS and
dtls at the at the transport layer and
they see they work fine as long as you
don't have middleboxes in between but if
you do have middleboxes in between
something like the application that we
did where you sign and send objects to a
proxy in between and and that ensures
end-to-end data authentication might be
actually useful and of course if you do
this you need erection communication
where the sensor only wakes up once in a
while and sends signed updates you need
to ensure that that there is freshness
so you need some some way of protecting
replay attacks and we have some
guidelines on how you can do that so of
course there is sequence numbers and
time stamps and if you have too long to
short sequence numbers they can wrap
around if you have too long sequence
numbers your packet size grows and how
you can get around that and even then if
if some entities get out of sync how you
can recover from that so we have some
text on on on basically how to ensure
freshness yeah so I went through it
quickly because I wanted to have time to
ask the group I think the authors
believe it's it's fairly stable
document it serves as a good data point
people are already using it and
referencing it if I have the up sorry do
you have a question please finish in
them yeah please go ahead ask the
question okay sorry juan carlos work
slow i haven't read that the draft so i
apologize no probably Thursday the the
it's very very useful information what
you have here what what kind of rate
interface were you using when you say
that you were comparing our processing
power and power consumption so for the
crypto stuff we were actually not
sending anything but for the real
application we use ethernet it was
purely Jesus alternate on the yeah yeah
internet on the kids are no radio or
over the earth day was yeah wired ya
thank ya so if it's okay with the chair
I would like to take a quick show of
hands of how many people have actually
read the draft your own dime a dozen
yeah yeah a thousand so then minute
takers please Frank Towson so let's take
click PO so seems that a big audience
has to read these droughts it's pretty
positive and I would like to ask i just
want to mention that I'm game ah tango
Indra and yeah I'm working on my thesis
would say the security of constraint
devices and i found the reference is
what you have been used in the
statistics as partisan so daft and the
presentation quite useful for my thesis
thanks ok so yeah i'll require ask so
how many of you have think that is
documenting useful and could be adopted
as a walking document ok whatever
doesn't close to 20 yeah so how many
think that
we cannot adopt this document no okay
cool yeah okay so yeah anyway we have
come back to the menu needs to confirm
this consciences okay good great thanks
thank you so the next one is Tobias
hello my name is Tobias I'm here because
Danielle can't be here and I'm working
with them on the minimal EST trust the
motivation for us on working on ipsec or
ESP is basically something like that if
you consider a lot of devices in a
infrastructure something like a house or
a university or whatever the current
status is you secure your device with
TTLs against a cloud and if you now add
like health centers you do the same
sorry Stefan tree yeah yeah so there are
a few problems with that there are a few
privacy issues because you always send
the IP address of the device you're
actually using so someone could track
you even could track your health sensor
and therefore could derive diseases or
whatever just because of addresses and
it's also difficult to manage like if
you're the owner of such a domain it's
very difficult to manage and to update
so what we are considering is using
IPSec to or ESP to step with something
what we call to main security so that
you secure device devices against the
Gateway and this gateway is secured is
ipsec are against the cloud or any other
VPN connection that makes it easier to
provide privacy because you don't
actually send the addresses anymore
through the internet
and also easier to manage to the
magnitude the owner of a domain you can
easily like update the security so we
believe that ESP or ipsec ESP
complements the toolbox of IOT towards
dtls enticed it has some significant
features to security IT first you can
provide the main security what i just
showed and it's also capable of to make
a multicast security you can secure any
transport layer you want and it avoids
like privacy issues but it just said
like if you or a specific application
apart it's also very flexible because
you're in the back not like dtls you're
independent of an key exchange you can
use any key exchange protocol you on the
obvious one is ike and we already have
minimal iq2 as an RC of this working
group but you can also use with like
radio key exchange protocol slagged x
which is very common in IOT devices in
the moment there is a RFC for multicast
key exchange and you can use it with any
other of you can even set up it manually
to establish the keys the goal of
minimal ESP is to provide guidelines for
an implementer to remain fully I could
be comfortable to the RFC how to build
the truck how to build the ESP fields
without a lot of computation and also
which ciphers should be implemented this
is already part of a working document in
the IP second d which points out some
IOT specific ciphers so in the next
version of minimal ESP we would probably
at over now a reference to this RFC once
it comes out how to read it so the basic
idea is how to implement ESP with
guidelines for the app developer just to
show you the basic idea that's the ESP
packet you have the sequence number to
identify
the security Association on the endpoint
so on the point which receives two
encrypted packet if a sequence number
and in your payload which is headed to
the IP alignment with the pad lengths
and the next terror which points to the
for example UDP packet in the payload
and then we have an integrity check so
what we want to say in minimal ESP how
to use this fields as a developer for
example for SBI you could use IP
addresses for the sequence number you
can accept and it's you know instead of
using a counter you can for example use
the time because the only requirement is
that it's increasing all the time to
avoid padding we have some
recommendations on that and yeah so now
our belief ipsec ESP is a valuable
valuable option for IOT 6 low working
group on Monday agreed that is PS a--
it's good to have in the IOT toolbox
ipsec working group just broke down the
field raft for example implicit i leave
was just adopted as the IP second to
develop you second me working group that
you don't have to send an implicit IV
for counter ciphers and like the one I
mentioned decipher supports yeah for
specific IOT requirements and we already
have minimal iq2 so we think that we
should have an ESP minimal ESP also in
the working group thank you so there's
Krishnan so have you gotten any comments
on this current draft from any security
people like specifically ipsec new
people yes for example taro is involved
and like the chair of five second years
involves int espero con ESP okay Brian
are you gonna volunteer to review he'll
be awesome
yes I have to cut a line right now yeah
Brian wise i did just briefly look at it
but I can do overview it looks like you
haven't actually cut any bites out it
may seem minimal it's really about the
methods of getting filling the various
values you're making it easier for the
constraint device yes there is no
compression involved that's why we are
here in Elba it's compression is another
draft but that is just to implement to
give implementer a guideline on how to
implement IPC EST nice to compress it
diced why didn't mention is opposed like
be too which really did like me to know
magraph did really actually try and
reduce some of payloads and such yes any
more likely to was actually the
motivation of me okay sounds good so I'm
the wooden group does about this like
I'll figure out like how to get some
more like Brian volunteer to do one I'll
also talk to the Securities to figure
out how to get more review on this sure
Norris related to this is that because I
see also have to travel related to the
ESP in the six low walking group what's
relationship is to document we stick
with the doc weenie just prison here the
once in six low are going to compress
ESP or the payload this one is just an
implementation implementation guide on
how to minimal implement ESP without
going out of the borders of ESP so well
exactly that's a name that Danny amigo
one of the co-author Erickson so the
main difference between the diet and
this one is that with this
implementation we allow a very small
implementation that is interoperable
with the existing deployment okay so is
there any open source support on this or
any code available online we implemented
it on configuring on Kentucky okay you
contribute that or me it was actually
kind of started to develop on from
someone in Sweden I think he and another
Kentucky I know I know that ESP it's
already implemented in Kentucky and
that's open source
okay great any more comments on them so
I'd like to ask how many people had read
a draft and some five six so uh so how
many is honestly yeah we can ask because
uh since that audience is now you know
who has redraw releasing ask Connor is
talking yeah the ad suggest we confirm
the contents on the list and hopefully
we can get some views from security
people okay great thank you thank you
okay we come to our last item on the
agenda which is from Causton so who in
this room knows what RFC 7228 s okay
good so the this has been out for three
years on and the question came up is it
may be time for an update after two
years this may be a little bit
surprising but turned out that the draft
actually was the RFC actually was quite
useful and there are two things that
that could have happened whether the
word has moved since of course so is
there may be something new that we want
to take account of like the other one is
that we might simply find that there is
terminology missing we've run into
terminology every day that is not
clearly defined where we have different
words for the same thing or the same
word for different things so it might be
an idea to update the raft pizzette so
even that it's probably going to take a
year or two to do this the next version
what we maybe 2017
2018 so it's not that bad so let's talk
about two areas of potential work one is
terminology for platforms so most people
know seven to twenty 84 + 0 + 1 + 2 +
and one thing we noticed is that people
have big trouble distinguishing big
computers from small computers big
computers are sometimes also very small
they're called fast berry pies and so on
so we probably need some terminology
that distinguishes between the
microcontrollers that 7228 really is
about and the big computers the
computers that run linux and which also
may be pretty small in the end but they
have quite different characteristics so
in the software update workshop we seem
to pick up the antenna terminology on
this so with an arm you know they have
these contexts a processors and their
context n processors and we started
talking about a class in m-class devices
and of course every tricky knows that we
are living on an m-class planet so this
is very good and we can now decide
whether maybe according this to this
terminology the big processor should be
j-class processors but ok so this is one
one point where we definitely need
additional feminine we also have found
that the two classes the two useful
classes last one in class we identified
sometimes artoo cause sometimes there's
maybe a use for a class 3 or class 4 so
for instance that would be useful to
identify a class that actually is
powerful enough to run something like
JavaScript by name you might want to
introduce subclasses so this this might
be another place where it might be used
for to do some graph then we have
discussed crypto capabilities so simple
things like we had access to an Aes
accelerator may be interesting odd we
have a yes instructions in this video
I'm not quite clear what that could be
but maybe it's worth looking at
different platforms and trying to
classify them in the capabilities
finally we are seeing more and more
micro controller class platforms that
actually do have some protection
capabilities memory protection units
memory mapping units even some have city
you'll flags like cannabis users we have
trust zone or secure element elements we
have 10 / proof capabilities in very
many platforms because people just don't
don't want their source code truly their
limitation code to leak out and so on so
maybe it's worth looking at those
probabilities and defining classes for
that we have a Java code and now me you
have record do you want me to fight to
you finish their presentation or not
really okay brain so we are also in ace
having problems defining clock
capabilities of the devices some don't
have time awareness at all so fresh a
token validation cannot be done the way
you do normal you out so you need
non-space methods some devices have
relative time capabilities and some
devices might be clogged or synchronized
so to express the problems we are facing
we also need maybe on a document like
this I a clear definition of the
capabilities of the note that's a very
good point actually ran into the same
problem already we could maybe talk
about power constraints some more so we
have some basic general terminology in
there I'm not sure how successful that
terminology has been I'm not hearing it
in everyday exchange but that may be
just because people another way of it
and maybe we also can look at these
sustainable power and energy total
parameters and maybe build something
like classes so we all know that there
is a watch class I OGE and a micro wat
class IOT and they are very different in
many aspects finally we could look at
terminal e front terminology from
networks some more so I found out that
we often have difficulty grasping the
different mpu properties of networks in
particular with AP when coming in we
have network to it with ridiculous and
key youth and sure so we should have
classes of ridiculousness hear something
like that also maybe the fact that these
have sustainable bit rates in the
military or second range also gives rise
to some classes we have new kinds of
asymmetry sewn in LP when we often have
very powerful base stations that talk to
two very simple battery operated devices
and this is a bit different from the
sixth floor plan case where mostly all
devices are of the same capability level
and finally I think the mobility
question that we managed to ignore and
in 60 for 10 years might also come come
in young in some form so as you can see
that there are a number of areas where
we could start defining things and I
already have one volunteer fall for the
the clock or time-based issue where
which has already done some work at so I
know that she is interested in this and
what I really would like to assemble is
a group of people who would like to
contribute to that so I will be pushing
out a draft blah blah blah 73 72 28 bits
and then i will stop collecting
it is Carrie Lynn yeah Karsten I agree
with your initial comment that this has
been extremely useful because I remember
in the early days of discussions you
know people were thinking that raspberry
pi was a constrained device and you know
of course to us it's a super computer
but just to follow up on your point
about memory consumption an example of
the world changing would be if somebody
has perfected a small fuel cell you know
the size of a watch battery and those
things where's law is not going to save
as here somebody has already made you
know the point in one of the earlier
conversations that there's no reason not
to pick a cpu that's capable of doing
the work you need unless you're powered
by battery so i think i agree with you
maybe the point is is that there's not
enough awareness of the power constraint
and i plug on electrical power not to
keep our be good if the next version
could take them yeah so do different
specific classes in line for a little
bit early yeah we had the Lions card
yeah please contain Christian gross
cannot support the work on this also
note there's already worker on going on
coop working group on the transport
negotiation they're proposing to extend
this around transport availability so
much no Chet into the draft this is
Sunday mean overall for mighty low and
agree with you about the problem we have
enough you want to describe the new
constraint of these networks then I can
work with you describe these because we
have a new scale then we are sending
packets per day and not per second right
that's the millage in year when you're
bajillion ram I fully support this work
I think Marcy 7228 was already very
useful and refrigerant could be uh well
could extend this usefulness however I
think that we you know if we want this
talking to be really useful we there's a
trade-off between you know describing
like so many classes and
I things I mean obviously extreme cases
like one class per device right so we
don't want to get there so um I think
there should be two phases in the club
in this document really first like we
kind of assessing okay what has changed
in and then you know try to reduce the
number of classes to the maximum somehow
is it straight up yes also one outcome
for instance might be if rent was doing
a lot of work we might have a second
drop that just discusses this like we
already have a draft for crypto or N and
so on his old and very open to removing
things between get so yes 80 comments
Cecil are no ID had so just just an
industry description as an individual
I'm just wondering right like if RFC is
the right format for this right like
since it's something that's like
evolving pretty quickly I would say
right like so 7228 is like like if you
look at the number its too young to be
obsoleted right and and I'm just
thinking like so this like a couple of
ways of doing this like one of them is
like probably like some kind of Vicky
somebody maintains another one is like
probably keep it as a draft right like
keep it as a working group graph for a
bit and give it some time maybe like a
year or two like just hold onto it and
then do it like I i just want like the
wasn't really think about that as well
yes so not my quick answer to this would
be a terminology is most useful when we
have consensus on it so this is really a
place where Ricky is not sufficient you
two need some to build something senses
but but keeping the draft active for
some while and then collecting things
they're competing with yeah probably
style would still don't have the draft
yet we have been waiting for bated haha
yes I think it is a place to call for
contribution for the people who were
increasing this and we can discuss over
the list so Carson like so you can still
do a consensus call without a draft
right like so you can see if there's
like eruption consensus and then Carson
can post 7228 as Miss 00 and then you
can continue working on it so don't let
that stop you from right going to
that you cannot see RFC and as a working
group lecture no I'm not kidding Gary
that's between done before just do it
okay thank you okay thank you yeah
everything ends the pre