you ready this is the man a working
group are gonna get going here yeah
right thanks Rick it seems we already
have a minute taker so thank you for
that we're passing the blue sheets
around please sign it we could use the
signatures of course the note well you
guys have seen this in every
presentation if you have IPR you need to
bring it forward or let people know when
you're participating and you're making
comments please use the microphone and
state your name try to state it clearly
as we have a new minute taker this
meeting and getting the names right
might be more difficult than normal
here's the agenda we have three
presentations today along with an
overview and then we have an open mic at
the end if anyone wants to talk about
other issues or other other things that
we're not going over does anyone have
anything to say about the agenda is so
working group overview we have not met
at the last two ITF this is the first
one we've had in a while we've had some
interim meetings we were we were on the
we were put they put to task to finish
up the documents that we had and get
them out we're very close to doing that
I'm not going to go over the whole issue
and the whole happenstance with a odv
be to that happened if you'd like to
talk to me after this I'm more than
happy to talk to anybody who wants to
talk about that we have deal app is
moving forward they're still comments
going on on the list that's still an ad
review ad review hopefully we'll get
that cleared out relatively soon the
other one is on my plate is OS r seck
threats the information one we had a
last call we didn't have really any
comments on that so I'm going to take it
upon myself to do a thorough review and
either write up the Shepherd document or
not I don't think it'll be a big deal
but I do owe them at least a thorough
review of that um the rest are
proceeding nicely and the only other
document that is kind of in limbo right
now is the OLS our multipath document
there's been a lot of discussion between
the author and Christie R love who's had
a lot of really nice comments on the
draft it would be nice to have more eyes
on that draft it had passed last call
Chris got in some very pertinent
comments right after that so we pulled
it back we did it again and it's still
kind of in limbo they're working out the
details and until they kind of agree and
I agree with them or Stan agrees with
them it's going to sit where it's at so
please read that draft and get comments
back I think it is a useful thing to
have if we do it right I don't want to
break things when we do it that's the
main thing for me we did get to two rfcs
since the last time we met or actually
since this year I debased signatures
that's been in limbo and is G for a long
long long time they finally got it
through and the dap metric for all srb2
past
so on to the next anyone have any
comments or questions about the status
we we missed a slide on our current
milestones and deliverables so I don't
have a slide on that right now i can
i'll try to pull it up at the end we do
have some milestones coming up and
they're relatively tight schedule they
include many management and kind of how
we deploy mayonnaise lots of people have
been asking for that outside of a
working group and we've had two attempts
at that before and they kind of missed
the mark on either end either too
generic or too specific so we want
something kind of in the middle so
authors of those two documents i would
encourage you to try to come together
and work on that i see one of them james
here hopefully oricon and thomas are
interested in working on that again but
others are welcome as well and the other
ones are dlf extensions olsr maintenance
or other extensions 20 srb2 and the man
a fib man a multicast fib which I'm
going to give a presentation on and I
need more people participating in that
and hopefully this will help facilitate
some discussions on how we restructure
this so the next one
okay so we are as a song we are tasked
with designing a forwarding information
base for multicast in mayonnaise so I'm
going to be presenting a little bit
about what we've learned at NRL with our
implementation of SMF and our
implementation of elastic multicast
which Brian presented a few I TFS back
kind of the structure of our code
because in the next slide and kind of
what we've learned in what's missing in
the current SMF draft and how we can
capture it in another draft and separate
things out a little bit better so real
quick background SMF is a simplified
multicast forwarding protocol and
experimental and the man a working group
it does man a wide broadcasts it doesn't
allow you to limit where the broadcast
goes it goes all the way through the man
a network they uses CDSs connected
dominating sets much like olsr and other
many routing protocols it devotes a lot
of the text in there to duplicate packet
detection and at the time we didn't know
what worked and what didn't it has both
hash based and I debased mechanisms and
we found through practice that it
depends on your network your traffic
your device is what you want to use so
we're kind of leaning right now to
leaving them both in there as optional
because there are some networks you want
to use hash and there's some that you
want to use ID it really depends on what
kind of network you're using with hash
certain traffic patterns will give you a
lot of false positives and you'll end up
dropping a lot of packets that you
otherwise would want similarly with hash
you can end up draining your batteries
when your mobile device was really fast
alternatively packet IDs is a big
security hole if you change that ID to
you know somewhere in the future and
then all the other packets get dropped
because they're in the past way past and
nothing gets through
to this crab attract do the two options
interoperate are there negotiated or are
they statically configured I actually
have a slide on that they're statically
configured right now and they they do
interoperate to some extent their
caveats in that if you're doing
duplicate packet detection with the IDS
the nodes that are injecting multicast
into the man a viet gateway andrey
forwarding and rebroadcasting their
sequence IDs or if their sources in the
men a they need to sequence the IDs
otherwise they're going to get dropped
by the nodes that are going to do the ID
based forwarding because they won't have
an ID but otherwise if those injection
points are taken care of then everything
would work and there is some merit to
doing kind of a hybrid where you mark
the package with an ID to give it a
different hash so you kind of get both
but you also get the drawbacks of both
and it's they're not intended to scale a
large networks because you're flooding
the entire network so you really don't
want to use this in 600 nodes thousand
node networks it would be very
inefficient some of the drawbacks of the
SMF design is the design kind of munge
is the algorithmic control and what's
actually being forwarded so with that
munching we get at deployment and an
implementation that is in user space and
performance suffers because of that when
you're scraping all the packets up in
the user space and then sending them
back down so we want a better design
where we have a forwarding bit that all
the rules are clearly defined and how to
control it is clearly defined so that we
can push that part down and keep the
control up in user space but have the
forwarding take place more in the kernel
space design-wise we want to design it
that way so it people can implement it
that way easily packets right now are
disseminated like I said to the entire
MANET that's fine for small networks
where everyone wants to hear all the
multicast traffic but in large networks
that's really not good so there's also
no
group membership you don't know if your
man a wants a specific multicast address
or not if anyone's listening or not you
just flood it there's no rules for
different multicast addresses and that's
an issue that we should address CTS
algorithms currently the algorithms in
the appendix of the SMS draft are only
nominal algorithms there are others that
could be developed but the ones that are
there do not support multiple interfaces
well they're either on or off in terms
of forwarding and flooding there are
other algorithms out there that can do
multiple interfaces a lot better but the
algorithms we define have not and we
should define the 40 information base to
support better control Rick Tyler um
have you looked at using broadcast
wallace links so using the broadcast
facility of the lower layer to assist
the multicast as part of the SMS work
not quite sure I understand your
question okay so if you've got a radio
system which has a effectively a
shoutcast channel on there so the
ability to beacon out to all receivers
that are listening integrating that
within your larger multicast topology so
and the one packet effectively costs the
same whether it goes to one endpoint or
all of them right OH flooding suddenly
actually becomes a cheap option I wonder
whether you've looked at integrating
that into any of the SMF stuff so far we
generally use the multicast on a radio
if it has that we like would send it out
to all of them here if you have
different interfaces I gave a
presentation a while back on how if you
have multiple interfaces it may be
redundant to send it back out the same
interface it came in on because it might
be a wired link and everyone already got
the packet on that it could be a
directional antenna a point-to-point
link and I don't want to send a packet
back out on that interface because it's
going to a guy who already hasn't he
send it to me the current algorithms
don't allow you to do that right so
there are other algorithms and very
simple ones
says you know if everyone if you have
only one neighbor on that link don't
send it back out there you could reduce
it but there's no algorithms it's not
designed with that in mind okay so we
should design the FIB affording
information base with interfaces in mind
and actually our SMF code has evolved in
that direction so that we can do inner /
interface forwarding based upon what pre
interface is coming in on and some other
stuff Brian uh my colleague who's co-op
whose main author of NRL SMF would
disagree with me on this last bit that
fording rules are not well defined with
multiple interfaces and my point here is
that in the SMF draft there's a lot of
text dedicated to gateways how to ricci
quence and forward over these interfaces
but there's not a lot of text regarding
algorithmic control of what gets
forwarded where based upon what
interface is coming in on and then to go
out on and that's kind of what I'm
talking about here and duplicitous one
is talked about on how to do it put then
various algorithms you're going to want
dpd to work either on the incoming
interface or on outgoing interfaces or
both depending on how your forwarding
the traffic sometimes you want to do it
on the outgoing interface because node a
wants it to go somewhere but this guy
over here wants you to go somewhere else
so you it's this even though it's the
same packet you wanted to go out a
different interface even though the
first guy didn't want it to go next this
is just a quick overview of our NRL SMF
and what it does it's open source it's
at PF dub and RL Navy dot mil if you
want to get the source code you can talk
to me it works with NRL NH DP it works
with ospf MDR algorithms and we have
that code as well and it works with our
olsr v1 implementation RV two
implementations not open source yet
just some process alone getting it open
it has a remote control interface that
we've defined it that that interface is
not defined in the SMF draft because the
draft just says either flood or not you
use these algorithms or not SMF is one
big happy thing well we separated that
out the algorithmic control is in the
routing protocols or the neighbor
discovery protocol and sm f is the
forwarding engine the forwarding bit and
it has we have a very simple api to
control it we want to expand on that
because there's more things that the
forwarding engine can do that we're not
opening up the api to do we know what we
want but we haven't defined that api yet
it's still the very simple because the
algorithms don't define those well it's
still very simple yes you forward on all
interfaces no you don't next slide so
this is a current SMF architecture and
one thing to note here is the SMF
interfaces on the left it can take in
from multiple different interfaces so
you can have multiple physical
interfaces and have them map to a single
SMF interface that then does duplicate
package detection it puts it out on
various SMF interfaces that are also
mapped to physical interfaces so that it
can reef or word on a set a subset or
all of the interfaces that you're
running on and you can have different
rules associated with those outbound
interfaces so you can do things like
Ricci Qin stew yeah ID next slide so
this is a conceptual slide again
illustrating that we want to separate
out the control from the forwarding and
there's another little bit here and that
the 14 information base should be a
conceptual design on what the fording
engine uses it's not it should be it
should be kind of like a table and NH DP
that it defines the table and how things
operate but
it's not necessarily a physical thing
and it might be represented in the 40
engine in some other way we have an
arrow going back to the control plane
and that is for our work in elastic
multicast we needed feedback on what new
packets were coming into the network and
what to do with them because if you're
going to do group based stuff you need
to know what's happening in your network
and if you want to forward that packet
or not it's into more detail in a second
next slide so this is our current design
you have n HTTP or another control
algorithm up at the top you have your SF
s MF management nib and the mid is kind
of in pieces as well because some of it
controls the algorithm and that goes
over to na GP and some of it controls
what's happening with your duplicate
pocket detection and re sequencing on
interfaces and that sort of thing and
that goes down to your SMF instance down
at the bottom so the SMF mibbe is kind
of talking to both pieces because of how
the SMF was designed i'm julia scrubber
check again I'm sorry I had a moment of
inattention so perhaps you've mentioned
it are you describing the architecture
or something that has been implemented
or is that your plan for something that
this is this has been implemented this
has been in place we've implemented this
and the code is available the code is
available and we actually are we have
some limited amount of the SMF
management mid available as well James
would have more information on that but
we did we did do some of the mid design
as well and I say undefined algorithmic
control here even though we have our own
API that talks it uses depending on your
system it uses different methods of
talking from one instance to another of
two different damon's running but it's
undefined in terms of the documents
we've defined an API that allows you to
control the SMF it's not as rich as we'd
like we'd like to expand that a little
bit more to go to the next slide
so we we want it to to change to
something more like this where there's a
richer amount of filters and state in
SMF that you're going to control
affording information base you're going
to control on this standardized fording
information base API that would control
what's happening in the last slide I
said it was undefined we defined one but
it's not specified anywhere and that's
what we want to work on Rick Taylor
again paypal and this is more of a
question to the chairs Leno you're one
of the chairs enter Alvaro is working on
an API a suitable thing for the working
group to be working on I understand
working on that the conceptual fib
definition very useful and then as part
of describing the phpbb you could go
into detail about well updates in these
ways are are useful you're starting to
drift off internet comfy yang II oh I
want to update an information base realm
or we're getting into well i'm using
unix domain sockets and this is what my
capi looks like and i'm not quite sure
whether this is that work specifically
it's good for should be done in the
working group fib yeah absolutely sounds
great API I'm uncertain I'm looking to
the chairs and over over for this i
agree with you somewhat at a at a very
minimum we're going to have to just
define what is allowed and not allowed
yeah in the same way you find in NH TP
is what you can and can't add externally
to it so we might not you know say
specifically what the messages look like
and how they're getting past but how it
can be changed to point in a strong
direction on an API that could be
written to do these things okay that's
reasonable Julie scrub a track there's a
lack of a key is in that space so
whether it happens within the work and
growth or no doesn't matter but working
the nike eyes is a good thing
next time this is just a quick overview
of elastic multi-gas and I'm presenting
this here because this is driving a lot
of our work at terms of what we've
learned about what we need in the
forwarding information base a quick
recap on elastic multicast it its uses
SMF to broadcast out all the multicast
traffic SMF informs a controller when
new flows are happening the controller
will then send out acts to see who wants
this if anyone wants this and if no one
wants it it ends up turning off that
flow so it will reduce the amount of
flooding happening in your network and
it's a very simple method of doing it it
uses multicast joins and acts to see
who's joined and then it kind of it and
it also takes into account very dynamics
so if your network is very dynamic it
won't slow things down as much and it
will let it flood around more brian has
more on that in the previous
presentations the main thing here is
that there's feedback and there's
dynamic expansion and contraction of the
multicast trees and meshes that are
being built another key thing is that
its flow based and I'll get to that in a
minute next again just illustrating that
for elastic multicast to work and other
algorithms one that it's not a multicast
algorithm but it is an algorithm is
reactive protocols need to know when a
packet is going out and there's no
destination so they inform up higher so
something like this could work for a
unicast routing protocol or be used by
it the feedback feature is kind of
important and the flow I'm going to get
what i mean by flow in a minute so what
do I mean by flow generally in SMF we
don't care about addresses it's a multi
gas okay do we flood yes or no that's
really simple it's too simple and it's
not efficient
so in our SMF implementation we have an
idea of a flow and a flow and contains a
destination source or protocol and
nominally an incoming interface so you
can categorize a packet based upon this
flow and that's kind of how it's how
it's being routed is based upon its flow
ID and its flow isn't going to really
change and we're still working on we
have some we have this working there are
other ways to make this work as well it
can get really complicated you can have
a default way of say if it's multicast I
flooded out on my interfaces I inform
higher up and then if it's a if it's a
specific multicast I know no one's
interested in I drop it because it
matches that source destination and I
know that no one's interested in that
flow so I dress drop it next so what do
we do what do we do with the flow do we
just Ford it or drop it well we found
that we don't just forward it or drop it
there are actually other things we want
to do and our implementation right now
has you either forward it you can
forward it with a limited rate so we
have a cue that limits how many packets
can go out at a certain rate that gives
you a priority basically priority or you
can reduce the amount of flow you get
more control we have a hybrid I don't
like the name of that but hybrid what
that does is it sends out a fixed number
of packets for upper flow and then it
shuts it down and what that allows it to
do is it goes throughout the network
everyone gets the packet they can do
their protocol mechanisms that they need
to do and they either inform or not
inform to allow a lasting multicast to
shut it down or not so a hybrid kind of
lets it go for a little bit and then
shuts it off with nothing else is said
and then we can we can drop it and then
some other ones we've been playing
around with are we can queue it up for
something like a ODB you can queue up a
packet and wait first fixed amount of
time and then drop it or you can send an
air
just to like no route those are ideas
again stressing that the the the
forwarding information base should not
just be a unidirectional flow of
information the foreign information base
should send stuff back up to the
controller based upon the flow and
what's happening next and as I kind of
hinted at it should we should we design
this with only multicast in mind is it
useful for other things are we getting
too deep do we just scope this and not
worry about it or can we design it with
other other multi-man 8 protocols in
mind and not specify you know they're
used specifically Rick Taylor again um I
spent the last two days basically what a
lot of the neck top net mod stuff for
completely unrelated reasons I'm really
liking the way you're going with this
fib stuff I like the idea of a
generalized conceptual data model that
that can be extended out beyond just
multicast perhaps I not sure how far
that's going to go but I'm very
conscious of what's happening in I to RS
where they're trying to maintain these
ephemeral models of things that are
happening and using the net comm
protocols to apply controlled atomic
transactional updates to these and
there's a lot of work going on in there
about managing this ephemera bellucci
ephemeral routing state and I'm just
wondering whether have you spoken to
those guys about it we have not Susan
hairs lovely knows a great deal and we
definitely need to integrate I think we
should be interfacing with them rather
than inventing our own little bespoke
solution and discovering that the big
system integrators because money is
always exists within a bigger picture
that there at the edge but there's the
rest of the system in there and if we
can use the same tooling this is moving
on from the mid conversation so this
cross over to the management discussion
is I think we should be looking at some
of the stuff that I to RS are doing with
net conf to solve a similar but
different problem
a letter to thought I Cisco completely
brick one of things that you may want to
do faster rather than slower is yes who
has been working with the net mod guys
quite a bit they're still I think
something lost in translation there for
them to understand the requirements from
a router for example so if you can come
up with requirements an ideal what is
really needed from them right then
that's something that not only we can
reuse whatever hrs is trying to get out
of that mod or we can help I tore us
water than tomorrow right so in other
words that's far from the fine whatever
HR yeah yeah and and and this
presentation is I mean it's coming from
our experience working with SMF and how
our protocol suite has evolved and we're
current trying to capture that in a way
that is more useful than just a one-off
implementation is it time for general
questions you about this yes I'm I
believe that was my last slide okay oh
this was just a slide showing that we're
looking at real code in kernels that are
and how we can modify them to get some
kind of forwarding engine in them in an
easy way that was all that was the last
night yes open open for questions
comments well my first question is let's
say you had several multicast groups
would you expect to have a different
instance of this for each multicast
group yeah you would have different 14
based upon the flow and their flows
being different groups would be
different so you'd have different rules
based upon their very low for different
group memberships yes you different
group memberships
the group membership part is part of the
control algorithm that's going to
control what groups get forwarded or not
but in terms of the forwarding base it's
just another identifier on a flow it's a
multicast address the group address so
yeah you could you could flood certain
group addresses you can send other group
addresses out a different interface you
can have different rules based upon that
the group address but we we consider
them just it the group address is just
one key part of a flow identifier right
but the dirt mean there could be some
columbia i'm not sure but maybe some
danger let's say you had 500 nodes or a
thousand nodes in the network and there
were three of them were scattered you
know to get to be part of a multicast
group then the total amount of control
signaling to find them somehow could
even be worse than just flooding I don't
know depending on the mobility and
besides that well for instance I'd the
original motivation for SMF I think to a
large degree was because flooding is so
inefficient and NPR's and cdss can
reduce the amount of control traffic by
upwards of sixty percent you know for
those those networks right so to give
you a quick overview real quick the last
multicast work we did worked exactly how
you're saying a use of CD s it uses a
default SMF algorithm it gets sent out
it would use the hybrid method of 14 out
the packet so they would get sent out
then the controllers would would be told
hey we got this multicast packet what do
you want to do and they would send out
messages the control would send out
extra messages using n HTTP and other
messages to say does anyone want this
stuff or you want to join this group and
if no one said yes they would turn that
flow off they would turn that group off
and as people said yes they would keep
it on they would add a rules to do it
instead of a hybrid approach they would
do the CD s flooding so at worst case it
would work the same as CD s flooding
best case it would prune off everything
and it would it wouldn't flood at all
can can I ask at this point that we were
over time so can we then pick this up
after the meaning or take to the list
yeah that's fine let me just make one
more sentence which is that you know if
it turns out that managing a lot of
group memberships is complicated it
would still be nice to put into effect
what you've got just for the basic
flooding operations as though you might
say a first step that's almost universal
there's there there is a draft elastic
multicast at brian has written and it's
out there you can read that on we
decided to step back to build it in the
right way instead of just moving forward
with it okay so okay well while we're
transitioning to the next presentation I
want to ask where is the blue sheet and
are there people who haven't signed the
blue sheet there are lots of folks that
haven't signed it do we know where it's
at I'm wait then we started again doing
something okay so I wanted to give a
quick update on Dale up status as a seat
it was quick as we said earlier dilip is
in ad review the ad did come back with
comments we've addressed those comments
and posted a a deal up 23 yesterday day
before one of the two the biggest change
was to use RFC 5082 or is it 5802 I
forget which it's a GTS n on the team on
the TCP session there's some discussion
about that going on on the man a list
right now and we will follow up with
that discussion I'd like to follow up
with our discussion before we give it
back to the ad
okay so that's where we're at their the
other the other issue is that we we had
disallowed some data items on
destination announced response and an
item was brought to the list that we
should allow the same data items on
destination announce response that we
allow on like desktop and that's been
changed as well so next slide please and
in terms of the credit extension it's
also an ad review the ad came back with
comments they have not been fully
addressed yet so it has not been
resubmitted to the ad the biggest issue
revolves around credit window
synchronization and that's work in
progress so next slide please the other
thing I wanted to talk about was an
extension that's not yet been submitted
to the working group the one that were
chartered for we had talked for a couple
of I ETFs now about deal up extensions
for metrics by traffic class are
essentially metrics by dscp code point
I've got that I'm writing that it's not
ready to post yet expect the draft 00
draft it's in the next couple of weeks
and once we get that posted we can talk
about it on the list to make the
necessary changes and try to drive for
first thing would be accepting it as a
working group document and then we'll go
forward but the work is in work is in
process and I think that's all I've got
on d lab so but I see people running to
the microphone so Rick Taylor can I just
say I have a couple of personal drafts
for other deal app extensions that once
deal app is finally rubber-stamped I
will revisit they've currently expired I
want to bring them back to the working
group and ask for adoption for them just
as a heads up okay since we're reach our
turd for day life extensions that would
be fantastic
lubra or 2 comments so metrics bike
traffic class sounds interesting I'd be
I'll be interested to see how you manage
the mapping of traffic classes to cues
and because usually it's the cues that
have the metrics not necessarily traffic
classes because you have multiple
traffic classes mapping the same cues so
that'll be interesting and have you
thought about credit by traffic class or
bike you uh let's see have I thought
about it no does it sound interesting
yes okay I've seen some some folks I'm
working with have a couple of thoughts
on that topic as well as some other
extensions so I would expect them to
come in also between now in the next
IETF and maybe they'll line up nicely
and we can just collapse them yeah that
would be fantastic Thanks ok any other
questions on delay wait wait one of the
authors has a question under yeah this
is it haha it's Rick Taylor again it's
not a dealer question it's a process
question following on from lose comment
that he and some of his guys he's
working with also have some extensions
I'm not sure how familiar people are
with the inner workings of Dean up of
course you've all read all the drafts
because you've come come to the working
group the extension mechanism is within
deal appears both parties announced the
extensions they support as part of the
negotiation at session initialization
does the working group one an extension
per document the draft or are you happy
to work on a draft which says and this
draft introduces three new extensions
that each may be independently and
provided by an implementation how do you
want this managed I from from my
perspective and I haven't I haven't
looked back at my chair you you hit me
cold with this but it just came to me
after Lou said he's got three up his
sleeves like it's whatever makes sense i
mean i could see a document
please hi Lou burger my experience is
having a independently implemented thing
per document really helps when when when
users and vendors are trying to
understand what it is that they're
actually delivering or requesting in an
RFP that doesn't care if it's going to
be delivered as a set sure do it in the
same document but call it one extension
that that's a fair point if you're gonna
have multiple extensions um yeah i agree
with you or or if they're all required
together you know if you have three
extensions but our implementation is
required and to implement all of them
sure but if they're going to implement
only one of three separate just as Rick
Taylor again just as a follow on from
that I understood I want to avoid having
optional optional things again so i said
i have one document with three
extensions which kind of go hand in hand
but actually i'm only supporting one of
them out of the such a set of three so i
think a little bit of care needs to be
taken with this I like the Julia
scrubber check I'd like to pull in the
other direction I like big documents
that have a single introduction and you
understand what you're reading and
there's an order and as you are
implementing you get all the background
in a single document rather than chasing
pointers between hundreds of documents
and so I would like to encourage the
group I know it's more difficult for the
group and it's more difficult for the
editors but I would like to encourage
the group to make big documents list of
contacts and few of them I I think I as
I interpret the point blue made its that
as a vendor it's hard to go to your
customers and say I support sections 38
and 17 of RFC 8989 right yes that's not
really a good deal but it's not a good
idea so if you're going to write the
document you either support what's in it
or you don't so it lends credence to the
idea from a functional perspective get
it down to something that's bountiful
and quantifiable and then publish that
and you need to publish multiple
documents if you're doing multiple
things
he's absolutely right and I'm right too
and he has he's pulling in the direction
that's convenient for the vendor I'm
pulling in the direction that's
convenient for the implementer you're
probably pooling in the direction that's
convenient for the chair and we'll end
up at the point that suits everyone or
nobody a nanny for watching we'll pull
it apart once again was a poor attempt
at humor blue burger I'm pulling in the
direction of the user yeah not of not of
the vendor I actually care more about
from the user who says I want RFC XYZ
because I want function that's very
function so when I specify an RFC I
don't have I don't know if there's too
many options I don't know what I'm going
to get and what's really cool is if you
have enough options and I've personally
been involved with a spec that failed
this way if you have too many options
you can get to vendors that say they
implement the same RFC and they don't
interoperate or deliver the same thing
that we're not doing our job if we do
that that's that's the real issue Rick
Taylor again just take you up on Judas's
first point which was I like a big
document because I like all the intro
stuff in one place it is in one place
it's called dealer I we're talking about
extensions to a core document that
describes what it is how you do it
what's the minimal you must support so i
think we've kind of satisfied that
requirement the rest are really
appendices published after the date for
loose reasons which I do agree with and
john diet lied I'd like to speak from
the point of view the poor people who
have to specify what it is that they're
buying because I don't think I've ever
seen a product listed with the sponsor a
section of an RFC it's a the neuro say
or isn't and I think actually the people
specifying have limited technical
expertise and they go right so do we use
this document or do we not and so I
personally would like to see it split
out as several RSC's and also that means
they can be worked on independently we
can say yes or no to each one and
you know it becomes easier to work with
all together okay points taken any other
questions all right thank you 6 16 min
Qiang okay okay okay yeah I'm seaman
would do this thank you for giving me
the opportunity here I'm talking about
mesh her eyes it's a mesh routing
protocol with network coding next slide
please so this is a work from Sri
Krishna Panti who is also in the
audience and myself we are PhD students
at the telecom dodgy telecom chair of
communication networks in t.o Dresden
Germany myself I'm with Batman mesh
software which might have heard of I'm
working on bed for more than 10 years
now it's also part of a linux kernel and
we would like to introduce our research
project called mesmerized we would like
to get your feedback for us it's the
first time at the IDF meeting and we
would also like to understand if this is
like material for our sees how to split
but how to publish it and maybe also get
you to collaborate with us yeah so
feedback would be very welcome I plan to
do this presentation in 10 to 15 minutes
so it will be very brief but yeah I hope
you can get a glance so next slide
please ok so basically mesmerized as a
multipath opportunistic mesh routing
protocol which is based on network
coding
we want to exploit the broadcast nature
because many routing protocols which are
also standardized on the yeah use mud
unicast routing and one of innovative
things is but we just don't have
repeaters which just forward messages as
they are but we have relay nodes which
recode using network coding I will
explain that in a minute so our
objectives is mostly high resilience to
topology changes and if possible also
aggregate throughput I think that's
already known from our multipath
approaches ok next slide please so very
brief introduction to that bar coding
typically in a Wi-Fi network you send
just packets they all have a sequence
number and if lost packets when you
would just reset them based on some kind
of feedback a network coding you just
don't send the packets as is but you
combine them to create linear
combinations of these packets you attach
a vector coding vector which describes
what kind of packets have been combined
and how and on the receiver side you can
solve a linear system and recover the
original packets and in that way you
don't need specific retransmissions you
just need a sufficient number of packets
received so you you can solve for in
your system all right one interesting
feature you get the fat linear
combinations is recoding so is you see
we have three notes here encode a rico
down the decoder and the encoder sends
two packets which are linear
combinations and as you can see the
ricoh to sense a combination of these
two packets it received so can create
unique you but still valid
information packets right and every
recoder can create different packets not
only from by for example randomizing or
choosing specific packets but also a
recorder might have got different
packets because i'm often when loss and
if they only got some of them well then
never slide here next please so you see
here i think that lets taking the second
and the third on top and combining those
two a new packet which has been sent and
received by the decoder ok next please
so what is good about network coding net
recording it's resilient in chaotic
networks we require a low feedback we
just need to make sure that the other
participants receive enough packets we
are pretty independent of arrival order
and i think it's very interesting to
apply all these characteristics to mesh
networks in two ways multi-hop and
multipath we will explain that next
please so first thing is a multihop a
typical problem if you have multiple
offices these these numbers show the
probability of the packet received from
A to B or HTC or hid and on each link
you might lose the packet and if if you
lose it the original sender has to send
it again so it the probability
multiplies next slide please and with
recoding we don't have that problem
because we can recover part of
information from the intermediate hops
all right so the probability rises to
them to the probability of a weakest
chain okay next slide please
we have a feature which we have is but
excuse me yes Julius chroma-trak could
you come to the previous I don't
understand your figures on the left hand
side you're assuming no AR Q here yes
this is assuming no irq so how does a RQ
so assuming a RQ you would get widely
different figures yes it would it would
look very different I don't have the
exact numbers in mind so i Iook you it's
much better obviously but with network
coding it's it would still be a little
bit better and recording is especially
interesting if we have multiple paths
which we will come to in a minute okay
so first thing you said recording to
leverage for broadcast medium we don't
just think in one single path we think
in corridors so there might be some
links which are met requires very
similar to the to the best path and we
think of every transmission as a custom
multicast we decide which nodes of the
way should take part of that way based
on on some metrics we go don't go into
detail but it could be airtime for
example and different relays will hear
different packets so we also made some
experiments that we saw but yeah they
just get different packets and some of
them are loss and these are not really
correlated ok next please so and another
thing what we can do to leverage the
network coding characteristics is but
Rico does only send out packets when
they're ranked increases the rank is the
number of linear independent packet so
figure of it is you only send out a
packet if you get new information if you
get the same information which is linear
dependent to the packet you already have
you then don't send anything and the
funny thing about that is but you can
implicitly avoid writing groups you
don't send anything which is already
known which might be interesting also
for the first as a math talk which we
heard today
yeah next slide please so for multi path
so if let's say one of the link fails
immediately or fastly we don't have to
wait for the periodic updates we can
still use the other our paths which
which are already set up to forward for
that specific multicast transmission and
we we will have feedback which tells us
okay please send me some more
information packet and this will control
how many which Rico to sense how many
packets we can also specify the size of
the corridor so if we make a call it a
very narrow we will be at the unicast
case which we already know we can also
make very wide to be more resilient
alright next we did some pretty yeah
some experiment we are also in the
process of implementing all of that
ideas and see how it works this is our
our chair and listen and we just had the
source destination and to realize we
were comparing with a battement protocol
and visa had very bad links and we were
comparing UDP as far as I remember and
you see with just using the second relay
gives some little bit of improvement
doing recording on the first relay give
some improvement and using both relays
at the same time even gives more
improvement yes Julia scrubber check
Batman is doing a RQ shearing I think we
were configuring as multicast but I have
to a check I didn't do this and do you
then do you remember roughly the packet
loss rate you had on this was it 0.2 or
was zero point 99 I remember that we
were using one megabit per second it was
already bad but I can't recall the exact
numbers
but it's just a simple scenario also to
give an idea what we want to do so Rick
Taylor sorry I for this test that is a
single stream going from source to
destination you're not running a stream
in the it's a UDP screen paper a single
udb stream across the network from from
yesterday sorry follow because i'll let
you finish and then i'll ask questions
ok so that's yeah so to summarize we
what we think we can do is to exploit
the broadcast nature of a wireless
medium we can improve error resilience
and possibly improve network throughput
as well maybe not if everything is on
the same channel but if we have
distributed channels for example we also
eliminate the need for xsplit explicit
scheduling and pathfinding which we
would normally have to do if we do yeah
multipath routing we are currently in an
evaluation phase so as I said there's
not really something written down we are
doing code we have routers scattered and
we are trying all right next so that's
about it again I would like to hear your
feedback now or later and see how we can
work with this group and Schwartz jigsaw
I've noticed that a lot of mesh routing
systems seem to work very nicely with
sparse message meshes where each node
can see a few other nodes and collapse
completely under radical congestion in
ultra dense environments with you know
like this room if we all had a mesh node
in our seat and we had total visibility
you get these for example situations
where somebody emits something and
everybody else tries to echo it
simultaneously on the same wireless
channel so how how does your system fair
in dense noted
and so we didn't implement that but for
the standard metric which we would think
of and you have a the source and
destination of in the same room we would
say ok the the metric to the destination
directory is lower compared to going to
another recoder and we would make the
corridor as narrowed to go to the
receiver directly how would you know
that so for example we we can find out
the the metrics like hop counters for
simplest one but we think about airtime
like like what kind of modulation rates
do we currently use and this is given
from the former selection algorithm
which are usually implemented in the
wireless driver like can I reach that
neighbor with one megabit per second of
maybe 50 for makeup per second I'm John
daddle and thanks for your presentation
really interesting can you go back to
the slide where you were what are the
slides early on where you were striping
the data across the outgoing packets one
before I think that's up on there yeah
so are you putting and data from one
particular of your x y&z in more than
one packet that's going out between SNR
yes so I am we are packing all the data
we are multiplying that with
coefficients and putting the information
from multiple packets into one packet
right ok so so what I'm getting at is is
the data from X Files I'd only sent once
across the link a store or is it sent
multiple times there will be different
combinations than multiple times so if
you just send one packet with you can't
compress free packets into one picot
right right now what I'm concerned about
if you lose a package through nessuno
you've lost several x y&z zat the other
end
no okay yeah it's oh yeah so it's all
mixed up the it's question of whether
that's recoverable or not yeah yeah yeah
it's it's it's coding so we can recover
the original packet through coding but
that's the idea where's also extensive
literature we are thinking about
employing random linear network coding
if you want to look right up right okay
so Judah scrub attract the critical and
it's really cool and the bit that is not
entirely clear to me or you actually
hacking at the mac layer are you using
the 802 dot11 mac or did you actually
implement your own mac layer that
implements network coding so we are
using 802 11 but we are modifying the
drivers for example to be able to send
packets and any modulation rate what we
want or we turning off the AF q so we
did some modifications but but we are
using the 802 11 max azria chip is still
running its original form or yes sure
yes okay thank you thank you for the
presentation um Justin Dean I'm working
group chair but I'm participating now as
a participant I think it's really
interesting work I see this type of work
becoming what we're doing in the future
I and I'm glad you're at the idea from
glad some people from Batman or finally
at the IDF I've been trying for a while
to get you guys to come so that's nice
the piece that I find really interesting
is how this works with what we're
scheduled to do right now which is a fib
and if that interfaces at all or if we
should design certain features into a
fib that would that this would be able
to take advantage of or not
so you mean how to split but in my mind
I just the one that came to me was I had
listed you know for drop q hybrid well
this is another one this is encode yeah
shuffle it's another thing to do that we
hadn't thought of so okay yeah I'm me
interesting to consider but thank you
would would definitely be good but I'm I
didn't really follow the IDF process so
far so I'm not sure I would be happy to
integrate that as well hello John Trebek
I was wondering does this involve metro
propagation like link state or distance
vectors to work without that I didn't
quick at different presentation yes as a
Batman guy was thinking about distance
vector and propagation to propagate the
metric and because we will need to have
metric to define these corridors
obviously okay so it still has
propagation like other mesh routing
protocols but it's this is just a better
way to send the data right right so so
we are thinking about implementing a
proactive protocol which is out of them
pretty much like a baby or also all this
out and yeah then we have beacons which
are flooded and propagating the metric
and then we can make up for past Rick
Tyler again um do you have any any data
on I understand with the network coding
you add overhead in order to to add the
redundancy within the mathematics get up
to get the error correction in there but
by doing that you overcome the failures
due to dropped packets across the
network for a I don't know a hundred
kilobits input stream how much do you
multiply out the packet and how does
that offset against the chance of
dropping so what rate do you get at the
far end for your 100 kilobits in I kind
I'd love to see a graph of or when if we
use very heavy error correction coding
so we're doing massive increase in in
packet size in order to get all that
redundancy in there now we don't drop
any packets at all I would drop and that
gets to the far end but it comes at a 10
times cost as compared to
very little networking coding but guess
what we actually lose some data along
the way that would be an interesting
graph as far as I he yes so we should
probably have something later on but
basically but Ireland see is a write
less code so we can easily say okay we
won a hundred percent of twelve percent
redundancy by default we were or in the
best case we can just send as many input
pack packets as output packets just hold
it right and if all of them are received
when it can be decoded and the only
overhead you will have is the coding
vector which is attached in the
beginning um but you lose the redundancy
by doing that so yes and and we would we
would decide on how many extra redundant
packet we send dynamically which would
also be part of the feedback and this so
you'd run that across the control plane
is your sort of distance vector here is
my metric propagation happening and I
think we should produce yeah but that
goes a little bit into detail but for
example of rate control algorithm from
Wi-Fi driver also tells us what is the
drop probability and we can take that
into account we can also say okay we
have two or three neighbors where we
sent some I will tell my neighbors
through feedback hey I have let's say
nine packets and each of you should send
free of them recode for example I think
this is really interesting stuff and
with my dear let authors hat on can you
stop looking at the Wi-Fi driver and
maybe look at using deal app and then
it's portable two lots a lot of
different radio systems lemon yeah but
that's actually your goods we've almost
got it published all right I will look
into that thank you thank you okay
this hi I'm neither you are on without
latency how is latency affected in in
this small test ah that's that's a good
question so usually if you use the
coding in a blocked scheme you have to
wait for let's say ten input packets
before you can start coding them and
sending them out there but there are
also other approaches where you for
example send the packet as is
immediately and just said redundant
packets at the end that's called
systematic coding in that case if you
actually receive the packet then you can
push it up immediately and only if you
didn't receive and you have to wait for
redundant redundant packet I am I'm Jim
we um I'm just wondering if you have you
testing a larger scales maybe like 20
note or I don't know 15 or something
like that as for things and and applies
some kind of money catalytically
mobility deeper option a delay packet
loss and also latency as well okay so
short answers no and no we have
implemented or tested it on for node
networks we also in the middle of
simulating and if if all that goes well
we will probably get a 50 200 notes to
make a bigger set up just in the
University at that point it will be
static and we have some ideas to also
test a little bit with drones and stuff
like that but that's not yeah we didn't
put too much thought into that yet
okay thank you that was our last
presentation so we'll have a quick open
mic if anyone has any comments or
questions regarding manet other than
what we've talked about or what we've
talked about now I'd be the time Julia
scrubber Trek and I wish to apologize
for two things one is that I didn't read
the two management drafts and the other
one is that I'm going to repeat
something that I've repeatedly said on
the mailing list and that i will keep
repeating until the chairs called the
security call security and get me kicked
out there is some really remarkable work
that is being done in the whole network
and group on autonomous management of
networks I've given a talk on that on
Monday it was we in Paris have been
trying to experiment with the hell net
technologies in a mesh environment it
works surprisingly well it needs some
work I think it would be a great pity
and a great wasted opportunity if the
management work for many was done in
isolation of the work that has been done
whole net what I'm hoping for is a man a
configured management protocol that
interoperates with the whole net stuff
in some weaker sense not full
interoperability what exactly can be
achieved is not yet clear to us we've
been discussing that with Shannon raga
and Martin and Marcus Steinberg and well
I will keep working on that and i will
keep repeating that at every opportunity
and and and i would say that sounds like
a i absolutely agree with you that the
work should not be done in isolation it
should be done in conjunction with on
that be we're looking as the IETF always
is we're looking for volunteers to help
us so would you like to take that work
on with inning rogue i and some of the
other people I have volunteered I am
working on that fantastic we look
forward to it yeah I actually saw your
you talking home that and
there were some really interesting
pieces there about auto configuration of
addresses and how it was working so I'm
interested to talk with you after this
as well and interact with you there
Jehovah armistice there is a lot of
research work going this direction for
mobile networks to consider the position
of the nodes in order to anticipate the
routing the connections between the nose
has this been already been considered or
is this is something interesting I've
had talks with with authors of all srb2
in the past regarding position I think
it's something that we would be open to
considering the first thing that comes
to my mind is how you can augment hola
sorry too with position information put
into TL vs attached to addresses that
seems like it would be relatively
straightforward and then you could
select mprs or next hop neighbors based
upon it that would be interesting work I
don't think we need to make a whole new
protocol I think I think we got the
pieces that we can we can build on what
we have and also allow it to be used by
other protocols that might come along
later so yes please please write to list
please if you have questions about our
many architecture and what we have right
now and how that might fit in please ask
are there are people out there myself
others we have an in-house project armed
with drones actually where we know
exactly the the path de ja flying and we
had already good results in increasing
the reactivity of the of the met with
such algorithm so we can we could also
share our work in for the working group
in order to standardize something like
that no that would be that would be
great um if you want to try to put
together a presentation for next ITF
that would yes even better okay Rick
Tyler again just adding my two cents
worth I would love to see something
informational draft in the working group
entitled augmenting many routing
protocols with jigar geographic
information or position and vector so
well thank you all for coming I'm glad
to see some old faces since since it was
a year ago since we last met so please
stay after talk we still have some more
time before the next meeting and I'd
like to go to this just before you close
so excited are we gonna meet in Seoul or
was this going to be a once a year thing
I I boo I have to check my schedule the
plan of error might want to stand up and
speak to this before the recharter we
had a lot of work that was kind of
blogging us down in terms of getting new
work if there is enough participation on
the list and there's enough new work
happening we're going to meet and so we
need to keep moving we have a very tight
schedule and our deliverables there's
lots of good work that's out there and
I'm happy to see new faces as well to
kind of energized the working group and
and move us forward in a good direction
so I think once a year would be too
little i think to a year might be okay
depending on like I said depending on
activity on the list and work that will
be presented and worked on at the next
idea sorry second point I've just been
reminded of I've got a draft up my
sleeve with I've been working with lata
45 triple for extension is that sound
like a working group kind of thing or if
we move beyond that now um talk to me
after this okay okay all right so
officially I guess we're closed thanks
everybody for coming and if you want to
hang around and discuss things man a for
another 15 minutes or so we'll be happy
to do so but thank you
there's no food thrown more than two of
them
you