Messi is ready sorry so natural it's not
sorry
looks good enough word yeah okay hello
my name is khan sattva and one of the
co-chairs together is the common refuse
to do the introduction right now well we
have tight schedule so this year we only
get one love almost for the workshop
unlike past years so let's likely start
so for the first four speakers i have
read you should stay here this area in
this area for the camera don't forget
that everything you say is recorded and
broadcaster and and we also passing
around this blue sheet where you write
well conservatism okay so i would like
so I would I like to ask the first
speaker people to start um since we have
only one of I want to speak very careful
with how much time you use we calculated
20 minutes first a committee need not
seek relief including question sir so
the more questions you want which is
actually the interesting part right when
you come to an ITF needy as I shorter
you should make your speech speech okay
it's fair to use this earth it's great
definitely yes
so thank you for introducing me and also
for this opportunity do you think
microphone is ugly oh I need to yeah ok
so I'm better Elena zolani I'm the new
peach tea student at the University of
Antwerp in Belgium my advisor is
Professor Steven a tray and also the
Xandra from Brazil and this work I made
in my Master's with designer and yurgin
in at University in Brazil and it's
about interactive monitoring
visualization and configuration of a
playful blades sdn so Ricardo can so
basically we consider it that sdn is
based on four fundamental principles the
first one is the network control and
folding the Seas farting planes are
clearly the copepod the second one is
the 14 decisions are flow based instead
of this nation based the third one is
the network farting logic is obstructed
from hardware to program all
programmable software layer and also a
control element is introduced it to
coordinate network-wide 14 decisions and
also a sdn has a flexible architecture
with four planes the application plane
lick on the control plane the folding
plane and also the management plane the
application plane comprehends the net
applications and services the control
plane comprehends the SDN controllers
the folding plane comprehends the set of
simple farting devices and the
management plane comprehends the
management solutions for example
solutions to resource allocation and
monitoring device status and nowadays
the most relevant as the end
implementation is stay open for protocol
because of these principles and it's
flexible architecture as the end a
reduces or even eliminate some
traditional management problems for
example enabling network configuration
in a high-level language and also
providing support for enhancing nectar
by diagnosis and troubleshooting
activities monitoring activities as
monitoring visualization and
configuration are fundamental in the
management contacts and there can be
considerably different from traditional
networks I mean for instance SDN
controller behavior can be customized by
network administrator and this
customizations might impact on resource
usage and traffic farting performance
and some proposals are that centralized
controller creates bottlenecks at the
control channel and also another
proposals like devil flow and the fain
attempted to alleviate these bottlenecks
by distributing the control logic open
flow but remains a question of how open
for control message can be used without
affect the network performance and
moreover there are other Sdn proposals
that use the monitoring information to
mark to automate tasks I mean to reduce
control traffic overhead and also
protecting the network but in what
proportion the SDN controller behavior
can affect both research consumption and
also traffic forwarding performance to
best of our knowledge there is no
solution available that to integrate the
monitoring information with interactive
visualization and configuration tools
for Sdn and we are with such a solution
the are the administrator could better
understand and interact with sdn so
basically we have two contributions the
first one is the control channel
analysis that we quantify the overheads
by impulse it by Oakland full control
message and then we propose an
interactive approach
of two Sdn management through monitoring
visualization and configuration
activities by including the
administrator in a management loop so
basically we'll start with the control
channel analysis so in our control
channel analysis we quantify the
overheads imposed by openflow 1.0 and we
use the controller forwarding behavior
implementation in a compass natesan area
we analyze it the control channel load
metric related to the installation and
monitoring forwarding rules and also
resource usage related to active and
either rules and it's important to
emphasize Ricardo that is an idle rule
is considered idle when its counters do
not change between two monitoring poles
this are all open for 1.0 control
messages we only studied these four
subtypes highlighted the modified state
send packet and Pakatan messages are
related to forwarding rule installation
and the wrists reach state messages are
related to monitoring because we only
studied these four subtypes because they
represent more than ninety seven percent
of the messages exchanges between
controller and foreign device and more
than ninety nine percent of the overall
control traffic because we use the
folding behavior without changing its
implementation and this is a simple
example of warning behavior and rule
installation between asserts holes in a
file server and supposing that the
controller already knows the source
holes in the file server the first step
is the source host sent a data packet to
the first switch in the flow path this
switch checks if has a falling rule that
match with the header header fields if
not the switch generates a packet into
the controller
the controller receives this packet in
the controller calculates all the the
the pad and sends modified state
messages to all Switzerland Pat accepts
the switch that originates the packet in
and then the controller send a modified
state with the send packet to the switch
that originates the packet in to in
order to install the rules and all the
switches along the path and then the
message goes to the file server normally
and the next packets goes without
requesting the controller okay so
regarding this scenario of study we
emulated over mininet our campus network
scenario with 2230 hosts 11 switches one
web server one video server and one
centralized flute-like controlling okay
regarding our workload we emulated based
on several previous studies we model
user traffic profile that dictates the
size of requests and the responses also
the reading and the watch time for the
view server and the and the file server
and we fix the polling frequency with it
in five seconds during the 30 minutes of
experiment and we decided to vary the
editor mode configuration that pic
indicates when the following rule can
the can be removed to a lack of activity
okay the this results show that a single
factor configuring the controller can
make a huge difference and in the amount
of rules installed in the later this
chart illustrates the amount of rules
install in the network and which of
those arrival giving a idle timeout
configuration and it's clearly to
observe when we set this idle timeout to
120 seconds we have more than 1,000
rules installing the network and being
seventy-seven percent of these rules
I'll the reason of this amount of idle
rules is because most of users are
request a web file web it requests do a
web request and then it's shortly
request I mean and then the rule remains
more time idle and this other charts
shows the control channel rate and the
packets processes per second during the
along the idle time and configuration
and we have sent packet modify state and
read state requests going from the
controller to the thing in the direction
from the controller to the foreign
devices and the packet in in which
states replies messages goes from the
devices in the controller's direction
and the height of each bar represents
the control channel old and the package
processes per second in both directions
so we can see that if we set the other
time out to a lower value we have more
traffic related to installation process
the message that our exchanges to
install more rules are more often and
but the overhead imposed for monitoring
is lower because we don't have too many
rules to monitor do it too and if we set
to a higher values we have more overhead
related to monitoring because you have
more rules to to monitor but we have
more less installation process in this
in this case and this means that the
administration needs to watch over this
parameter in order to avoid some
bottleneck because it's correlated so
now i will present our
watch and go regard so this is the SDN
architecture along with the components
that we added and on our approach inside
a management plane we have basically two
main to main components the monitoring
manager the visualization manager and
the configuration manager by creating a
loop with the administrator interactions
the monitoring manager is responsible to
retrieve information about the network
and store it in the local database and
to do that the monitoring manager
communicates with the controller through
the management interface and it's module
is the infrastructure synchronizer the
visualization manager aggregates data
provided by the monitoring manager and
also provides an interactive
visualizations to the administrator to
the graphical user interface and each
models is the chart visualizations and
the statistics processing the last one
the configuration manager is responsible
to check and configure as the end
related parameters unnatural controllers
and to do that this component
communicates with the same management
interface to access the data from two
axes and change the data from
controllers and it's module is the
footlight adapter in our case so this is
our interface at the interface of our
prototype we have configuration
configurations possibilities also a
topology view and with node information
and also interactive charts that
represents the graphs that I showed
previously and
we evaluated our prototype by simulating
some administrator configurations this
discharge represent the amount of rules
and which of those arrival during the
time also the rate of control traction
control channel load and the packets
process at per second so we can see in
the first change that the mutated do is
this is to increase the idle timeout to
6 60 seconds and this configuration in
blinds in a in more rules installing the
network and more idle rules also and we
can see that also the traffic that goes
to the controller traffic related to the
monitoring also grows because those this
traffic is also related to the amount of
rules that we have in the network but we
can see the traffic that is related to
the rules installation decrease because
the installation process is more rare in
this case so then the administrator try
to decrease this traffic that goes to
the controller by increasing the polling
frequency for example to 40 seconds then
we can see that the traffic test is
related to monitoring decrease but we
can see also that we lose we have a
precision loss we cannot identify any
more the idle rules because the
monitoring poles are too sparse and it's
also interesting to to see that in the
last configuration that mr. show to try
to identify the rules again and they and
he decreased the polling frequency to 50
seconds and we can see that we could
again to identify other rules in the
matter so
to our control channel analysis we
identified that a single factor
configure that the controller can make
all the difference on both resource
consumption and also control channel
load and through our prototype we we
were able to retrieve statistic about
the control channel that is a feature
that most sdn approaches did not
consider also we allowed them in stata
to interact with as the end to the
interactive graphs and based off this
interactive visualizations then stator
could could be able to identify
potential issues and change
configurations in in the SDN so the
major challenge of our work was to deal
with the control channel statistics that
in our case there are different
controller implementations nowadays and
currently there is no standardized
interface to access these data and
controllers and we are that as such a
standardization may foster further as
the end solutions regardless of
applications and controllers and foreign
in devices so this is our references use
it in and representation then thank you
for your time and open for questions so
we have a few minutes for questions if
there is any from the audience please
just walk to the microphones otherwise I
shoot the first one so Pedro you you are
talking about different controllers
implementation in a campus network was
your test bed let's say where you deploy
your your prototype or you're seeing
your simulations but why we hope how
would you imagine open flow network
deployment using different controllers
why would an administrator try to use
only a single controller
is there any case that it's possible
yeah we only consider one only one
controller but if if you consider more
than one yeah we should implement more
drivers because there are different
implementations and we could not address
for example we used floodlight our
modified food light if you want to use
box or you you need to implement a
specific driver to retrieve this same
information to to use in our prototype
okay and about the measurements do you
envision or do you see any sort of
traffic measurements that open flow
controllers provides Ord open flow
switch provide actually like at the
table at the forwarding table there they
are supposed to do some / flow
measurements number of packets number of
Vice did you ever use those do you have
any consideration on that we only
concentrate and control traffic and the
the counters that open floor provides to
us it's only data traffic we only used
to identify if it's a neither rule or
not but it was only this and because we
focus on the control traffic on yes okay
thank you if there are no more questions
we can quickly move to the next
presentation then as well Thank You
Pedro again our next speaker is Yan
right young to Scott from chestnut and
he will speak on the detection and
analysis of Siegfried attacks thank you
for the injured children good afternoon
my name is Anne busca I am safely
candidate at burning university of
technology and I'm also on void at
society which is an enron provider for
czech republic today i would like to
speak about detection and
this in this case of the prototype but
it can be generalized on any other kinds
of attacks and on 100g technology at
them which have been developed also by
it's a snap and incorporation with
including detection system Denis me act
so establish the inflection and the
motivation he employed a traditional
system no flow based monitoring this is
very beneficial because of its security
analysis performance evaluation
accounting and so on but it has some
caveats like if you want to do some
forensic analysis you want to learn from
others that are already detected or
improve your techniques or verify if the
attack is to positive or both negative
it's a trap how it can be done very cool
with only flow based unless so our goal
was to pick up okay is it better right
so our goal is to automate the light
capturing on demand and to include some
additional part or capturing from
so-called technology the time machine so
altogether we would like to combine the
combination of a kid capturing with flow
based analysis principles so this is the
basic we have a turn up for computation
on some probe and we can work with that
so this is the typical scenario that's
involved and by all networks so we
extend this to sdn we call it
software-defined monitoring this our
concept we create a special network are
on 100g it includes a pga core and this
capable of filtration medication and
computation of flows so using this
technology we can offload the
computation of IP fix fall to the fpga
and we can spare some resources on the
combination hardware that we can utilize
for other computations so on a highlight
principle we have the mercury Pro the
SDM
we want to observe the flow data that's
are generated this faux data are
analyzed by some application identifier
for example if the same position
initiation protocol we've analyzed by
URL and so on and we want to analyze and
detect these network incidents and we
want to give the feedback the alert when
the incident is detected back to the
monitoring probe with SDM and start the
full packet capture it so from now on
the full packet capturing will be
initiated but if you want to observe the
beginnings of the vector attack we need
data from the past so the time machine
technology so our real-time approach
we've included will give the film are
implemented on the car the light drink
so getting to the time machine we've
looked at the technology or the proposal
based on coordinates lamp axons building
a time machine for action recordings and
receive a high-volume networking traffic
and 2005 they use the storage of
packages on hard drive which is nowadays
some hopefully because we can store so
much data on the beat on hard drives and
they use it for long range 3 g's the
coronas was that not all packets have
been captured but only the beginnings of
the floor because the beginnings of the
flow contained heather's or diverted the
vector of the attacks and they can be
further observed and are more the most
interesting for us so our modification
to the SVM time machine we use the
principles but and I sit by storing the
traffic or the beginning the zoo traffic
into DRAM which is much faster we use
technology for 100g we implemented the
software ring buffer that give us as
much space as we need or it's given in
the ramp and restores only the first end
packets of each flow that can be stored
as long as possible always with the ram
so giving this when the other is
reported we are able to start the full
pocket capturing and retrieve the data
back from
passed from the ring buffer so in this
way we can look like in the past so if
an hi is this graph or diagram with the
time machine so the measurements or what
we have done with this technology with
the state on detection of vertical
rizendough network scans the detection
of communication tunnels in DNS and the
cipro attack or the kissing of dialplan
with pure configure Network private
break private branch exchange ease so
using the SDM if they machine we can get
evidence and verified to Detective
incidents from the past so you might ask
are the end but gets enough so we've
done some monitoring or our network and
we find out that the aggregation is the
red line if you look if you kept your
only 10 packet you get more than ninety
percent of all flocks of all
communication in the flows and the rest
and person is the data that I'm not so
interesting for you because it so it
captured all of its it contains a very
big payout that are not interested for
this analyzes because this attacks also
about the shorts or have short Paoli
built so if you look also on the 10 or
we choose decision threshold at 10
packets we can see that we eliminate
almost ninety percent of data that
otherwise would have to be captured or
stored in the ram so with the decision
threshold then we only store about ten
percent of all data that needs to be
captured or given in the time machine it
also diverse on different l7 protocol
that's used but in general it's it's
this so the machine that we've used for
the sting it contains two CPUs overall
24 cpu cores about 60
or get busy from the Bison from and I
think a bit over the version of SDN
capable card used 56k bytes of RAM for a
ring buffer and we've captured on full
utilized link speed based are only ten
packets of each flow and we observed
that we could store about 15 minutes of
the traffic so in this configuration we
are able to see back 15 minutes of the
traffic so we have 15 minutes to detect
the incident start full packet capturing
and retrieve the data from the past but
these numbers are very dependent on the
characteristic of the networks and
traffic volume distribution etc so it
might differ so some other measurement
on the configuration how many or how
much time you can capture or you can see
in the past if you change the trade-off
for capture packets so starting with you
we have about eight thousand seconds but
it's unacceptable most dimes so we find
out that the most reasonable trade mole
is around 10 minutes so it will destroy
all we are we have the most success rate
in detective of the incidents so but
look at the use case of see fraud attack
the basics of the attack is a
pre-configured private branch exchange
on some company using this technology on
our network we observe around or video
observe around four of these attacks or
different attacks per day on our
networks so as you can see it it might
be interesting for some companies to
know that they are vulnerable for this
kind of attacks it's based on boot
configuration because some
administrators just forget to to exclude
public internet from the private prefix
goals and or improper configuration of
authentication so
section of this attack and its effects
key we have an attacker computer that's
unfitted by malware or under to come
under the control of the attacker we
have the private branch exchange that's
connected to pstn which is the total
communication services the attacker just
rent a paid service does the premium
number that is very expensive to call
and attacker starts to guess the secret
predicts that you include before the
actual number if you want to call
outside outside of your company so when
the attack is successful attacker just
starts the call and withdraw the money
from the paid service so the sip session
initiation protocol is text based
protocol it contains just a few messages
and this message messages can be parsed
on the computer or the combination
hardware that that's used for the
capturing order for the product so we
just extend the IP fix that we use for
for net flow exports and we include the
URL from the invite messages and we
observe because that rhv so when the
attack is successful the server results
they or return the message 200 okay and
the call can't start so typical attack
looks like this other concerns very
large amount of invites with different
prefixes the server returns this message
and when the attack is successful you
can observe this pattern so perfect
guessing you can imagine in this way
this is the private number prefixes and
attacker tries to get this prefixes so
how we can detect this attack from point
of network architecture we just need to
be in the middle into interstellar
communication monitor pro export IP fix
and using our own system that does not
have developed the nimiya the intrusion
detection system which is based on flow
processing or stream processing of net
flows it can be text
this kind of attacks and white control
and report to a supervisor and give the
feedback through monitoring product to
capture all data so this monitoring
module has two parameters maximum prefix
on and the threshold on which it can
test that this is the attack or this is
not the attack so you can imagine like
this you have some domain some number
and a lot of sub trees with the prefixes
that are trying to be called so this is
the typical pattern of this attack our
monitoring or the visualization so we
can conclude this dispute the system
we've used the open source network
forensic analysis tool of detective that
been developed on bro faculty or below
your selfish maji this tool is able to
process ticket files extract some
information from application layer and
it mostly they are used for network
forensic analysis so it can operate with
vary among large amount of a certain
protocols and it can be easily easily
extended so for the visualization path
we implemented into this tool to be an
monitoring center or the overview and
this is the architecture that the
administrator couldn't see when he
deployed this technology can see the
process of the monitoring or the
detection of the attack the suspicious
eye peas transfers of the pcap files etc
from this table the unrest a jury could
see able to attack was successful all
filter the communication and find out if
it's real attack or not so this tool
also generates the prefix trees so you
can easily see if this is the first
positive or both negative of the attack
also it provides some additional
information like performance statistics
number of frames or bytes transferred up
down statistic on TCP hey there have
been some packet losses or some other
information distribution of protocol or
layers etc
sometimes in my views will to see some
packets chance to detect some kind of
attacks and of course the last
functionality the word shark like
approach to see the inner outer pockets
so conclude this presentation we
developed technology to monitor 100g
we've extended the flow records of the
application antivirus based on our
extension have been implemented into pga
and the present system provides for
records food packet capturing on the 100
g and it enables you to see the history
of the communication from the point
where the attack actually occurred on
the network and to reach the gap before
the detection so you get all the data in
the cat city so thank you for your
attention if you are interested you can
see our projects I'd lab router or
follow us on Twitter or so on so thanks
again and the questions Alexandra lemon
I'm sorry i'm not a big expert on sheep
but every obvious quase of the pending
attack on your system when you pair with
an important data and then the attack
vector passes through undetected yeah do
you have anything in plans to avoid that
or is it your system even susceptible to
it well it would depend on the
monitoring mechanisms of the
interrelations is that if it's able to
go with this kind of attacks or not if
it's detectable from the extended falls
or not to be I'm not I'm not the right
we drive this system against this this
kind of attacks we mainly focus on the
most common attacks on our network and
to provide us the feedback if we are
actually able to do monitor or detect
this kind kind of sucks actually and if
it if the detection are too positive or
we are just observing something that
isn't
on the networks so the question I'm not
aware if we tried in this kind of attack
can you thank you for your answer let's
have a conversation afterwards thank you
Geronimo from the floor International
University I saw you use a network tab
ah so it's a way for you to monitoring
the communication but you guys have any
plans you're starting to review the case
you see an attack less close a call that
thank you for excellent question we are
currently developing a solution that
would be able to filter the
communication and divert the traffic
that contains the attack or just been
eight or so on so for now we are
developing the solution for this
technology and it should be available i
think in december this year ok thank you
thanks i saw a very nice presentation so
it's on the same lines on what he has
asked so the tap device would relate the
packets from the incoming need to the to
your device the fpga so will it have any
effect on the throughput no you have no
no effect on the proposed it's just the
district knowledge is just the passive
monitoring their active part it's in
development all right so is it kid are
you as the FPGA also able to classify
any metadata related to vm short
containers which may be provisioned in
this bare metal machine yes hello hey
this this this technology can be can be
tested on virtual machine so not not on
the G bath you can avoid on some small
smaller networks and all the tools are
presented our open source so we don't
have any container that can be deployed
bath with the reasonable amount of work
it can be deployed under the sink
environment show some no communication
with the hypervisor as well no
configuration or anything coming from my
paralyzer you can classify know
okay sure thank you yeah my name is Sal
medic i'm francesco yeah thanks for
the question other questions look um
okay we still have time to look okay
either one question when you showed that
the statistics about how many peckers
you would need for for the number for
the different protocols yeah but ready
to blow blows idea I think you just said
that you cannot detect the protocol
right or online so you cannot say you
want diplom of packets for different
protocols well we we can we can detect
the protocols based on some primitive
and was like the port number about none
for now not nothing so so much
intelligent like machine learning
methods or of something okay because i
was asking leak awesome SSH I see
there's a picture but 11 right so it
would be yeah it just the ground for 22
the education of the stage no okay
thanks no questions you okay that's sexy
pic again I would like to ask sense the
next speaker to come to the I ok what is
Christian sorry Christian Christian
bahas is next week oh yeah yeah yeah I'm
sorry was away our photo oh ok Oh
okay you have feel you see your email
buzzing is my laptop I I can open your
presentation arachidonic problems that
we don't have synchronized what isn't a
burst of time come on okay um so I use
the time to ask the question how many
people are subscribed to the energy
mailing list raise your hand please okay
next time I want next year I want to see
more hands no so just joking so if
you're interested in the works at emoji
is doing which we are we presenting the
measurement for management part which is
what of course the entire my energy here
actually we have one of the energy what
is your official time actually chairs
hello so please feel free to subscribe
to the Energy mailing list and to join
other all other energy made memy Kings
at other ITF metrics and to also join
the discussion oh hello everyone my name
is Christian Juarez I work for a checker
limited and I wanted to talk to you
about an experiment with it together
with a lack Nick measuring connectivity
in south america and caribbean so a
little line line out we want to talk
about the challenge of measuring the
region with the already available right
atlas for example they're not so many
process there so i won't tell how we
overcame that problem with software
probes I want to talk you about the
experiment how it did with the fine
connectivity since we don't have a
standard definition for connectivity so
we defined there and I want to talk
about there
alson discuss a little bit about that
and what we did we find after they doing
these measurements ok so the Latin
American and Caribbean region doesn't
have too many probes in comparison to
other countries in the world you can see
in this this is taking from the official
site of ripe Atlas and the country with
more probes has is Brazil a giant
country with only 50 56 probes and and
the line down there shows a very pale
blue color the meaning that the
percentage of probes covered by that
country is too high in depth this case
zero-point-six percent of the total
probes of ripe Atlas and and if we
compare with the next with the rest of
the world we can see for example in the
United States and Germany their whole
they're both colored with dark blue
meaning they have a high percentage of
probes being available for measurements
and we can see their niche in Latin
American curry is either pale blue which
means a very low percentage or yellow
which means no information or no active
probes so what we did to go over come
these problems is a checker it has a
measuring network software in a with
with software probes called probe API
with which through an API we can control
measurement probes and gather results
and to stuff that it's not a up a level
with other measurements and since their
software probes they're easily to spread
and to install because they're not a
hardware that people have has to take
home and solve themselves and and
they're running in Windows computers
real users computers so they have the
advantage of easy deployment but also
that isn't a disadvantage of a they are
very volatile they appear disappear all
the time so we have lots of them so we
need lots of them to be able to make
reliable measurements and don't work
using synthetic traffic so we can see in
this graph a little comparison about a
plus and pro API Atlas is the leela
color
to the left and different a a SMS so the
vertical line is are just different ASNs
we chose we chose to compare and they're
very highly populated ASNs in terms of
users but not all of them are very well
covered by either by not atlas or api
for example if we take the top asn we
have 46 probes of in that ESN from at
last and 886 active at that moment when
we took the screenshot by pro api so it
can show this can shows us how we can
overcome these measurement problems with
some hot software probes and what we did
in this region using this kind of
measurement method next one like i said
before they are highly volatile that's
why we require high number of probes
than normal to make reliable
measurements because because they appear
and disappear as users normal users you
open and close their laptops or
computers and monitoring from the users
perspective yes lets us detect problems
that otherwise aren't really easy to see
because of the vantage point problem in
measuring networks that depending from
when you where you're measuring from you
will be able to see some things
happening or not like in the set in the
next in this case we can see if we are
monitoring from inside the network from
the center from the data centers of room
servers or whatever we can monitor a
website which will tell us that it's
okay totally okay or from other users
even it will be okay but if the an ISP
has connectivity problems or it has an
outage then the only way to detect that
is from that perspective and that's one
advantage i want to show you from using
this which can be of course it's not
better or worse than other measurements
its complementary because it has its own
advantages and disadvantages so we were
going now to the experiment itself we
were sending between probes and and in
servers in different countries in latin
america and caribbean
200 icmp beings over 12 months over 20
21 countries the geolocation information
was taken from Mozilla and max mine
databases yeah and the each measurement
were like ten things so to say and we
took the best out of them to make to
calculate our results based on the best
available connectivity the round trip
times and after getting the results we
group the countries like just observing
the results like clusters emerged very
there were very evidence to the eye and
and so we can say after grouping the
countries we were able to define
connectivity of them using these three
measurements like the number of clusters
found how these countries how these
clusters relate to each other in terms
of connectivity how did the latency in
between the countries in this cluster is
or outside the cluster how the
connectivities so we have here to the up
and the upper side in the left we have
the graph we built and to the right the
map corresponding to go to the graph for
example if we take the cluster number
three argentina brazil paraguay and or
why we can see that that cluster
internally like between Argentina and
all those countries they have a very
good connectivity 143 milliseconds
average and but to the outside of the
cluster like going to other countries we
have problems not a problem but higher
latency times or the count the cluster
number two which is Chile Bolivia and
Peru they have really not to encoding
compared to the other clusters the
internal connectivity or external
connectivity isn't really too different
and it's not very well connected to the
region in that aspect and it will
observe cluster 0 and number one we can
find that between them they have very
good connectivity in their boundaries
are very
evident in that sense we can also
consider in one big cluster but at the
same time they have some some
differences let us differentiate them so
to the rest of the region they have to
have higher times but between those two
the between zero and one they have only
157 blue seconds latency in average so
those are fairly interesting conclusions
we can say you can say to how the region
is behaving in terms of latency and yeah
this is a similar simple explanation of
them of the graph and the I think I'll
explain that already yes so I already
told you these about the results of
class number two's kind of week in
itself it doesn't really connect between
even internally or externally maybe only
inside the country's the connectivity is
good but between those countries Chile
Peru and Bolivia the connectivity isn't
very good like I told you also like
cluster 3a has very internal cluster
about lighting values but outside the
cluster it isn't very good so the
country between them they are very well
connected but to the rest it isn't very
well and like I told you before clusters
0 and 1 can you go back to two slides
yeah 0 and 1 are very well connected
between them it's not very clear cluster
in that sense but to the rest of the
countries they have liar a higher
latency values and yes go back three XS
so we followed the same procedure to
detect bad connectivity or so to say we
use the same value of round 3 but we use
the inverse to construct the same graph
and so it's not the the we weren't
taking actually the worst results but
actually it a comparing the least good
of them like that where we're always
taking the best ICMP measurements and
then we took the inverse of that and we
can construct the graph based on the
least good results so um web
connectivity was
detected in between Argentina and Chile
which is surprising in some sense
because they have a very big frontier
very large but at the same time if you
think you're geographically between
Argentina and Chile others there's the
end is in between and it's not as easy
to lay a cable between the going through
the and s which are very very big
mountains Colombian Venezuela they don't
have a very good connectivity between
them and Brazil and Peru mostly it's
because normally that they're preferring
we think that like our key SE cables are
being preferred to connect on land
cables and probably because the
geography of the region isn't really
that's favorable for laying cables in
that that's why we think that ocean
cables are being used and that results
sometimes in very long trips for things
that could have been lot shorter next
one please so yeah we're coming to the
end just three open questions we have
after after doing this little experiment
it's there we can we summarize is
anybody have an idea if we can summarize
this indexes per country or per cluster
so we can in one number we can compare
them like how good it is internally
externally or between them is there any
funny idea to get to that point maybe
our their physical connections that in
those countries are not really being
fully used and there's like
infrastructure that's being misused or
underused or maybe our measurements are
escaping some links just relieved that
with all those questions there's
sometimes technically not too easy to
answer but i would like to present them
to you and i think that will be all
thank you very much
take a Christian Christian yeah Kristin
some quite any question from audience oh
that's a lot Oh drew taylor from comcast
thanks for his presentations very good
to see so i think one of the big selling
points behind right ballast is the
hardware is very consistent so as the
software stack yeah so i'm kind of
curious have you done any studies to see
how that's affecting your data um no not
really up to now we've been concentrated
in expanding the network and making this
the probes as functional as possible but
quality assurance and measurements is of
course is a an important task we have to
take into account but of course the
tower running the probes is very diverse
depending on everybody's computers or
Windows installation how healthy is the
installations of so yes it's it's very
dependent on that yeah you're right
thanks well Geronimo from Florida
International University I have two
questions the first one have you
considered testing the the connective
the last mile connectivity for example
to understand if that users using a
Wi-Fi that could easily add 20
milliseconds or using wired connectivity
and the second one it would be good to
have a closer in US and other you
monitoring Latin America but it looks
like at least between Brazil Chile and
Argentina all of the traffic
intracluster is going through us because
143 milliseconds a lot yes if yeah I
think there's a lot going through Miami
or something I and that's yea big yeah
it's a bit stupid fruit from the sense
but that's how things are being done now
what was the first question again about
the last mile for example if you have to
users pinging between them each one of
the each users connect to a Wi-Fi you
have easily 40 milliseconds just for the
last mile yes yes so the protest is the
connectivity to the first to the first
router to understand if it's it's a
Wi-Fi wireless
we haven't done that that part we are
assuming like the users point of view no
matter what what is between them and the
server because there may be more than
one Wi-Fi in between there there's an
undetermined number of things between
them so until now we haven't done that
part but yeah it sounds very interesting
thing to do of course like to get that
part of the of the charts thank you
thank you I usually from GPRS my
question is about the software probe how
did you deploy your software probe in
lucky area and my another question is is
it available to the public if you have
any website I track you know if you have
a if you have any website about software
probe then I'd like to know yes yes we
have you can communicate with the speed
checker XYZ and you can download your
own profits at speed checking software
which users download and most of the
time the software doesn't really do much
then check your dsl speed and at the
same time the software is available to
us as a probe to to make measurements
most of the time the software isn't
doing anything but when it receives a
measurement I command it will measure
very shortly and we deploy that way we
offer the users to measure the dsl
connectivity and in exchange their make
them their computers available to our
network alexander team of curator lips i
think you know that tribe is not profit
company and right balance is also non
profit and so if you're running right
probes you are getting access for your
measurements for all right probes do you
provide such service to can you rephrase
that again so i can write back if you
are running high part as probes you are
getting access for your measurements to
all of ripe Arthur's probes you are
getting credits and you can use it do
you provide some kind of such service
for
users that are running your software so
if I'm tomorrow i will run your software
will i be able to create measurements
not only with my computer but also with
other probes that are connected to your
national yes right now we're not
offering that kind of exchange but will
be it would be very interesting if
people are interested in measuring
themselves we are open of course for
research to use our platform for free
and in that sense but like the users of
the present selves don't have a direct
exchange of credits like like you
described mostly you can you can you can
make an account with us for free and use
the to a certain point the measurement
system but such a system as you say we
haven't implemented that it's hard but
is it possible to customize these
measure measurements or it is only
opportunity to make something request or
something like that something somewhat
something yes that we have every probe
has very different measurement methods
we can make page load measurements like
we're using a real instance of Explorer
or Chrome the the probe response an
instance loads the page and it kills
itself then and yeah we can download
single objects or thing and in there are
customizable innocence that they are
available either as a ready product we
have like with a GUI or as I as an API
that one day one they used in this in
latnok to make this measurement which
they as an API you can code it's
available through mush mush shape so you
can use the code in java and PHP or you
can interact with the API using almost
any popular language ok thank you I
think to be very good if you will take
ripe as an example it also will provide
your users something in exchange thank
you thank you yes thank you yeah I'm
where to I saw Katie FL so I don't know
if you are aware but in Brazil dig deep
what the art is having a project to
perform measurements the project is
called cnet dar so the idea is basically
do essentially the same but using the
end user to start application and
perform measurements from the desktop
from the pie or whatever so maybe a as a
suggestion maybe would be nice you to
get this this data I think it's open to
the public is much better to use this
data then use the right probes and
another comment is that some answer to
their questions input did think there's
there are some operators in Latin
America I remember from inter Nexus they
have direct connection from Brazil to
Colombia and I remember another one that
which has connection from San Paulo to
Santiago passing through Argentina so
maybe it wasn't included to your study
so you could consider this working thank
you ya javani am the next speaker
actually work for SI the end so you did
your measurements using ICMP right very
good yes there's a lot of criticism in
regards to i7 b because it's heavily
shaped sometimes it's the lower key last
yes uh you know this criticism problem
so have you considered using other
protocols instead and compare the
results um like personally and
internally at the company not this is a
study done by lack Nick and we're
presenting this as a cooperation they
had their own they made an over their
own decision of using ICMP but normally
we use time to first byte using HTTP
directly because it's the protocol we're
using so normally with we measure either
I won by its file downloading it just
like that or just we measure the time it
take to download the first I'd and
that's mostly equivalent to a cmp but
using the HTTP stack yes thank you a
last one please pet line it Huawei I
work with ripe NCC and working on the
iPad last project so it's good the work
that you did but if you guys you know in
Latin America are interested in more
probes I'm sure they're willing to send
more pro
you know if you need contacts i'm sure
you have contacts but if you do need
more context please feel free to check
with me please let me complete that one
I am actually working off with ripe
Atlas as ambassador for Brazilian
regions so if you live in South American
you want probes I have them I also I I
do agree that a ripe ripe Atlas also
have a worldwide coverage but it's nice
to always have at diversity to
measurement infrastructure even more
when it goes to developing regions or
poorer regions of the country of the
world where it's difficult to get the
right ship to ship at you I'd like just
to complete the question session with
one question is your measurement running
over time or you do it once and stop or
is it running for for example I year
already it was done for a year and it
was programmed to measure in regular
intervals as how you want be using the
any any any time controlling algorithm
you want if you're using the iata and
yeah it's not continuous monitoring is
normally one test and you can repeat it
as much as you want ok so like suggest
perhaps for a talk for an NMR G next
year if you can see the impacts of
social and political decisions that are
going on South America I'm from South
America so I know that there are these
problems going on there quite often if
you can see from your measurement
framework the impacts that it have on it
has on the connectivity of people it's
always nice so we see papers being
published about Cuba about China about
other places where we have one ripe
Atlas to write pathless but they can
already see some nice characteristics
there so that would be awesome movie
yeah Thank you Thank You Christian again
let's everybody
our next Victor speaker is Giovanni Mora
Mora from SI quien laps do you need my
computer Germany oh yeah yes ok this is
not my computer disease Christian yes
kids say there's a lot of people here
today
yeah so I figure can start just give you
some context so the working on represent
here is not say letter purely academic
this is a paper we publish up the AP WG
e cron conference on the industrial
track so it's a bit mixed is like more
hands-on practical than research
questions so uh this is a paper
collaborate with you to the team they're
inside yen we have a big data platform
for jeunesse traffic and this paper
shows a couple of applications that it
what things you can do quickly but that
should go next one um okay give you some
context here what do you do if you I
think how many how many people here
actually they have a big data problem
like volume of data that's like you have
shown Eliza's fangs can you raise our
hands with those big data analysis here
and big data is very vague but yeah
there we go alright so I mean if you
have a terabytes of data and specially
pcap files have generalizes thing you
know how but a nightmare is or the costs
are going to have to do that um you need
to do that inefficient in a cheap way so
the engineers are going to company that
I work for they start to use and stuff
from other disciplines like the data
engineering people to optimize that then
bring that to that next working
community and they call this in product
this is a product that's build on open
source code i'm going to give the
details later one and what it does on
top of that it is designed to ingest DNS
traffic we work for a company that does
dining out the top level domain the
netherlands so we collect of the
authoritative traffic and a store in our
cluster for analysis for research
purposes uh so a couple things you can
do you can put on a single table if you
have this terabytes of data set since
things
you don't scare so you need something
that will I scales and once you need
more hardware just two more hari on that
and fro more hard when you know you keep
the speed so that's next lifeless um and
so that's pretty much what they've done
that since we need is a response type
interactive times they build his own
thing x1 please so entrada is basically
an optimized for matta in a platform for
performing data analysis on track
internet trafficking out roland also
uses some of the detector but not and
try to buy like Hadoop and Impala and
the same file on his project there too
the thing is it can analyze the
equivalent of 50 terabytes of pcap data
in a small four node cluster is a tiny
cluster and for example if you need to
know what is the number of it in six
packets you had only a network on a
vibratory if for example last year if
you would have to find repeat caps and
process all the Sphinx it do discounts
or the average packet size are going to
take forever but if you have stuff like
that it's going to be real quick like a
question of minutes yeah or seconds and
yeah that's like with so in try to buy
us down to get a DP caps converting that
thing to an optimized for map which is
park a park is implemented by apache
foundation which is based on google's a
dremel file system and which is
optimized callenders file format in
short if you need to like do a radio Mir
file if you want to just figure it out
what the packet size for all your files
for our your packet to this internet
work you don't actually to read the
entire file you just need to read the
entire column they're interested in so
it saves a lot of time and you the
beauty of this Fang it can query that
thing with Impala and Impala it's a call
data product open source as well which
allows you to send sick of co2 analyzer
pique pique pique pique rivlin files so
it's very easy for anyone who want to do
a data analysis fast as well yeah next
one please and the thing that they did
in the confidence just like rapid all
those things together and this in
implemented a data model to incorporate
DNS traffic and to a constant in chaste
as faim that's what Colorado and you use
this thing now for
over two years now have liked videos of
cures there 21 terabytes of data and
it's already converted and it captured a
date they get it from our miam service
that's it next one please do get a paper
published chef noms which is from this
measurement community as well conference
we just talked about more the details of
this the Spanx are faring in aressa just
refer to that place and this paper that
reflects this presentation right now
covers a couple of applications and I'm
just going to focus some of them here so
we have a page the first one there I
don't think I hands vital evident if you
check it out the webpage where everyone
starts at the side the N labs that are
now we update every day this page using
this glossary entrada with our
statistics over done an hour traffic so
the number of countries or tunnel
systems there's a bunch of stuff there
if you're interested just check it out
sell public I will also have some stuff
from malicious domains and I'm going to
cover this this one's in bold here next
one place so um one of the things we
need to do in a company in the labs is
to use this data we collect to improve
both security and performance and
stability of the you know the service
that we maintained that in El
authoritative service and there's a
paper from Nick Finster name c2011 if
i'm not mistaken they figured out that
domains that they're using for fishing
typically on the very first days or
hours after registrations they have a
peek on the number of queries that they
get and you'll deserve the same for that
now so for example the red the figure on
the right over there it has an average
number of 150 curious or 200 these are
domains that were provided by netcraft
that were found in fishing on a dianella
zone so we look at today our
authoritative servers and you see hey
how many queries we'd seen for those
particular domains after the
registration and you see there is a pic
and after 10 days it really dies down
while the normal regular domains you
have an average of five queries a day on
the first day is a tree or whatever so
there's a clear distinct pattern Nick
feemster found stuff and publish
whatever we kind of went a step further
when you run a different algorithm to
classify that k-means on top of that and
had a paper and on this particular thing
so next slide please and what do you do
again
every day all the domains that were
added to our data nodes on they were
registered we'll look for a couple
features the number of queries the
number of countries resolvers that are
creating that thing in the first day we
run k-means on top of that and classify
to to cluster suspicious and normal
normal and once you get a suspicious one
we notify our registrar's and red stars
are the confidence actually do the
registration for us it's a pilot's is in
a pilot stage right now there's a couple
false positives of course because you're
trying to identify fishing only from the
query pattern of the domains as like
it's because the Fisher's usually they
rely upon spam to notify their domains
in the first days so usually have a huge
number of queries but any political
motivated website also get this thing so
we are working to improve this but it's
it's working on a kind of status a
prototype phase right now next one
please this is a project of Marco who's
sitting right over here I guess yeah but
my detection so they they there's a
particular button that you don't really
talk much about it because if you are
the signature for this Batman and who
killed attack that one looking our DNS
traffic that is seeing there's a couple
of a think from a mistake and those are
CNC channels domains they use and you
kind of you know monitor the traffic to
them and once we get this thing we we
also use entrada that's a better form
channelized that is the whole thing we
notify what we call it sedition in each
initiative which is called abuse
information exchange so it's the place
in the federal level that collects
information about abuse it's run by the
government and it shares back with the
people responsible for those IP
addresses for those autonomous systems
so they can clean up the network's next
one please just worship to start cases
and this is the number to see the time
series and the counters that was bought
this is thoughts were observed in the
sent information regards timestamp so
they can take a look on that a very mind
that the way the DNS works once we see a
query on the Oratory ticket service
might not be the actual client might be
the resolver of the client on the ISP
network so they would have to do a
little more investigation on that next
one please
and they're there this two-hour season
that standardized different things
policy and pre-made security this try to
improve inmate security in a way to
define who can send email for a
particular domain and what is the policy
was you get mail from a different IP
address for the domain you can actually
measure their that the adoption of that
using simply SQL queries in our platform
because we get a traffic so you're just
one sicko run over the days and you see
like how this thing is growing a next
one please so we have a couple results
here and it as a percentage like there's
a lot of percentage of adoption in us
and of course this is the cloud
providers means chimayo most of people
use gmail so yeah in a cloud providers
that's why you see this is fixing right
have cloud we have the Spanx once the
adult that's it next one please do or it
is our tunnel systems where they're
located all these things it can be
easily be done as well next one yeah so
I think they did you showcase a cup of
case studies which you can do so if you
have a big data problem you should
consider yourself to use the tools that
have been developed at the data
engineering community chop two mice
queries and this is one case only that
uses Impala and uses parquet I'll open
source and rapid apps together to
constantly jazz DNS traffic in open
source we open starts the whole thing
the finger would develop it's all on the
website I would invite you to download
and contribute as well next one place
yeah you know we are constantly a you
know using an developing our
applications that benefit from there too
yeah and be happy to take any questions
any questions from the audience can I
might otherwise I have a some small
questions well one you just answered
it's all open source yeah yeah I mean
that the whole thing is open source and
the changes we did the things we did is
also consortium and also about the data
how much of it also you can provide 24
for example for open access for
researchers or even curiosity yet so
there's there's a we have a privacy
policy that defines what you can share
what it cannot and how we can use the
data we provide aggregated data on our
stats web page but uh provided to
research a fix that by that its case by
case we haven't done that yet because
it's pretty strict no they might be
classified a personal ended file of data
so its case by kid I think if you have
an idea just contact us a nice you can
do and on your malicious domain research
you said that you would you take only
the new domains registered per day and
then you classify them as malicious or
not do you have any idea or can you
close an idea of the relation the ratio
between register domains per day and how
many actually are malicious up so I
think it depends a lot on the day and
per day usually see like 1015 domains on
average and there's a bunch of false
some false positives to and I think also
depends will definition of malicious
than 50 malicious suspicious that
suspicious and let's say I don't know
depends on the day how many going to be
malicious but there's a different
definition definition of malicious this
thing detects based on the volume of a
curious so spam phishing is one case but
there are cases that they create like
you know websites and sell and
counterfeit products like shoes or
pharmaceutical drugs so it's as
malicious this is illegal it's kind of
gray area so does all of those things
too so it's yeah borderline yeah and one
one last question for me is do you can
you relate it similar to the question i
had to chris
young as well can you relate the number
of suspicious domain registration to
certain events that go around the globe
or mainly in the Netherlands because i'd
say an example the the i don't know can
be even queen's day in the never me yeah
i mean we can see some stuff i mean we
seen a cup of politically motivated
websites after some terrorist attacks
that he came up and they kind of spread
like fire on twitter and of course to
see this thing's next day in aqueous
patterns as well because they go insane
so they can a domain is very popular on
the first day Kim can be for different
reasons militias are not or like
political motivator or whatever so you
can be used as a sensor for that too and
so now we're actually working extended
this this project to incorporate
registration data to account for the
likelihood of being like political
motive ated so rule out this kind of
guys and you remain only those that are
actually trying to be malicious okay if
you don't have any more questions let's
thank you bunny again thank you for the
presentation then for the open source if
you haven't signed the blue sheet yet I
dunno where it is at this moment please
do so at the end when we when we close
it I just bring it here whoever has it
and then you can come here and sign if
you didn't I mean I think it's it yes
yeah thank you for having attended
energy workshop as usual we would like
to ask your opinion on on on on the
event right and also on future events
for example we originally started
several years ago that this kind of
meeting was strictly on a flow based
measurement form network management and
based on the feedback of the audience we
have extended that from first full flow
based net flow based measurement to flow
based measurement and this year we have
extended tool to any
kind of measurement based network
management so feel free to give us your
feedback whether you like this direction
whether you want to have other other
topics in the next probably next year's
instance of direction George now or send
us an email or joins imaginating this
fight right which is of course
appreciated anything as there will be
not an emoji joint event right maybe you
can say something and everyone just
commenting first on what from inside so
please join the mailing list and
interact on the mailing list and Ricky
if you wish on this measurement
monitoring a topic of energy also you
used to have a combination of locating
these IETF order network management or
rating conferences so you can express
also your views if you think this is a
consistent and if you want to continue
this way I will also encourage you to
maybe try as a community on this topic
try to define what will be some research
topics research areas and maybe document
that with some internet draft so that we
also show that as a working group as a
research group there is a activity and
maybe also higher perspective to wear
this measurement and monitoring activity
can can go not talking about
somatization but as a research topic and
also maybe try it in the future maybe
some interactions which there is this
map research group that has been
recently created they're also looking at
measurement from a quite different
perspective but I think there is also a
community they're also going to the
scientific conferences so maybe the two
activities can also be a bit more of
interactions that can be a topic for
another either an emoji or ma perché
joint session and so what ramming
mentioned there is a second energy joint
meeting with NF v RG and energy energy
on friday morning so it's the first
morning session the topic is on the
managing virtualized and programmer
network so we will have different kind
of talks that are more oriented towards
what are the challenges of managing the
new type of environments with an avian
sdn but also all these virtualization
and programmable techniques can change a
bit the way we manage networks so please
join this most interesting session
google app yeah just a feedback but
aloha already talked a little about that
like the map RG group is not really
chartered yet so not sure what's gonna
happen in there but just to make sure
that's no more refuses to go should have
overlap or how are you gonna handle if
they go chartered and they also had
started a workshop that took place in
Saturday so just to be aware that you
know not sure all I know them we try to
have some discussion with the chairs of
Mukherjee first to i-95 the deliverer of
overlap and what could be the areas of
collaboration interactions so since as
you mentioned it's still developing
Mukherjee some kyria or two things can
interact but as you mentioned we have
seen that there there were also part of
the workshops they have been some
they're already at some meeting so we
see that things may grow there so it
would be nice to at least discuss all
together okay thank you everyone for
participation here the sheets if you
didn't sign see you next time we have
been dancing about I'm one
you