and if you are here can you come like to
the like the first couple rows or
something just come up close because
there's only going to be four or five so
can you go down to charlottenburg 23 and
see if they the wall icons that we're
doing the anti-troll are down there so
so we were originally scheduled here
yeah can you go down and see if any of
for the huawei gentlemen who were
working on yang tick-tock her down there
ah wasn't some people mr. I yeah they
said they were here but I don't see them
if you just yeah I just bring them up
here if they're down there
he was but what she let it go
okay thank you I'm not going I don't
have a second person so I'm not going to
be able to monitor jabber and do the
presentation oh yeah ok so that's for ya
ok we're going to go ahead and get
started um this is the last session of
ITF 96 this is the MTP tick-tock working
group oh this is a much bigger crowd
than i expected exact actually i was
expecting like three or four of you as i
said on monday this is our note well
everybody understands with Noel is oh
this one makes sense this one's perfect
oh yeah I see it now oh but I exited
didn't I let's put that button did
really how do you see I don't see it
either below there it is oh maybe I
should put my glasses on okay so this is
a note will now that we've seen several
versions of it the agenda for the week I
ok
gender for the week we covered all the
ntp items on monday we have i want to
remind people we're talking about
scheduling an ntp face-to-face interim
probably in the October time frame to
deal primarily with the ntp security
stuff and also the potential to be CP
and the agenda for today is to talk a
little bit about the tick tock working
group status talk about the yang data
module model and the what we want to do
next with the scalable synchronization
Network work and then I wanted to step
back briefly and talk about the mid so
right now and I see ya cough is online
the one thing that I had left off the
agenda was next steps for the MPLS draft
mpls over 1588 draft so maybe we'll
bring that up at the end Jack over here
if you're actually online and can hop
into the speaker queue at some point
that would be useful so so I'm working
group status um so we have a a 1588
version to mid and it has gone all the
way through working group last call and
it's with the iesg and there is a
okay so the myth has gone through the
iesg and it is there is a in the last
call process there was a question raised
about copyright questions about how much
material is from I Tripoli 1588 that's
repeated in the mid this was a question
that I had told you might be resolved by
today but it has not been there is a
triple the ietf coordination group they
are addressing the issue and I think
we're going to be scheduling a
conference call in the near future but
that one should be really close to done
the only remaining issue beyond some
editorial updates is to resolve this
issue of how we proper do properly deal
with the copyright I think part of the
issue is because I triplet 1588 is not i
triple e a tattoo and so we we have
fairly refined processes for dealing
with i trow prieta too but not
necessarily 1588 so the next thing is
the yank data model there are no updates
to the ending data model the question
there is also around how we work it's
also currently a little bit in a holding
state as we clarify how we work between
ITF and I tripoli 1588 with the
intention being that the yang model
would be developed and it would for 1588
version 2 and then it would transition
to 1588 for development of a yang module
for version 3 and beyond and we also
scoped the 1588 version to version of it
to be specifically to model only the
data sets in the version 2 model in the
version to specification of 1588 so I
don't know if any of the authors of that
are here at this point I don't see you
so
and we also have no update on that I
think that the resolution of those two
issues are a little bit beyond the scope
of this working group so we need to work
with the IETF and I Triple E 1588
leadership to make sure that we have the
processes in place that will enable us
to do that transition so there's nothing
more to report on that work this week so
the next thing on the agenda was a
discussion of the scalable
synchronization networks effort and this
was brought to the tick-tock working
group a couple of I 80s ago then we
established a mailing list separate IETF
mailing list to talk about to further
refine the problem statement are the
authors of those documents here I
thought one of them was going to be here
okay I don't see any of the authors here
I think that to a certain extent that
answers part of my question about
whether the tick tock working group
wants to adopt this work or not I think
at this point we do not have consensus
to adopt it it needs to be much more
fleshed out are there any is there any
discussion about developing this work
let me ask this question how many people
have read the original scalable
synchronization network drives one yay
Brian how many people are aware of the
fact that we have a separate mailing
list to discuss scalable synchronization
networks
how many people have subscribed to that
mailing list now that I mention it
you'll subscribe to it okay well what I
would really
have working group consensus not to do
this work at this time which I'm go
ahead Brian I will not say anything that
discriminates against short people Brian
Haberman so the last thing I remember
about the discussion of that scalable
synchronization network I I want to say
it was Benoit was kind of looking at it
from an operational point of view and
the question was really is this a
protocol issue is this really just a
network management issue so I would
recommend that you talk to your ad to
talk to the ops 80s and figure out if
they decided if that was true or not but
I tent I tend to agree based on what
i've read that that this is not a
protocol issue but say it's an opposite
entrant issue okay okay that simplifies
that so the last thing on the agenda for
this week this is making me feel I hope
none of you stayed specially for this
meeting I did warn somebody you could
leave early so the next question is the
we've talked several times about the
merging of ntp and tik-tok into a single
working group we will be doing this we
have been strongly encouraged to do this
and I think it only makes sense I have
just a couple of just a sense of the
room types of questions we is there on
any strong feeling about whether to
leave the ntp working group or to create
a new working group that merges the two
did other any point do people out there
say any confusing the community issues a
soundless around that it seems to me
make sense at the time working group
then all matters related to time
technologies would have a home and you
wouldn't have any sort of fights between
the various camps all right for all
practical purposes these have been the
same working group for a while now so a
single time working group that delete
that addresses all things related to
time synchronization protocols all
network time synchronization protocols
hi I'm just relaying ecclestone here
calling it only ntp would be confusing
okay but that's the sense i wanted to
get I also from the ntp perspective i
wondered if it would be confusing to
move ntp to a non ntp working group but
if it was something as simple as time
then I think that would be fine so I
have struggled a bit to get a charter
put together on this is there one or two
people that would volunteer to help me
merge the Charter text shorter concise
single milestones Stuart would help me
India to excellence a deterrent Stuart
it feels really ridiculous in front of
this huge room with yes let's lest there
be any misunderstanding I was scratching
my head not volunteering I'm here
because time is clearly very important
in security depends on time but I I'm
sort of here in educational mode
learning stuff okay actually it's Stuart
Bryant is sitting behind you and that's
the Stuart I meant sorry um and I will
say that this is probably not the best
one to come to meeting to be educational
because it's the drugs at the end of the
agenda from Monday
oh that's true you did and I think about
it go ahead so yeah cough is suggesting
to name though a new working group sink
which stands for sink your network lock
thank you yeah i think is it yeah come
for Stuart that's response Stuart Bryant
it's responsible for a tick tock I don't
know okay so I have some volunteers to
help with the Charter I think we have at
this point too well 33 names that have
been proposed net time time and now sync
I would like to get this done in the
next month if possible I think we've
talked about it long enough and not
actually executed on it so with that is
there anything else people want to raise
about the ntp or tick tock agenda for
the week oh oh you click Thank You 1580
of RAM pls since ya cough is there yeah
cough I'm about ready to kill that draft
is there an update coming or what's the
deal
and he can go to the
remote key if he wants echo says there's
no update needed here just Pro do just
what roto do you mean by my right side
oh that's right so I thought there was
another job take the draft coming but
he's gonna wow this is really but so ask
him yeah cough I believe the proto right
up for that was in your hands are you
planning to do that says yes I really
need to get around to that okay so we
need the proto right up for the 1588
over mpls i will also note that Greg
Mirsky has sent some additional the
residence time documents have been
coming through the IETF as well oh and
now my hanging author is here okay so we
were just actually with apologies
joining the meeting I just saw you walk
in so perhaps we can talk afterwards
about the status of the various
documents um did you have anything you
wanted to report on the yang model or
this scalable synchronization network
this is a vietnam from hwy for the young
medulla we have a updated to the vacuum
floor during the last item meeting we
don't have an update yet but her as a
summer exchangeable emails with i took a
year 58 guys at Cynthia how some more
concerned
the transfer process as our IP f4
process so yeah like we studied to be a
half a mile at home itself okay so
independent of I'll repeat what i said
earlier just briefly but independent of
the update process I'm an independent of
the I Triple E 1588 IETF issue do you
see any additional technical work
required or is the document roughly
ready to progress yeah for the technical
aspects I don't see anything that is the
in conversely so I as it's quite a
stable now so I lactancia it will be
adopted here in its a toga workgroup
know so we can we can process it and
it's probably share a publication okay
so we can talk offline about the results
of the I Triple E 15 of the attribute by
etf coordination meeting earlier in the
week and how we're going to move forward
there but they they need to figure out
some more stuff and so i'm waiting for
the high level the leadership to figure
out the next steps i think the general
consensus is we want to do this and it
shouldn't be this hard and i'm not sure
what the application is but thank you
you're welcome the other we're also
involved in the scalable synchronization
network work right yes yes for the
scalable annotation we have a set up a
middle-aged discuss this topic as a
single we have a greater progress you're
the lot of a couple of months but we do
like to have more import from the
attendees in the ITV key and we also are
socializing with
more people in there industria we don't
see a quite a few inches from 10 so we
may be where we are our discussion for
the nest here i can meet you okay um I
think the conversation we had was we
don't see that I think we need
potentially we could send another
message to the time related working
groups but brian has also suggested the
management area working area management
area ops area so we can talk about that
offline but I don't think that there's
enough consensus to move it forward in
this air in this working group so we
think it might be a different topic area
but we can talk about that further
offline I didn't get a cat catch I
didn't see you this morning I couldn't
catch you to ask you those questions so
but thank you and we'll we'll work more
yeah thank you um so with that is there
anything else that people want to bring
up related to time or tick tock okay um
so for the folks that agreed to do the
first two to work on the Charter can one
of you I'm going to rely on one of the
two of you to do a first draft if that's
okay it's okay okay excellent any other
questions comments or inappropriate
remarks nope thank you have a good day
I
Oh