they are coming forward I what you have
no choice do you need to move on just
about to get sucks okay good evening uh
thank you for coming in such masses
hello you wouldn't believe it but it's
still meeting time it's not even in just
yet don't drink beer listen so this is
the radix working group on what our slot
from 1832 1930 and again thanks for
coming in such masses and not leaving
the room thank you okay so um we should
get started first with you know dwell
please note well denote well and then
let's see it together at the agenda for
the addenda bashing we spend five
minutes on the prisoners as usual there
is a document status update where we see
how far our documents have come we have
two active working group drafts in which
i get five minutes each for very small
small recap on the current status then
we have actually for individual drafts
to discuss actually three drafts and a
draft to be so act they have plenty of
new work which could be in coming into
this working group and then after the
wrap up we still have five minutes of
leeway so while we might actually spend
a bit more time on one topic let's see
how it goes so first of all for the
blimp preliminaries we need a minute
taker and age
scribe surprisingly I didn't get any
upfront notices that somebody is
volunteering so now is the time anyone
willing to take notes hey and on the
second notes wonderful and a jealous
cribe no javascript helen is here so
he's usually electronic Java guest okay
so then let's start with we have not
published now see in the meantime but we
do have one document in the IRC editor q
mmm that is the larger packets over
radios for ages over TCP from Sam hot
men this is actually in all 48 so this
should be out the door any time now and
I'm hoping that this is kind of next
week or so so we have an almost our see
at this point there is nothing in ivf
last call but we do have two documents
which are currently in the is to
processing state there is the radius
extensions for IP port configuration and
reporting this is publication requested
and is g is doing its magic on it and
then we have data types in the radios
our work of another and there is
one ad review from cathy moriarty um
with two dare i say fairly minor
comments so i think we can push this
forward yeah then i'll get to the other
one very soon i am sorry i had tried to
get it done before this meeting and I
was not able to no problem at all so um
this is alan i actually put in a couple
of comments and pushed out a new doc
earlier today so i think that should be
all right um I should
sorry i ah yes these mics have that
issue I put in the minor comments
earlier today and issued a document so I
believe we're okay for you know barring
80 review and time scale we should be
okay for a working group last call and
publication we know that we've done
working with last call yeah you meant
ITF last client James nice colleges okay
so basically our we're ready to push the
button on this one then that's actually
quite good now in terms of active
working with documents which are still
in the working group stage I think I've
completed all my shepherd write-ups and
just as well as leonel so well there's
nothing in that queue we have a document
which has completed welcome to blast
call at least once and that's the CUA
proxy there is another working last call
ending next week on this is basically
only to give Peter Deacon a chance to
revise his comments which he had a long
time ago so with this newest Rev if
there is no incoming comment basically
we should be done with that and we
should be proceeding to the right up at
this point so everybody who wants to
comment on this document to do it really
soon now another document we have in the
hue is my only considerations regarding
the correct use of ypres sponsored
entity discuss the new version just
before the cutoff and have a small slide
deck really with just one issue on my
side that should be remaining and I hope
we can put this forward at some point
soon now for the new work which would be
coming in this is actually quite a lot
on our plate and we have to decide at
some point which of those we want to
adopt this working group drafts so one
graft is pretty much set as soon as it
exists and that is the radius of a TLS
let's call it this document the current
RC 6614 is experimental and also needs
to be double refreshment for TLS 1.3 so
jim has kindly volunteered to edit that
document
to be the editor and so let's discuss it
today and at some point see draft about
it then there is laura1 authentication
in radius lower one is this low-power
radio wide area network and they have
their very unique authentication needs
and there is graphed a one also
submitted just before the cutoff which
describes how to authenticate with lower
one and at some point from looking at
the document at least some new radius
attributes would be needed and maybe
some reshaping of how this is actually
going to be done so again there is a
presentation here and we are well should
listen and comment the next one is
radius extensions for network assisted
multipath TCP on there was a
presentation about this on the last ITF
in Buenos is for those who were there
which was a lot of you a lot so there is
no new draft I also didn't get a
presentation slide deck but some this is
on the table today because the authors
have indicated they would really want to
have this as a working group document so
I guess we should discuss about the fate
of this one then there is a as a last
document the extended packet header for
radius which is fairly new um so this is
no submitted also just before the
deadline and yeah so let's see what this
is about based on discussions with Jim
and Bernard and Stefan this week I
suspect there may be another document
which would be useful which would be
radius proxy considerations which is
really a bit different than the TCP or
TLS document and it's what do you do
when you cross protocol boundaries or
you know what do you do when you're when
you have layers of proxy chains to just
again expanding things which are not
documented now are poorly implemented
are unknown
yeah so first of all thanks for sparking
off the discussion of the betting is
already on this since we have five
minutes of leeway in the end probably we
can just talk about it at any point okay
so that let's first discuss these active
work group drafts arm we have the cui
proxy document I gave it five minutes
actually there's not a lot to talk about
so it was happy if you just take one
minute for it let me just pull up the
slides and then let's see how it goes
just go through the slides there really
isn't much changed from the last IETF
proxy spoofing can always be done you
know the proxies can do anything they
want Peter Deacon had some comments I'm
not entirely sure what he meant by them
and i did not get clarification so
barring clarification we can go with the
document as is um go ahead so there were
updated text so the main issue is that
the coa server which is really the Nazz
must treat all attributes as mandatory
if it doesn't understand it it sends a
co a knack with an error cause of
unsupported attributes the issue is
their attributes added by proxies on the
outbound path which really should also
be sent on the inbound path but you want
to delete those attributes before they
get to the NAS because their proxy
signaling attributes not nazz attributes
and so the discussion here is trying to
come up with text which says bar by and
large anything proxies add outbound they
delete going back so when the packet
gets to the nez it knows nothing about
any kind of proxy stuff what I've seen
in in practice is the proxy state
attribute going from a co a client
to the nas and then the nazgûl I don't
understand proxy state and sending a co
a knack back which is dumb but you could
argue it sort of makes sense from
reading 50 176 so this is meant to be
future proof too simple hopefully
hopefully understandable so all
attributes added by a radius proxy when
sending packets from the visited network
to the whole network must be removed by
the corresponding CEO a package from
proud proxy from packets would travel
the reverse path so then as only ever
sees attributes that its end up stream
or that the upstream is intending to
send to it to do see oh yeah my only
question is if this is really foolproof
in the sense that the authentication
path could be different from the CUA
path so you don't necessarily travel by
the same ops so you don't know what you
have to remove because you never
actually saw the baggage yes the the
document of some other text about you
know we sort of assume that there's
mostly a one-to-one mapping between the
upstream and the reverse path and that
the upstream proxy can talk to the CEO a
proxy which sends things backwards right
if the pads are completely different
than who knows what the hell goes on
right it's almost impossible to know
some of Peter deacons comments were that
the CEO a proxy did not talk to the
radius proxy and was incapable of
talking to the radius proxy I think the
answer to that was well then I have no
idea how to do any of this right if you
assume that they're tightly coupled then
it's straight forward if you don't
tightly couple them please write a
document suggesting what to do and he
didn't it's a use case I don't know how
to solve
yeah okay I think that's it next slide
but I think there's any questions well
as all the all the explanations so any
questions comments from the room
everyone's happy or overloaded all right
one cushion are regarding the first
comment forgetting Peter deacon so you
are expecting what from him or it would
be nice to get an explanation as to what
concerns he had and how they could be
addressed okay so at least we can we can
we can say that on the mini me's and
saying that if there is no more comment
we can move on okay okay thank you so
the next presentation is done actually
are my own so p0 second so so this is a
shorts that is updated about the ypres
sponsored entity which has got a fair
bit of discussion last time but I hope
we were able to solve all these issues
so next slide if you do look at the
burners like a slight lag there are six
issues which came up on the rainiest and
which we talked about extensively I've
basically fixed all of those um in
addition to that I promised in the
winners iOS meeting I would do some SC
art to describe the use case behind this
a bit better actually I didn't do that
yet so there will be another ref with
just the SQ out basically because I hate
it and I have to find the will power to
actually do them I have put something in
this lighter here to explain this this
use case though so this flows addressed
yard really soon the real discussion
point i have now with it is now that
i've wrapped my head around these use
cases about when are multiple rachel's
available
the texts has done some acknowledgment
of the identity selection hints in the
e.r SC on which some thought could our
fix the problem in a more easy way the
more I look at this I believe the
identity selection well it's actually
rather implemented pretty much anywhere
and if it were it only has 256 bytes to
transmit identity information which is
way too few to be useful but even if it
were sufficient um it still doesn't
solve the problem so I think the text
about identity selection hints can
basically just go away because it
doesn't contribute to the problem
solving or explicitly say it doesn't
help now the reason why I think that is
on this next slide and this is here this
wonderful s yard so when the use case
basically came in prominently with the
new Wi-Fi line specification on past
point or also hotspot to point though
depending on how you want to call it
both names exist so let's assume the
user has a device with a sim card in it
and the operator has pre-configured the
device so that authenticates with the
sim card to cellular networks just like
as usual but also that it is allowed to
use all Wi-Fi access points which have
passed point enabled and indicate in
their beacons support for this specific
MNC MCC combination um that's just a
config item in itself and there's
nothing wrong with that the user from
that device also has a credential for a
other Roman consortium just for Wi-Fi
let's form of the suits the eduroam
Roman consortium and he has a config
pushed into his device which says ok you
can use this credential for the Wi-Fi
network with the SSID eduroam or for any
other Wi-Fi pass network which indicates
support for the roaming consortium
identifier and then there is this 5 x
identify which is basically 0 so at some
point the user comes to a JP protected
network there is an authenticator
and since he has different usernames for
those two credentials the one is fuji TV
network torg and tell dice whatever it
is at some point the authenticator has
to decide who can authenticate this user
so should i send the EAP requests to the
observer at the cellular network to an
ebay k prime or should i send it to the
radio server theorem consortium doing EP
GLS nothing wrong with that so on the
trouble starts when the authenticator
next slide actually is an access point
which has both criteria enabled so let's
say this is a Wi-Fi access point with an
SSID that is fubar so it's not relevant
here that it indicates you are allowed
to connect to me if you have a sim card
with this specific mcmc combination and
you're also allowed to connect to me and
that will authenticate you if you have a
credential with this past point
consortium end in fire now the device
looks up its local config and realizes
gosh actually I have a credential and I
can use it because I have this cell
phone provider my list and I also have a
TLS credential and I can use it because
i have this consult some identify and my
list so the client configuration simply
knows it has the choice to use both at
some point it has to try one um if that
doesn't work at twice the other the
important thing is and that's what the
document is all about when you try both
um always use the realm identifier which
matches your actual user identifier so
then just magically assume that you can
send one realm identifier and it will
try both methods in a row it just can't
do that because the routing depending on
the realm identifier might add that
might put you into a place where only
one of those will work and the other one
will never be tried this is the basic
problem space we are working in and
actually could exist also for wired
networks but these use cases are a bit
more more special it's basically
everywhere where the where the
authenticator cannot or indicates more
than one possibility to authenticate now
the problem with the identity selection
hints is if you are
put into the authenticator into the
Wi-Fi access point the identity
selection hints it simply does not help
because the Wi-Fi access point would
send in the EEP request identity but you
can use this or that and the choice for
the client is not narrowed down because
well they're both usable so they can
both be indicated in this message so it
just doesn't contribute to the problem
that the identity selections exist in
principle so since they don't help I
would prefer to reject them out and just
saying okay that's it and that is
actually the one issue I have so I
wonder what people think of that mmm i
would like to push out a new ref with
ascii art and then i hope that the
document has gotten enough meeting that
we can actually move forward to a
working group last call so this is alan
i have a question on oh not better is
that better yes ok mics are confusing
here i have a question an implementation
so how much does this change existing
implementations and who has to do this
and are all the access point vendors
aware they have to do this and are on
board with it so this is a bigger
question than just the supplicant side
what i can say is that the mention of
Wi-Fi access point manufacturers do
implement pass point these days so you
can just buy new cisco gear and or any
other window and it will have a config
option to do that the implementation
quality as always varies we have seen
that all the major all vendors on the
client side also indicate support for
past point so you have Microsoft Windows
10 there is also X iOS and even Android
in its newest version has the API is to
configure a pass point and react upon
beacons with pass point so in principle
the infrastructure is there actual
deployment I don't know we are looking
at this and at your own especially on
the client-side implementations also
vary in quality
on the lower end of the scale so we're
not quite happy with what we see there
but it is a problem that can come your
way any time and if I could add actually
the reason why I realized this issue a
long time ago was way before past point
was basically unique ignorant a
supplicant manufacturer in a mobile
phone which basically said okay you can
have as many credentials as you like but
as soon as you come in the vicinity of
any Wi-Fi access point I will try my
ebay k credential first and I will
always use the realm identifier from
3gpp Network the Lord so we actually had
customers in at your own who said I've
configured my mobile phone with the
right credentials I know my password is
correct but for some reason it never
actually authenticates and that is
because the routing of the request
always consistently failed luckily that
manufacturer has moved to android
meanwhile so their own implementation is
gone but you know back in the day I dry
like I thought I could just approach
when electrons tell him look you're
doing it wrong but it was never
mentioned as explicitly as it could be
but this is not something you should do
so that's what they stalk you mind is
trying to fix and this is you know in
another way is it is it will it be
simpler to say that it is assumed that
the user name the identity used in the
as a username will be relevant enough to
figure out which we are to address and
how how to do that it's not so relevant
for this document it's something that
Nick you can put rising simple text to
say that it is something to take into
account but we have the same issue with
diameter anyway yeah so um the document
already says it's up to local
configuration how to split the web Ram
identifier which is the equal sponsored
entity and the actual user identifier
which is whatever the method uses as an
identifier how you do that you I how you
ask the user I can't because this stuff
yeah so actually from my personal point
of view not as a sherbet as individual I
think it's enough okay shim shot okay so
I understand how to deal with issued to
you and I understand how to shoot number
three in your next steps um having a bit
of problem with one you've described a
problem and I will admit I'm tired so I
may have dozed off and missed exactly
what the options are for the solution so
that we can converge on the solution at
this point I'm kind of at this every
time I hear this is like we have a
problem it'd be nice and client
configuration could fix this to be nice
to find you I could fix this but we
really don't know what to tell clients
what to do on this so we don't really
have a solution it's just kind of client
devices should just keep trying things
until things become happy well it's not
actually something that needs fixing in
you I the UI's I know actually allow you
with your method to select which I'll
true identity you use what we call realm
identify I mean what so the UI why's
everything is fine the problem is much
more with the state machine and if you
have locally configured more than one
realm identifier well you have to
restart the new state machine after you
failed with one credential and you just
don't run one state machine for both eep
types that's not enough you have one if
state machine for one eep type if it
doesn't work and you want to try the
other one start fresh start fresh with
the new realm identifier that matches
the other reap type and then use that so
it's pretty much yeah back-end code in
the supplicants it's nothing to with you
I or changing configs the only conflict
ends you might want to have is for
privacy considerations if you want to
manually order your eep types and terms
of preference then the shake machine as
it goes along
should honor that that's the only change
Brian wise Cisco I'm a little confused
on the privacy situation so first
comment is that graph says you know
identifiers will be revealed and then it
says when privacy is aching important
and actually we're in an age where one
way developing protocols privacy is
always important so that's not a very
good statement actually we should be
designing otherwise but now the question
is in this example for example that
you're showing will the client device
try to use both of his credentials all
the time or just when he sees certain
pass points or other indicators from the
network you'll only use ones that match
which one is it yeah so this is the
situation way only tries a credential if
he knows it's going to work on this
particular criterion the other story I
told many years back was just ignorance
on these applicants he just did that
despite having new information I'm sorry
it's couldn't quite it was injected in
here exactly this is actually the
situation the eep type is only tried if
a local context says it is good for this
network yeah so that's not so bad i mean
least he's only responding when he's
getting some kind of indication of
course the network good or an attacker
could lie about that but it's a little
better than for example when we cycle
through all the SSID our device but i
would just suggest maybe making the
privacy statement obviously staying a
little bit stronger in that section and
explaining maybe you know where there's
better protection or not i mean it does
say that if you use the latest eep
methods you're in you're also somewhat
protected but i can not sure your
protect against an active attacker but
maybe you're protecting into passive
attacker then I don't know it that
should be may be made more clear yes I'm
all for making the privacy statements or
rigid no problem so basically for many
eep types which are in use today like
ttls peep and so on these private sex
engines do work we have some bleep labs
where they don't so a PWD on the
Dragonfly thing from from that hearkens
basically has no
possibility to hide the reuse identifier
so that's why the draft said rats s so
if you have these e types try those
lasts because you know okay so this
would be it is actually the two only
drafts we have to work on actively as a
working group at this point so here is
the new work um Jim chard for the RC
6614 this document and TLS 1.3
so when I volunteered for this I said oh
this will be easy no problems it always
is right um yeah I mean I I know exactly
what needs to be done here and it's easy
going towards up there's the next leg so
then I of course reread the documents
with an eye towards actually editing
them and said oh well there's a couple
of issues that i'm not exactly too sure
how to progress and there's a couple of
issues where i'm not too sure which
documents to progress so i'll cover
these things we can give some guidance
we can figure out which documents we
actually want to to rev whether we want
to combine some documents together while
we're doing the revving and see what
happens so there's a couple of nice
simple top-level topics that I need to
be covered how do you trust things what
does your tickets look like um how do we
want to actually say you should use
tickets whether you must use ticket
support tickets there's some real
advantages in doing so there's some
interesting questions about transport
layers and how things work or don't work
in terms of who does things what things
do which transport layers we want to run
over and then there's some some really
fast TLS option questions that we may
want to think about documenting as we go
forward next so trust months basically
there's to trust modes that are
essentially laid out in the current
document the first is to say oh yeah
well using CA infrastructure they're
relatively cheap but they're kind of
hard depending upon what sort of system
you're setting up to get everybody to
buy in the same infrastructure is of
course the pre-shared key which is
basically how radius is instead of today
you could continue to do that but of
course that's you know manual
configuration and gets to you know a
real mess in terms of trying to
configure it going forward uh this upon
Billy of using Dane and maybe doing some
some lookups in terms of trying to
establish is just the right cert to be
used but that still doesn't actually
solve the problem of do I trust the
entity that is the subject of the syrup
so it's like yeah this is a certificate
that's associated with you know food on
example for the domain but I still need
to make a decision is food on example a
domain I'm willing to talk to and is the
answer that they give back going to be
ace an answer i'm willing to actually
use in terms of doing things like
granting access to a network and things
like that um I actually briefly thought
about the whole question of should we
include the DNS lookup stuff in terms of
was in 75 85 and personally I'd actually
just rather bury that in the sand and
let someone else deal with it then put
it into this document so I mean if it
obviously we need to document the first
two in terms of how to do things I don't
know how much we want a document dane or
not document Dane in terms of
establishing trust in certificates since
it doesn't actually really solve the
problem it may merely kind of says yes
you have a certificate that's real but
it doesn't say anything about whether
you should trust the entity at the other
end okay next a certificate profile we
should probably actually talk about with
certificates what should be in a
certificate that is used for radius and
a lot of that is pretty simple we don't
currently have one arm policy OS is
certainly one way of establishing
whether or not you think they that a
particular trick of it is useful another
thing is extended key usages often the
times used there's a few other things we
need to talk about which is things like
so what sort of naming do we need to put
insert if
it's do we put in DNS naming do we put
in IP naming do we put in something else
that is URL based or in realm based in
AI something or other which would just
be kind of please no spare me arm so
most of that stuff I've got some ideas
in terms of how to go forward in push so
so I'm not immediately too worried about
these things next oops sorry I should
have talked about that already ticket
TLS 1.3 is making tickets and a whole
lot more useful I mean they exist in the
current systems but with 1.3 they just
become extremely useful so basically
what you can do is you can go through
the full validation process now send a
certificate generate diffie-hellman keys
do your client verified be your
certificate verify and say oh and now
that I've sent you the first message
give me back a set of tickets what that
means is the second time you hook up you
say here's the ticket from when you
validated me last time and here's the
pre-shared key that we used on this and
we don't have to do anything about
sending certificates around because we
already know the answers to all those
questions so basically you're really
reducing Rica next time or setting up a
second channel if we basically say yeah
you have to support tickets and that's
potentially a huge win just because you
save the cost on certificate validations
on both ends next so this is basically a
real fast look at some of the advantages
you get with us 1.3 in terms of
handshakes um this is kind of a really
scaled-back version of what things look
like so that if you do pre care to see
pre-shared key that the
application can actually send encrypted
data along with that message so this
says that not only when I if I use
tickets and you reconnect do I not have
to go through all the certificate stuff
I'm actually going to send my request up
on that first message whatever that
first set of a great whatever that first
rate hike it is so I'm really reducing
the number of messages i'm sending
between the server and the client and
radius by doing this this pre shared
secret ticket resumption because i'm
sending that message up the first time
i'm still actually saving things in
terms of if you look at the difference
between 1.2 and one and 1.3 and TLS
because in 1.3 even if you go through
that full certificate validation you can
send encrypted data up on your second
message whereas in 1.2 is basically it's
the third message that this client sends
out that they can finally send encrypted
data so in any event you're saving one
round trip and you're potentially
basically not having any round trips on
your encrypted data with with with the
ticket resumption if you set up parallel
dls ports so next this is where I
started getting into the funds of switch
exactly documents that my air being
revved and who needs to read them so if
you look at it there the the TLS over
TCP actually came as jus documents the
first described but to do with TLS the
second described what to do with TCP all
the TVs piece in Trey one did one one to
the other and if you look at it radius /
/ DTLS that was another document so both
of those documents are experimental
documents as well so at a minimum if we
want to do the TCP at over TLS
over tcp we probably need to rev the the
TCP document is unclear at this point
how many people care about doing DTLS
but as possible we want to read that
document as well to get it upped it up
from experimental the standards track so
this is Ellen again I believe there are
a fair number of people using DTLS to
connect their thousand hot spots access
points to their central controller but
not many people use it across the public
internet and which from attention now
these using uh it's a pretty much one
hundred percent rad SEC proxy and over
here we thought nobody was in traffic
proxy DTLS milk um and and when I've
send a message to Alan back in in in may
say I kind of interested in these things
get one of the messages he sent back
just cause my eyes to glaze over since
I'd actually never heard of sctp but is
something he was saying well maybe we
should look at this as a transport layer
going forward because it has some
interesting characteristics that might
actually be useful in terms of avoiding
some of the things like headline
blocking on not TCP um the other thing
that I immediately started running into
problems as I read these documents was
trying to figure out exactly what was
supposed to happen as you went between
boundaries of these things and who was
doing recentiy was not doing reasons why
were people who are doing reasons so the
the TCP document says hey this is a
reliable transport you never do a recent
because it's reliable transport that
works great right up until you say I'm
doing TCP up to this proxy and from that
proxy to the actual server is UDP ok now
send
who is responsible for doing the replay
the nast isn't going to do it because it
thinks is talking to reliable transport
the proxy is not going to do it because
proxies don't recent so the answer is
nobody does it that's probably not a
workable answer the other thing the
other world would be even as spurs on
UDP and it goes to a proxy which
converts between UDP and TCP the man's
is going to start potentially hammering
that that reliable TCP channel with
retransmits because things are timing
that somewhere down the line maybe
because nobody wants to talk to him but
there's additional traffic on the TCP
channel that doesn't actually need to be
there because well you got that far and
then somebody else's problem beyond that
who's reliable there's also some
interesting questions that they come up
in terms of the big message stuff that
went through it may be very nice if you
go from UDP to tcp and TCP to UTB to
reassemble those big messages so it's
basically you know unless you first UDP
hop I can confirm back real fast get the
entire message send the big message over
my big TCP pipe which may actually end
up going straight to the server and save
a whole lot of round trips on the
server's half behalf so that's useful
you're using our next this isn't all
that interesting there's a whole slew
possible set of things that be done um
next also question is which documents
need to be done and revved and am I
going to wrap all of them or some other
people going to wrote them at a minimum
I think we need to biz that's easy p
document or else wrap that into the TLS
document okay
Thanks maybe one quick question but
we're running a bit over x or no ok so
the next one will be the laura1 draft
Hyuna maroon I'm one of the author of
this draft and this is 0-1 version of
the draft and we got some comments for
the 00 version so the main motivation of
the draft is to include the existing to
play infrastructure into the laura1
infrastructure for authentication so
next slide so this is about the laura1 a
long-range wide area networks and we
have some impressive numbers it's taken
from the LP 1 buff so here there here we
have the N do in device and this is the
mass our network server in this case and
the N device communicates to the network
server through the radio gateway and
this is actually the picture from the
buff but actually available laura1
specification doesn't have the joint
server so all the authentication is
taken place from the network server
point of view so and initially we have a
pre-shared key between the end device
and the network server and after the
joint procedure we have arrived at the
session Keys so which are used to
decrypt and encrypt the communication
between the end device on the network or
the in device on the application server
next slide so our motivation is to
replace this joint server which was
actually not in the current
specification but to replace it with to
play server and the network server
communicates with the to play
server in with a radius protocol looks
like so while to play wii I mean as you
know that it's battle-tested and it's
deployed in the wild since years example
ready Eddie Rome and it's also scalable
it's suitable for the Internet of Things
and its Federation our suitable for
roaming next so now I'm going to take
you over the current procedure which is
used in the lower line so we have the
commissioning which means that app au
app key which is the pre-shared key
between the end device on the network
server and also we have that DVD y which
is unique to each of the device next
slide so first the device sends a joint
request with some kind of unknowns along
with Debbie you I along with the WI and
a pu y to the network server and then it
talks hour after verifying the
credentials that means app app key so it
sends back the joint request already
joined except and this device can be
able to derive the session case later on
next slides so this would be the
contents of the request and the response
the main fields to note note here is the
app eyw I unknowns a py is more specific
for the application provider and every
why is specific for each of the device
and the nonce is created by the device
itself and in the response apt nonce is
generated by the network's server and
net ID and the dev address are also
generated from the network server so
here the request is sent without the
encryption but attached with the mick
that is message integrity code and but
the response is always encrypted from
the network server so the n device can
decrypt the response with the help of
the app app key so the app key makes the
message that will show you check yes ok
so we calculate the musical sighnaghi
yes so these are the keys which are
involved in authentication part the up
key
is a pre-shared between the device on
the network server and the network
session key is used or is derived and
it's used to encrypt or decrypt the
commands or my commands between the
network network server and the in device
and the app session key is used for the
application specific data for now it's
what the keys are reside residing within
the network server so i can you cook
como slice so our proposition would be
to include the radius server which which
i mean in which actually does all the
jobs of the network server and we
exchange the keys through the radius
attributes so and yeah so in this case
the network the app session key we have
put two stars which means you can decide
to send to back to the network server
are you reading and you can share it
with another application server server
through another interface Oh next slide
so we plan to introduce three sorry this
for new attributes in the radius and we
considered the RFC 6 to 18 or 6 6 14 for
maintaining the security to transmit the
keys over the network next slide and one
open issue is that we have this a pu I
from the device n device and we need to
have some kind of a methodology to map
it with the application owner so we need
so basically when the network server or
network access server gets this request
it has to check the realm of the
application owner and use a dns a query
or something like that to send it to the
appropriate radius server so one such
solution which we found was some 0 for 3
but we need to do the inverse of this
thing
to make this happen the next life I mean
we tried to implement we implemented
actually a proof of concept we run the
radius implementation in go language and
probably we are thinking of implementing
the using the free radius for the Laura
nice thanks for everyone for the
comments and okay okay well then I have
fun mmm basically this slaw here says
you the Nexus request that you hack the
entire join requests with pipe it into a
single radius attribute the content
looks like this and that's pretty much
structured data so we have motor
subfields in one radius attribute we
don't usually like how attributes that
way we can also decide each each of
these parameters into a different radius
attribute that's what I'm getting at
there yes and no I mean I mean I believe
its 6158 that says where there are data
structures pre-existing elsewhere and
transported by radius unmodified you can
just transport them as is the thing is
basically the register bandits to tears
apart to do all the key calculations so
it needs some kind of a business logic
here the reason why we like to send
without modifying anything is that at
this point of time the network access
server doesn't have the access to the
app key so you have the mick calculated
based on the up key yeah but you can
protection using radios Shetty's or
whatever use so don't think that would
be an issue anyway for example the
device you I that's basically MAC
address if I got that right we usually
call this calling station ID and the
attribute exists already so yes yes or
no I mean my two cents is an implementer
in some respects would be easy if this
easier for this was all just radius
attributes on the other hand I do have a
low thing for re-implementing things
multiple times if there's some kind of
library which already does all of this
and I can just link to it and pass it a
blob then I'm happy right and it's it's
much easier the more complicated issue
is what policies do people want based on
this so if people are going to say if
the net ID is this then respond with a
different radius thing or if this other
lower Oh Enfield is that then do it
something else then it would be more
useful to split them out into radius
attributes and at this point just use TL
v's because it works so it's a matter of
what the use case is if your Express if
you expect this to be transported as is
and not really examined by anyone other
than a little bit of crypto dedicated to
this protocol it's probably okay to
transport it as is if the radius server
needs to do things based on the contents
you probably need to break it out so
yeah as a chair ne ne ne so we're not
responsible for defining the functional
solution so from from the lower point of
view is there any expectation to have
such kind of a solution based on radius
or it is a you are you are trying to
proposing some things that could be
after afterward
accepted by a zero a community how do
you how do you see the the rest of this
work assuming that this work is a grid
here in this working group usually in
this in this working group right now so
we are we're responsible for the
definition of the protocol but not how
this protocol is used by others so it
could be other working group inside the
ATF are in a service do so actually we
will work on this on the actor if there
is an existing requirements so i was
wondering what is the current
expectation from the lower community on
that right now actually we have not that
from the lp one group at maybe down the
future i have a comment from the driver
Dan Garcia say I agree with Alan we
agree with only one attribute there will
be an implementation that processes the
missus the massage aziz thank you know
to tie we had a meeting on Sunday
technical meeting on the p1 and we have
some people that say that it was a good
idea to implement this kind of things
okay because I think that the most
important part for us from red X
perspective HS past exhibit to ensure
that there is a supports and some
requirements from this community to be
able to develop that whatever I think
that from a technical point of view we
can discuss and especially the link
between what's come from the Alara and
what you want to export to a radio
server but i think that from from a
protocol it could be straightforward we
just need to to agree on the set of
attributes i may have some concern about
that and the way the attributes are
defined but the most important part is
to ensure that this work reserve the
lower community if not we will not be
able to say oh from the hf point of view
are seeking that this is a best solution
and and i think what would be at least
we tried from a problem statement point
of view it's to to consider the
different cases yet that you may have
regarding the location of the triple a
server if it is expected to have
multiple multiple players if it is the
same kind of during the both on LP one
there were some discussion about roaming
for instance but I don't really know
what's what is the the current
requirements regarding is rooming so I
think that this kind of stuff could
first of all good first of all militates
or I don't even know if it is English
but actually a promote the use of a
triple a beta a triple a basic
infrastructure and obviously 24 red you
server in that case okay so one quick
question for me is this is the lack of
radius attributes and the lack of an RFC
here holding back lower wall in any way
so is this urgent work that doesn't
allow you to continue it would be great
if you have these the various attributes
defined elderly yeah but when you use it
earlier that the triple-a part doesn't
really exist and right now the keys are
validated run right don't usually they
do everything in the network access
server itself okay so the standard as
such is working already you just said
they have discussion about the using
this Jason tunnel to communicate with
join server or something like that yeah
actually see if I understood correctly
the joint server doesn't exist as of now
in a lot of specification available to
the public they don't have the entity
called joints our ok so now they want to
decorate both type of server and and
it's where there is a discussion yes ok
we need to move on ok thank you
okay so for the next one there are no
slides out there's somebody here to talk
about it the multi-point the assisted
multipath TCP radios thing yeah no
competitor I yeah I have made the
presentation last time yeah the content
of the drug dealer since then and all
what I'd like to see that the content is
stable it adairs to the recommendation
from this working group and it's
fulfilled on the data type guidelines
and so on so it's just a request to
consider this as a new shelter item of
this working group yeah my question back
then was so it is actually being used is
it useful because the use case didn't
repair convincing but is it part of any
standard it depends what we what we call
standard it the sundial in fact which
exists with but it is not as wonder
about is an experimental track which is
in ptc psf which the the protocol that
defines the communication between the
two and that that support in participe
but you skillet we are targeting is
involves the cpe and another element
which located in the network which is an
another NP disappear and proxy which is
located in the concentrator and these
two entities are not songs are so far as
you know here in ATF it is difficult to
so not the TCP proxy staff even for TCP
existing networks but there is nothing
which is which is which is on the rise
so there is some magic there which is
this MPD CP proxies will glue multiple
paths the first that we ought to come
from the wireless network and the other
one that we've come from the wire land
and then it will glue this multiple
paths in order to increase the bandwidth
which is exposed to the cast and red
cell so the purpose dirty is to increase
the quality of experience of the
customers and also for the service
provider to optimize them because there
are some lines than access plans which
are all increasing this one to support
the new topologies is really capex and
opex consuming and there is a
a real trend today in the greater
community to to correlate multiple
access networks in order to provide
better service to the customers and the
NPDC p itself is deployed today in
various countries for instance in korea
telecom sk telecom Eugene in Korea drew
three of three deployments today based
on impedance approxi there's another
deployment in in Turkey based on in
participate proxy another one in belgium
in proximus which is based on another
input CP proxy but each time the dairy
implementing specific and proprietary
solution to authorize the customer who
subscribes to the offer to make use of
this one so what we are coming with the
strategy specification is to provide
something which is under eyes to auto
l-222 at well for this kind of service
providers to deliver the service to this
customer so MP DCP proxies in the
network today our deployments but we
want to go beyond the appropriate
solution to have something which is most
on the rez that's why we are seeking
your help on this on this part but maybe
based on this on this comment regarding
the use of MC p.m. MTG Sofia will be
pass maybe you can you can try to
convince people that it is a good
solution and to at least express the
interest for that on the mailing list I
think it was the basic question from
from Stefan things that I think that
from Zoe as I said for the previous
document from a protocol point of view
it's fine and actually you are following
the last recommendation so I I think
it's more about interest about about
this and if you at least if there is
some people interested by maybe even if
they are not used to but saying that
there is an existing requirement for
such kind of solution for authentication
particularly that don't figure to two
questions and the first ones you
interested in participating fighting
kids if there's a interesting
participate if it would be another
working group which this talk about that
I can invite people but I won't do that
because this is the purpose why aren't
coming here because there is expertise
about the radius extension so I think
that's for me the core point is to two
12-volt defines something which
which is completely this aligned what
you want to see in in erotic
specification so it will be hard to
convince the community in the radix
working group that impede ecp is good
it's it right it good if I have that but
I am NOT happy to see that and they want
i want fight to to see that because
there is no point there to do that this
is this is elegant I mean my two cents
is the the purpose of radix is not just
to extend radius but also to review and
accept and authorize other people's use
of radius and for one attribute that's
the use case is clear I'm you know I'm
happy with it it's it's partly true
because it's always possible to define
for instance under specific AV pieces
the question is that when when even if
we have a lot of room now the from from
a working group point of view you need
to ensure that it's 21 swear to request
but not only to someone but to two
people that will implement this yeah so
in it was not something against you
actually my colleague it was more about
to answer to this defender come and
saying that just to ensure that we are
doing something that actually even may
be used but I key that may be useful for
forces yeah related question is if the
rest of NP TCP is experimental why not
publish this is experimental I'm it
doesn't necessarily require a working
group draft it can just be published
with radix group going yet that makes
sense yeah and I think it was just to be
able to figure out what will be a as a
way forward for these documents so sorry
we are we are light we will not skip the
other one we just to say that we will so
we'd be late so the next one maybe we
can try to shorter maybe the
presentation but
and between at just time for some
comments so please I Ronnie yeah a and 0
this okay I'm anchor chain from cisco
systems this is a joint work with my
colleague lay machine from Cisco so this
is a okay I'm we are trying to finish
environment so this is the problem
statement I think this is where no into
the to the to folks in this room and to
the working group so this is body why
add 1 by to identify field which
basically allows only 256 requests in
flux you know that right so the work
around and basically document you might
put multiple IVs and is to to do the
work run basically you create the pyro
no station uses you using the multiple
source port in case of tcp of course
it's a true parallel notation X please
so the issue we are facing and at the
vendor actually as a reference so a
suspect that the problem is not unique
so currently we have actually deployment
we have an implementation and he pointed
at used to hundreds of UT positions in
the indicates a wireless wireless LAN
controller but it's the rental Hendricks
and for the next generation product the
requirements basically increase increase
this performance by 10 X ok you can
imagine now it goes two sovereigns of
sessions that's case I think very
difficult it's just so this so this is a
problem that I mean the ones a scale
goes to surveillance of sessions
basically you have you have a number of
issues right you have a resource
utilization a memory you have cpu you
have the local port local bodies limited
right and you have efficiency issues and
you get a TCP I mean it puts a lot of
load on your own or you're basically on
the client as words on the summer
harmonization can summer support if
these
wine a client actually connects generate
thousands of station right the
operational this implementation at the
operational complexity next page please
so here we basically we look at this
which is basically it seems there's
opportunity really for us to actually
address this it looks you know I I
really am new to this to to this radius
working group I have construed an upper
document looks like this the issue has
been postponed but VI I believe we have
a time that we are at points and these
need to be addressed in the protocol
instead of doing work run so this is a
that's what it is extension is about
basically we we propose a extended
packet header but basically to enlarge
the identifier field while we are doing
that we also it looks like reasonable to
also a large the code field ecotype
because that is that is a one-bite I
think we currently use about fifty-fifty
son so if we have a quarter then we will
basically to be future proof let's do
the Cabbage advice and be done with it
right so there's a then the way to hear
the key for this you know proposal is to
basically reserved to allocate a packet
we cope I are thinking in this
group because you really become message
type here we call package type code and
so as a carrier to in pain to actual the
real you know packet inside then we use
a capability basically to discover their
way that is the server is supporting it
so suppose is functionally next one
please right this is the this is the
extremely package a that we are
proposing so the first if you look at a
in the in the current standard here we
have the the first batch is that it's a
package code so we had to be used the
allocated my special one and the next
one we is a reserve field the ninth is
the same authentication is the same
become another reserved view that in the
code if you look at code is shifted
it's like a two bites named identify
four bytes so the somatic should be made
the same so these the why we have this
resolved field it's basically the
concise the bias is for the existing
protocol analyzers right if we with this
format we can at least pass it and
syntactical right yeah that's a bit if
if the if you focusing is working group
view that is not necessary of course
then we can reduce it right that we
don't feel that leaves the ID other two
by Scotty certainly we got a can be
reduced all right makes my face so the
how would this work basically you use
you the client initiated this stutters
stutters server message right with a new
attribute you basically to do the
discovery of capability on so that's a
pretty standard looks like right another
way o.o if you know that's a source it
is something that so much support spike
on you got to bike configuration right
so here once the capability is
discovered always is no universe right
you here interim implementation so we
recommend in the draft attached we
reserve the existing 0 to 255 the
numbers face and for the standard head
because if I discover or whatever right
and is it for the upper for the larger
numbers you use that as a as I
identified fill for the extent of it
yeah buzzer is this cover you can now
you can basically each year to the
packaging imposed for match in the
standard header or extended head I think
that's it so what you because this so
whatever we like to do exist we want to
solicited feedback from this working
group and the respect to address our
concerns and also basically 2k some
operational implementation fear
certainly from the cisco iOS
implementation and also with the open
source probably
Baku visa-free radius hopefully by next
IDF we have more basically
implementation curing disease so we like
basically address the concerns and spin
the drafter one more time and of course
be onesies we would like to see the bath
we adopted at that good could I first
make note that with my chair head on so
this is actually a substantial
modification to the protocol um we had a
similar one just last week basically
which is the a larger packets for radius
of a tcp but that was experimental it
was over a new transport anyway so these
were all fresh implementations what you
have here basically requires all of the
industry to update all their their
equipment and that's a whole different
story so here he is yeah actually I read
the number of drafts I also we have you
thinking we saw the part of this it
looks like actually the church is
although conceptually yeah it is a
fundamental I agree but the church is in
really limit to the header the encoding
and decoding so my I have a look at some
other some code it's look at my sense at
this point is probably a few hundred
lines of code Shh because it's really
limited in in the infection of encoding
at you Cody yeah living so but I don't
have that I don't have a concrete data
but that's just my sense yeah so this is
Alan um yeah something like this has
been needed for 10 years doing it is a
whole other nightmare as a point of
information there is at least one
commercial radius server which extends
the identifier space via of VSA they
simply put a VSA into every packet and
the client and the server have a
configuration flag saying allow this
vsause this VSA there's no negotiation
no nothing it's a hundred percent
compatible with existing radius that
might be simpler and and would work
without changing anything
this changing the header if you're going
to throw out the header you might as
well throw everything out and start over
from scratch which sounds sounds
familiar i think we did that but i but
they seemed we have with the radius
product we have these discs our mattress
that'll be that seems to be a nice way
to deal with the backward compatibility
to be technical the status server isn't
really about discovery it's been abused
to be discovery we have had capability
negotiations and radius going back 10
years right and everyone has run away
from them because they're different lady
is why that the reputed its capability
negotiation make use of it yeah ginell
as a individual i think it's a perfect
use case for diameter which saying if
the if if the idea is to change the
error if you can rely i didn't
investigate any any any solution for
that but if you can rely on a tribute
it's okay i think that if the real goal
is to enable to add will keep more than
250 556 concurrent operations it's the
it's it's because you have a clean it or
something more and more in that case is
diameter it's not i think you'd see
where we need to take care about how to
extend and so on and and and and as set
by us define if the consequence even if
it is simple from your point of view to
update the other the error n to modify
the also client and the servers to be
able to support that it's a huge impact
and and on all the existing
implementation and actually what we are
trying to do in this protocol is to
extend the protocol functionalities but
iranian something that anyone can decide
to support or to ignore yeah but is this
really i stand the principle this really
does not a violent that pretty simple
right so it's basically negotiation
basis based yeah
right so here it is just a very very
practical a challenge we have today I've
advocate with that the data point you
know implemented we have hundreds now we
are going to south I mean that's just
that this is just I mean to people who
have not been associated with the radius
who have not work it sounds really the
first time we talked about this sound
really silly then of course we have a
history right so it's just as Ireland
for now it's this new year with the
problem just one small additional
comment and I and after that I will let
the floor and we will flow the meeting
but the point is that for so for
instance for diameter it is said that it
is used in mobile network and join it's
fine it's it's it's expensive and so on
and and the fact is that everything
based on reduce as it is today is fine
for the current deployment and even
future functionalities now if we think
that the protocol is not so fine and we
need also to modify the protocol itself
not only at a adding attribute to be
able to support this kind that is a key
issue for you as you see a thing I think
it's oh it's always time to think about
how to redefine also how the triple-a
infrastructure using such kind of an
environment but that's all appreciate ya
my name is my mission from Cisco so so I
was thinking this so-called a
fundamental change is still if you don't
support it you don't support it right
from our a company point of view if we
have such a use case and we also have
the suicide of the supports and it's
nice to do although I agree to go to
things like a diameter is a simpler but
this is a protocol needs to move forward
right ah if we keep delaying this thing
this issue is a real issue are navigate
the soft right so if you
as another at the reference so for folks
who actually who do know me i have been
involved in the routing protocol area
for a number years so weary tradition I
don't know do you guys pay attention we
transition the global internet from 25
years into four bodies in DDP that is
the sole fundamental right but buddy
what's done is done really nicely now
the tradition where you were you paid
piece by piece spaces and the backward
compatible and the whole world has
tradition this this shall be some
fundamental but it seems to me is really
the big here in st. so full of of the
concept atacan concept from they were
not to know myself my feeling is that as
a as a product designer and also at the
at the coder my sense is that this this
is really a few hundred lines cultures
are we get more tea than later next one
okay yeah so I'm trying to find some
nice closing words but so I think we
honor I think what agree that this is a
problem worth solving and it's hitting
the streets so that's no doubt about
that now you have a solution here which
is a bit more heavy weight than what I
told us about with the VSA and I think
we should all go home and think about
how do we best solve this problem is it
sufficient to well not have to be as I
but standardized an attribute for the
extended header or something extended
identifier or you do do this rather big
change um so I think our options are do
we apply the band-aid on one place or
another and is it a small piece of n
tight or a big piece of band-aid the
truth is radius is pretty much as its
limits here and we can't do without
band-aid so we have to less than perfect
options on the table I think and yeah we
have to make up our minds yeah please do
that okay
so thanks for staying longer than we
allocated anyway and for next time I
will try to allocate 90 minutes because
actually we have plenty to talk about so
thanks for coming goodbye