yes yes Randall is here what was the
question is are you in the country and
dad the meeting Oh lava it's a shared
session the I meeting doesn't start
until eleven-thirty yeah you good to go
it is one minute past ten it's time to
begin welcome to the very exclusive slim
working group we were going for opulence
rather than a room fitting of the actual
size of the group so so yeah well begins
that we're going to have a pretty short
meeting today we've got a few things to
go through mostly around the two
documents that we have will go through
the agenda quickly Lucas is our Java
scrub thank you very much for that we do
not have a normal scribe with somebody
like to be the normal scribe are so many
hands so much choice oh why thank you
Brian
thank you so much for that any method
you prefer is fine I so are Jabbar is
limbs limit Jabberjaw I have two orch
Bernard and I your chest over here today
which is great right jab escribe we've
what we're passing around a blue sheet
just one blue sheet make sure you get it
I will check at the end we have ones
outside during we need another one we we
do have at least one remote presenter
green ours going to be presenting
remotely towards the end of the meeting
so please speak clearly and slowly and
say your name into the mic I like when
people do slow named statements into the
mic it seems to be a thing ITF which you
have to say your name really really
quickly into the mic in the most
inaudible fashion so you get as you
don't get any awards for saying your
name slowly it's just nice cool alright
so this is the note well this is how we
do things here at the idea if you can't
abide by said rules and please let us
know I guess or leave or one of those
things it's very small but it's it's on
the website so please if you put ITF
note well into your favorite search
engine you'll be able to find it and
press ctrl + until it's at a font size
which is good for you to read cool um a
little note about our expectations with
respect to IPR declaration there is
something called RFC 6701 which is
sanctions available for application to
violators of ITF IPR policy and these
are some quotes from it that we'd like
to remind the audience of the impact of
an IPR disclosure has on a smooth
working of the ITF is directly related
to how late in the process the
disclosure is made the IPR situation is
considered at key times such as adoption
of the document and during last call the
slim working group will be going to work
in group last call on several of these
documents shortly and our expectation is
that we will receive IPR declarations no
later than the end of that last call not
forming to the ITF scipy our policy
undermines the work of the ITF and
sanctions ought to be applied against
offenders and working group chairs are
empowered to take action so we'd like to
put people on notice that we are
considering the application of RFC 6701
and we would like those disclosures to
be made in the timely way that we expect
Brian Rosen thank you you're welcome on
behalf of the not cool thank you for
that awesome so yeah we have a like I
said we have a brief agenda today we're
going to have a quick overview on slim
the slim docks nick has a presentation
to do on a slim multi multi line content
oh sorry I was specific 01 there it's 01
not a 00 I'm apologies that's my mistake
and random doesn't have slides but we'll
just perhaps give a quick verbal update
on on on negotiating human language yes
that second then we're going to have a
next steps conversation what's happening
with the documents any new work that we
might want to do and we have a lot of
overflow time cool all right so i think
we'll move over to nick if you're okay
to present that's fine I'll go to the
slides all our documents obviously on
data tracker if you want to have a look
at the actual document you know where to
go slim data tracker IDF in your
favorite search engine will find it cool
all right okay this is just a quick
status update next slide please there
were a few comments from the last
meeting that's that's resulting in a new
version of the document the main comment
that came back resulted in quite a big
change to the structure of the
multi-language message itself and the
main change now is that the the first
part of the multilingual
layout is a single text plain part and
after that then you've got one or more
message stash I to the 822 or message
less noble language parts and they were
originally it was stated in the document
that they could be anything you like any
more tightly liked and that wasn't ideal
because each of those parts had subject
feels so the idea of the message IFC 822
was that the legacy clients will
definitely recognize others I don't
think you're talking into the mic it's
not better yes okay okay so the message
I've c82 to change was mainly so the
subject field can be picked up because
as a subject field in each of those
message parts the language message parts
anyway so that's now been updated on the
document and the language independent
part which goes right to the end that's
also a message osea to to type or
message globe or as long as it matches
the types or the other language parts
then that's right but with that part
there isn't a subject because if that's
in a mentally in a language this
completely nonspecific and the reasoning
reasoning behind the text plane for the
first part in multilingual preface is
that that's the reasoning for that part
to be them in the first place is very
similar to the mine preface so that it's
only ever going to be seen by clients
that they aren't compliant and don't
understand what the multilingual my
subtype is so it needs to be just as
simple as possible
and text plain I think there's a good
run dirt that has tested really well in
emails I've been sending around next
slide please in the previous version the
security considerations were
non-existent that was picked up in one
of the comments and I've now updated
that so that the main concern that was
raised was for spam filters that didn't
delve into each individual sub part of
the message I'm not sure how light it is
that's going to be because that seems
got a naive approach but that's now be
changed that's good consideration
seconds we in change that it does at
least mention that as a risk so that was
a good commenter to get back at the end
of last session so as you can see that's
the new version is I one on the end and
i've added three quite detailed examples
with the new formatting and updated
security considerations section next
slide I have been doing some testing
with that new format it's worked pretty
well but I would like to do a little bit
more testing using the examples directly
out of the internet draft just to be
absolutely sure that they they do test
well so I'll send those through to the
list of volunteers that I asked for last
time and I'm also going to send it to
the slimmest itself so everyone can have
some fun there was one concern still
that i had about these huge
considerations and that was that you
could potentially have an impersonation
issue where because each of the parts is
a message i see 822 it could have from
fields that could potentially say
something different to the very outer
most top level from field so that's
something I I think i should put in them
I'm not sure how lightly anyone would
would try to take advantage of that but
that's something that I want to
highlight just to make sure that people
have had that in mind when they
implemented me there was also comment
from last time about contacting some
multinational large male providers
getting them involved with doing some
preliminary testing and working towards
potential implementations i'm not sure
if now is the right time to actually
contact those people and get them
involved or whether it's it should be
after the RFC is published and then
changes that that they recommend could
be applied as a later version so maybe
some feedback on that would be ideal and
as always the discussions have been
going on this limb working group there's
not a lot of activity going on I think
we've pretty much near the end now but
that's the best place of thing because
in wherever you are in the world you can
just join in and doesn't have to be at
the actual event so that's pretty much
it for me thanks cool thank you Nick
does anyone have any questions for Nick
about the draft or comments Brian Rosen
to that to the last point I mean the ITF
is you know rough consensus of running
code so now it's much better than later
so if we could get folks to participate
that that would be great I think you got
the chicken and egg right which side has
to be running before the other side is
willing to participate i think as the is
the problem i personally know some folks
who would like to have this work and
they generate mail but they don't
in the infrastructure right they just
use the infrastructure so I think it's
easy to get people who would like to get
this to work yeah to try it on large
mail lists but they wouldn't be willing
to do it unless both the the system that
they use to send mail and their their
target mail lists recipients clients
could both use it and and so I think
that that we you know we have in order
to get it to work we got a lot of work
to do but maybe we can all work you know
grab the people we know and yeah see if
we can get them to to try these
implementations because I I know that
there are lots of people who want this
yeah and and so it's a question of how
we get it deployed thank you I think
Nathaniel and John Levine have offered
some contact details of those kind of
people so Latico chose to yet Oh Alex
tomography I just there are some people
from google co going to be in ut a
working group today so you they might be
good I got people to talk to you know
about you know whether they would be
interested to help you test this and
which work computer ugh okay okay thanks
okay great yeah I'm just winding that
down for the actions of everyone cool
thank you so much Nick right vandal it's
time for you to give a nice update on
your draft or sit there talking that's
also fine right um look at that magic
right Randall yes please give a very
small verbal update on your draft if
that's okay so there were some editorial
revisions made in a result result of
comments that were received from the
previous version no technical changes
it's nice and short and sweet I like
that how's your security considerations
section looking I think it looks pretty
good okay that's good obviously you know
I I try to I try to put more in and a
lot of people do in their security and
privacy considerations so that I try to
head off lots of nitpicky comments later
on but obviously i'm very happy to
entertain any further comments that
people have on it one tells me as a
chair i need to ask such questions so
things are dumb cool alright i'm holding
oh I know guna has some stuff Dee but
that's he's talking in the aob so
holding on gunas comments um does
anybody else have questions about this
draft for for round or tool negotiating
human language in the real-time draft
who we're getting through it cool thank
you so much for that random awesome
alright so i will switch back over to
the agenda our next topic is the next
steps for these drafts so Bernard and I
have been speaking about this and it
looks like this is a good time to move
the drafts into working group last call
do you want are you happy to do a home
for that or you just happy to sit
probably yeah okay that sounds like a
good idea so clear your throats everyone
so first talk about the draft that Nick
was that knickers Nick took us through
the multiple language content type of
for hum if you agree that this should be
moving into working group last call now
that's it well how about humming if you
think it should not be at working group
last time yeah Wow okay learning every
day randall gallons i just had one
question about moving a multi-line
content type into last call and that's
it Nick you mentioned that you were you
were growing if I understand you you
said you were going to be making some
changes to the security considerations
section so my question is based on the
extent of those changes should we wait
for that with
vision and go to worse working group
last call based on that so adding items
to the security considerations in
particular yeah right so yeah I think
that summary is basically we'll wait
till your revision and this is nick
tompkinson i will be changing the
critical situations so it's adding
another paragraph it's not like a huge
bunch of texts this is Barry liebe how
how soon will you turn that around it
can be within the days so we've
definitely so then we might start
working group last call at the at the
end of the meeting the end of the IETF p
yeah yeah if you're happy with that
that's fine I'm great thank you so much
for that Nick all right oh um note that
down the and maintenance 60 um let's
yeah so let's rerun it are we okay so
hun now if you are happy with the plan
being that Nick will add his items
security can oh hum now if you object to
beginning working group last call at the
end of the week assuming that Nick posts
a revision yeah what Barry said what
Barry said now no sorry well now I'm
getting confused okay hum if you Jackie
Schechter with blue Thank You Barry it's
an uphill struggle
um okay cool all right so right let's
move on to the negotiating human
language and real-time communications
draft this is something we've been
discussing on the list for a long time
we seem to resolve some issues that we
had on the list so it's a good time to
move to working group last call I do
want to take that hungriness on the my
segment push the red button do you know
you're up okay yeah uh before we take
you this into last call I think we would
like a new revision Randall agreed to
make changes already in eight of April
and we haven't seen any and we also
concluded that the all the discussion
about the Lang attribute should be
deleted so can we see a new version
before we go into law school I gather
this is randall gallons i did take your
comments into consideration the revision
that i posted that the one that's up
there did take into consideration your
comments that some of the text was
either overly specific or confusing so I
I did tone down the discussion of the
previous lang and I did make a few other
minor changes along those areas I know
you did send another word document I've
been reviewing that but I think that we
can go to working group last call on
this version and then if you Eddie if
you have additional comments you know we
can take that as working group last call
comments I mean I'm happy to make
further changes I just don't see
anything that is a that needs to be done
you know if you object but let me know
cool I
are you that so depending on how how
clean we shall have the diversion before
we make the last call I didn't see the
changes you say you made the long
discussion about in validity of the Lang
attribute is still there for example and
if that has there is still a discussion
about the existing Lang attribute as
justification for what we're doing it's
informative it's not normative and it's
based on the understanding that we had
and I did make revisions to that in view
of your comments if you go and look at
the data tracker history with the side
by side gifs you can see the changes
that were made in that section and into
that tax okay cool thank you for that I
think Bernard you can shout if you feel
otherwise I think the the plan of going
to work in group Glasgow and taking
action are taking any more comments on
that as working group last call comments
is sufficient so we'll go on that on the
basis of the harm and the learning curve
has been completed I'm going to ask does
anyone object to going to working group
last call on this laughs please harm now
fantastic so we'll move the real-time
draft to working group last call great
thanks so much for that so let me just
put back over to our agenda so we'll
we'll go how long do we spend in working
group last call Bernard well I guess
we'll for both of these I think we just
said we'll try to do this by the end of
the week begin it and then I mean
weekend the minimum i guess is two weeks
right and we could do it longer if
people you know it's summer so perhaps a
month
would be my suggestion I don't know what
others think three weeks yeah so well
we'll come up with specific specifics
about obviously people should send their
comments to the list that we always do
that we will talk about whether they can
submit them as issues and all of that
kind of administrivia but that's a
general general plan yes actually
regards to this I did want to ask a
question we do need to work on issues
we're trying to work out which is the
best way to submit issues if you have
any major objections to use we have two
possible methods right now using github
for our issues or using the IETF tracker
issues tracker so if you have objections
to either maybe post them on the list
let's tell us directly if you feel
really strongly you can go to the mic
but let us know directly which which is
something you prefer we have a github
repo yeah yeah hopefully we won't have
that many issues that it actually
becomes a really important thing which
one we use but we'll see lilium cool and
so I got a new work ? item into that
list also so but I guess we could
possibly discuss that may be out after
goon our slides so you're not you have
some slides that you want to go through
so we'll get them up on the screen for
you and you could do them now so okay
thanks oh hold on hold up hold on guna
for one I i I'm just as just for the
minutes I'll be confused to whether we
approved working group last call for the
for use cases we specifically talked
about the other two draft and I don't I
didn't understand whether we did or yes
calling we did not dis
Gus that or do a hum for it but it is
not a bad question to ask ok then then
as a participant can we do a working
group last call on use cases yeah I
suppose is the author of the draft it
feels a little weird but it was a
collection of use case like collected
from other places I think I do have some
edits to do on that as so I would ask
for the same for the same thing as Nick
actually if I could have a look at it
over the next few days and move to
working group last call on it on friday
at the end of the meeting I would be
very happy with that as an author
Randall is that the queue I i also just
this is randall gallons i just had a
comment on moving too well on publishing
the use cases because my recollection is
that at the time that we pulled the
youth cases out of the the human
language real-time draft and moved in
their own section on document my
understand my recollection is that we
just said we weren't going to publish
that as an RFC right that was the
original discussion right so that's I
guess maybe that's the first question is
whether we should reconsider that and
and then you know it has to be a
document that you did intend to publish
before you'd working with less call
right I'm yeah actually that's a that's
a very good point and I didn't I did
imagine originally that it would be
informational and helpful to the
situation that we had at that time
rather than official document so if
people are happy with that then I'm
happy to just clean it up and leave it
as informational than that out yet
that's that's okay well maybe maybe a
the appropriate thing would be to try to
get a consensus of the working group
whether that is something we even want
to publish or not right because if
there's always a lot of work associated
with publishing anything right and it'll
take up working group time and etc so
does that make sense yep I support
decide first if we want to go through
that overhead because my understanding
was at the back at the time that we
separated it out we weren't going to
publish it and we somehow slipped into
this understanding that we would and I
want us to just make sure we discuss
that explicitly right so that I guess
before we have that does anybody else
want to comment on whether they think it
is useful or not to bring me use cases
to publication does anybody else have
any thoughts on that Ryan is undecided
you can give us both sides of you yeah
generat generally speaking I think that
it's helpful for history to know why
things were done the way they were done
because when people come along trying to
solve whatever problem they have they
need things to enter to look at to see
why it was done a particular way and use
cases are really helpful for
understanding why things were done other
way so on that sense I'd like to see it
published on the other hand this is a
small group with that has a limited
amount of energy we have two
particularly useful drafts that I really
do want to get done and I'm not sure
that's worth that work Robert sparks the
other graphs don't reference the use
case document correct can you hand the
other dress to a arbitrary person in the
ITF say some sector or general reviewer
and have them not knowing anything about
the use case document at all have the
documents think that they would
understand everything understand the
motivation for why things were built or
do you think that they need to be
informed by what was in a use case
document in order to be able to properly
understand the documents my personal
response to that and I'd certainly like
to hear others views is that I don't
think you need to read the use case
statement to understand the
applicability of of the other one I mean
I think you can understand what it can
do it might be useful to understand
other things that people might want to
do that on
document but but not for the not for the
document but certainly willing to hear
other people's opinion on that so with
what I'm hearing I would suggest that
you don't publish it unless the
reviewers come back and say hey what's
going on here and you'd have to point to
that document to explain it the isg is I
was exiting the isg was starting to push
back pretty hard against those kinds of
documents I'm just because the extra
work that it took that that layer um so
understand Brian's point but I it sounds
to me like you've actually moved the
parts of that that are important in two
documents or more properly less than in
there so I'd offices Randolph gallons
again for anyone who forgot I just
wanted to mention that at the time that
we did take it out I think I'm the
understanding that we were proceeding on
back then was that we would just do it
as publish the use cases as a working
group wiki page or a working group web
page so that it was very low overhead
but it was there for anyone who wanted
to look at it Alexei Melnikov I will
actually second Roberts opinion is eyes
G doesn't quite like reviewing this case
documents unless that part of big
something bigger or you know a section
in existing document because there is
alone there was a long discussion I she
recently about documents which are not
necessarily going to add value long term
so but so if if you as chairs are
collectively the working group want to
argue that use case is absolutely
necessary for you know to be our cart
and RFC series then I think our I she
can be convinced that it needs to be
published but by default the preference
is probably you know if you don't have
hard feelings about not publishing it
dump them yeah I think that's it so yeah
we'll do that and send the other other
documents through the process and then
go back to it if they flag it as the
other documents not indicating that
there what or indicative of what they're
trying to achieve great cool thank you
so much for those comments guys right
guna you are I'm gonna just put your
slides up quickly okay go ahead tell me
when to change slides okay and I also
was in q4 commenting on the use cases it
was written as the kind of working
document and each use case ends with a
comment if it's feasible with the
current wording of the draft and there
are some use cases that are not
fulfilled if this information might be
lost we could check if we can comment in
the draft itself what is not covered in
some kind of scope statement or so I
also agree that it is a lot of work to
publish these cases as a proper document
and we should look for other ways to do
it so that just as you decided now for
can I just jump in at one point very
briefly um if we publish it as a working
group web you know page on the working
group website then it's not lost to
history it's all there hmm good ok let's
go into the presentation of the
real-time aspects and next I place we
start with the discussion about the line
esta piedra de I wanted to just give it
an overview of what's happening with
that in its place we have in the draft a
chapter 5 with a long reasoning about
the sdp Lang attribute
and a conclusion that I see is wrong and
that's why I feel we shouldn't have such
discussion especially if it's not needed
the what this discussion says is that
all declared languages must be used in
the session but it's much more likely
that it is meant to be a list for
selection and negotiation and you can
pick the language or the languages you
agree on to use and I commented on this
to a music for the RAC for the 145 66
abyss in the a music group and they made
slight small changes to that document
they change the importance to preference
so that it's clear if you have a
preference it's quite clear that you
want to do a selection from it and there
is also curl of lines added the the
events during the session can influence
which languages are used and the
participants are not strictly bar bound
to you only use it declared languages so
it is what you agree on is the initial
languages but then you can't take
responsibility for what happening in the
session so this the basis not exactly as
it is in the current SDP and it's more
towards interpreting as a list for
selection and however maybe more is
needed to really sort out how the
current Lang attribute is supposed to be
used then but we shouldn't discuss this
further herein slim the question belongs
to a music and we should anyone who is
interests
to have this properly settled for at
least four the best version of SDP
should go to a music and do it and we
should really not document assumptions
on this intention that may be wrong or
at least unclear and next slide please
so now that was a comment on the SDP but
now we go into our draft and start with
the issues with the current functional
scope within the current functional
scope so next slide so returning to the
Lang attribute and section five and we
suggest that we modify this drastically
text we have about the current Lang
attribute so that is just says that Lang
cannot be used because it does not
support different languages in different
directions which is a thing that we have
added and is needed for some use cases
so we should not and we do not need to
document any assumptions on the current
Lang attribute that may be wrong that
would cause just cause problems so the
little section here is what i suggest to
keep in chapter 5 to say that the RC
4566 specifies an attribute line which
appears similar to what is needed here
we need however more detailed
specification than the Lang attribute
provides we need a means to negotiate
which language is used in each direction
of the session
this difference means that the existing
Lang attribute cannot be used and we
need to define a new attribute simple
and no discussion about what line
provides next slide please and then I
think we are still nearly as unclear as
you think some somebody thinks that the
Lang attribute is we have current
wording that is fuzzy about the
intentions with both people language
attributes and we had an agreement in
April that something should be changed
to it be made more clear on this do we
have echo in the room I'll try to reduce
strength on me it's okay um yeah you
okay yeah yeah so some small
modifications are proposed in our
chapter six dot to this just question
gooner so it says is no no requirement
to use all specified languages but it's
not like the Lang attribute where you
might use some other language right you
you have to you don't have to use
everything you negotiate but you can't
can you still go and do something else
completely different that you never
negotiated that's that's a tsk oh right
there is a statement in a draft saying
that the answerer is not bound to use
the languages that were specified by the
by the offer which I dull I think that
looks strange but I haven't commented on
that
they say this discussion is rather make
it really clear that we don't need to
talk all the languages we specify that
we can do a selection and just limit to
one language i say that i can do swedish
and english and you respond english and
then we go with that I don't need to use
Swedish also because i originally said
so i rounded you have a quick question I
I just wanted to comment obviously what
we're negotiating is a technical
capability so we're obviously not going
to be prohibiting user behavior and the
user be normal user behavior is to only
use one language and there are a couple
of wording where it seems that you still
want us to use all languages specified
so this section here is there are two
attributes on handing in sand and the
other hand to indicate the language use
when sending and receiving media and we
the first proposal is to delete the
yellow part here so just starting with
sanding saying that is a center and they
receive attribute and then in the
sentence in an offer the human lungs and
values constitute a list of in
preference order of the languages they
offer wishes to send using the media and
I suggest to change wishes to to is
capable to select to change to send
and similarly for receiving side so the
user doesn't wish to send all the
languages he specified from the
beginning it is a list of what is
capable to select from so does that look
feasible to try to erase all
uncertainties about that it's really a
selection and negotiation okay next
slide and then we have some things not
clear what we do with languages in
multiple media if you are in 622 there
is this paragraph when placing an
emergency call and in any other case
where the language cannot be assumed
from context each media stream in an
offer primarily intended for human
language communication should specify
one or both human blank send or receive
attributes this intended for seems to
that new user would like to use them all
but it is really an alternative so the
intention may not be decided until the
answer is received and the answer cannot
be composed if the reason for specifying
languages is not explained if it is an
alternative then on what the preference
level compared to the language in other
media or is it a compliment so that you
want to simultaneous use of the media
though this is not clear yeah as I
rounded you have a question on that so
i'm not sure that i am following Gunners
problem with this text the wording here
is intended to differentiate between two
broad types of media streams one type is
where you are using it for human
communication in a language the other
media type is where you are not going to
do that it's just background information
you're not going to be talking over the
channel it's just providing audio as an
example or you're not going to be using
a video channel for sign language it's
merely a background for the other party
to be able to see what's going on in an
emergency call for example the peace app
that's the meaning of intended for human
language communication is to indicate
when you specify a language attribute
and when you don't right but and this
gets back to my core point which is that
I think part of your objection to some
of the material here is based on a
misunderstanding or at least a
difference in understanding between what
many of us see is the intent to the
draft which is to specify and to enable
a technical communication and agreement
versus user level interaction we're not
trying to dictate what the users do
we're not trying to dictate what the
client presents to the user as having
been negotiated having been set up
that's not just the intent of this draft
yeah but what the user needs is guidance
for how to firstly how to answer the
call what is most preferred by the
caller if the gunner answering can
respond to that properly then you have a
good chance to start the call in a good
way
yep Brock Rosen I'm going to repeat what
randy says this is a protocol mechanism
for mechanical use it is not an
indication to users of how to behave
there's a fundamental difference this is
a protocol mechanism to use to direct
calls to make decisions on how calls are
routed and what is presented it is not
how humans are supposed to behave big
difference and that's the part that we
keep running across it exactly so what
the UI does is completely out of scope
of this draft so as an example if you
have a UI where the user has indicated
in preferences or in setup what
languages and media are preferred in
what order and then that you I starts a
call and uses the mechanisms in this
document to set up multiple media
streams and manages to get everything it
asks for the UI is not obligated to
present to the user everything the UI
does whatever make sense if the UI wants
to then present only a subset of those
media streams to the users saying hey
you got your your preferred set up what
you exactly wanted it's here and you
ignore the rest that's the UI decision
if it's not supposed to be reflected in
the protocol communication and that's
actually not that different from what's
happening right now in this room we have
all these we have video we have audio we
have text it doesn't mean that you know
Randall now has to be typing in the chat
room right or has to be talking you have
all those capabilities ready to user can
use whatever they want yeah but the
column the call the answer needs
guidance and what we are negotiating
very good guidance can be very good
guidance for how to start the call so I
think we I think we somewhere say that
the use shall be informed
about the outcome of the negotiation see
I I feel that's out of scope of this
draft if you want to write a different
draft that is advice to the you to the
implementer of a client that's making
use of this mechanism that's fine you
can have that that would be guidance for
how to construct a user interface but
that's not the should not be in this
draft alright that's a minor result of
the negotiation is to convey it to the
user and that is what is needed to
complete the setup of the call all right
I believe those are two separate things
you've got the call setup and you've got
what's presented to the user well
usually you see if you get the video and
the that's part of the users the result
of the negotiation setup video and it's
apparent in the user interface that you
got video and similarly here if we agree
on one language we can display to the
user user her down with a good hint on
how to start the call yeah I actually am
not sure that that's really true right
you can negotiate audio and video n
lines but not turn on your camera right
and you still have the m-line so I
actually don't think that that's true in
today's ste gunner this is Dave Crocker
I have not read the spec I have no
comment on the spec I do have a comment
because i always get up at the mic when
someone says that an ietf protocol spec
should say something about user behavior
and that is we don't do that when we try
to do it we do it badly we don't need to
do it we shouldn't do it yeah and this
doesn't say how the user shall behave it
says that the intention is guidance to
the juice
so that the court can be properly
handled Brian Brian Rosen no we're not
providing any guidance to users we're
building protocol mechanisms the intent
of the document is to describe a
protocol mechanism for mechanical for
computers to do the right thing not for
humans to do the right thing there's no
guidance to users here we don't intend
to inform users of what to do this is a
protocol mechanism for mechanical for
computers or other physical
implementations of the protocol to do
the right thing with the media and
routing and all the other things that we
do know how to do in the ITF Dave
Crocker again I apologize I was much too
terse than what I said what I meant was
anything having to do with interactions
with users is part of a specialty called
user experience usability and any number
of other terms of art we don't have that
expertise in this community there are
some individuals who do but the
community doesn't and our specs must
stay away from that domain let me
attempt to put it really succinctly it's
a layer violation you've got the what's
going on between the user and the UI way
way way way up above the nosebleed layer
and you've got what's going on with the
protocol layer kind of kind of in the
middle that's what we're doing here yeah
but the language preferences are
definitely what the user have input
somehow and it's now conveyed to the
other side and the other side is
responding what the other user has for
preferences and it's very close to user
interfacing
and that's the layers that's that stuff
the filters down the user has indicated
to the UI through the UI in some way
that's completely out of scope of this
document what the users preferences are
all that stuff gets into the client and
then the client uses the mechanisms here
to set up what's going to happen and
then the client informs the user in some
way that's completely out of scope of
this document as to what's happened now
this is very limited to really drill
down on that this the way you get the
indication from the user of what
language they want to use can be an
explicit selection from a list or simply
what store they went to to buy this
product and what language it comes in so
you know trying to do anything more than
saying you are reflecting a user's
preference for language communication
anything more than that is has got to be
out of scope yeah so this is rather a
discussion or what what we need to
convey in the in the protocol to be able
to do the right decisions and there is
if we say if we talk priority between
media we leave the the result in doubt
what what shall we use this language is
for so next slide
that's it looks light is enough yes it's
nothing didn't we have that slide for
her not good for you ah ok that's next
when reading the draft I looked at this
section about advice reversals required
and wonder if that is really needed we
have a notation with an asterisk that we
can add to a language tag and if we have
it we mean that the coal shall not be
the shall be connected whatever the
result of the negotiation is and wonder
if we really should fail calls because
of not completed negotiations on
language it is really realistic to ever
automatically fail calls because of non
matching language indications mmm you
can have combinations you never thought
of specifying they will work in reality
for example Norwegians can usually talk
with Swedes Spanish people can usually
talk with Italians and you never thought
about saying in the setting of the phone
that yes I can receive Norwegian or
Italian if you are from the other
country so ing the question yeah this is
the brine rosen arm there are many
reasons in protocol mechanisms to have
that kind of alien mechanisms explicit
failing call a great example would be
us a sip fork you fork to four places
looking for some facility that can
handle the specific language is you want
three of them decline the call one of
them accepts the call and you go to take
it the way they were one that accepts it
you want a mechanism to to be able to
say I cannot meet this specification no
I think that's a very useful protocol
mechanism i would like to retain it the
any implementation can choose not to use
that mechanism but the mechanism should
be present yeah I'm not randyll yep
Drake but I wanted to and Randall has a
forum I just want to reiterate that last
bit that Brian said there's nothing in
the draft that mandates failure of a
call instead all that that's in here is
talk about preference for for proceeding
or not proceeding in the event of the
mismatch preference for and in fact the
draft explicitly says that there are
cases where a call will probably never
be failed no matter what such as an
emergency call that's we're not trying
to force anything on hey I think Barry
was going to agree that um cool okay go
ahead okay yep next so next slide then a
couple of features that are not covered
in the current draft is a way to specify
relative preference between alternative
languages in the same direction in
different media and a way to specify
that two or more languages in the same
direction are stronger than fraud to
provide it together and we have
discussed this many times before and I
have a new thing on next slide
and that is when we get into media that
are not using any of our time types them
main types video body or text for
example if we go into WebRTC and use sdp
for it we need an additional construct
probably not in this draft but that's
work to be done to have a multiplexed
data channel to be declared as used for
text for example and we need to work on
that so that we can use this mechanism
also in WebRTC and other places where
the media is not typed as video audio
text and the there are dsca attribute in
the stp neg is useful for the WebRTC
case and next slide and that's it we
have a comment from Randall we go back
to the first two slides because I didn't
respond to those directly I think so
actually I think we did talk about this
right i don't remember now you mean
about delete oh yeah so is so yeah if
you if you look at the changes in the
draft if you look at what's actually in
the current version of the draft
regarding this material what's there now
is a very small statement and then a
parenthetical aside about it is that the
interpretation of the
authors of the draft so I don't think
there's anything in there that
constrains any future revision of the of
the document of the attribute at all if
in fact if you want to project what's in
the draft now I'd like to hear if
anybody feels that that should be taken
out or that needs to be modified well I
do yeah I mean I think he's wrong and
should not comment on that okay next I
mean as I recall in previous meetings we
did say that was an issue for the M
music working group so so on what's
what's in there now says RFC 4 5 6 6
specifies an attribute line which
appears similar what is needed here this
specifies that i equals line is
declarative which it does and it says
that multiple Lang media use multiple
languages and that quote the order of
the attributes indicates the order of
importance of the various languages in
the ellipsis media close quote and then
there's a parenthetical aside that is we
meaning the author's the draft interpret
this to mean that the media contains all
of the languages indicated blah blah
blah for example video of an interview
by a person speaking one language of a
person speaking another or subtexts in
the language of the interviewer blah
blah blah so the interpretation is what
we said needed to be done by the M music
working group not this working group
right because it's not our draft so
that's like this is Joseph providing ok
at the time that this this document is
written one that we're talking about now
we're going by the publication of the
specification of the attribute that's
there now and we're just saying why we
can't use it but it's our own wrong
conclusion it's nito wrong conclusion at
all it's a perfectly valid conclusion
well I think the point is the point here
is that we agreed in this working group
that that decision would not be made
here what is way seeing a decision here
we're not trying to say what the
language what we really mean now
previously we had a consensus that this
discussion of the interpretation of 4566
would be may
a by the working group that owns the
revision sure so that's so your
assertion that bet that we already
decided that that would go there so you
know in arguments about interpretation
of a document that's owned by another
working group probably isn't right the
right thing to be doing in this working
group and I provided a simple
alternative to so that you still can
invent this new etiquette yeah I mean I
the overall point was that that
discussion should go to em music so
probably having that debate here
probably yeah yeah so in which case
although the topic is extremely
interesting i'm sure but there and that
needs to that needs to go and we could
probably close up the debate with having
it yeah I'm all right I mean I think
probably the less said about the
existing one the better but we do need
to say something to indicate why we're
not using it and I'm not sure that
Gunnar's Texas is necessary but perhaps
we could say even less that might be
good enough yeah okay so then there was
one more slide so just to reiterate what
Brian said we'll take it to the list to
have this discussion but I'm interest
yeah I idea it probably would be best of
it I I don't like cross-list posting but
um I guess I'm use it probably is the
best place to take it to ya I mean one
thing is I has this has all of this gone
to em music I don't think gooner you
didn't post all of your comments there
did you no no I I think that's very
smooth yeah so I think really we
actually bring it there you know in in
toto Braun Rosen what I suggest is that
we have a discussion on list of
alternative boarding to what's currently
in the text right for ir r on our list
okay when we conclude that we should
take whatever language that is and bring
it to em music and saying our document
proposes to say this are there any
comments and let's see what we get
and I very quickly I think we can
resolve this particular slide because
they didn't comment on this one you
presented it so your objection really is
the wording where that says wishes and
so if we change wishes to keep a built
is capable of I don't like is capable to
select two because to me that doesn't
make sense but we can just change wishes
to send or wishes to use to say is
capable of yeah that's probably good
enough great Haim thank you going on for
that um I'm gonna press the big red
button again okay who knows what magic
the red button does I thought it was
getting rid of things than putting kids
always Goo Dolls also on the list so
it's just putting you vacuum her okay
right I hope you're done ok goo not add
yourself back to the list if you do have
anything that you want to say more on
top of that um sorry ok cool we're at
any other business I'll wrap new work
into any of the business as well I'm the
future of this working group is you know
right now to complete the two documents
to go for the rse process the two
documents that we have and then probably
wrap the group up so I don't know if
there is any more work for us to do this
might be a discussion for the list but
you can feel free to come to the mic and
make a comment yes hi Tom Gallagher I
just wanted to point out mentioning the
use case document from earlier there's a
section there about security
considerations Nick I'm not sure if you
were planning on incorporating those but
if that's not going to become that's
like a good a final call then that
section does seem relevant to both other
documents so that it would make it in
one of those just so it can be part of
the okay cool thank you for that um
cosmid right now if I do you feel that
the current security considerations text
in the two documents is insufficient and
needs
additional material I just feel like the
security considerations in the use case
document isn't mentioned in those other
two documents I don't know enough about
the what's in the two other documents
that are going for final call as I like
the text that's in the use cases
document and would love to see that make
it somewhere else rather than to go away
this is Nick haven't seen the security
considerations in the use case document
yet but i will take a look today and
it's very it's very short disturb it
said if it's almost a fingerprinting
type of thing that you're able to
understand a little bit more about the
user their preferred languages so you
could probably guess their nationality
that kind of thing yeah privacy related
issues actually um I do recall that one
of the the security ID actually
mentioned that he was concerned about
that text so anyway that's something to
bring up I think during working with
less call excellent thank you for that
um brilliant ok so this group will then
work towards completing those two
documents and moving them in if you're
moving them up to the RFC tree if you
have a comments on new work that can
begin after that then please make it
though I will state that the goal of
this group was to complete those two
documents does anybody else have any
other business great so just to say
thank you to Brian prescribing and Lucas
for being our Java scrub and Randall and
Nick & goo na for being our presenters
and Randall Nick in particular for
writing the troughs much of the work of
this group we have a lot of a DS here
past and present thank you for attending
and if anybody has not completed the
blue sheets please come up to the front
to write your name and company onto the
blue sheets and now you are all free to
go about your merry way thank you so
much everyone and do stay for the I
meeting
in 20 minutes oh and i'm eating both 20
minutes whoo yeah in this room so yeah
if you're not if you don't want to stay
for that you do need to leave but if you
do you can stay what Pete and I are on
about with staff is that establishing a
consensus is a question of addressing
objections yeah science so if you focus
on who has objections rather though yes
no yeah but usually you don't have to
ask the questions you do yeah but
usually you can just call for objections
and then when people hum for that you
said can you explain what your objection
is and let's try to address it ok cool
No thank you for the judge thanks ah
yeah so I'll give you a perfect if I'd
this is perfectly good to have recorded
in one of the working groups that I had
when I was an ad yeah they there was
something that was an issue that was
being discussed there were four option
you