greetings from the 96th meeting of the
internet engineering task force or ITF
here in Berlin Germany I'm Dan York and
i'm here with yari our co-chair of the
ITF so you re how was the meeting it was
a very good meeting and everybody likes
to come to Berlin for meetings and it's
an excellent place to have meeting
speakers there so Matt's you know
academic students Internet technology
business around so we got a good turnout
1400 people also and and of course the
ITF is not just about the idea of
meeting itself we usually get a
collection of other events around the
meeting us as well and this time for
instance had some interrupt events by
etsy research workshop by the I RTF and
so forth and the ITF also I mean it's
not just about specifications and
working group meetings we were also
about running code of course so we've
been working on that this time we had
150 plus people working on that on over
20 different projects and some some very
interesting ones that had you know big
significance for the internet as an
example we worked on TLS 1.3
implementations had interrupt testing of
seven of those implementations against
each other in a successful manner and
that's a that's a protocol that's
underneath https you know the web
security protocol so it's it's quite
important yeah I was like you one of the
judges in the hackathon and it was
pretty amazing to sit there and see the
breadth of topics covered by the IETF
and to be reminded of that and seeing
all that that open code well speaking of
those topics what were some of the main
topics you thought had a lot of activity
here at ITF 96-well many things of
course but the one that was highlight
for me at least was the the evolution of
the transport and web protocols and and
this weekend we had the most
well-attended meeting that the quick
protocol both which is a discussion of
possible new new work at the ITF and
this is basically a redesign of that
some of the basic protocols in the
internet like tcp and how you know how
web traffic is transported and that has
a big impact if it goes forward so that
was very interesting for for lots of
people and of course we had many other
topics security IOT we even had a
discussion about blockchain and
as kinds of payment systems or
interoperability between different
payment systems so I good good variety
of topics yeah there's a there's a kind
of meeting here called the birds of a
feather Boff session those were some of
them the highly that's an area of
bringing new work into the ITF so it the
ITF continues to evolve and have these
new topics and things now obviously a
lot of working group sessions but what
else happened this week well one thing
that I of course was very happy with
also was that this week we announced
over three million dollars of new
support for the idea that this is of
course very much appreciated came from
our friends at ripe apnic arin and I
sock so thank you for that you're
welcome and it was it was a good thing
so now this is all ending the network's
being shut down were some of the last
people in this area at all what's next
of course we go back to work and the
mailing list and and and virtual
meetings and so a lot of these topics
will continue right away and and you
know I expect much progress to be made
in that in the next weeks and months
before for the next meeting and the next
meeting of course is in Seoul Korea in
November all right well thank you for
your service is the chair and for all of
the activities that were here this week
and we'll look forward to talking to you
next from ITF 97 in Seoul you can find
out more about it by going to ww ietf
org and that's also the place that you
can learn more about how to participate
in how to make the standards that make
the internet work better thank you
you