good morning besides columbus
uh welcome to the blue team session
powershell
pew pew pew skills for the blue team my
name is ashley mcloone i'll be your tour
guide today
are you tired of the red team taking
your lunch money
with commodity power shell
attacks that have been available for
several years now quite common
and i'm gonna show you some a way that
you can turn on the black light so to
speak you've watched these csi shows
where they have uh the black light that
shows you all the evidence well here we
go
we're gonna show you some evidence today
with powershell a little bit about
myself my name is ashley mcglone i live
here in columbus
and my resume includes companies like
toyota and microsoft and now tanium
and so that's where i've been now for
about three years at tanium doing uh
security at scale so let's dive right in
so today we're going to talk about how
do we get here with powershell
malware and then we're going to look at
the windows powershell policies
and then i also want to talk about
powershell core
which is the cross-platform powershell
how you can do the same policies there
because uh powershell core has been out
for several years now
and started against the momentum and we
don't want attackers
bypassing your traditional windows
powershell policies
for core so i want to show you how to do
that as well
and then i'll share some free resources
with you at the end as well as a demo in
there
so a brief history of powershell
security how did we get here
so 2003 powershell was announced as
project
monad at the pdc professional developers
conference
years ago 17 years ago wow so 2006
powershell one was released
2008 was the first security oriented
blog post from the powershell team at
microsoft
and basically the point was that
execution policy
in powershell is not a security feature
all right it's easy to bypass it's
designed that way out of the box
and you can check out that blog post for
more info 2008 12 years ago all right
2013 another blog post powershell
security best practices coming out of
redmond
all right 2015. this was massive
if you've not read this blog post yet
you need to go find it powershell hearts
the blue team
this was written by lee holmes when
windows 10 dropped
and they put in a massive amount
of logging and fingerprints
so that you can track exactly what's
happening in powershell
this is huge there were some earlier
attempts at this
but this became de facto standard
out of the box with windows 10 and
available
down level on older versions with a
windows management framework install
massive 40-50 page white paper i want
you to go read that
because that's a foundation for a lot of
what we're going to do today
and by the way if you've not seen lee
holm's derby con talk from last year
i would encourage you to check it out
too because he tells the story of how we
got to this point
of uh wanting to make uh powershell a
better world
for everyone but that same year 2015
powershell empire premiered at b-sides
las vegas most likely this is in your
daily toolkit
powershell empire was a framework that
would allow you as a plug-and-play
framework that would allow you to extend
it
with additional toolkits and made it
really easy and really turned powershell
malware into a commodity
and after that then we saw another blog
post from the powershell team this was
paul higginbotham and lee holmes
talking about a comparison of shell and
scripting languages
proving that green bar across the middle
that powershell is the most
secure solution out there really when it
comes to
scripting languages and i'll talk about
this a little bit later but in
environments where uh leadership decides
hey
we need to turn off this powershell
thing i heard it's bad and just shut it
down across the entire environment
what that's telling what really what
that says is hey let's go
use some other unsecure scripting or
automation framework that we can't track
so you don't want to do that you want to
actually use powershell
to your advantage in that way
so and then 2017 uh matt graber
a popular security researcher he says
look
because of this new logging it is so
good i'm moving on to other language
where
they can't track me right and the
industry kind of followed
and the other point that he made there
is look you can burn powershell with
fire in your org but that doesn't
bother me powershell is not the reason
people get
owned okay uh powershell is usually
not the point of entry um maybe it's
dropped in a phishing attack
but it's not the point of entry
typically and so that's what you need to
keep in mind powershell itself is
very secure but when people misuse it
that's when it becomes
a problem that's what we're going to
talk about here
so uh 2018 powershell core was released
this is cross-platform windows mac and
linux and it has
the security policies built in that we
used over
on the windows side as well
so those policies are still there we're
going to walk through each of those
last year the announcement came out by
zawyer that powershell
empire is officially dead and
at the same time you saw a number of new
tools emerge
however there is another group that has
obviously powershell empire is open
source it's out on the web
there's another group that's got a repo
that they're continuing development on
powershell empire but the original
founders of it
uh declared it dead but it's not dead
because
in the headlines every day of the week
you can still read
where powershell script is quite common
in malware attacks today across the
enterprise
across the entire industry so
because once it's out there it's out
there and people are gonna lose
the least path resistance and powershell
malware is easy now
to obtain and use with little training
or effort
so that's why we have to guard against
it right also
a lot of people are struggling just to
identify malicious powershell and
environment that's why i'm doing this
session today i want you to know what
tools you have at your
disposal um this uh tweet by naked
security said hey what if you could
eliminate one file type on the network
what would it be and
the majority 34 said powershell ps1
saying we need to eliminate that again
that's the wrong mindset
i want to teach you today how to monitor
what's being done in powershell so you
can use it to your advantage
2020 this last january during the
iran cyber attack concerns
there was some guidance coming out of
the u.s cert
that was both helpful and not so helpful
and one
uh in this u.s cert bulletin on one side
they said
turn off bb script and power shell and
turning off power shells really not the
best thing you want to do like i said
but then they did give you a list of
recommendations for mitigation and
detection that are all
valid and lee holmes says look you know
there's a lot better ways to do this
powershell can be a great honeypot and
so you don't want to
turn it off entirely in the environment
so even as recent as just this last
january i know when i was investigating
some of the methods used in these
attacks
they were literally just commodity
powershell
with a couple twists so it was really
the emphasizing the reason why
even though empire is dead we need to
continue
to uh investigate and monitor these
techniques
so uh as we get going here something you
need to be aware of is there are
different powershell editions now
so there's windows powershell which is
built in
since windows 7 2008 r2 out of the box
but you want to upgrade that if you've
got old machines make sure you get them
upgraded
windows 10 ships with version 5.1 out of
the box of windows
powershell there okay being specific
there for a reason
that version of powershell was complete
microsoft
likes to say that means there's no new
development going into it
it's achieved a step stability level
symbol
similar to python 2.7 where there's not
going to be
a lot of develop any real development
excel outside of bug fixes going into
that
and so powershell core then uh
is started an open beta in 2016.
but then it was released in 2018 now
we're up to
uh powershell core version 702
as of this recording windows mac and
linux you can see here in the screenshot
you've got
dollar ps version table will report to
you the powershell edition
and also the version and the platform
that you're running on there are also
some variables that will tell you
am i running on linux mac os or windows
here
true or false so there's uh os awareness
built into powershell core and when you
install this oh
that's also available on arm so i've run
this on a raspberry pi as well
back in 2016 when it launched so
um pretty legit stuff you can actually
do pwsh
is your shell now you can run that on
windows mac and linux i
drive a mac every day for work and i use
powershell
quite frequently i wouldn't say every
day but
at least weekly i'm using powershell on
my mac
for you know processing json files and
different things like that automating
tasks
so this is open source now powershell
core you can go out to github powershell
powershell and they also have a
third third thursday of every month an
open powershell community call go check
it out you can actually get to interact
directly with the
product team at microsoft who's in
charge of powershell i would encourage
that
so let's talk about how to do powershell
security again so that's the background
how we got here it's a new field we've
got
multiple types of powershell editions
now
not just windows anymore to be concerned
with and one of the things
about that that you need to be aware of
is they can have what they call
powershell upgrade attacks as well as
downgrade attacks so powershell v2
on windows 7 did not have the logging
we're about to talk about
pwsh the new powershell core edition
most likely has slipped under the radar
and doesn't have
logging configured either so you want to
make sure logging is configured
everywhere that you've got powershell
enabled so how do we do that
so powershell hygiene strategy is going
to include number one making sure
all your older machines have at least
powershell five one on them
uh so that's your baseline for your
older windows 7 2008 r2 servers all
right
even your 2012 2012 r2 get them all up
the windows powershell 51
and then there is an os feature for the
v2
engine you can disable that you don't
need it
and then what we're going to focus on
primarily today is implementing and
monitoring
the logging and transcription which is
turning on the black light so to speak
so you can see what's happening
but you also want to use remoting to
your advantage
enable that is that's uses all the
windows
permissions and protections but also
don't forget that
in your firewall rules and windows you
can then
allow one rm port 5985
specifically
requiring that to certain
firewall destinations right certain ip
ranges whatever so you can
restrict remoting and there's even tools
within
powershell to as restrict promoting
further
and then actually get to the blocking
phase
uh you would use app locker device guard
or out of the box ampsy
and also be careful with amc because if
you're using if you're not using windows
defender
not all windows av
products will tie into amc that's the
anti-malware scan interface
it's working for you every day and yes
there are bypasses for everything i'm
going to talk about today
but a layered defense is your best
strategy
so feature matrix basically
what i wanted to mention here i've kind
of covered most of this
the main point here is that uh the
windows
uh logging and transcription i'm going
to talk about today
are built-in on windows 10 and above
server 2016 and above
and powershell core when you install it
however you have to enable the logging
there's an additional
step that you have to take and that's
what i'll make make sure you take away
today so upgrade your stuff
so real quick we're going to go through
these in a demo in a second but module
logging is also known as
pipeline execution or execution logging
and so you're going to see module
commands in powershell the parameter
binding that happens
as they're executed in the logs script
block logging you're going to see
whole blocks of code as they're executed
appear
in the logs transcription is literally a
text file output of what commands were
run
and what output was generated and that
all all of these techniques that i'm
explaining to you those first three
all work on code that was interactively
typed or run in memory
from an administrative tool or a hacking
tool anywhere that code executes it's
going to be logged
and then ps readline command history is
uh ps readline is a module that comes
out of the box with powershell
and it basically gives windows folks a
unix like command history experience
that's persistent between sessions
so you can look at that file to see what
interactively type commands could have
been malicious as well
and then finally we've talked about
anti-malware scan interface
so i'm putting this chart in here for
your reference i don't want to get into
the details here too much and for the
sake of time we're going to do this
in the demo shortly but suffice it to
say there are
multiple windows event log log locations
as well as syslog if you're doing uh
powershell core on mac and linux
and so there are paths here you can see
where the policies defined for
transcription in the registry
which window windows logs you want to
monitor and which event ids you want to
look for
to see where those things are popping in
your environment
so policies on windows using group
policy you can set these policies
under administrative templates for
windows
on both the user computer side obviously
it only makes sense to set this on the
computer side for all users
in the group policy you go and set those
and then you'll see there this is a
little local version of group policy
editor here
but um sometimes active directory
environments are complicated
you've got non-domain machines and so if
you want to automate this at scale you
can simply just
run a rich script that will drop
the registry values into the policy path
under hkey local machine software
policies microsoft windows powershell
and then these different module logging
script block logging transcription
so i've got some scripts that'll help
you with that in a little bit here
so group policy in the registry
or through the gui tool
powershell core now i want to be careful
as i was looking at this in my lab
over the last few months i noticed that
when you install powershell core on
windows
this is not a thing on linux or mac but
on windows specifically
you have to make sure whether you're
doing the gui install
or the uh behind the scenes msi package
command lines this is all documented
in a link out of microsoft on how to
install powershell
but you want to be careful that you make
sure you register the event log manifest
when you look in the ps home directory
you'll see a powershell core
instrumentation dll
and the install powershell remoting
install ps core configuration
definitions policy definitions and
register
manifest those scripts are called when
you check these boxes over here in the
install or supply these flags
make sure if you're deploying powershell
core
in your enterprise that you enable that
because that's going to give you the
event log that we're going to look at in
a minute for
powershell core so what does that look
like
in policy then how do i set the policies
for powershell core
all right let's talk the windows first
so
in the ps home directory you'll see
there are
there's a script install ps core policy
definition which has an admx
group policy template that group policy
template then will
add now notice this is no longer windows
powershell
this is powershell core so they've
dropped the windows name
and so now you have a second location
for
policies in group policy management
called powershell core
with settings that you can apply that
look identical with one exception
if you already have the policy set for
windows
powershell you can simply check a box in
each one of these to use the windows
powershell policy setting
so it would mirror whatever settings you
had configured
on the windows powershell policy side
i know that might be confusing re-watch
the video a couple times if it needs to
sink in but
there's now two places for policy
configuration because it's no longer
windows
powershells powershell core got a
separate place in the registry
and a separate place in group policy so
now under
policies microsoft powershell core we'll
see some of those same settings in the
registry as well
now if you're doing this on mac os or
linux and you can even do it this way on
windows powershell as well
again in the ps home dollar ps home
directory
you look for json files and there's a
powershell.config.json
if the file is not there most likely you
can create it
and so then in that
powershell.config.json file
you can provide these settings which
will be in the slide notes later for you
and so this is json saying hey turn on
script block logging
turn on module logging for all modules
turn on transcription and write it out
to this var temp directory which is a
persistent attempt
right that's important there if you
write it make sure you write it to the
correct
temp directory that will be persistent
all right so you can turn on those
policies on
other powershell core as well now i
tweeted this
screenshot back in december as i was
looking with the preview
on powershell 7 but it basically kind of
puts it all together on a windows
machine
using the json powershell config so
under
program files powershell now just slash
7 no preview see your powershell config
json file it's got these policy settings
in the json
you run your malicious powershell
command here as an encoded command
and what you see behind you is in the
event log
you can see the plain text of the
command that was executed behind the
scenes
behind that encoded command
as event 4103 or 4104
then in the ps transcripts directory i
open up the date stamped folder and in
there i'll see
files which will have a full transcript
of the command
the user it was run under the process id
all that good juicy forensic data that
you would need to investigate a
powershell attack it's all there this is
powershell
core but the same thing applies to
windows powershell
same logs you're going to look for
except the location
and the registry is going or the event
viewer is going to be slightly different
we'll take a look at that
so uh pro tip here when you're making
changes to powershell policy
you need to make sure that
you log out of your powershell session
and open a fresh one
because uh powershell policy settings
are
cached in the powershell session when
it's created in memory
when it's instantiated so if you're
changing powershell policy
settings and you're not seeing the
logging happen the way you expect it to
it's probably because you need to exit
that powershell session
and then come back into it and then as
you make changes you'll see that hit the
logs
so that's one important thing as you're
working with this you need to be aware
of so
let's do some demos here so let's take a
look here at windows powershell
so here i am on a windows box i've got
the
windows powershell command
environment and i've also got the
powershell
core that i'll spin up here so here in
windows powershell
i can type things like get process
right id 0
and there's our idle process all right
run commands you know whatever you want
to do and let's go
grab a malicious uh powershell
encoded command here and what we'll do
is i'm going to drop this into the
command prompt and i'm going to run
it both as powershell which uses the
powershell engine
oh look it changed my font size
and then i'm also going to run it with a
pwsh
which is the exact same um
kind of syntax here
as let's see get that in there
all right so demo
fail let's pull up a fresh command
prompt here
there we go and let's uh paste that guy
in
come on edit
and paste oh well
let's try this one last time here there
it is
there's my uh powershell core so what
we've done is we've done an encoded
command
we cannot see if you're using command
line logging all you would see is the
encoded command you wouldn't know what
was in there it's base64
you decode the base64 but then it could
still be obfuscated
so this is going to show you what
happens in memory all right so we've run
it in both
powershell core pwsh and in powershell
so we've introduced some malicious code
let's go take a look
so you'll notice here in the registry we
have the
windows policy set for example
transcription
script block logging module logging
and then up here under powershell core
we have module logging script block
logging
and transcription turned on so those are
turned on
now we can go look and see where they
occur but let's
let's take a look also at a couple other
freebies we get
here so if i type invoke mimicats
on a windows 10 box see this script
contains malicious content has been
blocked by your antivirus software
i want to point out something if you
don't see this message
that has been blocked as malicious that
means that
anti-malware scan interface or ampsy is
not enabled on your machine
certain third-party av if you disable
defender you're disabling ampsy
and you're opening yourself up to this
basic protection built into windows 10
be sure that your av
provider supports amsi for that reason
alone
so invoke me cats is there
but it there's no command on that
command has no module installed on the
machine but just the name of that
command is popular enough that it knows
to block it
i also want to show you a ps readline
history so if i say get module
see what we've got notice ps read line
module is loaded in the background by
default
it includes some commands get ps read
line
option and we can see the options for ps
redline
which include how many
history commands to remember and where
am i going to stick this
and the thing i like about this is it
puts it in the user's
app data path on windows it puts it in
another location on mac and linux
but here it's in my app data path so now
i have a console history session
of every interactively typed command in
powershell now
be aware it's easy to just unload the
module when you start your session okay
if you're malicious you may do that but
most everyday users wouldn't know to do
that so it's going to record anything
that they do
so what i can do then is i can say
get content which is the powershell
version of cat
and i can tell it to use get ps read
line option
history say path
so it pulls in the path it opens the
file and shows me all the commands that
were interactively typed
on that machine there's the commands
that we just typed a few minutes ago
all right so that is the only problem
with this
file however is there's no date stamping
on the commands that were run
so it is a fingerprint location you can
look for powershell activity
just know there's no date stamping in
there
so that's running commands on the
powershell side
so then over here in
core i can do the exact same thing we
just did there
now let's go take a look under ps
transcripts
here let's start with the ps transcript
and today's date and
notice here there's a number of
transcript files
let's pick one and see if we got the
right thing there it is yep
so if we go in here and we zoom in
let's zoom in and let's take a look
here's a powershell transcript file that
shows me
date time it was run the user context
and if it's a remoting session it will
tell me the user id it was run under
tells me the windows computer name
the in this case the host application is
the encoded command
it shows me the process id and all the
addition
the version all that shows me here's the
actual
invoke expression it's just just for
demonstration purposes but this was
further obfuscated in the code that it
was actually in that encoded command
so while you're looking at invoke
expression here
you'll note that
in this case the invoke expression was
the result of other obfuscated code and
the output was just pew pew pew
powershell pwned
and then you see headers here for the
time that that command ran so this is
incredibly valuable for forensic
information
for investigation you'll see the exact
same thing happen with powershell
core it will put it into the transcript
path that you specify
i'm also then in windows event log
what we want to look at is under the
windows application logs
powershell here you'll see 41.03 let's
refresh this view and let's
take a walk down through here these
event logs until we find
our powershell pew pew pew
and we're looking for 4103 which is
module logging at 4104 which is script
block logging
and because i'm kind of doing this demo
on the fly
i should probably go back and look for a
time stamp maybe but anyway
what you're seeing here is you can see
each command as it's being run
the parameters that are being bound to
that command as it's executed
for powershell parameters are okay
keep going there's our invoke mimikat's
output in the console
i will keep going and we'll look for
pew pew pew should be coming up there it
is yeah 4103
so here's the output of the command in
the windows event log
there's the same thing that we saw in
the transcript earlier
all the metadata about the session that
makes it interesting for us that's in
the 4103
module logging we can also see that in
4104 script block logging
and again the benefit here is it doesn't
matter how the code was executed you're
going to see the output in the logs
similarly if i scroll up to the
powershell
core log here
so under my logs
now i have powershell core on the left
as well if you've installed pwsh
same thing here i can look at 4103
there it is pew pew pew same metadata
so make sure that if powershell core is
being used in your environment that you
install it with that manifest
switch to so this log gets turned on on
windows
and we'll see the same thing with 4104
script block logging so there we have it
on a windows machine
now let's pivot over to the world uh
cross platform with a centos box here
so here dollar ps version table
actually i don't have it my logo so i've
got an ssh session
to my centos box pwsh
and now i've got powershell already
installed there the installation
directions are on the microsoft website
or that github slash powershell
powershell
and so here i'm running uh powershell
now on a centos box
ps version table tells me this is the
edition
powershell core the version is
702 the exact same version it was
running on my
windows box i also have it on my local
mac here as well
so uh here i am and
uh what i want to do is change into the
dollar ps
home directory which is the dollar
ps home sends me to the installation
path for powershell
and here watch this just for fun
normally we would do an ls i'm going to
do a dir
on a linux machine just to mess with
people star.json
and here is a windows style directory
listing on a unix box is hilarious
anyway inside there for everybody else i
can do ls json all right
there it is so powershell.config.json
cat that file
json powershell.com.json you'll see here
is our
policy set on this box with script block
logging we don't do the invocation
option typically
but we do enable script block logging
when do enable module logging for
all modules here and then enable
transcripting
to the var temp and you just pick your
path
ps transcripts is what i picked so
transcription module logging also
so so the transcription is going to come
out in this path
the module logging and script block
logging are going to come out
in syslog which we'll take a look at
here
so here again invoke mimikatz is not
even a thing
on unix platform there's not that much
malware
on powershell core but i expect it to be
out any day
so here we want to run some commands now
get
process id one
so now i'm running just like i run get
processes
on windows machines i can now run it
here
and i'm going to exit my
powershelf session and um
haven't helped us it won't be that much
longer before cross-platform
malware will be doing things like this
calling pwsh with the exact same encoded
command i did on the windows machine
and how i've got the malware here pew
pew powershell pwned
it's an encoded command it's obvious
gated in the original code but now you
can see what the output
is so we want to go find that in
the logs now so remember this
var temp ps transcript so let's uh
let's take that path and drop in there
now we do a an ls because we're back to
uh actually no no we're still in
all right anyway we've got 2020 716 so
let's see
2020 and inside there
i see a number of log
files that have been written so i'm
going to cat
out power shell transcripts
and toss and let's look for the most
recent one starts with a y
on the randomized name and here we'll
see
in a transcript on a centos box
the same data we saw over on the windows
side
the start time username machine name
the host was that encoded command
process id
and all that goodness here's the start
time
here's the command here's the output
it's all good
all right so that's transcription now uh
for the windows folks you might think
well there's no windows event log how do
i see
what happened
so let's do this then for for the event
logging so on windows we know 4103
4104 and the windows powershell or
powershell core log
how do we find that over here so what
i'm going to do
is i'm going to run over and
take a look at the
syslog so i'll start up another
session actually i'm going to do it
right here
pwd
all right notice i'm not in powershell
core right now it's not tab completing
that's important because if i'm
reviewing
malware in a powershell session
viewing those logs gets written back
into the logs and it becomes kind of a
ship in a bottle kind of thing
uh a nested logging of logs
which is not pretty so you want to exit
out of powershell before you do that but
what i'm going to do is i'm going to go
to
var log
and i can do
sudo grip for powershell
in the messages file which is the
syslog file put in my super secret
password
and now you can see here
in that i've got pipeline
details that's the module logging
feature
invoke expression and there's a
pew pew pew powershell pwned right there
all right and also comes out so that's
pipeline details you also see a script
block
uh same thing two styles of logging okay
two different options the different
policies that we've enabled and they're
slightly different in the output that
they generate but you can see the
commands that were executed there
so now for fun what we're is we're going
to entail this
pseudotail minus f messages
all right and so now i'm going to go
over here to another
ssh session on the same box and i'm
going to
run pwsh notice it just dropped
commands behind us in the syslog
and now let's do um
hello from pwsh
and now back behind us uh in the
log you'll notice prompt shows up a lot
but here it is right there in syslog
hello from pwsh
as a script block log
and then it's uh also there as a
pipeline
details all right so that's the two
styles of logging
so now you've got it and i did that on a
centos box it's the same
on mac except syslog is a little
different on mac but
you can still have your transcripts and
all that there too so
so that's cross platform powershow i
know
most of you are probably in windows
environments and that's your primary
concern
but i want you to be aware of the
concerns for
powershell core that's emerging that's
going to be your next
attack vector that the red team could be
using against you
so be careful out there a couple things
you need to know before you
implement powershell
logging at scale across your environment
so transcription specifically can cause
some issues
and this is not a i guess this is really
just a
core fundamental issue with the
operating system the way some of the
transcription works i've already
um had a meeting with the pm at
microsoft giving them this feedback
this is feedback that i've seen working
with customers is that
if you turn on powershell transcription
it will crash
citrix not cool if you have citrix in
your environment all right they learned
the hard way
active directory administrative center
is that little powershell-based version
of
active directory users and computers
it'll hang that as well
and if you're using scom some of the
management scripts in scom can fail
if you have transcription disabled and i
saw a note from microsoft
support that said they were going to
potentially automatically disable
powershell transcription out of the box
when you install scom so watch out for
that
be careful on that conflict if you use
microsoft's
also some older versions of i use vs
code every day on my mac
to do powershell note-taking and things
now there's a
script analyzer plug-in that happens
when you are editing powershell and vs
code
that plug-in using script analyzer was
backed
by uh powershell code in the source
which would then cause additional
logging
to just spam your logs i've talked with
the
powershell team on that last year they
said they're fixing that i
presume i haven't checked lately it's
probably fixed by now
but just be aware that if you leave vs
code open with powershell in it
it can trigger log writing all day long
even if you're not doing anything
in it um also i haven't talked about
hardening yet i'll get to that in a
second
but you want to harden your
transcription directory
if you do that on powershell for an
older version that does support
transcription
uh that's why i don't recommend the
older versions you should be on
powershell 51 but if you've got like a
2012 r2 box
that you've turned on powershell
transcription
and you open the powershell prompt it'll
it'll just crash it won't even
run so you can break it hardening means
setting that transcript directory so
only so
everyday users can only write into that
directory but they can't read from it
only
administrators and local system can read
transcripts out of there
reason being is you don't want everyday
users
on servers or workstations being able to
get into those
transcript files or those event logs for
that matter
because if they can then they could
potentially see
secret information that you would put in
your powershell scripts and run across
the enterprise now i know
nobody watching this video would ever
put passwords into a powershell script
however you might have other things that
are you know sql connection strings or
you know some other type of
privileged information that you don't
want people to see so make sure you
harden transcripts and event logs
and if you harden the event logs you
have to set it through the registry
i've got a script that'll help you with
that some
some editions of windows that might
require reboot before that hardening
would take place
now i'm also interested to know from you
what issues have you encountered
with powershell logging in the
enterprise
if you've got any of those catch my
contact information at the end of the
deck i really do want to hear from you
because i'm
trying to compile good guidance from
field
experience to help other customers as
well
so some free resources for you number
one i have created a
ps policy module out on github right now
it only works with windows
powershell51 it doesn't do powershell
core yet but what it does is instead of
because again group policy is unwieldy
in a lot of environments because it's so
um it's so long in the tooth and it's
been i usually most places it's not been
managed well
and you've got conflicts of policies
everywhere it's easier to go straight to
the registry to set these so i've
provided some scripts for you that will
set the policies
also will increase the event log size
because
the default event log size for
powershell
is 15 megs and that's not going to hold
very much of anything
especially once you turn this on so you
want to increase your event log size
i've seen
industry standard guidance that says you
know set it to a gig
so that you've got and then monitor
those logs to see
how many days of activity you're getting
in those logs and that's what this
ps model policy module is designed to do
it'll also give you the code you need to
harden both the transcripts and the
windows event logs
and then clean out those transcript
files if you start writing files to disk
and you never clean them that's going to
be a problem one day surprise you filled
the disk up so
you want to also schedule a task to
clean those transcript files
on your endpoints and then also you want
to
be able to search across all those
logging locations that we looked at
in the event of an uh investigation a
forensic
investigation so i have a script that
will do that however i put here foot gun
warning you can shoot yourself in the
foot this way because
if i'm typing in meme cats as my
search string and i'm searching that
from a powershell prompt
now i have introduced the word mimi cats
into
the very logs that i'm trying to search
for mimi cats you see that
ship in the bottle you know inception
kind of problem that we have there so be
careful with that
there's a command here to do it you
should do that obviously as you already
practice on a
machine that's dedicated to
investigation where you don't have to
worry about corrupting your own local
logs
so this is a work in progress
you can ping me if you run into issues
it's not really
released widely yet i haven't really set
a powershell gallery yet either
so i'm interested in your feedback give
this a try let me know if it's helpful
to you and your environment but what
it's designed to do is take care of some
of the cleanup
and nuances around these policies that
don't come out of the box with group
policy
also last year i spoke at the powershell
summit
2019 unfortunately it was canceled this
year but last year i did a hands-on lab
going through all of these policies on
windows and there's a lab on
linux as well and so there's a guide
here
on github you can go check out and walk
through building out your own vms and
build your own environment where you can
practice with powershell policies and i
walk you through step by step
in a very teaching method how to do a
lot of the use cases
that we went through very quickly today
it's a lot of extra tips packed in there
that you want to
check out also if you're curious how do
i get
powershell on my mac or linux box
there's
instructions there at the
docs.microsoft.com
also i'll provide a pdf of this deck for
you out on my github
and as always uh you can reach me
actually.mcglanatanium.com
or on twitter at go tpfe
and i work for microsoft my title was
premier field engineer
now i've left microsoft and i'm still i
can't change my twitter and
i'll lose a bunch of people so anyway uh
reach me at go tpfe
out there on twitter and this
presentation
is not a vendor commercial
it's designed for public education right
however that being said
there are some challenges with doing
this automation of setting these things
at scale and that's exactly what tanium
does really well so when i came to
tanium
i brought this knowledge of powershell
investigation and
policy management and i built it into
some content for tanium customers
so that you can set these policies at
scale see where they're set what the
settings are
very quickly within a few seconds and
then also
once you've got the settings turned on
how do i keep the transcripts clean
all that stuff the hardening is all
taken care of and some content i created
on the titanium platform
but then more importantly is how do i
look for mimi cats again for example how
do i find that then across
thousands of machines in the event logs
we can do that
very quickly with tanium as well so if
you'd like more information on that
you can reach out to me so
uh besides this has been fantastic
sharing the day with you i look forward
to the q a here in a few minutes
happy to answer any questions you might
have there
so in the words of mark
manassee one of our industry mentors on
the windows
side of things use your powers for good
and not for evil
so thank you for attending today's
session and i hope to see you
in the q a soon
you