hello besides columbus attendees
thank you for attending my session today
which is titled linear irs
my name is matt shear people may follow
me on twitter at c3rkah
also i have my linkedin contact
information on this slide
anybody interested in obtaining a copy
of the slide deck from my talk
may do so at slideshare.net circa
let's begin a couple quick things about
me is i work for a big well-known
organization
as an infosec engineer performing dfir
on a c-cert
i also run the simpa security sig which
is a local
information security meetup group based
in cincinnati ohio
quick disclaimer is that yes i do have a
day job however opinions expressed are
based solely on my own independent
security research
and do not express or reflect the views
or opinions of my employer
my objectives are to show live demo
reenactments of real attacks
how these real world attacks worked how
and why they defeated security solutions
show instant response to these attacks
and demo investigation tools and
techniques
along with discussing lessons learned
and key takeaways
some of the acronyms i might use during
this talk are ioc
or ioc ir for incident response
dfir which is digital forensics and
instant response just to make sure that
we're all starting on the same page
other disclaimers are that the demos i'm
giving are
based on 100 percent true stories these
demos dutifully recreate
actual attacks however some details were
altered
investigation demos are sped up
considerably in the interest of
allotted presentation time attendees
should only perform these techniques in
a dedicated securely isolated and
volatile sandbox
now something with my talk today is i'm
doing live demos
on a host laptop
this is a local system when the real
investigations happened those were
done within a sandbox environment
so for the purposes of this talk let's
please just use a
pretend sandbox when i'm doing these
demos how it was originally done
the first scenario i'd like to start
with is called the mystery attachment
do you set the preface for this there
was a news headline from august 17th
of 2018 mousebam campaign targets banks
using microsoft publisher
the reason this is a little unusual is
not that
malicious threat actors were sending
email messages
phishing email messages with malicious
attachments
it's just typically when you see those
things they're very often microsoft
office documents
like word or excel rather than
powerpoint or
you know another thing that is commonly
used is adobe pdf files
the flawed amy rat was part of the curse
botnet as reported by researchers at
trustwave
and i've got a link to that original
article the unusualness of
leveraging microsoft publisher and the
fact that it was targeted against banks
i got picked up in the news cycle by
quite a number
of other places one week later
i'm sitting at my desk dutifully working
on probably a number of
things at the same time when somebody
comes up to my desk
and i can see that they're very anxious
and a little frantic
and telling me matt help one of our vips
with access to lots of very sensitive
information just got hit
in that recent mousebam campaign
targeting banks it matches
the iocs from the reports of that new
flawed amy app which is part of the
curves botnet
the recipient attempted to open the
microsoft publisher attachment on their
smartphone
i need you to drop whatever you're doing
and investigate this we'll get you the
attachment
asap and uh just sort of important to
note here that uh when
i was first approached i'm thinking all
right another thing to investigate and
look into
but uh as the individual kind of stood
there and kept talking and saying oh
this matches perfectly
uh the things that we've you know we're
seeing in the the news about uh
this most recent threat um you know sort
of
i started getting amped up listening to
them uh tell me about this stuff
and uh once i got the attachment i just
really started tearing into it
so i'd like to do today is open the file
demo in the sandbox we're going to do
detonation research attempts and failure
to understand anything about this
malicious file
as well as i can i also want to showcase
some other tools i use
when i am looking at a file i don't know
a lot about such as strings
do some hashing and simulated online
research
and then we'll look at the exif data
which was sort of this fleeting thought
i had as i was
pondering my my next steps so with that
let me go ahead and open up the file
here
and here you see in the folder i've got
the microsoft publisher file
now when i open this up it's going to
open up in libreoffice draw on my missus
on my system in reality the sandbox i
had access to really did have microsoft
publisher installed on it
so again just sort of pretend this is
our sandbox and we're in publisher
uh and the document really looks
something like this uh
you know it's pretty typical of a lot of
malware
i've seen and it would come up and say
you know macros have to be enabled to
essentially see the contents of the
document and please click the enable
content button
the trick for me was i couldn't actually
get this to pop up
i tried a number of different things and
i just couldn't get it to work
and uh was sort of scratching my head
about that and contemplating and
wondering
why that was i also poked around
publisher for a little bit but i'm not
very familiar with that at particular
application
so i really couldn't find uh the macros
i was looking for
really just sort of threw me off a
little bit so this was the kind of thing
that i had uploaded to our
automated sandbox to do detonation and
see what it would find out and hopefully
get a disposition
on uh whether the document was malicious
and how it might be malicious
so while i'm looking at that and kind of
letting it go through i decide that
i'm going to go ahead and run strings
against this file
to see what's in it so i'm going to run
the strings command
specify the file name what i like to do
is
pipe the strings command to less
what that lets me do is that lets me
just slowly review the file
i can even you know look at things line
by line if i want to
otherwise it would just scroll through
the screen all the way straight to the
end and i wouldn't see
you know the stuff you know leading up
to that
strings command what it does is it
strips out human readable text from
most any file and in this case
it comes up and looking at some stuff
that
turns out to definitely indicate this is
a legitimate
microsoft publisher file and
i started looking through some of the
text that pulled out
fortunately i didn't really find
anything interesting just some basic
commands like i didn't find
comment code or other things that might
be in human readable
text format that would tip me off as to
what this is or how it might work
so unfortunately that was a dead end for
me
what i decided to do while i was waiting
uh and certainly
um you could get the hash values from
the sandbox detonation with with most
sandboxes
um however what i decided to do is do
some online research
so i'm gonna go ahead and oops pull up
the shaw 256 sum for this particular
file and see what i get and so here's
the
the hash value of the file itself um
one thing that's important to note is
you sort of have to understand what
tools you have in your environment
and the types of tools and utilities
that you might use
and really know what the hashing
algorithms the supported ones are
in any particular given environment
in my case at the time shaw 256 was
universally supported across most
everything
there's some tools and services that
might
still only support something like md5 uh
and
reality is during the investigation i
probably looked at some of the other
hashing algorithms as well
but again the interest of time we'll
just use this for our demo
so i had the hash value and armed with
that i decided to
go online and see what i could find out
so what i did is i decided to search for
this hash value
in virus total of course virustotal gets
a lot of
submissions uh every day
and chances are very good if there's
some repurposed malware that it will
find it
because what virustotal of course does
is they use 70
some odd search well i'm sorry
antivirus scan engines to analyze a file
to see what it can detect so
fairly unusual when you have a file and
fire's total has never seen it before
so while that was a dead end i decided
to look at a similar service called jody
malware scan
went ahead and searched for the hash
value there so
it's it's one of these interesting
things where
javi doesn't have as many av scan
engines as virustotal does
but you never know from one engine to
another which one might have
slightly more updated virus definitions
i'm sure there's a lot of overlap here
but maybe there's potentially a couple
uh new pieces of saw or you know av
engines between the two as well
unfortunately
you can see i searched for the hash
value and it just didn't return any
results
so i decided to run the search through
hybrid analysis and that's another
um sort of a third-party sandbox
platform on the web
and uh surprised again that didn't see
it either
so it was you know a little bit
disheartening that i couldn't find this
particular file being seen anywhere else
so i just went for broke and searched
for some hashing algorithms on google
and no matter how i tried it i just
didn't get any results back as well
and so some of the questions i'm sort of
pondering in my own mind at this point
are you know could this be a zero day
variant of that particular
malicious file what um
other you know things may have been done
could have been re-encoded
or could have even been modified
specifically to target our organization
so these are very concerning um ideas
that i had
and uh go back to the slide deck here
so then i'm thinking okay well i also
spent a great
deal of time doing research on flawed
amy on the curse
looking at the iocs that have been
reported
trying to see if i can draw some
correlations between those
and what i'm seeing that will sort of
help me prove out what this thing is
and how it's working what it does
and unfortunately i just couldn't piece
anything together i couldn't get a match
here
so then my mind immediately shifts to
all right i've looked through this thing
as well as i could um i haven't done
an attempted memory forensics on it
but the tools i have are basically
running
for desktop os's as an example and this
device happened to be an iphone
so things are going to behave
differently from
one platform to another different
hardware
all these things come into play also if
there's
some sort of uh you know anti-forensics
built into
these things to make them hard to detect
um you know i the options i'm
thinking are well it's it's somewhat
unlikely that
a publisher file could execute malware
on an iphone
but i can't prove that it doesn't so you
know but
i didn't really have a risk tolerance
for
just kind of letting it ride assuming
that the
infection was likely low
another option was to perhaps do a
security wipe on the device
and uh hope that's good enough to
essentially
remove anything that may have been
dropped onto this
mobile device but that didn't really
seem like
something i wanted to accept the risk on
either simply because i couldn't
prove or disprove that it was clean
since i couldn't really understand the
infection itself
so really my last thought is it's time
to probably just
look at confiscating this device
shutting it down
essentially inventorying it inside of
our digital forensics lab
and go about getting this individual new
device
i looked they weren't quite due for a
refresh yet
uh however they were within six months
of um
qualifying for a refresh device so i
started feeling comfortable with that
as probably my best course of action but
the interesting thing is i thought well
this is kind of silly but i actually
didn't take the time to
look at the exif properties so in a
microsoft
windows environment to look at exit
properties for something like a
publisher file
you would simply right click on that
file go into the properties
and then start looking at the details
and those will show you things like
maybe who authored it
you get a lot of other potential
information if there's you know
copyrights sometimes with image files
you can get geographic data
just some things you can do then maybe
get some sort of attribution
but you always have to take that with a
big grain of salt because
exif data can be spoofed but it's still
something i hadn't looked at
and was kind of surprised that i didn't
take time to look at that so let's go
ahead and
do something like that since i'm not in
the windows environment i'm going to use
the pearl exif tool
to take a look at this particular file
and so when that comes up some of the
things you get about the exit tool
itself
you know the file name file size
some really good information around the
time stamp particularly
with the file modification date time
this would give me a clue when the file
really came into being uh you see more
current things where it's accessed and
you know things have changed but the
file modification date and time
could be an important indicator some
things that were a little bit unusual
is since i don't spend a lot of time
looking at publisher files where the
file type file type extension in the
mime type here so those definitely
struck me as being a little unusual so i
actually researched those online and
found out that yes
this is what legitimate pub microsoft
publisher files look like
and uh certainly it's it's telling me
it's a publisher file
uh i get down to the author now it
didn't actually
come out and say test fish uh it was
actually similar enough to that
what it was was this face palm moment
where i had our test fishing vendor's
name in it
and uh for me sort of embarrassing when
i realized that the
email attachment i just spent hours
looking at
actually came from our test fishing
vendor and it's okay if you want to go
ahead and laugh at my pain here
but i want to talk about some of the
lessons i learned from that
now again i talked about exit data could
be spoofed so i didn't want to just
trust that so what i did is i went back
to our secure
email gateway and looked at the message
headers
from this and uh you know if it was
supposed to
come from our test fishing vendor it
looked like what i would expect
of course i looked at it like yes matt
this really is your test fishing
vendor's ip address you don't
so what went wrong here i got caught up
in my
the moment really by subconsciously
letting somebody else influence my
investigation
their anxiety and bad assumptions wore
off on me
so i should have started with the
message headers first which is what i
typically do when i investigate phishing
messages this one time i abandoned my
own standards this one you know by
focusing on the file attachment first
and ironically i've given phishing
forensics talks and that's where i
always start with the headers
the one time i don't sure enough it
comes back to bite me
so let's talk about the remediation
really in this case it was just a road
to redemption
were painful lessons learned for
reminders to stick to my standard
investigative processes and procedures
if i would have started with my or my
investigation by inspecting the message
headers first
i could have closed out this
investigation in minutes instead of
hours
and since it was testing there was no
further actions that were required
my next scenario is called security
scanner evasion
just to set the table for this identical
phishing emails started hitting inboxes
and we started getting wide scale
reports of fishing coming in
usually those reports sort of trickle in
throughout the course of a day
but within a relatively short period of
time
we had a huge influx of these pouring in
really got my attention is something
that we need to look at
sooner rather than later so the phishing
page link
within the email once i i pulled it back
and saw that it was it no longer
appeared to be working
in my security scanner so i had to ask
you know
was the malicious site taken offline
already maybe if this thing's been shut
down
it's something we don't actually need to
worry about
so let's investigate and find out
for the investigation i will look at the
email message source code and i'm going
to demo that
and again this is our pretend sandbox
environment
and look for hyperlinks we'll check the
landing page with a security scanner i'm
going to
simulate that and then we'll look at the
landing page source code
again in our our pretend sandbox and
then we'll also
open the phishing page in that just to
see what it looks like
so let's go ahead and take a look at
this phishing email
oops hold on we'll get to that one
here in a moment
all right here's the fish email i was
looking for um so this comes in
and uh it's a uh
i know that the short headers are
probably a little hard to read but it's
from evil scam or promise we are
legit.com
the subject is this link is totally safe
and it's targeting an unwitting victim
and it looked something close to this
hello fishing target we have a really
important message for you to retrieve
your message
click here that's not real subtle um
and then regards spoof sender so let's
go ahead and look at the
header or the message source on this and
see what we can learn
and i'll make this a bit bigger so it's
easier for everybody to see
i'm going to search for http and
here's the text here on click here
that we saw within the email itself but
here's the
address where it's actually going so
again what i want to do is throw this
into a security scanner tool to
understand
what this is and how it behaves so i
want to see
screenshots of what it looks like i want
to see source code things like that so i
put this in our security scanner
solution and it comes back with a server
404 error
essentially telling me that the content
is no longer there
it's well it was there it's just not
there so
it by all appearances at this point
looks like it's been taken offline
if that's the case then perhaps this is
something we don't have to worry about
but i have a little bit of concerns and
i wanted to take a look at this a little
bit further
so let's go ahead and get the source
code from this
and see what that looks like there's a
couple options for this
i'm going to show you a couple of them
so i'm going to use
curl with the address and
let me stand we're going to output this
to something we'll call unknown
dot html and we retrieved it
now if we don't have curl available
on the system or you know maybe not
comfortable with it there's always a
tried and true utility like wget
in this case wget put in the site
address
and retrieve the file that way now if i
take a look at what we have
for html files
we'll see the two files that i pulled
down unknown is what we pulled from
curl and index is what we pulled down
using wget
you will notice that they are the same
file size
one thing to be aware of in this demo
since i'm retrieving the file from a
local
server the local machine server i'm
getting the original
time date stamp on this as opposed to
when i actually pulled it down
in the real world if you're using wget
to pull down files from a remote
server on the internet for example
you'll actually get a
more recent timestamp for when you
it should reflect when you actually made
the request and the file was
pulled down so it's a little bit of an
anomaly here
but i do want to show folks that it's
there they really are forensically the
same file so we'll do a shock 256
some value of html files
and here we can see we have an exact
match for both files
so we know this really is the same so
it's one of these things where you can
really sort of use whatever works for
you in this instance
you know what your your best option
might be
so now that we have the file let's
actually go ahead and take a look at
that
i'm just going to pull one of these up
here in a text editor
we'll just look at the index html
and that's going to open it up in our
text editor
and make this a little bit bigger so
it's easier to see and what we have here
is um really just a typical html file
and then we get here to what is really
javascript
and so what it's doing is saying if
navigator
user agent index of and we start seeing
common
web browsers such as chrome microsoft
edge
firefox internet explorer opera
and safari and what's interesting is
notice that they're really kind of going
to the same
page and this replay this location
replaces essentially doing a
redirect what gets very interesting here
at the bottom is we see an
else statement so if these conditions
aren't met
then it's actually sending the visitor
somewhere else and
what i believe the threat actor actors
doing here is they're checking to make
sure
that before they send somebody to a
malicious page
that it really is a legitimate web
browser
and not some security scanner because if
it's not spoofing one of these common
browser
user agents it's never going to see it
it's going to go to the
fake for well yeah really our fake 404
page
but if it is one of these browsers it
will send the traffic somewhere else
so let's go ahead and take a look at
this and see what that
looks like for real and put in the
website address here
and here we have a microsoft office 365
credential harvesting page it's not
really office 365.
it's just something threat actress has
set up to collect people's
usernames and passwords from there they
can do
obviously a lot of a lot of bad things
so with that now understanding how this
works a little bit
let's go back and we've seen this
we talked about the evasion code and how
it works using the browser's user agent
string
uh in this case i got really lucky
because the threat actors
had used javascript which is a
client-side language
meaning i actually see all the code uh
when i pull it down
if the thread actor though had used a
server-side language
like you know php python or any of a
number of
other ones i would not be able to see
the source code without
some sort of special access privilege to
the server itself
something you're unlikely to have uh
when it comes to third-party internet
sites
um so you know i was able to see it
and understand the code if they had used
one of these server side languages
i sure i still would have been able to
tell a redirect happened and ultimately
know where it goes but i wouldn't
necessarily
see it underneath the hood perspective
of how it works
and then some other thoughts i had that
would have made this also harder
would be if they were targeting specific
browsers so let's
use a hypothetical example where maybe
malicious threat actors have a
mozilla firefox exploit
and they have a page set up to
essentially launch an exploit kit
against site visitors if they
are using firefox they can actually
filter out
everybody else and really um what they
can do is
send everybody else to a real page if
it's firefox they can send them to
a page that has the the
xsplit kit on it execute that and then
round robin
redirect them to the real page
and all that tends to happen fast enough
that most site visitors aren't even
going to notice that
split second less than the split second
probably that it takes for that to
happen
so definitely some things that could
have been done that would make that
harder and going a step further with
that
let's say the exploit kit for firefox
they had only worked on
certain versions they can actually check
the versions
um use essentially
really to focus on just the vulnerable
versions
and that really makes it harder to
detect and know it's something you
should block
because then the scope gets really
narrow of what they're targeting
so definitely some scary thoughts around
that
the remediation plan in this case where
to determine the actual
phishing landing page and block through
web content filtering
we also worked with our secure email
gateway vendor to block the phishing
campaign
i believe we also made sure that the
message was quarantined throughout the
environment following that
um so that's what we did to address that
problem
the third scenario i'd like to cover is
something i call the rabbit hole
and set the table for this i received a
request from a user to investigate an
email message they received to determine
if it was legitimate or not
the email appeared fishy at first glance
but i had to ask the question
is it just suspicious or is it malicious
now is it just suspicious or is it
malicious is actually a
fishing forensics talk i've given
several places uh if you're interested
in
looking at that you can search youtube
for b-sides cleveland
in that title uh that's probably the
best recorded version of that that is
out there
the investigation um from this point was
i could tell from the message headers
that the source ip address was a
mismatch for the
sender domain the email message source
code was particularly interesting
uh and in particular because the link
tax didn't match the hyperlink
destination we're going to look at that
here in just a moment
the malicious threat actors objective
appeared to be credential harvesting
and we'll see what that look like for
the purposes of account takeover
so let's go ahead and pull up the right
fishing email for this one
and see what that looked like so here we
have an email message
and in our case it's supposedly coming
from paypal support
but what we notice the actual email
address is
listed as pp support at
pwndashserver.org
it's got a subject of paypal bank
account change confirmation
and it's targeting an unwitting victim
again
and so when we see change confirmation
if you have a pay compile account and
didn't make changes to it
and you get an email notification like
this uh you
you know might be something that you get
you know inquisitive about one take a
look at so looking at this
uh dear paypal customer we received your
request to update your bank account on
file this process will complete in the
next four hours
if you did not request these changes to
your paypal account please log in to
reject the pending activity
and here we see the paypal address
and interestingly enough if you went to
the paypal address you see
here it would take you to the real sign
in page
for paypal but all is not quite as it
seems
then we'll take a look at the message
source here but i did want to highlight
that you know this four hour window
is designed to instill a sense of
urgency
if i see that bank account changes have
supposedly been
made to my paypal account and i know i
didn't make them
as an end user i might be inclined to
want to hop on right away and block
these changes from happening to protect
my account
we're going to go ahead and look at the
message source here though
let me pull that up
and then we're going to take a look at
that that link that we talked about
so here what we see is we have the
paypal address that we saw in the email
and again
that's the legitimate address that you
would use to log into paypal
however the hyperlink isn't going to
what we see in the link text that's
actually going to this other domain
so we want to take a look at that in
particular
this is a be domain which means it's in
belgium
not something i would necessarily expect
expect to see from a
legitimate paypal account so let's go
ahead and
see what this looks like in our pretend
sandbox
and what we have here is you know
something that would resemble a
paypal login i've made it a little bit
bigger so it's easier to see
um but uh you know it definitely isn't
isn't where we would expected it to so
let's go ahead and use curl
and we'll pull this site down and look
at the source code here
and i'm going to output that
to first page dot html
now that we have it let me clear this up
and let's go ahead and take a look at
this
inside of a
text editor and you can use the editor
of your choice i'm just trying to make
this easy for
demonstration purposes here but really
it's just a very small html file
and certainly doesn't really have
content like we would expect to see
if it was a live page so what we notice
is there's a meta tag here an http
meta tag with refresh and content equals
zero means it happens
right away so there's no five second
delay for example
like you would see if you have number
five in here and we've got this other
address
that doesn't match the first one and we
know that because we see
de domain would indicate that it's a
german
website domain so
sort of unusual because we knew we
started belgium but now we're going to a
different place
so let's go to our slide deck and catch
back up here
the destination uh you know it was going
to
it was hosted in one foreign country it
didn't stop there though
so we see now that we've got a second
country and it doesn't stop there
and so let's go ahead and get the page
source code and find out what's going on
there
and we'll use the same method i'm just
going to use curl
the web domain
and we're output that the second page
dot html
and we'll take a look at that in our
editor
again pretty short file not really much
like we would expect to find in contents
but we don't see an http meta refresh
like we did before
what we do see though is an iframe
and here we seem to have a another
domain
and it's even in yet another country the
netherlands
so already we've got several layers of
obfuscation here
so we've got the link text not matching
the landing page
it's one layer of obfuscation it's not
going to a real
page but that page is actually
redirecting to another page
another good layer of obfuscation and
then that page is serving up content
from somewhere else
and we see here that the
when we look at this we understand that
it's essentially a borderless
seamless iframe so it's going to look
like you're actually visiting this page
when you're actually at the other site
and some obviously bad things that can
happen for the paypal
account are that it could
you know when somebody has those
credentials they can use it to transfer
money to accounts
um do fake purchases uh maybe even as
far as a
fake online store where they're just
collecting money on the back end and not
providing any services or shipping goods
so these are definitely concerning
things um
let's go ahead and grab this third page
and see what we have here
so we'll go ahead and and
grab this content and see what's here so
we'll go ahead and
pull this back i'm going to go ahead and
run curl and
put in this other domain and we'll go
ahead
and output this
and we'll call it third page
dot html now we have that
we will go ahead and take a look at the
contents of this
file as well let me clear this up here a
little bit
and now we've got something like we
haven't seen before instead of a
page or a redirect of any sort
we've got some javascript we've got this
document right and we've got an unescape
sequence
and what appears to be a bunch of
gobbledygook this is encoded content
and i'm just going to theorize and
looking at this that what we have
is a function that's being fed back into
this unescaped sequence
now in the olden days to essentially
look at this what we would have to do is
we would have to
unescape this out to essentially get the
formula to feed
the function content back into so we can
see and understand what's happening here
so all this is getting really
interesting really fast because
again these are yet more layers of
obfuscation
piled into what we've already looked at
i talked about what we had to do in the
olden days to kind of
reverse this by hand fortunately the
thing to remember is that if something
can be rendered inside of a web browser
then it has to be something that can be
decoded otherwise you would never
be able to see it in the browser when
you visit the page
so what i'm going to do here is uh
pull up this final landing page and it's
again just what we looked at before but
instead of the iframe we're actually at
the real page content now
where this actually exists or what we
think it does we kind of
understand the page code first
so i'm going to go ahead and pull up the
developer tools
inside of chrome and i want to go back
to this page and refresh it just to make
sure that
we're feeding in the content that we
want to look at
go to here
brought up the wrong one here hold on
so what we're gonna do is we're going to
go ahead and click in here
oops that's the wrong one
let me go here to elements uh here we go
this is what i want to look at
we'll edit as html and sure enough this
matches the text file we were just
looking at
so this has that encoded unescape
sequence
the function now i made this purposely
more
readable uh which is hard to believe
because we're still looking at encoded
content right but
the fact is with the white space you can
see this
an escape sequence you see the function
javascript up here in real life you may
see this whole thing all bunched
together with no spacing whatsoever
so you start looking for some of the
telltale signs like the semicolon
inside the parentheses things like that
so i talked about how the browser
decodes it the neat thing here is if we
scroll
all the way down we actually finally get
to the decoded
content that the browser is rendering so
here we actually see that decoded
or you know unescaped rather formula
that is feeding sure enough a function
into it
and i expected to see regular html code
but what was interesting is some of the
early stuff
were actually more encoded content
uh looking at the line in front of this
um you know it's telling me that uh the
mime type is
a data image x icon and here we can tell
because it's listed as base64 that is
base64 encoded content
so it's a relatively big blob of stuff
here
if i scroll down past this then i start
getting into the
actual html code and i got a little fast
there
so here's regular code and then we find
yet another
base64 encoded blob within this
same web page web
that we're looking at so this is a
little bit unusual if i do scroll past
this again i see
more traditional html like i would
expect
so looking at the at this blob right
here
the bigger of the two there are some
neat tools built in that help us with
this
so if i click on the
data image that it pulled down inside
the developer tools
here we can see that same line we had
before that's a jpeg image it's b64
encoded and this is the same blob of
stuff that we had
what's really neat is instead of having
to decode this by hand we can actually
click on the preview
tab here and see that it's a pal
logo if we go back to the page sure
enough that matches what we're looking
at so we've actually found the
graphic image but when we go back to
developer tools we didn't really pull
back any other image files that's the
only one and if you remember we actually
had two
base64 encoded um items
so we'll go ahead and talk about what it
takes to decode that by hand
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
scroll down and copy down this whole
blob and we'll throw it into a
text editor and save it out and
talk about what we do to decode that
so i've done that now let me go ahead
and go back to the text editor
and paste this in here and
this is that same blob we were looking
at let's go ahead and save this
out
and we'll go ahead and call it um
icon.txt based on the mime type that we
saw
and see what we have i'm going to go
ahead and save that
and come back to our text editor and i'm
going to use the base64 command
and do a dash d to decode do a dash i to
just sort of ignore
any errors that might have with it and
uh
we'll go ahead and uh oops
do that against the icon.txt file i'm
going to redirect the output
of this decode into something i'm going
to guess is favicon.ico
when i do that i end up with
that completing and let's go ahead and
take a look in our folder
and see what we have here's the fav icon
file
i'm going to make this much bigger so
it's easier to see
and i guess i'm going to guess here if
we go back to our web browser
that we should see that rendered in the
session itself
and uh might be a little bit uh small
but
here we have the icon within
the file here so at this point
we have a real good idea of what we're
looking at
that it really is the proper favicon
file
so let's go ahead and catch back up on
the slide deck
we've looked at the source code we found
the encoded content
and we used javascript encoding well
that thread actors use javascript
encoding to avoid analysis and detection
while hiding the page source code the
true source code
we decoded the page using built-in
browser developer tools
we looked at encoded elements and i'm
not sure
whether they did that simply to further
avoid analysis and detection
or they just simply wanted a one page
file and base64 encoding those image
files and the fav icon was a way to keep
that as one page
but whatever their rationale for doing
it the way they did
we did decode that using the built-in
tools and we also did that by hand
the remediation plan in this case was to
well we determined the final fishing
landing page and we blocked it through
web content filtering
we then blocked compromised web servers
through
web content filtering then we reported
compromised websites to domain owners
using
in their hosting companies through whois
contact records
so that's what i have for the demos for
this talk uh
in closing i will be hanging around
online as you see me hanging around
online
please share your own dfir stories with
me with that i want to say
friends romans besides columbus
attendees lend me your irs
i will stick around and be happy to
answer any questions anybody has
please hit me up online through the
conference and i'll be happy to uh
chat i want to thank everybody very much
for attending
i appreciate you checking out my session
thank you very much
goodbye