okay okay thank you very much
so it's been a while since in spoken and
a key University Hall so yeah looks good
so I'm going to talk to you about the
tsunami about all of those io T's and
all of those devices that are a bitch
forsaken or the people don't think about
so let me start with a few really short
questions and I appreciate it Saturday
at 3:00 p.m. so try to do my best here
how many of you believe that there well
that's not with that how many have a
seem to be at work seem to be okay
how many of you think the seem to be is
accurate okay that's a really good
response so look at it this way if I
would ask the same question ten years
ago I think that about the same number
of people would say that they have the
same to be but then most of them would
say yes we have an amazing CMDB yes we
have a good seem to be or at least yes
we have some problems but we'll fix them
we are on a way to fix that thing is
that the world kind of change sense so
the explosion of those IO T's what's an
IOT any examples here ideas what's
what's an IOT device cellphones electric
meter okay yes it is yeah that projector
exactly that projector that yeah that's
not a small TV it's not the TV but yeah
actually I've seen some of those smart
boards that have the cameras on both
sides right that you could just capture
what's on that same thing any but these
are just you know these are office
environment or electrical environments
what about your innovator what about
your HVAC system what about what's the
funkiest thing I've seen lately
that actually connects home anybody
heard about the fishtank example
medical care everything is an IOT
whatever whatever you touch is an IOT
fishtank
so as you see I have a presentation I
have many slides III hate slides so I'll
go through some sites do but I hate
slides when you look at there was a
there was a casino in Vegas that had
what still has it a huge aquarium with
lots of amazing fish lots of expensive
fish in gorgeous dish and this fish had
a small sensor that was supposed to
measure how hard to what was right
that's really important measurement okay
how much you think that sensor cost
yeah I'm five bucks ten bucks you know
something something you'd get from eBay
I'm sure the casino said they didn't get
him from eBay so they pay fifteen sort
of five that's fine they connected it to
the guest Network because Fisher gets
our guests and and they had to connect
it because that's how those fish where
I'm sorry that that's how the head
sensor connected to the Internet
okay and there was a hole knock
somewhere in China I don't know where
this that was actually monitoring them
and that water and made sure that the
fish will still be alive
what do you think happened so usually
when I tell the story somebody would say
fish tag is the nice thing that that's
usually somebody would say did the fish
burn no the fish did not burn what what
happened I actually went to see that
aquarium like the fish are okay what
actually happened there was that
somebody came with his cell phone and
connected the tiny computer to that and
used Bluetooth in order to connect to
that $5.00 sensor now
it got now this $5 em so you might
imagine doesn't really have too many
security features right I mean it's a
sensor it protects fish so connected via
bluetooth nobody cares about that was in
the network was what was in the fish
tank
then from there he went into the guest
network from the guest network he went
into the corporate network because
that's what people do nowadays you know
the distinction between guest and
corporate network is just for show if
you know what you're doing takes two
five minutes and got into the database
and got all the lists like the one thing
that the casino has that's the most
expensive thing which is the list of its
high waters okay you can google it later
true story so fishtank $5 devices
everything that explodes in the world so
yeah I don't have some slide so let's
just go to some examples here it's smart
office right looking at all the devices
in your office how do you know if your
printer is malicious why do you care
same thing like same thing like anything
else right if the printer is doing
something wrong it will get into your
network and will get to wherever the
most important value but whatever things
is not to mention if you really need to
print something and it doesn't work
that's not good hospitals right health
care that's where it becomes just not
funny right
so when you're looking at patient
monitors and we're looking at infusion
pumps right these are true examples that
happens in hospitals in the US so when
you look at a monitor you know just
think about the possibilities here
I mean monitor saves lives right it will
give you an alert when somebody when
somebody needs attention that's not
funny anymore so what happens if that
monitor just doesn't alert what happens
if it's a I don't know a famous person
and that monitor instead of what
monitoring would just send all the vital
information to someone in the cloud
right privacy issues infusion pump in
other I mean it is a funny story now
because the patient is actually alive
and well but
again true story there was an infusion
pump that was connecting to a person and
that person was not in a good state and
that infusion pump was compromised and
it was discovered that is compromised
but they couldn't take it off because it
was actually really important
so they actually for a whole week like
they literally didn't know what to do I
mean taking it off is bad keeping it is
well bad too because you don't know
what's going to happen they actually had
the nurse 24/7 looking at that person
with that infusion but not have really
known did not want to be in that
person's family there was a nurse 24/7
sitting there in making sure that the
patient doesn't deteriorate because of
that infusion time that they didn't know
what's going to do okay left one of
those robotic arm industry ot
environment all of the all manufacturing
things and at have a few like funnier
examples about manufacturing later but
all of our everything that's being
manufactured works in a protocol called
SCADA anybody here know SCADA that's
actually a lot for that question okay
SCADA is well old right there are
several protocol where there are million
protocols inside SCADA some of them on
you or some of them are older but when
you look at the factory most of them
have older equipment because guess what
it's really expensive to replace that
equipment and 20 years ago not to
mention 50 years ago but 20 years ago
when you create when manufactured a
million dollar worth of a and an away
manufacturing machine nobody cared about
security wasn't didn't existent
nowadays the newer things would have
newer protocols that are encrypted that
have lots of interesting things you can
actually look at the automobile industry
as the evolvement of those machines
right anybody knows what happens when
you any cards you're using when you hit
on the brake yeah what
[Music]
exactly exactly
it's literally like like the day the
petal itself doesn't do anything it just
it just triggers a command it's not
SCADA because it's car doesn't matter
but it's the same idea right just
trigger the command and then something
breaks who protects that well they're
companies that do that that's not us but
but that's leave or when things they are
way more encrypted when way more
protected okay a few numbers few numbers
look at those numbers of devices green
device and just going from 2010 to 2020
one I have numbers for 2025 and 2030
this is actually a gardener grass the
green is what we call the normal devices
okay
normal devices increase obviously things
evolve but not too much normal devices a
big computers PC servers things like
that you know in normal growth then you
have all of your BYO these laptops
tablets smartphones I'm not that old but
when I was in college nobody had the
laptop nobody could afford I mean we had
laptops nobody could afford it there was
like nothing there and two years later
everybody came to class with a laptop
right I mean I guess it's the same thing
now same thing now all of that is
exploding
but IO T's 25 billion devices in 2021
they're talking about a trillion devices
by 2030 a trillion from 25 billion which
by itself is crazy all of those devices
are unable
so when you're looking at 10 years ago
again in any n 10 years not 100 not 20
not 50 10 years ago 5 years ago when
people talk about protecting networks
protecting devices usually the next word
that came was agents right how many of
you have agents on their laptops at work
ok make sense
every corporate it basically means hey I
work in a corporate right every
corporate would have you know one agent
to agent 25 agents whatever it is for
different purposes that would protect
your computer better or worse whatever
that's fine but would protect your
computer you can put any agents of those
if we're looking at that correct
projector right there you cannot but you
cannot put an agent on that that's what
we like to call the ungettable device
great those are devices that you cannot
put agents on 95% of the devices by 2025
are going to be an agent over okay
before we go to that I am from so again
my name is live I hope a it's got a bit
of your attention with all kinds of war
stories I have many more to continue
with I'm from Armas and I'm heading
solution architecture in the East Coast
and strategical accounts that means that
and we'll talk later about what we do
and why we're doing I just want you to
remember one thing as I continue my
story what we do is listen to traffic
with any story that I continued that I
continue saying and telling you about
think about the fact that every device
that I'm talking about cannot have agent
every device that I'm talking about has
traffic we listen to the traffic and
give protection any examples that I'm
going to give towards the end there will
be ok what we would have done any
differently then the reason I'm saying
it now we're not waiting to the end is a
short story like to tell you I like to
tell you those things why did they join
arms what great place to work at but
beside that I used to work for five
years in a small startup that was in the
telecommunication completely not cyber
had nothing to do with cyber and we were
managing cellular antennas ever thought
about here at the cellar antennas around
wherever you are right there are so many
of them some of them are hidden low tech
trees some of them are way too obvious
8%
of the power consumption in the world is
cellular antennas 8% yeah that's crazy
the reason I'm saying that that my old
company used to do managed capacity of
the antennas and saving energy my pitch
used to be hey if you're going to deploy
us all over the world
we will save 10,000 Niagara Falls a year
okay my point is I had a project in
Indonesia and I went to Indonesia and I
needed to connect to their networks go
into the main part of their corporate
network that actually manages the
antennas we won't get into all the
details there but just to that one place
from which I can power off and manage
all the antennas in all of Indonesia and
I needed a VPN could you give me a VPN
anybody to that one server that can
power of all the attainers in your
country so I I can tell you that some
American companies did give me vpm but
wouldn't tell you which ones but to go
back to Indonesia they would they didn't
want to give me a VPN I flew to
Indonesia I met with the CTO of one of
the biggest Indonesian several companies
in three bottles of wine later he signed
a document saying ok you can get a you
can get a VPN ok two-story so why am I
telling all of that story well we
started walking with this with this
network and and we powered off those
antennas we did whatever we needed a
week later we discovered that by
accident we actually powered off also
all the cameras in that building
by accident connected to the network who
knows where it goes where it continues
so that's when I came back and said okay
I need to switch to a different place to
where we actually protect from those
things that's another example of
something that we would have done better
and protect from that would have been
discovered in like five minutes okay 84%
of security professionals believe that
IOT s are more vulnerable than computers
I should have asked you first before
saying 84% but okay enterprises have
experienced IOT security incidents just
like I've said before and 74% believe
that they have in adequate security for
IOT s okay
showing some numbers here cyber attacks
on IOT devices surged by 300% don't you
like this big slides of you know scaring
you about something
and Microsoft ones Russian hackers can
breach secure networks okay anybody
heard about those guys strontium or I'm
sure it's pronounced differently because
it's in Russian nobody okay this is a
Nash nation nation nation-state this is
a group backed by the Russian government
everything that I'm saying now is not a
top-secret whatever this is
was actually published by Microsoft so
the Russians are really good at doing
those things and you might think okay so
there are against these governments so
not to get into which ones but against
this government so what do I care or
what can I do about it
well according to the statistics twenty
percent of what they did was actually
intended against governments around the
world 80 percent was not true story
anybody knows who Mondelez is really
nobody knows their name anybody knows
who or what Oreo is come on motive in
the
or yours come on the cookie yeah okay
Mondelez makes Oreos they actually made
they make like half of the chocolate in
the world okay in all kinds of other
snacks and whatnot in 20 I want to say
2015 might have been a year or two
before after Mondelez was attacked who
the tech chocolate makers and they make
chocolate they they're specifically a
factory that they own was attacked and
it's only problem was or the reason that
it was attacked supposedly at this
Factory has the misfortune to be placed
in the Ukraine now they they have over a
hundred factories around the world and
that factory was in Ukraine was attacked
you know globally and that Factory was
one of them and if you can google later
wanna cry attack in Mondelez or Mondelez
Ukraine or any other combination of that
you will see that ok public record it
got into their new queen factory it
close it shut down the Ukraine factory
can you just imagine if like there's no
more Oreos in the world it was the globe
they didn't manufacture Oreos in that
Factory I don't know what exact type of
chocolate they made but can you imagine
the world shortage of that specific type
of chocolate because somebody attacked a
chocolate factory in the Ukraine okay
that was one of mine anybody knows wanna
cry oh that's actually nice okay doesn't
wanna cry exist anymore okay so if you
go to frankly if you go to manufacturers
if you talk to the sea to the sitios of
the sea sauce and you kind of mention
the word wanna cry they would knock on
wood they would jump three times they
would hide under the chair like
everybody is really afraid of that and
the reason is it's it's kind of like the
plague
it's was supposed to be radical about
two years ago and yet we keep seeing
that again and again and again I was
actually doing a POC with this company I
wouldn't say that company's name but I
was doing a POC with the company
just last month and we were installed we
started really small in a tiny lab that
they had somewhere and like five minutes
into being there hey you ever wanna cry
and the lab manager literally went under
a chair when I said that okay
so let's get a bit in depth you know
we're not too much but in depth into one
of the more interesting attacks and the
reason I say it's more interesting is
that actually we Thomas discovered that
specific vulnerability and I'm about to
talk about so who knows what vxworks is
higher like really
okay very good is the most okay let me
ask differently what is the most common
operating system in the world right now
exactly yeah sorry about that so I was
shocked when I heard that and when we
start with that I mean know what's the
most no operating system Windows Linux
don't want to get into that site I'm I
have a Mac but I don't know Android iOS
for that matter you know whatever it is
so no but not not even close
okay so there are over two billion
devices that are running vxworks VxWorks
is a actually over to two billion
devices that are running older version
of VxWorks they're over 10 billion
devices that are running fix works right
now
Vic's box is a simple operate and
amazing yet simple operating system that
literally everything that's an IOT has
so
projector I really don't know but most
likely is running vehicles all of your
printers are running VxWorks all of your
Xerox machines fridges lots of switches
by the way and a lot a lot more we'll
get into that so
Forbes when was that July 29th published
that the reason this is July 29th is
that we or every year we published some
new vulnerabilities that we found before
blackhat everybody does that
so that's when that came in two billion
IOT devices that got the critical object
now critical object now means well that
it is critical and it should update
right now and then we're going back to
the medical part look at those devices
anybody recognize those all kinds of all
kinds of medical pumps there right that
is also running vxworks okay because
again there's they're simple and sure
they're doing amazing things but your
simple i of T's right running the same
thing decade old code is putting
millions of critical devices at risk
okay so let's forget a bit into that
debt vulnerability and this is what this
is one ability that we came with it's
called urgent 11 anybody knows why
anyway that's how anybody heard about
urgent 11 okay
not too many okay that's well it's bad
for us but it's good because you won't
be bored
anybody knows why of those who knows it
why it is called urgent 11 so sorry
it's what Oh excellent now now it's it's
action hmm no no it's actually it's a
combination of eleven vulnerabilities so
urgent 11 now marketing guys so
so what does it actually do so if we
look at any type of device or IOT for
that matter
there are basically three layers we have
the physical layer which is the Ethernet
port itself or Wi-Fi for that matter
we'll call that a layer then there is
the network stack layer which is the
network and transportation so basically
everything that runs in the network and
then we have the application layer which
is well the application the layer of the
application okay everything that's in
the actual code right that will run at
the application if something is a
vulnerability in the physical layer it
is really bad because then you need to
replace the actual cables I mean that's
that's crazy
if anything happens in the application
level then then it's usually a patch
right because okay there is something
wrong with the code it will impact
something very specific right so you
just protect that it's usually easier
and you'd usually have different layers
that would protect you from that so
urgent 11 is in the network layer
meaning that meaning that if a device is
vulnerable to urgent 11 all the attacks
will happen through the network layer it
means that it runs through all of your
firewalls so let me say that again
traffic that goes through the firewall
without stopping
isn't that what 5 was a 4 to stop
traffic going from A to B well not at
the urgent 11 so basically and I won't
get into all the sub versions whatever
many versions of VxWorks
are vulnerable to that over 2 billion
devices in the world and the whole idea
is that attackers are bypassing security
traditional security is just a fancy
name for firewall so what bypassing
firewalls and just going through that
and get into the devices so if there is
one device that is vulnerable inside
your network an attacker can go through
the firewall get into that device and
spread all over the network as simple or
alarming as that
so what is impacted well I said that
everything that has the Xbox right but
everything that is SCADA oriented all
the in just all the industrial
controllers all over the world patient
monitoring MRI machines firewalls VoIP
phones printers have some list of
manufacturers I'm allowed to put it all
here because we actually announced it to
them a few months before we published it
to the world right and there actually
and this is the story of how we did that
so look at that this actually happened
at Def Con last year so I think it was
definite
it's biohacking village that's what it
was so our CTO stood there you don't see
him on the picture but that was right
there and he was sitting with the CTO of
Alerus and that's why we're showing
their logo right there I mean true story
he was sitting right there and he told
him let me show you something and it
took his laptop and broke into the
device and like five seconds and just to
show that he broke into it see what it
and don't see it really well but here on
the zoomed in picture it says
communication error so basically took
him five seconds to make this medical
device stopped working and that device
was a new device that was shown in that
you know in that biocking village I mean
it was the newest latest whatever they
had in five seconds communication error
then we came into the into the hospitals
and announced it to everybody we
actually took I think it's three months
between telling them and announcing to
the world we worked with the FDA and DHS
and with Alerus before the announcement
and made sure that everybody is aware of
that and that the on the day that we
announced that they would actually have
a patch already ready for that right not
just start making the patches then but
so the vulnerability is only VxWorks and
then it became a bit interesting so two
weeks after that there is a big hospital
chain that we work with and we came to
them and said hey you know you have us
installed and said yeah we're very happy
with you and we said so this is the list
of all of your devices that are
vulnerable to urgent 11 please go ahead
and you know patch them because it's all
dangerous and we like to do that on a
Friday so that way they have to work on
the weekend and only for those we want
them we want to work on the weekend so
we did that and then the next day
Saturday we get a usually like to you
know call us back the next day ins
during the weekend because we started I
guess you know what white so the colors
back Saturday and they call shenanigan
and they said this device right here
that you say this vulnerable is not and
we said hmmm why I mean you know we
found the urgent 11 we're kind of good
at saying who is fundable and who is not
nobody else knows anything about it
because we just came out with that so
why are you saying that said well we
contacted the the manufacturer of that
device and they said that this device
does not use feet folks so therefore
it's not vulnerable and literally
culture Nanga was not a good weekend I
can tell you that it was noon right so
kind of okay maybe we have a bug in that
mechanism that discovers the devices or
anything else I mean you know make sense
so we came back and so we actually
checked it out verified then came back
and said okay we found a problem
actually urgent 11 is way bigger than
what we thought VxWorks bought some I
mean many companies throughout its life
20 years ago they bought a different
company that I won't say its name but
they bought a different company the bug
actually started at that company
so all of the older devices that do not
use VX works just use that company
before it was bought by VX works
actually also have that bug and that was
that medical device yeah so it keeps
expanding actually every month since
that summer we found some unpublished
some more things that came in with
urgent eleven so you can go to a website
I'm not done yet but you can go to a
website and see all of those reports and
patches and everything about urgent
eleven it's really fascinating when you
get into that and see some more things
and the interesting part is that it's
not it's it's you know it's everyday
it's everything that we touched every
day that is vulnerable to that okay so
let's continue with a few other examples
here so we talked about wanna cry right
and run a cry for chocolate so what
about wanna cry for MRIs true story so
all of this okay I didn't look at this
right the reality of real IOT what
actually lays behind that is real
customers of ours okay so all the
stories that I'm telling you now and not
things that I read on Google that are
actually our customers MRI machines that
are connecting to the internet who knows
what is running on what operating system
is running on MRI come on it's only it's
on the slide Windows XP Windows XP MRI
machines are actually pretty old
computers that have amazing things
connected to them right
being an MRI machine but from the you
know from our point of view it's it's a
Windows XP machine that's what it is
so you don't have to tell you how
uncatchable or and how vulnerable
Windows XP is being so old right not to
get into Linux windows things just being
that all more than
it's under warranty it cannot be patched
unless it is patched by the manufacturer
you can you know I actually went to one
of the hospitals and say you know I'm
pretty ignorant there
why can't you upgrade the damn windows
XP I mean why said what we can it's the
FDA not approved actually doing anything
everything that you do in a hospital has
to be FDA approved right a manufacturer
approved and I said where we can't we
can't do anything about it
okay having said that that MRI MRI
machine is connected to the manufacturer
in order to get updates yeah bit of an
oxymoron there but anyway it is
connected to the Internet Windows XP do
I need to tell you what what's going on
when that happens right
so when equai got into the hospital got
into that MRI machine started connecting
to anywhere in the environment using SMB
protocol and infected everything around
okay I told you I don't like slides so
I'll tell you a different story about an
MRI which is not on the slide another
true story this is in hospital and I
won't say where but it's say that's
quality cost and what they did was where
I started with a lack we discovered it
throughout the story but I'll tell you
what actually happened so this lady did
they found her like I know her name this
lady was bored one night at 2:00 a.m.
and she wanted to go on Facebook I said
she was on hospital and she wanted to go
on Facebook I don't know why I guess she
doesn't have a phone or a tablet or
whatever and she had to do it from a
computer and she had to choose the MRI
machine to go on Facebook I really want
to meet her and
so she went to that MRI no MRIs are
connected to the metal of that MRI
anyway it's connected to the network
using Wi-Fi I don't know why and she
went to that and you know literally you
know facebook.com and Amy didn't work
you know why with somebody to this job
within that hospital and it had a
firewall that in other solutions and
whatnot that basically you know point
where that segmented the medical network
into you know so you can go on Facebook
kind of make sense and I'm all into
network segmentation it's an amazing
thing it's not good enough but it's
really good so she was so so so she was
really she really wanted to go on
Facebook at that 2 a.m. so she changed
the wireless network to Starbucks it's a
hospital heavy Hospital has a Starbucks
right so now we have a Windows XP
computer
oh excuse me MRI machine connected to
stop so she spent about half an hour
this is all what we found in the logs
she spent about half an hour doing
whatever she did on Facebook then she
was was really good about it she
connected back to the medical network
and you know went back to doing your
stuff no no she would not she was
walking there she was oh yeah I hope
patients don't have that access to the
MRI machine
so so anyway three weeks later so
everything is okay right I mean it's
stupid but it's okay because it's back
on the medical network always good sweet
mix later there was an outage in the
medical network elect two seconds so
nobody really paid attention to it okay
it shouldn't happen but okay did a few
seconds or was back on all is good
except that the MRI machine switch to
the Starbucks Network so now you have
MRI tests being sent out on on the
Starbucks Network public network Smart
TVs so we talked about projectors let's
talk about TVs every boardroom has small
TVs heavy board rules where not every
most board rooms have really top-secret
personal information things that we
don't want to get anywhere right this is
another true story Smart TV was
compromised
and with a malware that malware instead
of trying to spread in the network
started spreading using Wi-Fi smart TVs
are they don't have chromecast nowadays
or other casts for that matter the
broadcasting an SSID right they're
actually doing the same for broadcasting
for bluetooth so you can connect through
that you so they just started
broadcasting that whatever was open just
cut it and got the malware by that so
you're asking you might be asking okay
what did armies do about it right
because you know and again and I'll get
at the end like in the next five minutes
about what we're doing about that but
it's not in the network and I started
with saying protecting the network so
how did we found out that so people
don't know about people don't know that
but I was like oh okay the access point
I don't see which whose access point
that is but yeah it's right there I
don't see who's the manufacturer but
anyway most likely its Cisco aruba
because we're in the u.s. so people
don't know that those access points
actually have a model
that scans all the Wi-Fi in the area on
2.4 and five niggers that means that if
I am using this computer right here I'm
not in I'm not in the guest network here
I'm not on any network if I'm connecting
it to my phone's hotspot it will know if
I'm connecting it over Bluetooth because
I have a I know FM keyboard that I
connect to the computer it will know
nothing is connected to this access
point but it will still know about this
axis same for ZigBee same for any type
of information of traffic that's two
point four or five gigahertz that's how
we know about it we come to these places
we look at that information we say hey
did you know that x y&z connected to
your Smart TV usually answer is what my
favorite boardroom story is actually
about it's one of our first clients we
came into an office environment
nothing special not medical not ot not
nothing and we did a nice POC we
connected ourselves we got spam traffic
right copied the traffic of the network
listening to that Network
and and then we came back after a week
we kind of give results and we show the
dashboard that we went through alerts
and we say you have to have death and
this is what you do and what's very
interesting and then the last one was in
by the way did that tablet that you have
in your boardroom this is and then they
stopped us which tablet that work you
have a tablet in the boardroom that's
sending traffic every night at 2:00 a.m.
to somewhere and that somewhere is
outside of your network I don't know
where it's in a cloud and they and they
say well what happened we don't have
that we don't have it habit
there's no tablet in that bottom so
everything I don't know I know there
isn't have that I know it's connected to
the access point called the boardroom so
either you have another access point
called the wardroom which I hope you
don't or you have a tablet connected to
your boardroom so they literally we were
sitting at that boardroom
he stood up went look at all the there
was some deaths around there's some
closets and found the tablet tablet was
there like forever and was sending that
in for me it was recording whatever was
in the office and send it up to wherever
it was yeah so this is why yeah so this
is this is the help let me jump yeah
okay
last example and then and then we'll go
to the last slide actually no I'll stay
with the TV's last the story this is one
of my favorites it's not type of
security though it's a bit more funny
than that so Friday 7:00 p.m. I'm in the
middle of a a POC with the most
important client in the world must-win
project everything has to work ok again
Friday 7:00 p.m. right and I get the
phone call and said well there is this
lady in this I don't know why again it
was the lady I later I later I later met
her instead there is this lady on the
fourth floor of this building in
California in which were installed and
she says that Internet is really
sluggish and there are issues in the
network and I really wanted the same way
she might want to go home and it's
Friday 7 p.m. 4 p.m. California fine but
ok let's call it a day a week and I
couldn't do that so we opened the Consul
together and we saw a few alerts so the
first alert that we saw was abnormal
behavior for a device of type Smart TV
so a few things there first of all a
Smart TV should do very specific things
right I mean it should
well show something right it should
download traffic because if you are
using onion on Netflix or whatnot it
should download that it should download
some updates right software updates for
the TV hopefully not much more than that
so this mart TV was uploading 100 gigs a
day and there were 4 of those in the
building uploading uploading so so that
was one alert second alert was a policy
violation so they basically according to
their regulation that company small tvs
should not be connected to the network
at all that's whatever that's what they
sent some companies do it this way some
other way but they had the strict
regulations regulation no TV should be
connected to the network and yet it was
so that's what the alert that's the
second order that came third alert was
abnormal behavior for the network
nothing should upload 100 gigs a day
right so one alert was a small TV
shouldn't behave that way neither alert
was a nothing should behave that way ok
just take a look at that
anyway what happened was and that's why
I'm saying it's it's so funny because
it's not it was not an attack I'll get
to the end of it it's kind of like the
fish that we didn't burn so it's kind of
the same thing it was not an attack that
the Russians were not you know attacking
that office in California or nobody else
attacked it what happened was that
somebody connected that TV to the
network again he shouldn't have right I
said it's against the law against their
regulation and yet he did that if we try
to get an update as it should it was
blocked by their neck so now the TV
tried because it was not connected to
the network it didn't have a certificate
so then the TV tried to get a
certificate and failed because TVs are
not receiving certificates so then we
try to update to up to update the
software and fail and then try to get a
certificate and failed
and it did it quite faster than you know
my withum of speaking and got to a
hundred gigs a day this is a really big
client so they're not just a big client
of ours they're also big client of
Samsung okay it was the Samsung TV so
they reached out to Samsung and said hmm
like what are you doing and told them
the story and Samsung said no way that's
not happening so they came back to us
and said hey well first of all you saw
your network so something did happen and
B here are the logs of everything
because I see everything I listen to all
the traffic I show everything here are
my logs
so they went back to Samsung Samsung
came back and said well we're gonna do
it there's nothing wrong with the TV X
exactly it should be here's a patch by
the way ok so not to spend all the
weekend I'm going to jump over all of
that and get to the last point in two
minutes to nothing I hope so why am i
speaking about all of that except that
IOT so fun what are we doing so we are
armas and we are basically coming to big
corporates and we are when we are giving
three things discover analyze and
protect full discovery of all the
devices in your network
everything computer servers BYOD device
IOT device ot devices medical banking
whatever it is if it has a pulse now if
it has a MAC address or an IP we see
that right that's why I started with
asking who has a same DB who thinks
Aseem DB is good
nobody this is the only source of truth
because it listens to the traffic nobody
can hide second thing is understanding
what is this device doing so okay gets I
discovered the device and I see it has
traffic great I am able to compare that
to my knowledge base and I'm able to
show what type of device it is this is
the camera this is a dishwasher this is
a projector they say whatever it is and
I can show how it should behave like
so going back to the TV I know that it
shouldn't behave that way going back to
a camera that has bought net I know it
the MRI machine I know that it shouldn't
behave that way
that's the strength of what we're
showing completely passive no agents no
installing anything not doing anything
listening to the traffic knowing what
the device is what it should behave like
in saying hey that's not good that's
abnormal
that's malicious that's a breach of
policy and the last part is protecting
and saying okay you got the malicious
device let's take it out of your network
okay I'm still within my two minutes so
questions okay yes so I'm getting two
sources of traffic one is the two
sources of traffic one is my wirelessly
your wireless LAN controller just read
only show commands and the second and
most important is a spent port or tab if
you have it but basically spend port
copying or receiving a copy of your
traffic that's why I call it listen
because we just get we're not in the
middle and not poking the devices we're
not trying to reach out to the device in
any way we just receive that traffic
from your span listen to it and do
everything yeah so first of all we are
in the cloud so there's a nice cloud
picture there we put something on site
we get that traffic we parse it we
reduce it get only the metadata and send
it up to our cloud so that that's one
thing second thing nothing stays only in
the cloud so it's good enough that let's
say that you have a million servers in
the cloud and they are connecting to
your actual network because you need to
get out of the cloud one day connect to
your actual network that's how we'll get
all the traffic coming from the cloud
by the way you know roadmap pretty soon
we're going to just duplicate everything
to the cloud itself and kind of put
instead of a appliance and like a
physical thing we'll duplicate that into
the cloud
you okay yes I it's nothing so we're
usually doing its either virtual machine
just four cores something really small
or we're using a one you have deep tiny
server so it's really simple and the
reason it's so small is that it doesn't
do anything it just takes the traffic
which uses it and send it up to the
cloud so I can throw that the cloud
environment is a monster one but you
don't care about that okay thank you so
much and