here we stay in homes
my job here and we were seen as a system
admin we're gonna stand over a year ago
so coming up with in their last year the
idea was to be called me up and Troy
like a we want to have a hardware
hacking village we want to have a
project everybody's bad we want to go
outside hurry and get interested in
hardware and said well that's cool but
we should do it on the badge so we got
seventy eighty percent of the people
here through the hardware hacking
village they cited their badge everybody
loved it was awesome and this year we
said well it was cool we did it we don't
really want to do it again so the theme
of this year was to use the bags to the
conference experience you know what can
we do to make the Badger link back to
the conference in the conference back so
keep that in mind so there's plan and
then there's reality that's the plan is
what I presented to the committee of the
board and said hey here's how to go down
here is how we're gonna pull this off
go ahead and get a check and get
together and make it happen now and then
on the Raiders reality
hardware development took a lot longer
than we expected we were expecting to
have hardware prototypes pretty much
locked in by April we got it first
prototype PCB back to life the TV in its
trusted us part by little exactly to
this day they were just over so we goin
on the hardware and so were cutting into
the software with hardware tool that we
also used to contracts simply house
solutions you're not gonna make the
badges weren't about to pick and place
my hand 600 badges technical lovely wife
and I had our perpetual prototypes that
would be a full time we finalize the PCB
design it and blocked it in August 30th
and an EMS gave us a call back on
September 11 and we picked up finalized
production run of badges on October
eight so slight you got to talk and we
want to get to a Q&A so we just gonna
get arrested these on your left there
was one is responding right yeah this is
the first attempt the screen when it
when they lit up we have been sent one
right been struggling trying to get it
to load up your mom probably was the
step forward but they're bored we use
$30 that's the chip will use the next
nigga its review
we're going out all the things you need
not be choosers so it's great to death
but it's tough to have these big mess of
wires get ahead to have to look it up
for what he wanted to work good and then
worked on it and then it was unhooked
outweigh the time I got home so text you
were a couple other shootings we have
played around with it
agreement with one year left is a
monochromatic LCD backlight which is
kinda cool but it was actually more than
the screen we did it go across the one
on the right was just a little bit
bigger I want to say is like a 2.8 yes
the 220 and touch screen but calm the
interfacing with it was a great option
that you point to sit on the left that's
cool cat which is the cat package we
used your card where I attended the MSU
start out with you do the schematic you
throw down the pieces you're pretty sure
we're gonna go on board and then you hit
the snooze button and it drives me a
little liars are talking using you get a
train route so that it was fun on the
right that's the word I was talking
about that have two problems if you look
just to the right of the prototype an
upside down there
Gold Line speaking through there's
nothing on the left's that's where it
was her mask was shifted to make some of
the pins and usable suspect about two
weeks so that was the build out on that
first prototype even though we solve the
problems like let's try we was the first
time we had the likes of the board is
pretty awesome but it was still a we
just had shorts on the right was the
greenback's the second round of the
British exports
and Canada first batch so everybody's
been asking us all week he can happen to
bad what's what is under the hood what
is the better here's the laundry list
Alex Megane 2 5683 video goes into the
Big Brother the mega chips Arduino and
tons of open source projects use we
really ran into limitations on his
memory will will really hit my Sharona
the memories the things just the RAM
memory so this year we knew just like
everybody loved another through with it
we just can't make a bad joke we are
something that got us all the way over
these super cheap ass press it tastes
like modules came out about the same
last year yes b12 is also the only two
inches TFT were talking about flash
memory to store the schedule and
whatnots so around after the attack and
process is good enough to use as a quad
waiting to see a trip to Egypt actually
didn't end up using so there's some
features that we go hard work or because
we cannot wait on the hardware we didn't
get a written for my bad time these
things are pretty cool chips ECCE Shaw
also be cool if you did when you were
part of that is saying to you and you
entered in the country for two weeks we
talked about being challenged by Contra
Costa gotta do kind of slowed down down
left right left right BA start slow
excerpt unlocks the future just 600
Andrew yeah
IR receiver there's also neier led on
there that you can drive where want to
do some batch of education that almost
made it to the cutting room floor
everyone should be my own children how
to use a model of an ideal my own self
and because we got last minute shipments
of lithium ion cells that were I'm
convinced referred from China they
weren't free then we had a little light
syndrome if you look at the bottom left
is you're looking down at your bad
looking chip that's a juvenile
approximate slights answers you can
celebrate it is the room there is a
tension century there was never a major
component is like three cents and PC for
mister right above the buttons we're
gonna put up all the hardware and
software stocks leading the Gerbers in
the material so you can still make your
own badges
so this was billed as one last night the
slide last night
punch card for the repository just ended
up sure what time we are working on this
thing
lot of other stuff in the lead us yet
after work in early mornings on the
weekends and even during the week
attention to the 9 a.m. lunch boxes of
those were all done the night before it
can be found in the morning when I came
in from another thing we give advice
here because we had WiFi module we
tracked you like the Big Brother that we
are so if you went into the maps and
strolled around if things are working
well it would show your current location
with a pretty good approximation
accuracy on there to do that we use our
wireless system that we have here is a
Cisco Wireless and they have a piece to
that system itself the connected mobile
PC and macs we import a floor mat BedRug
assumes its location of the eighties and
it's not great three issues accuracy but
it's good enough to get a feel for how
many people are in each tracking true so
we're gonna get some cool stuff that she
would structure popular which ones
weren't maybe get some feedback to the
presenters on well you did something to
really take people off about 10 minutes
and you presume that slide out whatever
it was and then kind of this is these
are all the steps that we pulled from
the CMX Andrew into a plastic surgeon
combining things we did
individualize easy what would your inner
what room you were in based on your
whereabouts was and you can kind of see
the different rooms growing and
shrinking as the day went on
so we stand on the shoulders of giants
were blocked so we gotta get major props
to Jill grands he say he was the first
one to do it electronic batch of 14 and
even before that would just run clark
also has lost you to get to the next
level
why was he was but was and the ninja
networks those kids ages including one
that has pretty much the same layout for
letting me crippled bits of the
electronic components and software and
software you know them so you Jonathan
Harris to work on the firmware for the
SP is an attempt to your firmware to
handle the communication then all the
other open source hardware folks with
all the great tips thanks to you talkin
organization think I'm going to the
committee by slashing team on top of the
top /
Ogden great contract manufacturer they
were amazing to work with a whole bunch
getting us our first job of contract
manufacturing done with all the mistakes
made by made mostly parked for getting
US number of words and getting some new
western red around stencils out of Grupo
Matt wants to get in big props wherever
matt is ya down the hardware hacking
village we overnight it so
JRC this experience for a good price is
who I was never a group of CNX and some
cool stuff we were so University
activism for letting us hijack the
wireless network in doing company time
now to launch their friends families for
letting it slip through standard and my
wife for helping me this first time
types fears about scene I did most of
the hardware wrangle the team lifted the
software software Jonathan news as I
said the amputee nude MCU you were set
this wouldn't happen although the
integration with the ridge 6 many routes
and challenge gave system everybody that
has had to have their badges switched it
has been manual work by some including
some sequel statements to get him switch
server lessons learned for next year
Dustin graphics for the maps mike got
gift you working about that mister minit
Mart getting a mass area code of silence
now there's just a placeholder now will
probably get it up there by the end of
the day for sure we didn't want to the
game board of the closing minutes there
are more than one where it's not really
anything currently in with you again
Patnode billion in it into something
where the screen of just a black you
look like you're not powered on but that
means you're ready to play
yeah you're a different USB you get in
stone yet you driver put up all the
instructions but the point is you don't
have to buy a $50 programmer inside Iran
headers or anything to change the code
we built in mic figure that out for us
got it the right thing set up you need
it lacks the bootloader where you just
totally brick church if you will still
lead programmer make sure you make it
through the hardware hacking village
realize now that I'm signing us how much
people but we do have slightly updated
about yours if you have any problems
especially with the battery's gonna take
the battery out what you can control
without any extra hardware I think
that's it yeah we want to leave that
slide up so you get your first and then
who like the better last year where it
was
here's a big pile of parts to build it
so pretty slick here in the room the
people have been asking so far has been
they tended to like it will be better
than it was fully functional we've got
to be back and some good ideas it's it's
functional but here's an extra bling you
can add a little extra functionality and
that's kind of what we're leaning
towards for next time
any other questions that's right that's
right I'm sooo next year we've only
committed to an electronic gadgetry the
year we'll see how it goes but the next
year the Arts and Crafts Village gonna
have googly eyes glitter I've got a bit
in right now on a retro the Dazzler
so yeah thank you for the reminder I
question whether it is we wanted to do
some cool stuff for the whole enhance
the experience here at the con we had to
have everybody was working backstage one
you know the the rate of bad building
was about 20% 30% of the back just got
to every day so it really work we need
everybody did ones development features
we had mine done so we're really only
use and three-quarters of the hardware
it was decided earlier with the board
and just suck it up and plugged it in
every time you waiting for hardware
another run of the same exact same
hardware and you'll notice the prototype
doesn't actually have a year on it so
yeah what would people think shook hands
with that be a good idea to do the exact
same hardware next year with more
software seems to actually be pretty
popular so here's a question are you
saying you do a day's alright dave says
you have attended every year if you're
on a team that they can only send out
the team you there one year you miss out
on the cool you've gotta have to do this
so we really have to have like just
about everything every year we get
people so we got was kind of a deal with
the IR we did our with the bags last
year one of one of the Jones is that you
take last year's batch and pointed at
this match the IR receiver will plateau
you have to put it in my youth level 34
if you built the Arduino down in the
hardware hacking village and accept it
because you could probably get it going
to so they just got a bill get points
for you so it's gotta be dealing with
that
so I need an error on the PCB and I the
backlight for the LCD is tied to a pier
and the plan was modulate that just the
brightness of the light sensor but I
cited to appear but doesn't do hardware
PWM PWM we didn't interrupt what would I
do so they didn't interrupt depending on
where was in the cycle of PWM it was on
the screen would stay white and it was
it would just watch the screen until
finished it'll be kinda like a radio
seizure inducing bad we just gonna do so
I we do another record it won't be the
same things like that but yet you was
between accelerometer the working right
now everything will go back to sleep
backlight of be the LCD adjusting more
so you get more battery left there and
it's you have a dinner cruise
you know right so deal we really thought
we would be able to get away without how
did not but we didn't want people will
show up than happy to the day ended it
with that would be better days anyway so
we probably would put an on off switch
just to see you next time
anything else
anybody else or whatever at wifi loot or
general feedback
fill out the survey for the Con and
there's just a general comments as well
at the bottom right so so tag on a bad
idea
things have been since the comments and
we'll get all this factory worker at the
US government class what's up
so much