and the true story call him brian has
named Ryan came home one day this is
gonna have a bad day
CEO's office say this is what your
senior season their head buyers right
slashing lives there is no choir and the
start over
you can probably imagine what's coming
and they're so Brian's house burned to
the ground and fortunately it was
unfortunate it's as if this is ok not a
problem we had a bit of a data breach
some of our stuff for Davis left our
grandmas control first responders here
the forensics teams here they're doing
their assessment of things out gonna be
okay and then you hear him say he sees
the news and news man is now here so
it's no longer your business is business
that you'd like to release that
information not so thats
in his mind he or she is thinking in
their mind what did we get here how did
this decision and I don't know what
would be really for your your
environment if you have a situation
however brian is pretty straightforward
photo lies a very telling truth I think
it applies to both I T and home
ownership and you may not be able to see
it so this brainless in Phoenix so in
Phoenix their specific things that
happened due to the weather in the
summer make it tonight with that it's
also not very cold in the winter so here
is something in this season's has to do
with that byron there is only three
years is a couple of times a year that
means we can grow things that may be
more in line for a tropical climate like
four inches for example there there or
in any way so when it was free it would
cover your plans for some sort of blamed
he keep them warm
died and oranges all through the winter
has this really hope so the blanket is
kind of like the latest installed
your e-mail spam the blanket the problem
is is that if you did have a breach you
probably have a problem in your floor
now working your core configuration
update your passing and most importantly
your users ok so Ryan's problem with
this house is that he added on a room in
back to his house and I don't know if
you did away with the warnings to get a
core problem with this house that would
have been easy to solve Bryant requires
a little more work but would result in
his house not the grounds so don't be
like Brian don't put the blame on the
black box and not cover the date six so
how are these breaches occurring any
ideas
firewalls no no one's hacking firewalls
I mean somebody is maybe somewhere where
something but rising 23% emails and
attachments how are they getting in so
obviously are set for sour
Casey have 60 minutes to reduce the rate
by 50 percent of the problem may be
Thurs had cyber espionage has included
66% you have to look first few seconds
to compose email saying don't work on
this side against your lunch may be too
late
alright so there's a couple of data
points from my own and in the senate
involved in and got two case studies one
is a mature company they've been around
I mean in the triple digits of years
long time and then we're going to
compare them to get started pretty good
sized company but fairly similar sample
size hundred and thirty 85% open trade
order company k and three on the on the
other company so I'm not a math genius
he 500% 385 raised by people have
clicked on this email one time this is a
hundred sixty-five place and saying that
even on the on the uncertain about how
24 unique logins from the mature company
58% tried to do it more than one time at
work not just tried again and then for
some reason to pasture then gave me
their Newcastle which is nice I mean I
can see that nice legs start-up not much
different 64 login Cyrus insect larvae
higher but then I got ninety most asking
for support I'm a nice guy Hayes not
working right now my team team we're
working on it
check back in 30 minutes so shocking to
anyone besides you were shocked if I
wouldn't be in here so members baby so
out there if you have to run an argument
to get funding whatever you do or time
or whatever it is that organization from
doing now and data their DVR prices are
as good as well so how can you do this
cases to make it successful anyone can
do it we've got princes from Tanzania
wherever they are they are doing
obviously a bit of a target market there
but so gotta convince them to write a
check for business sometimes that carry
out or so
you the first time it's actually does
periodically so they see the video and
I'm serious I open until users just beat
it up get the first one done its funding
may be great just let me do one will get
it done and then look at the data
guarantee you you will be guaranteed as
much money as you need as much money as
you going on a quarterly basis which is
gay
give this tax and then the important
part sometimes we need to train the
users it's not be users were gonna trick
them we're gonna do things to them that
no human student at a human hey it's me
it's Melissa it's not nice and we're
doing it right that's all we have to
train them now this isn't necessarily
we're not training them to avoid targets
of opportunity that's the prince in
tanzania or whatever and wherever it is
those are targets of opportunity that
they're looking for
we're trying to avoid the next level
which is targets somebody that your
organization's been targeted for
specific reason
about her behaviour so we're going to
get some money running the first time
report that creates and then we're going
to help our users not only learn the
things of this giuliani things that
should look for but we're going to help
them to be motivated to keep you going
alright we're gonna talk about this is
variable and basing it we get people to
do what we wanted you
13 obviously so I'll make it relevant it
may be that your organization you want
to check some kind of Laura Brown like
hey we're doing a blood drive is in that
when you may not be or what I like to do
is make this specific it's possible to
the company one of the take up early
with the data I knew there would be
buildings so I sent an e-mail reference
for building a pretty successful and
we'll talk about it got some examples
here as well so what is happening what's
given some contacts what's happening in
your position right now and then make it
believable right in the verbiage that
you use in your company if you use an
acronym for something
throw it in there that makes more
believable now we're making the body of
the email buried but there's gonna be
the normal flags there should be able to
pick up on and they will be able to come
up with the given the proper training
ok so get a domain these people are very
happy with their domain maybe they're
getting married submitting to me how to
read anyway so these are some of the
means I've used to demean saks.com so we
gotta run to make those are a couple of
of ideas and then there's always a
lighter note say to someone's that I get
for our company so this is where it
comes into play
who in here you see him at all
ok that doesn't happen does a great deal
of 18 USC and again at 11 everyone loves
it how to proceed with the amazon has
promised us is pretty cool so as a
service called route 33 where she may
get the reference 53 is used for DNS
J
so we're gonna go to rapidly 32 Amazon
account and would have to have to open
Amazon accounts credit cards and maybe a
face to face so credit card credit card
card and then your face up to rate
remained around 53 if you want to get to
different sources
a little box later so little box in
certain areas were gonna do
resides so resumes you three straight
boy and I was trying to register for our
company and I use the Greek letter a
different Unicode I tried it didn't like
it
thankfully Ramazan they said hey you're
not read anything on the screen like
we're gonna bounces back from regular a
problem would get most of our guys ok
but I did slip the Greek language even
get it to submit so for now but see
racism and thank you hang out for a
minute we'll send you an email I know
when you're ready you can check in your
pending requests in 33 over here to work
rate of 45 anyway and progress and then
use the failure of my reach litter a
domain so that it working for different
register or mechanisms they used to the
doctor does it up on his predecessor
which I just made it the second day
which is also preceptor sense it's not
really an addict Behav circuits and
clicks having to give me a min
53 is just a list of names down 69
protected outsole james rubin never done
so looks like it is my domain walesa
catches you can swap receive but cannot
get the uppercase lowercase things just
recreate something that's what you got
going early so we're gonna set up being
shocked by saying a penis right now
knowing is good news
easy it's super easy especially if you
buy your domain gravity three
going here and we've got the street and
then
we still here posted sounds we have
three yes I did have read that thing
that's easy easy i'm happier I don't
like things that are hard things are a
lot of work to be easy and when things
just happen for me because I like those
people about those things to do so it's
all done you have to do anything I click
on their second look at it it's there
and then once you're in here here's the
settings for your your domain the only
thing you'll ever need to know this this
is you ought to have a server that will
talk about as well
entry here and a record for your IP of
your server but super easy basically
here and I don't think so that means all
set up if you want to use Gmail you can
put those MX records in here
disclaimed other good thing about it is
it's lots of documentation did you
really good job by step how to do this
and you can read more it's pretty well
honestly so if you have questions about
that issue gone to that there's
documentation so sorry I send email
right so
we need to run one that sounds hard I
don't like exchange exchange the
exchange for smart so are you sorry Jay
sounds hard to do something to set up a
case policy at simply mail service in
here and again the little cardboard box
in the corner to find the SES and then
it brings you here
verified yes yes please put your domain
generated details to the gym settings
are a little bit of a signing a
lucrative graphic signing on your email
outgoing mail server email box revealed
train will say is assigned to get out
some long but guess what to do it all
you do is box so check is a check box
then were gonna be revised two main
there's a bunch of stuff to top
that's boring that's hard I don't know
what those letters numbers and stuff so
we got the bottom line 103 tests so
we're going to talk about this is the
degree of things
everyone every just like things are all
remaining three weeks is this more stuff
that we don't care about and then
another button says go get a free to go
but that's an extreme all of our at CES
outgoing mail server settings in our DNS
server verifies it for you and then you
get to see you know wait a minute does
he just goes into accused around 45
minutes then she's out approved mike is
a real labor
automated it happens when you get this
and we're happy so we have verified
email we can send your outgoing mail
server got that email client gay so
typically in my dreams I will send email
I don't know it seems is you can send it
to send mail sendmail writes that sweet
do you like that you can automate this
entire process yes it's both pretty
sensitive APIC expose the enemies you
want and then it just typical but it'll
destroy everything you compose email it
take a little bit of coding but not able
to use your Gmail client BBEdit external
demand of the Gmail climb before yes so
it's hard but there's plenty of houses
on that so I can go into the details
about all sorts of reasons
outgoing mail server to my to exceed
to look back on that one degrees a
couple settings and something given to
you for all the good stuff to me and
then you're gonna read so just bounce
about this outgoing mail server that
would be insecure so we have to consider
yes my crabs crabs they're long they're
gross just talking a senior client
before the race is going well server
configured
I don't know there's always one male
just stay with us an email as well I see
a lot of times now claims it easy to
configure that's good news for us we're
doing now
ok so Van Dyke today my last last I got
nothin no time like this in the bag so I
like doctor who really doesn't have
doctor what's the one with Vincent van
Gogh and you'll be hooked for life
seasons
since 2006 we're gonna try to fool our
users so we want to establish some trust
these are the components and essentially
creates insurgency is a sound like a
marketing you know they want else yes so
again
little marking and then sports just
example he was abused the path so I've
got some highlights there soon read on
the status of trust so buildings and
such a Klein buildings building security
in a very important action required
emails and you start my paragraph as you
know the new building and I know this
because of you so we've got called
action please login and the blue box
there and on specific company they
wonder about these
now available secret you may or may not
know people are vain selfish one of them
so it's only got their first go-round
about page updated cycle thing uprooted
update your photo of the new one and
then we need to emergency so we're going
to make sure you take care of this by
noon today now I don't know that are
conducting investigations you may or may
not know this but there's a long tail to
the city so you got to grab this kind of
like a ramp up and then it keeps a
little while to get people to get people
but by the end of today and it drops off
and of course 5 o'clock nothing but then
Monday around people that I don't know
if they did see the email on Friday of
the traveling and didn't work but all
getting all get credentials up to 14 11
days after the engagement so they were
on a training partner that this is fake
but his email that I use now this was
more but I'm basing was the end of the
year to December engagement so who isn't
worried about the health care it's
changing things are moving in the
usually ends up in a higher price so we
set up
nice-guy company website so you can
learn about health care and how it could
affect you
demystified you changed your health care
plan so we r selfish and trust and then
called acts and login learn about your
health care if you don't even care
everyone must login to at least confirm
next year's average of my hands are tied
so and the other thing in the green box
bottom make sure that your changes are
going to adversely affect your premiums
are lower
they're going to get so long against
teams and then we've got a link there
and then of course the signature SVP of
a jar which do you expect to get this
room by the way sometimes I meet people
and I send the ads in social situations
and it does tend to get a little
something like the person that you maybe
pick there something I don't know but I
results of the minutes anyway good times
good times
verify right that's ok so now we have to
have a server to run he seems once we
have our email server we are outgoing
server were you trying to figured we got
to be able to have users somewhere else
right now there's lots of different
engagement types you can now where is it
at its website then delivers malware
what I like to do because now where
would you like to see them out where
nobody nobody the next series and nobody
wants to see this message back doors and
things happen and this is my third
method do whatever he wants so this is
just an appreciating the sides I give
you a special set of slides for the palm
prints were you can obtain them in my
right someone in slides they look
different from my slides where they have
a little more instruction that it does
it really exciting on the screen like
this site you can work through so proud
and so you can call on those anyway
decision to choose for setting up a
Linux p.m. in your interview us again
this is also gonna fall under the age of
yes documentation to really good at
documenting all these things how do I
want to set up an Ubuntu instance ok
here the steps they're really good at
that
billion to cover here but it's a couple
of guys changed
and if you're less technical get your I
teaching to help you and say hey you
know don't make create a team that still
see you need to make this successful
gave you need to make sure everything's
good race 2 billion somebody that's cool
maybe less technical either way to get
some particularly devious you think
they'd be good extracting emails and
great bring them in but don't tell if
your company only has 10 people you
might be good on your own button get a
team together
leverage other people's interests and
they're still sense
creating an Amazon Linux instance and
we've given IP address that we can
remote to it and this is a DNS settings
for the tobacco industry and give the IP
address to your DNS that used to be DNS
took like I don't know hundred million
years to update it was like 72 hours
sitting outside in seconds
domain it was like a record I do you
dress you just gave to your Amazon
instance
go by and that your domain info so
whatever the Republic nothing yet
because we haven't started yet to be
like actors in the movie yes
underwhelming response seen advertised
ok now those you seen hackers
if you didn't like it had ok so this
movie came out in 2005 the junior in
high school and it was awesome I sound
like a hundred times its initial release
anyway so answer to social engineering
toolkit which is anybody in here watch
the show mister Roboto
amusing sign in yes super cool tool
written by Dave Kennedy super cool guys
don't follow on Twitter you see a good
guy from speaking many many times just
just a nice down to walk up to him have
a conversation with them
called the social engineering toolkit
down this doesn't seem to like these
things
day has spent his time making things
easy for us ok so there's a few options
in there and again they'll be in the
slides that you'll be able to grab this
is a tool of sight is a command-line
tool
don't be scared just a number for the
menu item like it super easy still
amazes me about Dave Kennedy this
version happen to be called Mr Roboto
being on the show that he's cool so
number one really good social
engineering attacks have called things
you can get a spare hours just look at
all the different things that second do
it's cool I think you miserable to send
SMS messages directly to the back in
setup looks like on that but there's a
lot of something to do is make websites
so we're gonna social engineering
attacks and then we're going to website
actuators back to specific website
people but criticism so 11 enter to
enter three enter the complex I can tell
you the critics harvester attack three
answer to into a real estate in going on
sorry there was no number four but
123 so now there were here
website great so let's pretend we're
gonna put the IP address for our server
but we just set up and then we're gonna
put into your own URL to clone yeah
that's pretty cool it will just go out
scrape the site where you I'm using the
Google login here never logged into
Google ever
yes everyone has a lot of companies
other companies assume you because we're
gonna grab those who insist on that
website just for example website login
website or BBS engagement
black as a company logo this exactly
like their company login same here and
that's the fake one and I thought to
tell because it looks the same to go
through a web page and then like did you
get whatever the recursive command is
where is it and then grab all the goods
right images JavaScript it just doesn't
seem like easy things so it's pretty
legit right so my credit of course
there's the crabs and there they pop out
and say that
applause and 33 minutes for me
explaining how to do this by the way
when you just do it doesn't take as long
to financials reindeer games the hearts
of once so there is a little bit of a
hand waving but once you put in that
that cites 7 docs out soon command here
on webserver story you like it just does
it goes and then it is important et and
then you've got this login page that
system automatically and then its
potentials a gradstein posts from that
site on your server displays them in
line here and you can see the bottom
when your fancy control CDs generate a
report so you can get the report about
your friends that you did and you can
see that we're going ok we're gonna go
into that so that makes them easy
equals goodness in order to slide image
of the corners this is the focus our SMB
notice of Sciences but said after school
cars coming out from so so so the other
things you can do so that done you just
put a bow on it right now reports and
management collect money from them
because they want to do this more annual
training right they're going to want to
do that
so the next couple things a second
engagement you want to get a little bit
more of your game right i mean anything
over that can use the proper what's
their second is a patsy do it so you can
pick lines give you a previous life its
server it's all the same to the user is
going to the day afterwards I typically
like to do things like patsy
using patsy I use internet access across
the nation but not much to do with the
ruski web serves money so very little
consideration to get up and running yeah
it's easier than a passing but 72 patsy
for you so you can use different web
server wherever the thing about SAT is
it will grab that website today scraped
off the login page it'll save it for you
can also see the PPT file that handles
the POST request the data coming in and
then what does it redirects the user
back to the legitimate login
so the user sees they go with their
credentials in there you get them and
then they get redirected back to the
login page that's legitimate so they
think something's wrong in seabright was
right side
everything's going fine until I guess
that's fine I still get emails for
supporting an active member but it's
getting gas without getting what you
want you can use a web server you can
also add as a cell login pages
everyone's right to it or not but
psychiatric but common Komodo Kamado
nice-guy komodo they will give you a
free tell us if you get for 90 days free
domain that you come up with the website
so that's a link so that's what I
usually use 39 days hopefully the United
still getting emails but maybe a couple
things you can do to kind of game in the
second and third time and keep it up
keep doing the quarterly thing
running engagement once a quarter if you
can get if you can convince management
to do it twice a year something like
that make it really easy for them to say
yes so the reason I support charges
never tried to grass cutting grass on
the report and Anna training as well so
we're talking about that so who cares
it's so funny and so do the same done so
questions for management case of what
what can we do best success we have a
bitch engagement case of Morse's users
and/or melissa's Packers could deliver
malware but we talked about earlier
anywhere from local compromise to never
compromise when so many cats and they're
just hitting a network and only thing
that's the fire truck showing and then
the new truck every time
ok once they're there it's the server
data availability just hang out right
how many breaches last seven days not
many K usually go on for months and
months before the attack did I think the
average is like I want to say it's like
90 days or worse back me up on that
2393 days that's longer than three
months down I get a better 293 days the
average three so that's a problem
to back that is critical they could walk
in the external resources that have to
do anything to CVS air right it's an
email get financials are you no longer
have persuaded you share your opinions
with others
ok this is an example of a malware link
download it seems legit wright also
dates one tattoo me now is obviously did
and then helping us ko bhi is not on our
side and i wanna help us another have a
nice building in Utah County you will
get over here I'm sure you write this so
obviously minutes malicious PDFs are
paying hackers like those and others
like those bad guys like this he has
their help page this morning does not
necessarily mean this page or website is
harmful yes it does
never got a PDF got a legitimate PDF the
brand code inside of it nobody is
raising their hands nobody does this so
maybe you can submit a support ticket
for this video be so yes it's harmful
always bad and if it isn't bad don't
send it to something else there's
another way to comment saying goes
so we talked a little bit about this
already but how do we defend against you
seeing in spam
ok so yes sample the black box right
about self help you get rid of some of
the low-hanging fruit it can detect if
there is an email sent to hire companies
in the same address right maybe that's a
red flag so not a bad idea
box in this case not bad year
surprising that he didn't compete hear
it and they can be beaten by determining
factor to you again
get rid of the opportunity attackers
listen buddy how weightlessness gmail
balking at their decision like this so I
listing as hard as 100 K
so you can white less you can do it well
meeting rooms in otherwise difficult
somebody has to like call you on the
phone still no problem right to do you
know centers not bad if your environment
for static in the CD will email you a
controlled environment i cant being
taste testing and training is by far the
most of that way we make humans better
at detecting malicious things are
getting better at the
almost as things so we can teach them
what sort of bad luck ok has a padlock
deadlocks and still be ok to make sure
the domain is expected to be things
everyone in this room knows things that
may be too many chart does know like
Georgia me to do his job and one's
design and information i had a foul
words whatever last year so yeah
setting it can be hard to beat you
training in here at the organization how
many of you also do a nice i like it so
horrible could be worse that's even
worse the size waist training fun that
make users interested in a couple of a
strategy that I've heard of our PC users
as if you're helping them just in
general though not necessarily to work
context but hey this is how you detect
this in any context at home at work you
can get your spouse and she's your
friends can teach our kids that kind of
thing the other is to have some sort of
reward who's the first person to
report this machine was Susie and you
know some sort of whatever department
really I guess here she gets a Snickers
bar spot in the front of the building to
park her car or she was mentioned in the
newsletter these things that weekend
easy or cheap and they help users to
realize that hey this is important and
it's kind of fun to be involved in it so
don't be like Brian don't keep your
plants in serious but then you come down
kissing put in $5 cheaper wiring or
whatever day makes it how the bases
covered
you running your engagement ring that
those inside your data training they are
able to say hey to get some real when
you sit in front of a group of people
you say this is what you guys did last
time we did this is what you've done
don't put individuals names on there but
these are just a day before was how many
people put in their credentials
it will help you I promise and social
engineering and fishing is the way that
compromises any questions
yes
sometimes I have a 24 hour notice before
doing any good
yes I like having that time to formulate
an event website what was happening its
organization do they have announced on
their website and newsletter public and
look at those what's happening in the
future for this company
things you can use those and Taylor that
evil and inhuman towards being
successful trick question
arrived too many things that are similar
and things that are up by one is that
we've seen by Ahn but in between binary
yeah that's a great suggestion for sure
questions yes
how do I make sure it's Ryan Taylor my
approach to where Billy just seein say
the victim click on it which does happen
over time how seen that I don't see it
as often as I should see it if that
makes sense
usually on an email blast it's a fairly
I mean those companies are both you know
$1,500 employs 200 may not hit those
employees even hit two people sitting
next to each other so usually sample
size is the weighted apt our whole
organization I would say you have to
come up with a systematic plan to you
know what we're gonna hit ten people
from the Department of people in this
apartment today and then and hopefully
you can get an additional sample size
and kind of statues thing but yeah great
question
good thing it is a good metric it really
just comes down to what the engagement
looks like what are your goals
challenger goals before and you can
tailor all that but yeah I agree I agree
that is a good match and it seems to
last the whole thing I mean this
reportedly you can mix it up you can say
this time without having read this and
want to find out this did win this time
tailored towards a yes
which is true so you may want to test if
you get up to run on the first game in
which I agree with so yeah definitely
becoming yes but the question was ever
used to mark records for its recording
and i havent today on candidates running
in tracking is and remember I like
things that are needy there's a plugin
for that were said she male called the
super weird name but it's the email to a
little image jobs or whatever but also
like to click track opens today and it's
like that you can do to get some free so
yeah that's pretty much for data
collection pretty reliable methods you
can also as a side note on I miss the
set design and see that the files
including the PHP and a couple things so
modifying their one it's a date stamp to
each post requests which is hard and if
in the end she to the code word it's
pretty straight forward to a timestamp
you have a few other things you clean up
the forms that doesn't pose all these
fields are usually just like a login
form so it wasn't easy to customize and
this is
hey you've got eight hours to an
Associated men go by so I just you know
I'm an extra susser and tested so I
don't necessarily get the time to hang
out on the inside and make this better I
just do it and I do it again they did
against though they're definitely
prevent on this and I've done nothing
new this is just the information
knowledge transfers so pretty
straightforward stuff again get any
questions let me know the facts I'm
setting stuff though so contact
information feel free to reach out to me
on Twitter on the emails so many
questions are you doing something you
see my sliding a typo or hey this isn't
working whatever just let me know and
I'll do my best to get back to you and
make a comment