everybody hear me alright so what I want
to represent today was decrypting SL
traffic in the villages i'll start I
guess this is mrs. me I'm husband
forgives programmer analyst i can make
her over analytical person who doesn't
always think things just kind of who i
am i'm sure relating to some of you out
there my name is Daniel LTE and let's go
over some exercise
can everybody raise your hand you raise
your hand a little bit
all right good ok can you stand up
sorry I guys but I suppose I know that
you all can will you all stand up
alright so my idea of them so you can
start you can sit down my idea what this
was a workshop and so I wanted to be
able to interact with with people and
wanted to make sure that other people
can interact with other people to make
sure that we get this understood
it's beginning I had seen online that it
was possible to to use your browser to
decrypt the traffic that you're sending
back and forth as if you open up
wireshark when you're trying to do this
and it doesn't it doesn't catch it
doesn't know what's going on
so these slides are available on to the
conference so if you want to take a
picture that you can if you want to
download the PDF and then click on the
link you can't but I always had problems
actually getting it to work I would
follow the different steps and then
things just weren't working so i decided
back down this and this actually helped
me to do what I wanted to do so i'm
going to steal a bunch of his stuff and
so on that link you go to he chose you
this this example of work of some vessel
traffic duty he has and it's all just
jumbled since then
so I guess let's go back so i traded
time I had a server that was that was
using SSL and i was able to get the the
private key because well you know I want
to manage it i try to use that private
key then put into the wireshark command
dreaded can see the traffic in my web
browser and submit it still it still
didn't work so apparently he they may
use the certificates to create some sort
of pre master key and then it's that
that secondary session key but then is
transferred back and for used to encrypt
the traffic back and forth and so that's
why I couldn't do it
the there's a resource slide that I have
at the end of this that explains in more
detail about how to do this and why it
works and stuff like that
see ya firefox and chrome I i know they
work I don't know about any other
browser so what happens is you can you
have an environment variable but you
said and then when the browser goes to
some SL cider it starts up then it says
okay I'm gonna don't my SLPs to to the
file be specified in the environment
variable so depending on how you do it
you may have to start your web browser
from the terminal if your mac or linux
appear windows that should just kind of
work so
let's do some experiments and try to get
this to work
yeah so who here has a windows machine
in front of them and so this these next
couple slides will be for you to help
you go through the the process a lot of
us have done environment variables
this is the name it has to be all caps
at half-speed specifically SL key log
while and then you tell us where to go
that it ok so so I wanted to make sure
that everyone has everyone who wanted to
do this as they had the time to do it
and then if you're on a Mac or Linux is
the way to do it
so if you in in here if you do export
necessarily blood keyfile log file then
you have to use firefox from within the
terminal and then it'll dump it that was
where I was having issues before i was
doing the export and then trying to
start firefox from my was already open
was always started and so then that
didn't it wasn't something the file it
looks like if you do the The Bachelor
see file and you put the be a variable
in there and then log out log back in
maybe we started firebox and that will
come up and that'll work
and then with maggots a similar
situation
you know that works in them i don't know
about emacs editor you know I don't
really know much about macs and then so
has everybody who wanted to gotten this
far to raise your hands of someone who
wanted to do this but couldn't couldn't
do it
so it's very possible that we will get
done
30 because i was expecting more
interactions more trial-and-error heavy
on the other side but in theory all this
is fine it's just if you don't go
through it then you made it snacks and
stuff and it's better if you hit the
snags with a lot of help around you but
yeah so then in white shirt you go edit
preferences and you going to the
protocol section SL and then that's
where you but the browse to the file
that was dumped
if it's not dumping things then you
don't have anything to put here
I don't remember that it and then so
after that after you going to do that
and then you can open up be the pcap
again and then you'll see another an
extra tab that wasn't there before and
it's called encrypted ssl data so then
you can see the the data that goes back
and forth with back using my resources
this is the one that I have found that
actually helped me to get this to work
this is one from Mozilla says hey this
is what this is how you do it
this is right
yeah this can be done i do that for a
while I just couldn't figure out how and
then this is another one from I suppose
some sounds that kind of gives you a
higher overview
I mean at the similar situation to what
I've explained maybe in a little bit
more detail and then this one is like 20
page paper on how to do this and delves
into more
for the details and that's my
presentation I I wasn't expecting a
presentation but more of a demonstration
so if yes
yeah
you specified it but it needs to be
something that the wires that a firebox
can write 2 and then it needs to be
something that you can access with the
with white shirt
great
yeah
ok
so get a little spit out a bunch of
different keys in that file you have
different different websites and stuff
and so than Ben that was different as
different key if they talking different
protocol then you may have a couple of
keys in there for the same same website
but it's on that same file so if you
take that file and throw it into wires
shirt then it will help you to encrypted
yes so this is not a yeah I do
it's not that you're accepting a
different search your just your
everything was normal that as far as
certain concerning you're just seeing
what concert is and then using that to
decrypt the track of how many more
questions
yes
yeah
so in denver VI yes
so the question is what when you use
them in this environment variable or in
this place here what you put into the
file you would just use the same texting
during the same text right here
SLP log file equals than that
yeah so that's about musical persist
over restarts and then it's it's a few
right to this file right that s so he
logged thing and then log out log back
in and then it will be there and you
should be able to dump these files so is
there anyone that is attempted to do
this and has gotten stuck
is there anyone that's working on it
good so I yesterday i found out that
works we will we'll have a created seems
to fit for were sweet and then you can
use that as a prophecy and then you can
then see the traffic you see I'm trying
to troubleshoot something that you own
that you know is gonna you're gonna
trust that that CA sert then then you
can use purple sweet that's maybe a
little bit easier than this
we the major issue that that I see with
this is the environment variables can be
changed without really you knowing and
so this could then be done so that year
that sell keys are being logged to a
file without you knowing so there is
evidence of it happening and that's that
that environment variable so if you know
that it's there and you say that
shouldn't be there then
you can go through the same process and
just delete it if it is there so there's
still people working on it
that's the best times for there's not
much more content so if you are it's
interested with everything else then
you're free to go to sea horses
yeah
so who thinks that they understand this
and make it possibly help someone else
out
ok so it could you those that could you
stand up if you think you understand it
and you could have possibly help someone
else will you please stand up and then
if you need help then could you raise
your hand and then someone else here
could could help you out
well pretty confident in our skills or
we don't want to admit that we need help
in either way sign all first apartments
yeah