investigating PDF mark so how I got
started I was sitting at work one day
and one of my coworkers send out an
email where you can download free books
like that I was curious what would
motivate someone to provide downloads of
three books most of which are probably
under some sort of copyright and as a
result I decided to investigate it and
the conclusion I came to there's really
only one reason to allow for downloading
books that are owned by someone else for
free and that's because the people that
are doing that are actually getting
something out of it and the way they get
something out of it is so essentially
the majority of those kinds of things
part of larger criminal enterprises and
they're using these things and other
things in there are also used in
conjunction with pitching
to be able to get access to your
computer and the things that you have
access to so first of all we should talk
about what a PDF PDF representing
documents in a manner independent the
application software hardware and
operating system used to create them and
the output device on which they are to
be displayed or printed according to the
docs so essentially the media is a
growth from postscript that as a
language designed to identify the
locations for objects on a page and
there in a way that is cross-platform so
why mall where on PBS well is a really
great idea
anything you can write once and it works
on every platform that's really helpful
to us it's everywhere so how does he at
work in general I might go through a
little bit of history here
originally called camelot developed by
Adobe and it was introduced first
introduced in nineteen ninety three men
in 1996 they added a couple of extra
features including passwords encryption
objects and links and it defined a more
structured format than most programs and
the special biohazard including
hypertext links they're not part of the
patients themselves but they end up
being useful
tour interactive kinds of doing how many
of you and HTTP or HTTPS link in a PDF
document Italian people
rate is hopeful but it's a little bit
evil in 1996 they introduced version 1.2
or they had forms that were added to PDF
how many of you fill out a PDF form
maybe their tax documents call a lot of
movies and sounds off the rails here
next two thousand they added JavaScript
and embedded in my dreams of you hackers
are excited about those two things
everyday better be ready to get into
things then finally in 2001 they added
to his impressive images saving to
decode has some serious issues in PDF
documents that's a great place to do
some exploits gonna steal a couple
different versions moved to Thurs 1.7
they added encryption encryption in
Britain 1.7 D was added in 1.1 was based
on AMD 5 NRC for does it work of two
people know that's not a very good idea
so they added a second in 2008 and then
they discovered how thought it wasn't
takes it in 2011 there's actually I
believe a specification for version 1.7
and I don't have a lot of information
about that there are two standards for
PDF documents you have entered an EIS
Center the ISO standard is generally 21
that is included in almost every single
PDF document that you have ever seen the
double standard simply content to that
so they generally a return to those as
Adobe extensions on top of the ISO
standard in the end what is an attacker
want to execute they want to gain access
to your devised when it rang to your
computer to a video so what they really
want to do is be able to get some code
document and executed so the way that I
like to look at this ever since I was a
kid whenever I was playing those games
where I would be amazed I love to start
at the end where the solution is already
apparent and work my way backwards if
you served from the beginning
oftentimes all the third seemed really
come leaders in the hard to understand
but if you see the place for you know
you need to get to it seems easier to me
so I wanna talk about some of the
fundamentals of how a PDF that is built
how many of you have looked at appear in
some sort of editor before you knew this
is what it looks like a really in the
back as a minute just a minute but
essentially it's mostly binary data and
reading binary data is hard for people
it's really easy for computers but it's
hard for people so let's talk about the
different components that are in PDF
documents for beginning the first one
point four people were written by seven
entering the document catalogs and
that's not terribly helpful but this is
what it looks like 20 to the right thing
whereas a percent PDF 1.3 and then some
things out to that that's generally the
person that you got back and he added
that to you know what kind of a PDF
document that you have unless of course
it's over in the dictionary that tells
you to version thanks to be due
importance there are other ways to DVD
out headers
doesn't have to be right at the top they
can be in the first 1000 bytes chances
are if you have a PDF document it looks
like this instead of a default one that
I was showing you before there aren't a
whole lot of pdf Tools that inject
content into PDF documents before the
header and that's because it's very
helpful to do that you can but it's very
helpful to do that once the document and
the next thing that goes for is a
trailer which is at the end of a
document that sets up the object the
route we're gonna talk about a little
bit more and the data to the training is
probably that if you have anything
that's injected into the document after
the trailer declaration probably not a
good thing and documents should be
suspects or any kind of malware and the
truth sets are cross reference to object
locations by character position in the
and the cross-reference table is a map
all the items in the file by showing you
the the root element so this is the end
immediately that I was experimenting
with you see much of lines in the year
the trailer will cross reference table
and then surely make a service this is
the day that you can go to and then the
EOS declaration anything after that is
probably bad there's not a real good
reason for you to include items after
that and much more
building something for hackers count
which there may or may not be any of
them so once you establish the head and
the free to have a pretty good idea of
where the bounds of the document our
media standard you are adhering to the
next day that we need to get into the
root element so the document itself is a
collection of objects under the root
element and all of the objects in a PDF
document descend from that root element
threw one pass for another and
essentially it's a tree structure we
don't have some big trees in here today
but we don't have any real trees look at
this is just a sample of what it looks
like some of your photos and they would
that be publicly with the data
structures retreat as well so there is a
single base object inside of a PDF
document everything comes out of that
to other objects inserting pages and
other things so documents objects that
are embedded inside of media documents
some of you who have used documents are
probably things like text and images
which is kinda nasty JavaScript which is
really exciting for hackers files and
then PDF documents yes you can inject a
PDF document into a PDF document can be
embedded into a PDF document that's when
you can inject immediate access to a PDF
document so you get a tree inside of a
tree
fortunately though it appears of the new
language standard does not allow you to
inject a PDF document into a PDF
document into a PDF document so you'll
have to a two layers of strains are
several things once you've gotten the
basic idea how the tree structure words
and the methods of interacting with the
different objects inside of the tree
structure which will probably talk about
a little bit more
attacker what they really want to do to
execute their cell code is create some
sort of it's free or not or something of
that nature where they get through
enough viewer randomly distributed
memory jus location pointer that points
to their telco and executors of code
of you who are unfamiliar cellco give
you a good example of how many of you
play the game channel and you get there
you move forward to the basis of
something announced that is essentially
something that says move forward once
phase space over and over and over again
until you get to the Lakers forward to
being able to do that is really exciting
if you're trying to compromise between
its not so great to be saved and there
are a lot of functionality and features
built into new modern applications to
try and prevent attackers from the evil
to create enough said and other things
like that but getting creative in the
way they're making their no walks in
these things and so it's not necessarily
a simple task to be able to identify the
section of a document happens to be
enough said and this is the shellcode
until you get into the good some of the
more simple versions of software that is
injected into PDF documents tomorrow
we're very easy to detect because they
have a clear pattern operations in them
and then all of those things of course
can be included an encrypted with around
talk about it in just a minute so
let's talk a little about the different
kinds of objects that are inside PDF
documents the objects that you can have
any PDF document object object itself
and then end up ject you can have a
stream and then stream those are the
areas around a stream across the trailer
pages you've probably seen those in PDF
documents thank you to encrypt intense
jet stream which allows you are kinds of
objects and files and JavaScript objects
and open action objects that executes
when the document is opened
actress honors for form content to
decode is contents were compression
images rich media is for sounds and
videos and then I'm not a dude ranch
house allows you to add files in there
and then exit eight colors so those are
pretty good list of objects that are
found inside a PDF document so the basic
object in a PDF document looks a little
bit like this you have the object number
and the object reference you have the
length of the Dixie stream which will be
about screaming this case it's just a
dream that indicates there were gonna be
printing out some texts there's a pond
and a size in there and then the one
hundred seven hundred is the position of
the text on the page in this case is
fight sequence even has hello world in
plain text that's great and if you're
reading a PDF document it's really
exciting to be able to see plane tickets
and say I know what that point of
printing out
could read the JavaScript upfront
because you're really good at
seventy-eight documents that challenge
with that is that it's usually not that
simple I don't know of a way for you to
create this except by doing it manually
because the tools you would create a PDF
document with filters I believe that
there are 10 different kinds of voters
is Romans and I have been able to find
the most common one that I know of
inside the PDF
decode if you do LZW compression like
giving the impression that you have that
one as well but any one of those things
can be used as a filter on top of the
objects dream that you have inside of
your document all of those filters
different effects unless you that
particulate filters so it's not as
simple as a single signature for some of
these items of video eyewear so here's
an example an item with the ASCII decode
the third grade so I'm not alone that's
really hard to read and being able to
decrypt that requires you to apply that
it gets worse though someone indexing
mall where into your document can
actually filters on a number of levels
and so this particular example uses
including 85 decoding
to be able to read that content there's
also encryption inside this rings that
are contained inside a PDF document so a
document that is encrypted will have the
strings and side of an encrypted but the
objects will not be encrypted so when
you look at an object you'll see this is
the object table you'll see the subject
to the terms of the end it's an action
it has a URL and the euro is this thing
which I can read without detailing so
all of those things contribute to a
little bit of difficulty that we have in
being able to identify and address where
in PDF documents so objects in PDF
language the ones I think are the most
dangerous of these ones here in red and
JavaScript because that's the judgment
scripting language which to do a lot of
things when it's enabled and then open
action open by default and exit i also
very dangerous the accuracy to decode
and rich media and used to supplement
select Send but their little bit harder
to exploit so when you're looking at a
PDF document if you can identify some of
these things are in there that should
raise your alert level a little bit
she you notice a you have a PDF document
it has GPS and JavaScript and a and open
action in it he wear a reason for you to
have all of those in a regular PDF
document at all it's possible that I can
think of one and in the end all of these
things can be areas and all of these
things can be benign you have to be able
to understand the content of the
document that you working on someone to
send you an invoice I would question the
need for having JavaScript an invoice I
would question the need for having
something open as soon as you open job
executing some code when you're just
doing an invoice so this is an
open-access object looks like the object
this is a big number one it's a
catalogue of these outlines and some
pages and then open action which refers
to the number eight when you have that
this is a document opens it probably
opens object number one which might be
the route object in this case it
probably is and then
the fires off a couple of different
pages and then execute the open action
so all of these things are parts of the
PDF structure and this tedious allows
some of our attackers to be able to
inject into PDF documents so at this
point I want to talk a little bit about
some of the tools that we have to get
PDF documents how many of you have seen
work by any one of these three people
love you so Stevens a built-in
researcher has done some incredible work
on where and identifying it and being
able to execute those kinds of things if
you haven't seen his work you're
interested in understanding how that
affects you I would recommend this site
its cities even that it is even so calm
and he's got some incredible tools there
the the two that I find most useful or a
PDF by the in PDF parser DFID is a tool
that you can use you run it as a threat
against your media documents
and it will identify the basic objects
inside of the PDF document to give you
an idea how risky that document is and
as you run that tool if you're under a
lot of PDF documents you'll start to
recognize patterns of turkey recognizes
when certain things are applied together
there are more likely to be dangerous
and when they're a part for example of
an open action together those are likely
to be some sort of nowhere then he also
has a PDF and PDF our stories and much
more in depth tool PDF ideas very simple
very very simple it doesn't do a lot of
musicians inside the PDF document and
the reason for that is because the more
you add to your tool examining PDF
documents are probably have could have
more in the more likely you are to have
some sort of vulnerability included in
that PDF reader as a result DFID is very
small it sorry sixteen and generally
does not include a lot of features that
you would use as far as debugging were
deep investigation into those documents
as well the good thing and a bad thing
but mostly good thing because it can be
used in conjunction with PDF PDF parser
is a more sophisticated tool as far as
investigating the contents of the
documents
when you use PDF parts are you have the
ability to follow an object stream
object I object to decode all of the
filters filter by military and extract
the contents of individual objects as if
they were playing tax anything that's an
awesome tool I do I think that's
incredibly useful know what kind of jobs
have someone has injected into a PDF
document as soon as I'm aware and be
able to come up with patterns to prevent
that from a Senior Network work
installing ransomware on someone's
computer or some sort of back-door shows
like that being able to identify that is
really helpful and it's really hard to
do that when a PDF document has
encrypted streams ran and whites phase
and Kim have any number of filters
applied anyway but the PDF parser allows
you to do that also D PDF I D tool as a
desk here that removes the JavaScript
and open access features the document
and gives you a new PDF talking without
those just removing those things
basically removes most of the
possibility of vulnerability in that
document so if you're trying to remove
media in order to your environment and
the ability to say script pdf doc answer
incoming email you want to read PDF
aidid Ashby then all of these documents
can be modified to remove
items and then moved here immediately on
opening the document which is really
cool
not being able to do that in the simple
command is great I'd also like to
request if anyone here is really good at
C code I'm working on a faster version
of that sort of thing
writing it and see because he is
indicted on and off the pipeline is a
great language not nearly as so I'd like
to do is if anyone has interesting that
works see development skills come talk
to me now to discuss and I would love to
discuss the possibility of you helping
out in building at 201 ability that
allows us to really large PDF documents
in a very short time frame and as we do
that removes these are the most
dangerous without modifying the document
in a way that prevents people to be able
to use it so anyway they're in it with
those two tools that that PDF I D tool
in the PDF parser tool you have the
ability to identify very quickly on a
relative scale using PMID how risky is
this document if you are an icy manager
or security manager and someone sends
you a document and they're not sure if
it's risky you can download pdf idea it
is open source as a link to get home
then I did not post comes from 37 site
and you can tell that to yourself and
running yourself and find out how risky
that is if you find things it includes
JavaScript or open act and says probably
not so great
and you might want to remove those items
the PDF parser is more advanced things
and if you start digging into you will
start to identify someone is getting so
good on to your systems it's worth
noting that executing showed to a PDF
document is not an easy thing to do
simply bcoz PDF readers out there and
most suited in PDF documents are
actually persons the city or software
specific how many of you open PDF
documents with the Adobe Acrobat Reader
to open PDF documents with the different
reader coming to use the Mac prev using
ok to use your browser's with the
built-in Firefox Chrome whatever so all
of those things different code bases and
having different databases means that a
different developer came up with that
and hopefully they got all of the season
they were supposed to but they're
different vulnerability for different
software applications that are used to
open these things when you visit dr. is
hard to determine whether or not you'll
be vulnerable to that
a lot of those things are
vulnerabilities with older versions of
PDF readers so if you haven't seen the
talk he better get updates to update
your PDF readers making sure that your
doctors appt today is also really
important factor in preventing video and
then the next is by Jamie Gillis and he
wrote he PDF and to my knowledge there
isn't any functionality inside that
software that allows you to be able to
remove undesirable pieces of the
document were to detain them so to speak
but it does give you a really good you
inside the PDF document and it's very
similar to the PDF parser a lot of the
things that it returns are very similar
simply because they are reading the same
format in the same kinds of things are
dangerous
the PTS also includes the software that
allows you to kind of a sign a new lease
sale to documents which
really helps what you're trying to
determine how risky is this you don't
want to do the investigating itself if
you just want to strip didn't have a
certain number that says this is risking
up whatever that might be a good thing
for you I guess I also failed to mention
did it is even speedier processor has
the ability for you to plug in
headphones that could do that same kind
of thing for you automatically there
have been a number of atoms that have
been released for that so that's very
helpful as well and then the question
today is preparing for this talk about
what do you do if you're sending out a
PDF document you want to extract all the
metadata added that it's not necessarily
a mall where the question but it is a
PDF reader questions so if you want to
do that you'd probably get indexed tools
by my colleague and essentially draws
the screen for the PDF document takes a
group eg then goes back into a PDF
without many of the meditative which is
also very cool so here's an example
output of media if you submit a comment
the size of a battery which is almost
always true whether or not it's accepted
any objects and streams in there and
nerves which a lot of times areas can
indicate whether or not your document is
not areas then we've got a catalog which
the objects inside of a whole different
object reference then your streams and
then down here the more dangerous stuff
the object for job code suspicious
elements and some heat corruption which
have a CD next to it if you get those
kinds of things out of doors trying to
look at PDF documents that's probably
bad it would be worth also looking at
that CBE or whatever CD that might go up
and if you find that your system is
vulnerable to you either need to not
have people over in that document where
you need to make sure that your software
as fast as possible
document that crashes everytime you open
it chances are that's not very good
views the pilot for the show mister
Roboto you saw this segment of the show
where the gentleman and a CD for his
whatever end someone that into their
computer and they said it doesn't matter
what I do he keeps crashing as soon as I
don't know that's an unhandled exception
occurs love unhandled exceptions because
that means that there's nothing
preventing them from being able to jam
something into memory and hope to
execute code it's usually a trick to get
past that but being able to know that
there is an unhandled exception is very
very helpful so we need to have some
questions what I'd like to do is sit
back and show some line usage of the
media idea to write
my demos directory
couple of styles that are included in
that directory
the PDF documents that are included in
here for PDF documents that I downloaded
from this brief look site as I thought
that would be so inside of you we've got
a book on a tour 2011 wireless networks
the definitive guide second edition how
many of you would like to read a good
book great Photoshop cs6 50 Lightroom
and of that or advanced had a very
testing 123 testing
like I said it's my tongue so soon a
great job but i dont not as fast as
compiled code
their results and let's see we have here
so if you had the PDF headers his first
album by six there's 7374 objects and
700 7074 and objects that's probably
good because they're the same number of
the streams are also the same tables
trailers 414 pages in the document 226
objects unit is down here is the number
one and if you notice a little bit down
further tax reform has a number one this
document probably so that's our first
try another one
thank you to complete that would be
really hard to type without being able
to see it
a lot faster so we have the same number
of Jason Hoppy Jason streams as well
this is a PDF version 1.4 and inside of
your we encrypt object and ingest
objects so there may be more we're in
here but you'll notice there's no edta
open action so if trouble does inspire
the second you open the document that's
probably a good thing
agree
and the open action calls the accuracy
and the Act reformist so is the only to
then not so much so now that you bring
that up with something about a document
that i think is a little bit more
interesting
the Adobe Photoshop cs6 family from the
free book site since I did it
1122 pages but it has five JavaScript
objects 20 size and one open action
items in there so when you open this PDF
document $0.26 fire it is just a book on
Nov three times yes indeed that I don't
know and in the end the reality is that
you need to investigate these documents
one on one you need to look into them
individually to be able to tell is it
somewhere or not the doctors who looked
at today this one seems like the most
obvious one to wear because there are
lots of open actions and lots of a
records all of those things all those
objects are potentially dangerous the
higher the number the more likely they
are to be dangerous
you can also see that there is a
difference between the object center
open and the objects that are intended
that's probably also not a very good
thing and then
run this was the death D
so that's what this says it doesn't
regular expression replacement change
its open action with the capital only
capitulate to everything is the wrong
case and the PDF document reader just
says that is moves on the cool idea
waiting for that GTA question
the question is whether I have seen more
where that is
be attached where or links inside the
the email and said I would say that it's
probably more common to see links inside
the email because there are a couple of
things that are really great about
things inside and email and that is what
number one people click on them over
time and number two you can control
what's on the other end and you can
update it for you can deliver different
content based features that you might be
able to detect when you send out a PDF
document to someone you really hoping
that they have something that you
already have codes or so you know it's
you know he s nowhere specimens really
really good but it works on Windows with
Acrobat Reader seven that's awesome if
the person you are sending to has
Acrobat Reader seven if they don't then
that's not so great and so I mean if I
were trying to create more sophisticated
phishing malware kind of thing it might
even be beneficial to give people a link
to a PDF document on a website does that
answer your question
alright who also has a question relating
to this design that a yes
object program a lot of the same
question
it's really cool to be able to do things
that the full-featured programming
language like like JavaScript as opposed
to just a video of language itself
however the moment you open up a
full-featured language like Java Script
you allow hackers to do things like
bumper overflows and when they did you
vote for overflows they can do not sides
and they can ensure show code and they
can execute that whenever they get to
some sort of unhandled exception and the
same thing applies to the TSS
application also allows for you to
embedded files in there and just say
this is out but somehow someway someone
decided that saving out executable files
is not a good idea so they disallowed
that so at least we have some open that
yes
is some of the PDF said he has seen
actually try to open up jar files and
the end result of that is there's no way
for me to tell you for sure whether
that's bad or not it could be great for
your environment but the GPS allows for
that and that's the real danger the UPS
facility allows for a lot of incredible
features but almost all those incredible
creatures starting with version 1.1
we're really great for attackers evil to
inject for JavaScript stuff being able
to act use forms to inject names being
able to embed told files and save them
out to the disc and some of the
advancement in PDF readers lately have
been you know working on mitigating
those kinds of things by the way if you
haven't updated your PDF reader in the
last little bit you might want to
consider that a lot of vulnerability
three pts in question was little bit
other questions let's take a look at the
results were
removal of those things so we had one
open access the government placed a
couple things and then either another
set of their kind of open access
journals and JavaScript so at the end of
that it also gives you the PDF Editor
results and objects and everything for
that particular document and it shows
you the Council of things before that it
created a new document inside there so
if we do a video by the
the
6 disarmed so take just a minute and it
will show that those things have gone
away which will be really helpful
do we have any other questions like two
minutes left
taco relating to this is in the end I
found the PDF mom wears a very
interesting topics for me I like
research if you want to know more about
this the research done by some of the
people that have created these tools is
incredible D Stevens has a number of
videos that are available on YouTube
he's given talks security conferences
around the world if you want to learn
how to use his tools he's much better
teaching them that I am and you can
learn some great things of that he has a
lot of things and he regularly updates
his tools as well so that's really
helpful and then there have also been a
couple times I think we're definitely
talked about PBS yes
militias PDS Google's free ebooks
that'll be a really quickly to get some
sample ones then you know i i dont know
im pretty sure that did it even has a
number of things he also has another
tool that I didn't mention the stock and
he has a tool that allows you to create
your own and hopefully you use that for
good but that allows you to inject
content into PDF documents in being able
to do that i think is out a meal
understand how that affects PDF
documents and hopefully helps you to be
able to identify those kinds of things
inside of your PDF documents was
answered questions first where you can
get those and what you should do about
it maybe I i dont have a repository that
I can help with that which is probably
okay because I wanted to show you where
right so if you look at the results the
DFID now it looks a whole lot better
all those objects that can be seen as
negative have disappeared
and is that did not negatively impact
the document in any way you can still
read all of the things that you want why
not there's nothing that prevents you
from being able to do it if you can do
that across your organization for every
PDF coming into your email can you solve
that problem of people emailing you in
PDF said this is an invoice for
such-and-such to your accounting
department and they open it up and now
you're counting hauser ransomware to
whatever so that the other tools that an
elicitor also very helpful
any other questions okay thank you very
much