thanks for being patient on the ground
white and when I talk to you today about
hacking web apps in this is more kind of
an intro for people that are interested
in getting an InfoSec or as your
developer and wanna learn how to secure
your own code or anything like that it
says dear towards helping you get
started it also shows what I do with a
10 tester from client can't wait to
report delivery and again
constraints gonna have to keep certain
things but this will give you the
groundwork to go Google and figure out
where you need to basically redo the
client we have a kickoff call and this
is where I was checking out the rules of
engagement with the scope is when can we
scan is it ok if we look at this
application 24 by 7 network its
introduction may be the only one testing
on off hours so we're not messing up
anything this year what's the URL or
whatever the application is so we make
sure that were actually hitting the
right in the end in case something does
go wrong if we do break it or we
actually have now service is something
we need to have the points of contact
that we can call and say it's three
we broke his stuff and then hopefully
that doesn't happen very often
evidence gathering so we're doing these
assessments
a report is expected so the more
evidence you gather going through so
much easier going to make your life when
you gotta start writing the report when
I first started you know and tester
doing this stuff they were to assess
into the beginning where they had
ordered shut off access and I didn't get
good at screenshots or I didn't capture
the correct get imposed on us and our
ability but I had to go to them and ask
them for temporary access that I could
write documentation of course that's
kind of a bigger say in their best to
make sure that you're recording as much
evidence that can gathering so keep
everything that I find it there's so
many tools out there that you can use
that are three things that I like to use
personally keep know it comes
pre-installed Kali Kali how everyone sit
it also has an installer for the Mac OS
X or Windows compatible with everything
about it if the client wants to see all
of your raw notes outside of the report
you can easily export everything is a
HTML file and they can see anything as
long as i have a web browser
my information so there's a couple of
ways the more you do this figure out
what works best for you and what I found
works best for me if I have several
applications that I'm working on a
single by my group the vulnerability by
the host or IP that way I can break it
out her application to hand for single
application oldest documented by
vulnerability and as you can see a
different color coding and the green
references such as the Cisco credentials
that they have provided me so I know
that I can just sort of ignored those
when I'm reporting that dark red nose
with your critical direct would be your
serious or high and so on
to me that's just a personal preference
in ashes to quit this or references to
territory I found it and how it's going
so far
you document what is considered evidence
earlier about the get requests in the
response you're sending to the
application that make sure that you are
documenting what you're sending as well
as a response to see just a course for a
job
cross-site scripting don't just show
that the pop up with the wider dialogue
make sure that you're actually showing
that this is what I sent this is the
parameters that was vulnerable injuries
to respond
wrote that I've actually seen some
consultants get into some deep water
over don't have her shares closed half
but he did for a client
not a good idea you're probably under
some sort of non-disclosure agreement
anyway so distracted that what's your
friends that you know maybe you were
yesterday you can trust or sanitized
make sure that you get relevant legible
screenshots and more ability to reports
comes through our QA process where you
didn't really tell exactly what it was
that they were trying to call out in a
screenshot so make sure that you are
coming in and actually showing hey this
is where the problem is not obvious
example sequel down corn assessment that
I did I wanted to really show the
information but obviously if I were to
take this image in a report and had to
shrink it down you would really be able
to read it so when you have to figure
out how to take areas that are really
just going to show the importance of the
vulnerability you sound zoom in and make
sure that it again you heard me talk
about HTTP request and response example
to sort of how I dotting the code in a
report and you can see the hard part was
when I actually sent to find more
ability so what is easily the report
they can easily see what the problem is
and try and replicate it themselves
your testing all parameters and
application don't decide about someone
perimeter and then move on to something
else you're looking at every parameter
and if you do
injection make sure that you are testing
that matters and then document every
single parameter in your report that's
far more that way their client isn't
saying how about how bout them the
password parameter for each other is
horrible to you can't answer that it
looks like you didn't do it for a job so
methodologies are great thing to have to
go by citizens about the methodology
these are displayed good enlist help
keep you on track so you know especially
as pen tester reduced several
assessments basically one right after
another and so this is a good way to
make sure to make sure that I'm looking
at each section is sort of a guideline
just something I want to mention to its
don't sell to the methodology that
there's something that's not listed in
there that you know should be added
you know jack that two methodologies are
good guideline and helps you to reach
the party there's a previous hack then
you can find you know credentials are
you can notify them by doing this data
base side found higher benefits humans
have also found test accounts that were
posted on a development helped that were
still active so you're gonna go
development to get help make sure you
sent it I just don't give the real data
base name of the rule table names and
then you get someone on your test
account make sure when they're done is
we've actually been able to leverage
that quite a few times were open source
intelligence there so many tools
Google's great tool then you have things
like this cover by leaving here this has
many many options that are built into it
to help help you get through this
assessment pretty quick after all there
are several reasons why again as I
mentioned I usually do you expect an
automated scanners are covering a wide
range of things very quickly and they're
good at finding as what you however
can versions that can so does that mean
it means that it's just quickly scanning
it doesn't do really much about dinner
accident things that humans and do you
don't rely on it and to those that say a
bone scan is again with automated
scanners you have to verify the results
don't don't trust was perfect right
they're good at certain things quickly
but don't trust him so for example if
their response and scripting
vulnerability or something
make sure you go check that see what
it's a replay the request and see if
it's legitimate how much further can you
take that more ability if it's not then
marketable move on again there's so many
of them out there remember it was saying
they're the ones that he's a regular
basis
Nexus is a Grade IV MS stands on a
regular basis to really get it deep dads
on applications
gonna grow by three times in the next
two witnesses actually built in the Cali
already you can also install it on
whatever other destroy you have again
it's equipped with automated scanners
it's good for people add me
10 voters were back of 54 looking for
basic CDI water deliveries and so on so
it's a good time saver DreamWorks
DreamWorks whenever it's built on
Wordpress cold fusion for Joomla Drupal
or anything like that makes me very
happy because I know it's gonna be a fun
assessment things like WGC can those are
available in there dude specifically for
you know frameworks like WordPress for
example bogus numerate
version that's installed it all and
numerate they have so you can search and
see if there are no next words for those
plugins and you can also a numerate user
names which you know brute-force
brute-force the login
but basically any meaningful words
commonly named for workers there are
huge risk for foreign names where you
can actually do it true brute force for
not only soldiers profiles as well and
by using this school several times I
have found backup bad sequel database
files that I could just pull down
because they weren't you know any sort
of authentication security by obscurity
was a good idea and and that's not a
good idea so this helps finest things
again have many more options in Cali I'm
not quite sure what the menu layout is
the new version but and the last word in
Cali this this is then you listen menu
layout is where you were trying for
ability scanners experts
automated scanning don't just open the
standard and put in the URL and click Go
taking a chance if you do that you need
to look at the application and see OJ is
that this is how it's handled good about
traffic data tests in a little bit and
see me know if you have it open as it is
it gonna kill those gonna knock
something over you don't have dental
service checks available on certain
those certain clients request that you
don't really care and again as I mention
the number of threads at a time
transmitters are functions that you want
to avoid with the automated standing in
time you'll find that there's a contact
page or maybe a sign-up form that it's
ok if you test manually but if an
automated scanner it's gone flooded and
put you know thousands of requests and
their data base and then some guys got
to clean that up and he's not too happy
about that
again if it's if it's a test environment
it stopped production but if you are
testing in a production environment just
make sure you ask those things and then
go on but those exceptions in the stands
and everything and you're ready to go
then then hit start testing I wish I had
a little bit more time to dig deeper
into manual testing but again we're kind
of going back to the scan results so as
I mentioned before anything that
automated standard gives you make sure
that you're going through and manually
verify their signing those so if it says
that there's you know again
cross-site scripting vulnerability or
something instead of just documenting a
wide problems or something like that can
you actually bring in a malicious
javascript and then start blogging how
far can you take that so make sure that
with manual testing you're really trying
to leverage these things as much as the
application again rely on the automated
standard to do it put it through a proxy
like 30 or a proxy for several others
out there to make sure that that you're
trying to get a very accurate view of
the application
a spider at you when it goes through and
there's a content discovery option on
dirrty bro that it will take no names of
URLs and things that it's already bound
and see it sort of information that
might be linked pages thats cool down
already
disaster response sometime
most of the time to reply will actually
show you what version it's running
whether it's the version number and
sometimes very riverboats and that can
help you save your exploits in your
attacker with more parameters I
mentioned earlier mixture your testing
all parameters and application if there
are several is make a list and down make
a list to make sure that you're hitting
each one that way you can you know if
the client to check for scripting
cross-site request forgery sequin held
up in Jackson Hole and remote file
inclusions those are all things that are
great British accents and still find
quite a few of these results
unfortunately
okay so it's sensitive information being
passed to get requests instead of those
there are quite a few applications i've
seen where they actually cached page to
the browser with the URL username and
the password for the user ID or
something that can be leveraged its so
while optimizing that machine and and
doing some simple forensics that I've
been able to grab gather credentials for
an application so you want to make sure
that any sensitive information is
actually being center post requests
looks or look at the source code that's
incredible how many three DS if you want
I've actually sound source code
developers into each other saying hey
this causes the fog let's fix this and
whatever Jan test with this account and
so they told me what the bug was and
they gave me credentials to log in and
test and all of this was found as an
unauthenticated user so you know you
wanna come over its its all time
consuming but come over each page
response sometimes appliance and get
information
death by PowerPoint for a second
have to do it
going back to the source code so there's
so many times again that obscurity or
security by obscurity where they'll
utilize JavaScript
admin wings so if you're using him as an
admin it won't show you on the screen
the and leads but if you look in the
code that is right there so can you go
to those and still see them even though
you're not a little user to see those
things as a not been indicated user so
you want to make sure to tested from as
a dedicated and indicated user and see
the links and things that you find what
did you get to that you're not supposed
to see
looking just just focusing on the
application itself
host that it's on there have been times
where the host has been outdated
unpatched and we've been able to
leverage some of those extra weights
again at no damn roots you the box so
check that is well-known excesses
scanner for that we're just looking at
yourself look at the response to see
what the servers running and then again
you searched and searched or something
just fine
exploits to turn to track weapons that
have been portals get talked about the
adamantly
available something that you can brute
force be like tom cat or something
cPanel so many things you can look at
directory traversal are they using
dangerous HTTP methods there have been a
handful of times where they've had been
able so I was able to use a lot of
scripted PHD's order asap and the
antivirus and catch it and there I had
you know basically ShelterBox just from
crafting a request and then when I was
done
method to get off something like that
and you're not able to remove it
yourself make sure you keep a note to
let the client know there can take it
off so you get clean up its better for
you to tell them instead of a year later
when some guys going through a what's
this you know what's the shell script
that's on there you know look and see
what what a gorgeous what services are
open with using something like in map
pls see what cipher suites have enabled
us 012 RTOS 1.0 who are you know some
weak ciphers leads so these are things
that you can check them know what they
need to get rid of what they need to
enable or disable and then again as I
mentioned methodologies
just getting into the US so that's a
good way to help keep you on track and
make your own notes something that I do
I am not very smart so don't really
remember demand really well
savage I ganic cheat sheet I guess you
call it but I made using cheap no broken
things down by vulnerability of war by
tool a reference that hasn't tried those
things over and over again on defense so
keep practicing figure out what the best
way is to your notes and then when
you're ready graphics and web sites are
we doing on time
good cool so make sure to leave some
time open for you and I if anybody has
any questions or anything or we can talk
afterwards I know there's a Chinese
cleaver a high level to make sure to fit
everything in you say about our talk so
thanks for sticking with me
told him the author but it's got like
the picture on the front of it there are
so many resources on YouTube and Google
Web App Store suite 403 videos and
walkthroughs to help you can see me if
you have any questions