here there's a lot of open space like in
those airplanes that you feel free to
text kind of lay down take a nap it's
the perfect 2 o'clock slot and
compliance is in the name of the
presentation it's conducive for nap
taking I imagine that you guys are here
for one reason or another even if it's a
it's gave vendor tables or just where no
one else would be but I hope that there
will be content that you guys can take
away from this talk about objective of
this discussion and I say discussion I
mean that I'll be taking questions
between an uncomfortable with that if
you guys want to raise your hand during
if I can't see you guys there is light
shining in my eyes and just kind of fell
out and try to try to field questions as
best they can but just wanted to
understand well I guess I'll introduce
myself my first time presenting here at
st. Khan and yeah it's exciting
nerve-wracking have never presented in
front of the large room before
and we'll see how that goes but when I
worked at work front and Compliance
Manager is managed by title I don't
manage any people but managed the
compliance processes of policy in fact I
really geeked out about reports I can't
get enough in my spare time for some
really fine reading check out Amazon's
you learn absolutely nothing about their
environment that's that's like the
standard it's perfect but in all reality
I do I do enjoy a passion for compliance
have a passion for the framework that
people come up with and seemed to
continue inventing in order to get one
thing or another and make more money
from my background I worked in Novell
that was kind of my first introduction
of technology when I graduated from
Brigham Young University I went to work
for their now called and they're one of
what are known as the big four
accounting firms but did you I T audits
provide people soccer for its that's
what I did all the time
60 70 hours a week was just renting out
these reports are they hold a special
place in my heart I do I think it's
important to post this disclaimer
compliance is not security and I don't
want anyone to leave here thinking that
because they put in place any kind of
compliance measures frameworks that
they're secure or not they can help
guide
news they can help instruct certainly
management and customers more
importantly of the security measures
that you're following but it doesn't
surprise doesn't dictate security and
security actually doesn't dictate
compliance item in this presentation I
really do want it to be a little bit
less formal I wanted to be more of a
discussion I'm gonna be following some
very specific steps on how to present
and so from my book how to present
buyout of Wingate I've got a couple of
rules you really need to move your hands
a lot so you'll be seeing a lot of this
appear on the podium tons of memes and
that's just a little bit about knowing
your audience you know I mean
conferences is full of memes in addition
you need to repeat yourself a lot just
to use words even in the same sentence
and talk down to the audience of time
really helps with that so being able to
really just kind of inform you all how
things work
definitions that things are you guys
could be googling I think that hopefully
and hopefully see some of that
throughout the presentation as well
including yourself
credibility is key when presenting its
partisan agenda we're gonna be doing
what is right so the conversations about
managing compliance in the Devils
environment so we want to see
we want to try to understand what
devices they try to understand the
question mark I think we all know why
that's that is a question mark but the
problem statement we're gonna talk about
compliance criteria we're gonna be
addressing here in this in this
conversation and then talk about deficit
controls will get into some
brainstorming essentially what are the
challenges of DevOps and what can you
put in place what can you be considering
what kind of controls you put in place
to help developers from rolling code
into production
developing in production and then I'll
have a formal Q&A the end but again
asked questions throughout raise your
hand and make sure they get them so what
is it really it really does feel this
way you keep using that word means what
you think it means what does it right so
many organizations are take making us
here today because they feel that it
will mean quicker release customer will
be happier to have features faster right
so this rapid release really drives
organization to research and implement
some form of death and development
operations are taking the operations of
people to keep the wheels on and
combining those roles responsibilities
with people that code the applications
that work on top of those systems more
collaborative that can that can seem
really attractive also in hand in hand
with that rapid release continued
employment because they're moving today
it's always rolling code right always
introducing new features and and
customers responded that the honest with
you the user the end user response that
rapid release is
a benefit of device that people tend to
latch onto deeper in the cloud right we
can reduce costs just put everything in
Amazon and it's a lot cheaper mention
rapid release rapid release like getting
hitters out there
repeating yourself in a presentation on
my keys and then I can google it for you
turns out it you did not even googling
what is David's just DevOps the top half
of the post-war what is Devin answering
it but also asking genuinely what in the
world is now you know now you know what
devices you have the reality is that if
your organization and by raising hands
are you in an organization that we're
planning on moving today so this year
already into whatever it says there are
so many different flavors and no one no
one goes old emma but in reality its
challenges and so every organization has
to tailor their approach and
problem really what we want to cover a
shift can introduce risk to the business
and its data and I didn't spell check
spelling errors just blame the editor
they probably missed it this isn't a
unique problem
anyone had ever dealt with risk
compliance evaluating risk in an
organization knows that if you're
introducing anything new
it's going to introduce risk there are
challenges there can holes opened up in
your systems because of these new
processes systems new organizational
structure so that the real problem if we
distill it down is that this shift will
introduce our Canon risk as with any
organization shift then there are
certain process is it appropriate risk
the city we're talking about managing
compliance the perspective that I'm
going to be coming at this from is
security compliance and there are a
variety of reports I didn't include them
anywhere in the side because everyone
has their own requirements the
organization where their customers so we
could be talking about HIPAA PCI my
personal favorite reports one two and
three
ISO 27001 and actual certification right
even if you guys are dealing with
government entities and you and i SMS
right so logical access physical access
and other I T operations at home in
that's why that's why those bullets and
you can see a lot of things missing from
that and if any of you ever interacted
with an auditor and I was an auditor and
so I feel like it's Pete someone tells
you they interacted with an auditor they
have so you can lead an auditor down
whatever path you choose almost but they
will latch on to certain things that
they see or find it may not have
anything to do with your organization
but all the sudden they thought that
seems important to me and it falls under
one of my categories and I need to
follow up with it but it when the
reality of things it doesn't flood risk
urination or or or otherwise but change
management large black this physical
access and other I T operations such as
disaster recovery monitoring network
security those are gonna be the areas
where they're gonna focus and where we
need to be aware for making a shift or
have me to ship them to keep those
controls in place the reality that
that's the problem the reality is that
it isn't a new concept isn't new
combining developers with giving
developers the responsibility of
top-to-bottom control system right now I
think back to
accompanied my dad worked for and they
would just basically hand out some
vendor came and told us this new tool
and then they would he would hand it off
to the idea the idea will maintain that
system was the tech support he was the
one pushing patches and updating the
system may not have been the developing
the company developing kirby's certainly
had some of those change management
responsibilities patching change
management so there's a new rewards the
DevOps is a unique from any other kind
of fancy trendy organization structure
and in the end wrist and evaluating
those risks measuring the communication
isn't new
so then it's really boiling down those
aspects of Debye challenge the controls
that we have in place so as we go
through the rest of this presentation
and discussion I want you to think about
what is the risk that we present some of
the challenges of the area's control
areas the criteria to security about
what is the risk what the rest of my
organization will talk to Erica Lee
about what that could be
think about what is the risk is this is
this something that would matter to me
that would matter to my company
customers that would matter to
executives in my company
and to making an adjustment any kind of
reorg is looking for you can you can
identify similar processes overlap those
are your auditor help them understand
that they're the same look we we we do
steps ab&c in both of these processes
let's just look at them as a simple
process and you're gonna win reduced man
hours managers finally we do need to
talk about what others are looking for
you have interacted with auditors and
some may not have dealt with auditors
very much but I am NOT lying on its
themes that may or may not have any
consequence of your organization so what
I want to talk about in this is gonna be
aligned with the trust services
principles so if you've heard of the
sock to it is a control framework that
is based on trust services principles
their status by the ACPA it's a
framework that's definitely more
credible carries much more right here in
the USA and it doesn't actually but it's
growing and it's developed rapidly on
the coast
2012 everyone was asking for one and now
we're seeing here in Utah now and saying
that a lot of our customers are becoming
aware of sock to what's included in it
why it's different than a stock one and
why that might be important to them I
didn't choose ISO 27001 I didn't use
federal and just because their control
frameworks are they tend to be a little
more redundant and it has its purpose
but their large control frameworks that
ramped asthma if you choose a medium
risk your going to be looking at over
300 controls and you can implement a
sock to any organization with less than
just to give kind of an idea
requirements so that is something that
your organization has to follow make
sure you get a consultant or make sure
you understand what is needed
they're gonna be pointing you didn't
miss all the time saying you have to be
doing seven past you have to be smashing
those hard drives and I built this
conversation of comic control criteria
on sock to the controls that they are
then recommending a testing on to
provide this site to report have to do
with these topics the first is
organization and management so when when
an auditor is evaluating a company
outing for security right the trust of
his principles include other criteria
that aren't just security but we're
right now we're talking about security
organization management they want to
know that it's a top-down approach to
security and they want to know that it's
the executives are communicating these
requirements that they have strong
passwords that they're saying yes
encrypt your heart rates because we care
about the data that were protecting so
we see that entity level controls or
entity level safeguards and these are
overarching principles in your
organization does your a chart do
background checks and we don't think of
that as security per se but in the
compliance world if you're if an auditor
is evaluating our customer is there
representing us if they're evaluating
Organization for Security they have the
right people
coding that you have the right people
that have access to the custard they're
they're sensitive information so they
want to know are you doing background
checks how often are you doing security
training annually or or have whatever
frequency right and what all does that
include organizational management is the
first criteria in security communication
so the facts are not only having those
of overarching securities
but also that you can be killing them
internally your employees understand any
time they know where they stand in this
whole machine of protecting information
right they can have access to all of the
policies that they would need to have to
do their job that customers would
understand also that you've communicated
customers what the boundaries of your
system are you know that you have Terms
of Use
you have some kind of NDA in place that
you're reviewing those things are
communicated if you have an incident how
is that how you write so communication
is the second criteria the next couple
risk management controls this one is my
absolute favorite and are you are you
presenting that to management are you
able to communicate risk down so that's
often we find the risk we find them on
the low level we find that someone has
read access our back door into an
application but once we do the risk
assessment we find yeah we've got this
one billion communicate that are we
helping the organization get better
are using that risk assessment to
implement actual security and controls
controls are just the way of helping to
enforce its just a way of measuring
for your users shouldn't be doing it
gives you a chance to check to make sure
see where you're at
control is just that it's just a
necessary evil in this whole compliance
machine but they definitely result from
the risk assessment overall control
might be a way of mitigating along with
his hand in hand is monitoring those
controls putting them in place doesn't
do a whole lot unless you monitor and
enforce yeah
question so the question was it you have
some control these damaging organization
and correct me if I get this wrong but
if you establish some criteria you want
your employees to follow this and then
you adopt a third-party solution some
kind of South provider maybe your vendor
what can be done to ensure that your
enforcing that for those vendors as well
right is that so depending on the
framework that you follow your order me
also
and you or your use of that software
good example is ATP lot of organizations
using ADP payroll often becomes in
school because of the amount of money
that's coursing through my veins and so
and Auditor we'll ask you is your
position have you evaluated ATP are you
following your own policy
ATP provide you the opportunity to set
your own passwords in the application
and then they're gonna include that wrap
that up into the audit and not really
would only be in scope it it's
financially significant doesn't mean
it's not a best practice sales forces
another that may be a better example
right a lot of sensitive data or
customer data goes for Salesforce and in
your organization do you know are you
aware of the password settings on the
sales force in question you should be
asking yourself if you have a password
policy should you not then hold your
vendors to a similar policy front we
develop software within the tool itself
we allow customers to set those
parameters they could set a password
policy so it seems easy enough to just
kind of wash your hands and say it makes
you strong possibility that you could
set it up everyone and a lot of vendors
that way you'll find the majority of
those solutions that way but yet as a
compliance organization then you
certainly want to establish a vendor
review process and we're going to talk
about that but yeah so that you can no
physical access this is kinda standard
across the board it's something that we
often take for granted I really I really
do believe social engineering is the way
into an organization just by the people
and this is the gate right so protecting
the logical access of systems and the
physical access of your facilities and
resources is absolutely key to get in on
that it's easy for them to do your gonna
invite into your company at some point
of a walk through the front door they'll
be looking around like no one knowing
look now from IIT right so as long as
you don't have to check but as long as
no one's coming not just anyone is
coming in taking up a laptop but along
with logical physical access you can
consider increasing devices right
protecting those resources assets and
logical access a lot of times we wanted
to think about the four systems and may
be important and auditors can look at
that they may start asking questions
about where we noticed that you gave us
a password
yes the users we understand that we've
gone through there are you VA's this all
appropriate what about these system
accounts you know anything about the
system accounts
and give them an opportunity to dig
deeper
even though it may not matter this could
be some API into your payroll systems
employees something necessary they made
their diving down this whole so
understanding not only user access and
password system accounts and how their
access yeah
fantastic question and its slide so we
were gonna will tackle that the question
was about that
access list tends to grow in a divisive
and what are some of the things we can
do about that will operate in this can
be kind of a blanket at times but
supporting systems a composer centrist
information security so are you catching
your systems do you have appropriate
place that something that I really think
backups security right we're still
talking about common security criteria
for an auditor
think about backup says something that
we now have responsibility for his
passion right back up protected if we
say we're gonna rest are equipped their
backup restore backups were they being
stored overdoing tape when we drive that
tape the tape storage facility who's
going with that vehicle ER wait times a
day are we doing it right we have the
proper texto we absolutely should be
considering backup when we're looking at
the security of our persistence of our
data of our environment
finally change management and other
subjects I'm really passionate about
along with risk management change when
we can break everything right here
lingers really and then hitting enter
France right so cloud applications
in the inexperienced innovation in a
DevOps environment even more so how you
manage change management is going to be
there are some additional control of the
part of the sock sock to framework so
you can elect to also have another test
for availability controls
confidentiality availability right
especially just a solution this can be
this is generally the number two doing
the stock to their usually doing the
concrete you have to do
security and availability customer care
escalates in place so why not give them
an idea of that time the systems that
are there to support that help them be
comfortable they're asking for it
because we don't have to give them
anything
confidentiality protecting that
information data integrity so the
accuracy of that information
inputs and outputs you're measuring them
to make sure that there are on par and
finally privacy is hardly ever adopted
surprise in the United States we really
don't like it we don't like talking
about it i mean we would love to see we
don't care about it but we love it and
it's not really a conversation we found
this out I guess we've always known
right but safe harbor is is an agreement
that the EU had with the USS in export
and import data they wanted to make sure
that they are you citizens that their
information is secure protected not
being looked at by anyone that shouldn't
be anyone other than the aggrieved party
so we had safe harbor in place as we
know a student who came to Santa Clara
University filed a class-action suit
filed the suit against Facebook
ruling was from that that safe harbor is
no longer in effect we can't use safe
harbor as a protection just got this
kind of beside this discussion but make
sure that your organization can be
getting those questions what are you
doing with Article 28 article 29 that
contract extension with a blanket and we
need to have one-to-one if they have a
breach of course that's what that
privacy privacy has to be concerned
about whether we test-fired I would
encourage you to right now the AICPA is
rewriting their privacy criteria so they
they issued criterion 2012 for all of
the other controls except privacy 2012
first update since 2007 and 2012 well
we're ready with everything else we need
to be considering there's only one cover
all so when we look at these frameworks
we look at solutions there's really only
one cover all and that is Lorenzo Cain
the center fielder for the Kansas City
Royals will cover everything everything
else we need to be looking at as we
can't have a blender there's no blanket
compliance report there's no blanket
solution and security right we can't
just got a firewall so we're seeing
right only Lorenzo Cain can cover
everything and there's only one of them
is busy so let's let's dive into each of
these topics
let's put them in the context of DevOps
and let's brainstorm some of the things
we need to be considering what what
could be a solution to the potential
challenges that are introduced in the
device environment so organization and
management and I don't know how big is
that people not sure about collaboration
or just pops losing responsibilities
right so organization and management in
this year in a shift from 972 DevOps not
apply to start of right at the start but
a shift to delve who are you reporting
to you what does the organization now
see as requirements and compliance and
even security can result in merged
technical leadership roles you may find
that you no longer have an advocate
directly right or or they don't speak
your language
the people that you now have to talk to
about compliance requirements they may
or may not see value in it definitely be
a challenge as a direct result from that
if they don't see value there may not be
budget for it I really appreciated the
keynote that was given the ISO from
University of Utah you mentioned that as
far as priorities we need to be ready to
communicate management we need to be
ready to fight for those budgets we need
to have the relationships developed
right
and I think that we should consider that
what what can be done in order to
communicate those risk management and
process owners manager doesn't manager
doesn't speak your language translator
charged I think that's really Menteri
we may think that but it's it's
certainly an ability it certainly
provides us an opportunity to learn that
provides an opportunity under standard
the new business card at so just as an
example
graphs-n-charts right here's percentage
of budget that you receive for the
approved versus the hours that you spend
on LinkedIn per day
you know so if you have let's say
hundreds in your budget you may not
spend 90% you see it goes up but tell us
a little bit like five hours a day if
you're getting the budget then there's
no point you're doing something wrong so
why even though that's just my attention
from the data the data it's science I
hope no one can be super valuable so
along with maps in your risk assessment
intelligence behind it
likelihood understanding where you're at
risk senior visually can help you'll be
surprised you will find benefits from
running a risk analysis may be higher
risk of reach I don't know
graphics their license I don't know they
are diagrams are reports right
presenting the management what our
security inventory is what do we have in
place the chart presented yesterday that
he know that was again it seems really
rudimentary but from the ground up you
know what our foundation what tools do
we have in place to address the
are known risk categories and they keep
calm and do a risk assessment and really
own it really dive in
you should not be if your security
professional you shouldn't be the only
person involved in compliance
person involved in risk assessment the
audience for your understanding
input from different parties actually in
the new organization we're in a new
organization structure
communication responsibilities then
related to communication these are
critical to both idea development and so
this is the reality the implementation
made push for a common process right so
if I'm a developer and I've got a
changing data center locations were also
rolling out these new features why not
do that in one class so instead of
having rpms just communicate new
features and then having I T operations
communicating infrastructure changes
they made one emerge this process is Nov
out use only challenge or one of the few
challenges to that
roles responsibilities related to these
may not be defined so if the business
that has an expectation you have a
common process we don't let our
customers with man about these updates
we learned that my advice something to
consider understanding illustrate your
communication requirements good examples
incident management if an incident
occurs a security incident performance
incident whatever you're responsible for
an incident occurs what's your
communication plan that communicates
management make sure they understand
risk management controls pretend to know
everything about
man gene compliant in a diverse
environment but I will say that neither
DevOps for operations development more
operations risk they are not they are
not the end party does not stop there
you may not feel that way you know the
pressure maybe on you and your
organization to implement a to manage
that risk but you certainly don't own it
follow the dollar finance on the risk
and we need to educate customers about
what they can again expect that is our
responsibility were the ones that know
the technology that is set up the
systems that maintain them but it
doesn't mean that you can't advise
certainly specially if you are doing a
risk assessment then communicating as
risk becomes even more important than
risk management controls look again look
for common process and repeat myself
he's that again
accounting processes like change
management and operations process you
might see the change request comes in
it's approved right which needs to be
replaced
ticular take it out put anyone in right
down in development that can be a little
it can look a little longer but you need
to be ready to establish this common
processes an auditor can understand but
it doesn't mean that add additional work
you don't want to add additional
questions and so helping and I don't
understand these are common process
request comes in it needs to be
authorized and unauthorized request now
needs to be developed and tested once
tested appropriately when it passes this
test it is formally approved and then
another party or responsibility then
released
that code there is a concept that an
editor finds sacred and it is
segregation of duties fraud protection
so in this process of building in at
least response
responsibilities will be critical
shots this can be a large challenge
finding someone else that can authorise
or approve it and have sufficient
understanding to be able to prove they
know the lines of code that were changed
but it's something that I would
encourage anyone look for this kind of
process you don't you don't just need to
change tickets for coaching so if you're
in AWS need to make a new security group
or should have something for you as an
organization we want to be able to find
out what did we change what was
different yesterday how can we fix it
access management it's another example
an access request my cum in you have
different systems development you may be
managing their access to LDAP they don't
have control that will change monitoring
the monitoring of these controls
combining development operations again
they may not be considered one of the
big challenges here is if I giving
developers the responsibility or the
ability to start a service from the
ground up they throw together a system
on whatever platform how do I know that
it can be monitor 25 Nagios refined
using any other tool to manage to figure
asians
I need to observe those systems if they
can put anything together I lost control
there is no control of shifted over one
of the considerations
is developing and enforcing standards
standards regarding system requirements
parameters prevent holes in in scope of
the complaints so you know a gold
standard gold image critical in helping
to ensure that controls around monetary
systems right that's so effed I've had
experience initiative the next day we
had a request for a developer for access
to the navy's next day like somebody
died and they were asking for their
couch and I was breakfast but this is
that this can be the Devils intimidation
and is open things that presents
absolutely no challenges the
organization just open it make sure
there's a ticket and they'll be fine
that's not true
yes make sure they take you through with
the organization they need to be on
board they have to understand the risks
make sure you can communicate them
parties so it doesn't do any good to
just say no
have the conversation so from a
compliance perspective if you have a
ticket and track that arise it was
reviewed and approved by the appropriate
party the system owner
than actually and I would come in they
include in their sample that check it
off they would ask probably little
questions about that but if they really
wanted to dive into appropriateness of
the access that's where you need to have
that conversation he be prepared to say
yet what actually is responsible for the
performance of our application developer
but his role is performance of he needs
to be monitoring tables to see how long
queries are taking he's he needs out
that you know that being able to have
this conversation before opening those
access floodgates yeah working with them
outlining what your approach is going to
be outlining certainly the complaints
require they have to know that any time
this happens they're going to need to
take it may be right but understanding
your scope they are going to need to
have some record that this was approved
that we said yes they can have access to
customer data these are required
requirements that you want to hold as an
organization but you may have to hold
and then more complex than that than
just having the ticket the record is how
do you maintain that segregation a
developer can now write and roll their
code what mechanism do you put in place
to check that to make sure that we trust
our developers honestly we we we all
trust our developers that we all make
mistakes are setting up security
parameters are configurations or in
mistakes so what can we do to make sure
that doesn't impact the customer
checking we put in your review is a lot
of large organizations and I have an
interesting their DevOps change
management and logical access to have
peer review in place
and so while yes we say a developer has
access to roll code they're gonna be
triggering that there is there is a
mandatory logical review that happens
that goes from one of their peers who
may have the same responsibilities right
but in that case they are not the
developer rolling code and developing
there there are ways to manage that
logical access and if there is any more
questions about that
happy to those operation certainly a
challenge and endeavour each team on to
manage their own sister talked about
they get to determine how to set that up
the last if you were in here for the
last presentation only got the last
night but it looked like it was about
doctor doctor is fantastic and I i heard
you like doctor doctor for your doctor
they're actually the doctor doctor
doctor doctor then the challenge by
deviating from against standard
platforms coding languages access
mechanisms protocol storage etc
you expose yourself to additional risk
reach outage misuse right so if you're
telling people yet you can set up your
own system wherever just make sure it
works if the customer the role in all
the time they're gonna go grab you know
it'll be PHP Ruby on Rails in some kind
of no sleep all day today I don't know
and there's no standard you can't
monitor it you can't control that
so again we're talking about making sure
that you provide any one of these
responsibilities with automated to
implement a system if they need a server
spun out there click a button that will
help developers certainly if the
developers are leading the developer
stay in compliance up a new service
management rapid release this integrated
production hopefully it means in some
kind of ternary release you have
different levels of production
environments and honestly I didn't
understand that some degree
can't dictate the way that we operate
the way we do business there are best
practices they are smart and secure ways
of doing it but the joke is always made
like I do right on I developed when I do
a development production and development
production is in nineteen what are you
going to do what are you putting in
place consider understanding
authorization execution approval testing
deployment making sure that those pieces
are in place that you have a strong
mechanism for protecting your customers
through this process something breaks
you have a way of putting them in an
environment that isn't broken for the
time being some kind of canary in areas
that they managed and you get the Canary
Build I something's wrong in the mine
mine the gas gas those pieces are in
grow and change me that you have to
maintain them but it can be done in
David's even in releasing the debt
becomes really important developers
understanding requirements their systems
not just the code right the application
of developing on but knowing knowing
something about the systems of those
applications and not only civilian
ticket changes I said that already
repeating myself but submitting tickets
having tickets approved for changes to
their ATM yes environment but whatever
you know wherever it's hosted blades and
the complication facility I don't know
but making sure that you're jacking we
get into some of those additional
criteria availability we just
availability easy thing about
performance deficits as a solution for
that can we just go to the shops where
is made of your account right that can
be there can be like it needs your
reaction
cloud infrastructure outsourcing these
complex cumbersome seemingly costly
process but this may look at this and
say capex right you gotta stand up these
servers that's that's expensive moving
tomorrow in objects they would reduce
costs help them understand that it may
be true it may be true but your
application you need to know that your
system that case you're targeting for
that shift really are cheaper there
running some back in process to keep
their server live all the time and you
can you get twelve thousand dollar bill
and you didn't expect to spend six times
as much as we are right now
help them understand that preferably
before
to remain on death but it struck
management that outage risk there are
out at risk with a cloud has has your
Gmail ever on down has Twitter ever gone
down right just because Netflix Netflix
is a great example right that's a yes
have you ever had problems with Netflix
has it ever gloated slowly or has it
ever have they had an hour just
absolutely so it doesn't solve just
saying I'm going to Amazon doesn't solve
your problems of even redundancy or or
availability need to make sure that
you're in separate regions opening up
new regions you're gonna have customers
say I can't have that in the us- you
have to isolate that right so making
sure that management understands that
it's not as easy as just saying to the
cloud whenever you're opening access to
additional responsibilities roles people
opening up additional risk so it's just
more attack point more laptops
smartphones grabbed and so when we were
thinking about considering what we need
to have in place in this kind of remind
employees about boundaries computer and
device use for seeing strong
authentication is you factor where ever
you can do factor authentication data
integrity I'm gonna skip this one
because it
it's really about input and output and
it over last change management thinking
about it
contact privacy third-party tools again
in a group of teens killed whatever you
call them have the ability to stand up a
system from top to bottom
they're gonna say thats shining and they
say it does what I needed to do I'm
gonna use their now you're putting data
in a third party and how are you
evaluate so here we are talking about a
vendor so critical
customers will care tell us about the
security of your tell us about security
organization great let me explain to you
everything looks good are you putting I
get any third parties but you're ok
we'll have you done in evaluation of it
yes no but I'm pretty sure they're good
but that's not that's not what we can
tell customers in here so it's damaging
amateur vendor review is important
my one caveat there is it's not a one
size fits all again
Lorenzo Cain is the only blanket that
covers everything other than that you
have to do data classification you've
got to educate your customers are you
putting in our appt why is that
important to you when you're evaluating
your vendors what am I putting that out
if its marketing that's just putting
maybe internal communications documents
graphics in Dropbox are you gonna be
evaluating that the same as you do your
nets that has your DL right so making
sure you play some intelligence in doing
that third-party review is critical of
save everyone time it just makes it a
better world
getting to the end you're welcome it
should not jeopardize compliance
consider the disgust conversations with
management and you should be fine and
tackling that ship jobs from wherever
you're at today but it does it does
include a couple of these key takeaways
I wanna bring expected considering the
rest when you are looking at potential
when you're looking at a system where
you're looking at a change endeavor but
this process we really want to do away
with this or something
asking you for access to some system
really think about what's the risk what
is the risk that I don't mean that like
her no I mean think about and how table
this is especially in an area where you
may have had operations responsibilities
security operations even if your
application security make sure you have
a seat at the table you can communicate
to your new management if it is new
management what those security
requirements and compliance requirements
are because they are different
understanding then those requirements
will be key in having the conversation
it's knowing stock to knowing the
criteria is availability on the table is
confidentiality on the table if I'm ISO
20022 I have an eye SMS are we reviewing
all these policies and procedures
annually so now I mean now you know
better than the guys that are doing and
that's from you know it so I think I
think that's probably the most key
takeaway and equip myself because I
thought I would give up for them no
additional risk your decision unless of
course you would consider all the things
that really didn't I did not realize
that I have researched like a stage for
we have two minutes if there are any
questions
be happy to take them otherwise I have
work at this point any questions
a great idea