mathematics and cryptography there's
something wrong with my sides are
licensed under the Creative Commons
Attribution share-alike License this
news that you're more than welcome to
take my presentation modified needs if
you like it just gimme credit also your
final my sides pretty boring I'm not one
of these fancy transition text let's
start with random numbers this is pretty
much going to be the overview of my
presentation I'm going to discuss what
random numbers are and then we'll just
jump right into the three
classifications of random numbers that
pseudorandom numbers to graphically
secure surrounding numbers and then run
the numbers and then we'll talk about
some randomness tests and wrap up was so
why do we need random numbers it turns
out we actually use random numbers quite
a bit in our daily life example lottery
drawings although illegal in City Utah
running out of power
possible in fact generically gambling
Las Vegas are you playing against the
odds that read we also apply very much
in the physical world such as weather
modeling thermodynamics quantum
mechanics randomness fits a pattern
recognition game theory before the
presentation I was showing somebody here
physical contraption called the Dyson
not seen the day somatic to YouTube so
this guy runs a runs games by email.com
and he was using a random number
generator for his dice crews and people
were getting upset and so he ended up
creating this hardware and software
application and he says if you're not
happy with the results he felt that
dates down email it to you and let that
be a lesson so game theory cards online
games like World of Warcraft rely
heavily on Monte Carlo simulations our
way to approximately eight numerical
values using random numbers and then
finally of course record numbers of the
workhorse cryptography we need random
numbers to create unpredictable
random this is a pattern or predict
ability of events without a without
border
otherwise individual unpredictable which
for example of random numbers million we
should not be able to predict the next
is drawn however we generate large
amounts numbers we can start to make
some predictions of some sort of 100,000
random numbers 12 million I can say with
confidence that about one out of every
10 numbers certainly affect loaded on
the number line I could see that ratio
so I can begin to make some say it's
important to separate randomness yes
there is the study of dynamical system
where conditions will determine the
outcome but that doesn't necessarily
mean we can predict we can make some
predictions short term for example
population growth reaching makes an
immediate predictions about the
population and that's as we increase the
next that's really the separation
between here is an animated gif showing
a Monte Carlo simulation
numerical value of pi
we have the unit circle inscribed inside
of a units and then we are generating
random xy coordinates and plugging it in
the square which makes the ratio of the
coordinates inside of the coordinates as
we calculate more and more coordinates
that racial approaches
pseudorandom numbers so random number
generators have four properties that
we'd like to have a must first off sorry
to see a pseudo-random number generator
is mathematical need something to kick
started many of you are probably
thinking but I know not to start my
serial number generator with time
essentially really bad
a random number generators are just to
provide randoms second and then we might
have
an actual discussion had random number
generators also we want them to be
uniformly distributed this means that
number is likely to be out good as there
is no favoritism bias towards one number
either all of the output we want our
pseudo random number generators a random
number generator is treating a secrets
of random numbers earlier friend of mine
just like 10 minutes ago so what's
random about the number 88 well there's
nothing inherently random about any
individual number when you're talking
about random numbers were talking about
a sequence or actual assumptions about
random is individual number itself sure
what about 7777 so that we can start
making assumptions about the generator
so large period is creating a sequence
of repetition three members as soon as
that sequences generated we found this
site we want that period to be as large
and of course there should be no reason
why should have to wait around for my
random number when I request so how do
we create a pseudo-random number
generator here are three methods that
you could do you want to impress your
family and friends Thanksgiving next
three generators the middle square
method for linear tonga winchell
generator and legs
cater to these methods begins with the
end agency did we swear that to get a
two digit zero padding as necessary and
then we take the middle and digits and
use that as the next see the process so
for example here's me taking a four
digit number
473 I swear it to get to 245 1218 take
the middle four digits as my next year
it generated sequence comes out as for
it
1985 5 12 10 so this is the middle
school has a very small period in fact
when this generator fails fails and it
does so by usually 20 this is the common
case of the generator is a number of
other than the middle numbers 2554 10
and some others these two failures make
up the bulk of the failures 0 comments
World generate maybe 10 or 11 random
numbers and then I will cycle back like
the previous 30 get stuck on three
numbers in my site so it turns out this
isn't a very good pseudo-random number
generator you want to do something
better let's look at the generator it
sounds fancy this is really nothing more
than what you
this is just why except reporting module
song it sounded because the numbers are
going to continue to grow at an upper
bound on it keep it going to take a seat
lot so the generators to find as
exhibition plus one equals times
accidental and then we were equals x
plus news as an example for C 27 are
scalar 217 and will do this in my 10 so
our first round one time 74 seed plus
seven or scalar that becomes our new
seat exit 201 times for + 71111 my
tennis 10 new seed right as simple as
why
generate a sequence comes 4845 two
nights its obligations
period is that most the size of the
modulus are . life is going to be the
best numbers and for some choices we do
like the congress generator because it's
faster requires state but its third
point is basically saying it's highly
predictable it will lie in most in fact
royal times and paper planes and
interventions might expect you to
understand that the takeaway is as
predictable wanted to maximize I paid
leave wanted it to be the size of
then we have some requirements and and
the offset the constant be must be
relatively prime that means they share
growth factors 8-1 missed by all the
prime factors of em an 8-1 requirements
are met
year period now my personal favorite the
legs he cannot see generator the legacy
of the nazi generator comes from the
Nazi sequins to ensure all equals 1+2
basically we're taking a 2003 add those
two elements in the results and popped
the first and then we read the new to
almonds in this case we're going to
genera size instead of hard coating that
a rate which would make a larger array
and which are going to be doing missions
we call these the taps so jiang will be
are two types and also we're going to do
a modulus put an upper bound on it to
keep it inside space if you want to
generate audit even numbers that you
will need at least one and even number
that comes through the taps entirely
even numbers that you're going to
generate entirely so you'll want I don't
even have one alright so here is our
form an equal amount of such a process
model or serial so you don't have to
have two types also
three types of properties to go into it
has been looked into and mathematicians
like toward doing the service so let's
start with a seven digit range seed will
use a famous number 8675309 which by the
way as a site that's if you ever use
fresh values card's value membership
cards and they allow you to input a
number to identify your accounts 8675309
really well so just as an FYI
let's go ahead and choose to tax papers
377 so our third element 79 @ DeMott 610
620 haha the first one our third game 6
process it showed us a little bit more
clearly put the third and seventh in
brackets so we can see the generator
what's getting added as someone is the
phone number is 678 913 710 elements
10066 ended eight gets
6753 1961 gets extended sixties pop off
speaking to you right after a suburban S
780 number
so to the seven is 24 8 16 32 64 is 27
to 29 right so are the size of our
period of maximum weigh 127 times 512 in
this weather in order to maximize that
we have to make sure that this second
straight out of the alleged generators
is highly complex as well studied for
those of you with Donald Knuth the art
of computer programming he has done
research to tap generators failed what's
called the birthdays just the transfer
random but research has been done to us
that show that three and four tap and
other tests generators also you're not
stuck with the addition you can you see
traction period
generation are the most popular
pseudo-random number generator is the
default number generator in Python so we
like losing sister because it's fast
others liked when your feedback shift
register to play with Kerry and a number
of others write a cryptographically
secure generators cryptographically
secure generators have the same for
properties distributed we want a large
but we're going to add two more
requirements to make them cryptographic
the church says they must satisfy the
next what this means is the generator
could generate extra flights can
generate a whole massive data and
regardless of how much data you better
accuracy and 50% and no amount of data
beforehand will give you any inclination
it's going to be resumed sister for
example require must withstand
compromise extensions that means to
state the generator is either partially
or wholly compromise we should not be
able to determine the creepiest
generated numbers generator so we know
the current state about the generators
constant ceded that it won't tell us
anything about this because
these are the two requirements for a
cryptographically secure and rebuild yes
first off you generator absolutely must
be here if you are designing your own
algorithm for a generator and you're
using a mathematical function already it
will not be secured just by the nature
and you will be able to predict the next
year but help us existing cryptographic
primitives ciphers or if you want to
design something from scratch the return
address the discrete logarithm problem
or the quadratic these are problems that
are easy to compute the discrete
logarithm problem says I'm gonna take
roots and raise it to expand our prime
modulus if that prime modulus and those
numbers are primitive roots then I will
get an even distribution to all members
of the month for a repeat accounted for
its future series of that Prime
quadratic residue problems just a fancy
way for saying it's hard to factor
numbers if i take 2 prime numbers
multiply them together I get a composite
ACT composite is small but it's not very
difficult for my computer to discover
those factors that affect members
charged that it becomes impractical to
discover so if you can guarantee these
two
computing results the discrete logarithm
problem generator for example here's one
called
shop this is named after the last days
of the generator this is why this
addresses the quadratic residue hace
problem in other words you're trying to
the factors cue from a modulus always
requires a seat and then modulus which
is the product of two primes cue
unfortunately setting up show the primes
must be congruent 23 much that means
that she is the greatest common divisor
whalers cycle actors had the generator
is plus one equals excellence and then
we let accident very simple generator
example nineteen NRC this fall the
previous requirements that I just set
the other side so have a large generator
and then we just go ahead and square 2
seed 209 which is the product of a
weapon 1909 i squared lot 281 and so on
following sequence like this generator
because it guarantees
find it does have that security provided
that are modulus outside
encrypted with an encrypted and continue
in that manner or 256 etcetera
so this means that we're going to
require this is the secret security in
the generators this is where you would
not want to use your time as the G
mister time can be discovered we can
compromise the generator so you want
this to have sufficient entropy again
and then we'll have a secure generator
so here's an example 128
those of you who are familiar with
cryptographic primitives and bauxite
you're probably seeing a bunch of red
flags right now and I'm only gonna be
encrypting one block Teresa this fits
fine because i dont have a second or so
I don't have any structure and it's a
completely new to walk so you see people
who don't have an initialization don't
have a counter
828 bits of zeros its Mikey right and
Casey etcetera and then we go ahead and
just a quick bit 0 with the result
cancer encrypted there's counter script
and so forth
security secure well and also the
private key but it also must have
sufficient trippy he needs to be
unpredictable the unpredictable nature
discovered further because these graphic
primitives using operating binary mode
probably output primary blobs to your
screen to do some coding and that may
head to the overall market another
generator standardized generator by and
see its find in NZ X 917 and its initial
defined by using 64 bit troubled us a
sense been superseded by NZXT 43232
where to find 128 bit AES generator
works in this way and its seed of course
have my private key and then all the
numbers and I want to generate each time
in this I'm going to get it current
precision picosecond I'm going to
encrypt that time stamp to create a
temporary value next step is to
exclusive or the sea as for a reseed
regenerate and you see and I do that
exploring just recently random number
with temporary earlier and that becomes
mucci generated timestamp get him to
tell you about seventeen I ignore the
fact that I am importing some modules
and setting up safe environment
variables and functions rents the
structure of the generator for I in the
range of the numbers I create that
temporary bankrupting the date when I go
ahead and get an output by encrypting
the and the temple and then print out
there but I wrote a Python script to do
this
switches to generate a key I see this is
a standard generator and interesting
side effect you are using this as an
adversary could set your clock and
manipulate the outlet generator there's
been some including myself out tried a
switch cryptographically secure random
number generator in the Linux kernel
with the exit 79 so
question
an NTP service running on the host a
sufficient time
other concerns keep giving some other
cryptographically secure random number
generators blum blum should be addressed
the quadratic residue opposite problem
let me charlie is another one that you
could do by hand
addresses the discrete logarithm problem
last some others like Isaac the inverse
congressman generator rule 34 turns out
the guys not only did businessmen short
mathematician scientist she developed
thirty as a random number generator
where looks chaotic nature there's an
article on it and there is controversy I
wrote as a learning exercise for myself
program I decided to write graphically
secured to the random number generators
so far
node to see guys but projects generated
alright enough with pseudo-random number
generator into true random numbers true
random numbers have a completely
different set of requirements and their
surrender counterparts for stuff to
random number generators must I do not
know
so this means that you're going to need
to do
generator in my generation as well as
you can't verify that the generator is
doing what is aimed toward I know that's
a simple question and I'm not accusing
the agency of your USB port or random
number generator but if you can't verify
the hardware and software you're putting
a lot of trust in someone who's making
such claims that might be sleeping
certainly be using this for long term
cryptographic keys getting stuff you can
verify also the physical phenomena using
for the generation process should
probably also be verified it's really
easy to say yeah this is really two
classifications thoughts are random
number generation discuss the quantum
state things like nuclear decay to get a
Geiger counter on the nuclear source or
sources after a week's time when
particles traveling through a
semi-transparent
shot noise circuits and the case of
reverse transistors and as a result
strikes so on and so forth
resource not even culture is hard drive
by human interaction humans are very
random when they think about it but they
are random in their physical
interactions world for example the
timings between your typing actually
turn out to where you moving the mouse
also have some people as I mentioned
earlier true random number generators
are almost always they are just so they
need to be widened by seeing you talk
about a couple second a statistical
tests on the quality of the random
numbers should always be run as hardware
is degrading the quality of your random
number generators
and of course she was fortunate with
generators is they break meaning that
it's not easily detectable that
generators may be influenced by outside
interference I have a list of guys this
one right here
open hardware Open Firmware Campbell New
Zealand just called the one reading this
uses shot noise one source also has a
2.4 gigahertz wireless antenna range as
a source of rounders I know that this is
being used in infrastructure and I'm
close to the January waves I could
manipulate so while can be a good source
so keep that in mind
simply by see Methods one common way is
the john Dunn normandy by assume this is
at two consecutive bits in the generator
identical we discard them if they are
not identical 101010 we're going out
after the guarantee you will not
guarantee you random white let's say we
go ahead and discard all of our funds
and we're left with 111 111 111 while
technically we did biased generator we
produced very predictable very
predictable stream data so that is
another way to do the biasing whitening
of the random number generator to send
it
graphic primitives IKS shot you could do
six data hardware the output from the
true random number generator becomes the
seed for the cryptographic primitive so
the output of the cryptographic
primitive is still truly randomized
however provided that we have the
necessary security much margins from the
cryptographic primitive we can see that
generator for the data was shot 256
output 256
is going to be some devices are here is
some USP true random number generators
if you're interested if you do it
Wikipedia search for comparison of
hardware random number generators I
actively contribute to value her dollar
per price you see the intel Ivy Bridge
processors later that are here and on
that I would get the most expensive bits
per dollar spent generator the hardware
is closed and there's no guarantee that
missus
Realtek realtek STR software-defined
radio you can use those with an open
source project as $119 per cent
usually close which is an additional
ones they're kinda can I have talked to
me afterwards little baggie mentioned
wondering
readiness test our way to analyze
patterns and runs statistical tests to
see if they meet some criteria that we
know about this is used to judge the
quality of the generator there's a shift
so there's what's called the diehard
tests has a battery of tests that he can
run like the birthdays and then there's
also a userspace entropy s here's a
diehard tests these days facing parking
lot test so forth
hard there's a die harder userspace
utility that you can use I'll go ahead
and use one of my hardware generators
one of these guys will generate a file
of say a megabyte megabyte whatever size
harder on this case I called it and
speed up in and we'll see if he's just
wanted to do with the shape of
considerable time I file looking at
dozens of minutes so that it runs set
aside and see what the FIPS 140 test two
tests a different set of tests
generator
and use an example of tips 140 destitute
there's a user's users and we can see
what we can see that it was roughly 130
megabytes 172 tests 272 successes and
there are two the only difference
is def random will block within the
system thinks that the entropy of the
system as weird as you read it will not
take away from this is really random
numbers which have seen a random number
generators cryptographically secure and
then Sri random number generators each
with their own advantages and
disadvantages we should always be
running randoms generator and whenever
in doubt used a few random that's all I
have are there any comments questions or
remarks
generator generator and then go ahead
and HTML files so any other questions