you gonna do and such just remind
everybody that sank on as a production
of the Utah st. organization did you
haven't had an opportunity while you
were here to learn more about US aid
organization that's sad but at the same
time it's a group of network security
professionals throughout the state of
Utah and beyond now there's members from
all over the place where we share a lot
of information we want to make you aware
of this organization it's free to join
the organization and contribute to be
part of its the glitches that we had in
some other of the sign up and betting
systems have been fixed so if you have
previously tried and haven't heard
anything back those issues are fixed
point of GV doing a lot of weddings over
the next couple of days for sure and so
will you hear back from us one way or
another and then I'm not going to bore
you with the details on how it all works
because we talked about it during the
opener suffice it to say it with a buddy
that's part of me doesn't Organization
help you out
and I'm getting himself and he did
remind me this earlier but if you've
already signed up you don't need to sign
up again we have all that information
the vetting process email system and
other things that we were there we use
wasn't working properly
had taken down two times against you
between Amazon and our server so next
thing appropriately so we want to thank
our sponsors this year
ok that reason why you have a really
cool bags around your neck is because of
the sponsors like this
Cache Valley Electric is active network
management comp unit but nine Aruba
ported checkpoints Adobe CenturyLink
balcom Bluehost and a few others that
have donated either a lot of time like
the Utah Education Network we can't run
a conference with five UN employees
being on the committee without the union
organisation don't get a lot of our time
to prepare for this conference but it's
these vendors it's these people that
make it to do things like the Badgers
that allows us to buy the audio-visual
equipment this year that we needed to
make sure that nobody here's a sweetie
Mike ever again
we appreciate their involvement of some
time to visit them out there in the
vendor Expo will only let them come for
two days some of my be here today still
only let them set up their wares and
talk to you guys for two of the days
officially so that you don't get
overwhelmed with it but at the same time
it compresses it down so you can go
visit them you have two days to do it
and it doesn't interfere too much with
the conference because we like to be
vendor-neutral as much as possible here
with a lot of the products you won't see
many product recommendations come from
any of the lease the space the
committee's stocks the next people that
need thank you and a big round of
applause for these folks
not only donated the venue that we've
used for the last number of years but
this year as well as ellison the room
good it is not that I can see this
outlook and just say that he's got a lot
of employees that a lot of nights and
weekends but probably a few hours during
the day as well helping make this
conference possible the badge ranging
networks of other things these guys have
done an incredible job for us and it's
kind of sad that we're probably not
going to be here next year to continue
to to take a full benefit of weaver
takes university's hospitality but will
most certainly continue to use their
employer resources right and then I want
to thank you the attendees for coming
for spending your time a little bit of
your money to come here to learn
something new to experience something
new and such because truly what makes
income possible what makes it important
really gives us the drive to continue to
do something that is becoming big
unwieldy and requires more time than it
used to
so the next thing is really quickly a
plug one more time for the survey so
this is how we continue to make sank on
as cool as it is we pick your feedback
for positive and the negative and we do
our very best to make sure that anything
you guys so telling us it's considered
as we do planning for the following year
we learn things along the way we have
learned this year that 600 people up to
the conference and everybody comes on
that first day of the second at nine
o'clock in the morning everybody sitting
down there the parking lot still trying
to get a shuttle over to the conference
and the first three talks of the day are
pretty empty we've learned a lot of
other things along the way that we take
back what we want to make sure we're
getting your input so please take the
time to the love that survey I would sit
as prizes involved and it's raining over
here so it's not ringing sorry this is
the Twitter buzz going on
that's right actually let me stop there
just caused aids and up per second
this guy must be on Twitter 24 hours a
day because within seconds of sync on
twenty something he's favored it and
then retweeted it like those of you that
have access to those types of social
media things we'd love to get the word
out about the conference or one of the
other reasons why we think that it's
growing there's a couple of questions in
the survey so we can validate some of
those resolves once again I want to
thank the AV guys they've done an
incredible job this year making this
work
do it this year there were very few that
we didn't represent presentations as
time goes on we're gonna be a little bit
more selective we've got some great
speakers we've got some excellent
speakers in the event that you were
choosing whether to get talks going on
talks going on and I can only be in one
place the time we did our best this year
to talk and I think that we did it with
a few minor exceptions with audio issues
and some other things and so within a
couple of weeks to give you a deadline
we're gonna go through gonna post
produce all of those and make sure that
they have leapt out I'm sure there
weren't very many bad words like I said
damn a couple of times in mine
talk them out but will also make sure
that you know all of the leaders on both
ends and stuff them and make them public
it'll be the first person to have all of
the talks out there for you to watch so
you don't miss a darn thing so that drew
right there said that given that no
troops they work together to make this
happen and it was quite the themes of
class
talk about $1,000 and that's what's
coming next year so we moved ahead but
successful and we're awarding the prize
to the group that got through it the
best and so would the 2nd L
you know who you are come up because
they want may come up to the room at the
registration table gonna take a look at
them you didn't say it im gonna explain
real quick how it works you would go to
the challenges of physical security to
defeat motion sensors to take you a few
doors and all kinds of other things and
alternately successful teams ended up
with the bags tamper-proof bag that had
a USB stick in it than just a password
hash but they had to crack to prove that
they were able to get into the back and
then they were instructed to bring the
bag back to us and handed to us as if it
hadn't been tampered and so you can see
top of the line
bags that we used these guys did an
incredible job back sixty one of them
and we were elected out there and nobody
was able to find out how they got into
it but they were able to get into the
back taxes the USB and pull the
information often correct password did
it seriously we had to ask for seconds
late so we wanted to be really really
might roll holes and so we started with
some lanting needles were 3333 knows
that that's not gonna work right up and
everything
videos so then we switch to 26 TH plants
needles
so we're looking at different places in
the corner turns out the deep purple
blush ability to do a little bit of
nasty with actually just a tiny bit
smaller building tracking mechanism if
you try to do too much so that's that's
what we did a little jig hook it up
immediately Friday $200 to do it all 33
of us now really confused like 11 talk a
trip to the sporting good store for some
for us but what we're doing is tapping
the USB through the bag
supports USB so holding the bag training
get it just right without creating
sitting there trying to get the USB to
work just fine and
rig was awesome speaking of videos that
need to be edited so what we have $200
on this challenge we've got $30 rubber
duckies can separate them up here but
the only thing you can tell they're just
tiny little ridges on the top of this
completely inspections we didn't see it
we didn't feel it in their hands and so
on so now the runners like ok them to
prove that they got into the back of the
other group member he just keeps
whatever
to come up with a group named pretty
quick and so whatever came out these
guys did the second best the Glee the
same but they did a slightly different
strategy I won't make them explain it
but we got a little prize for them as
they did is it took advantage of it in
the bag when you seal it if you don't
just perfectly rigid and so they used
that thing and get out there and then
that just held it together and we get
that one but it took us awhile so they
get these really cool wireless devices
i'm happy to say that because they
donated all the stuff to us
failed miserably because you guys open
up the bags to be true we did go through
and we had the layman people come by the
had no idea of a construction was says
hey do you see any evidence of the speed
tampered with and there were some the
past the lame and muster mustard let's
just hope mustard people to $1 cecile
that's all good and so for the most part
we got back as somebody wasn't looking
the the contour the seal or whatever the
was violated nobody would have known we
got some great submissions back ahead
wanna talk about one and only two goals
never mind that there's one black thats
contest will probably expand that in the
next couple of years with the time and
energy we're going to put into expanding
the bolts and what it's going to be
tempered evident kind of challenge that
we're going to actually break out of its
own accord next year
probably have a couple of extra black
badges were gonna work next year but so
rewarding one black bad for a year to
the winner of that game so to announce
the winner is everything else going by
Josh Galvez a master to come up
201 key prints hours available to the
game open or close during those hours
there are only two hours they fighting
and window with one key was tried
so the key to open their 2011 the board
one of them was a black box challenge
challenge at the end but with the new
division method in this method the game
we had a lot of competition between 2nd
3rd in the top that it was a lot of
pride
it was a 100 200 300 points you can this
year opened 1,000 points and then your
we had six codes committed so bored with
62 points there was one getting
challenged called challenges that were
scattered to the conference
34 policy Live On the Border Agency and
I had a lot of help
so good job
good job
background and security guy this guy
just barely he's a senior in high school
has not graduated yet
greatest tool toy whatever there's a
land turtles if you haven't seen these
are really cool so no room whatever you
want with that relations later
together and give Josh a round of
applause we talk a little bit about
future because the size the logistics
and other things we've decided that
worked
very likely I can't say they're likely
going to move the location of sync on
next year and right now we're looking
for that site to be probable help some
people believe some of the travel for
some increases the level of travel for
others but we feel that there's a number
of different reasons to move the
conference some of the ones we talked
about it just needs to move so that
makes it easier for certain people have
been here for a long time
the logistics the room that we're going
to be growing into to build an entire
room next year's gonna require a lot of
room and so we limited what we can do it
here because of prior code and some of
these other issues and such so I want to
talk about that from Provo city and if
we really can't believe we might be back
here next year but we were still has
agreed to let us come back if we need to
talk about first of all
we want to thank all in tears
we actually had a list that we could
pull some people have people with
registration and things our nice was it
on Tuesday morning to not stand in line
with 400 people want to your badges
right that's because of the volunteers
and things we did that almost nobody
stood in line at all for registration
they did incredible job and they were
hiding in the background doing the
things they need to do to make the
numbers on the smoothest so there's a
couple of first time ever to talk about
it for the first time ever I V word all
the way we had some major mess up with
registration of other people that need
to be recognized during the opener
but there is a lot that goes into sync
on there's registration their sponsors
wrangling the sponsors of helping them
how ministration things that hardware
there's executive track things that you
can see on the screen and these are the
people who made it possible and I'd like
to invite all committee members come up
here
above and beyond the call of committee
this year we've already awarded Clint is
partnered black patch over here we would
like to also award a black best the
designer of the hardware
we will be responsible it's really worth
it I promise
we would love for you guys to respond
and perhaps be part of the committee we
might actually shrink the size of a
little bit next year kick some totally
mean that as a joke
everybody was exceptional this year just
to give you an idea we met every single
week
months we met every other week the
months prior to that and we met multiple
times together to talk about what we're
going to do to make some comments
cool and the successful as possible they
didn't credible job that but i just want
to make sure you guys understood what
has been put into this opportunity again
to thank you guys for being here
we've had a lot of fun it's been great
for us the Twittersphere continues to
blow up on my stand up here and so
obviously Davis doing something happy
enclosing a little weird but if you have
some time to donate we would love for
you to stick around and help us with
navy tear down and things are a lot of
people have been here since Sunday
morning ensure that everything is
working so a little bit of a long way to
give you some guidelines for that I just
wanted to say we don't need to put his
stuff in boxes take cables electrical
cables holding up nice things
accomplished them all the files will
have our EV group kind of sort through
them and put them where they need to go
that might be broken and damaged you
might just leave there and let them take
care of such but your help would be
appreciated so these guys have been here
forever and go home to their families
enjoy the rest of the week weekends and
such and that's that's all the slides
thats the end of the show we appreciate
you being here and we'll see you
somewhere next year
together