all right I am here to talk about a tool
I wrote a little earlier this year and
just released called icebreaker it's a
Python tool for getting a foothold on
Active Directory networks my name is Dan
McInerney I'm a senior pen tester and
researcher at coal fire Coal Fired it'd
give me quite a bit of time paid to work
on this which is what I'm giving them a
shout out about half of it was my own
time half was about coal fire time I've
been with them for a few years and
that's my github dan McInerney pretty
simple it's one of the top 100 most
popular Python accounts in the world
just going to give myself a little pat
on the back there this is the overview
of the tool so in order to set it up all
you do is get clone it and then you CD
into the directory and run the setup
script after you've run the setup script
you do pip end which is a new Python
packaging tool which makes it easier to
use virtual environments and that way it
doesn't mess up your system quite so
much and then hit them shell and then
you can actually run the tool
one issue that icebreaker has I'm going
to start off with the disadvantage is
the installation process takes a while
so if you're on a low resource machine
then it can take I mean low resource
with bad internet connection you're
looking at like a half an hour for the
install or more so I'm working on
getting this docker eyes anybody wants
to help me with that I don't know
anything about docker but they were just
gonna make this a lot easier to install
the script is largely just glue between
already known techniques and attacks
it's not brand new research or attacks
it just makes the whole process of
getting Active Directory plaintext
passwords a lot easier this is sort of
the the base I'm not gonna do a lot of
Python code teaching here but this is
sort of what it's what it's based on
sub-process is a library for python that
lets you make system calls now I'm sure
if any Python East Azure in here you're
probably looking at that and thinking
you know that's not all that impressive
you're you might as well just use a bash
script if you're just calling a system
calls but there's a lot of complexities
I added into this that that make it
worthwhile to do it in Python namely
asynchronicity so I can do concurrent
programming I can
test usernames concurrently in parallel
so there's a bunch of reasons for why I
wrote this in Python not just a silly
little batch script but this is the the
basis of how it works it's calling other
tools and then I also have the whole
thing packaged up so all those tools
come with icebreaker you don't have to
go out and manually get clone responder
and get clone ready nom and all the
tools that use this everything just
comes already built in
including the password cracker so it
comes with John the Ripper it will
automatically compile that through the
setup script that way it's just nice and
simple the installation is not anything
farther than running the setup script
Pip and Ben stall and pip bombshell so
it does five different Network attacks
the scenario that you want to use
icebreaker for is when you are on an
internal network that's Active Directory
but you don't have any passwords so like
you're just a Kali Linux box on an
internal network but you have no access
to the Active Directory environment
whatsoever this will get you access to
the Active Directory environment it does
five different attacks to get plaintext
credentials and ntlm hashes which are
the equipment more or less the
equivalent of passwords the first attack
is the nice simple and fast rid cycling
into reverse brute-force so reverse
brute-force is when you take a short
list of names
I'm sorry short list of passwords and a
long list of names and you just test
those that short list of passwords
against those names the reason we're
doing that and not an actual brute force
is because brute forces tend to lock
systems out so we are doing just two
passwords per username the way it finds
user names to actually brute force is a
it looks for null sessions in all SMB
sessions and be it will if you give it
like a domain name it'll go out to that
domain names great email addresses and
then use the email the first half of the
email address as the username because
that's pretty common in corporate
environments so rid cycling is pretty
cool it hunts for null sessions first of
all no SMB sessions are when you can
connect to a remote Windows computer and
query it for information and stuff
through the SMB protocol you can query
it for usernames what you do is
something called read cycling so every
account on the computer will have a SID
and a Sid is a thing
you already identify or something and
it's a big long string of numbers and
letters and at the very end it'll say -
and then a number and the first number
that it starts out is 500 that's the
built-in local admin so the SID is this
long string - 500 that's local admin the
users will start at a thousand so it'll
be a little bit longer number - 1000
will be a user and you can ask through
null sessions what is the user name of
this person with the grid is that final
number the SID is the full thing rid is
the final number what's the user name
with that final writ and you can just
cycle through all the ribs because you
know they start at 1000 so you can just
start on 1000 and go up to like 50,000
and get everyone's user names that's how
it finds user names then we
asynchronously test all of these user
names using two passwords and these are
the most effective two passwords on ADA
environments that I have ever seen and
I've been working in a tea environments
for years it's password with an at and a
zero and it's season and year like
spring 2018 so this tool has built-in
capabilities to detect what season it is
and then it'll automatically look for
password user names that allow the
password spring 2018 but right now you
know last season they would say winter
so it's not statically spring 2018 it's
whatever the actual season is is how
this will work
you can also use a custom password list
I'd like just stick into the first two
those first two passwords are extremely
effective if you can get a long username
list man I'm gonna say like if you can
get maybe 30 to 50 users there's a
excellent chance that one of those two
passwords is going to pop back out which
is fantastic and then you have the
plaintext cred for a username and then
you can you know pump those creds into
bloodhound and work your way through if
you want to do that you a synchronously
tests it using I think 10 different jobs
at once so it's pretty fast it does that
attack first because of that that attack
is generally pretty fast this is what it
looks like in use you can see it'll say
you we're doing attack 1 we're checking
for no no sessions it found an old
session on tend up 2.0 to 99 which then
gives it the domain name it also gives
it the user names and it brute forces
them pretty quick
the second attack it does to get
plaintext to get passwords is the SCF
attack this is one that a lot of people
actually don't seem to know this is
probably the most what's the word I
don't know rarest known attack that uses
but it's really simple Windows has a
strange file type called SCF it stands
for shell command file and I keep
wanting to say SDF file but that's like
saying ATM machine the SCF is a very
short file that you can tell it to find
an icon somewhere in the network
normally these files are used for things
like opening up Explorer just simple
little things like that open Explorer to
a certain folder like silly little
things I'm not even sure why this exists
but you can tell it to have an icon
inside the file and if you tell it to
have that icon hosted on your own
attacking machine whenever someone opens
a user file share that has this SCF file
on it their SMB hash is being sent to
you which I don't get it it's it's
absolutely ridiculous but it is the way
Microsoft did it so Microsoft patched
this only for Windows 10 it is not
patched for Windows 8 or 7 or you know
any of these other ones
so what Icebreaker does after does a
reverse brute-force finds username to
the reverse brute force will say it
doesn't find anything it moves on to
attack - attack - it's gonna find all
anonymously readable and writable
Network share it's actually just
writable not necessarily readable but
all anonymously writable Network shares
and it will upload an SCS SCF file an
SDF this is what it looks like
it just says shell command - and the
icon files where it actually matters
that's the attacker machine that's my
machine the Icebreaker machine so we'll
tell it so we'll upload that file to all
the file shares anytime anyone opens up
that file share
they don't even click this link they
don't have to click on this file they
don't have to even know this file exists
they just need to open the file share
where this thing is held and you have
their SMB hash so Icebreaker you can't
actually pass a net ntlm hash which is
what you're gonna get from this you can
crack it though so icebreaker
automatically does password cracking
anytime it gets any kind of net ntlm
hash it'll automatically try and crack
it using a custom word list and that
custom word list comes from the github
account SEK lists I took every password
insect lists and then I
got rid of everything that was under
seven characters over 32 characters all
lowercase all uppercase all numbers all
that's gone so now the password list is
down to about a million passwords and
they're all default ad compliant we
don't want to be testing passwords like
one two three four five six that's not
valid on default ad environments so we
have this nice short concise password
list that only works that's very
specific to Active Directory environment
so that makes password cracking much
much faster this is what it looks like
in action it'll just say rideable share
found succesfully wrote it
it'll make sure that the file is
uploaded by then querying the file share
to see if the file is there and they'll
say all right great everything worked
great now we're just gonna wait for
someone to open that file share attack
number three again the first two attacks
are currently fast just expect a minute
or two of the SCF one doesn't even take
a minute attack number three to linger a
little bit this is where it's gonna be
doing responder responder is a really
cool poisoning tool that Laurel Gaffey
wrote I don't know if I'm saying that
right but it sounds French someone
pronounce it like that
he wrote it to do poisoning for
multicast and broadcast based protocols
multicast and broadcast broadcast
protocols are protocols that send out
messages to either the whole subnet or
just some of the subnet but it sends out
messages kind of just like blown out
there on the network for whoever wants
to receive them all of these protocols
eliminar and BTN s and M DNS are all
basically DNS they attach an IP address
to a host name which means you can
poison them just like DNS you could be
like you know their computer spits out a
request for hey who's at you know slash
slash Google you know who's got the
computer at Google you can be like I got
Google and they look oh great well
here's my net NT lan hash and you're
like okay thanks a lot the responder is
used in the background of icebreaker to
poison these protocols and because all
these protocols implicitly trust the
responses a piece of cake to poison them
what you get out of responder are net
ntlm version two hashes again you do not
get hashes that you can pass you can't
just take the net ntlm hash and then use
that in place of a
password but that's okay because
icebreaker will automatically crack it
this is a kind of how L eliminar and NB
TNS poisoning works it's pretty simple
you're basically just man in the middle
of them
computer sends out a packet you respond
to it you respond to it faster than the
than anybody else and this is what it
looks like in action so you can see the
ntlm password is that long long string
of numbers and letters there it says Bob
lab Bob's username labs the domain and
you can it ice breaker ice breaker will
automatically crack that you can also
skip cracking if you don't want your
resources to be used on that you just
use the - s flag to skip any of these
attacks so you can like just use the SCF
attack if you wanted to or just the NT
line relay but it'll try and crack it
and you'll notice here it's using john
the ripper and it found the password
which was of course p @ sign SS w0 r v
one of the most common ones the fourth
attack is the one that i think is the
most effective this is the one where
icebreaker if it lingers on attack 3 for
10 minutes by default it'll just run
responder and wait 10 minutes for two
captures and hashes if nothing is found
or ten minutes is up it'll move on to
attack 4 which is ntlm relay ntlm relay
is an awesome awesome attack it works in
I would say the majority of Windows
networks for getting passwords and
command execution as a local
administrator which is really what
you're looking for this is a man of the
middle attack gift SMB connections two
computers are connecting over SMB and
they're sharing files back and forth or
they're just pulling information about
the system SMB is the file sharing
protocols it's pretty simple and so
we're going to be using ntlm relay X
from in packet to be doing the ntlm
relay so what we are going to be doing
is essentially running responder and
ntlm X at the same time so we're
poisoning the SMB protocol so when the
computer calls out hey where is exchange
you'll be like imma it'll it'll go
connect to the actual exchange server
but you are going to be right in the
middle of that connection so you can
hijack that connection after you hydrate
the connection you can get the net ntlm
version 2
password credentials our password hash
and then you can just relay that to a
machine so net ntlm version two Pat
hashes you can't pass but you can relay
so you can take the hash that one
computer sent validly to another
computer and then you pass that hash to
that computer and tell it to run your
commands there's a few caveats with this
one though
number one SMB version one has to be
enabled I believe by default now Windows
10 no longer has that enabled it's still
enabled ok fantastic Thank You Microsoft
it has to have SMB version 1 enabled and
you have to have SMB signing disabled I
believe that I'm not sure if Windows 10
now has that enabled by default too but
it hasn't been enabled for the last
several versions of Windows SMB signing
actually slows down the network
connection by about 15 percent so
there's a valid reason why you would
want to disable it so it's disabled all
the time especially in older systems so
once you have those two caveats met then
ntlm relay is just gonna go ham all over
the network so NTM ntlm hash is the top
hatch net ntlm version 2 is the bottom -
you'll see the net ntlm version 2 is
what they use for usually network
services that are communicating with
servers ntlm hashes are what's actually
stored on the computer in LCS so those
are the hashes that you can just pass
like a password and then net until i'm
hash you cannot pass that you have to
relay that one you'll notice the net
ntlm hash also includes the username and
domain that is part of the hash so if
you're trying to crack these in hashed
out yourself you need to include admin
colon colon lab you can't just have the
actual hash data there and this is kind
of what a net ntlm hash looks like it'll
start with the username and then I'll go
to the domain and then I'll go to the LM
hash which is disabled pretty much 100%
of the time you'll never really get a
valid LM hash and then you'll get the
actual ntlm hash it's a challenge
response protocol which is why you can't
pass it you can only relay it
so there's there was a bit of confusion
for the last few years about exactly
what the passing the hash accounts you
can use and it turns out as of today you
can pass the hash with the local
built-in administrator account but rid
500 you cannot pass the hash with the
other administrators on the box that was
a Microsoft patch they called it the
pass the hash patch but it wasn't I mean
you can still pass the hatch you just
need to use the red 500 so Microsoft you
know I don't know blowing smoke up you
can however pass the hash with other
administrator accounts if you set a
registry key that register key is in
local machine filter administrator token
so if you have admin access to a box you
can just set that key to be one and now
you can pass the hash for everybody
which is pretty cool yeah if you want to
read more about this harm joy has a blog
that is extremely good there's a little
link there I doubt you can read it but
I'll post the slope slides publicly so
you can do that later if you want to but
he goes into a exceptional detail about
the pass the hatch patch that Microsoft
put out and why it's just a piece of
crap this is how Intel and relay works
so you've got one computer negotiating
authentication with another computer you
are in the middle of that so you are
going to copy the server challenge pass
it back the server challenge is gonna
send it to you you pass that over to the
actual valid to the