are you everyone welcome to our first
talk we have Stefano who will be
discussing as it says tales from the apt
world I Stefano is a malware researcher
with RSA and I let him take it away ok
you hear me right ok thank you very much
guys and I also a always I hope in any
conference I just apologize for my
spaghetti English but but of our that we
will cover today one of the
investigation I ran recently it's
related from an attack to huge and I say
huge logistic organization carried out
by ad I knew or at least not yet quite
know i PT a PT group and this attack was
showing interesting news in terms of
strategies in tactics and tools so it
was definitely an argument that I want
to discuss way with a in a conference
like this Thank You Raj so the first
step of the investigation started with
an anomaly recorded in San Paulo in
Brazil from understanding users in a in
a logistic warehouse where it was
loading some Lost & Found items of the
expedition that were recovered by people
in the war rise so during the late shift
this guy was in charge of loading this
type of information and it was basically
accessing the website as usual the
website is basically the front end of
the data is that it shared to the world
the world the world organization the
organization is present in about 100
different countries so it's really huge
but when he was attempting to load info
into into their website it was having
problem because
every time he went into sending
something from the from the UI it was
coming with errors with strange errors
about sequel database so either side
simply to stand an email to his boss
saying this is a technical problem I
definitely can't finish this so I will
probably shift this activity to the next
to the next colleague the for only one
was having the same problem and at one
point the boss the the following day
will escalate the problem internally to
the help desk the escalation took two
days to pick up and because it was not
really a critical system but the app
desk found accessing the system that
obviously was the internal at this the
backend lots sequel logs were disabled
that is not normal because the standard
is to keep the three days of logs
available for any database in this
organization and through the analysis
they discovered that number of logins
from a service account that it was not
related to the system but pertaining to
a different web server in the same data
center were recorded into this so you
know it was escalated at this point to
the sock people and with the initial
triage they ran in the initial analysis
Neron they discovered that there were a
number of strange artifacts into the web
server from where the sequel database
was accessed so the initial analyzed
come from analysis confirmed they
suspect compromised and they will start
to collect some some items from from
this situation but in the end the people
there was not able to correlate events
and items they discovered because they
were evilly packet so they decide to
escalate the problem to to our to our IR
team that is already was already having
a contract with them for escalation of
the second and third tire
so we pick up the Nicole and we pick up
the analysis on October 23 and we
definitely started with the items that
they were showing us and they have they
have collected before us so we were a
being a DMZ machine from where some of
the traffic was generated strange
traffic the sample over session and the
the sequence server so the DMZ machine
was the sensor or for the initial
speculation because was the web server
and was having a number of different
item interesting item we started from
this point and we asked the customer
basically to give us visibility of
systems in the Brazilian data centers
using our tool I'm not just telling you
guys I'm not ads I mean I'm not a sale
guys this is not because it's our say it
would be ok if there is any other type
of tool I mean last week I went into
Detroit present a triage make buy make
through claim IV so just to let you know
about that but anyway we were looking
for system visibility we were already
having instead network visibility
because the solution of RSA was already
deployed into the sium environment so we
extended the full packet collection on
other eyes on other areas of the network
not normally touched by this and we
deployed us forensic tool in about
20,000 21,000 OS in few days obviously
we collect active active covered but
initial attribution was not possible for
a number of reason I would discuss with
you guys
so forensic analysis make by the other
team show at the presence of a number of
strange PHP file drop it on August 27 on
the web server collecting the logs of
the web server the team identified a
number of as no number of machines of
the development and maintenance
accessing the web server forensic
analysis of this machine granted the
identification of another
compromise for session and the
creation/modification date of the
suspicious file show it that these were
session was infected later than the
webserver analysis on the other DMZ
server on the same block confirming the
compromised I mean the lateral axis of
the sequel database and the compromise
what in September 13 2017 so these are a
number of items that we collected
immediately after we have been engaged
by the customer we were just looking to
extend the analysis collecting all the
items that were around this segment of
time already presented by the customer
and by thanks to that we have been able
to collect these items over their vast
majority is a mimikatz variance I mean
number of minutes files but also nettle
scanner develop it in go
that was really peculiar I mean there
are a number today of go developing
malware but this one was not yet known
anybody I mean compared to our
knowledgebase it was not firing any
correlation and an NBP scanner that was
in fact a common open-source tool but
that we recomm pilot for a proper a
proper capability to sneak through
antivirus and the last one was the
windows credential editor still an open
source project are very easy to collect
from Internet okay we start to focus on
the web server and between the PHP
content with the scholar these strike
from the collection there is nothing
related to the to the system it was just
a downloader this one is the downloader
if you execute this page you basically
can tell through the page to the web
server to collect and download on it
a file simply and it was used by the
attacker to collect is Arsenal and to
move this arsenal of tools in
the system luckily for us we win able
through the network packet decoder of
witness to collect the initial sequel
injection of that day the 27 of August
where the attackers start the infection
basically he check for to upload a file
a C dot txt in a in a folder of the web
server to a sequel injection that you
can notice I lighted by red and it was
succeed it was successful in in doing
this however because the web server was
indexing the content with dynamic in
different pages after that he started to
look to the page that it has uploaded
the C dot txt and so he started to spend
some time it would take about five
minutes but still he spends some time to
go search for d c-- dot txt and once he
found it he know that the sequel
injection was ok was working so from
that moment on I started to upload is
real stuff
C dot XT was simply the coin is a it was
written one two three four it's empathy
brother and the following one was a
china shop or china chopper is really
known everybody in the IR feel probably
if with a minimum experience of apt as
already faced the China shopper so I
don't want to spend much time on this
Chinese chopper is over very powerful
it's common you can download it you can
collect it you can even yes for the
client-side or for the web you can just
collect the script that is available in
a number of different web site and just
drop this in a file and executed so and
load it so from the perspective of China
chopper there is not much to say apart
that the following step in in infection
was to drop the web shell and to start
it in a system unfortunately because
this traffic was into the wool container
of the HTTP traffic that was not
targeted by our technology as potential
malicious at the beginning we were we
were not able to continue collect the
other items after the the web shell drop
in so the other would be robust waste
because normally our technology have our
attention about one or two weeks so this
was a more than amount however bits in
the file immediately dropp'd with the
downloader I mentioned before into the
web shell powered web site it was this
SS dot exe that is a back door and this
vial was was phone found into the web
server but was not active
there was no tracking data of these but
immediately move it into the world
session immediately well take some time
he move it through the word session and
in our session he started to use it at
the beginning this file was packet and
it was potentially not needed malware
analysis normally we tend to use malware
analysis especially for packet even if I
executable only once we have the time at
the beginning of the engagement we were
running out of time I mean we were
considering all the chances of the
compromise we were more interested in
identifying other occurrences so the
first thing we went to to do is yes
analyzing it dynamically but not spend
much time into reverse for a moment just
because we need just to understand how
it works so it works in a way that is
similar to net cut more or less but it
has some it has some very interesting
feature if you run it through the H flag
it show you all the potential options
okay and if you put it in listening with
the L flag is basic
a simple server I mean I'm a simple
vector but if you try to collect connect
to this vector and in send parameters it
doesn't work it means that if you run
this file as a simple backdoor it
doesn't work as you expect like a net
cut or other type of vectors like that
so he requires additional elements I
don't want to waste time with this we
will discuss a little bit later but
instead if you put in Reverse as a rest
shell immediately it works so once we
discover that and you can notice between
in our lab this is obviously now we
identify this and we start to beginning
to the occurrences of this into the
packets okay looking for other
commonalities of this behavior in other
the first thing that jumped to our eyes
immediately after unpacking the bower
was that it was the coded in go okay go
is not a new for an hour the first real
powerful go power read the development
hour was the demeanor I bought net a few
years ago but however is a something a
little bit new in the field of malware
to have the development in go running
but these days I noticed a number of
these occurrences from the perspective
of the malapa there are some valid
reason to to coding go first of all it's
difficult to the compile it's difficult
to do the worse at the beginning because
there is no real the batter and the
compile needs to be configured
accordingly into either pro or other
tapped a compilers but also the symbols
also the the configuration of the of the
strings and the communion a common
elements are not really really immediate
to understand at least for me that was
not really exposed to to the go second
tool is the enmity scanner this one is
obvious I mean it's basically like
and map with the chance to it's very
small compared to net to blend map sorry
but it got the chance to generate an
output that is possible with other
script or with other tools so this is
the reason why they use this instead of
SSS SSS dot exe in general to scan for
example net buyers share so this is a
common and easy to collect file so there
is nothing in trees that is really
peculiar but still useful to know
sixty-four dot exe and en dot ps1 where
two different flavors of of mimic ads we
know mimic ads we know our rewards I
don't want to spend much time on these
the only thing that was obviously
interesting is that the en dot ps1 was
stupid it's a common power sploit tool
for the poor democrats but it was stupid
of all the strings and common items that
normally are used by the antivirus to
identify the file so good from them to
think about it and in fact it what is
nicotine into systems easily not noticed
by the antivirus of the code however up
to this point not in you I mean okay
scanners mimikatz
but difficult to attribute these to
anybody because every not only apt group
but even this is common cyber criminals
know about these tools and know how to
to manage this so we were looking to
something you know bigger something more
interesting something more capable of
attribution and classification to
understand better where they were
looking for in our I speak as a team in
our previous experience with apt reward
we normally know more or less what what
is the goal of the attacker based on the
type of field
the victim is is working on okay but
this is logistics guys it's not like
aerospace it's not like defense is not
like
political institutions is a a logistic
company that move boxes from one place
to another
okay I went into another engagement a
couple of years ago where Iranians
breaches rigid and environment there was
a a night fly company a common area
company okay travel company they jump
there just to access databases where the
passport are recorded because they were
attempting to infiltrate people showing
record different than the one shown at
the airport to the guys on the desk okay
so it was it was difficult to attribute
I mean it was difficult to think at the
beginning because it was complicated to
understand the flow that goes into this
system that was not into the company but
was just connected to the company okay
but this one was extremely more
complicated because there is no chance
to start with something even when we
asked manager who can target you okay
cyber criminals yes totally okay because
credit cards are in in a number of these
databases in a number of transaction so
yes but the way they behave the way they
target this particular data center this
particular set of machine was not really
Brazilian cyber criminal gang okay
it was difficult to attribute to them so
we start to dig in a little bit into
into the question and by generating a
number of IOC based on SS dot exe and
based on the other items we basically
discover a number of other occurrences a
number of other tools these are
explained like they're there okay some
of them apparently are not really
malicious I mean this sandbox II DLL was
the problem I mean it's also often used
as the first layer of protection sandbox
II especially for the browser in a
number of situation I noticed this so
but in this case there were not
there were no the entire sandbox G
application running in the system just a
number of dialects and on adjust one
executable so and it was not the entire
executable and not the entire deployment
of sandbox
however there were others like the bug
as V dot exe that was another malicious
- evilly packet using VM protect to
encrypt very complicated to reverse and
there was this strange file that was
explored dot DLL okay explored the DLL
there is also a version that is a
legitimate okay but this was not
compared to the real one totally
different so we start to think okay hmm
these tools are and these items are
strange but we go forth we move to this
war station where all the real problems
were generated because this was session
was extremely active in in the last 30
days since the beginning of the
engagement so that since the beginning
of the attack sorry so going there we
found another of additional items but in
general to where the folders where the
infection was recited one was in see per
clock not not you and another in Windows
the back deeper analysis on the system
so it that immediately after attacking
these this box
the attacker remove every long okay it's
kind of like putting a sign to the
entities basically from this system a
number of lateral axis where executed
this was against the file server that
was shared between the were station and
the systems in the Brazilian the in the
Brazilian environment not the data
center but the internal between what
session okay we were considering the
chance that the beginning of the
infection of the war session was done by
windows exploit windows burner ability
net buyers vulnerability something like
that but a number of problems
we're negating this possibility
especially one this the the DMZ and the
internal system were segregated by tires
of firewalls and SMB was not available
so net buyers was not a chance
for this ok so we start beginning to and
thanks to the WMI scripts and the new
forensic tool we were able to identify
the execution of basically SS dot exe
the tracking of SS dot exe that started
from the drop of these tool and all the
Arsenal in the dot file from a java
application so definitely they have used
a vulnerability of java to achieve the
construct this box and in fact they
abused the the actually known cv 2017 10
346 that is basically a vulnerability
for the old version of java and this
machine was running 1.6 so old okay
where you basically force through
drive-by download the infection of the
machine you just need to create a page
rising a java exception into the machine
rising the java virtual machine the
Machine goes and then you can be able to
you know interact with the system all
other items discovered into the system
into the were station a number of other
accesses but true in particular were
important one access to the AES VM a DSM
console of the aasa' firewalls if the
environment the ones of the local Brazil
and one was the system that was used as
a jam box
probe for contractors to work in the DMZ
ok so in the cases interesting item to
discover and frankly we start to
considering these
apt because the way they behave the way
they used to move was definitely not
something in the end of the common
cybercriminal we have experience of
different cybercrime no more advanced
like carbon acts like that and it was
potentially comparable to that but
carbon not normally use specific tools
that we know and nothing of that happens
to on our on our eyes our eyes and our
eyes the attention so once we noticed
the scan once we noticed the remote axis
we also noticed that vast majority of
the system access laterally access once
interesting for a reason were also
infected but on the system were having
updated antivirus a number of my other
tool in place so we were starting to
question how that happens
I mean without any sign on the antivirus
console without any sign of logs on the
CM without any other additional
potentional normally recorded before
that guy with the access to the database
okay so start to think about about this
end up by the way looking into the
sandbox see staff we depth we just
notice another element that is the
sandbox see our pcs s dot exe that is
basically one component of the execution
of SM boxing so go back a little bit
about some boxing it's a program
designed to protect system it's a
program designed to send box the
execution of an application and if you
know I'll send box works it basically it
create an environment that is almost
segregated almost where the single
application is detonated so in general
my personal opinion in these at the
beginning at least is if I am an
attacker I don't try to force the
firewall I don't try to force a security
tool to achieve a control
system I can have a number of other
options but they think about it in this
environment the average protection was
good from the endpoints perspective okay
so having these other range good
protection the attacker wants to rely on
something the he knows and it probably
is not known to the vast majority of
people so once even you have an anomaly
you before you think about that normally
as correlated to an attack you think
twice you probably look to other items
the more than that okay so from a
certain point of view if you have the
chance to exploit in a way or another
the same boxy and same boxy is
considered legitimate in the environment
why not one item that immediately jump
on our eyes doing malware analysis and
comparison between the tools related to
the sandbox he discovered in the system
and the typical sandbox environment the
typical sandbox he program was the SB he
the dll that is one of the main
component of sandbox in comparing the
DLL between the typical DLL for that
particular version okay so the same is a
question that the meta were representing
and the ones that we have thus the
malicious one was extremely more light
he was including a number of typical API
is an instruction it's are in the main
if he are in the main dll but he was
having a couple of different components
that were not into the typical sandbox
in dll was that think about that and by
the way on the 6th of August of that
year 2017 on internet a CV related to
sandbox E was published related to a
vulnerability into the sandbox
stellar so things we're aligning a
little bit
the attacker executed the attack on 27
of hours 20 days almost 90 days later
okay
so the typical sandbox execution of the
Installer is expressive like that I
don't want to waste much time it's for
is for posterity but basically when you
have downloaded the exon boxy and you
want to install it you simply click
files Erdem loaded are drop it into the
temp from temp are moving into the
program file then from that a number of
these items are executed in order to
finalize the setup of the system and
then start the weakness relies on the
execution at the beginning of the drop
of the file into the temp folder if
during this particular step I subvert a
number of dll's
I can basically let the same Boxey
execute different behavior than normal
the same Boxey will be installing a plea
normal but in fact once I execute a
glancing the sandbox II executable if I
linked into the sandbox CD ll the SB
Hedo DLL additional I don't know
commands additional code that go will be
executed just one step two to highlight
in the boxes we have analyzed sandbox II
was not installed at the beginning so
the original executable of sandbox II
was not present so from certain
perspective it's okay the vulnerability
it's okay that we have the DLLs that are
different and probably the ones that are
abused to execute malicious file but
sandbox II was not into the system's so
we were looking to the sandbox
executable into the system and the
typical executable sandbox was not
available so
step of the attacker tactic was to
create the condition exploiting this
particular part as I told you the temp
file subverting that strip sandbox e
temp file of all the items that are no
needed and create a small package that
executed through console lured the
sandbox II process that is sign that is
allowed' into the environment but
immediately after execute malicious code
that's the passage that the attackers
have make into interests and looking
into the code of the sandbox as the
baha'i dll we noticed that explored the
dll that was malicious that we have
already identified was rise as an in
okay into the SB he'd the dll some
dynamic library during the execution
also another another function was call
it but in case where is not available
not executed that car that is called my
lord o dll we investigated a little bit
about my lord the dll because we weren't
having any chance to find not there was
not available in any of their invective
system and by speaking with a different
company we found that in environment
they were having almost the same
situation but they have collected my
lord the dll and my daughter dll was a
variant of tesla crypt use it to wipe
out all the items in the system so if
you drop my lord of the ll and you
execute against sandbox see immediately
that particular dll will cancel securely
so we double passage all the file in the
system that are pertaining to the
infection that's the goal so they have
the explore dll that is basically the
third stage of the infection after this
unboxing and if you drop my
in the same folder is the Explorer
executed but again my lord is executed
as well and basically wipe out to the
entire folder so leaving no trace okay
okay I told you this is how they make
possible the hasta scape obviously we
need to consider one aspect the same
boxy process executed by this attack is
not completed so it's not really a
complete sandbox available so this is
also the reason why they use this as a
trampoline to infect because basically
they have incapacitated sandbox II to
really block occurrences like a normal
security tool those they just use it
because creating the process of sandbox
see that design they came back to us and
number of items and because for the way
sandbox awards the resources in memory
are declared on the environment and our
stick they can achieve a control that is
better than standard because the address
space layout randomization is not
working the one that is provided by the
operating system so they can basically
leverage on these to have the chance to
run their mouth in the end if you drop
this set of tools this this set of file
with explore the dll and you rename the
function of the Explorer the DLL that
loads the second stage you basically can
execute the different manner potentially
the mower the day of the unit is the bug
a servidio DXE this is evilly pocket as
I told you however anticipated in the
backdoor able to have Kayla ping in
fulfilling capability a number of
capabilities but in the end is a Trojan
unfortunately we haven't found any
correspondence between this malware and
other items we have
in our knowledgebase this it probably
don't means anything but we have a
relatively huge database of files and
our so we normally once we proceed in
creating io seas or in creating
components to investigate our database
if there are even just correspondences
of segments of code they normally jump
up even if false positive but in this
case absolutely nothing absolutely
nothing this is also the reason why not
only having problem in classification we
will consider these a different apt a
different apt group and we HECO some of
the conclusion that Trend Micro in
Casper sky have reached about a new apt
group that is basically not really
interested in geopolitical stuff but
more into cybercriminal sponsored
activities that is called chasing other
and there was having basically them that
the same type of mechanism of subverting
the system using different application
not the same boxy but really similar to
this so we have for these just concluded
that potentially we are facing the same
the same attacker absolutely not not not
sure about these and consider these
obviously just a speculation a pure
speculation but still chasing other in
the in the reports of casper sky and
train micro show the similar capability
mainly focus windows mainly focus on you
know leveraging on windows application
vulnerability dll hijacking to overcome
the standard protection of the systems
in order to run their tool to that are
almost evil IAM pocket heavily encrypted
they normally change easily and quickly
there see to stay you solve the rhythm
domain generation algorithm for you know
having the chance to skip the typical
network i/o system
okay this is for posterity just as more
number of Euro rules we have developed I
just want to spend one second with this
we normally don't create Yara
in a way that is fire-and-forget so we
normally tends to create yara that stays
in our knowledge base in order for us to
help in the attribution oh so these are
our our Atomics but we are developing a
different ones based on a number of
sample collected from different you know
companies with different malware
researchers in order to realize a yara
that is not only about able to catch
malware where it is but also to
correlate by firing the different
samples in in different parts of the
world don't move ok this is the timeline
of the incident we have just put into
this timeline the most important
elements we have we have identified
because there are a huge number of
system you can see in the following
slide we were having about 273 system
analysing about them to 266 where
touchid or infected but we have just
briefly identified some items into this
timeline that are important to consider
so the first part just make the same
part that I have described another item
that was interesting was that at one
point the attacker identifying the a DSM
the console of Cisco a sa identified the
radius server behind the VPNs so he
immediately spent all his effort to
reach this reducer ver that was an
Active Directory system a Microsoft
System and so by leveraging on the
password they have stolen earlier they
have been able to create custom users
with a number of different profiles in
this ad and from that point on they
stopped using their backdoors they just
accessed through VPNs and they have
attempted to move laterally not just in
the Brazilian Audis in South America
they try to move into US and amia data
centers looking for real things looking
for data and just in this moment from
that moment on we understand a little
bit better what they have in mind
because they totally skip an interest in
financial data they were able to call
credit cards at one point they don't
care they simply don't download this
type of information they started to
focus on a number of shipping contracts
specialized shipping contract dedicated
to Africa where a number of these
contracts were related to UN
organizations
I don't want to go further in this
because obviously means discussing
something that is still under
non-disclosure agreement still under
investigation but just lets you know
that they were looking to understand how
the UN is moving gear into conflict area
in Africa especially in Central Africa
where on the other end China's is really
interested in buying land that's all
this is still for posterity is a simple
set of the world project so we started
on late October at the time a number of
systems were already compromised we have
basically been concluded the
investigation the triage in about 30
days at one point going back to the
timeline on the u.s. part we have
identified the X field about this
project we told you about you titled so
they we have corrupted the the
as normally is intended to do to avoid
further further breaches but in the
other end they insist and insist and
insist and we kept them working up to
the moment when we are we were able to
scope the entire infection and remove
them
okay they have attempted few weeks later
to come back using almost the same
tactic in a different data center but it
was already under under our eyes so was
easy to defuse okay I have anticipated
this the remediation was basically
running us forensic analysis triage and
distributing IOC's atomic Isis on the
entire environment looking for
infections looking for the presence of
any malicious activity we haven't really
studied much the logs apart for the
machines already touch it because we
know they probably have even laterally
move to our other systems but it was
difficult for us to to scope the logs as
often these logs were just not enough to
allowing us to dig into because the logs
were roll it out so we have mainly focus
on items like the files like the network
behavior to realize the triage one
lesson that we learn from these if it
was needed but definitely was okay is
just not to think in a way that is the
standard because the attacker normally
think - ow - views the standard way of
thing so that's that that's the thing
thank you very much guys for for that if
you have any question I'm available
[Applause]
that of course hey do you have any
question guys please okay
a good question and I would just say
probably not I mean probably they are a
very skillet set of individuals okay
probably coming from the cybercriminal
world but not the ones that sees you
know in enacting forums standard rating
forum stuff like that but really really
good and the way they defuse the
protections and the capability that they
show it in terms of development
definitely put them in a higher set of
an n small set of very dangerous group
but definitely it's sponsored in a way
that they at that time we're working for
somebody okay hmm I don't know if they
are cyber mercs or or not in other
investigation that I anticipated by
Trend Micro and and the casper sky they
have stumble in these guys in two other
companies private companies and they
were not looking into copyrighted
material but more into how the money
moves or but but not stealing credit
cards that's the point more financial
data something that you can use to
blackmail people supply that so they
were if if confirm that they were the
same they were looking into items that
normally are used by the politics till
okay in this case this is just the
beginning because after that I was
engaged by the UN organization and we
discover part of these guys in the
environment as well so this is something
really really big in a way that is
developing at the moment
one question one element that is
interesting however is this one one
second okay it's my right hand okay so
here somewhere
sorry there are some references to
Chinese language from the browser so
that browser was Taiwanese or Chinese or
Chinese language power so you know
something that let us think but in a
cuspid sky case the language was not
Chinese
so we're still in doubt not confirmed
okay all the questions please
no it's not custom is only well the C
dot exe was obviously created by on the
fly okay but this was a standard sequel
injection or against windows powered
Apache server very vulnerable because it
was version if I remember correctly but
it's show it somewhere it was 2.4 or
something like that so it was vulnerable
that's for sure
and in fact this was one of the weakest
link in the entire organization
unfortunately we are not aware of this
version they haven't analyzed this in
the previous penetration testing
everyone inaudible assessment they have
run so unfortunately this is the
occasion all the questions please
okay we haven't been able to show you
CNC because it's still under
investigation two points or whether one
of the c2 was in a very peculiar Chinese
provider that is not really common I
mean they these provider owns just six
or seven segments of C C Class so very
smooth okay and it's a bill to apply
widows okay
the other one instead was in a French
French environment unknown huge provider
of VPS services one of the first thing
when we go into an environment and look
for packets is to go for country China
and the other is this particular ISP in
France because is very famous for
holding a number of situations in the
past they have an abuse that is
definitely not working much so if you
send requests they don't cooperate at
all and they no no no yeah the problem
was that the bugs dotty I survived
because this is the only elements that
is actually really communicating it's
funny because he basically as a psycho
that runs and then can be modified on
the fly with a command so he runs for
after 30 seconds we start beginning ok
for a minute or two and if the answer he
collects answer from the other side the
other side will reply saying six minutes
then the following will be after six
minutes 12 minutes or whatever so from
the perspective is very peculiar
unfortunately I haven't been able to
show you guys this because still like as
I told you is still under investigation
the communication we're in SSL
unfortunately so it was a little bit
complicated to
to solve and we are still working on
that but definitely there are some
commonalities in the beaconing way so
there are a number of content we have
developed for our technology that is
able to pick up the presence of the
beacon following the beacon when the
commands are sent still investigating on
this now really easy to a chart control
upon this set of communication stuff
please well related to the same boxy
stuff they use sandbox II so they can
blacklist sandbox e in their environment
and unfortunately if you send box if you
black box
sorry if you black list the application
running in sandbox e you don't achieve a
real block because basically sandbox you
present the process and Boxey for
executing the malware the model so from
that perspective is not really a way to
block the infection the whitelist thing
we normally don't consider that really a
solution for a number of reasons that
you can understand okay any other
question thank you very much guys
[Applause]