okay hey good afternoon
15:06 I got two notes here I got my
slides and I got some other notes that I
put on my phone so I have to start with
saying thank yous so thanks Rob for
having me
no Lacan wouldn't happen with all the
staff so thank you staff for being here
and all the work that goes on behind the
scenes it is an honor for me to be here
so last week I was actually at cyber
shield it's a National Guard cyber
exercise I'm in the National Guard the
Louisiana National Guard yeah baby
and so I was wearing the uniform last
week and with a bunch of fit army people
like real good young in shape strapping
young bucks and so I feel a lot more
comfortable with you guys here so thank
you thank you all for being here
I just I'm not I feel better so uh you
just kind of want to know my audience a
little bit how many of you guys our gals
are not from Louisiana anyone from out
of state here oh that's kind of good
kind of bad as bad as you might not know
what a Cajun is I mean my talk is about
Cajun doctors so just I'm gonna I'm
gonna teach to the lowest common
denominator and assume you know nothing
about Cajuns a couple things to base
level set about Cajuns they like to
drink a lot of alcohol another thing is
if you've heard of the New Orleans
Saints in their little pitch catch
phrase who dat that dat sound the dat
that's really how they talk down here
dat is Cajun for that they can't
pronounce the ths so dat dim and dere is
that them in there so the language is a
barrier I don't know if Cajuns really
have much of a short temper I think
probably
not they just like to drink and party
and and have a good time hunt and fish
and all that stuff so Cajun I just put
that slide in there that that word in
there the descriptive word just because
it's no Lacan I had to make it something
caged related so really you can
eliminate that word and it really
doesn't lose any meaning to this talk
also couple disclaimers I submitted my
talk back in September didn't think I
would actually get selected I was the
last-minute fill-in so I was doing my
slides this morning so all the cool cat
pics and funny slides this is your only
picture you're getting that is it but I
know the talk in my head so that's cool
all right so what else I got
all right so how many of you guys are
interested in cybersecurity
okay a couple good you're the right spot
for that right okay good that makes this
talk a little easier how many of you
have actually been to your a doctor a
family practice doctor or dentist in the
past year people go to their doctors and
dentists pretty regularly okay cool
good I think I'm talking to the right
crowd with this talk okay nice moving on
okay jokes you got to tell jokes to
break the ice I have a 16 year old
daughter she hates my dad jokes but dad
jokes that's kind of a thing that's what
I do I'm a dad so just just two quick
dad jokes it's just gonna relax me yo
y'all go go be easy on me so one dad
joke is did you hear about the Scarecrow
who won an award he was outstanding in
his field
okay okay nice okay all right here in my
final dad joke just to kind of break the
ice a little bit when does a joke become
a dad joke when it becomes a parent okay
nice okay nice moving on
alright I'm done with that I feel
comfortable now I can relax I got more
than one person in here all right all
right here's a real disclaimer this
presentation represents my opinions and
thoughts all
and not that of my employers plural I
work for two I'm in a civilian who works
in the National Guard part-time so my
employers are I'm an InfoSec manager at
CenturyLink I assigned to the
headquarters in Monroe Louisiana but I
work remotely from Lake Charles is
Southwest Louisiana Monroe's northeast
Louisiana I make the drive a lot it
sucks but whatever so that's one of my
jobs and they said you can say
Centrelink just don't attribute any of
this to us okay cool and the other thing
is I'm an NCO I see which is civilian
code word for manager or supervisor of
the 159th Fighter Wing cyber security
office we are a unit and then Louisiana
Air Force National Guard I hope to
retire later this summer after serving
20 F and years and so NCIS NCOIC that's
answer non Commissioner noncommissioned
officer in charge so basically
Commissioner hey hey I'm not a
commissioner got it anyway so so
anything this is all just amateur Josh
doing stuff on his own nothing to do
with the National Guard or essentially
Who am I besides a dad to an amazing 16
year old daughter I've been in AI teen
InfoSec for 22 years I have my security
plus my ceh my CSSP all that from my fat
Airy side is kind of needed as you guys
may or may not know and the federal
government's face they need you to have
all those certs clew CPEs are important
and a lot of industries not just ours
how many y'all knew that like we're in
IT we're in InfoSec we get our sis P we
got to maintain our or continuous
professional education if you got tunnel
vision
I always thought oh that's cool that's
the thing just for cyber know all kinds
of professions have that requirement I
just learned that last year your guys
are gonna hear about it on the military
side so I've been and I did active duty
Air Force for about nine years and I've
done National Guard for the past eleven
you guys aren't really from here most of
the audience raise our hand that's our
out of state so let me tell you these
words Alexandria New Orleans Fort Polk
Baton Rouge
those are like all like different parts
of the table statement Oh Northeast
Louisiana Lake Charles Southwest
Louisiana Alexandria right in the middle
Baton Rouge kind of South middle New
Orleans that's what you guys are half of
the state is Cajun territory and then
the northern half like above Alexandria
and North is like country redneck hick
territory so there's like really the
state is like really divided in two
different areas you got Cajun South and
you got country redneck hick North so a
funny story I met my my baby mama
when I was active duty Air Force I was
in Omaha Nebraska and the girl that
moved into the dorms next to me just
beautiful blond hair just beautiful
South Cajun Louisiana girl and I'm
homesick I'm in Omaha and uh she's from
Lake Charles which is Cajun territory
and I'm from Monroe which is Yankee
Louisiana tour but I don't know it I
just know that I'm from Louisiana I
didn't know I was a country redneck hick
because you know you don't know what you
know until you move out and then you're
trying to date this Cajun girl she says
oh you're a Yankee Louisiana Yin I was
like I'm not a Yankee she's no Yankee
Louisianians so it is two different
cultures but my job in the National
Guard and Centrelink I pretty much
travel the state so I love mistake I
cover it a lot just various roles here
so that's a little bit about me also I
founded Neela sec so when I started
essentially four years ago my my
director was like he's out of Kansas
City he's like I we started set KC
it stands for security Kansas City is
like this monthly hacker security meetup
I was like oh that's so cool I wish we
had that in Monroe and I looked on like
meetup calm or whatever no no security
meetups in Monroe so I talked to mark my
friend marks in the audit hey Mark
thanks for being here bud appreciate you
talk to mark of the hey we need
something like that in Monroe and so
heat we started it neela sec we've been
meeting a monthly security meet up once
a month or about four years so that's
another passion of mine is just talking
to people about security and technology
objective I'm hoping to help anyone here
that has the time skills and desire to
break into consultancy private practice
whatever you want of auditing pentesting
assisting to make extra money maybe to
help doctors and dentists protect
themselves and for patient data so
that's kind of what this is about is if
you've ever thought about hey I want to
I want to fix what this what is broke
but I don't really know how to talk to
them I don't know how to get them to
listen to me then that's kind of what
we're gonna touch on I also want to help
regular InfoSec professionals like
hoping you know some of you guys just
who are patients you got your patient
records out there the doctors and the
dentists they have your sensitive data
and if you've walked in have you've been
like me you've walked in you're like oh
my god why are you doing it that way
that is so wrong you just left the
database wide open with all my patient
records and so maybe you can help them
stop doing that because that's a big
deal
and also they need your lading our help
there they're professionals at what they
do but they don't know what we know just
like I don't know about that rash down
there oh well they know that but they
don't know what we know we know their
rashes I never thought of that one
before till then so I'm pretty proud of
that one expectation management I'm not
a Health Insurance Portability and
Accountability Act expert so I don't
know HIPAA inside and out so if you
think I do you might want to find
there's a child porn talk I think across
the hall I mean seriously I will not be
offended I'm not a professional
pentester auditor vulnerable assessment
guy compliance professional not what I
do I don't own my own private practice I
only volunteer as a
passion as a hobby to try to help people
and doctors need our help they do
they're people just like us
I'm only the subs professional with some
experience talking to medical and dental
professionals and want to share my
experiences I'm an amateur basically
when it comes to that but I've got some
good war stories for you
agenda how I got my start why did I
choose this topic like how what do I
experience - have I got some whatnot to
do some failures when I told the doctors
their baby was ugly and munroe like
Charles kind of yeah what I did wrong
why it was wrong you know I had the
right intention the right heart the
right motive but my delivery was in my
delivery I think was okay it was a
timing but why did I do what I did wrong
and how to get them how to get doctors
and dentists to take us seriously when
we talk to him about how ugly their baby
is so how I was how did this start with
me so I have InfoSec as a career been
doing IT and InfoSec for 20 years I go
to a doctor I see all the bad things
they do I was playing basketball with
the I didn't know the guy young kid
looked barely old enough to be out of
college but he owns his own dental
practice and I cool good for you man and
so we're playing basketball together and
he's he knows what I do cybersecurity
wise I know what he does dental but he
also does dental but he's kind of got
like what's it called we have a major in
one thing and you got something else in
another with minors like got a minor in
cybersecurity
so we synced up we hit it off and then
smallworld I do you know I do cyber
security for the National Guard one week
in a month in New Orleans so I'm going
to get my teeth checked by my military
dock my military dentist and it's making
small talk with his dentist guy he's
like oh yeah oh my own practice in Lake
Charles I'm like I live in Lake Charles
I noticed a small state but still when
you when your dentist in New Orleans is
also from Lake Charles it's just weird I
was like cool his dental practice is
like a block or like a mile from my
house so we may different friends he
knew the guy I played basketball with so
they were dentists friends and so they
started talking to me about their
NEADS what do they need they knew what I
do like oh my god we got hit with
ransomware I met I was at this talk and
this dentist got hit with ransomware and
they're scared poopless so what do we do
how do we help them so they invited me
to give a talk and next thing I know I'm
realizing that's the way in that's the
way to get them to listen to you
alright so story time my failures so I
go to this podiatrist that's what a foot
doctor is I think so I go see this foot
doctor and I'm like hey what's this rash
here but while I'm waiting to tell her
about my foot situation I'm in the
waiting room art no you wait in the
waiting room and then you go to they put
you in the little room with the bed in
the chair
whatever that room is called the patient
room literally I'm counting I'm looking
at the clock 30 minutes with this
windows like a workstation wide open I'm
looking at all the patient records on
there luckily I searched mine I wanted
to click around so bad but my ethics got
in the way I'm like no that's unethical
Josh don't do it and all their USB ports
are wide open I'm pretty sure I could
have done whatever I needed to do USB
wise so I'm looking at that and and
times 2 first of all I'm mad cuz they're
taking so long
second of all I'm mad because what if
anybody else could just go in there and
grab all that so I let her do her doctor
thing on me and and after we're done I'm
like hey ma'am I'm in the military I
have a top-secret clearance you can
trust me but what you did was wrong here
cuz I could have done this this and this
and you should have done that here and I
don't want any money from you I'm not
trying to sell you a service I just want
to help you and she she didn't like the
message I had she said oh yeah talk to
IT I embarrassed her I'm pretty sure on
accident I told her her baby's ugly so I
didn't get anywhere with that she she
blew me off she told me to talk to IT it
didn't work so for all I know they leave
people are still to this that I was the
over a year ago they probably their
Windows workstations wide open with all
the patient records left unattended with
an unknown patient for at least 30
minutes so that's the foot doctor
I was helping my daughter and Lake
Charles to go in the doctor's office I
don't remember what they did is a very
similar story this time I got a little
bit further this time at least the
doctor is like oh that's good to know
you know but we outsource our IT and we
want to fire them can you can you help
me you know figure that out so I go they
refer me to somebody who it just goes
nowhere though but at least that guy was
initially like okay I want to fire them
but how to you know help me get them
fired because it's bad but still I
didn't get anywhere so though and I'm
sure you got anybody got a story like
that nod your head raise your hand on
anybody go okay got one hand race thank
you I'm not alone so why my approach was
wrong I was on I was that's their
livelihood that's how they make their
money that's their bread and butter and
I'm a patient and I'm a threat to them
I'm telling them their baby is ugly I'm
telling them what they did wrong on
their turf I didn't mean it on purpose
I had good intentions but it got nowhere
is I mean anybody else can think of any
other reason I mean that's just that's
the only thing I can think of there has
to be that all right so talking about
continuous professional education
credits so we do it we know what we do
an IT insecurity but so do doctors and
dentists they they need continuous
education credits they have to maintain
their licenses I put here in Louisiana
doctors need to have 20 credits a year I
know that because my padai
and he told me that last night I say hey
what's that accrediting body it's called
the Louisiana Board of Medical
Examiner's it's a real thing so in
Louisiana if you wanted to give a talk
to doctors on continuous educate on
cybersecurity to help them understand
the importance you can just a doctor
can't just listen to you and then turn
that in it's got to go get accredited
through this Louisiana board of medical
examiners other states have probably the
same or similar thing so that's
that's how you got to get them to listen
to you is you gotta you got to make them
think they're getting credits for Denis
participate in a regional district
dental association Louisiana State
Dental Association and American Dental
Association Club that Dennis need their
continuous professional education
credits as well that one dentist
basketball friend of mine he taught me
he's they asked me hey we need CES we
have a bunch of dentist meet up once a
month to get their CES and we would love
for you to talk they need you we had a
ransomware attack in our group and they
don't know what to do can you help us so
I go to this they I think they meet
quarterly and and I just want to drink
and get some free CER cheap easy CES for
their dental license they normally talk
about first aid or CPR or the new dental
technique of the year and and my friends
told me after my talk I got out there
and I talked for 30 minutes and there
was this beautiful dentist in the back
she was laughing at all my jokes I'll
never forget her anyway so so after my
talk was over this beautiful dentist
lady she comes up to me she's like I
just want to meet you your talk was so
awesome so funny and said thank you you
should come to all my talks and be my
height man I love you but my other two
friends is a basketball friend and the
New Orleans National Guard dentist
friend they both said Josh your talk was
so engaging I've never seen these
dentists care so much and ask so many
questions now I did kind of fend this
one dentist lady though she was in the
back and she was asking a question about
malware or something I don't remember
she raised her hand and said can I ask a
question
I said no you've already met your quota
of questions man I'm like real serious
she she didn't like that but other than
that joke the rest of the jokes are
pretty good but but they they those
dentists they needed that they thrived
on that they loved it they were drinking
it was casual I wasn't at their place of
employment telling them how ugly their
baby was I was in their environment with
drinks with booze with alcohol in a
relaxing atmosphere telling them all the
threats and then telling them how
can help them without trying to sell
them something or making them feel
uneasy and that you can leave now that's
the end that's like the meat and
potatoes is about that's my advice if
you really want to get and listen to you
get them in that environment and tell
them how ugly their baby is and what you
can do to help them so yeah that's how
you tell them and you don't die how to
tell the Cajun doctor and live you tell
them why they drink Cajuns love to drink
I'm sure most dental professionals and
medical professionals probably enjoy
that like we all do yeah they do have a
lot of pride in ego I think that's
another thing I need to touch on if
you're talking to a medical professional
they went to school for a hundred years
and they got all these student loans
they got to pay off they're afraid that
you're trying to sell them this service
and you can't live up to it and with
their ego and you tell them they did
something wrong it's kind of like in the
milk you're in the military sir
are you a pilot by chance okay good it's
like the pilots they they have this such
a huge ego and if you deflate a mini
it's just not gonna go well you're gonna
put them a defensive right away
so what I did at that talk I asked like
hey I just want to help you I'm not
trying to make money off of you
let me come talk to you your your staff
has poor cybersecurity hygiene they're
clicking malware lling they don't know
how to hover hover and over Lync is like
the easy thing just hover over it see
where it's going like you'll offer to
give them a 30-minute lunch and learn
hey let me talk to your staff let me
teach them these things and then
eventually you're gonna do such a good
job and they're gonna see the value and
they're gonna trust you you're gonna
build that trust in that rapport and
they're gonna want to listen to you and
they're gonna call you so after my
little talk with that dental the
Southwest Association dental chapter
like not even another day later I had
this dentist I had my dentist New
Orleans dentist friend called me say hey
I got a dental guy he just fell for you
guys heard of the tech support scam the
Microsoft Texas board scam where you
think you Microsoft is calling you hey
you've got this malware please scare
where so this dentist fell for that and
he like gave up the
fred's he gave up the kadena he gave up
the the credit-card information like he
bought it all hook line and sinker and
then eventually caught on to his mistake
and he missed my talk the the previous
week but he knew he heard about it
because those dentists all talk to one
another and he was I hate hey can you
give me Josh's contact info so I go help
this guy he was so scared to death he
knew he was like brand-new to the dental
practice his boss was like the senior
old guy who's about to retire and he
thought he just ruined everything and
he's like oh he was shaking when he was
talking to me when I saw that on my oh
my god they need us I'm in my call for
paper kind of outline I mentioned having
a servant's heart I really think this is
like a community service pricing GLE
person in this room could go do that
just give a talk for CPD to get in front
of the dentist and then help them or
help the doctor that's kind of like you
know lawyers they do stuff pro bono I
feel like we as security practitioners
we can go do that we can help because
you benefit but you know building up
your skill sets you're gonna learn some
this poor guy he thought he thought I
knew everything about credit monitoring
and credit this and credit that and FICO
scores and I'm like dude I thought you
need to call your bank about cancelling
your credit card but that that's
something you guys need to be aware of
is if you go out on on site they're
gonna have a lot of credit card
questions and financial questions
especially if they fall for scareware
type stuff like that but basically
became like his financial advisor hey do
you know how to do a credit freeze but
still they need that and if we could all
do that I think that would be good
alright so here's an example of this
lady her name is white now first of all
there is a Texas Medical Associates so
we talked about Louisiana how to they
got to get approved you got to be
approved for the medical professionals
to get credit for you're talking to them
well there's an event right now today
in San Antonio where all these Texas
doctors they're meeting right now and
they're getting their continuous medical
CME continuous medical education credits
so in order in order to get a credit in
Texas has got to be approved and all
these talks are approved so I just
googled I was doing some google
searching last night ahead of this talk
and I found this talk there's a lady
named Cathy Bryant I don't know her I
just found these slides publicly
available and she so the doctors who are
at this conference they're gonna listen
to her talk Kathy is not a cybersecurity
professional now her talk is pretty good
I read through her slides pretty
accurate but a couple things I want to
point out that I found wrong with her
slides as to why a real cybersecurity
expert should really be going and doing
this I have you heard of a network
traveling worm I don't think I've heard
of that phrase but anybody is that a
thing and I just never knew of it
anybody so yeah I want to see a network
traveling worm I mean I think I know
what she's trying to say but that was
kind of interesting also if you look
above Network traveling worm you well
the top this slide is common types of
cyber threats so one of the interview
questions I like to ask young cyber
security professionals coming up is hey
can you tell me the difference between a
threat and a vulnerability and an
exploit
well this titled aside is cyber threats
and she's got unpatched software anybody
have a problem with that yeah so so but
for the most part like she had like I
don't know like 50 slides they were all
pretty good this was the only slide I
really had problems with but really good
those doctors in that room if they can
overlook those two little things they're
gonna get a really good talk and
hopefully this will light up their eyes
and see oh I really need to worry about
this but I'm pretty jealous of this
Kathy lady because she's getting to tell
these people and they're probably gonna
look at her as a foremost authority and
want to reach out to her what if that
was you would have
that's probably if you're trying to
start your own business there's a huge
need for it and there's an easy way to
do it right here I'm showing you I don't
have the time to do it between my two
jobs but maybe y'all do pros and cons
benefits of doing it without pay that
you might be thinking but Josh well I
don't want to do this without pay dude
we can why is that doctor charging me
$50 an hour to look at my rash on my
foot no 150 200 whatever their prices
are but you want me to give them cyber
security consultation for free yeah I do
I think that would be good why don't you
go do it because you're giving back to
your community also you think of doctors
as rich like they're rich think about
how many student loans the pay they
could have pay all their staff they're
not as rich as you probably think
especially if you like do a salary
survey for like state of Louisiana top
paying jobs I always get like wow I'm
not doing so bad like the average income
is like 40,000 or something and doctors
now we're not talking anesthesiologist I
think those guys and gals make a lot but
anyway you'd be surprised they're not as
rich as you probably think they still
need your help they're still humans and
all they got your records so if you do
it for free
like when I negotiated with that guy I
was like look you fell for this exploit
this this text of Microsoft's not going
to call you and try to help you
Microsoft is too big they can't do that
but you fell for it you gave him a
credit card I will help you I'll help
run malwarebytes I'll do forensics on
your computer I'll help you I'll teach
you I don't mind don't know that for
free because I want to help you also I'm
a little bit lazy I don't want to set up
an LLC I don't want to be liability for
their stuff if I exchange money then I
probably got to do some things I
probably got to deduct taxes for like
that's another reason you might want to
do it for free
to not have to deal with all that stuff
while you're getting this valuable
experience to launch your own
cybersecurity consulting business and
then work for yourself and not the man
also if you get in front of those people
the doctors and the dentists on their
turf while they're drinking it'll help
you with your
public speaking and you might have some
sexy dentist lady tell you how great you
are yeah
yes sir well look at that you good CPEs
by helping other professionals get their
CPE that's like win-win is what I call
that double win triple win nice good
point thank you sir
I didn't even think of that that luckily
the military sends me to these
conferences so I get on my cps I don't
even think of that but great point thank
you
so disadvantages of free work
time-consuming if you have a family baby
mama drama who knows what you got my job
is stressful and my other job is trying
to make me do stressful job while on top
of doing the other stressful job I'm
like hey I'm already stressed out and
then I don't want my phone blowing up
for these local dentist saying hey man I
just clicked this fake virus malware
malware exploit Microsoft said I was
hacked can you help me okay sure I can
thanks mom
and that what moms do right my mom
called me and said the FBI just emailed
me said they're gonna arrest me if I
don't write back is that real mom really
FS good if they know where you are
they'll just come get you like they
don't just email warn you moms I think
that's it y'all I'm done so any
questions no clap oh yes ma'am
absolutely absolutely
if you can't hear in the back she say
and this applies to all careers all
industries if you got a connection
inside to get to their CPS or to help
them out absolutely help that's a great
point I agree that's kind of what a foot
salt like IT is not the only industry
that needs CPEs medical financial I'm
sure in any industry great point arts
they need CPCC well there you go
agreed so just find a way I guess the
meat and potatoes is find away in a
non-threatening way outside of their
place of employment where they don't
feel like they're gonna go to jail to
tell them the bad news thank you
anything else Oh
clap you can clap go ahead start it yeah
baby thank you everyone thank you