all right we good all right hello and
welcome to mind games is exploring
mental health through games so this is
me surprisingly normal photo of me
actually that's got my contact info and
so forth
oh as it notes I'm a DevOps engineer at
Unity Technologies I am a security
enthusiast
I'm an enormous fan of games and if you
want to talk to me you can probably
notice a bit of a theme here with my
name is frozen fox you can find me on
all sorts of services and I'm sure
Google is probably something on me
anyway that's enough about me though
let's talk about everyone's favorite
subject mental disorders so mental
health is a real serious issue today it
affects the lives of millions of people
just in this country alone not even
thinking about the rest of the world and
thing is is about all those millions of
people that are affected we aren't
really any better in InfoSec we we deal
with this the same way that everyone
else does and at the end of the day
behind every hack every tool and every
exploit is a person and people make up
InfoSec and we need to start thinking
about how to better understand and our
fellow people whenever they're
struggling so with that let's take a
quick look at how things are now so
first up is depression for this and the
others I've got an appendix at the end
of this that all have up and I strongly
encourage anybody who's interested in
this stuff to go ahead and take a look
at but first let's look at the numbers
an estimated 16 point 2 million adults
in the US have had at least one major
depressive episode just let that sink in
for a minute
that's that 60 million people have had
this at least once that's an enormous
amount of people right I mean the
prevalence of adults with a major
depressive episode was highest amongst
individuals aged 18
25 that's 10.9% of those 16 million
people and again that's just here that's
not even worldwide in 2016 an estimated
ten point three million US adults aged
18 or older had at least one major
depressive episode with severe
impairment and that means they were not
able to function normally
that's how depressed they were this
number represented 4.3 percent of all US
adults I mean that's over 10 million
people chances are pretty good that some
of you know or even are someone who's
had one of these so what about ADHD I
personally suffer from ADHD and it
affects everything I do every single day
including this talk actually I don't
have any super snazzy graphics for it
unfortunately but these are a few
interesting data points I found that you
might you know also find interesting 4.4
percent of the adult population in this
country has ADHD but less than 20
percent of those people actually seek
any help for it I mean that 4.4 percent
okay to put this in context the
population of the country is 320 3.1
million people give or take a couple
people that's about fourteen million two
hundred sixteen thousand four hundred
people that's a lot of people with ADHD
and think about how only a fifth of
those actually seek any help because
they're too embarrassed or they're too
ashamed or they're told that it's not
really a problem but it affects
everything they do that's a cultural
problem we have in taking a look here
adults with ADHD are nearly 50% more
likely to be in a serious car crash
having ADHD makes you three times more
likely to be dead by the age of 45 ADHD
prescriptions spiked 85% between 2008
and 2012 it but that's just in a four
year period for women aged 26 to 34
anxiety disorders occur in about 50% of
adults with ADHD which includes me
actually and only 1% of that ADHD
research is focused on the disorder and
women but you know what's really
terrible about this
that right there I know plenty of women
with ADHD it is no easier on them there
is no reason this should exist like that
there's no reason one person over that
doesn't make any sense that just at all
move them right on let's take a look at
PTSD so I pulled this graphic from PTSD
United org and honestly that's a lot of
people with PTSD apparently according to
this graph my entire state has PTSD
which also does it that totally
surprised me anyway seventy percent of
the adults in the u.s. seventy percent
almost massive right these people have
experienced some type of traumatic event
at least once in their lives this
equates to approximately two hundred and
twenty three point four million people
that's huge as noted eight percent of
Americans will have PTSD at any given
time it's not just one or two people
it's not that one guy in your
neighborhood or something it's enormous
it's huge amount of people that 24
million people up to 20 percent of these
people will go on to develop PTSD as of
today that equates to approximately 44
million people who are struggling with
PTSD and an estimated one out of every
nine women period will develop PTSD
making them about twice as likely as men
which also is just mind-boggling that's
just it's a huge amount of people with a
serious problem so things are bad that
doesn't really help us explore it though
so this is going to be my approach
during this presentation and I'm gonna
need a couple of disclaimers first so
our first is that basically we're gonna
break this into three sections and each
section we're gonna talk about a
disorder and a game that helps us
explore this in a more interactive
fashion this is a huge one I am NOT a
licensed psychotherapist
please take anything I say with a grain
of salt my word is not gold if you have
concerns if you have a problem if you
know somebody with a problem or if
you're just interested in want to help
please actually seek a professional for
these things that is license to be able
to give advice on these things we're
just gonna be talking about exploring it
and naturally because we're talking
about games here there spoilers sorry
okay what we're going to be talking
about has a lot to do with
interpretation of story and in many
cases a common question is about what
the author meant for it to be about we
call this authorial intent and while
it's a big subject on its own these are
the most popular schools of thought when
it comes to criticism
so in our anti-authority we have new
criticism psychoanalytic criticism
Cambridge school to contextualism and
post structuralism in the pro with a
real intent we have marxist and we can
turn a weak intentional ism and
basically under the other the catch-all
is reader response how it made you feel
the pro authorial intent ones here
though will say something along the
lines of it's interesting and worthy of
an investigation but doesn't actually
help us understand it any better and
they all boil down to the fact that we
can only analyze the finished product
not the author's brain so that's where
our examine examination focuses on this
is kind of like say when you find a
terrible service or a terrible piece of
code there's no way you can actually
understand what was going through that
person's mind you can only analyze what
we actually have so that's what we're
gonna pay attention to okay so great
first up let's have a look at depression
through the well-known game depression
quest uh before we go any further it is
important for everybody to be on the
same page and I know that not everybody
plays video games so to make sure that
everyone's on the same page and
everyone's up to speed I have a demo of
the game play kinda you see there's not
actually any good trailers or anything
for depression quest because it's not
really a traditional sort of game so
instead I've taken some screenshots
which should help us illustrate what
sort of game it is let's have a look so
this is our first screen shot and the
most positive this is from later in the
game and you can see how the game tells
you your state of mind is more positive
constructive steps have been taken to
manager
and the characters outlook is positive I
don't have any options to choose from in
this one but overall it looks like a
pretty good day for your character in
this screenshot we can see what starts
to happen if your depression management
is allowed to slip more of the options
that are posited to become crossed out
and your available actions are dwindling
you can also see down there at the
bottom how the text below lets you know
your current state and finally we can
see here what starts happening if your
depression goes unmanaged for too long
almost all of your options are
unavailable in the same way that a
person with depression feels unable to
move on or function normally so now that
everyone's familiar what is depression
question so like I said it is a game but
not in the traditional sense it's more
of an interactive fiction it's kind of
like a choose-your-own-adventure
gives you a block of text you get some
options it gives you some descriptive
text about where your depression level
and things you've been doing and then
you make choices the it's pretty simple
and straightforward it's also completely
free so there's no reason not to check
it out which I highly recommend honestly
even just like 30 minutes with this it
will tell you everything you need to
know it's really good ok so that's the
game but what is depression let's have a
look at what the dsm-5 defines
depression as so you have a depressed
mood or a loss of interest or pleasure
in daily activities consistently for at
least a two-week period not within like
a Monday blues thing but for a long
period of time you have a subjective
report or observations made by others
the significant weight loss or gain
insomnia restlessness fatigue and
tiredness just being totally out of
energy feelings of worthlessness and
guilt any diminished ability to
concentrate or think and recurrent
thoughts of death or suicide so we know
what depression is we know what this
game is in this context what is it
actually about what what is it actually
about not the gameplay itself in this
case this game is about experiencing
depression you are a depressed person
to deal with everyday life going through
going to work making friends doing the
things that everyone does but in this
case you have depression it's daily
sometimes hourly battles to maintain
mood and you have to make the most of
the available options whilst knowing
that others are available you see most
games give you a box we call it a game
play box and within that box there are
all the things you can do so like say if
it's something like grand theft auto
your game play box includes buying
things driving car shooting people
whatever it happens to be and that giant
game play box all the gameplay is
focusing around within that and most of
the fun comes from having a giant box of
things that you can do the genius in
this game is that it accidentally shows
just what depression is simply by
showing you the size of the box and then
by taking away your options if you're
not well enough to choose them it shows
you what they could be and it shrinks
your box and that's it you know the box
is bigger you know there's more options
you can see them but you can't choose
them you can't just do it so how does it
really do this right let's have a look
in all of these and like in all stories
there's always symbolism so the first
symbol that we have in this are the
choices all the choices as I noted are
known to the player only a limited set
of options are able to be chosen and
depression sufferers are aware of those
other options but they're unable to
execute upon them they're not able to
just shake it off they know that say
they need to go to their therapist they
know they need to be cool at a party or
whatever it is they have to do but due
to their condition they're not able to
they they can't so anyway what else can
we do here well we can take a look at
the text color we have read for crossed
out options as a study found and emotion
back in 2011 it showed that red text
actually causes a more visceral reaction
hence why all the crossed out options
are red because it should piss you off
it should make you angry a little bit
similarly the options that are available
are in blue it has a calming effect and
it can also create feelings of sadness
even choosing something knowing it's the
only available one can still kind of
bring you down a little bit so this
about wraps up depression quest it's
pretty straightforward and simple to
understand how to explore it so since it
didn't really take a whole lot of
symbolism or explanation for us to
examine what depression is like let's
tackle one that's a little harder with
ADHD and the game double daggers so
first up what is devil daggers so I know
this won't show up in the recording
unfortunately there we go as before it's
really important that everyone's
familiar with the game so I'm going to
go ahead and play a quick demo for you
it's not immediately obvious but a
single touch by any one of these
creatures is enough to instantly end the
game notice the sound as you can see
there's a lot of target priority going
on but ultimately it's the same sort of
gameplay that I and many shooter fans
have played for decades
the controls and tactics are simple the
design is much deeper circle strafe hold
down the left mouse key target priority
what you're seeing here is my very best
run on devil daggers this is my absolute
best no matter what and that's not
saying that I'm amazing as I'm not what
you're seen is what's inside my head I
don't mean just during this game but I
mean all the time but most especially
whenever I meditate whenever I try to
clear my mind
let nothing in it things come out of the
dark those racing thoughts those rushing
memories all of those things and if you
watch carefully here you can actually
see as we come in towards the end you
can actually see me lose my focus you
can see it just chip away
this is right about the very last moment
when I still actually have control
and right here you can even see where I
try to pick a target ones that I
previously paid attention to I can't you
get in here is there's more sounds to
key in on I look like I'm gonna do a
little better maybe even last for a long
time
nope there's not there are people
significantly better than me way better
they can play for 15 20 some of them
can't even play for 30 minutes or more
and just like that it's all gone it's
all over so now that you're familiar
with what the gameplay looks like what
is devil daggers anyway it's a
single-player game it's available on
multiple platforms it's really cheap
it's like ten bucks it's the style of a
90 shooter it has one movement style one
level one weapon one game mode one life
in infinite enemies not everyone is
actually familiar with the actual
definition of ADHD beyond pop-culture
references
so let's actually have a look here and
see what the dsm-5 actually says ADHD is
it's a persistent pattern of inattention
or hyperactivity impulsivity that
interferes with functioning or
development they fail to give close
attention details difficulty sustaining
attention and tasks or play activities
forgetfulness does not follow through on
instructions difficulty organizing tasks
and activities talks excessively
interrupts or intrudes on others and
fidgets
so some of these especially if you know
me are gonna sound awfully familiar I
for instance talk excessively and fidget
as well as struggle with forgetfulness
and sustaining attention even in the
middle of this talk is much
fact that's why I have so many notes as
before with all that in mind how can we
explore ADHD through the game what is
the game about in this concert and in
this context the game mechanics are
simple the play options are simple the
challenge is in playing this focused the
game is structured to require absolute
focus and when the attention slips the
player tends to die very quickly as
you're able to see the thing is is that
it's focused not hyper focus as we'll
talk about in just a minute but this is
our goal of the game is to be focused
with otherwise simple tools our first
bit of symbolism here are the skulls
themselves these are racing thoughts
uncontrolled influence every single
enemy in this game is a variant on a
skull rushing thoughts and other
distractions are naturally from your own
head so that's kind of what you're
trying to clear here you're gonna start
noticing a turn in a theme here with
ADHD and this game is focus in this case
the platform is the mind of an ADHD
person like when meditating the goal is
to try and keep it clear of idle
thoughts hence why we try and clear the
enemies within the platform to do so
requires focus everything in this game
about this place about everything in it
is about the clear platform getting back
to it trying to wipe everything clean
even the sound itself is a huge
influencer here we have when you're not
firing and the platform is clear I don't
know if you're able to tell but there's
a faint calming music indicating peace
of mind it feels like a place you want
to get back to you'll like this place
but these things will stop you when you
reach maximum power a howl is added to
your stream of daggers giving the
focused player something to kind of hone
in on mentally enemies have distinct
sounds like whispers of racing thoughts
just like how in the mind of an ADHD
person when they have four racing
thoughts it's something that you might
even feel chipping away at your focus
something kind of starting to kind of
get in there that wants to take your
attention away it's even the sound here
though is one more thing that demands
your attention
if you don't you won't hear enemies
stinking up on you if you hyper focus on
it you'll get swarmed because you can't
target or move as well focus but not
hyper focus and finally there's the
score itself the score is a measure of
how long you can remain completely
focused on a single objection on a
single objective to the exclusion of all
else to focus and to pay attention
everything in this game demands your
attention it chips away at it it demands
focus and teases you with hyper focus if
you slip up the game is over every
second is a struggle every minute is
draining what precious attention you
have to give to the task at hand my best
time that you just saw was 225 seconds
it's not even three minutes so it's just
over three minutes not even four that's
it that's all I've got
that's as long as I can pay attention to
anything even something I love so this
brings us to our last topic PTSD and in
this case with the Last Guardian so as
before let's have a quick look at the
demo of the Last Guardian so that we're
all on the same page
okay sorry about that it always kind of
pulls about hurt rings a little bit and
rightly so that last line what's wrong
are your wings broken that's what we're
gonna be exploring here and kind of what
it's about so what is the Last Guardian
it's a single-player game came out on
ps4
it's a story puzzle game kind of thing
you do puzzles and so forth you play as
the boy in this and you awaken to find
yourself in the belly of a maze through
some sort of ancient city and next to
this dragon called Treecko you don't
have any means of attack you don't have
any means of defense you can't escape it
on your own and you have a pet dragon I
mean that's great right or do you so
we'll be exploring that a little bit
before we go any further though let's
find out specifically what PTSD is these
are some very quick notes a full
diagnosis of PTSD is complicated and
should only be done by a licensed
professional
so the dsm-5 says that it's a person who
is exposed to death threatened death
actual or threatened serious injury or
actual or threatened sexual violence the
traumatic event is persistently re
experienced avoidance of trauma related
stimuli after said trauma negative
thoughts or feelings that began worsened
after the trauma trauma related arousal
or reactivity that began or worsened
after said trauma the symptoms last more
than one month the symptoms create
distress or functional impairment and
symptoms are not due to medication and
substance use or other illness so the
sort of exposure they're talking about
is direct witnessed or indirect via
close friends or family or even
employment by reinstate intrusive
thoughts nightmares and flashbacks avoid
and so trauma related stimuli refers to
the feelings and reminders of the event
whatever it happened to be negative
thoughts can be very broad including the
inability to recall specific details
maybe you can only call back key
features overly negative thoughts
feeling isolated someone and so forth
and the reactivity are worsening can
mean among other things irritability
risky behavior hyper vigilance
difficulty concentrating and sleeping
there are several methods of treatment
for PTSD but in particular we're gonna
be concerned with exposure is see this
is the game it doesn't really touch on
the other ones but it hits exposure
really hard and this is also one of the
more effective methods of dealing with
PTSD this is a really complicated topic
though the full scope of which is way
beyond this presentation so if you're
interested I urge you to check out the
VA site detailing therapies and also I
do need to note that while these
resources are from the VA PTSD can
affect anyone anyone at all not just
soldiers but anybody so with all that in
mind what does this game actually about
in this case the game is actually about
being a caregiver to a person with PTSD
in this case the dragon' you're going to
have to console him when he's enraged
and there are many enemies in the game
here that will try to attack you and
your dragon while Trico is much more
powerful and he's more than capable of
dealing with them he'll be completely
and totally enraged like way beyond he
does not look like he does in the
trailer he is a beast a terrifying one
it looks like he's stuck in a flashback
to an earlier time his eyes changed to a
different color he sounds and acts
differently
and will keep pounding lifeless bodies
to dust before he can proceed you'll
need to leap on to him climb into a spot
in between his wings and you want to pet
him and reassure him you ought to tell
him that it's okay and when that happens
you'll see eventually he'll start to
calm down the light will change color in
his eyes and he'll turn around and he's
become the gentle giant once more you're
going to have to guide him what he's
unsure where to go next you see there's
no button to like drag him anywhere
there's you can call to him but he has
to decide to move forward you don't
direct this narrative it's his narrative
you're helping that's that's your only
goal here you can't do it
you have to care for him when he's had
too much pain there are these metal
monstrosities these statues that will
hurl Spears at you and whenever some
gets stuck in him earlier on in the game
he can only take one maybe any recoils
in fear and you have to actually climb
onto him pull the things out and let him
know that it's okay before he settle to
proceed but a fascinating thing happens
which is that through your help as you
go on through the game he's able to take
significantly more and more damage as
it's going on until eventually not even
those can stop him you also have to help
him grapple with the source of his
trauma you're surrounded by the thing
that has given him his trauma he's not
able to just do it on his own left to
his own devices he's down stuck in the
cave just like you are but with your
help with you being able to help move
things out of the way being able to
direct him being able to help guide him
solve puzzles and everything else you're
going to help him in this way the last
bit is that your primary job is you're
going to lead him out of darkness and
ultimately if you want to help care for
a person with PTSD this is literally the
idea is to help lead them in this game
you actually literally ascend out of
darkness but this getting back to being
able to help him reclaim himself to
become a normal person is the idea so
what do we have for symbolism well first
obviously we have trekkers face the eyes
will give you an eye indication of where
he is mentally the as you can see here
they're kind of more Placid that kind of
thing their streaks down a space right
bond right below the eye sockets that
along with the horns indicate a horrible
trauma that you're going to help him
overcome just looking at this face it
looks like someone who is obviously in
need of some assistance of some kind as
he gets stronger the horns are gonna
come back as eyes will glow softly as
you hope guide him out of darkness he
gets stronger while your actions his
horns regrow he becomes more luminous
and the light in his eyes returns we
also these evil eye thing
as I mentioned that you're going to help
have to help guide him and grapple with
this trauma these things are literal
symbols of trauma and until they're
dealt with they literally prevent all
forward progress but through exposure
eventually Trico is able to overcome
them especially near the end where they
cannot stop him they can't hurt him
anymore when you come across these
things he gets very angry his eyes
change he flat out refuses to move past
them he'll growl at them it's like
literally you cannot make him move past
them you have to help him with it with
gradually increasing that exposure he
gets from being able to see one and stop
everything to be able to see a bunch of
them near him and he can keep moving
eventually you help him through that
exposure put away those symbols of
trauma that they can't claim him anymore
we'd even see the armor on trico it's
like with the armor on him he's
terrifying he's a beast just like his
former comrades are however once the
armor is gone you can see that he's
actually just a gentle giant his healing
can only begin when the armor is gone
which is why the literally first thing
that you do in the game is help him
remove the armor without it he can't
progress we also have this other
creature called the troika path we can
see it here in the foreground we can see
trico there in the back
it's symbolizing his former self at
first he's unwilling to attack it he
knows it's like him you see honestly
it's only when this version of his old
self tries to directly kill you that
he's willing to even attack it willing
to even engage that he doesn't want to
deal with that former life because it
involves acceptance you know that's
where we know that something terrible
happened or we did something terrible or
whatever it was and we have to accept
that and incorporate it and say okay we
can move past this we also had this item
the mirror shield it's actually a
literal key in this case but it's more a
symbolic key of acceptance of trauma you
see early on in the game you find this
thing and it helps you use his powers
you can help focus it to be able to tear
down some walls and so forth but he
looks really angry and upset whenever
using this because it's too early
you can't drag people to being better
you have to guide them and help them but
they have to do it on their own so he
takes it away from you until the last
third of the game when he's healed
enough he gives it back to you and now
you're able to use it with him he's no
longer super angry and upset he's no
longer afraid together you can harness
this power that he has with its when it
comes up later he's this can't hurt him
anymore either you'll keep noticing this
as a theme with acceptance he games
appreciation for his skills they don't
actually have to be associated with the
trauma it can be something just that he
can do just in the way that many of us
have special skills special powers that
we can do they don't have to be
associated with trauma it's okay it's
part of you even the sound in this game
is used to drive home this allegory and
that's how this thing is unbelievably
committed to its allegory in this case
almost all of the music is driven by try
codes actions there is a single small
exception and that's whenever you're
being chased by the stone golems and
even then it's very muted and you could
actually make an argument that it's
because Trico can see you and it's
distressed that he can't help the all
the swells all the drops everything that
happens sound wise in this game is all
as a result of treecko's actions he's
big he's the center of focus the camera
is about him he has a he has literal
keybinds dedicated just to interacting
with him everything in this game even
the sound is telling you this is his
story it's not yours it's important
we're going to help him the only notable
sound from the boy is whenever you call
to him to guide him that is literally it
it's a small tiny sound off to the side
you kind of hope that he's paying
attention to so this is the kind of
thing I'm talking about here is that the
title itself is the Last Guardian it's
about you right it's about the boy the
ending tells us that there are more
dragons but there are no more like you
there's no more children there's no more
people like you that can help you had to
be his guardian you had to be that light
he
go home otherwise when we experience
awful traumatic events we often need
help from those people we trust they see
us at our most vulnerable and they
protect us they guide us out of darkness
there are Guardians and with this game
you can learn how to be one too so what
does it all mean mental health and
mental disorders are huge topics that
have fundamentally affect who we are
everyone here no matter how powerful
their skills no matter what tools they
built is a person behind everything that
we do everything that we build our open
office plans even our people and we need
people we need to interact with people
and we need to be better people if you
suffer from a disorder you are not alone
if you know someone the disorder you
need to support them and let them know
that you support them that it's okay you
you know it's alright our intelligence
and skill has made us very strong but
empathy for can pay treats is the only
thing that really it all needs to be in
service too because if we can't have any
empathy this is all for nothing none of
this matters I strongly strongly
recommend checking out SpecOps the line
if you're interested in this stuff I
can't tell you a whole lot about it
other than the fact that this is my
favorite version hands down of heart of
darkness it is a terrifying experience
it is a legendary in the gaming industry
experience you got to see this thing and
on top of that no blades send you a
sacrifice if you're interested in this
stuff it does a better job of explaining
anything that I think I'll ever be able
to it is the most clear concise
straightforward and powerful experience
of psychosis that I've ever seen I've
never seen anything like it ever period
it's it even comes a little documentary
with it you got to check it out so thank
you everyone for your time I've got an
appendix here at the end of the slide
deck I'm gonna put up but I've got some
time for questions thank you very much I
really appreciate it
[Applause]
any questions ah yes
I might said okay all right yes yes I
will go out with you okay is that all
right I think about this stuff and spend
a lot of time with stories all the time
ah yeah what's up of course
ie it's like I mean it when I say I'm
not a psychotherapist uh it's like I
know that I can sound like I know what
I'm talking about
but I am NOT a licensed psychotherapist
those people are amazing and they
dedicate their lives to making the rest
of us better that's kind of Awesome
yeah I I wish everybody would put
appendices up yes yes yes I especially
with my particular condition I will
think about I need things that help me
key in that help me kind of I can never
really just like in devil daggers I
can't clear the platform I can only do
it for a little while I can pay
attention to one thing but that's about
it so I either need reliable methods of
distraction that are like say small
games maybe turn-based actually work out
amazingly because I can just pop in do
one or two turns and save and quit and
it's like okay I did the thing that
anxiety is gone I can go back to what I
was doing or if I can think about it and
especially in the case of stories they
affect me for a very very very long time
I finished the Last Guardian I guess
like I think was like last January or
something and the it still affects me to
this day I still think about what it
looked like what it felt like no it's
that one of the marvelous things about
games is that especially modern games
honestly is that games are designed to
be beaten you know even if it's a versus
game it's designed to be beaten and most
games are actually either single player
cooperative their design
to be beaten together or even with
online help or through all sorts of
things you can actually probably make an
argument that even InfoSec maybe one of
the things like I know that I find
frustrating is that if it feels like
something can't be beaten it's
frustrating and it's like yeah but it's
supposed to be right we know it's
supposed to be a solvable problem it can
be frustrating but it doesn't make me
feel worse it's more like I'm eight need
to take a break sometimes if I'm not
doing very good but I can go out I can
research I could take a quick break I
can get back and I can get through this
thing I can be better I can make my life
better and I think that's an important
lesson for everybody
hmm Oh once in a while I'll jump between
a couple but I've never just totally
walked away except for darksouls but
that's only because I thought it was
terrible
I know I know like hashtag rage really
gonna blow the Twittersphere he start
souls yes sir
offhand I haven't found anything like
there are a few that I can think of that
would be interesting to examine but I
haven't found anything yet that does
just what it's like or how to help the
honestly the very closest it's really
really really good is here I'll put it
up here real quick is really held late
it's not about her being bipolar
honestly
but in watching the video of how it's
done you can see how this this is the
way to be able to make something about a
disorder it's like honestly it is yes I
know you have a question
one of the things why I look at games
and while you think about games is that
games have been a huge part of my life
but as even my shirt is about I believe
very strongly in stories stories see the
the most off a little bit but stories
are the most human thing that you can do
there is no more human and endeavor than
you can possibly undertake then tell a
story we see ourselves and stories we've
told there's only 12 13 there's 12 or 13
types of story
and that's it and yet they're unending
you can always hear a new story you can
always hear someone's life that amazes
you with things you never thought of
before and yet we've been living with
how many people have like walked the
surface of the earth it's like that's
billions and millions of billions of
people right it's like it's it's massive
that's how many stories we made out of
just over ten and we're still making
them that's kind of awesome to me games
are a fourth medium we have visual we
have auditory we have written and now we
have interactive it doesn't need to just
be a video game it can be and can be a
real-life game it can be a sport it can
be anything even sports like one of the
favorite things that everyone tells me
about physical sports is that they tell
the other drama between where teams were
supposed to go what players beat what
players the backstory of it they care
about those stories the one thing that I
like about games more than anything else
that really separates them is that they
are an interactive story you drive this
thing it doesn't drive itself
if if nobody plays it it doesn't really
exist if you don't really read a book
the book is still out there tons of
people can play it
tons of people can read it tons of
people can experience a movie it moves
at its own pace whatever it is faster or
slower you can't really do much about it
but games games are a little different
games are something you drive you can be
a part of you can tell your own story
really great games give you lots of
variety and story I my favorite game of
all time is doom is my hands-down
favorite game I just played this thing
to this day I've been playing it for
over 25 years like I love this game
I still build things in this game and I
can tell you stories about doom I can
tell you stories about how it made me
feel about my life going up to this
thing about how it helped me grapple
with things like my ADHD knowing that
actually part of the reason I do better
in this is because of short bursts of
massive target priority I can't do
long-form things that was weird to me I
didn't understand but I do now
an interactive game helped me understand
that I didn't understand how to hack
things but I knew doom and I knew that I
wanted to pull apart wad files and I
wanted to make levels and I wanted to
make sounds I wanted to record those on
my weird little 386 and I want to see if
I could put those in for every time you
shot a weapon it's setup strange sound I
figured out how to work with systems
because of doom that helped me in a way
that I love books and I love movies and
I love music I love plays and all of
those things but they don't need me to
work but games need you to work they're
built for you they're only for you
that's kind of Awesome anyway so I get
really fired up about games and stories
and stuff so alright I think that's all
the time I got thank you very much I
really appreciate it
[Applause]