that's spooky you can take it away hell
yeah awesome yeah and thanks y'all for
everything so yeah this is um this is my
talk this is called adventures in binary
golf so if you've seen some stuff that
I've done I'm gonna power off this
machine real quick anyways okay so if
you see my stuff before I mean you know
that I really love really small little
old fineries so I like to make really
tiny things and just do generally weird
stuff with computers so and files so
just I don't know how to use this too I
never use slide that I use command line
first up so yeah so alright let's go do
it
so Who am I this is a view or net spooky
on Twitter and github my website is in
zero lol and I do a lot of things with
bugcrowd next slide here so talk outline
it's real simple we are just going to be
going over some file format hacking
stuff some various case studies abuse
use and abuse cases and different
approaches to elf PE files and then some
further reading resources so let's just
do a little brief overview on file
format hacking so there's been extensive
research done into file format hacking
different people doing stuff since files
have been a thing people be messing with
you know putting making tiny files
putting files and other files we got
it's awesome repo but the smallest
possible files
mims small anything is like a valid file
is um you know catalog here the smallest
possible versions of it there's also a
lot of cool research and stuff like
polyglot files you may have heard of
chimeras it's a phrenic files tons of
stuff like that you name it those kind
of things have been endlessly research
there's a lot of really great research
especially by and Albertini posted a lot
of stuff in POC or GTFO if you want to
see issue 7 article 6 abusing file
formats is a really good primer on a lot
of that and then also this really
I just threw it here cuz VI great text
in the chat VA great tech made a game
boy ROM NES PDF HTML and zip file
polyglot which is like I think the most
I've ever seen is really awesome so once
again keep clicking out of the way
window so if you've done a thug crow
challenge before one of our chat
challenges or one of our just general
CTF challenges you may have seen
polyglot files before so this is an
example I just wanted to throw in here
for file format hacking this is the
background if you've never done before
this is bad gif
so in Kuni 18 we did a challenge for Def
Con for a custom Def Con badge and so it
was a gif file where there's a polygon
file was a bunch of stuff in it so there
is a you know gif a gameboy ROM and a
zip archive or the main ones to actually
look at but there was like an elf
there's like a Commodore 64
demo there's some like Jas hook there
was like a bunch of ASCII art so I've
never been in scenes before it's a lot
of files in there and they're all valid
so if you want to see other ones to
others an example I'll top of my head is
the spider-man frozen elsa challenge
from last year which is a polyglot that
was used it's a youtube subtitle file
with a hidden JPEG in it you could only
see if you downloaded the subtitle file
and so for stuff like the Pogo file you
can create with a hex editor
some people use assemblers there's other
tools you can use I generally use a hex
editor just because it's easier for me
to come app things out so the internals
of this file just for curiosity's sake
so we have a gift at the top of the of
the file as offset 0 0 0 it's like a
very tiny gift
there are 28 bytes there's some random
asking yard and then there's Ana Gameboy
header 0 X 100 and then a very end of
the file is a zip file that contains a
text file and so basically he goes in
the process of it if you go back to this
sucker DICOM slash Chau slash bad shop
gif you can go through it yourself but
picking it apart and dude in the file
forensics you see that there's a valid
give at the top there all the rest of
the bytes are ignored and then there's a
zip file at the end of this Gameboy ROM
which is really the base file because
the Gameboy ROM itself doesn't care
about anything it happens that above 0 X
100 so that's just a basic primer on on
being able to stuff files into
themselves and stuff random you know put
her in filed around so when I talk about
this this leads into binary Gulf so
binary Gulf is the practice of crafting
the smallest possible mock binary that
still performs a given function so you
know any file that is is you know super
duper tiny but it still actually works
whether or not any other tools or
software can understand it all it really
matters is the operating systems running
it can understand it and execute it so
these can be created with or a lot of
compiler I generally don't use a
compiler to do these I basically just
use NASM and a hex editor if I have to
do any any mistakes you can you can use
like phazon or any other sort of
assembler if you want to I have seen
people do binary golfing with GCC
anonymous if you're listening he's
definitely made some very tiny things
with GCC and some crazy linker scripts
but it's a lot of work to do that and
it's generally a lot easier if you're
going to play around with this to use
NASM so what are the use cases for a
kind binary so there's a lot you can do
basically anything on here there's anti
debug anti forensics you can prototype
exploits and shellcode AV and detection
bypasses file upload filter bypasses
fuzzing malware loaders and fun and do
it's all the above is pretty fun so
here's some examples here the top one is
a GUID drah not being able to read an
elf file that I made
there's also s trace that I was using to
analyze an elf file but seg faulted
because I ran it trying to trace this
calls there's also some like borked
output from Reno and the very bottom is
a completely crashed so called VM on an
ESX host because of a file that I
I had Rome that corrupted the VM image
so approaches to binary golf similar to
polygon files but basically we start off
by examining the binaries file structure
so every binary is going to have headers
gonna have sections you know different
parts where data is stored so you want
to really like understand what the
actual binary structure looks like and
there's tons of tools for them there's
read elf there's tons of things for you
know pease basically just being able to
understand what are the different
components of a binary and being able to
like understand how they all fit
together so you can do a lot of this by
also analyzing specifications of the
binaries or if there's an RFC or some
dev notes I'm gonna be able to get a bit
more understanding about the format
there's also and like you know open
source parsers for files that you can
analyze that will you know allow you to
get a little bit more insight into how
those actual parsers look at and
understand in the file and so once you
get a good handle on that you can start
slowly removing things that you don't
need and so whether that's zeroing out
sections or patching you know specific
parts of the binary that are pointing to
different structures or seeing if you
can override certain things you know
what happens you can also use a fuzzer
to generate small binaries or you know
binaries in general that that have
certain sections fuzz and try to run
them seen a lot of cool tests with that
too and you can also use binary dipping
so if you say you get a regular compiled
binary and a stripped binary you can
look at the differences between those
and see where the extra sections are
that were taken away and so it's there's
a lot of different tools that come come
into play and there's no one right way
to do it but whatever works for you and
your workflow is you know all that
really matters so let's start off with
the ones that you may have seen the most
these are elf 64 so elf files are
binaries that run on Linux they're
executables so if you run Linux and say
have zoom you know zooms gonna be
compiled as an elf file when it runs on
Linux which notoriously cos I have a SLR
or a bunch of other things there
so before they have a lot of so these
include debug symbols all those things
that a debugger might use to understand
more about the file you know it could be
everything from you know certain
function names and variable names all
the way to like the path and the
compiler that you use to make the binary
there's a lot of unnecessary sections
and headers GCC likes to put a lot of
those in there they can ruin your day if
you you know weren't aren't doing it
right there's a lot of padding in the
binary to just lots of zeros that there
could be stuff you know stuffed into if
you ever saw the tick-tock that I made
of the docker run C you know finding
code caves in capes where you can put
data there's padding but it's still
executable I do that with a docker run C
binary and backdoor billet docker image
was a tik-tok would be a hit or miss
song there's also a lot of other extra
info that's needed by parsing tools like
retail for Rob's dump so all you really
need for a standard elf binary is an elf
header a program header and then code to
execute and so the big important note
here is that shared objects and kernel
modules require additional parts and
I'll get into those later
so County elf files so there's there's
been prior arcanist so there's a muppet
labs.com this one here the teensy elf
it's a very small elf file but it's 32
bits and so it doesn't run exiting for
Linux Cisco interface is different now
so the code doesn't even work the right
way and it's really cool I love the way
that it was done but it doesn't work
nowadays
so when trying to do something in in
2020 this is you have to look at it from
from modern perspective so I have a
bunch of 64 bit tiny elf examples so if
you go to github.com slash nets golf
club I have a lot of my tests in there
ah you can take a look at the source of
and see how I did it
so I updated a lot of them for modern
systems some of the payloads and other
things that are interesting you know
they they also wear you know older shell
code or are there little snippets and so
I updated those as well for modern
systems though you are interested in
and how to make shellcode - that is
another big part of this and you can
look at that repo for it as well and I
wrote three parts of a blog on binary
mangling as I called it of how to
actually go through the process of this
and what I did for the research so when
you're doing elf golfing basically
you're going to need to do a few
different steps and so a lot of my
Berryman figured out this is kind of a
workflow that I did so I went started by
stripping the necessary headers and
sections which is a you know it's only
one bullet point that's a very very
large part of it is figuring out what
isn't needed
the other big thing here which you
didn't go and look at my my blog post if
you want more information about it but
overlaying program headers with elf
headers or overlaying any sort of
headers in general significantly makes
the code or the header smaller but what
you're doing is reusing certain values
from other headers at the same time so
there's this specific binary here there
are parts of it in the thing that's
called SIA and the little label that's
used my mouth like almost halfway down
this is not only is it code it's part of
the elf header and the program header at
the same time so it's parsed three
different times for the kernel when this
executes so this is a very very
important piece of this too is if you
can figure out ways to point headers
elsewhere into the file and move them
around then you can overlay them and
create you know put multiple values and
use them for the same purposes so this
is takes a lot of time and energy to do
to figure out but once you do you have a
really tiny way to go or tiny template
to work with so the other big thing
about this too for binaries is storing
code and other data in unused sections
of the header so headers even though
they have these structures that might
need to be a certain length or whatever
they might still not actually care about
some of the values there's some of the
things like flags are only using the
last three bits of the byte writer or
however big the size of it is and so
that means that you can as long as those
three bits are set correctly for
executable
you know read/write permissions those
you're still able to execute it but you
can also use the first let's say you
know like five bits of it first some
other piece of code or data so that part
is also pretty complicated that you can
read my blog and more about it too but
we're using values from the header and
those are all you know parts of it that
are really important short jumps to
locations in the header so if you see
SIA and Reeb and start as labels in here
these are all all these little jumps
here are just jumping around the header
because I don't have enough space to put
all the code that I want but I have a
little bit of space and short jumps are
only two bytes and you can use those if
you have four bytes you can still do
something like the Cisco command or move
a l0x a nine and then jump somewhere so
being able to do that kind of math and
figuring out where you can actually put
code and how you can jump to and from it
is important but there's a lot of cool
resources that I have in some my blogs
the other big one is loading the binary
yet 0x1 I'm in a bunch of zeros
basically that's used so let the e entry
for elf header and P type for program
header matches and it's loading at a
very it's still within the 64-bit
address space but it's um it's pretty
high so next is okay so I saw obviously
have a day golf thought so so there's a
recent CTF challenge to create a shared
object that's under a hunt 24 bytes it
also pops a shell so there's a link here
I want to make the slides available um
shortly after my talk but so shared
objects are really cool they're
interesting because they they have a lot
more strict checking so if you do
something like say what I did up here
where the start is that 0 X 0 floor in
the health header you'll get messages
like this and say that you can't load
something because it actually checks
whether or not these values of where all
the other jumps and stuff are in start
actually are so it's actually invalid if
this whole thing is varies a lot it's a
lot more difficult to do the techniques
that I had so shout out so the people
who actually solve this this is really
small shared objects also yeah I was
invoked using le pre-loaded so golf
thought so II so what this is this is
the source code for it and you know what
they did basically here was determining
the needed section so they have the
dynamic sections with BP string tab in
it and some tab and they put these in
here and it's still overlaid with the
program header and the elf header and
the dynamic section is also overlaid
within the program editor too and then
their code is right there I tried to
make this smaller and but it's it's very
packed this is a very very good version
of this code here they use NASM though
the same degree at the final binary and
the resulting file was a hundred eighty
five so look a lot of elf here elf is on
you know more of my specialty but I
started to work with PE files and they
were a bit different than what I was
used to
I'm similar sort of I guess techniques
but I'm not a windows person at all so
if anybody who is one in here forgive me
but this the exciting piece because
there's there's different versions of
Windows so each version of it may change
the spec slightly so there's there is
been prior work on this and there was
you know changes between Windows 2000 to
XP to Vista cetera and so none of those
work in Windows 10 so I had looked for
resources for you know modern Windows
systems and I found the PE files must be
greater than or equal to two hundred and
sixty eight bytes for whatever reason on
Windows 7 and 10 and so I saw some
examples cork ami or endeavor teeny had
done a lot of work with PE files this
hour RCX flush tiny PE repo is really
cool actually gave me a framework to
look at first to see how somebody
actually would make up tiny PE because I
think they use Visual Studio which I
don't know how to use so I don't know
how they did it but I I had translated
to NASM and work from there and so but I
had come up with was a tiny PE
you know had done similar work to what
like my ELF files did but I used some
more techniques but there's a slightly
different thing with PD files so this
for encode cave is really important so
the same things to do before we're
putting little bits of code in like a
couple of bites and values in the header
is really useful
so I identified some different caves
that I can put stuff in so there's like
you know 12 bytes that zero exceed 2 0 X
1 8 and stuff like that so identified a
bunch of them by analyzing all the
different headers and figuring out which
ones weren't used and then put my code
in there after the overlay and so I use
short jumps again to hop around the
header and you can use a buzzer to to
check for these but my process is really
manual because I was trying to figure it
out myself so a lot of these headers
that are in here I'm actually used it
just pretty cool so you can even though
they're big and they're annoying looking
you can still put you know code in them
so what my my you know POC buyer I did
was launch calc XE so I used the peb to
win exec technique to launch calculate
XE but the shell code for it that I
found was a bit longer than could fit
into the actual binary it was like 310
bytes rather than 268 so I was like all
right I'm gonna shrink this payload down
even more so I optimized more of the
shell code by writing it like you know a
little bit a little more optimization
and then I manually patched and put
stuff in the header so if you see the
side here this is all the header being
created so you can read the PG mangle
write-up that I did explains it a bit
better but these are a ton of jumps
within the PE header so there's it looks
really really crazy now that I'm looking
at it trying to explain it but there's a
there's a lot of these things are
overlaid and there's like multiple times
where it's parsed like three or four
different ways while executing so I
basically done no it took these caves
here and basically just put all these
jump labels into here and put a code in
there and work
the actual flow before I get to the very
last line of this thing on the side jump
six that is the actual start of the code
section so there's a ton of code that
happens to set up reading the PDB to
read kernel32.dll in this but if you
want to read more about this there's a
big write-up I did it recently and yeah
so cool thing about this dose so you see
all this you see all these different you
know pieces of code and you are able to
pick where each individual byte is and
so what you can do with it is defeat
detection so there's a lot of detections
for for small binaries and weird
payloads and stuff like that and so tiny
PE is very very well known this
technique is not me
and so there's detections for them that
are on virustotal there's tons of them
that run yarra rules for them and so I
was made aware of one of them that was
put out there because I'm gonna chair de
yarro' rule they had written about it
that I thought had caught this on
virustotal
and so what I tried to do is see if I
could actually defeat this so what I
ended up doing was if you see the little
circle red red circle there I changed
one bit
within this to be a zero and now it's
just a zero one so one bit and I was
able to actually bypass the yard rule
because it would have checked because
even though it's very small and there's
a lot of stuff is going to be in the
same places they're still extra data
that you can put in there and so I
rewrote the outer rule to actually make
it catch this but this is an example of
actually invading this detection so if
this detection has been in place for a
long time um this would have still been
able to you know defeat it and there are
still ways to actually get around this
detection but yeah this was the this is
like an example of being able to control
each individual byte and also showed us
his shell because he had actually done a
ton of work on fuzzing Vitti detection
engines which are really funny I don't
have a link to it directly right now
she'll probably can post it in the chat
but very good write-up on on how fragile
you know antivirus stuff still is
and so I'm getting towards the end of
the talk here so lessons learned
you don't need huge blow to the software
to run binary programs in 2025 parsers
are generally pretty lazy and they only
really care about a few things to
consider a file file whether it's a tool
that parts of stuff or you know your
operating systems kernel mostly buggers
and binary parsers really do suck at
understanding minified binaries like
there's a couple of minor areas that
i've found that it can be open in
anything but when re2 and red are a true
struggles to open it I've also gotten
passive so not even but all right you
can open it but yeah you can move you
make files that basically like no
program can read the only the operating
system can understand which is pretty
cool because if you're writing anything
that's wants to be secret you might want
to have me something really small and
nobody can read but even with a tiny
binary even with a very small surface
area to actually move by surround if you
want to throw in extra bytes to defeat
hash now something you can still bypass
detection it's definitely possible
you've got to be creative and see you
know where you can can move data around
and binary golfing can give you complete
control over every single byte in your
file so if you like that kind of control
over something definitely a fun thing to
play with and you too can add a hole in
one
so last is other resources so burn re2
is a great for debugging weird stuff
it's probably the best thing in my
opinion for debugging weird stuff
there's still issues with you know how
it actually works but as far as being
able to understand certain things that's
my go-to for you know biases file weird
and what's wrong with it if you want to
look up court commies stuff amazing work
and opportunity has done you know making
files more accessible to people file
formats archive team.org
is another amazing site where they have
catalog tons of file formats because
there are kind of team for archive.org
and they are trying to you know save all
the files and lastly I did a stream a
few months ago called intro to assembly
optimization and it talks a lot about
this sort of techniques for actually
optimizing your assembly code and making
it even smaller and smaller you know
Shoko basically and so yeah that's
pretty much it for for this I'm gonna
stop sharing them quick kind of briefs
do it really fast cuz I was started a
bit late but like yeah