next up we have sniff from Ventus table
and and so pentose elaborate talk we've
heard sniff on the third crab podcast
I've done a bunch of pen tester lab I
highly recommend it some free stuff you
can try and then if you liked it you can
you can go on but let's get on the way
with the pen testing ninja one sniff
hello everyone
ok that's outfit DNZ you look very
pretty so for people who don't know
what's behind me it's like an old TV
show Dark Angel part of it so my name is
Louie
I work I do like this thing named Penta
Sara but you may have heard of it but
the ends I recommend and today I'm gonna
talk about code that gets you poor so
basically my job is to teach people
where bad security or OPSEC basically
and by doing that I'll come across a lot
of bugs and how people find them our
people fix them and our people exploit
them and I also do like especially
during lockdown I do a lot of code
review because that's something that
helped me relax weirdly enough so I do a
lot of contributors
some interesting patterns and I wanted
to share them so that's where these
talks come from so the first one is in
golang and that's handler to manage when
someone is uploading a file so basically
what you do is you upload a file we've
you get the file from form file and
that's the parameter file if you don't
get anything you print you get an error
message with print and then then you cry
to defer to close the file so that's the
way in going to say like Oh after
everything is done just clean up called
colvett closed method when
call IOU TL temp file and pass to
argument / 10 and that's where we want
the file to go and handler dot file name
but the name but we got from the HTTP
request if we get an error we return
when we read everything from the file
and we copy that in the file we got from
10 5 and if everything goes well we
close the 10 file and we successfully
uploaded the file so what looks pretty
safe right there's nothing like really
really bad about it
however if you look at 10 file you can
see that in the documentation the 10
file is gonna cry the file in the first
arguments dear and it's gonna and you
can pass a string to say like ok I want
this new 10 fight to look something like
I don't know file - 1 2 3 4 - gee peg or
file - some random number but a 10-5
will pick for you - something else and
you can use the start for the wild-card
to decide like ow where the random
number will be put so it looks pretty
sad if and when you can use F dot name
to get a path of the file the problem
comes from the fact that if you use 10
file and you see like oh I want my file
to be created in / 10 but as far as the
file name you put like a directory
traversal and you put like dot star
slash dot dot slash dot dot slash root
slash food at startup specifics for
example the file will be created in
slash fruit slash through that something
and that's pretty surprising is as a
developer you for like also file you are
gonna go in slash temp right so I got
something you need to be aware of when
you're developing going application and
using temp file so of a problem is that
in golang in most let's say in most
frameworks like Express or rails or
things like that
when you have a directory traversal in
the file name like we have here the
framework will just give you base name
of the file name that was provided so
you can do dot slash your way out of
that
but in golang it's not a framework is
just program
language so they give you like the
finance trader as it was sent by the
user so that's why this kind of issue
come can happen
and you need to be aware of that because
if you use Express and move to Golan you
may be surprised by this behavior
because you have never seen that kind of
bugs before and saying if you come from
like a writing background so here yep
and so I reported that and it's fixed in
recent version of golang so they were
like a bit of back and forth with going
development team because if are like oh
that's not the pattern that we see often
that's not a big issue inside but at the
end they still manage to agree and
change fees behavior to say like ok
avais the dot slash we should probably
like that's not a bad pattern but that's
very surprising if we look at other
languages like Python descent bad
behavior I didn't report this one yet
but I should probably do it so if you do
10 5.9 temporary file and you want it in
slash temp and you pass a prefix of the
dot slash route your file will end up in
slash route so if you think of thing
like uploading a web shell somewhere
that's pretty handy if we look at will
be will be when you pass so the first
argument is pattern and the second one
is a directory if you pass a directory
traversal as part of the pattern it's
gonna remove the slash and create your
file in /tmp where you wanted it so yeah
so that's kind of like surprising
behaviors that I really enjoy when doing
code review and that's something where
you just like fire like a nya B shell or
Python shell and you start like trying
and see what works and what doesn't and
first one are pretty interesting because
that's kind of tricky bugs and if you
quickly read the code you can't find
them you just need to go into deep
understanding of the code another one so
that's really command so here we have a
Python application but that could work
in any language so we're gonna get a
endpoint named fetch and we're gonna get
a URL parameter named e to you hell and
if you use a URL starts with pandas
Telecom we're gonna fetch that data so
you can think of these as
Paul wanted to avoid server-side request
forgeries of they put this jackass UFL
that starts with when desolate that car
most of the time when you doing coverage
it's not as obvious like that you need
to look in the configuration file to
know like what's the actual value of
Pentastar that kameez because you're
gonna have like a global variable or
something like that but the promise that
starts with is a really bad way to
validate you FL because HTTP colon slash
slash trusted that pentacel a becomes
starts with trusted because you don't
have a slash at the end of trusted same
with HTTP colon slash slash trusted ads
Venter celibate combatants will start
with trusted and you can imagine
chaining bug to get bugs together so if
you for example have a URL but is
trusted and which generic is you can do
trusted /zw case dot slash file upload
or link to an app an already right to go
to another server so you link to the
open redirect under trusted server but
so how can redirect allows you to go to
a mattress or an hour malicious web
server and that's why you shouldn't burn
open already right and same for header
injection you can use that because you
can potentially create a response with
whatever you want in it so that's why
before doing starts weave you should at
least make sure that you can you can
even equalize the path the URL to remove
or the dot slash to make sure that it
starts with something sign start with it
but in Ruby or each body's any language
but sometime it can even get nuts so
that's C sharp so what's on so when
you're using dotnet and here we have a
string and s and we want to make sure
that the UFL starts with HTTP current
starts because we want things to be
secure right and when we using the
default web client class and we call it
a new web trial and we download string
based on the URL so we just fetching
content so that looks pretty good like
you can potentially have server-side
request forgery but you don't have
anything worse than that right if you
look at this code and actually that's
kind of surprising but you do
so if you pass HTTP s : sudo service -
UTC possibility you're gonna get the
content of makisi passwd but for a Linux
on dotnet and something if you pass
another file on Windows that night both
what the crazy thing is that when you
exploit a directory traversal on Linux
you have this limitation but all the
directory in your travels all need to
exist and you don't have this limit in
Windows it when you're exploiting
windows and dotnet mimic the windows
behavior even on Linux so even if you
have a directory that does not exist in
the chain of your directory traversal it
will work if you're using dotnet on
Linux where with any other programming
language on Linux it won't work because
that's not all supposed to work right
and yeah so that's pretty surprising and
I love this part
now another one is her handler that's
gonna take a file name from the URL
again in golang and it's gonna open that
file name and differ FD dot close so
this way so five will be closed on to
the requests is on the response it's
sent back if there is an error it's
gonna return like a four four five not
file and otherwise it's gonna copy the
content of the file as a content of the
file FD to the HTTP response so
basically it's just starting a fire and
here we can see that we making things
secure by using path that clean because
pub that kink in right things so if you
look at path dot clean documentation we
can see that a /e we have a lot of
examples and how they're gonna go for
path third key so we can see that ace
she become a slushee a slash she
becoming a /e the dot slash a be the dot
slash slash slash C so the one before
the last one become a slushee so the
developer you look at right and select
that's exactly what I want
that's exactly what the security guy
told me about dot dot slash those are
bad after clean remove dot dot slash so
that's what you get if you
read the documentation and actually it's
not actually the case what part the King
does it cleans a path he doesn't remove
like dot slash magically he just tried
to canonicalize the path as much as it
can so if you do dot dot slash dot dot
slash dot dot slash a slash B you still
end up with dot slash dot dot slash dot
dot slash a slash B because these paths
are as clean as we can be for pastor
King so that's something said in a
previous talk and someone tweet about it
and fee Depot is looking at getting this
example added to the documentation and I
did like some notes around security but
again like so golang development Timmy's
B is pushing back saying like that's
probably not the right thing we probably
don't want to put like security
implication of every function so you
probably got a bit of time before that
gets fixed everywhere another one is
regular expression people get regular
expression wrong all the time so let's
say you have like an event listener in
HTTP in an HTML web page and you want to
make sure but the origin of the message
come from Pinterest about.com and you
want to do that because that's the first
thing when you look at how to create an
event fist a nice check the origin so
you create a new reg i've swift dot
pentacel Abdallah because you want to do
to make sure that the origin ends we've
come and nothing else so otherwise the
bad guy will be print a solid col dot
bad guys dot net and its origin matches
you do something sensitive so here's the
problem comes from host name and a
regular expression works really well
together when you want to find bugs
because here the ray guys will match the
www.pmtasetup.com any subdomain dot
pantyzoo.com but also wwsz pentester lab
dot-com and wwz went to STAR Labs econ
because the dot ins a regular expression
our wildcard and here they have not been
expect so but something people already
failed to understand or fail to the
property is that if you have dots in
your regular expression you need to
escape there
and sometimes you have this regular
expression in a configuration file so
it's not escape properly so that's
something you should really look into
like that's a good way to find really
cool box another one is around this
little snippet but does okay it's an
Express application but it works in
another lot of over language you have a
list of a low domain example.org
gmail.com google.com and when you fetch
content from the domain you have this
handler but we say okay if you access
slash fetch and but the value of domain
to uppercase in using the list of your
allowed domains we're gonna fetch a
content otherwise we send you a for free
and that looks pretty saying nothing to
be worried about right so bring that
there was various really good blog post
about someone who found a bug in github
and you have characters when you
uppercase them change so for example the
Turkish dot lest I become an uppercase I
and gmail.com if you register a domain
and you do to uppercase on it becomes
gmail.com so here you just need to
register gmail.com with I without the
dot and you're in the white list and you
can get your content fetched so if
you're doing bhagwanti it may be worth
registering domain that kind of match
the domain that you are targeting with
just this kind of weird characters so
this is a list again from the same blog
post and that's this blog post got me
thinking like oh this is interesting I
need to look in more depth on that like
that's really really interesting so I
start digging and digging and digging so
first you need to know that that's an
expected behavior that's the most
surprising thing for me so if you look
at the Unicode documentation or our
implementation guidelines like if you're
normal
you should get from like I to uppercase
I and dot less I here become uppercase
as well and then you have like other
weird behavior but if you oh if your
local are configured to be in Turkish
lowercase I become uppercase I with a
dot and lowercase I with no doubt became
uppercase I with no dot so even if your
system even like this behavior will be
different between two system with
different locals between like u TF n
Turkish of course so that's really
really weird and but good bugs like
really interesting facts to look into
and if you want to play with words you
can check these two ull captures of Ag
one two three four and captures of Ag
five six seven eight so that's two
challenges you can play with if you want
to like get a better understanding of
these kind of bugs I'm gonna keep them
running for like two days maybe so we
talked about regular expression we
talked about Unicode what if we mix the
two what happened so if we do a compiled
very light version I and we try to match
the less I it doesn't match so I kind of
expected so that's in Python 3.8 for now
let's add to this regular expression R Y
dot ignore case so basically match
without taking into account the case and
we sang we can see that dhoklas I
matches I so what's interesting that's
an expected or kind of expected behavior
but that's certain now we look at other
things so if we look at upper case s
will match the long Latin s if we use
our either ignore case and upper case K
will match the Calvin sign if we using
our Y dot ignore case so that could be a
good way to bypass a regular expression
if the regular expression is using our Y
dot ignore case now we move to Ruby and
Ruby so if you want to match so I
the real expression I if you ignore case
doesn't match that less I same thing if
you using an upper case I but Douglas I
as we saw when we capitalized it become
upper case I so what's kind of weird and
it gets weirder is that even if that
less I doesn't match I if using in okay
so the /i at the end here so Calvin side
will match uppercase K and lower case k
as well as long as you ignore the case
and same thing for the Latin long s it
will match upper case s and lowercase s
as long as you ignores okay so you have
different behavior between different
characters so that's pretty odd now if
we look at golang I'm good and we do
exactly the same as Ruby so I will not
match that as I so in golang if you're
using a regular expression you need to
put them at the front like that so
bracket question mark is for ignore case
so we can see that dot less I does not
match I but K but Calvin sign match is K
and Latin long as match is s so again
some interesting behavior that can
create pretty interested pretty cool
bugs in c-sharp we have again a
different behavior so that's really a
good weight maybe to fingerprint
applications so we can see that dot less
I match doesn't match I but Kevin sign
much is K and the la la Latin long ass
doesn't match s if we're using in your
case and another interesting thing is
that you can use in C sharp is ends with
and there are a lot of ways to check if
something ends with something else so
you can use the default one but we say
so test that dot less i NC doesn't end
with i NC but you can use environment
creature in no case what would give you
the same and you can use ordinal ignore
case that gives you true and current
culture ignore case that give you false
unless I will say you're in Turkish I
haven't checked that and as a friend
said like it's what we come back from
all the bugs fat
were found in Unicode in windows back in
the day so if we look at Java now so we
see that all these characters are equals
if you in okay so that less is equal to
I is equal to or less I and KKK curve in
sign or equal to each other but if we're
using patterned encode pile and we're
using regular expression the dot less I
will not match I so long Latin s will
not match s and the Kelvin sign will not
match okay so again like moving just
from like string comparison with ignore
case to a regular expression may change
a behavior between two applications the
code looks the same
I'm just going to move to a regular
expression it's more efficient but when
you change the behavior of how it works
and why does it matter let's say you
have somewhere in your application that
checks for but a domain match is
something with your eyes something with
a s and you ignore case potentially you
can use it but you can bypass this by
registering the right domain or
something fleeing with a k but it's less
likely because it's pretty as far as I
can tell really hard to get to domain
with a Kelvin sign in it and simply for
an email address you can think of
company that say like okay if your email
address ends with Pentastar calm you are
an admin in this application and if you
do that you need to make sure that
you're not gonna get use ignore case
because you can use this bypass to
bypass this check and register for
example github.com with a lot less eye
or gmail.com with less i or things like
that and that's it for me so conclusion
computers are hard devil is in the
details
don't make assumption i think it's
really important to do code review
that's for sure and to try to build upon
people's research or like for example i
start looking at this unicode because
someone sure like did a write-up or a
cool bath and then you get deeper and
deeper and deeper and you find new
things that are interesting and you find
new but and you talks about you talk
about this new
bugs and then someone else we keep
digging digging digging and find new
bugs and that's how you keep finding
bugs and yep I think I'm a bit early I
got five minutes to go
yeah and don't make assumption because
the snippet I show during restore kind
of pretty safe if you like just read
them quickly but again you need to look
in the F and see like okay this looks
suspicious
maybe I should like start an IRB shell a
Python shell or write some golang and
see like okay how does vast function
really really work like what are the
boundaries what can i push it forever
okay this part clean seems to clean but
how well does it clean we did clean if
something is encoded will it clean
unicode really do something else like
yeah so you need to make sure when
you're doing code review but you go into
all of these details
otherwise you're missing like really
cool bugs as we saw in this talk and
yeah thanks for your time and you shove
any question I'm gonna keep like hanging
around for few minutes after the talk
and yeah
don't hesitate or shoot me an email or
add me on Twitter and I would be more
than happy to answer your questions and
that's it for me thank you so much that
was awesome I'm never in a chair have
any questions here on the chart because
was I didn't want to have both running
at the same time because I'm in
Australia and Internet is terrible here
yeah
no yeah oh thanks so yeah yeah I think
there is a good comment about the good
thing is that yeah a lot of people are
moving to it I think the interesting
part is what people are they are used to
develop with frameworks and then they
move to go and
have a framework anymore interests of
like a programming language so it's like
everyone moved to like smart PHP
framework and you can't find as many
like tear about PHP bars and now we've
go we go back to a programming language
without using a framework and you can
find all those bugs because people are
back to not having a framework to
protect them yeah
now as definitely as well it's it's
tough with the new languages it's just
it's harder for for people who's just
starting from scratch basically so like
you're given the toolset that it's given
and then it's difficult to you know
really know where to go from there
because so many things in so many
different frameworks that are already
taking care of all like they're really
benign sort of things that are security
testing and it's you know whether or not
it's incorporated into the full overall
you know like structure of a language
it's like there's stuff you can still
important easily
important looks like jQuery versus like
trying to implement all that yourself is
like you know yeah yeah that was awesome
though so thanks very much for coming
out here and and giving our our final
presentation of the day it's what I
think me yeah of course
so