um so yeah mg will be on here he is
going to be talking about rapid
prototyping chaos so for those of you
who have followed mg at his his work he
has done a significant amount of really
really interesting projects with
hardware including backdooring
everything from charging cables to power
bricks to you name it he's probably back
door in it and so he has a few projects
that are out there that you can purchase
the OMG cable and even Steve you may
have seen some of his POC videos I heard
him on our podcast in years past but he
is here to talk to us about rapid
prototyping hardware so yeah it's almost
guess the minute everybody tweet out
about this if you want to and initial
folks from the foot crab alright you
hear me yes we all right we are good to
go um I switch over to my desktop real
quick and share that doesn't my about me
slide it's really all I got
I'm going to talk about the last I don't
know about your worth of the rapid
prototype you know done because it kind
of changes the way you think and here's
a just a stack actually about six months
old now stack of all my failures like
all the PCBs I've made that just didn't
work but before we get in there and go
back to 2017 before I knew how to do any
of this I decided I wanted to make an
exploding USB Drive
I just cool idea right but let's cross
it with the USB rubber ducky cuz you
know naturally had no idea how to do any
of that so I sketched it the basic
schematic out on paper that's literally
what you see here and this is the
physical layout
the board it's uh it worked right like
there were a lot of software packages
out there for designing things that it
was just too complex it was just more
hurdle than I wanted so I was gonna use
some some paper right and didn't know
how to make PCBs but I found these cool
grids of copper squares called SMT pads
and what I was using to kind of
construct this very first prototype
using copper tape and stuff it works
kind of you know assembled it and that
was the first prototype here I call this
mr. your self-destruct all right and
here it is you know chopped off a USB
connector from an existing flash drive
because you know where do I get USB
connectors right
um this had the little bonus if we go
back up in to this schematic over on the
right is basically a kind of like a
relay that would allow an additional pin
to I want to be careful here but
basically that allow the the fun
activities to happen later on that was
really the only addition the rest of the
circuit was basically just an eighty
tiny that would Bank bit banging is
where you may not have inside the
silicon of the chip the ability to do a
certain thing in this case this chip
didn't have USB but we can turn on and
off the pins really fast and emulate
what USB is expecting on those lines
rest that circuits already you know
well-established so I just took that and
added a little high power relay to it
and ultimately what we got was this
plenty of room inside here for all the
activities and I don't have sound shared
here let me see if I can do that real
quick that's crew whatever we're good
anyway
this was the first mr. Sol District
right so you plug it in and ducky pelo
come out and once on the screen opens
your browser
and opens the video and you see little
Jack in the Box here you hear the
jack-in-the-box sound is what you would
hear if I had sound sure but I don't and
it goes for a little bit longer than
you'd expect because you we got to build
tension right and then eventually pop
bunch of confetti flies out that's cool
put other things in there like smoke
bombs right looks pretty cool ultimately
you know that that was pretty cool uh
what else could I do with it and I
started playing around with this
basically really tiny duckie which you
know the actual USB rubber ducky has way
more spacefill and it's a lot faster but
everybody knows what a ducky is so just
using that as a general term here this
started shove the demon seed inside of a
cable and that's where we got this right
my cable didn't actually work as a cable
it just look like a cables it's not
really a cable but you know there's
always room for improvement there basic
idea there right
it was chunky eaves big is you know very
the very first one right and might as
well shove that into a USB condom at the
same time right why not
that makes sense it really every looks
at Oh cable is why we need condoms I'm
like cool you need condoms let's up
your condoms same concept right polish
this up a little bit more and suddenly
we've got a little bit same concept but
now it charges we're not getting data
sync yet but it charges right which is
an improvement and visually looks a lot
better it's not exactly a match to a an
apple cable but it's close from a
distance but
you know if we will want to use this for
actual offensive to lean it's probably
not gonna pass when it's in the hands of
a target
it looks cool on stage that's about it
so but a year later so that was all 2017
very early 2018 but a year later I
decided I wanted to kind of ramp it up
actually here's a there's a good
comparison it's a close match but you
can see this this physical the large
connector here on the right and the top
is it's a bit chunkier it's longer it's
a close match but it's not perfect
anyway year later I decided I wanted to
chase that further let's let's get data
passing through so it's a real cable
right he works like a real cable data
passes charges but also you know let's
let's update these payloads remotely
because that's kind of what I would want
to do as an attacker and are you wanting
to what you just saw every time you want
to update a payload there you have to
plug the thing in update it you know
cool and it will just play under your
computer as you plug it in you can put a
delay but it's much like a rubber ducky
in that sense plug it in and then it
starts but in addition to updating them
remotely it would be cool to have a
trigger that's remote you know how do I
do that
I have no idea it's just I want to
accomplish this how do I design that and
about a year ago year and a half now
decided okay um software when you
approach it at least the way I approach
it it's it's really quick to just change
something compile see what breaks see
what changes just keep doing it over and
over and over that's you know a matter
of seconds per per cycle or spin with
hardware you know creating a PCB weeks
roughly per spin you design it and you
send it off to some manufacturer now
there are in-home methods for doing this
and that's what I kind of started
exploring there the older one is using
acid to etch copper off of a board so
fr4 or there's multiple types here but
I'm using fr for basic concept here is
you've got copper at least on the top
layer sometimes also the bottom layer
this is the number of layers your PCB is
so this is a two layer in between you've
got some fiberglass and epoxy mixture
that's just non conductive that's the
basic of what a PCB is and ultimately
those get turned it into PCBs right and
here's a raw fr4 panel right it's it's
just all copper sheet on at least one
side and then that yellow you see is the
fiberglass protector so here's a mil
cutting out traces instead of using acid
to remove portions of the board we're
just using a mill and this is quick it's
a lot more accurate more repeatable in
my opinion anyway and that's what I
decided I wanted to start chasing you
can see the process here millet solder
starter things up and boom you get a
circuit and it's it's pretty fast
process you know maybe an hour roughly
per spin depends on what you're making
how big the before it is complexity but
that's just what I wanted to chase like
cool I can now take my approach of rapid
failure to learn how to make these so I
decided to get one of these Bantam Mills
they're like 2,400 bucks now there are
other Mills out there they're much
cheaper I specifically went for the
Bantam because the software flow is
really easy just dump the file out out
of your design software Linda the the
Bantam and it abstracts a whole bunch of
things that are kind of connected to do
a C&C traces and Rob was called speeds
and feeds you know the mechanics the
physical nature of your tool movie and a
lot of that is abstracted into pre-made
libraries for you so it's like quick and
easy and you know I can save a revision
to my PCB and pull it into the bantam
software you know in seconds you hit go
and
new PCBs ready to go so on the Left I've
got kicad this is just PCB design
software this is the mr. self-destruct
at the time I pulled this in I'm like eh
that's gonna be like my hello world for
the Bantam mill I just got and the red
layer is the top layer the green is the
bottom and put let into the the bantam
softer right and probably took an hour
or two of back and forth and eventually
you know this pops out it's like cool
this this actually worked um would
fitted a cable pretty nicely so great um
hello world let's let's chase this
deeper like let's get a finer traces the
the mils advertises not being able to do
these smaller footprints but we could
definitely ain't chase it so lots of
testing here different depths just
really repetitive iterations just to see
where the boundaries on on this mill are
this board looks wet because I've got it
covered in oil fr4 it's fiberglass and
when you mill it it's glass and dust up
in the air so you got to have some way
of either rapidly vacuuming that out
which I would later upgrade to but oil
really really heavy oil kind of paint it
on would do a good job of trapping
everything so more more testing right
test test test
and here's some microscope shots on the
top this is just a minor difference here
but you can see the traces nice and
clean on the bottom really rough on the
top and the difference between those two
is just the tips of these bits right
here the one on the left with a little
sharper tip was making these nice clean
cuts and the slightly rounded one would
make these rough cuts and you know you
don't you don't really know and I I
would always buy the cheapest tips
because they're called and mills rather
I was breaking these a lot and you know
I can't pay 25 bucks per get a 10 pack
for you 20 bucks so you know figuring
out what is a good good process here
took a lot of iteration
around and ultimately here's here's a
much more detailed board that I was able
to get out of this after doing these
tests and you know that's great
we've got copper and clearly uh places
to put our components we can solder
these on it totally works but we're
missing one key thing and this there is
no real good solution so I started
playing around solder mask right so
that's that green or whatever color
you're used to seeing basically it's a
lot like UV cure nail polish right
there's there's a solid film and other
stuff but the most part UV cured gel is
the basics of most solder mask one
common way of applying that is you know
put a sheet down and you're using sheets
of like transparency film that have like
black printed on it to block off UV but
you know you've got a mil so why not
just remove that right so I was able to
get pretty reliable results here and
here's the basic process I end up
settling on its first you cut out your
traces put some tape down apply the guru
you know it's gel right here this is the
UV gel and then scrape it with a razor
blade the scotch tape I put down here
kind of acts as a shim so I get this
nice thin layer of gel and I take a UV
LED this is a really big panel I started
with like a UV flashlight but I didn't
like waiting so you know I got this like
a 40 watt panel that just happens to fit
inside of the mill perfect right let
that go for a little bit and then up
pops a cured layer of SAR mask and then
I started just using the same engraving
bits here to remove the cured solder
mask from the areas I needed it removed
over the pads and you know work pretty
well but ultimately I discovered the
things called drag tips and again
expensive but I talked to a somewhat
local tool manufacturer and convinced
him to make a really reduced version and
this is kind of what popped out and this
is what it looks like so a drag tip it's
got this engraving tip mounted inside
like a spring mounted call it around it
so that allows the softer solder mask to
be eaten away and the copper is harder
so the tip kind of stops and hovers over
its you can't sit for too long but it
buys you more time so that you're not
cutting through that really thin layer
of copper quite as easily and this made
the process a lot faster and that was
great
and I was kind of the result right get
this and then you cut it out cut the
holes got the perimeter pull it out and
there we go that's you know that's the
the basics of what this process looks
like now one one problem with a lot of
these is a basically one problem with
all homemade PCBs is the vias the vias
are what transfer conductivity from the
top to the bottom so you get a hole that
goes through and the easy way is to just
put little tiny wires and solder them
into place on both sides and it's kind
of what you see here those little blobs
of solder I started playing around with
a couple different other methods using
conductive epoxy and stuff like that
these all were interesting it's not
super reliable all the time depending on
how much current you're passing through
it but again you can produce some really
good-looking results with it so you know
here it is the vias are hidden under
that solder mask and playing around with
a lot of different designs and
accidentally did a cross-section it was
cool because you get to see that the
conductivity of the top layer passes
through to the bottom layer just what we
were going for
this isn't good for just making you know
little prototypes and what uh when
you're designing things bread boarding
for instance breakouts are great but
that restricts use to you know parts you
can find breakouts that match right but
you know what if what if I just make my
own break out school like here's this
chip that I didn't have a break out for
it is fairly common you can find
breakouts that match this but again I
also don't have to wait for delivery so
that's cool I'll just make these in a
day or you can make you know custom
little breakouts like I wanted this
specific component it's really tiny
component that wouldn't fit in a bread
board or on here
I wanted that in line on USB for some
testing and you know this is what I got
out of it you can make full-scale a full
circuit prototypes we can also make
these little breadboard expansions so
again you got some really small
components you want to test them on a
breadboard oh you know how do you do
that especially when you want a very
customized breakout so you know here
this is our right and we get real small
here that one on the right on the red
that's a BGA component and there's a lot
of different ways to go about it I
started to playing around with the
solder mask define left right so instead
of bringing your solder mask up to the
edges you actually bring it over the
copper so that you get smaller detail
and that allowed me to do things like
this right so this this I think there's
a point four millimeters between each
ball here Center to Center point four
millimeters and that's you know really
tight and you can't really pull traces
between those balls but you can do
interesting tricks like you can see here
there's a ball that's missing because I
run a trace underneath and I use the
solder mask to kind of insulate that
layer so we get this very first
prototype this was oMG cable you know
the one that
in what was it it was 2019 February uh
you know worked barely had a lot of
failures so many different attempts at
this just just in that first month is I
started in end of December and early
February so I think it was like five six
weeks to go through the whole process to
get the very first prototype working it
just barely worked and that's kind of
what you see here that's a little over a
month of playing around to started
playing around with different approaches
of programming and you know I I lost
track but this is several months later
it's getting closer to what would
ultimately become the production version
of this know again the OMG cables that's
the you know the wireless connectivity
he's got a hundred times more space I
just I really wanted to see how far I
could take the concept like the eighty
tiny with its what like 8k of space is
cool but let's let's add like a mega
more let's add an 802 11 radio let's put
a webserver in this thing let's like
just see how far we can go
and that was the point of the oMG cable
right and you know we're gonna need to
start playing around here we're getting
close to production I need to solder a
bunch of these together let's get a
toaster oven and mod it and that's gonna
allow me to solder a whole bunch of
these oMG cable components onto boards
using solder paste you know basically
put that in the oven for a very
controlled period of time and it allows
the solder to melt and all your
components get attached get the family
involved too because you know things are
scaling up more the family
this isn't def kind of like nothing ever
stopped it was barely done in time this
is me still assembling oMG cables in the
hotel room and like heat curing
components and stuff uh but before Def
Con I said I had this idea of like hey
let's also make a whole bunch of the
eighty tiny versions you know they're
really low gray but you know they're
interesting to people who still gets
that concept of a malicious cable it's
not really
for field use but it looks like a USB
cable and it's malicious from a demo
perspective right but cool let's let's
make that on a whim there's like a month
before Def Con I'm gonna make a whole
bunch of those that's kind of what they
look like hand-assembled e is this this
sucks
um but basically the solder paste on
this panel and all a bunch of little
components is my wife helping with a
tweezer putting every little component
on every little panel and here's me
programming them on the airplane he said
we would call these demon seeds to
differentiate them from the Anki oMG
cable but of course nothing's ever done
time here's a whole group of people
awesomely helping me in a hotel room
pack all these into the little drug
babies that I chose to use for the
packaging that was great um everybody
loved it I was not expecting that little
$20 bags you know hand out kit uh
everybody was asking me after death kind
of like oh I want to buy these I want to
buy these and it's like well this this
was not something that I thought was
worth like mass producing and selling so
I thought you know what can I do to make
this better so I wanted to get a basic
wireless trigger functionality and get
data passed through working without
really adding any components and
ultimately I had to add I think it was
two more resistors to the entire circuit
I don't have to put a USB switch to put
an antenna or any of this stuff on air
and it it works the antenna kind of
barely works right but that's the point
it's more of an educational experimental
thing to play around with them which was
what everybody likes so that's kind of
where the the v2 you're version and
that's what this board would look like
and me this kit and I was like yeah you
can sell it on our site it looked great
cuz I don't care about fulfillment or
anything like that I just want to make
it then you get it you got these pins if
you can see right here bottom left
there's a bunch of there's like six pins
needed those to program it as part of
the kit right
sort you know certain count six pins per
bag that sucked so made this little
tumbler that's gotta a vibrating arm
vibratory feeders what these called you
know 3d printed this a lot of failures
but ultimately you know God we get this
working it was great and it would
dispense you have six pins at a time in
a little Dixie cup and we put all the
other parts and make a whole bunch of
little bags and see going on right here
packed a whole bunch of demon seeds into
you know hack five bags great um come on
screw picking place so instead of
tweezers let's use the machine to place
these little components on board so
start it here basic concept is starts
off so this this machine uses cameras to
see what it's doing and this little
white strip of paper hair contains
little components the camera sees it
lowers a little syringe uses a suction
to pick them up and then places it onto
the PCB that already has paste on it and
I'm testing here by placing on
double-sided sticky tape slow yeah kind
of worked first results things were not
aligned ultimately we got it there and
it was fast at this point you know a lot
lot faster than we started a lot of
modifications and we can see it you know
rapidly placing components onto the
boards
field of panels here it works um
the addiction keeps going of speed more
so you know I'm using a mill and a 3d
printer to make these feeders and
feeders would feed instead of putting
these strips of tape on the table and
have to carefully calibrate where it is
just have a feeder just kick up a little
component out one at a time and just
goes back and forth um oh this was
Christmas vacation with the family in a
hotel and we're like well we got to pack
all these oMG cables which had just come
back from the factory those components
are so small because everything is more
complicated here actually we had a
factory do it
and still have to test them and bag them
and you know that's basically what I was
doing in the hotel room when the kids
went to sleep and of course nothing is
complete without a really cool logo so a
year ago saw this cool
dust dust real made this awesome shirt
like man that looks cool
you must be logo huh I should do like
this you know it's thinking oMG and I
need a cable design right
my wife said that that just looks way
too phallic and I'm like oh yeah I see
it now
hmm that sucks but you know this was my
reply to her tweet the EM threw it away
you know came back months later when
demons he came back I'm like wait a
second maybe it's not an OMG cable logo
and this is the demon seat logo because
now our the the weakness suddenly became
a feature I said dust really exist for
me like it was crap and this is what he
made so this this was the demon seed
logo that popped out and it was great
like holy this is perfect man and
then OMG cable of course needed its own
logo cuz totally different result and
that's what came out and here a lot of
you know revisions he was making but
anyway that's kind of like the end and I
still wanted to leave space for
questions do we have yo let's see MJ tho
sorry I said it was sick I always loved
your hog Rafi of razor blades just
around the place nice all right there we
go
oh yeah do we have any questions is
anybody in the chat any questions for M
G here Dean says show us the Furby oh
man I have to go running on the house to
get that the Furby I have so many ideas
yeah the Furby is this horrific I mean
we just want to make the Furby as ugly
as possible and just horrible as
possible for instance one of the
features is that just popped into my
head I think the other
is every time there's a general
sentiment expressed on Twitter that is
negative towards offensive security
tooling I would like the Furby to
release actual flies from its mouth
so I don't got all of that working
except for the sentiment analysis but
you know skill six is what's the next
step what's your next I never know
that's the thing everything is this like
I presented this in a fairly linear way
but the reality is all of those were in
tandem and they would come up and go
down off the you know the the work table
and I just had this table in my mind of
just things that could be or things that
I don't know what they're for I just
know I need them for later and they all
just kind of assemble into whatever pops
out um I've got some really cool stuff
that we have been chasing on the og
cable that you know hopefully we'll be
able to show off soon together I mean
there's there's refinements as well I
mean I had like a 40% manufacturing
defect rate on the first batch of 'omg
cables so I think I've got that worked
out now but I mean that was huge if
anybody's in a manufacturing like you
know you've got like maybe 1% or 2% I
had like 40% and that sucked
um but chasing things like that has been
consuming a lot of time and all this
stupid around like business and
like registering and I hate that stuff
so thank you hack 5 for offloading some
of that for me it's great and what if
everybody wants to like get some of
these things or just look at some of the
stuff go deeper
I have archived a lot of this on oMG lol
oMG lol is where I got the blog oh down
MGE LOL is where i got like the products
if you want to just kind of look at
what's in that landscape there's this
was a very quick speedrun significantly
different yeah yeah you can go check
so on the screen the stream but yeah oMG
oh well lol if you were wanting to look
up either of those