I've made it welcome hell yeah so we're
super excited it's Luigi blitz turn is
done for telling people versus
engineering so y'all haven't heard of it
it's a satellite modem for the SNES it's
really really cool history of it there's
a lot of really interesting things that
happens with the tell of you it's Luigi
but is gonna go and tell us all about
what he has learned and how he was his
approach to reverse engineering it so
super stoked luigi bud you are you ready
to go yep oh yeah take it away ma'am so
I I'm blood and I've been we'll talk
about how I ever since you need the
satellite view
stuff my ability to speak English so
this stuff will be like I will present
what the satellaview is then I will talk
about how I reverse engineer it someone
who didn't know really much of anything
and then I will talk about how it
actually works to hold that what we know
of it today and then pretty much like
what I've learned out of this process so
first I need to explain like what I do
for the most part most of my focus has
been about mostly obscure Nintendo
things so I've been working on Saturday
view I've been doing some 6040
preservation I'm in Mission and I have
done some leaders stuff in the past
hopefully I will get back to it and then
if you know me a little bit you know
that I have had done some CGI stuff in
the past with some HD high quality rips
and so my knowledge like in 20 in 2010
so when I started to reverse-engineer
Citterio
I learnt programming with basic the next
thing I've done was like a hello world
on blue for the Super Nintendo it was
quite a mess of code when I look back to
it and every time I tried to do
something I asked everyone all the time
I expected other people to do stuff for
me that's pretty much what was my level
at the time and it was also like I was
like around 15 or something just to give
you an idea of
was when I was about to do this kind of
project so now let's talk about the
Citterio so instead to review is a
peripheral for the Super Famicom that
allows you to access satellite like a
service by that was managed by Nintendo
and sent Giga you could end up games
magazines additional content for some
games that support it and you could also
listen to radio which was something that
scindia was pretty much all about and
some games also use the radio broadcast
as part of the experience is also I
think that Nintendo doesn't like to
acknowledge all the time some sometimes
we do release stuff and sometimes I'd
like to bring some attention like in
Super Mario DC but most of the time
reserves don't talk about it
so one of the main reasons why I was
into a Saturday deal was very detains
there were many like original games that
came out for it
between a news of the game a remake of
the fizzled but somewhat different way
there was also some Mario games some
really obscure stuff that we never see
anywhere else some games like radical
dreamers which was a sort of Chrono
Cross some kind of Chrono Cross prequel
rather a draft of the game that was that
we did not consider you and then there
are tons of other original games that
came out for it and some things
sometimes we will release on as a
cartridge so now how did I begin reverse
engineering
well first of all I looked up most of
what I could find about the system I did
not care at the time if the information
well-situated was try to look for
everything that I could and at the time
I had a basic which is the listing with
which just like just which resistors we
use but none of their purposes and then
a bit of emulation code for memory packs
that we're in emulators that was pretty
much all that I could find at the time
and how this thing with Super NES is
really like in 2010 debugging was a mess
they were really limited to pretty much
just racing and quick points and that
was about it
there were there was also like a
disassembler but it was only a toss
application so I had to corrupt some
emulator for it but most of my work
most of what I did was tracing tracing
and lots of patience to figure out what
is even happening so to give you an idea
of what I - I decided to take to talk
about the first thing I pretty much
reverse engineered which was the memory
back because it has the most information
at least at the time and basically what
it is is just flash memory storage it
was 8 megabits which which is 1
megabytes you do the calculation they
were apparently four types of them and
it requires a rig compatible cartridge
which is the PSX or any any other games
that used it like an RPG maker so we go
a little bit technical on how it on how
I try to figure out where
if there is was like anything to figure
out and it mentions something about
vendor information and you Cruden a bit
by reading some some by use into the
memory and then you've identified out
like there was like MP so I assumed like
it was about some kind of ID and then
there was another another value in there
which was which was pretty much
something like did we know much about
and this thing says when a so to figure
out that that stuff I was rather lazy at
the time so I did a run hack instead I
did figure out where the bsx cartridge
loaded this information and I replaced
it with just hard coded value instead
which is explained here
and then I fired out like the game that
I had loaded name later was loading like
four times for some reason there was a
list of four times the same game and
then I figured out like with some trade
motivating and stuff I forgot like when
I change one a to one see it was reading
four times the amount the amount of the
memory which meant that instead of eight
megabytes it was 32 megabytes so that
was that installation vehicle is not
something that ever came out
but just by doing this I kind of figure
out that most of the reverse engineering
technique I use I figured out on pretty
much my own I use it is assembler for
just to get to the code that I want
without necessarily going to trace trace
logs which I did use it then to figure
out the flow and the flow of the code
and then I did lots of blind were making
which is probably not the best thing to
do because then you don't necessarily
understand what would have happened
sometimes sometimes when I do that stuff
nothing really is noticeable but it's
always much faster to get an idea of
what I'm doing and hopefully gets into
more detail later and then I figured out
like most of the some of the BS techs
save data I will explain vsx a little
bit later how to download content and
how to use the memory back batting with
e-reading erasing and that's all that I
have kept like logs of what I did before
like in forum post and especially video
logs where I've shown my progress
throughout all these ribbons engineering
so you can still find all of them like
on YouTube on my channel
and then in the middle of all that I
stopped everything because something
happened and that was no cash as in yes
this simulator is made by Martin cough
aka no cash and this person is also
known for making a huge amount of
documentation
and also just being really good at
reverse engineering and this
documentation came up came with full
documentation of downloaded content it
also came with like full documentation
of the beer of the PSX and how he had a
screeching engine and everything so
basically messed up pretty much stopped
right there and then it was just all
about using that work and hopefully get
somewhere with it
so that's basically how I did most of
what most of what I figured out
throughout the whole thing but now let's
talk about like the actual thing of
pretty much everything we know EFT
so first of all I would like to talk
about the BSF Scot which because it's
the thing that pretty much was the base
of all reverse engineering because it
was pretty much a BIOS ROM for using
this attribute the satellaview
hardware it is pretty it is pretty
complicated sometimes because this
coverage is unique because it uses it
uses a very unique hyper mapper that is
only used for this and basically it has
a memory back slot and then a matter
that maps the BIOS from the place run
the SRAM and then there's something else
that we found out that according to a
penton's
it was internal flash memory but it was
removed so that was pretty interesting
and then the chip that passed that
manage all this is called the memory the
memory map controller and security chip
which
Taine's American stroller and the seed
ship that makes the cut which work on
the Super Nintendo or Super Famicom in
this case so let's explain what the BIOS
run is about so the BIOS ROM light it
has whole most of the basic functions to
use the satellite view and memory pack
it also came with a bike : gene which is
used for most of the interface but also
some medicines that came out there's
also like some kind of operating system
with a trading system
and also obviously the menu and also
fonts that games also used but the most
interesting thing about the functions of
the BIOS ROM is that you can and did
update them there's a jump table in the
restaurant where most of the functions
from the PSX got BIOS ROM have code from
there is all there is a lot of jumps in
jumps that part where you could just
pretty much replace the jump jump to
another part of its families contain the
updated code I did jump back to the bsx
run whenever that's necessary it also
has many saves engaged safe which some
of some of the parts of the SRAM has
proper checksum checks to make sure it
fits in corrupted or not
and basically the bsx is like a whole
like RPG like menu
which is so neat and oh really try to
make this as friendly as possible but
also a little bit charming
it looks like hot bummed but it's not
actually developed by any there is
actually no real stuff in common between
this between these two which is
interesting and the thing with like bsx
is that there are also a lot of NPCs you
could set up you could set up also this
season there is also like a fountain in
the center of the town where pretty much
where you could change it to pretty much
in almost anything and there is also a
building that you can change to whatever
you want so basically the PSX use pretty
download service that pretty much all
the time some of them are shot in
updates and some of them long-term like
like for certain
you pretty much download spread like
constantly every move all the time and
this this data is pretty much like a
status ID which basically means if it
changes that means the data is different
now so it replaces the data with the
news there is also a directory ID which
I will explain later
there is also audio setup where you
could set up pretty much if you want to
enable sound effects music
or the or the radio or not and then the
there's also a bunch of NPCs you can
enable with like the maximum of five
with some exceptions and then a list of
available via DS which which is pretty
much like when something can be
downloaded it's available on this on
this service data then the first thing
they downloads it's pretty much a
welcome message where as soon as you
connect as soon as you start up the town
you see a message I mean could be pretty
much anything that we want to write and
then in terms of long term there is the
directory which contains an ID which
went is which is which if it does not
correspond to the town status then then
it will update in contains the folders
which contained file files all items
because since the menu is pretty much an
RPG
you can also buy items that are mostly
useless and then there is also expansion
data which contains the event Plaza
which is the bird which is the building
that change that you can just you pretty
much anything you can bring in pallets
graphics also and also like where is the
tool in building and you can also bring
Justin by code for custom NPCs and then
there is a patch system where you just
print the address and data that's how it
updates the BIOS on the rest from
folders are pretty much like every
building and NPCs yet you can find which
means that you can you can also change
you can make them as sharp shop for
items you can also make them something
NPC that gets
to download a game or other content so
and you can also make them say pretty
much anything you want
since the folder contains a name and
also a description which is actually
like the first thing that you see when
you talk to them or or opportunity when
you go go to the building and then now
let's talk about cetera view so that's
that was pretty much the basics of what
ESX does but now let's talk about like
how it actually downloads stuff so the
side view is pretty simple on the
outside you can you can see that there
is a PS import which contains the bit
stream of everything it downloads it
plugs to the extension ports for this
per Famicom and and you can also notice
there is that there is also an extension
pot on the Saturday view which is a
first time IDE thoughts kind of thing
and where you can use it for a hard
drive or or maybe make an adapter for
compact flash which is what someone else
did and what's inside is pretty much a
PCM decoder for the audio for the radio
something called the SPR BSA which is
just an in from which contained the
serial number of such a review then the
main drain of it all is the data channel
decoder which is not just doing what it
says its way it means so to first to
explain what the data channel decoder
can do we have to talk about what's in
the satellite
well what what's in the bitstream is
pretty much like a constant a constant
frame frame up the frame of that
contains PCM audio channels which can be
like up to four of them so you can do
like up to two stereo tracks of audio
and then there is a data channel which
is con which contains pretty much
everything else including the gains and
VSS service data there is also error
correction for everything and that's the
part that we don't and not everything
that we entirely understand yet first of
all before it gets to the data channel
decoder it goes to the MN a eight nine
two two one which goes pretty much like
this it described all the data during
the leaves and then it manages the audio
for itself
and then sends the data to a data
Channel decoder so then you can do way
when it needs to do
so the detection a decoder is not just
decoder is pretty much how you
communicate to the satellite view all
the time the test destiny decoder first
of all this is what it is supposed to do
with the data but it can also do some
management which pretty much spoilers on
the decoder the PCM decoder and the
alias and the LED there is a general
purpose input output which is mostly
used for the extension pot as well as
well as muting the pci module if need be
there is also a SATA interface to access
the EEPROM and the PCM decoder and then
it also brings a custom address
interface for the extension bonds so the
data channel so I have to explain what
it contains basically one packet
contains all of these things it contains
a prefix which contains the logical
channel which basically is pretty much
an ID for the data whether the packet is
the first
or the last odd none of these or both
because obviously you can just put every
data in 22 bytes so you have so it's
pretty much a chain of packets and then
there is a continuity index which is
mostly used to make sure there's nothing
missing in between and then also an
additional error correction for
everything
then there is the datastream register
sets so that's what this printer can
access and that's what the bsx use there
is a logical channel selector which
basically adds like a way to select to
make sure what data we need there is a
prefix hunter which basically is about
like the amount of packets that in the
buffer a prefix first in first first out
where you get the prefix data also a
data before the data and also an or gate
which is used every time you read the
prefix the prefix it actually all the
data into another register so you can
just check that resistor for every
packet that you're about to get and you
can easily figure out if there's an
error or not
so here's pretty much how the data
channel decoder works the data channel
goes to a messia I compare so if the if
this is what you select is the color so
if the data channel packet goes goes to
the decision Airport decoder
it only gets you only takes captures so
to speak the packet that we want with
the right LCI then it performs checks
with some checksums and continuity
checks and then it puts everything into
the prefix person first out and the data
and then after that everything is pretty
much handled by by the by DBS expires or
any other cartridge that best support
this
for technical parts personally I don't
want people to use the real hardware
except laughs for documentation or
possibly other special cases that maybe
we hear about in the future so what did
I learn out of this so first of all or
when I reverse engineer this review I
learned pretty much low level system
knowledge of this I learned how to how
to run hack properly also learned like a
bit of art with knowledge so when I
looked at hardware I can get a basic
idea of what I'm looking for and how to
document stuff everything I learned from
this I tell you was used to figure out
the 64dd
so that's pretty much the end of this
talk
lot of people who worked on such a group
reservation and documentation and and a
lot are still being discovered today so
I really would like to thank Davey
pockets like in the last few years
tooth for helping figure out how the
satellite data actually is and maybe
we'll be able to use the actual sensor
data to figure out how it works and then
maybe provide like cropper experiences
that internet on a relation
so that's pretty much it for this talk
thank you for listening that I made like
mid like in 30 minutes I thought it was
going to be shorter for a second and
then longer but we have our next panel
coming up so if anybody has any
questions for the wee people or wants to
talk please go to the air-gap
discord and you see stream Q&A channel
if you want to ask any questions or talk
given how much sure however much time
luigi but actually has but yet that's
what we're talking about stuff so and
yeah we don't have a discord but we're
not that fancy here here's the here's a
link to the this boom already so maybe
are we going to be Irena be restarting
real quick the stream yeah I believe we
will be brief slotting right now