heard of this before twister shell is
basically twitch plays trying to hack my
server so if you want to I guess break
into this this is it if you want to try
to try your your luck you do it so
basically here's what's gonna happen
we have this box here and you have to
there's a file what's called like secret
dot txt somewhere on the server that you
have to find and you have to prove esque
via twitch chat so this is gonna take
we're gonna basically spin out of half
an hour about this and then we have our
next talk if we don't solve this by the
end of this 30 minutes we will be doing
it again later during YP crackers that
at the end of the stream so don't worry
if you either aren't around or somebody
isn't around or has to leave right now
they probably will be time later I don't
know people might be able to just
actually hack this box to then but for
the time being let's get started missing
a double check this works so watch this
not work but yeah so this is this was
pretty funny to watch last time and we
needed to give a lot of hints I think
this time probably the lessons
but uh we have more people playing so
you'll have to fly the little bit harder
to get out of life ah let me stop this
share real quick
but where my leading controls are there
there one second I have to just try to
restart something Ryan see I believe
there is network access
but will it help you who knows
you're gonna download every known risk
Under the Sun please try one moment I'm
just uh just getting in here all right
one moment just double-checking this
works we got it
we did do the computers use the computer
all right here we go
so we're gonna do a shout out to the
Duchy for your somebody sold you a
challenge you by the way the Duchy so
you can do this control see that if you
need to escape something so yeah this is
it
you can't remove everything it's
definitely not the first thing everybody
tries to do but now you have to wait for
it to finish with its RM before you get
to do anything else
so yeah this is pretty much it you're
gonna have to wait a second
so you should try to cat assignment dot
txt I just in case guys know that
you
so now you're in cat how do you get out
of this
you
korto mushing
as to whoever
[Music]
how about this people who are here
there's a thing called assignment txt Oh
perfect
I'm studying apps right to talk about
this anymore you guys this is uh you can
escape from from this bye-bye there's a
way to escape this this happened last
time too
you send an escape by doing a carrot see
yep yep got it well
you
so
[Laughter]
that's your killing it over here you can
do it escape with control C on this
there a lot to collaborate yeah you
watching this you here right now you
have not escaped yes alright so you got
a control C there I'm terrible at this I
can try to make it bigger alright what
the hell you guys trying to do there's
um two called an assignment d XD so
you're trying to figure out what's going
on you have this bins here
I mean everybody get some some chaos
playing there shout out to chaos
okay yes yeah she haven't listened to
young Internet should definitely check
him out he's some Club
cool so you got out of this everything
is getting is getting out before you can
get out and yet I peasley
[Music]
hello that's actually one about speeches
later on so the point of this whole
thing is there your your Carter and
you're trying to prove that you are able
to be a part of this party and so you
have to have a bunch of credit card
numbers and you have to check by Amazon
gift cards with and that is the purpose
of happening now but there is a backdoor
somewhere on the system that will allow
you to prove ask that was something that
was supposed to be a monitoring tool so
how do you look for those things so
somebody's monitoring your box and it's
not everyone on Twitch what do you got
howdy what's what is this box I think we
got shell with this now in the
commentary man classic classy twitch
plays but think this this in an attack
is
shock you which is challenge especially
I like
[Music]
if you were to find if you were to be
looking for some back door or somewhere
how would you go about
[Music]
yes so it bends definitely a slight you
can look for the sketchy ping there's
some pretty good one-liners out there so
your your guys probably have to do ctrl
C here yeah you can use you know there's
a user flag of the group flag on fine I
don't know if it I hope
[Music]
Oh
final boss new files have nothing in
them so you guys are still in vim right
now forever the final boss at wish to
show
[Music]
like the people that's been trying the
CP challenge
[Music]
fuck this up
yeah can you can you I want to see
someone trying to navigate now I was
just just you can do it control oh you
know what happened here with ya so what
are you trying to do again you are
trying to prove s there's a back door
somewhere on the system that you have to
find how would you find it back door
yeah you need to go it yeah you have a
shell already I never write the file
separated
[Laughter]
[Music]
so when did we first do the first wish
to show so we can see that so
interesting right what did they what
have they done before maybe maybe you
can look at what's in some other
directories there's anybody really
LSE anything where did it come from
you're on the road check their 1000ps
one is just work all those Birkin before
I mean it's still Bergen now right
so we're gonna do another five minutes
of this and then so we are going to do
another five minutes of this and then
I'm gonna get
so I don't know we're stuck in this is a
a server the big carding server credit
card fraud and you are being tested to
see if he will actually do the using the
tool to verify credit cards and so
there's a back door on the system to
make sure that you know a stealing cards
and be
you did Joey Joey on so now you should
go to that folder
nice helping it's done before the so now
what was that file that was in flat roof
hardball
exit codes
well so that's uh you guys have actually
broken it so good luck good job breaking
it all together it's all working
yep that's our MRF instead of actually
doing something it's done
oh good job yes from breaking it up
solving it but you guys did it so I'm
sure that's a Joe a on DMS on Twitter
anymore but yeah oh