my name is Mohammed Abbas today we will
talk about small thoughts multi-factor
authentication using smart cards and
Android on web first we'll discuss
authentication and then we'll present
our proposed solution this talk was a
part of my master's research in National
University of Science and Technology
authentication is an important security
control to protect the system regarding
CIA properties to protect the system
form an unauthorized entity the
authentication process is basic and
first line of defense millions of users
have been affected on that from all over
the world because of unauthorized access
unfortunately in this puzzle so as we
saw user authentication is important and
require to achieve our security walls
and I've seen mobile transactions are
expected to exceed 100 billion dollars
by 2020
we can use NFC for authentication
purpose with smart card as smart cards
can provide strong security to
authenticate an entity to achieve our
security goals objective of this
research is an alternative approach for
secure the user authentication which
provides mutual entity verification
using smart phone and smart card for
more than 15% of Internet users have
reported experiencing the takeover of an
email or social networking account
making progress to make a password free
world we will review the shortcomings
and strengths of popular authentication
factors and select the best approach for
small table knowledge-based based
authentication has some problems like
remembering according to a psychology
review an average person tends to
remember only 7
random characters of debt approximately
one two three four five six was still
the top password in 2080 according to a
Google research in the case of third
party data bridges 12% of the exposed
records including included a gmail
address serving as a username and
password of those passwords 7% were
wellick due to reuse microsoft says to
50% increase in fishing in year 2018
other known issues with passwords
including but not limited to social
engineering more where's key loggers
shoulder surfing if your password is no
longer safe due to a better wage
password check up gives recommendation
that you should change your password
immediately it's a prom extension by
Google I will recommend to select this
roles in cyber security system is only
as secure as a weakest link it has been
established that humans are still the
weakest cyber security length we can add
we can add multi-factor we can add to
multi layers of security to authenticate
and authorize user if one pointer fails
the second factor can still protect the
system home and not first entity because
of limited time I would like to refer
something you are authentication factor
to a talk social engineering and
emerging multimedia technologies
conducted last year here in besides me
on the speaker analyzed this
authentication factor in details
this is evolving technology in the talk
the speaker discussed tools which are
available to generate real-time fake
targets even some are using AI n in
future it could be possible to
impersonate any
two factor authentication is recommended
one of the influence behind this
research was an alternative approach
home SMS authentication telecom shared
on small location in my region on the
time of my studies as some as two factor
authentication won't work in low
coverage areas until you can receive SMS
for example in high tower buildings or
basements tracking subscriber location
obtaining call details
tapping intercepting text messages that
contain security codes are the harsh
reality will live SSS seven
vulnerability weakens SMS two-factor
authentication NIST has restricted the
uses of SMS one-time password and
organizations are taking risk while
using SMS OTP signaling system salmon is
a thirty years old
out-of-band signaling protocol
originally designed for wired networks
in closed environments later SSS seven
integrated for wireless networks without
encryption in GSM international mobile
subscriber identity historian SIM cards
Chinese authenticated from home location
register after authentication of I MSI a
specific mobile switching control
provides cellular service to the
subscriber to send commands on SS s7 the
attacker can obtain access with only
several thousand dollars with can access
from with only seven thousand dollars
from black market ss7 attacks may be
performed from anywhere
additionally the hacker does not need to
be a highly skilled professional either
attacker sends update location ss7 come
on to H a lot in such a way that SMS are
redirected to a fake MSC
of the target subscribers they are taken
now intercept SMS of the target
subscriber which may include OTP or
other positional information Google
Authenticator works with shared secret
key this generated time-based one-time
password with server and user user has
to enter the OTP within 30 seconds if
there is a database and the attacker
gains access to the passwords and
secrets then he or she will be have
access to you user accounts unlock this
security tokens are portable devices to
authenticate users adds an extra step
for typing lots of numbers and an extra
device to carry with you
requires battery to operate they tend to
work poorly with mobile phones people
don't want to use authentication that is
not seamless when I was looking for my
master master's thesis topic my
supervisor dr. Abdul Ghafoor Abbasi
he showed me smart cut and PayPal mobile
card reader that Plattsmouth smartphone
audio tech he guided me to work on smart
cards with smart phones as smart cards
are becoming new normal
identity smart cards does not require
batteries to operate and are protected
from all waves this is the basic
architecture of smart card open platform
the card manager is the code component
for open platform it provides interfaces
for one word services and interfaces to
the outside world a Java card Jacob has
a Java car virtual machine to run smart
card application written in Java the
function of security domains is to
provide keys and cryptographic services
for applications for example symmetric
or asymmetric cryptography
smart card microcontroller physically is
protected by different
layers or passive and active security -
which includes sensors embedded in the
tape had an attacker has to work through
many fold of security measures before he
can gain access to the secrets on the
white we have photo for human hair in
comparison with semiconductor structure
of smart card microcontroller on the
other side with the chip is chip in
depression the lower picture the lower
picture shows the electrical potentials
of ram cells are measured using an
electron beam destin scramble scrambling
of memory cells is the present
protection from this attack smart card
can be used with both contact and
contactless readers having to an
interface hybrid smart cards can have
both smart card chip and RFID this is
common our employees employee ID cards
for physical access control systems for
two-factor authentication
most solutions are required to trust
third party we discuss SMS OTP and
observe the vulnerability Google
Authenticator does not provide mutual
entity authentication for example
attacker may gain access to shared kill
former death of break even even if we
implement two-factor authentication it
does not mean that we have secure
authentication with half secure
authentication if we design it securely
in this video two-factor authentication
implementation had a design flaw where
the client can send a random phone
number during the second factor flow and
the server sent the attacker the SMS
one-time password holding account
so this is quality peak just so this
this is our ability Justin isn't
watching we propose smart of
multi-factor authentication using smart
card and Android one F with public key
provided the architecture of smart auth
is designed to achieve security through
obscurity with PGI it is divided into
two parts
suicide user site includes Android smart
phone and smart card based on public key
infrastructure certificate authority to
verify entities we use open SSL gin to
generate self signed certificate for
concept authentication server to
authenticate authorized entities
database of authorized users in center
we have smartphone running an Android
application I think as a medium to
communicate between web and smart card
for mutual authentication purpose smart
card module is to be responsible to
communicate between smart card Android
and Android over NFC for a successful
authentication Papa user the user is
required to authenticate first with
password on web secondly we then
authorize smart cards one smart cards
one smile are secondly with an
authorized smart card on web with smart
phone communication with smart card is
done by apdu commands IES odep is
required as android supports different
NFC technologies actually we had a one
problem while using smart card I had a
hybrid smart card which was also an RFID
and smart cards so as per Android
dispatch
for NFC technology because and have seat
there it was going to enough see death
and was not selecting as a smart card so
it was take a lot of time to figure it
out that actually we need to select
highest death for communicating with NSF
and also the smart card the smart card
has javacard PKI is a open source
project for the support with java and we
integrated smart web mail server got a
PKI project we follow Phipps one Lansing
protocol entity authentication using
public key cryptography Phipps 196
protocol was introduced and published by
list we have to end it is that we want
to authenticate virtually on web one
entity initiator a is suicide and the
second entity is user side responder B
which enclose Android and smartphone for
second factor authentication with smart
card
server sends authentication request to
smartphone while a push notification
with a token ID Android responds with
token the a one and a random number RB
which is actually a random number
generator from smart god next several
are generators of generates high
pseudo-random number and this early
signs are a concatenated with our be the
random number sent from smart card and
sends back to the smart home ok at this
step at this step when it receives the
smart the smart phone receives that
deserves it signature token a B it
verifies that it is validated and after
successful barrel validation this aware
the entity is verified then smart card
digitally signs the random number all be
concatenated with re a sends back to the
server after
successful validation of token beer to
both entities are now mutually
authenticated let's see
smart toward election after user name
password user selects device they
receive a push notification one
smartphone and using smart card after
wiping their application distance
militant is sent back to the server from
smart hand sign bus Muslim and on there
it is authenticated successfully the
summary of whispah analysis of smart dog
is safe as we are using public key
cryptography and follow-up its 196 I
will spa stands for automated validation
of internal security protocols and
applications the be spies are tool for
analysis of Internet security products
and applications
the prodigal problems are written in the
high-level protocol specific language
and automatic it automatically analyzed
with hospital according to the
specification of security protocols
small thought provides mutual entity
authentication protection against replay
attack as validity or patent occasion
request one is only 120 seconds prevents
phishing and man in the middle attack
during my research Phipps 196 protocol
was announced obsolete and also be
withdrawn because it has not been
updated since February 18 1997 we
continued with Phipps 196 as it still
provides the required security for small
dog as of now alternative afips 196 is
not announced yet political cryptography
is a next-generation approach to
cryptography that uses mathematical
formula
it provides better performance and
greater security with small key size as
compared to RSA keys we are specifically
interested in sccp 256 k1 the Bitcoin
elliptical curve 12 implement with smart
ID with that will have more security
with smart earth and a simple yet secure
wallet a cross-platform smart card
wallet with two-factor authentication
awareness about threats and protection
is the best defense
this is an email from my bank on
educating users about cyber threats and
how they can protect themselves from
different threads thus some references
and thank you very much
[Music]
how does it protect against man in the
middle attacks Italy yes it's a very
good question how this small talk can
protect men in the media as I so you see
we have a random number two if I can go
back to D this one for example this is
mutual entity authentication so we have
our a and our B then the signs are a and
it also sends the array within so there
is no like this is a rule cryptographic
secured random number so it sends from
server to the time and it has this own
RB which was sent in register in
previous strength now from sour hand
from its own both random numbers the
validate that is original and the
certificates are validated by CA in
architecture that we visit
this one so the certificates are
validated from this one and the
signature is validated with I and our
way so it prevents actually the
mechanism so similarly the next step
next step is to reverse random numbers
like first it was RA because it was sent
from server next step is RB it is sent
from sign on our responder B so both
entities can verify each other actually
this is also a good question because the
approach we want to like provide a
solution for organizations they are
certificate authority they will control
like in this side architecture we are
not dependent on any third party of a
certificate authority organization and
have their own like I and it provides a
unified attend occasion for organization
for example we have Keith key cards
so in key cards employees always use but
there's like opportunity to use smart
cards on web we can use readers on
physical access control systems but with
the this gap so this solution actually
it's targeted for organizations that
they can use in point ID cards within
organization and this architecture is
totally dependent it is independent of
third party so they don't want to like
like if they want to have a physical
access they can use T card as a key card
and if they want to event accattone
organization's website they can use like
this solution on that and after after
also if the access is devote only one
click they all have access from
buildings physical access as well as one
harbour how like our unifor Unified
actually authentication for imagination
so this is certificate authority
paralyzation can have their own actually
but still is a one-time solution like
for example OpenSSL we can use for okay
we can have a central database that do
we can manage easily so like central
database for all employees sword movie
or maybe less shortage validity of
certificates so then they can be like
[Music]
actually actually I do have I do have
with me if anyone interested convincing
no actually I did not implement that
idea got your own question we haven't
implemented anywhere but we all know
think we are trying to do this one and
I've already started like I have a this
one I don't have a white paper website
and interestingly coin smartcard coin
from litecoin so I want to let based on
this research I want you made smart card
wallet putting Bitcoin Club smartphone
so this will be like a product here
looking into thank you only thanks me
so like this is simple like the pros
would be simple this smart card wallet
we can sign transactions between
Schnauzer Chen over any cryptocurrency
the cross-platform cross-platform
support if we have mobile phone we can
sign it like putting your wallet in your
wallet literally so with mobile phone
with NFC you can sign your transaction
with for example POS we can buy products
from smart card model and similarly ATM
we can use like like people are already
familiar with credit cards and ATM
technology so it would be key to mass
per mass adoption of cryptocurrency yeah
yeah right now right now we'll be
working on this tool like Java card
maybe later we might have a specific but
I right now we'll be working on this a
one project one project I think open HSN
I think they have they have an open
source project will be actually
integrating different technologies to
make it more seamless okay