So this is closing ceremonies.
If you are called up on stage
for some reason, like you one a
contest or something, you are
going to enter from this side of
the stage and exit. You're going
to walk all the way around and
sit back down. Everybody clear
with that situation? Very simple
traffic pattern of entrance.
Exit. Victory lap. Sit down.
Thank you. >> If you ever do
that again I'll smack you. >>
Hi, everybody my name is Ross my
partner in crime over here is, I
don't drive cars we're the guys
organizers and creators of the
TVXL film contest. This is our
second year. This year we had
eight teams register. And four
teams were able to submit
entries. When I say submit
entries that means they had to
write, create, film, produce, a
film from 6 a.m. as early as 6
a.m. Thursday turn it in by 5:00
p.m. on Saturday. So we had five
-- correction four great
entries. And my partner, I don't
drive cars, is going to start
showing them now. Thank you. >>
Hope you had a good -- all right
so I got another issue that
security system you set up for
me isn't working so can you call
me back when you get a chance.
All right. >> Hey, man, it's
Robert. Las Vegas, more
importantly how is that -- has
been a mess. Seriously. >> I
heard you just got back. Call me
back. [ inaudible ] >> Andrew,
where are you? How many more
days are you going to be away?
We have clients trying to stay
online. Seriously, call me
immediately! >> Your boss just
called me what's going on? What
are you even doing? You need to
call me right now or we're
through. >> Hey, man, I haven't
heard of you since Vegas. What
is going on? I'm having a party
this weekend, my security system
is down, I need you over here as
soon as possible. >> It's fair
for me to wonder if you are
honest operator, operate in good
faith with me when you have not
turned up for work in three
weeks. I don't know what you
think you're doing because it's
not working here any more. >>
It's been almost a month. I
don't know what is going on with
you but I'm not putting up with
your shit any more. I'm done.
I'm fucking done. I hope she's
worth it. >> Meanwhile, no
unheard messages. Press one to
replay messages. [Applause] >>
What do you mean he's not there?
It's the damnest thing. The
whole thing was one big hoax
that son of a bitch has been on
the run over 70 years now. >>
But you'd think that -- >>
That's the thing. The CIA knew
there was ex Nazis for years.
They hadn't expected the whole
thing was a diversion, a ruse to
distract them while the big man
himself set up shop in the
strip. Find out only a few
things. >> What is he doing at
DEF CON? >> Sources tell me he
plans to release massive zero
data in one of the presentations
tomorrow. What I heard make back
office look like child's play.
>> What are you going to do
about it? >> Well -- [ phone
ringing ] >> Shit. Take this. >>
Is this red hat the right
detective? >> Yeah, who the hell
are you? >> This moment for a
long time. >> of course I'm
okay. All seriousness my life
flashed before my eyes. I think
I know ho I can stop him. >> How
can we stop him? >> Chances are
he'll be signing up for the
beard and mustache competition
tomorrow. If we can get to him
before he starts his talk we'll
have a chance. >> That sounds
like a plan. I'll go there. >>
We'll leave in the morning.
First, make it -- >> the contest
isn't open yet but I think he's
going to show up to it early.
He's trying to -- >> Is that him
over there? >> That's the worst
-- we've been looking for. >> I
don't think, definitely not -- [
inaudible ] >> I'll go to the
lounge. >> 999 how the hell am I
supposed to release the zero day
when all these pineapples
shitting up the network. I've
been running all around this
place for 20 minutes. I've been
pawned twice still can't get a
good connection. Ruined. Will be
over before it begins. Got him
now. >> RX modulator. Back door
to the GSM system. Initiate a
SQL injection. Might end his
miserable life once and for all.
What the fuck, this is a burner
phone. Nobody has -- and that's
why you don't try to take over
the world at DEF CON. >> Nobody
actually lives in Las Vegas. The
suckers at the blackjack table
are just visiting passing
through town on way back to
their real lives. For us poor
saps, these are our real lives.
We're passing through to
somewhere else. Move to Vegas to
start a new life, to create a
new identity and get on my feet
before heading somewhere better,
some where permanent. 23 years
I'm still not sure where that
place is. I decided to head into
the office, at least that's
highway I thought of Joe's bar
combination of bar, gin joint
and waiting room. Waiting. So
Vegas detectives was outside the
alley that he was waiting for
CSI. The conversation was short,
got a glimpse of a body. Joe's
has always been like a second
home to me, someone bumped off
in my back yard I take it
personally I decided to duck
through, just like me. 23 years,
the last thing I said to my old
man before I had to fake my own
death to get out of the agency,
projects didn't scare me it's
what they were doing with that
information. I'm sorry you feel
that way, just another way of
saying, whatever. I grabbed some
pain killers headed out, I got
this little man he lives in my
chest, that let's me started to
squeeze looked like the corpse
developed an interest. I wonder
if he was dead. Victor working
project like bull run possible,
when they decided he'd out grown
American intelligence agencies.
I knew he had a plan. I didn't
have any idea what he was up to
these days. Nobody knew. Victor
played the long game, something
bad happened on the Internet,
odds are he was behind it. But
type the hold a grudge and
Victor could profit from it,
chances are 'require new tools,
another time you realize who you
can damage with them and
convince them in corpse had been
a writer, hard boil detective
stories, maybe 60 years ago that
might earned him some scratch.
Come to Vegas after a failed
marriage somehow ended up with a
bar with small group of packers
decided to go modern. Sounded
like he managed to worm his way
into their crowd I doubt he ever
really earned confidence, get
enough liquor in anyone they
start to talk. The corpse had
been taking notes. But after 2
years of notes, come together,
DEF CON 7, tells story about a
guy who DEF CON 11 early bird
and wizards speculate on just --
DEF CON 13, amidst the alcohol
haze. These guys were smart,
they probably never realized
they were talking about the same
guy, Victor. 23 years of careful
notes started to look like a
different bird's egg. It was
right there in the Corp's book.
He had tried to make that
blackmailing Victor. On the
laptop that story had Victor
behind bars. Probably back
behind Joe's bar. Is to one
starting to smell. Seemed like
open and shut case. The little
man wasn't buying it. Popped a
couple more pills. 23 years. The
novel DEF CON. Drinking
contests, 2 years at the same
bar. Then -- [Applause] >> It
was my first time in Vegas. The
city was great. It was all I
expected and more. It's just
another day. Or so I thought.
Did you get a badge? >> I was
just down there. The line -- >>
I know. Want mine I'll sell it
for a hundred. I just got it. >>
Yeah, sure. I think I got
enough. >> Perfect. >> Thanks.
>> By the way, don't count your
chickens before your eggs hatch,
all right? >> I know what it
does. >> We're going to be super
quick here. Winner of this
year's contest is the 23rd badge
the film you just saw by lake
state studios, like to thank the
Seattle film institute for their
scholarship. Scholarships. It's
huge. Video maker magazine for
giving everyone who participate
a subscription, like to thank
DT, DEF CON and we hope to see
you guys next year and make a
movie with us. [Applause] >> the
videos will all be online. >>
Okay. Our problem is we don't
use any wireless microphones for
obvious reasons. [ laughter ]
Let's get this hooked up. All
right. Thank you. This is our
official closing ceremonies as
if you hadn't guessed. I'm the
dark tangent we are here for a
journey for the next about an
hour to tell you what happened,
what you missed, who the winners
are of all the contests and
villages. Make some special
announcements of what to expect
for next year. Yeah! That's me.
And to my right with the great
full Mo is Russ Rogers.
[Applause] >> Awesome. Russ
really made things happen this
year. As you know the first year
in a new hotel is always
exciting so I want to thank
everybody for putting up with
the chaos of that first day. And
we really tried to make some
changes. Next year obviously
we'll make some more changes
and, you know, what is this,
we're huge in Norway? What's
that all about? >> That was
voted the best thing left in
lost and found. >> Every year we
end up with a big -- it's yours?
Who does it belong to, render
man? I think you just trolling
us. What we're going to do we're
going to go through and give you
a little report from what
happened at the networking
teams, some of the other teams,
some of the contests, the
villages. Going to make some
pretty cool announcements. But I
am going to tell you ahead of
time, yes, we're back at this
hotel next year we're not
masochist not changing hotels
next year. On DEF CON forms,
we're looking for your feedback
for what worked, what didn't
work. The stuff that was really
painful obviously we figured
that out. I remember I was
speaking at the opening session
I came out for the first talk,
first day, opened up the doors
it was just packed with people
and I'm like, he's mad at me,
he's mad at me. She's mad at me.
I could tell this is not
working. Then by lunch time we
got a bunch of it sorted out and
so, yeah, that stuff is obvious.
But all the non-obvious stuff
really let us know like we
really want to try to improve
it. Also, by show of hands who
thought having a theme was cool?
We don't ever really announce
themes. You like the theme?
Theme is okay? [Applause] I mean
we're doing a convention anyway
we may as well have some
organizing principle, so next
year we're running with a new
theme "Rise of the machines".
Yeah! [Applause] One of the new
overlords is here next to me in
the cyber-grand challenge box.
Just getting ready to look at
it's new territory. Next year
we'll have more of those. So I
figured it's pretty appropriate
next year. You can expect movies
and short story contests and
imagery to be around. And
badges. Think about the number
24. And think about "Rise of the
machines" and you'll have really
cool idea on how to maybe if you
are organizing a contest or
making art. I wanted to give
that I heads up. Also give you
quick heads up if you like
staying at the Paris or Bali's
any of the other hotels we
already have registration open
for next year. That's online. If
you go to the tab in the upper
left hand corner DEF CON 24, you
can start grabbing a block or
getting rooms you want now. And
we've never managed to do that
before it took us 23 years. So
for those my administrative
announcements I want to move on
to the first team that keeps us
all connected that's the
infrastructure team. Or the the
NOC team. You'll see wearing on
the back of the shirts we have
the teams. EFFFFN here
represents the NOC team I'll
pass it off to him for making us
-- helping us stay connected.
EFFFFN. [Applause] >> Hello DEF
CON. Is everyone alive still? A
little bit? So, I have five
minutes so let's do this very
quick, this slides will be
online on the URL that we have
at the end of the presentation.
What do we do? We keep you all
-- connected so the wired
network for everything that you
see on the slide can barely see
that, but you can see on your
computer later. The DCTV who
watched on their hotel rooms in
Bally's. The video man and
Morgan. And the wireless
infrastructure our ugly child of
all the time. It worked. We did
a lot of planning as DT said
it's always fun changing venues
especially for us. Having two
hotels was very awesome. And it
worked out really well, the
hotel staff was awesome. We had
a few concerns as you can see
there, the DC-TV streaming to
both hotels was a little bit of
a challenge but our team, so
that's good. Not everything goes
as planned, right? We got some
new gear this year so we got
some new access points, a little
faster, got more powerful
controller to run everything
from there. And some new
raspberry Pis for big shout out
for the sound of knowledge
people. For actually being able
to put the slides, I don't know
what's happening here. It's not
me. We're being Dos'd again.
Upgrade is blue. Anyhow, again
shout out for sound of knowledge
for putting the slides, when on
DC-TV you're not only looking at
the speaker or speakers. I'm not
going to go through this. This
is the timeline for the set up
since Monday. We got here, we'll
be here for a week, trust me
it's fun. Challenges that we
have is like mapping the boards,
all the connections right, we
have a lot of V-Lans. That have
IOS and Windows instructions was
enough for you. Sorry. Next year
we will -- including for Linux
but if you run Linux and Wi-Fi
you have -- [ laughter ] And we
obviously didn't get
requirements some time and we
have to work through the
last-minute changes. More
challenges, there's a lot of
those here. And when vendor area
opens we get a lot of those. And
that's always awesome. Major
issues that we have again, port
mapping, we plugged something in
-- we expect people to see one
thing they see other things,
thanks for letting us know so we
can fix it quickly. The debacle
was fun. And hopefully it's
going to be fixed next year,
it's not our fault. And we
couldn't get any of the devices
to authenticate the server side
certificate. And there was
another small glitch that I'll
talk about in a little bit.
Numbers, not going to go through
this. You can download and see
that. These are some key numbers
that we have, how many terabytes
of data we streamed or you guys
downloaded or uploaded. But the
little red thing there that's
when the Wi-Fi got very tired
and we put it to sleep, right?
The Xanax and it went away but
this morning it was up again. We
had a little issue there. And
you guys are very creative. When
you pick your passwords for the
Wi-Fi Reg these are the kind of
PG ones. More stats, you guys
like graphs, stats, what kind of
devices we have. You can look
this online. And one of the most
important things is give it up
for my team these guys are
awesome. [ Applause ] They're
here all week. I cannot see
anyone but if they're here,
thank you. They're probably
working. And also thank Jeff,
Russ. The Caesar staff, Encore
always helping us with the
network drops and everything
else. Big shout out. If he
couldn't fix wireless nobody
else could he was my default out
there. Thanks thanks for all of
you for this year behaving as
much as you could on the
network. Thank you. [Applause]
>> All right. So, see if we can
get started here. I do want to
take a minute thank all of the
departments that worked within
DEF CON. It takes about 300
people to put that on, if you
add up all the hours we put in
just at con it's about four
years of full-time work, that's
just for this weekend. I can
assure you I worked about that
much over this year with Jeff
and Sheryl and the rest of the
team trying to get this planned
throughout the year as well. So,
thank you to all of the
departments, all of the Goons
all of the volunteers, all the
contest POCs, the hotel,
everybody that really helped us
out with. This I really
appreciate it. You made my life
much easier this year.
[Applause] So, next call Agent X
here for speakers. >> I'm going
to use that wireless mic. It is
now. Quick. Own him. We had 218
speakers speak this year. 132
talks. 28 hours of content all
compressed in. I'm abley
assisted by 21 speaker Goons who
just work like 18 hours a day
for me then party like rock
stars every night. We did
something new this year, Nikita
organized workshops we had seven
of them running for total of 24
workshops and 104 hours of
workshops. People went in there
all day long and basically
learned a ton of stuff. Who went
to workshops? >> Yeah! >> Do you
want more workshops? [ Cheers
and applause ] So, yeah, that's
the quick one. One of the things
I was enlightened to this year
was our closed captioning system
is amazing. And you know, you're
like, we feed them audio they
type really fast. No, they take
last year's talks, they do
frequency analysis on the words
so they know what we talk about
this year. Every year they do
that. And they unlike the
speaker operations staff read
the bio and know what the person
is going to talk about ahead of
time so let's give it up for our
closed captioning people spread
out all over the world.
[Applause] They're real. This is
not a test. [ laughter ] >>
Thank you. [Applause] All right.
So, one of the best parts of DEF
CON every year are the badges
and all the hidden clues and
everything else around the
conference that includes all of
our artwork, our floor stickers,
our program, the badges,
everything at this conference is
now been tied into his master
plan. Like to introduce lost boy
to talk about his badges and his
badge challenge. >> We had
really good year this year, I
was really happy with the
camaraderie and participation,
actually seeing teams help out
other teams. There were teams
that camped out before us even
starting the conference this
year when I tweeted out a
certain -- people actually --
where we were on the conference
floor we were like on top of me
within the space of like a
minute and a half. Russ looked
at me like they just already
found you dude what's going on?
Another couple quick things
looking at the lanyards thought
you might find it interesting
that the lanyards were both
based on current literary works
you had Edgar Allen Poe and
Charles Dodson. It looked like
it was two separate ciphers but
it took all six lanyards to
solve, it took 12 hours to get
just past the part that involved
the lanyards. I get all
energetic. I get excited when I
talk about this stuff. You
actually had to take and realize
that each of the codes had a
similar number of pieces and you
formed a core -- that mapped out
physically on a keyboard which
letters it was that it popped
out. So it's actually coordinate
system based on keyboard that's
what the -- side story that we
didn't give out in the opening
ceremonies, people keep asking
me about flying with these. As
an experiment, I put six of
these in my bag, the uber badge,
the radioactive badge flew here
with them. So as we're going
through the check out, TSA pulls
my bag. I was like, here it goes
I'm going to have the story to
tell at DEF CON but they pulled
me aside they go right past the
six uber badges that are in my
bag two vials of uranium and
other -- no, it didn't. Which is
-- maybe I shouldn't say that
out loud. [ laughter ] One of
the vials actually had a sticker
on it that said radioactive with
the little symbol on, they
didn't. Reason they pulled me
aside is for part of the
challenge this year they had to
-- you had your team had to
present me with a $2 bill. And I
had gone around was collecting
all of the $2 bills I could get
my hands on, I did that around
the hotel as well, too, to try
to make it -- so the thing that
they thought was interesting I
had this fat stack of cash
because it was $2 bills it
looked like a whole lot of money
when they pulled my bag out
they're like, radioactive,
radioactive, okay, why do you
have this stack of money? [
laughter ] So I just gave the
lady a dead pan look and I said,
I'm going to Vegas. They said,
go ahead. Get through. I guess
they had been collecting these,
you can see. I'd like to -- >>
Tell them about the -- >> The
tritium vials. Those were in the
other talk how you can actually
buy tritium in U.K. but you
captain in the United States. I
found a guy in Singapore who had
a machine for packaging coffee
and when I ordered the tritium
vials from him they would ship
them over hidden inside packets
of coffee. When they first -- I
was like, crap, I'm going to
have to tell Jeff I wasted a
bunch of 1999 guy totally
fleeced me on the Internet. But
he sent them, you rip open the
coffee packet, there is all your
tritium. Good to the last drop,
I guess. >> Not really sure what
that is all about but it's
probably not legit. >> Wait,
sorry. That was hypothetical
story. [ laughter ] That didn't
actually happen. Nor would I
advocate that. Anyway -- [
laughter ] They're like, what is
the URL of this individual? The
only other thing like I said you
all heard me, this badge was my
homage to Richard fineman this
year. [Applause] The only other
point that I'd really like to
beat you over the head with is I
asked in opening ceremonies how
many heard of -- I pronounced it
wrong, Wassinar that is sad and
scary, the reason we did the
record this year now you all
have a recording having to come
to DEF CON. Important for those
of you that are security
researchers are hackers these
laws are going to affect us
going forward, it's really
important that you know all know
about that go home, look this
up. The guys that are on the
winning team, where is the
council of -- come on up. Send
someone up. Everyone is tired.
These guys were like a
well-oiled machine. They had
like covert operatives from
their team hiding in my room in
the corner like acting all quiet
and listening to everything that
was happening. So at one point I
actually turned to one of them I
said, don't think I don't know
what you're doing. Because
there's guy back there, every
time -- sees a phone come out
somebody whispering into the
phone they had actually also set
up an -- teams that set up an
auto -- had hacked one of the
badges from previous years to
flash L.E.D. whenever I sent out
a tweet they used a badge from
previous year as an alarm for
whenever I tweeted out. Anyway,
I want to -- got very limited
time if you have -- they
apparently they have pair of
grifter shoes. Do you have a
spokesperson from your team that
would like to say a few words
about what it was like going
through this? Hurry, hurry,
doesn't matter. >> So there's a
part when we were about half way
through the challenge you put up
-- we thought it was part of the
challenge it had two coordinates
on it. We went to one of those
coordinates and there was a land
cable hanging from the ceiling
that wasn't connected to
anything at one end. That's all
I'm going to say about that.
[Laughter] >> To explain that a
little puzzle pieces actually
was a sequence that they found
in the online integer sequence
database that was submitted by
person who had the last name of
herring. So, anyway, I'd like to
present the first black uber
badge to the council of nine for
winning this challenge. [
Applause ] So we're doing this
-- did you want to talk about
this real quick. Going to do
actually a book next year we'll
have much larger presentation.
But so we are actually
registering all of the ubers
that go out from this point
forward but I would just like to
say I encourage all of you every
year to play with the puzzles. I
put very easy puzzles in as well
as some very difficult you might
have noticed there were some in
the program for when you're
bored standing in line. But also
may be coding about half way
through. Play as much as you're
comfortable. I encourage to you
talk to each other, get to know
each other that's why I put
stuff on the lanyards so you
have to talk to other people. My
favorite part about this year
was the team that, some that
have team said, I was new last
year, I met these guys, we
worked together and they stayed
in contact all year long. And
that kind of stuff is what makes
it worthwhile to me. I'd like to
thank Jeff and DT for letting me
continue to do this because
apparently you guys like the
abuse. [ Applause ] As you saw
this year was non-electronic
badge we're going to continue
with our tick-tock cycle.
Electronic badge next year. [
Cheers and applause ] That's it,
thank you. >> I'm looking for
uranium vials under the podium
here. Okay, so, one of the
things with DEF CON is that over
time people come and go. They
get tired of doing certain
things, if you have been here
more than 15 years you've seen
me in about five different job
functions. >> Well, you retired
last year I thought. >> Three
years. It has worked out well as
you can all tell. So, these
aren't the only two people that
are retiring. I know we point
them out specifically because
they're department heads or
seconds, Agent X who has been
running our speakers for well
over a decade. 15 years. [
Applause ] He thought it was 15.
So, he's -- then we have flea,
where's flea? He's at the Goon
swim. He has actually retired.
Yeah, he's been here for a long
time so if we can give a round
of applause for him as well. [
Applause ] So, we're going to
give this uber badge to both of
them hoping that since leaving
us hanging the radioactive
components will take care of
them for us. Thank you. [
Applause ] Just to add on to
that there are -- quite a few
other Goons that are either
transitioning to other
departments, want to do
something else or moving on
because you've beat the crap out
of them for 20-plus years. So,
we've got this strategy that
because we're so community
driven that you shouldn't do
something you're not interested
in and people are creative they
want to -- try to create an
environment at DEF CON where you
come and you can do stuff, get
burned out, you leave, you can
always come like family you can
rotate through. So, I am not
convinced that we won't see the
last of X. Might see you again,
maybe. And so that is the
environment we want to create.
So, like you guys, sometimes you
come to DEF CON, sometimes you
don't. But we really try to
create an awesome environment
where you can come and do -- and
so, I think for the next slide
want to talk about all --
grifter. Contest, who stepped up
now, right, grifter used to do
one thing now grifter is running
our contents events and villages
a new role for him he came in
sort of at the last minute and
really did a fantastic job.
Let's give round of applause to
grifter for stepping up. [
Applause ] >> Somehow ended up
being the contests, villages,
parties and the penthouses and
demo labs. >> No pressure, I've
lost my mind. We were trying to
come up with something for the
eye but we were saying pelvic.
Events. Labs. Anyway.
Fundraisers. We have obviously
every year we have lot of people
who put a lot of time and effort
into just doing something for
others. These people stepped up
in that regard we have Eddie
raised $2,590 for the EFS.
Awesome. [ Applause ] He raised
$4,590 for hackers for charity.
[Applause] Then we also have Mo,
there's quite a few Mohawks
running around out here, thanks
to Ed and her crew. Mohawk the
EFF raised $2,434. [Applause]
And for hackers for charity
additional. $995. What's that?
donation there. Then crash and
compile while they're doing the
contest they raised money for
the EFF as well they raised $700
for the EFF. One thing we also
do the blood code is out there
again. There were 84 donations
given. People out there giving
blood which is awesome.
[Applause] And that's for the
match. Awesome guys. I have an
interesting moment where some
attendees came up in the contest
area they saw the blood code
stuff out there, if you saw
everything they were like, holy
crap. Is that where people go
and they get hurt, why are all
those people laying down? It's a
blood bath in here, get out.
Then also just two quick things
that we have hackers for
charity, we have a misprint
badge that will be -- yes, only
one of these. And it has some
artwork by Eddie Mize on here
after we're done with the
closing ceremony we'll be
auctioning it off for hackers
for charity. I'll show you
something. It's black. It's not
a Black Badge. It just happens
to be a badge that's black.
Anyway, then also I want to talk
about the EFF. At their booth
with everybody raising money all
over the place, parties were
raising money, different things,
and climbing this weekend. [
Applause ] So thank you all. We
have somebody from the EFF here
just with a few quick comments.
>> So, thanks everybody, thanks
for your support. Your support
like yours let's us do our work,
this year we followed more than
15 new lawsuits, major progress
and 11 more, something like
amicus briefs all over the
country at every level that's
tens of thousands of hours of
work. Just this week in -- told
more than ten security
researchers representing,
hopefully kept everybody out of
jail, so thanks a lot guys. DT
and the Goons thanks so much and
to our supporters who raised
money for us, waffle Con, wall
of sheep, mohawk, hacker
jeapordy de. The DEF CON
parties, check marks and crash
and compile. >> Thank you
everybody. >> And he lost his
voice, thanks for that.
[Applause] Is that it? All
right, so moving on. We have a
lot of villages around here, we
had 12 villages this year all
different venues kicking off
everywhere. Something we started
at DEF CON 14 it's just grown
and grown. It's fantastic. We
always say you can make this con
your own and these folks help us
do that please give round of
applause to all of our villages
for helping. [ Applause ] So we
have something for the
organizers, they don't have a
lot of contests and things for
the villages but for the effort.
We have really cool custom
T-shirt that we're going to give
three of them to each one of the
villages. Agent, hand sewn and
Agent X will be modeling it for
us. Give him a turn. I don't
care if there's nothing on the
back. Turn anyway. >> So this is
a limited edition shirt that Mar
made with a Daisy running, she
hand stitched every shirt with
conductive thread that ties it
all together and so we're going
to give the organizers of the
village -- they can do with what
they want but relegally want to
give them something special and
limited because they don't run
contests, they never really get
recognized with Black Badges or
anything. They really do awesome
work. We want to recognize the
village organizers. [ Applause ]
>> If you are one of the
organizers of the village,
please come over here to this
side of the stage and we'll get
you guys set up. This slide
says, other contests and events.
You can imagine what it's like
for us going into planning this.
Like Jeff said, myself and
Panadarro who is running --
there he is, he's waving giving
out those shirts. We put quite a
number of hours, I didn't
realize quite how many it would
be when I got the phone call
from Jeff and Russ. It's all
good. This is all that stuff out
there. Please, give a huge round
of applause to all the
organizers of all this content.
[Applause] Also if you're
interested in doing something
like running a contest, hit me
up at grifter@Defcon.org. Once
we are moving forward on a
contest we put together stuff on
the forums, get on DEF CON forum
say this is what I want to do.
If I don't see it somebody will
let me know and we'll get
planning. The sooner the better,
the more activity the better.
Moving right along. Our uber
contest. So we have a number of
badges up here, we're just going
to start running through them.
We have our social engineering
CTF guys up here? He's coming.
He's very sneaky. >> I came up
the exit. >> These guys are
incredible. They grew this year,
we gave them double the space,
we thought that that would be
enough and it wasn't so we'll
have to discuss that for next
year. But it was nuts. You guys
absolutely loved this village.
Thank you. >> Thank you. I think
we need this room for next year,
right? You think? It's been
great this year, I tell you the
communication with grifter and
his team, if you guys had any
that have it was really awesome.
They were just so on top of
stuff. So thank you grifter.
Russ, Sheryl, reason we got
stuff done so CTF we had first
and second place winner our
second place winner was John
Sherpa came win over a thousand
points between the report and
the calls. >> We're on the
screen if you can see this one.
We made some really cool awards.
I'm blocking it. Really cool.
For you, John. Whole bunch of
cool hacking stuff. We had
Raytheon came in, I don't know
if you're going to trust us,
Raytheon came in they gave us
some devices and said, this is a
puzzle. If you would like to
solve it you can plug it in your
computer I went I'm going to
give it to the winners of the
contest. [ laughter ] They're
both getting one. Thank you,
great job. Great job. Now we
have real serious thing, guys,
this is the third year in a row
a woman has won the SECTF. Third
year in a row! It's awesomely
beautiful. Come up here, Jen.
You also get a clipboard full of
awesome hacker stuff. You get a
Wi-Fi pineapple-like device.
Bigger thing you can hit someone
with and hurt them. But now here
is the -- look at this thing. If
from what I understand this
thing is like radioactive I'd be
careful where you hang it on
your body. Depending if you want
children or not but there you
are. Congratulations. [ Applause
] Guys, next year we got to step
it up. Got to step it up guys,
three years in a row, come on,
you got to represent again. Back
to you grifty. Grifter. >>
That's my pet name. All right.
Badge hacking. All right. Open
CTF. >> Open CTF. No applause.
Open CTF. [ Applause ] >> Open
CTF almost didn't happen this
year actually. Test test test.
Close, can you hear me? Open CTF
almost didn't happen this year.
I'd like to thank Sharelle and
Betty from DEF CON, mark from
Bally's, and the rest of legit
for 11th hour save. [Applause]
Open CTF is jeopardy style catch
the flag contest open to all DEF
CON attendees. Out of over 150
registered teams, 61 teams
scored this year. Unfortunately
we had to turn some people away
due to lack of space, but we're
already working to make sure
that doesn't happen next year
and our winners, best write up,
mad hacks, hacksters and Los
scriptors. Third place was --
with 1,960 points. Second place
was Neg 9 with 2,710 points. And
first place was OX8F who stayed
up all night the first time to
solve -- I'm sorry, 1500 points
worth of challenges although I
do think he had some remote
help. And he had 3,410 points.
For donating we're giving to our
winners. Keep what you kill.
[Applause] >> We're switching it
up. I was trying to keep audio
guys guessing. We have our next
one is Warlock games, you guys
here? These guys a new
organizers this year. I'll let
him tell you about the contest.
It was a lot of fun to have the
contest area, there's always a
bunch of craziness going on. The
guys who are competing seem to
be having a blast. >> Thank you
very much. How many got chance
to play Warlock games this year?
Couple of you. >> Nobody played?
>> Some up here. Fair enough.
Warlock games is a capture --
challenge-based CT if you have
things that go in, forensics,
digital forensics those kind of
things, live malware analysis.
We always bring in a physical
security aspect because it's not
all about the electronics and
the security world. So you get
in there you get a chance to
give it a roll padlocks, those
kind ever things. This year we
also got chance to bring --
bring in some old school like
street fighter and Pac Man and
what not kind of blast from the
past. And that way we brought in
entire gaming experience, the
hacking challenge and physical
security piece. So, we have two
teams up here with us, our other
teams had to take off. And we
always talk about that this is a
networking type event. Lot of
you have been coming here for
many years you start to see the
familiar faces of people that
you know. So, our second place
team, I think they knew most --
I think they picked up two
people while they were standing
in line. And they made up six
numbers of their team other four
already knew each other I'm
going to let them come up and
give few moments about their
team and how they did the
challenge. >> Super nervous. We
did great. I think we -- commend
these guys for doing great job.
But it was fun, it was awesome,
you guys -- I'd like to give it
up to the guys that host this
thing they do such a good job
spending entire time doing it.
[Applause] Good job. Really good
job. All of our team had to go
back to their normal lives but I
had a great time I want to thank
everybody, myself, disco, Mega,
Dick, molotov for their -- thank
you guys. [Applause] >> Okay. So
our first place team they're
actually out of Samsung in south
Korea we've had a few of their
team members compete with us in
the past. I'm going to let them
come up and give a few seconds
about their team and how they
accomplished some of their
challenges. >> I really
appreciate Warlock. Thank you.
[Applause] >> Short and simple.
Thank you very much. Thank you
very much for that. We were told
kind of as our contest closed
out that we were going to be
Black Badge event this year,
it's kind of a humbling
experience, if you will for
those that put contests together
to be acknowledged in this way.
It does take a lot of time and
effort to put this together and
to get the nod DEF CON staff and
from DT that we're there. I
would also like to give shout
out to the Goon staff that was
running that contest, they did
it and they were all over the
place helping us out and they
were everywhere, so, good job to
them and congratulations to
them. [ Applause ] >> We'd like
to do is present the Black Badge
to our first place team from
Samsung South Korea. [Applause]
>> Thanks very much, DEF CON,
we'll see you next year.
[Applause] >> Hack fortress,
where are you at? Heads up crash
and compile you're going to be
next. You want to get ready. >>
Hey, what's up? First of all
would the winning team come on
up stand up front real quick. Go
around up front. Because we
don't want to get this shit on
people up here. We're going to
get -- otherwise, our fifth year
at DEF CON we appreciate, our
first year at black badge
contest we're super excited
about it. For those that don't
know hack fortress is a contest
that we run, normally bring out
to DEF CON, 30 minute combined
team fortress 2 and hacking
competition, winner moves on
usually until they play jolly
and friends at the finals seems
to be the may it happens every
year. This year the team is
called not ready for this, the
genesis of the name was, bunch
of scabs got together signed up
a team they didn't know each
other we need a team name, we're
not readied for this. Sweet,
that's your team name. That's
what they have been tagged with.
They ran the gamut, they had a
ringer, there's a pro running
around here, actually a pro
gamer, good job. Random chance
worked out for them very
effectively. So, on the hack
side of this thing, the team
fortress 2, who has played team
fortress 2, best video game in
the world, Whoo! Fantastic game
engine that allows us to control
the game environment. We can
make realtime manipulation of
the game environment, and so
what we've done is then add a
hacking element to it where
there is all these different
challenges be it forensic,
database, physical, that kind of
thing. And then what they get a
currency where they can buy
basically different hints or
they can modify the game
environment like set the other
team on fire, blind them, freeze
them, do all that kind of stuff.
It's an interactive process
between the hacking team and the
TF2 team where they can
manipulate each other's
environment. Ongoing adventure
and worked out pretty well
largely runs without too much
hassle. What they have got
besides one Black Badge for the
entire team, so if you could
clear out we're going to do like
a hunger game style thing right
in the middle just let them all
go at it we've got some shit and
see how it works out. I thought
it was really funny, actually.
Anyway. What they also get is an
opportunity to jump the line and
buy a ticket so that they don't
have to try to hit F 5 for those
that know what that is. We are
also shitty remembering who won.
So this year we're going to mark
them all with spray paint so
that we can remember, they can
show us their hands next year
we'll let them in get the
ticket. If you can just line
uphold your hands up we'll spray
all your hands. We'll chrome
them up real good. We also were
able to raise about $255 for 8
bit processors for EFF. That's
not a lie that's actually how
much we raised. We appreciate
the bribes we got from all the
teams. >> Very "Mad Max". >> One
of the challenges was spray
paint your face with silver, I
can pick up the bumper from the
scavenger hunt, around the
contest area screaming "Witness"
as loud as you could. It worked
out very well. That's good look
for you, X. >> I live, I die, I
live again! >> It turns out I
haven't seen the movie so I
actually don't know -- why it's
funny. Anyway, I think that's
it. Thank you very much. [
Applause ] Hand out the badge.
Here we go. Actually I'm going
to buy Fiat because I like
Bitcoin, I'm going to hand this
guy the Black Badge because this
gentleman here took motivation
to actually commentate the video
game for us. He's very good
eight, his name is -- Jaysup. >>
Is that your God-given name. >>
That's not a handle just sounds
like one. He was very good at
it. He did about five rounds for
us, he's British it sounded even
better. We really appreciate the
effort that he put in so
congratulations. [Applause] >>
If I may take the pulpit for one
second be so bold not to bite
the hand that feeds me, fewer
cameras next year maybe?
[Applause] >> Somewhere like
where they're doing the closed
captioning that person's fingers
are smoking. Motor mouth potter.
Crash and compile. >> So, those
people that don't know
combination of ACM -- and a
drinking game. So you get a
problem, you solve it in code,
and if your code isn't viable
you take a drink. If it doesn't
the right output you take a
drink, if another team comes up
with the solution before you do,
everyone else takes a drink.
Anyway, we've been running this
for awhile and one of the things
we change this year is we wanted
more participation. So we
actually ran our
prequalification round at DEF
CON. So we had more teams, we
had teams try out for this,
there's only nine spots
available. So we had excellent
showing, everyone had a great
time. Our winning team -- so
this is a basketball size, crash
and compile trophy. This is
originally when we first started
we had -- decided to program in
random program languages.
Started out playing the game.
And what better way to pick
something random than a giant
dice. So, the winner is -- our
second place team was Frank
rules then third place was Meg
9. [Applause] Like to present
the Black Badge.
Congratulations. >> What was the
winning technique? >> the
winning technique it was the
beer points. Thanks Crux, I'm
missing others, team
distraction, you were way for
fucking annoying than last year.
>> It's what we do. >> Thanks
Ryan for bringing it home, I
couldn't read by the last
problem set. We've been doing
Cons for ten-plus years. We did
contests now the last three.
I've met ton of people in the
last three years, get involved
in the contests, great way to
meet people. Thanks. [Applause]
>> Thank you very much. All
right. Next up. Scavenger hunt.
[ Cheers and applause ] Of
course. Yeah! >> Hi, I'm Salem
with the scavenger hunt, if your
DEF CON experience is slightly
weird, you're welcome. Or I'm
sorry, one of the two. I have no
-- I have a bunch of stuff
specifically for DT, a shirt.
One of our trophies. >>
Excellent. >> One of our
challenges this year, last year
we gave out floppy disks which
was a lot of fun because find
out where to find a floppy
reader. This year we gave out
VHS tapes. [ laughter ] The VHS
tape on the Scav list was worth
20 points it had a lot of fun
stuff on it and really fun
tie-ins with the gold of 23. We
got one specifically for Jeff.
>> We will encode this make it
available to the public. >> of
course,, on the list we had 220
possible items. The first place
team turned in 104 items. Second
place team got 96 items. There
was literally a two-point
difference between first and
second place. And told -- held
out to eight items in that two
points. Our second place team as
well did end up raising some
money for the EFF. We ended up
getting $216 just for the EFF by
one random Scav item, it was
great. >> Any live chickens? >>
What's that? >> Any live
chickens this year? >> No, no
live chickens no horse heads.
Because I didn't want to deal
with them again. [ laughter ]
All right, so, before I call up
my winning team. I can't do this
alone, I'm Salem, I can't do
this. My team here is what makes
this happen on the end dual flip
flop, Zora, evil Mofo these guy
make this happen so much harder
than I do even though my face is
charge. This is my last year
running this. I am giving my
badge to this guy. I'm making
him be in charge of this from
now on. [ Applause ] All right.
Third place. I have no idea if
you're here. >> Yeah! >> Don't
bother coming up, go over there.
Go over there. Go over there.
We'll meet you over there. Like
I said two-point difference
between first and second place.
Second place team, the national
shit posting agency. Our first
place team, our winners, grit
greenwald Santorum, come up
front get your Black Badge. I
want to give some love to the
people who gave us free prizes,
no starch, DJ jackalope, Unix
surplus, about six others. And a
big thanks to Grifter and his
team for putting up with us.
[Applause] [ Cheers and applause
] >> All right my three teams,
go over there for prizes. Go
that way. >> All right. Before
we bring up the last folks here
I just wanted to say thanks to
my team, the guys who were
running around like crazy or at
times just sitting on the couch.
The contest and events team and
especially to Panadaro who is
back here hiding in the shadows
without this wouldn't happen
please round of applause for
those guys. [ Applause ] >> the
moment you've all been waiting
for, ladies and gentlemen,
capture the flag. [ Cheers and
applause ] >> We've been
drinking for a couple of hours.
>> Get some beer while you're
doing this. Beer is good. >>
Okay, hi, everybody, I'm grump,
bear we are the legitimate
business syndicate this is our
third year running DEF CON's
capture the flag. We would like
to thank DEF CON for having us
back again. We want to thank all
the fans that come by the room
throughout the weekend, it was
super rewarding to see the same
people coming back again and
asking even better questions
than they were before. We want
to thank the teams that played
this year, everybody played with
honor and extreme skill. >> How
many teams tried to qualify? >>
registered our qualifying event
back in May. Ten people were
invited to come play here.
Teams. >> Five other teams that
we prequalified through other
CTFs give everyone a chance.
Highlights, Friday opened up
with X86-64 binary. Later
standard 32X86 binary. Then we
opened an embedded form the
CI20. And Friday night we had
lightning round that we actually
ran on a nexus 9 which is as you
know android which is arm 46.
Saturday for the first time in
at least ten years we ran a
Windows 10 challenge on Windows
10 station IoT core which is
running on Raspberry Pi. Also
for the first time the DEF CON
CTF Saturday night which we took
four of the best hackers in the
world we hooked up to their
computers ran capture cards and
watched what they were doing for
live hacking challenge. Check
out our that's going to be post
processed released to the world
very soon. >> Cool. [Applause]
Yeah. Not a super big surprise.
But PPP won that live CTF
challenge. [Applause] So if you
guys check out our website
pretty soon we're going to go
ahead put up a capture of the
whole game running in fast speed
so you can watch the whole
visualization. There is missiles
that jump across the screen it's
really super cool. Okay. Now I'm
going to hand it over to the
leader of legitimate business
syndicate is Gyno Phage and give
us the results of the game. >>
In third place this year we had
zero days sober. [Applause] >>
How many points. >> All the way
in the back. Stand up. If you
want, or not. In second place,
we have the two-time champ PPP
the plaid parliament of pony.
[Applause] And in first place a
first timer at the DEF CON
capture the flag finals we had
Def Corps. [Applause] Come up on
the stage. Come on up, guys. The
winners will be receiving eight
black badges and eight jackets
for their victory at the capture
the flag this year. It is the
only contest that gets the
jackets. [Applause] >> Good luck
getting them back home. >> Okay.
First of all thank you for the
-- for the hardest challenges
ever. We really enjoyed the CTF
we also thank all the other
teams that competed with us. And
luckily we won this year, we are
very happy. And -- secret
technique? We have the world
best hacker, John. [Applause]
Also Windows 10 Raspberry Pi
challenge he didn't even have
the debugger he solved the
challenge the second night.
Thank you so much. [Applause]
We'll be here again. >> So the
winning team gets to come back
to defend in the following year.
We're going to see Def Core next
year. Thank you. >> Thank you so
much. >> Predict the future but
on every uber badge there's a
Korean saying that says... Which
means the Taffy Peddler can do
what he pleases. >> and now -- I
have one final announcement
about capture the flag. Next
year, the Thursday before DEF
CON, Darpa would like to show
the world how far automated
program analysis has come.
Through the Darpa cybergrand
challenge. In honor of next
year's DEF CON theme "the rise
of the machines" we would like
to have the winning computer
from Darpa cyber-grand challenge
compete against best human
hackers in the world at the DEF
CON 24 capture the flag. [
Cheers and applause ] >> Details
will be available on our
website, legitbs.net soon. >> I
remember the day the machines
took over. >> All right. That
finishes it off for contests and
events. Thanks to everybody who
played and all the organizers
again and now we'll turn it over
to DT. >> So, this is the point
where I tell you the closing
comments. Which I've already
told you at the beginning you
see how I did that? So, what
we're doing is as usual every
year, we'll do it faster this
year going to release -- two
things. One we're going to
release all the video that we've
captured with the captioning.
And, two, this year really what
sort of DEF CON is composed of,
what we get to pass on to those
people who aren't lucky enough
to be here, is all this video
and the villages. And so this
year I really want to step that
up and so we recorded a lot of
the speaking in the villages.
Never done before. We almost --
you heard how many hours of
speaking we had. We have almost
double that in all of the other
villages. So we're going to be
releasing all the video that
we've captured in all the
villages and all the official
speaking tracks so that's going
to be a huge amount of data. The
other thing I want to announce
which is not directly related to
DEF CON but every year I do a
data duplication village. And
the last two years I've been
collecting you a the videos from
all the other hacking
conferences around the world,
curating it, cleaning it up,
putting it in directory
structure that's what you get if
you come to the data village
it's about 5.5 terabytes right
now. And so, all of that data
from all the other conventions
will be online as well in the
coming months so I don't have to
do all this work release it just
once. So in the next couple of
months you're going to see a
huge data dump all the other
conventions I could find, all
the speaking at Black Hat, and
at DEF CON and I'll release
Black Hat data, too. [ Cheers
and applause ] Give me a beer.
Bring me a beer. I got a new
beer. Full beer. Okay, new beer
for drinking. I want -- hacker
jeopardy, Wyn Schwartauer won
jeopardy this year. He didn't
fuck it up. I want to give shout
out to little Roo. Give a shout
out to the hotel. Who sit, the
-- mark and Christina from the
hotel for putting up with us in
the first year. They were
amazing. I want to say that
video channels for next year now
that we know the infrastructure
will fix that. My point of it
all is that we're super proud to
have the biggest conference
ever, we grew about 15% and
we're super proud to have
captured more of it than ever to
give it away to the world than
ever so with all that have said,
this sounds like bullshit but
it's true, DEF CON has become
what we make of it and this year
I think we've made a fantastic
conference. So, thank you so
much. We'll be around. I'm
really looking forward to seeing
you next year, get on the forums
and give us feedback. With that
I'm going to officially close
DEF CON 23. >> Thank you
everyone! [ Cheers and applause
]