Thank you for coming to my talk,
Chigula, a Wi-Fi forensics
framework. A lot of talks going
on. I appreciate you coming
down. And hopefully it will be
fun. Before I begin, a little
introduction about myself,
started as an electronics,
worked with a bunch of companies
programmer to architect. Moved
on to wireless security. I
discovered the cafe latte
attack, a couple of other
interesting things, and then
started my own training company.
I also run SecurityTube.net and
Pentester Academy. I've written
a couple of books on wireless
security. The latest one is Make
Your Own Hacker Gadget. So
before we begin with today's
topic, this has been a team
effort. I started off with the
idea of creating a Wi-Fi
forensics framework around
January of this year. Beginning
when I worked with a lot of
interesting ideas, I eventually
figured the amount of work
requires a theme, so we were
primarily responsible for
creating this. Chigula will be
available at
PentesterAcademy.com/Chigula.
Right after this talk, you can
download it and try it out. So
what was the motivation? Now,
I've been doing wireless
security probably for the last
ten to 15 years. And a lot of
times, I've struggled trying to
use Wireshark to get meaningful
information from places. How
many of you have tried to do
forensics with Wireshark for
Wi-Fi? How many of you
succeeded? So given the sheer
amount of traffic at the very
same time, all those different
packets, I figured Wireshark is
of course, great as being a
sniffer, right? Showing you the
packets, passing them.
Unfortunately, framework to
build stuff, Wireshark is
difficult to work with. Yes, you
could write protocol dissectors,
maybe lure -- matter, but the
learning curve is actually quite
high. So I really wanted a Wi-Fi
forensics framework, first for
myself. I was the end customer
to begin with. And something
which pentesters can use, not
just programmers, right, because
a programmer could probably
write his own sync code and
stuff. I wanted something which
would allow pentester SQL, go
ahead and run -- and get
meaningful information. So what
is Chigula? It's a set of tools
and scripts for wireless
forensic. The core is written in
C++. This basically involves all
the packet parsing, pushing into
the database, and all the
plug-ins which you can write are
-- actually you could write
plug-ins in any language which
has a SQL, driver. You don't
have to only know or use -- What
platforms can Chigula work on?
It can work on Windows as well
as Linux. Actually any --
system. The packet, itself,
could just be -- on any
platform. So here is a
screenshot of Chigula on
Windows. Here's the same on --
this is one, 214. Now, what can
Chigula help us with? So what
we've done is we've -- we take a
pcap file, pick up individual
packets, parse each field and
map it, finding SQL*Lite table.
So you could actually write SQL
queries which could be as
granular as select -- MAC,
equals something, dot subtype
equals something, and pretty
much go ahead and, you know,
write tools on top of that,
which could probably work -- and
take up some examples today.
Now, Chigula can allow you to
create blacklist signatures, so
if you wanted to go ahead and
create a signature for -- or any
Honeypot tool for that matter or
aireplay. It can allow you to
detect and visualize Wi-Fi
attacks. MAC -- can be detected,
reasonably reliably using
Chigula. So what is the
architecture? At a very high
level we have data sources,
which basically feed the packet
into the actual packet parsing
engine, the engine pushes that
into a data store, and through
that data store you can use any
data tool which can work with
SQL, or scripts which can create
the database. Now, Chigula can
work both in and offline, and
online mode. In the offline mode
it's going to take the files and
the online mode, which is
currently experimental, and
works only with -- based systems
can actually sniff packets off
-- as well. Okay. It's -- it
looks like the captioning
probably a little off the -- I
have an accent so I don't know
who is captioning it. So either
way, as I said in last talk
yesterday, you'll have fun
probably looking at Chigula,
looking at the captions, so -- [
Laughter ] Now the packet itself
is a standalone tool, which can
be used for a lot of other
purposes. In Chigula, we convert
packets into SQL*Lite databases
but the stand-alone tool,
SQL*Lite can convert packets
into XML, so that you can go
ahead and write -- all of that
stuff will work as well. The
focus of Chigula is to use
SQL*Lite but you can use XML and
SQL, to generate both, if you
want. Now, we currently parse
most management -- packets of
interest. So all those little
subfields inside, Beacon frame
can be passed, so you could
write queries, which are
searching for a specific
information element in -- across
the packet, which you have. Now,
the data store is a SQL*Lite
database, the reason we chose
this to begin, available on all
platforms, does not require a
server-based process. You could
even -- to embedded systems,
right? Isn't limited to just
your workstations. Of course,
you can migrate the schema to
pretty much any database you
like. Now, once all the data is
in sight, you can use query
tool, SQL*Lite browser on
Windows, or whatever is the best
SQL threading tool on Linux,
analysis scripts, written in any
language as I mentioned. So let
me go ahead and show you a quick
demo. Actually, rest of the talk
is really just demos. That's
probably going to be the most
difficult part. Here, Windows
has color change. Screen
background. Is this better?
Okay. Great. So I have a pcap
file here. Pick up a sample.
Right. I think this has around
tested Chigula up to 3 to 4 gigs
of pcap file, there hasn't been
any problem but if you report
any bugs you can always send it
to us. So you can give the pcap
file as an input. Hyphen S
option, stands for the output
SQL*Lite database. Okay. [
Laughter ] Not the best thing to
happen. Okay. So here is --
figured out what went wrong. At
the end we check if it is the
latest version, so I have to do
it -- so it works. [ Laughter ]
So if open up the database file,
here is the schema, for
literally every single header
field actually have a table in
there. So as an example, let's
begin with MAC headers. So you
have the protocol version, the
type, the subtype, every single
field including bit fields have
been mapped to an actual column.
Now, across different frame
types, and at the very same time
we even save all the -- values,
pretty much all the time IEs --
elements, separately so that we
can query them. Now, here is how
the data looks like. So we could
look at the MAC headers -- and
you can see we have around
every single field is map. So
now let's actually run some
interesting queries. See me type
everything out. So here is the
first query, finding all Beacon
frames, right? This is something
Wireshark can do as well. Let's
try this with Chigula. In here,
run the query, and then there
you go. Thirty-six Beacon
frames, basically inside the
packet, capture file. Now, let's
look at something Wireshark
cannot do, but Chigula can. With
Wireshark, can you figure out
all the unique devices around
and get a distinct list? So I'd
like to know just the unique
list of all clients and -- now,
with Chigula, this is actually
quite simple. All we have to do
is select distinct across
address one, two, three, and
four. And the moment we do that,
actually see how powerful the
framework is. And there you go.
We have 395 rows in there. Right
now, folks, the broadcast MAC is
included, you can always write a
little wrapper to include
broadcast and -- addresses. This
is just a query to look at all
distinct addresses across the
different fields. So we have 395
rows. There are 394 devices
actually in there. Now, if you
are to find all the axis points,
again, extremely easy. All we
have to do is find the distinct
addresses with send out Beacon
frames. There we go. Thirty-six
APs, right? Managed to do this
with Wireshark? And you can
actually write your own scripts,
which can query and dig this
out, reports and do a lot of
other interesting things. Now,
if you wanted to look at all
devices, sending data packets,
basically just do a select
distinct address one, go in
here. And there you go. You have
all devices in your pcaps with
send data packets. Now, we can
actually even do other
interesting macro level --
what's that? >> [ Inaudible ] >>
So basically we have a -- there
which does interesting stuff. We
look at MAC address spoofing,
you'll see that demo. That's an
interesting thing you noted, but
using the same thing for the
attacks as well. So you can
actually go in here, select
average, and the average length,
106 bytes. Now, here is another
interesting query. You could
actually do a time built up
between packets, you can figure
out what is the time difference?
Of course, you can add the MAC
addresses as well, in case
you're interested in just one
device. There you go. Now, we
can do simple queries but what
about more complicated ones? If
we wanted to find the list of --
MAC addresses, and return that
as a table, right? Something
currently you may be rely on
error dump and G, to export
everything, and then maybe read
the CSV. You can actually do
this quite easily, using a join
in Chigula, go in here. Paste
it. And there you go. This also
-- SSID net works. Right? So we
see the AP MAC address and the
SSID. It is broadcasting. Now,
what we've done is, we've -- the
packets and actually added more
macro statistics in there.
Things like encryption, you
would not have to go and pass
the IEs yourself, already have
in tables we create. So we can
go in here -- do that in just a
bit. You can do the hidden SSID
net works. Show you this first.
So these are all the hidden in
SSID net works, all the distinct
lists. Now, if you wanted to
figure out the different SSIDs
on a given channel, you can do
that as well. Again, join
between multiple tables, the
entire SQL schema published
along with the tool, so you can
write your own queries. If you
love SQL injection, you'll
probably love Chigula. [
Laughter ] Well, for what it's
worth, Chigula could have a SQL
injection. Packet -- code --
Now, one of the other
interesting things as a
pentester which I always wanted
is a list of client MAC
addresses and SSIDs they're
threading for, again as a
distinct list, so this is
something we can easily do with
Chigula. Actually pick this up
here. And run the query. And
this actually gives you the MAC
and the -- SSID. Keep in mind,
every single client also sends a
null probe request, right? Null
probes, including a ton of other
SSIDs being queried for. Now,
you can even optimize this on a
-- basis. You can go ahead and
say, hey, for this specific,
which are the SSIDs being
queried for? So there you go.
This client with the MAC
address, AP61B, et cetera, is
actually querying for all of
these SSIDs. Now, we're talking
about macro tables, right, SSID,
all of that, here is a query
which can actually give us the
SSID authentication and
encryption, just simple query.
There we go, right? You could
have passed the packets
yourself, and figured out a lot
of this information. But Chigula
holds many of these in macro
tables as well. You can
reconstruct Beacon frames.
People were there in my top
yesterday, Beacon frames was one
of the ways we were using to go
ahead and create signatures, so
you could construct entire
Beacon frames using the PLVs for
any network in there. You can do
the same for client probe
requests as well. Right, so
these are all PLVs sent by the
client. The value is bit 64
imported, it makes it easy for
you to go ahead and put it in
your scripts, rather than having
to work with binary values. Now,
ahead and look at transmissions
on a device -- so for a given
MAC address, we can look at
different time stamps when the
device transmitted. You could
even join tables to figure out
what were the actual frames. So
this is Chigula going ahead and
querying, marketable data from
the pcap, in the bottom of the
SQL*Lite table. So these are
queries you can write, you can
extend, you can add your own, if
you like. Any questions about
the querying? Or anything about
the architecture? Now, this is
step one, right? Step two is
being able to actually do
forensics and ideas for this.
Now, broadly, if you look at
forensics or intrusion
detection, the first is being
able to detect signatures of
existing attack tools. This is
actually quite easy to do, and
again, people came to my talk
yesterday, most attack tools
have fixed CLVs, most of them
don't even change the values. Of
course, fingerprinting tools
would depend on the -- tool,
tool can change that, but you
can do this with Chigula. I'll
just show you in a bit. The
second attack, or rather --
attacks are -- attacks. How many
of you cracked WEP? Replayed the
same packet over and over again,
right? Another example of replay
attack could be D. Go ahead,
send a huge, packets from time
to time, to ensure that we can
disconnect clients from the
authorized network. Right? So
this is an example of the replay
attack. Then you have
unauthorized devices and
associations. So for example,
you can have an axis point,
which you created for your
network, but someone can create
fake APs and Honeypots, right?
How do we go about identifying
them, using extremely simple
scripts. Now last, but probably
one of the more interesting ones
is how do you detect MAC address
-- so let's look at each of
these. Now, the first signature
we look at is MD -- a lot of
people. Mdk3, can create fake
Beacon frames, the most common
use is to randomize the SSID, so
that your devices get confused,
everything looks completely
gobbled. Now, if you analyze the
Beacon, for Beacon, what you
find is, fixed values, as well
as the SSIDs values, or if you
look at the alphanumeric nature,
skewed. Written two scripts, one
for each. Let me show you that.
I'm sorry. Wrong directory.
Okay. Real solve because it's
checking, basically we have a
newer version. Now, what you'd
actually find is, Chigula
detects that all of these SSIDs
created by Mdk3. Let's see how
simple the script is to go ahead
and do this. How many of you
have -- before? So this is, most
of the stuff you've seen,
arguments and help, just so
people can look at it later. So
here is an example, what we
check is of the number of
alphanumeric, on an average, is
-- specific threshold. That's
one way of looking at completely
random SSIDs. Now, the other
interesting way is to go ahead
and look at the PLVs. Okay. The
screen is actually giving me --
so here is what we are doing. We
go ahead, open the pcap file and
written a very simple library,
which you can use directly,
called models, and to that you
can go ahead, import most of the
intelligence Chigula has. And
all you have to do then is
basically tell Chigula what kind
of packet you would like to
select and analyze. Right. So we
have a MAC headers module, and
you can go ahead, create macros,
look at different SSIDs and
things like that, and associate
it with SSIDs and check which
ones are skewed. Now, we can
actually do the same thing with
Airbase-NG. Now, Airbase-NG has
a very specific signature.
Anyone know the only four
elements Airbase-NG has in probe
packets and Beacon packets, for
probably the last seven years?
Quite easy to fingerprint. So it
has the SSIDs, of course, the
channel, the -- and the
extended. And at time some of
the older ones even have a bug,
where the probe request packets
probably go ahead and add a null
SSIDs as an additional. So using
that, we can go ahead and create
a signature, run all the entire,
and if there aren't any issues
in -- if there are any issues in
packet passing, it will tell
specific packets. In most cases,
some of these packets have been
truncated by Wireshark, so just
tells you, I have to stop
somewhere in between, because I
don't have the full packet. And
there you go. It actually tells
you that this is the MAC
address, of which creates the
fake, and we can verify that by
looking at the trace file, so
this is something actually
created at DEFCON. Let me go
ahead and apply the filter. And
all of these Beacon frames as
well as probe requests have been
created using Airbase, so if you
select any of these, actually
find that these are the only --
right? Most attack tools are
actually quite easy to
fingerprint, if you look at the
time frames. Unbelievably easy
to fingerprint. Now, attack
signatures, easy to write. What
about replay attacks, require us
to take a single frame and then
check the entire SQL*Lite
database to see if something
matches directly and if it
matches about a certain
threshold. Keep in mind, in
Wi-Fi, they can actually be a
lot of retries, so you need to
check that this isn't a retry
packet for a previous one. So
with Chigula, you can actually
go ahead and check for replay
attacks for any -- I mean, this
is frame agnostic, even though
-- further, frames or
disassociation frames or
anything you like. Let me show
you a quick demo. So one of the
things which are adding is also
a hash for everything. So that
this check can be much more --
that's something you already
working on. And Chigula tells
you senders and the number of
frames replayed by that sender.
And it also gives you the frame
ID, so you can actually go back
to the pcap file, open it up,
look at the very first screen,
which is there in your pcap,
actually replayed. And the
replay attack even has an option
to isolate the frames which have
been replayed. Now, detecting
honey parts is basically a two
level problem. At level one,
quite easy to do, the admin,
whoever is checking, has a list
of allowed SSIDs and allowed
clients, and if you have any
associations of clients or --
which differ from this list,
then of course, you have some
kind of a -- Now, the biggest
problem with this kind of
detection is AP MAC spoofing,
right? What happens, spoof
access point in which case, a
detection would be very
difficult to succeed. So in the
first one, I'll show you the
plain way of looking at it
without AP MAC spoofing and in
the next example I'll show you
how to detect AP MAC spoofing.
And all of these scripts are
available so you can try them
out later along with your own. I
already have a list of
authorized APs. Just -- two of
them, just as a sample. And then
I'm going to be running against
the pcap. And this gives me the
list of all unauthorized SSIDs,
advertising the same SSID,
right? Now, this is of course,
quite simple and trivial, which
brings us to the next part, MAC
spoofing. What happens when an
attacker spoofs the MAC of
alleged -- at this point? Could
someone tell me how you could go
ahead and detect that using
something like Chigula? And
whoever answers that gets a --
The Beacon frames might even
look identical, actually, so you
can take an existing Beacon
frame and just replay it. >> [
Inaudible ] >> Time difference
might not be it, simply because
the attacker's AP would be
running concurrently as, you
know, the enterprise AP. I mean,
almost the same time always.
Could even be -- fake access
points and probably one of the
more difficult things to crack.
>> [ Inaudible ] >>
Transmission, one dimension,
unfortunately just one sensor
it's difficult to go ahead and
ascertain that reliably, because
in any wireless communication,
you have things like multiple --
right? So the same location, you
can have maximize and minimize,
depending upon how the
environment changes. So all your
commercial -- vendors at least
have more than three sensors who
-- access points -- anything
else? >> [ Inaudible ] >> So if
an attacker clones let's say the
Beacon frame or clones the MAC
address, clones all the
information elements as well,
how do you figure the difference
out? Right? If he doesn't clone
the -- you know, that's what was
about yesterday, which I spoke,
which is the IE cannot be cloned
exactly because the attacker
won't have prior knowledge, but
in this kind of fake AP attack,
attacker in the parking lot,
somewhere close to the
enterprise, he can actually
clone as least the Beacons. >> [
Inaudible ] >> The attacker
could probably do an MIT --
attack, where he can read off
the traffic -- he would have two
client Wi-Fi cards, read out the
traffic -- Anyone? Who is that?
>> [ Inaudible ] >> What are
sequence numbers? [ Laughter ]
Okay. You're on the right track.
So a little bit more. A little
bit more. Yeah. >> [ Inaudible ]
>> We might not be able to look
at the protocol layer because it
would be entirely encrypted,
right? It could be encrypted --
and Chigula right now, I mean,
we are just looking at layers,
we aren't looking at layer three
and above. Sequence number is,
like, right starting points I'm
going to give you a book for
that, but who can explain -- [
Applause ] [ Laughter ] But who
can explain all sequence numbers
can be used. For two books. [
Laughter ] >> [ Inaudible ] >>
So sequence numbers, unlike
things like TTL, in the case of
IP, basically get incremented
and then wrap around. Unlike TTL
where you could see a Linux
based system could have, I don't
remember, but 128 as their
default, or Windows could have,
you know, 64 as default. In
Wi-Fi, the sequence number just
getting implemented one per
frame and when we reach the end,
we wrap around. So it's not
operating system specific. >> [
Inaudible ] >> Okay. Very good.
Here you go. So if you have two
devices -- [ Applause ] -- so if
you have multiple devices, and
we actually do a sequence number
analysis, for a MAC address, so
here's what we do. For every
given MAC in the place file you
have, do a sequence ID analysis,
and what you actually see is,
you have two different sequence
-- sequences, sequence ID
sequences or clusters, which are
moving in completely different
directions. Now, you might say,
what if the attacker tries to
clone the sequence number as
close as possible and what you'd
end up having is duplicates.
Right? Either way, it's going to
be duplicates, if the attacker,
the moment he sees the real AP
sent out a frame, fix the
sequence number, immediately --
next frame, right? You have
duplicates. That's very
difficult to do, simply because
the attacker -- speak next,
right? The other possibility is
of course, that both the
devices, both the devices are
progressing on their own. So
this is probably the standard
way of detecting MAC address
spoofing almost in all wireless
intrusion detection systems.
This is an extremely powerful
metric. In 2007, I gave a talk
called cracking WEP cloaking, at
DEFCON, which was basically how
do you crack WEP in the presence
of shaft packets? Absolute
garbage injected by SSIDs and
one of the key metrics I
actually used to separate
different kind of packets was
actually sequence numbers, so
let's actually see how Chigula
can allow you to do a very easy
and simple analysis. With
sequence numbers. And we can
open up the image. There we go.
So if you looked at the pcap
file, which I'll show you in a
bit, in the very beginning, we
had one device, and really this
-- extrapolated as well, depends
when start file. You have one
device, but often sometimes you
have another device, it seems to
have a separate sequence number,
kind of going in a very
different value -- I'm going to
show you how it looks like in
the sample. And you can create a
fake -- and same MAC address and
try this out. This detection
actually works quite well. So
closely look at the SN. SN is
basically sequence numbers. So
as we scroll down, currently see
one device which has an
incrementing sequence number.
And now you're probably starting
to see something in the range of
range of 3,500. Right?
Interestingly, you can even
detect the number of pcaps by
figuring out each one of these
progressions and clusters and
Chigula allows you to do that,
because you're basically picking
up the individual numbers and
defaulting it. Work by default,
no magic required to do this.
You can see that. Now, if you
started collecting the trace
file in the very beginning, you
would probably see this stretch
out absolutely from the very
beginning of your collection
time as well. Right? This
actually is -- a lot of times
pentester to scan an area, find
Rogue devices mimicking MAC
addresses of authorized devices,
using Wireshark, but allows me
to explain that there are
multiple devices to admin,
people higher up. Okay. So we
are going to be releasing
Chigula. You can download it,
maybe within next hour, the link
should be live. All the scripts
are included. Already developing
more plug-ins, more attacks and
visualizations which can be
detected. Going to be completely
open source. So feel free to,
you know, look at all the bad
code we've written. Already
written crash, right in the
front. The other thing which
you're going to do is something
like an -- I don't know how many
of you have used the feature,
when it was available. Right,
automatically tries every single
exploit. So what we'd like to do
is for every device have a go
through each of these individual
plug-ins so we can detect
different attacks which may be
happening. Right? So
streamlining so that the moment
you pass the pcap file it can
actually automatically tell you,
these five MAC addresses are
being spoofed. That is a replay
attack happening for these
streams, right, and all of the
stuff that you saw right now,
going to -- different MAC
addresses. Finally, reporting
capability. So do we have time
for questions? A couple
questions? Okay. Questions. >> [
Inaudible ] >> Yes. So that is
an -- there is an option
available. You can go ahead and
sniff packets live as well. So
you actually notice there are
sniffing options available. This
will only work for -- you can --
feed interface in. Right? Any
more questions? >> I have a
question. [ Applause ] >> Thank
you. Thank you. Thank you.