This talk is the ham sandwich
talk. It's a replacement talk.
So if you look in your guide, in
the paper guide, we're replacing
a talk that was canceled. What
we're really replacing is a talk
that was in the press about two
weeks ago. And that it was a big
-- kind of a big deal that
people thought that maybe
somebody else's talk was
canceled. We're really a
replacement for that talk. So we
are two researchers, Dave Meiner
and Robert Grahan and we have
been doing a lot of SDR things,
that is software definable
radio. But what it really is is
hacking of the internet of
things. Lots of stuff these
days, your car, your phone, your
gun, all these things connect to
the internet over radio waves.
So a big deal these days is
learning how to use computers
and software definable radio in
order to hack everything that
talks radio. So I'm Robert
Graham, I do a lot of blogging
and Twitter. I'm famous for a
couple of things like black ice,
flak Jacking and I do lots of
conference talks. My partner
here is Dave Meiner. He is also
notorious for the apple hack
from several years ago, some DA
hacks and he is one of the
awesomest pen testers in the
world. And he also has done lots
of conference talks and we've
done many of our talks together.
He'll be setting up the demo
here if he can get it to work.
We only have a 20-minute slot
here so we don't have much time.
The talk that we're replacing is
this proxy ham talk where a guy
put together two boxes in order
to create a point to point link
with the idea that one might be
in some place next to a bar or a
Starbucks with an open wifi and
the other box would be up on a
hill somewhere with your laptop.
So as a hacker you could be five
miles away from the bar and
using their wifi and when they
track back the IP address of the
hacker they wouldn't be able to
find the real hacker. This talk,
that talk was canceled under
suspicious circumstances. There
was suspicion it was the FBI or
the government tried to suppress
the talk. And that was sort of
our motivation for talking about
this. There was things like NSL,
national security letters that
have quieted people and
suppressed things. There's been
lawsuits and lots of things in
our industry that try to
suppress research. So this was
our philosophy. This really
should be the philosophy of
DEFCON. When we see a talk has
been canceled and it really
isn't in the area of our own
expertise, or something we've
been researching lately, people
ought to step up and say I can
do something similar to that.
That rapid transit thing from --
when that was canceled. There
are other people that do
research along those same lines
from my fair car hacking for
example. So when we see a talk
that's been canceled, people
ought to step up and say, hey, I
can do something similar.
However, what we found was this
talk in particular though wasn't
so dramatic. We don't know why
the talk was canceled. The proxy
ham talk was canceled. But we
guess that the agency that was
involved was probably the FCC
rather than the NSA or the FBI.
If you see here -- we'll get to
that in the next picture. What
he probably did was boosted the
transmit power and the FCC is a
very prickly agency. They have
people staffed at every major
city in the United States whose
sole job it is is to hunt down
people that transmit power,
radio frequencies at too high a
power. Or who interfere with
other stuff. So we suspect what
happened is that the FCC caught
him, they came to his door and
they probably gave him a letter
and this is what the FCC does.
The big thing they do is they
don't want to prosecute people,
they don't want to hurt people.
But they do want people to stop
causing the interference. So one
thing they do have is a consent
decree which is to say, you sign
here and agree that you won't do
this stuff anymore ever again
and then we'll let you off with
a small fine or ignore the
situation. Also I'm guessing
that the real reason this guy
was quiet is because his lawyer
said, hey, if there is a legal
situation the first thing your
lawyer is going to tell you is
to shut up and stop talking
about it. So it's probably
something simple like the FCC
coming down on him rather than
the FBI trying to stop hackers
or something like that. So this
was the picture from the Wired
article. From Wired magazine.
What we see from here is he is
using standard off the shelf
equipment. This device has a
yogi antenna for the directional
antenna and you see this white
box on the back of the antenna.
Well that's just a Ubiquity
device. Ubiquity is a company
that cells point to point
internet links. This is a
picture from their website. If
you look at it, it's essentially
the same thing. It's just a
little box plugged into the back
of a Yogi antenna. So -- >> This
is a great lesson actually for
all of the kind of security
types you see. A lot of times
when people do press ahead of
time, they give away enough
details that you should be able
to reproduce what they're doing.
Like in this example, all it
took was Googling for Yogis and
900 megahertz to find the
Ubiquity device he was using in
the photo. >> Yes. As Dave said
from the press we can often tell
what the talk is about. We went
online and bought the same sorts
of devices from Ubiquity. The
rocket end that he was using was
a little more expensive and
required an external antenna and
I'm cheap and I bought the
cheaper units. I'm going to see
if this goes here. We bought the
units -- so you can see these
units. I'm going to pull them
out of my bag here. I probably
should have brought them out
when I was waiting? >> While Rob
is doing this, the basic premise
of our theory is is that the
original researcher assumed that
because the ubiquity would give
us point to point connection
over 900 megahertz instead of
2.4 gig hertz, it would somehow
provide an additional layer of
obfuscation that would make it
hard finding the signal and the
source. That is really what our
talk is all about. So you can
buy these Ubiquity devices on
E-bay for $125. Not much at all.
You have to get two of them,
though. So 900 megahertz if you
don't know, it's an ISM band by
2.4 or 5.8. It can do longer
distances because the wavelength
is longer and penetrates things
better. They can go through
buildings and trees. As an
interesting note because of the
demo we're going to do, I ended
up getting my amateur radio
exam, my ham radio license just
so we could do this demo.
...(applause)... I didn't want
to brag but I knocked the
technical and general and extra
out in one sitting. >> So Dave
actually cheated. I say cheated.
He had actually been studying
for the exam for like two years.
So he didn't really just go up
there and just do the test. He's
been studying for it. >> Rob, in
reality I just learned how to
use SDRs and only stuff I really
had to study for was the
procedures. So 900 megahertz
band and these are the devices
right here that Rob has. >> I
didn't really want to set them
up in the hotel because they
really cause a lot of
interference. But they're just
two boxes and as I -- as you see
in the previous picture, you
just set them up and what the
connection is, is on the
left-hand side you see one of
these bridges connected to a
little wifi device. Almost every
wifi access point can act as a
wireless bridge or a wireless
client. So you go to a bar or a
Starbucks and find some power
outlet outside or bring a
battery pack. And you can
configure a little wifi access
point to connect and log onto
the wifi at Starbucks. And then
you connect that access point to
the 900 megahertz bridge and
point it five miles up a hill
where you can see line of sight
with the hill. Up on the hill
you sit there with your laptop
and the other bridge pointed
back down towards the Starbucks
at your other device. And then
you can log on remotely from
really, really far away. I used
to live in the Bay area where
you had the hills up between the
hills and the Bay area they had
views over almost the entire Bay
area. This would really go
really, really far. So yeah, the
reason by the way that you use
900 megahertz is it goes farther
than 2.4 megahertz. >> Do we
have time? >> We have time. By
the way these boxes though,
they're still just wifi boxes.
One of the critical features of
this proxy ham thing is whether
it's an encrypted connection.
And it is. It's just using WPA2.
The configuration of the boxes
is the same as the wifi access
point. And when we pull them
apart, we see if they're using
the same or if there is tip set
(ph.). The only thing different
between these and a 2.4 gig
hertz wifi device is they have a
little converter on it that
converts the signal, the whole
block of that range from 2.4 gig
hertz down to 900 megahertz.
That's why they're more
expensive. Ubiquity sells the
identical devices that run at
2.4 gigahertz but that's really
the only difference. These boxes
come with a flat panel antenna.
So when the flat side faces you,
that's the directional antenna.
And this is the shape of the
communications. So directional
antenna means less radio
frequencies on the side and
behind and more out front. That
is why they're directional and
you point them at each other.
You have two directional
antennas pointing at each other
that improves the signal. So at
the maximum rate, and I set this
up, I got 22 megabits per second
download. And I'm not quite sure
if that was the limitation of
those devices or that little
wifi access point that I was
using. Is your demo ready? >>
Yes. >> Okay. So this was the
picture of what -- I set this up
last night in my hotel room. And
I used an SDR to go look at the
900 megahertz spectrum and to
see what it looked like. So I
walked out of my hotel room down
a ways to a bar in order to see
how much of that signal I could
see from pretty far away. So
through many buildings, with
these devices not even pointed
at me, this was the signal that
I got. And what you can see
slightly to the right is that
bump. And that bump is a very
obvious 900 megahertz signal.
Even with concrete buildings in
the way I can still see this is
very visible. That's the problem
with the proxy ham concept. Is
that I think the orangal talk
believed that 900 megahertz that
no one was watching but in fact
we are watching. We actually can
see the signal and it's very
easy to track the signal back to
its location. The FCC has banned
in every city all the equipment
that is necessary to point the
antennas, do the directional
finding, and go some place,
stop, scan, go some place else,
stop, scan. Triangulate and they
will find you really, really
quickly. You think you're nice
and secrete and point to point
and no one can see you, they see
you very quickly. So what we've
done, what Dave set up here is
an alternative using the SDRs.
They're more expensive and
they're going to be slower. And
by the way when I post this
presentation online, here are
some links to other people doing
similar things. What our
technique is, is in our case is
to hide the -- that point to
point link below what is called
the noise floor. Another way to
think of it is a negative signal
to noise ratio. And what the
noise, what the noise floor is,
is like the radio static you
hear on an FM radio. It's the
background noise that comes from
the atmosphere, from lightening
storms, from manmade objects,
bad antennas. There's a dark
line on this picture here,
that's where I unplugged my
laptop from the power and
plugged it back in. Unplugging
it reduced the noise floor. So
in theory anything below the
noise floor you can never catch.
You can never have a radio
signal that will work. In
practice it does. If you tune to
FM radio station with an SDR you
see that, you can find FM radio
stations by hearing the music
that as far as the SDR is
concerned doesn't exist. There
is nothing above that noise
floor. So conceptually what
we're doing is, our technique,
instead of building up a strong
signal that jumps above the
noise floor as you saw that bump
before in the graph, what we're
going to do instead is do lots
of little channels all below the
noise floor, all co-opterring to
amply fie our signal but still
hide behind the waves like a
little submarine thing. By the
way I tried to draw this with
PowerPoint, I just gave up and
just hand drew it and took a
picture. So the problem with
this is that it's going to be
slower speed. We have time. We
have 7 minutes. The advantage of
this is undetectability. If they
knew exactly what we were doing
they could find us. But in all
probability they can't detect
that any signal exists. So I'll
let David continue with this and
then go onto the demo. >> So as
a young man I used to look at
the moon and I would dream. What
would it be like to touch the
moon? Since I can't become an
astronaut after getting my ham
radio stuff, I learned there's a
thing called an earth moon
bounce or an EMB. It's basically
how you bounce the radio off the
moon. You use a protocol called
the JT65A. This is designed to
work with a lot of noise in
between. It's great for our
purposes. Because that's
basically what we're doing. It
was really limited to the amount
of data it can transfer. So
instead of using basically one
carrier, we multiplex it over
several different versions of
JT65. This is our demo. Hold on
a second. Any questions so far,
comments, suggestions? >>
(inaudible). >> We have done
about 20-miles. Once again,
we're going to show you
something really interesting. >>
(inaudible). >> Well one would
be less than -- basically less
than around two bod. But with
multiple, we can get up to 56K.
>> So the limitation is having
lots of SDRs, you can increase
the speed. One of the problems
is that signal strength is
logarithmic or exponential. That
means you don't really see on
the graphs very easily, that's
the easiest way to increase the
speed is massively increasing
the power. It's really easy. But
we're going length wise and
that's linear. So the faster you
want to go, you need more SDRs
and faster SDRs. >> So this is
kind of what the signal would
look like if it was being
broadcast over 900 megahertz
using the Ubiquity gear using a
2 megahertz channel. As you can
see if you're looking at that
and you have any clue what
you're doing, you're not hiding
from anything. That's one hell
of a spike. Right? So what we
did don't look at my password.
>> So what Dave is doing here is
we're using one laptop because
mine I couldn't get working with
the video. He is going to use a
VM to do the transmit. He is
actually going to transmit his
signal and use the other to
receive on the graph like this
to see what the signal looks
like. And now he seems to have
broken it. He had 20 minutes and
he told me to hurry. >> Somebody
in the audience is, jamming us.
That is always funny. We really
appreciate that. Who wants demos
to go right the first time? You
don't go to NASCAR races to see
the completion of the race, you
go to see the carnies right.
This is what it looks like
normally. If you look at the
graph at the bottom, that is the
signal. You can see over on the
left-hand side the DB, you can
see the peak, where the signal
is rising. This is over time,
right. So with the other one --
where did it go? >> While he
figures this out. We just put
this together with the new radio
which is the standard tool kit
for SDRs that everyone uses. >>
This is the same spectrum. This
is actually us transmitting. If
you look you'll see there is a
much wider and lower profile for
the signal. That is because the
JT65A modulators, there's
when we recorded this. Basically
multiplexing all the data across
a little over 2 megahertz to get
a 56K signal which may seem
strange, but you can be easily
located by standard direction
finding gear. With that being
said, people that have nation
state assets can easily find you
with this. But not a person with
a $20 SDR. >> What's that spike
we see to the left? >> The spy?
>> The spike. >> Here. >> Yes.
>> This is the noise floor. And
this is -- we recorded what's
under it. Without the rest,
we're basically pushing down the
rest of the noise floor. In
addition to being able to hide
the signal, the thousand or so
JT65A encoders that are running
actually collectively cause the
noise floor to raise making it
even harder to find the signal.
We plan or putting on this code
on GitHub and hopefully one day
be able to integrate it into a
simple raspberry based solution
so you can do these types of
things without having much radio
knowledge. >> Any questions? So
the thing that really made this
all possible and keep in mind
just for a recap, the proxy ham
and the proxy gambit, the proxy
gambit still uses a 900
megahertz connection. But they
also added a cellular device.
And Sammy said they did that
because you can basically use it
from anywhere in the world using
the same techniques. Somebody
could find a -- find your device
with the cellular modem that
you're using or a point to point
link. At that point your
identify is kind of blown. That
should be the take away. And
there are ways to hide yourself.
>> So are there any questions?
>> Any comments? Any
suggestions? >> Question over
there. >> (inaudible). >> The
question is, why is this
illegal? Because the guy was
doing it over the ISM band. We
don't know the exact details but
we suspect the reason is because
he boosted the signal. If you
look in the manual for these
devices or these devices, it
says this is -- this meets these
requirements for part 15 blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah of the
FCC regulations but there's an
external antenna here and the
documentation clearly says if
you add an external antenna you
must be a licensed person to do
so. Because the regulations
monitor, regulate how much power
at a certain distance. This is
directional but still spreads
which means the power is less.
The more directional you make
it, the more you're likely to
then exceed those regulations.
That's what we suspect happened
is that Yogi is just too
powerful, it's beyond the light
distance operation and you can't
do it? >> Also if you're over
the power limit, if you're not
operating legally as a low
powered device but you're over
the regulation, you're not
supposed to send any encoded or
encrypted data. What he was
doing was proxying WPA2
encrypted wifi which is against
FCC radio standards. In our demo
we are not proxying that, we are
just sending a message that says
send it? >> Was a big question,
the regulations are complex that
way. >> We have a question over
here? >> You had said you can
still download data, et cetera,
et cetera across this line. How
much data would you be able to
send? >> Up to 56K. Basically
the same as one of the higher
speed dial-up modems from the
late 90s. >> Okay. I just wanted
to confirm that. A second
question that I have is if you
were to have two of these
devices and you're using it on
your property, does that still
make it illegal? You're still
going to have the FCC showing up
at your door? You're in the
neighborhood and you're on a
couple of acres? >> Well the FCC
controls all the air waves in
the United States, so being on
your own property doesn't negate
or doesn't stop you have having
frequency plans. The FCC is very
specific. That although these
devices are technically
unlicensed, they're only legal
as long as they're operated in
the correct capacity that does
not cause interference with
other devices. Once you start
doing that, you have to stop
your operations. >> In practice
you probably can. But if
somebody nearby complains of
interference, whether or not
you're actually the one at
fault, they will probably see
that you're transmitting at a
very high power and come and
knock on your door and tell you
to stop. But you won't have to
pay fines because you didn't
damage anybody else. Probably.
I'm not here to give legal
advice so I have no idea. >> We
are not lawyers. >> Question
over there. I'm sorry I can't
hear that. Something about ...
whoever was doing it stopped.
This is what it looks like on a
GQRS. The peaks are minimal but
we have our devices, the one
that is transmitting and the one
that is receiving very close to
each other but that is what it
looks like when you're running
it. Whoever was jamming us,
thank you for stopping. And
we'll find you. >> We're worse
than the FCCs trust me. >>
Great, so the big take away here
is we really wanted to prove
that there was nothing hokey or
hinkey about the talk being
rejected. We just actually --
not rejected or pulled -- we do
believe that at some point the
author just decided or learned
that it was a bad idea and
wasn't providing the level of
anonymity that they thought
originally. >> That's our talk.
We'll be heading out. So thank
you very much. >> If you have a
moment when you're done and
you're leaving, there is a young
blond woman in the front row
named Sophie Kotch, if you could
spend a few minutes talking to
her about IOT that would be
great. Thank you.
...(applause)...