>> Good morning everybody how
are we feeling today? Good thank
you all for coming. These guys
are unfair advantage because
everybody come in yesterday
morning and said what in the
world is that thing. It looks
like the pro motion worked. So
let's learn about how machines
are going to replace us all.
Let's give these guys a big hand
[ applause ] >> Hello Defcon. So
thank you for the intro. Yes, we
did put a high performance
machine this year. My name is
mike walker I'm the program
manager about researcher agency
darpa. >> Hi everybody I want to
put out the url on the left
front stage, if we are going to
talk about capture the flag we
should let you guys play one. If
you go there, you might want a
laptop, there's binary, source
information. Connection
information. Have at it. We
might have to give you hints
later on. And one a little bit
advice if you connect to it, try
not a long session, you will see
why later. >> Hopefully some of
you can hack it and capture the
flag. In the meantime, I want to
talk to you a little bit why we
are here. When I walk around
Defcon and I'm around darpa. We
are also known for our history
of challenges. Starting in 2004d
arpa started opening global
competitions. First in
self-driving cars. We gave a
million dollars to the first
team that can drive an
autonomous car and another in
city traffic. Again, global open
competition developed technology
that doesn't really exist yet.
We are here today to talk about
bringing autonomy to the sport
of hackers to capture the flag
and we will take this room and
knock down the air walls next
year and have three times bigger
realtime, with sports casting
and imagine an events where all
the contestants are machines. We
will talk about how it works and
why it's so important. So if we
are going to talk about computer
security and autonomy, we need
to recognition that computer
security is adversarial contest
of the mind. Bruce and Dan talk
about a field that is defined by
an intelligent opponent. And
computers have been playing the
adversarial contest of the mind
for a while. We will start with
checker. It's a solved game. We
are able to write every single
position in a database all ten
to the 20th position. Solve for
what perfect play looks like. It
turns out once the checker was
solve the conclusion with
perfect play the winning move is
not to play. But the big play is
chess. Chess was proposed as a
grand challenge for machine.
Father of information gear. And
the idea of the computer that
can be the very best people at
chess took 46 years. It wasn't
until years later where deep
bluetooth became the chess
champion. In 1970 acm created an
all computer chess league just
so computers can play each
other. At prototype competition
in 1977 one of those competition
computers beet the grand master
for the first time. It was
foreshadowing things to come.
That's chess. Let's talk about
harder game. This is go.
Recently go computers have
started to be competitive. Very
best master at go. This board
which is a beginner board. This
is not the board that master
play on. They play on this. 10
to the 7th 6th power position.
10 to the 86th power number of
atoms in the known universe.
That is not infinite but not
possible to reason about. When
it comes to boards computer
don't have a chance with the go
players. So when we start
talking search spaces, machine
starts to breakdown when they
start to play against us. But
the game I've talk about is
actually a very simple game.
Let's talk about a real game. We
appeared locked up. I'm just
going to keep talking. Let's
talk about poker. Poker is very
difficult game for machines to
play. And it's difficult for a
variety of reasons. The first is
this is multi opponent. You
don't have a single opponent in
poker. If I'm at a table and I'm
playing poker and I'm a little
fish and at the table is another
little fish and big fish. It
behooves me to get the big fish
to eat the other guys, which
means I need to mold player
versus player interactions that
are not my own. Thank you.
Additionally, keep the mic? All
right. I'll keep the mic. Oh,
yeah. We can switch that back to
the slides. We'll do it. This
game is none zero sum. So what
does that mean? It's if I play 9
games of chess and I win except
the 11th. If you win 10 games of
chess and win every one but
loses the 11th game, I'm
winning. If you win 10 games for
a $1 and lose a million dollars
at the 11th, you are not
winning. Poker is a game of
incomplete information. I can
see my pieces and you can see
mine. Poker everything is a
secret. As a player you have to
keep a statistical probability
model what your opponent has and
move throughout the game. So how
are computers doing against
human with poker? This year four
versus 4, 7 hundred thousand
chips. Do not reproduce. So
since we are not just in Las
Vegas we are Defcon. Let's talk
about a really hard game.
Capture the flag. It's being
played right now in the valley
with about 15. You can tell from
the get go that this is multi
opponent. This is the live
network exercise. Big team
sport. Let's talk about what the
teams are doing. Imagine you
have a friend who is not a c
coder. And he's written a whole
bunch of new services and he's
giving you a new one and said
plug into a server with best
ones in the world. That's
capture the world. First you
have to defend information.
Capture the flag. Flag is data.
And code you have never seen.
You want to keep flag so you are
protecting data. All as fast as
you can. Second you want to take
your opponent's flag. You want
to feel the patch and take as
many flags as you can in the
short amount of time as
possible. If somebody hands you
that server please plug it into
this hardware, the clever
amongst you will say I know how
to win this game. I will turn
everything off. This is a
network exercise. I'm going to
talk about what that referee is
doing. It's a gigantic cinder
all the data in the game. The
game changes over time. The
upshot of this you don't know
who the sender is and the
referee the game organizer
talking to every piece of
software and making sure that it
still work, they are connecting
to it and e-mail server they
send you e-mail and make sure
it's work agree correctly. And
web server to make sure all the
content is there and up and
running and running as it needs
to be. So if you slow the
software down, damage it you
lose points. If you turn it off
you lose all your points. Keep
your data, take other os data
and don't break any of the
software you are trying to
defend. This is obviously a game
of incomplete information. The
flaws your o-popes have. So
sounds hard. Let's continue. How
is it that teams play this
exercise. If you play live
network defense contest. It's
simple and I'm going to sit down
with wireshark and get to work
and, wireshark will decode
single pack of data. And the
reason for that is it's running
all new protocol, software.
Nexus don't have a single
vulnerability signature that
works. You have to do binary
reverse engineering the entire
time. You have to, you are given
binary code, no documentation.
And the only way to know how it
works is to reverse it. To write
your own vulnerability scanner
and do it as fast as you can
while your opponents are trying
to do the same thing to you.
Research space. The number of
atoms in the universe and size
of the go board. Big numbers. It
turns out when you want to
reason about the number of
inputs into arbitrary un examine
software we have a good proof
that says we don't know anything
about software in the general
case. We don't know when it's
going to halt let alone input it
has. Research software is
infinite and it gets harder from
there. If you want to explore
space and software and it's none
trivial. You need to learn how
to have a conversation with it.
If I'm an e-mail client and I'm
calling a brand new e-mail
server and I say hello. And
hello your sequence number is
50. I don't know what to do next
unless I reverse out. Maybe I
need to add 51 or maybe I need
to hash it or add a match. Even
to explore the state pace and
know how many position there
are, I think to synthesize in
order to talk to the software.
You have multiple opponent. None
zero sum game with incomplete
information. If machines can't
win at go and win at poker do
machine have a chance of doing
this at all? And that's exactly
what we are talking about doing.
Taking the team away from ctf
table and let the machine. But
any machine but this one over
here. We will fire it up for you
guys [applause] so this year we
brought one of these. Next year
we are bringing 15 racks. But
that one is 1300, 16 tb of ram.
The whole computer outlay is a
half megawatt. And we are going
to run it and all that heat as
the Las Vegas summer. Machines
is not enough. This contest is
about automation and software
about the system that's going to
solve this challenge. Let's talk
a little bit why this is
feasible. For the last year
we've been running the
qualifying round. The result of
that qualification are free and
open and available and download
them. That's everything the
machine did in our qualifiers.
Every binary that patch
themselves every vulnerability
they built. How many capture the
flag we let the machine played?
In scale, Defcon capture the
flag, team up to 80 people have
to solve 10 challenges in 48
hours. Ten difficult reverse
engineering binary challenges.
Machine 131 in 24 hours. The
machine skill capture the flag.
They were able to synthesize
vulnerability in 75% of the
software we released. When I say
they prove vulnerability I don't
mean they binary code and spit
out we need there's an integer
over flow here. Not false
positive. They were able to
create the input and logic
recreate the binary they've
never seen. That means the
conversation logic and the input
that creates the sig fault. We
asked them to patch software.
Now, obviously we have
conditions on this because it's
easy to do that. Start exit. So
what we asked them to do
original functionality. The unit
test, make sure the software was
reasonably undamaged and not
slow if software down.
Performing within the limits.
Given those preconditions we
know there are 590 bugs and of
those bugs we can test for as a
field the machine's patch 100%.
So we think we have believable
autonomy in this space. 7
finalist qualified who built the
system we will introduce to you
later. But think about the scale
of that capture the flag that we
will try to bring onstage near.
131 binary to run it in a day
live network head to head that
is whole tons of data sports to
you live event. So how to go
deeper from a sports casting
perspective. It's easier to have
raise of the bar contest. Team
has points. But we wanted to
actually to be able to see in
realtime structurally what great
patch looked like. What a great
cashing input, flag capture
looked like. To do that we have
to build some visualization
software and we did not decide
to bring you screenshot. We
brought a live demo. With that
Jordan you are on. >> Thankfully
I'm shorter. This mic works.
Let's go ahead and pull up what
we are talking about here. Mike
talk about we have software
that's able to look at other
software. If you've done binary
reverse engineering this will be
familiar to you. S tray this.
Sample sys call log. I'm able to
see from here what kernel system
called were made. But I don't
see the logic. I don't see
comparisons. I don't see certain
things so to do that I'm going
to pull out the debugger and
look at what it's actually
doing. Ctf is command-line game
and understand is command-line
exercise. >> I do pro, so that
get you some graphical
interface. You are looking at
886. Don't try to read that.
This one, though is the
challenge you are running right
now. You've seen the source.
Hopefully you are working hard
at it. I would love to see
someone do crash on it. 300
lines of code. Clapping for
something they saw there. Oh,
that's good [ applause ] >> So
we have little traditions to
welcome new speakers. Are these
guys doing a good job? [
applause & cheers ]. >> So we
have a couple of patches here
for these guys that we want to
give to them. And we have one
for the competitor over there.
Thank you, guys. Give them audio
round of applause. [ applause ]
>> Nice. That makes more sense
than source code. So this isn't
really all that useful. Let's
look at what the program does.
It's a customer support message
board. It's a classic
application. Two vulnerabilities
that we know about. Possibly
more that's a beauty of c. I'm
going to go ahead and put my
name in there. Let's view some
threads. Welcome to our message
board. Let's reply to this one.
Your software broke. Like most
customer support request. Check
the threads. Oh, good. It's got
my message. So we can add new
messages. Simple service. Let's
exit back out. Now we get to the
fun spot. Instead of looking at
that, that execution right there
is loaded up live in here and
maybe it's 37. This is good. We
got lots of input. I don't know
if you could tell which one is
mine. Let's see if this one is
mine. >> So you want to give us
technically what this is. >>
This is me. I'm looking at
someone else's. This is hexes.
It's a visualization engine for
cgc and this view is tracker.
Memory trace viewer. That's what
we are looking at. This is
software running over time. And
time, of course, on the x that's
how it's done. When we start
here at the beginning. The
assembly bottom left. >> So the
program ran in the dynamic
sandbox the events recorded and
what you are seeing left to
right is execution overtime. And
structure that was created by
that data being executed by that
software. >> So the fancy
explanation is we've got realty
address mapped into curve to
maintain locality what it means
it's a picture that shows what
the program did. We took the
program and we feed it input.
And in this case is what I just
did. That's what we are looking
at right now. When other tracks,
these are what you are doing.
I'll see a little red one. If
somebody manages to figure that
out we will see it there. We can
step through this track. Let it
run. Change some layouts views
of it. We've had system calls.
Saw earlier this is my use. I've
got transmit. I can see output
to the program. Allocation. I
can see memory. Layer on top of
linux. All of these being shown
in the gui. We've cheated. You
don't need source code to track.
This is viewer thread. And
looking at this you can see
structure. You can tell the
piece that outputs data over
here. This is the region of
memory the piece of code that is
doing word wrapping. It's
reading over. Bouncing it back
and when it gets to the end of
it. You don't have to know
exactly what the assembly is.
You can make comparison without
having that. >> Locality is
preserved. Code that is closed
together, it's grouped together.
So a far jump is a far jump. >>
And likewise a tight loop down
here or something looks thin.
This is the code in the original
disassembly program. >> Over
time is cool. Over time it's
able to compare traces. We are
hoping still that somebody is
going to capture our flag and
give us a crashing trace. We
will show one now. Should we
drop a hint? >> Yes. >>
Structure links are super
interesting. Strength of 30. So
I might want to try that minus 1
plus 1. Anyway. >> I'm going to
go ahead and generate a
different use of the program
now. I'm going to post new
threat. My subject. Software.
It's better. My spelling is too.
All right. Back and look. That
one is not mine. I don't think
that's mine. >> Let's go take a
look at that. >> Here's mine.
That's the different one. Let's
look at here. Let's pull them
both up. So now, you. >> You can
see the green trace as the red x
of doom. Which means a security
harmful crash. Signal 11.
Generally bad. >> Well done. We
have your name. If you can tell
us your name that validate that
you were the person. And this is
yours the first to solve our
capture flag. What was your
name, sir? Funny thing that.
Trust and verify. >> If you can
come up and tell us to the table
quietly what you signed in as.
>> You can also tell us
password. There's a root
password [ inaudible ]. You want
to scroll through what happened
in the case here. >> So we've
got, in this case whoever was
able to crash it, you can see
outputs, we already know. We see
output. Someone viewed the
message board. But in this case
there's extra data. Leak out
extra data. If your subject line
is exactly 30 characters long.
So [ inaudible ] read out the
data actually send way too much
data and causes a segmentation
fault. >> It's a memory over
read. >> So let's look at patch
to that. Patch it for us. We
want to see what it looks like
when it's fixed. >> Before we
were using the same software to
compare different inputs. We
will put the same input into
different software. So the crash
generated by the crowd going
into patch and unpatched. So you
can tell immediately which one
is patch. Huge memory leak
towards the horizon. The patch
one ends normally. We should see
the moment that they diverge. >>
We can see right in here. Let's
look at a different one.
Different patch for a different
program. >> So notice that was a
very tight patch. Whoever wrote
it knew exactly where to test
for. They didn't change the
program, there wasn't whole
bunch of testing. This is
software that is not connected
to the internet. This is a
completely different program. >>
If you look at the shape of
these, clearly it's doing
different stuff. There's a flat
initialization and broader peaks
and valley. But they look
similar. Two runs on the same
program. One was able to trigger
a program. >> The blue as the
doom. See what we can learn
about this patch. Anyone see a
patch? >> Remember, a far jump
is a far jump. In the very
beginning is jumping as far away
as it can and it's calling
allocate and jumping back and
that to me looks like a classic
jump patch. Inserted by the
patch author. I'm doing
something allocate to protect
the program. Never this fast,
you will see at ctf. And here
end. >> Nice easy. Something
happen at the beginning.
Allocation maybe it's tracking
where memory is legitimately
allocate. Instead of crashing,
it exits cleanly. With an error
code. >> Stack cookie detection.
It looks like detection jump
away hand code. We only have one
more surprise for you about this
patch and how it was made. >>
This one was written by a
computer. This is a binary from
the qualification round that we
recently finished and this is
software patching software with
no human interaction. Completely
autonomous. This software was
unknown to the system generated
this patch. No access to source
code or documentation. It did
this all automatically. It
decide to submit this to us as
best case approach. And healed
vulnerability. And it looks like
what it is incredible tight
patch and a flawed that it
probably know about. >> In that
case, it was a tight patch at
the moment of the flaw. So it
was able to detect that exactly
there. It went go ahead clean
and exited it. Readable error.
Those about 200 thousand. Third
one is 9 hundred thousand. So
right off the bat it's a much
longer execution but it's still
the same program. If you were to
pull this on ida and step
through gdb it would have
different functionality. If you
look at it here, no system call,
no other interaction until the
very end. Much like the others.
So it's the same shape, same
gram and in this case different
program doing the same thing.
It's got the same input. So you
get the overrule shape that
looks the same but it's got a
lot more to it. And we can see
what it's doing. Hide underneath
it. I call this the railroad
track. If I click along any of
the spot blue plain, it's where
it was in that binary. If it's
in the same spot, it's in the
same spot. This bottom rail,
line here, it was doing the same
little check over and over
again. We can hone in and look
at the assembly. We don't need
to because we know this program
was successfully defend this
particularly flawed. Instead of
patch at that flaw, it was
checking everywhere. It was a
longer long. But it was able to
do that not knowing exactly
where the flaw is. I like to
look at the traces and digging
through the qualifier. And they
almost have a personality.
Because you see different
approaches the system will take.
Here anybody could see it you
could tell right away where the
changes are and what's
happening. >> In that third
trace machine grab with
uncertainty. Jordan when his
team can actually pull out
difference in approaches. It's
another thing to say I know
which system built that. So
which system built this and more
important who built this system.
Because we started this whole
thing with about a hundred team
registered around the world and
we qualified the top 7 scoring
team and they are mostly in the
audience with us today. So I
want to take a moment to
appreciate that. We say can
machine do this stuff in
adversary format. We have
researcher say maybe it's
possible and maybe we can do it.
So I want to talk about the
teams. You can see the
submission of their system.
Capture the flag operating
system available online. I want
those teams to come up right now
and join us in front of the
stage. If you are a finalist and
you are here today, come on up,
guys. [ applause ] >> So when I
call you out please step forward
and let everyone give you a
round of applause. Our finalist
in no particular order. Team
partnership between university
of Virginia team tech x. [
applause ] From the home of
university in pa. This is a team
with deep ctf for all secure.
Come on up [ applause ] Team
code gazitsu. This was a much
bigger team than was able to
make it. An international team.
Whole bunch of folks calling in
from skype. [ applause ] Team
dissect. If you play on the ctf
circuit. Michael Cotraous. [
applause ] From the university
of Idaho, led by Dr. Jim Elsfas.
[ applause ] Team shellfish. You
know shellfish working out of
the lab of University of
California Santa Barbara led by
Yuns. [ applause ] And team deep
red lead by Dr. Tim. Say hi,
everybody [applause] These are
our seven finalists and I want
to close with a few parting
thoughts. First, why are we
doing this? Teach computers to
play this game. Because it's not
just a game it's one of the
toughest applied reverse
engineering on earth. And these
are the hard skills of computer
[ inaudible ]. Hard skill right
now where machines have no
chance. I'm from darpa. That
means we try to invent the
technology of the future and
it's really easy to understand
why we need something that can
react to a new threat and attack
in realtime. There was time to
deny before. These are the
pioneers who signed up to do it.
I want to send out a big thank
you for Defcon conference.
Everyone on the team. Who let us
put this big logistic into the
move and hotel. Thank you very
much. I want to close with the
most important word I've said
all day. It's not cyber and not
darpa. This talk is Thursday
august 6. Machine play capture
the flag before Defcon. That
means if you want to come back
this room when we triple the
size put in 15 of these racks
and play capture the flag today
you need to show up one day
early. I want like to close with
a round of applause for these
teams. By this game on that
machine live in this room next
year the machine play capture
the flag. Thank you very much. [
applause ] >> And I think we
close this up with time for
questions. >> If you have
questions, come down here. I
have the mic. >> That guy has
the question's mic. >> There's
one important question. Looks
interesting. >> So what do you
guys think about inviting the
winning team to play against
humans Defcon capture the flag
near? >> I'm going to repeat the
question. So I believe we have
the of the legitimate business
that run capture the flag with
us and he asked if machines will
play human next year. I can't
ask these teams to do that. Well
you can. Show of hands would you
guys do that if we set it up?
[applause] Okay. If you guys
will play, we will keep the
computers on. If you will
basically tell everybody that it
is a basically a fair and open
contest for machine and people,
good? Okay. We've got a deal [
applause ] And for the record I
think it's probably early. But
if you guys will make the game
open to the machine entering and
team wants to play, we will keep
the machines on absolutely. >>
Awesome. >> Great presentation.
So just a couple observations
and two questions. I want to
start off with [ inaudible ] a
lot of discussion domain way.
Checker poker ctf and throwing a
lot of power at this so is it
safe to say this is mainly brute
force type of problem or Denis
at deep mind you can create game
ai in naturalistic from
neuroscience or is that just
science fiction. Sorry. A lot of
rants there. >> But I think the
question is basically like how
feasible is this and what
category of problem does it fit
into. The world top programmer's
mind are literally standing
right in front of me. You should
ask them. We don't know what
kind of problem, we will find
out. Is that it? >> That was a
cool visualization of the
tracing. What did you use to
trace instruction to do that?
Emulator. >> How the tracer were
generated in this case? We got a
patch qmu. You can substitute
that with anything. You can use
anything that does execution
system tracing. >> To make your
visual software available after
the contest. >> So far
everything that's part of the
infrastructure from the
operating system we built for
ctf up to all the challenges are
going to be released to the
public and also releasing
everything that happens in the
event. We have open track for
almost everything we are
building but that software, I'll
let him answer that question. >>
That's joint work with another
company that generates that bits
of it. We are still working on
that. Mainly because it's an
early prototype. We wouldn't
rule it out. That's for sure. >>
Thanks. >> Thank you, guys.
Let's give them another big
round of applause. [ applause ].