[Music]
hey hello everyone thanks for hanging
out to the nearly the last talk you know
Duncan is officially always the last
Kirk on talk but thank you praying it
out to the nearly last one ever known a
good gherkin it's a good event yeah whoo
Chris and Jamie and the whole team they
run a fantastic event so I hope you
enjoyed it thank you guys for the
volunteers I really appreciate it this
is excellent
so this talk is bounty hunters my name
is Wolfgang Gorelick and occasionally my
clicker works like that good
I'm with CBI I run a strategic security
programs practice within CBI that's like
data and identity and governance and
pretty much nothing we're gonna talk
about in this talk but that's who I am
I'm also on YouTube and I talk with my
hands way too much which annoys the hell
out of the redditors by the way you want
to read it yeah everyone on reddit who
sees my videos like you gotta put your
hands on the wheel you got a I'm gonna
call your insurance I'm like you should
call my insurance that would be great by
the way it's progressive if anyone on
from reddit is watching my policy number
oh yeah so Moss on YouTube in undoable
thanks when I was a kid I used to wake
up at 4 o'clock in the morning I woke up
at 4 o'clock in the morning for the
spaghetti westerns so if you're about my
age you may remember those four o'clock
channel 20 we only had three four
channels those terrible's a little gray
little grainy but cleanses will come on
and it was fantastic and about six
o'clock I was in my glory and I'm like I
want to be that guy I want to be the
gunslinger I want to be the bounty
hunter I want to be the guy riding into
town and shooting up the bad guy and
putting or my sandal and dragging him
home for coin currency and swag and I
did not understand what's called
spaghetti western so about 640 thousand
week up my parents go can't get
spaghetti like you are nuts kid but but
that mentality and that pitcher stuck
with me forever so when bug bounties
became a thing I got really really
excited about I love the concept so for
those you guys
new to this concept it works something
like this there's no settle there's no
gunslinger
there's no spaghetti why is there never
any spaghetti but but what happens is
all the great things about hacking that
we know and love we get compensated for
and there's a legal and ethical way to
do it
companies build software as we all know
software has bugs lots and lots of bugs
companies put out a bug bounty program
it's a legal framework people sign up
for that bug bounty program or sign up
through a number of organizations like
CAC 1 and and bugcrowd to come in and
participate your hack stuff you do stuff
you find vulnerabilities and the
companies pay you fantastic and you do
it all for coins swag and glory this
talk is about some of the things that
bug bounties bounty hunters find it's
about some of the common ways they break
in series of stories that highlights
that thing that will give a quick
framework of how to address these
vulnerabilities and some things that you
can do at home to play along some of the
things other about bug bounties some
kind of misconceptions one of the things
is their column we can't do a bounty
because the bounty hunters can hack
anything and companies can oftentimes
get very concerned about that so if
you're a company looking to do a bug
bounty program I highly encourage you to
check it out there are legal
restrictions around it hackers you can
usually trust them usually kind of
people are chuckling in the background
especially the guy with the pinata but
you can usually I mean within reason
also to the other concept that our
organizations learned about is when
you're doing these bug bounties kind
actually trust the company will they pay
me fairly will they not sue me they're -
for the most part as these bug bounty
programs are matured we can trust them
they can trust us we can all come
together which is good which is good
it's not a free-for-all it's not
anything goes so let's look at let's
look at some examples of what happens
with bounty hunters one of the first
ones I want to talk about is aqua tone
and uber first I have anyone run aqua
tone anyone play with it couple folks
most coolers I go you should google it
you should check it out
it's awesome the one someone $4,500 I'll
get to that in a minute really cool tool
so uber puts together a bug bounty and
they run this bounty program for quite
some time very very successful what
low-hanging fruit was found with this
program lots of folks came in and they
broke the app and they broke the back
end website and they broke all sorts of
things for me this screenshot comes from
one of the bounties where they were
looking for domains that could be
hijacked so what aqua tone does is it
will run across domains and they'll find
demands that you can go ahead and take
over right so you run this tool aqua
tone takeover pretty simple face report
you run that tool you're running against
your target thank you for that
politicians and all right you're on your
target and it will come back with a
bunch of lists of domains that you could
potentially take over
specifically with uber they were on
cloud front so it runs across call front
they find a bunch of domains that you
can take over you execute that domain
take over you use AWS you point it to
that subdomain now you know
such-and-such dot over comm belongs to
you and you can profit this particular
researcher set up some things through
beef and tracked a whole bunch of who
was going through it came up with a
really nice report and profited $4,500
awesome run a tool win 5k what's wrong
with that
one of the things very interesting about
bug bounty programs and about the whole
like a script kiddie mentality in
general is there are so many ways that
we make mistakes right it's the whole
like if Shakespeare or if you gave a
million monkeys typewriters they'd all
talk about Shakespeare we all heard that
amount times if you give a million
monkeys a bunch of code they'll produce
a million vulnerabilities everywhere and
they'll publish it up on Amazon or you
can take over the domain it's okay
because that's we also open and if you
want an additional data it's there it's
probably credit cards you're good right
there's so many things out there so much
low-hanging fruit and that's one of the
things I think bug bounty programs are
very good at open it up everyone coming
in hack or on your favorite tool sharpen
those skills and find those things you
don't wanna pay pentester for that right
if you pay a pen tester to fully test
out all your
your domains pentester rates weeks upon
weeks upon weeks that's expensive
so for a company it's pretty good as
well you get some of the best of both
worlds so this is one against uber with
a very similar situation happened with
Azure and Starbucks so Starbucks is
running a a bug bounty program as well
one of the the domains that was open was
SBC gateway us that Starbucks com that
was under Shore so on Azure they found
that they created they opened up the
Azure page they took that through it end
that's not my domain fired it up and now
all the kodos going to that goes to the
the attacker now of course SVC gateways
us is probably something that people are
not like typing in a browser and purpose
but that can then be from an attacker
perspective if you're not using a pro
bounty a way to get on to future attacks
right especially if they're white
Lessing Starbucks comm and you want to
do a phishing attack and now you own
that subdomain a lot of cool little
things you can do for that so after the
night EWS happens is your this is one of
the common attack vectors we're seeing
with cloud that a lot of folks never
really thought about when I was on Prem
when you owned your own DMS and things
were much more tidy so some of the
defenses against that obviously domain
and subdomain inventory knowing what you
have in DNS which should be simple right
we should know what we haven't DNS but
with things like
DevOps and things like wrap it in
deployment everything else and everyone
can create their own DNS it's very
common that we end up with date gateway
SVC gay tweet at us or app tier one or
you know pry wolf's testing it's okay I
promised Microsoft that things like that
right a million-in-one domains are being
crated all the time so they're out there
and there is the catch the other thing
to do is not only have a good inventory
but routinely check and then clean up
those unused domains if you have a
software development lifecycle where
you're laying the developers create
their domains at the end of that process
we want to have a thing that stops
cleats and deletes those domains right
so just some good software
on the inventory another one another
bounty that thought was pretty
interesting was from a while back was
from nest nest even still around
that's still a thing you laughing at me
like it's do hmm yeah they're still
nesting okay good yeah that was what I
thought was a bee Cyril don't know
everyone's making their own thing but
hey people still buy it who knows I mean
you know if Elon Musk Tesla that people
would be a buying Tesla spray that make
sense well said sir all right so what
Tesla had was Nast in the early days had
a certified reseller program they're
trying to build the reseller base anyone
could sign up for and become a reseller
and so they built this website where the
resellers could come in and upload their
certification right I certify that I am
a reseller here's my certificate and
that's awesome that's great so now they
prove that the reseller they do the
resourcing that's good I'm that there
was no validation in the upload whatever
it's supposed to be PDF but there's no
check as to whether was and not only
that when it uploaded it went to a
folder on an apache site that also had
browse and execute permission set on it
so as you might imagine you upload a PHP
shell BAM your root on that register
reseller site this was one that was
found during during one of the google
blasted out bug bounties and I thought
that was pretty cool because again how
many different websites do you have out
there and if you think about a certified
reseller program you're a company you're
like I'm gonna start a reseller program
are you gonna have them come in pen test
that probably not you know guy money for
it right well pen test our financial
services app that's a little pen test
but that reseller have been with that
shell along with a phishing campaign or
along with you know blast out email
the resellers come back in and then used
as a pivot all sorts of cool things
could happen and of course PHP shells
are on the rise this chart is a little
out of date I use this chart I pull this
chart when no equifax happened so it
shows the level of web shells bouncing
up up into the Equifax attacks something
about 90% of all shells today are PHP so
PHP web shells getting uploaded and why
that Equifax thing was kind of coolest
you guys know how many different shells
were uploaded and the Equifax attack you
don't want to guess one attacker two
attacker you in the mass shootings right
on so with Equifax because that
vulnerability happened in struts and
everyone jumped on it like a
million-in-one monkeys right a million
and one attackers the common curious the
criminal to be sure we're scanning for
that struts vulnerability within Equifax
when I got hit it didn't only get hit
once and breached that's the story that
I've inherited right oh god for reached
and they put in a shell and everything
was bad it got hit over 40 separate
times when mandiant came in they found
over 40 different shells uploaded
because that vulnerability and they had
command line monitoring too on that so
some of these like super attackers that
went in and found the struts
vulnerability ran cool things like Who
am I and what and their IP address was
never seen again
you know that some was like I'm good to
everyone I did this and hope no one
notices right you don't have said so
what if Equifax had done a bug bounty
program right what if they had invited
everyone in their brother to attack
these sort of things and that Who am I
kiddin five grand a pad in the back
right and then used something that might
not come to her account of course that
would be much better I would argue that
waiting for everyone and their brother
to try it once the Metasploit hits and
in loading up PHP shells so some
defenses again
this you know arbitrary file includes
right what do you onto most people
blacklist don't allow PHP don't know exe
if the windows yada yada yada many
people also whitelist if you're only
looking for PDF just look for the PDF
extension this is kind of like the
old-school way of doing it a lot of the
new frameworks and languages will
actually do file type detection which is
fantastic I'll read the first few bites
of a file just like an OS would and say
yeah nice try
shell dot PHP dot jpg I know what you
really are
right it will actually look at and
detect and prevent it and of course
along with that if you somehow bypass
that if you bypass that upload then have
some restrictions on your folder so that
when files go into them they're not
executable right away so read only where
they need to be or how keep you can
prevent from read write run all together
all right next one I thought was kind of
cool this one has to do back with Google
Google is like the number one consumer I
found as I bring a lot of stories about
bug bounties and Google Calendar got
beat on quite a bit one of the things I
thought about was neat about was the way
the command actually ran so most people
use Google Calendar yeah I use it all
the time okay with my progressive
insurance great now I'm going to be in
for trouble you ever get those bugs
where it emails you like the same
calendar right like three four times
like what the hell is this I'll delete
it I'll mess up you know clearly they're
having a glitch so maybe I email you
wants twice again again again again and
eventually they're like what the hell
I'm gonna just delete this that common
pattern especially the early days of
Google Calendar would glitched a lot you
would see that three four times so just
keep yelling you're like I don't know
what I did wrong this counter we're
gonna delete it and recreate it this
particular bug was found that they could
embed access ass through the API to the
application API interface into Google
counter
you open up with Google you say okay
certain applications go into my calendar
like if this than that and on that
interface there
ability to have actions on deleting
calendar invites so you use delete to
insert some JavaScript classic
cross-site scripting over JSON so you
can search your JavaScript into the
calendar right now the calendar invite
will only trigger if it gets deleted so
now you got to convince the user to
delete it so again you keep sending it
to them again and again and again so
they eventually delete it usually the
researchers found it took about five
times I think that's kind of interesting
it tells us something about human nature
we will pay attention to Google's BS
bypass no fun fact but so you send it
again and again and again and eventually
the person's like this is ridiculous I
show to delete this invite the minute
they do that that action execute that
JavaScript that's been embedded in it by
the API hook the cross-site action runs
and now they get a little JavaScript
popup message whatever it is they click
it of course make that all go away and
when they do that javascript is
executing on their box kind of an
interesting kind of cool kind of clever
attack something I would have never
thought to try and that's another thing
I like with bug bounty programs is
because you have a little more time to
think these things through a little more
time to play a little bit more time to
try different scenarios you can come up
with weird things like what happens if I
embed you know something on a calendar
invite what happens if I screw up with
this particular executable or upload
this file with pen tests and you talk to
most pen testers though give them a cup
of drinks first I should add that always
get pen testers drinks come bearing
offerings and say hey how frustrated you
get when you have a tight scope drink
zero they'll go oh that's no problem
because we can always provide the best
possible value within the time
constraints drink three or four man I
could have got it and that was right
there and I'm like the reports due in an
hour and I call just five more minutes
but I don't write the report and I
didn't know you know drink six yeah
they're taking you to another bar and it
gets a real exciting sex
my point is pen tests are limited in
time engagements right so therefore the
results are always limited in time
whereas
bug bounties more people more time more
flexibility you can put a lot more time
your leisure to come up some really cool
really slick attacks and a lot of
attacks to see from bug bounties are
much more exciting because of that the
embedded calendar truck is just one
really good example and I love that
because I think that gets back to the
true nature of hacking when a lot of us
get into it we're doing it you know
before school five minutes here 10
minutes they are running out the door
jotting down on a piece of paper all
I'll try this one get home and having a
more or free farm with no restrictions
with no restraints approach to it allows
for a lot more creativity I think in
some of our attacks really really
interesting dynamic the other thing I
want to point out is JavaScript right
when I say JavaScript executes in the
box most of you were like yeah okay so
what right we did my sec right my sexy
user group few people in here with my
sec yeah all right woohoo my sec so my
favorite cross-site scripting talk of
all time was at my second I was sitting
in there I was sitting there with a
couple of my friends one of them ran the
data center that we were in not
necessarily the most technical guy but
very astute very smart and another guy
was an Operations guy he kind of knew
how things work together an IT side and
that Roy a hacker and the whole room a
bunch of hackers and this was a my
second meeting where they're explaining
cross-site scripting and the speaker was
Jos little and Josh littles sitting
there he's got a player for the dramatic
who's like here's the job JavaScript
here's what goes in here's my input
BAM I've got you and it pops up a little
you know message haha I got you and he
goes all right now I'm gonna put in this
control and puts in this other control
does is a little messy pile up haha I
got you business again and again and by
the time it's like six seven times every
time it's haha I got your yeah you got
us yeah we got us there's Roy again
saying we're all cheering we're all
jumping down except for the CIO because
he's very reserved he's looking at psych
with us but we're I'm sure we're all
getting into this again we got us yeah
and there's this bypass snap bypassing
this control they went through like six
seven different ways of cross-site
scripting go to the hospital or a wasp
page Atlas saw them all out you can
follow that in your own but he goes
through all this off and the
last one we're like and there's no
dialog box the fun's over it's okay I
guess it didn't work so let me log into
my banking let me log into this let me
log into that well we neglect it to
realize until about two minutes into
this description was that he had
actually instead of popping up a
JavaScript hey I got you he had ran the
Metasploit key logger so he was doing
JavaScript key logging he's like anyone
else want to log in and by the time he
like flips and showed a granny didn't
log into his real bank account but by
the time he flipped everyone in the room
got silent and the little director guy
that's a l'eau director by the director
guys looking at me to see how I was
looking at me the data center guys
looking mean he's mouths to be like why
did you guys invite this guy I think
it's okay just login to everything when
you get back to your desk it's all fine
only if you see the box this is how I
got you to be ready to worry but what we
think that right we think on across that
scripting yadda yadda but with with the
tunneling that's in place now with the
key logging that's in place now with a
lot of new Metasploit payload process
scripting is incredibly incredibly
weaponized so just keep that keep that
in the back your mind some defenses for
this obviously escape all inputs your
HTML your JavaScript your attributes
website folks have gotten pretty good at
this UI folks have gotten pretty good at
this awesome where we're seeing most of
the bug bounties also - where we have
most of fun we're doing Ben tests is on
the api's because there's a mentality
with developers that it's hard to build
it's probably hard to break there's also
mentality with the hackers that if it's
easy to break it's probably easy to fix
therein lies a tale of two completely
different cities and that's where most
of the fun comes in whenever you're
reporting any sort of result but
building api's most people don't browse
api's right most people don't use api's
most people are not typing in service
gateway dot amazon.com or Starbucks they
come
most people using the front-end webs and
therefore a lot of the times when the
developers creating an API they're not
necessarily putting in those same types
of restrictions that they would have put
in heretofore if someone's using a rig
Rand pipe because like all input is a
text box or an input is a file upload
like a cover earlier a lot of people are
not going oh ed input is every single
time I send JSON every single time I
make a request and sedges of data that
some input you better be escaping that
we forget that we forget that and when
we forget that new bounties open up new
bugs open up the world changes so one
escaping all inputs and everything is an
input these days number two of course is
using platform specific exercise
protections so mentioned earlier there's
a whole bunch on Oh wasp depending
whatever your platform you are go to
that documentation pull it down there's
a lot of new frameworks and modules in
place that will add it to it which is
awesome you just got to remember to wear
it up and again why I think the front
end exercise is somewhat on the declines
because of the front end now of days
with a lot of the modern UI's we'll put
that in there for your IDs rather we'll
put that code in there pretty cool
so cross-site scripting and messing
around Google another one I want to talk
about is is cryptocurrency so it's a
blockchain right I've mentioned
blockchain in abstract I'll get called
to speak blockchain is fantastic I did a
talk you guys can catch it on iron geeks
page if you want to along with this one
when it goes live I did a talk was ax
Eric in on cryptocurrency and classic
cons what's kind of interesting about
cryptocurrency today has a lot of these
security around cryptocurrencies in the
blockchain is all around the hard core
mathematics it's all around what happens
if there's a split or you know what
happens when we hit quantum computing
and they can break crypto and now we've
got qubits that are you know it's all
about these sort of like very advanced
very sophisticated attacks that are now
made possible by this very advanced
sophisticated technology what I would
argue you guys think about be it
blockchain or cloud or whatever the next
crazy thing is next
right AI with everyone wants to talk
about a hey now is whenever this is new
technology everyone's concerned about
the zoo threats but before they get to
the new threats whether as every
criminal and their brother gonna try
what is every bounty hunter and their
bro they're gonna try they're gonna try
the things that work they're gonna try
the same old classic ons they've
happened again and again and again by
that I mean how if you look at
cryptocurrency well they're all worried
about all the sort of stuff what people
are doing is phishing scams and stealing
your keys and pump-and-dump
once the money's go to those things
right especially they pump it up in
pyramid schemes you're like oh my
goodness this is like a hundred year old
200 year old scam alive and well crypto
currency I had a one guy great guy great
friend of mine was like hey can you give
me some advice make sure I want to do
mine that sounds great
he's like so I I'm told I have to buy a
mining contract I'm like this is our
land grab on like GPUs now but there's
like a whole like scam running around
where they're selling mining contract
cool pieces of payment says you are now
eligible to mine Bitcoin they're like oh
that's awesome I could mined Bitcoin
classic handsome so so one of the things
that happened was - - is a digital
currency - has a wallet - wallet is
called copay and - got on board and did
a bug bounty and everyone piled on top
of - and broke in a million one ways one
of the ways they broke it which I
thought was kind of interesting was they
found that when you install a wallet it
will write the private keys of that
wallet to the log and clear text for
those of you not laughing if you have
the key you are able to steal every
single last penny or Bitcoin or Satoshi
or whatever a cool term you want to use
from that wallet because it's public
private key encryption if you have that
private key you have the wallet so the
the bug bounty was
all around finding that flaw right there
was in debug mode that was problem
number one debug mode would cause all
the keys to get rid of the log and the
log had then the clear tax version of it
one of the things that I thought was
pretty interesting about this is a
reminds me of Twitter I don't remember
the whole like freaked out about Twitter
because all the usernames were and not
all the usernames sorry Twitter colleges
a fraction of the usernames and
passwords which have not yet been
disclosed
we're written to the logs and clear tax
when people were logging in oops and
then of course they had to disclose that
that had happened in a whole bunch of
people were giving notices and we all
had to change our passwords and everyone
said oh no no you guys are terrible we
all pout on Twitter for a while hmm what
yes yes wall of cash Walla fail all
right
so that's one thing that's interesting
is we've seen repeatedly big big
companies fall prey to this concept of
if it's in our logs it's fine nothing
goes censored or logs or logs are only
for metadata and some other attributes
and there's a mistake like debug mode
gets turned on or Twitter gets modified
and it writes all this stuff to the logs
and now it's a clear tax and now we got
a breach similar thing has started
happening with same concept different
implementation with big data
implementations right oh we've got up
we'll just throw everything elk all
right we've got a data Lake it's fine
the data Lake is all pristine I was
talking to someone in there we're gonna
implement a data like I'm like that's
great what even first security oh we
don't need to secure it why not well
because it's only gonna have like it's
it's I think it's anonymized you you
think it's anonymized yeah I'm pretty
sure I mean it's just usernames right
that doesn't and people's names and
addresses and maybe an ID oh my god okay
it's anonymous and who can get it well
everyone because we're doing analytics
okay okay what is your company so don't
buy for you but that's that's just human
nature right we think of the log is
something that's not necessarily needs
to be protected
we forget that anything can be written
to the log the other thing that's
interesting to me about this is
- immediately said no this in our
problem because we're a fork of Bitcoin
Waller
bitcoins copay was where the original
bug happened when - both their copay app
they Forks bitcoins copay app and went
great we'll start with this and we'll
change the logo it butts - I love open
source don't get me wrong fork the heck
out of everything right but perhaps when
you do fork check the code your forked
because once it's now fork it's now your
code even if you didn't write it even if
it's not yours and when the bug bounty
has come you know and the bounty hunters
come banging on the door or god forbid
the criminals they're not gonna go I got
you oh wait sorry that was pre fork
nevermind my bad
the pen testers will you can scope the
hell out of that a pen test right if you
find anything that's pre fork that is
out of scope somewhere somehow in
gherkin today there's a pen tester drink
three will tell you what that horror
story but my point remains my point
remains that when you fork or merge code
you're still altering responsible for
that code which can be very very
difficult because even the best
intentioned F shops focus most their
controls on the code they wrote even
though it's predicated on all those
other code so defenses one check the
original source code two crazy idea make
sure you're not in debug mode especially
in published public applications that
would be a great thing to add to a CI CD
pipeline when you're going through your
checks have the Jenkins job
turn off debug mode before you publish
it up to the Apple Store where we can
all download it and then protect those
logs right when it comes to logs assume
assume please that at some point at some
time for some reason there's someone who
does something and you want to smack
them on the head and they're right a
bunch of data that they shouldn't
passwords private keys username so I
don't know that stuff it's gonna get R
into your logs so please guys protect
those logs right protect those logs as
if it has sense of data because God
knows it's going to get that sense
all right couple more hmm couple four
unkept passwords this was kind of fun
Tavis or Maundy is fantastic you should
follow everything he does cuz he always
cracks me up Microsoft Windows 10 right
Microsoft edge and now whoever thought
and with Windows 10 new features come in
and they go out and things pop up and
they pop out and up pops earlier this
year a password manager which is great
who likes remembering a million
passwords or writing them in a book or
putting in a text file no one does
so we all should have password managers
on LastPass KeePass whatever it is
awesome awesome stuff so pops up in
Windows 10 there was a game I actually
don't think anyone really noticed no
noses will go that route but Tavis did
tab is what oh wow this is cool and
started playing around with them the
main applications of Apple's password
keeper the main application absolutely
fine great app life is good
kudos to those guys they included a
password or a browser plug-in the
browser plugin had a door to that main
application of course your new browser
you want to put password makes sense the
browser plug-in was full of holes
the browser plug-in ran in the context
we could get all the passwords because
of course password keeper browser plugin
had the ability to do code execution
within it and take over it so what that
meant is if Tavis could get you to
browse to his website and you had
password keeper and you were using edge
one why use using edge cromoz comes a
thing um if you were using edge or a
Microsoft browser and you browse to
tamás's website he could see that
plug-in inject it grabbed out all your
passwords all your passwords say save it
and do a log file which I'm sure he's
encrypted sure and and and that was
pretty cool so he found that he reported
it
it was another bug bounty that ended up
eventually getting paid out one of the
interesting things about this thing
though is remember early on some of the
things that always happens is company
are fair to hackers hackers are pretty
companies this was one of the cases
where things went a little bit off the
rails for whatever reason the Whalers
reported in the time I was reported had
violated that bug bounty contract if you
guys are gonna do bug bounties please
read the contracts very carefully
please follow them I'd urge you to abide
by those rules are usually some pretty
simple rules but Tavis is Tavis and
Tavis is great in Tavistock dollars
Technica and ARS technica published an
article before Microsoft could remediate
and ended up being a lawsuit they
actually sued the reporter and they sued
have us out of it I don't know the
current state of the lawsuit I couldn't
find it so I'm assuming it's in the goal
whatever at this point half anyone knows
report is off the hook yeah good he's
free and clear
good yeah it's not so much that's good
to know
all right but this this brings up a
couple good points one is please be
careful when you're doing this about how
its disclosed and you're following the
process two is of course whenever you're
releasing features in an agile way such
as Microsoft is bundling password keeper
you're increasing your footprint and the
agile world is fantastic for development
but that also keeps all the security
people up at night because that means
every single day there's a new thing
that can some and beyond a million one
desktops and open up everyone to
vulnerabilities and that's a scary thing
it's a scary thing there's very few
controls were on that so I like the fact
that bounty hunters are attacking that
space it's exciting to me it's exciting
to me that they're jumping in to finding
these things because better than then at
beyond with the Windows desktop for a
year or two and and then who knows what
bad guys have been doing but why steal
passwords when you can just bypass the
authentication all together like what
happened I github so github runs Ruby on
Rails this is another bug bounty earlier
this year Ruby on Rails has a session
secret by default that session secret is
a static string that should have as many
gasps from the public as the private
keys if it exposed because that means if
you know that a static string you can do
all sorts of bad things you can
cookies you can impersonate users you
can even use it in the case of get hubs
Management Council to do remote code
execution some really bad stuff came out
of that when this was found and it made
the news it reminded me of something did
anyone catch how to implement crypto
poorly Shaun Cassidy a couple years ago
it's that link you guys should see it it
was at gherkin two years ago and he
actually walked through several
applications that had this exact same
problem what he was looking at how to
implement crypto poorly but specifically
for like a watt framework shared sees
that type of authentication like the
github was talking about and he he does
a lot of these application pen testing a
lot of the application analysis and he
looked at something like a hundred
different apps and was finding all the
common bad ways people do them and of
course static shared secret is one of
them so talk with see the key defenses
here are hey don't use static secrets
hey JC things up use the randomized
features and what have you don't roll
your own ah back to what Sean Cassie was
talking about agar con a lot is hard and
it sucks and there's a lot of code and
you're like man I just want to like wire
up a user in and and whatnot
but trying to roll your own even though
it seems simpler is a real real quick
way to open yourself up to a whole bunch
of vulnerability so either don't roll
your own or have a really well funded
bug bounty program that's good
another thing is very similar to the
concept about forking mind the code you
wrote in on this was not necessarily a
github bug this was actually a bug
inherent and rails this is how Ruby on
Rails is set up it's how it works they
built the enterprise console on it they
inherited that vulnerability much much
goes into building apps these days right
and no one builds full stack you don't
even builds partial stack usually we're
building today the integration glue that
brings all these apps together that's
where our secret sauce why that's
important is just
all the rest of cold we run in on the
frameworks the webserver the servlets
other libraries we pull into there's a
particular type of process called
composition analysis that's well worth
talking your developers about what
composition analysis will do is just
like static now so we'll look at your
code and say ah look there's a bomb
what composition analysis will do is it
will look at the code within your code
the libraries you run on the frameworks
you run on those sort of things and look
for common vulnerabilities and those and
report them back to you very very cool
you can run it off your get take seconds
to do because it's looking at a back-end
library thinking like nasus for your
code right software composition alright
so with that let's talk a little bit
about a framework for preventing some of
these things we heard about and this
talk and then give you a couple of
things and we'll probably finish a few
minutes early so framework one protect
your authentication protect your museums
and passwords obviously we need to
protect those also make sure that in
addition do proper hashing that you're
not writing about the logs that you're
not relying on static secrets that
there's not easy ways to bypass these
things protect your authentication great
thing to pen test on as well stop
injection stop injection attacks or
cross-site scripting anyway can embed
code in number one way that's being done
today is not the old school here's an
input form I've typed in my stuff to go
the number one way it's being done today
is with the api's because that takes a
higher level of knowledge to go ahead
and test and implement and because
developers are not yet thinking about it
so stop the injection any inputs
sanitize the hell out of them watch your
foul uploads obviously watch your file
uploads every single time so people
aren't uploading shells on you clean
your code clean your code that means
static analysis if you can scanning it
for vulnerabilities dynamic analysis if
you can watching it in the real real
world and see what people are doing to
it that means composition analysis and
it's not only the cotija rope but the
code you beg to borrowed you steal the
code you copied off of
stackoverflow all that code now it's in
your codebase is your stream it's your
world and then secure the locks like
we're talking about secure them like
they have sensitive data and now we got
all that going make sure that someone
doesn't go ahead and take over your
domain and violate at all because they
put up a nice pretty dialog box and gab
your username and password didn't
probably write it to a log file so
pretty simple framework right a lot of
stuff we're talking about really bows
down to some of the fundamentals of
software development security why we're
not finding these things without bug
bounties I believe is because we time
box pen tests are so tight like I
already talked about so I think you need
a pen test too time box to be tight to
find the things that matter and then a
bug bounty after that to be open to
allow for creative solutions to allow
for people that have playing time to
bang on it to get people involved and
look at it new and different ways to
attack it in ways that pen testers won't
usually think about visa vie the the
five Google Calendar invites and really
build on that program that way so
there's a framework another frame of
course is Austin you can't beat that but
everyone's like yeah I'll stop down fine
we'll do that I think what's interesting
is frameworks like that cost out ten or
any of these get you so much that you
start to get to a point where developers
kind of glaze over yes I'll stop then
yes I will follow the CIS okay got it
and that's the other thing is
fundamentally whether it's OS top ten or
the framework I mentioned earlier we
have to understand and recognize and
defend against our or defend our
applications against the very fact that
now whatever lessons we say these things
so we gotta have some understanding that
they're not gonna pay attention they're
gonna do their own thing anyways right
so how can we encourage folks to come in
and help us out all right
wrapping up wrapping up the Bounty
Hunter section three takeaways hey
anyone who's writing code today we live
with a price in our head we live in our
price or head either from the criminals
because that's where the money's at
right why do you why did they break our
apps well because you can monetize the
hell out of that today if you get the
right data or you can get the right CPU
access and alternatively you live with
the price in your head if you're doing a
bug bounty which I'd rather have that
person a little bit less money and they
tell you about it life is good
some of the best things to do for
developers if you are developing your
own applications is to implement a
secure SDLC which can put in place the
right things as the apps are being spun
up and spun down simple things like give
me a domain and when I'm done with that
domain make that domain go away so no
one can hijack you if you're a company
consider doing a bug bounty I loved
boobers quote though over got so beat up
they actually a statement don't extort
us I think that's correct thank you for
joining our bug buddy please no more I
can't take it there is a lot of guidance
in and resources out there from major
companies that do bug bounty as a
service versus many folks who built
programs or and frameworks for spinning
up your own bug money I really think
it's a great idea after of course a pen
tester should be an ST OC should be a
pen test but then opening it up I think
is a fantastic idea to find some
low-hanging fruit and some really
creative things that would otherwise be
missed and of course if you want to do
bounties there's plenty of ways to get
involved bug crowd and hacker one are
two of the primary ones they talk to all
of us and they talk to the companies and
they run the bug bounty program and life
is good and you get alerts to and
notifications as well when new apps come
of a LeBeau new ways to hack so a lot of
times when folks are coming to me and
say hey where do I start what do I do I
want to get into this I want to play I'm
usually putting with this because if you
think back to one of the first stories I
told you all that you had to do was run
the right tool at the right domain and
pocket for grant what a great sense that
is man our problems are the gas money
that I love that idea
and though we may look
the Greybeards down and all their just
script his wearing scripts no I bring on
the script is in have them go play let's
give them money it's fantastic let's do
it so great way to start and that's just
level one as people get more and more
advanced you can get more and more money
and greater challenges until after
Spector was on his board okay you can
now win spectre like vulnerabilities I
think are like a half million or a
hundred thousand dollars do I have
million major major payouts as you get
to be really really good so all the way
from script Kitty to uber elite and
everything in between
so that's my my take on bug bounties has
been taken bounty hunters I think it's
fun I think it's cool
heard you go do it if you want to do it
if you're right software I encourage you
to go build one and if you're a pen
tester I encourage you to come out with
me for some drinks so with that thank
you so much
[Applause]