my coworkers are throwing gummies at
people because you know my talk comes
with candy I'm gonna give it a couple
more minutes for those of you that look
confused at the slide up here I do to
unforeseen circumstances out of my
control
I'm not able to give the social media
persona training but don't worry this is
still gonna be the best talk you see
today it still comes with memes and
Intel and candy so you're already like
three four three over everything else
alright we're gonna give it like one
more minute and then we'll get started
I could see you leaving yeah you in the
baseball cap yeah I could see you don't
worry we'll come get you later if if the
police ask you it was not a threats all
right we're all in agreement
I see shaking their heads good and that
threat good yeah those sentiments are
well-received
all right well the sugar the sugar is
what's making people violent today
all right our doors are shut so we're
gonna get started this talk is called
the high rate analysts I know some
people were expecting the social media
talk I not allowed to give the talk so
instead we're going to talk about Intel
analysis and threat Intel which I feel
like is a very important part of
cybersecurity but also an under
underutilized and misunderstood part of
cybersecurity so where threat Intel is
currently is not where it needs to be
and where I work we currently have Intel
as the center of our cybersecurity like
I meet with all the different teams we
work directly with all the different
teams and instead of complaining about
there being a problem in Intel I'm going
to show you how to fix that problem at
your company you're going to be able to
translate this across any industry
across any company and enterprise
government non-government whatever you
need alright so let's get started my
name is Rachel my last name is
pronounced Jackie boxy I know every
single person was wondering that I am a
cyber threat Intel analyst at Target
like 12 other presenters that you've
seen in the last two days I also work at
Target I have 14 years of Intel
experience I came from military
intelligence to government contracting
intelligence social media intelligence
now I do cyber threat intelligence I've
done pretty much every version of Intel
that you can think of for the last five
years I've been a cyber threat Intel
analyst for three of those years I was a
strategic analyst for the last
two-and-a-half ish years almost three
years now I've been a technical Intel
analyst and we're going to get into the
difference between strategic and
technical Intel and why that difference
needs to happen by the way my Twitter
handle
is soulcrusher eight-six is not my
birthday that's my level I'm currently a
level 86 soul crusher and if anyone
wants to challenge that you by all means
I always like a good challenge all right
so our agenda today we're now thinking
about how to structure Intel training
for the next generation of Intel Intel
2.0 if you will
sorry my phone is blowing up on the
podium I thought about what we do at our
company so we check phishing how many
people here think that they track
phishing really well at their company
okay everyone I work with these to put
their hands down okay I think one person
back there I feel like fishing is a
great way for Intel to become active in
day to day cyber security operations
phishing is a major attack vector at
every single company and a lot of times
threat Intel is regulated to like
reading briefs or creating executive
summaries or searching out the new bad
guy and really what you need is someone
that's going to be there to help your IR
team get faster and better and close
those cases more help your detection
team determine what detection you need
and we do that through our fishing and
this is actually a lot more of my
personal experience of how I became what
the new hybrid analyst is and we I did
that because I've been monitoring
phishing for three years and if anyone
thinks that it's impossible to monitor
phishing I'm going to show you our
manual process it's been just me for
three years at a company that is one of
the what fortune 500 companies like if
you think about it I'm here saying that
I can do it a large company by myself
successfully so any size company that
you have you can scale this you just
need to invest in the person you need to
invest the time and this is how you can
do it alright so let's talk about 30
intelligence there are two versions of
threat intelligence there's the more
traditional version of threat
intelligence your strategic intelligence
this is high-level Intel this more story
report or brief focused this is what the
majority of vendors
by when you get those like 50 page
briefings that they come out like four
years after the facts but it has a
pretty name on it
these are made for executives and
contextualized stories or blogs for mass
consumption they make it as generic as
possible to allow the majority of the
people to be able to consume it and
however whatever manner they need but
they don't provide you actionable Intel
they provide you an atomic indicators
and these things are not something you
can really go off of when you're writing
detection or you need IR the irony
something that's going on currently like
you need to be able to provide
behavioral indicators and phishing
allows us to look at indicators in a
different manner so a target we started
doing something called the technical
intelligence I'm on our technical
intelligence team it's me and two other
people these are operational it's
indicator or tactics both focused so
when I say tactic I've bent it's like
three other briefs that I've talked
about stepping away from the IOC s and
going more into behavior and that's what
we do
it relies on collaboration between Intel
IR and detection and my IR and detection
team are all sitting up here with
engineering and they can all tell you
that like we do talk on the daily basis
right team's up here like all of our
teams are in this room and when I say
like oh you need to talk on a daily
basis I mean like I know a lot about
them they know about me that's on a
personal level as well as a professional
level and if you're not willing to build
those relationships and talk to people
on a daily basis you're not gonna get
very far in inserting yourself into the
team all right so why track fishing so
the majority of companies fishing is
just a daily activity it's not is you
know you get the indicators in probably
between 10 and 100 alerts a day for
fishing depending on how bad your
fishing problem is but it's the number
one attack vector ninety percent of all
cyber attacks and cessful cyber attacks
started with the fish out of that forty
percent of them were spear fishing and
they were also looking for credential
fishing now credential fishing is
considered like a social engineering
tactic it's almost always glossed over
or pushed aside by a lot of Intel and by
a lot of incident response teams but
that's where you need to focus and
that's where we've been focusing is
commodity malware commodity malware and
social engineering phishing and we've
been tracking it on a collective basis
don't just track it one off and done we
collect it and track it and report it
and we have two and a half years of
searchable reportable intelligence on
every fish that has been able to be
analyzed against our company for two and
a half years I can tell you when Hans's
horse started coming against us I can
tell you which group to a five thirty
actually malware to PA five thirty
actually runs out just what Proofpoint
says it runs I can tell you how many
times credential fishing hits us on a
daily basis and this is something that
you really need to have at your company
to understand your threat landscape
because unless you work for the military
industrial sector your threat landscape
is 90% phishing
alright so we're gonna go over sources
of information where do you get the
information about the fish now ninety
percent of time you're gonna get an
entirely you either have alerts or some
form of incident response case or pass
from another team sometimes vendors will
pass over like hey I think someone's
accounts been compromised can you look
into this a little bit that's a very
common thing that's happening now
especially with o365 there's third
parties there are vendors that provide
phishing and the vendors are good but
you're gonna get to a point where
vendors can't help you because they're
not industry specific and you have
listservs and those are industry
specific I suggest that you have an
Intel team you get them on industry
specific listservs they're out there I
work for retail I'm on a retail listserv
I'm on a financial listserv I'm on the
hospitality listserv I'm on a listserv
that runs FBI and CAFTA
I'm on one that's like kind of on the
down-low of just people that want to
make Intel better and I get intelligence
from them and I give it back we're gonna
go over a whole slide on why it's
important that if you are producing
intelligence internally you need to
share it externally having good fret
intelligence is not a competitive
advantage you are not making your
industry better by keeping your Intel to
yourself there are ways to you know
there are ways to get around the need
for legal like we sanitize our reports
we track way more than we externally put
out there but we still put it out there
it's important to me that if we as a
retailer are getting something that the
other retailers also block it because
once it's blocked in our industry those
attackers will move on they are out for
the easiest target now you do have some
every once in a while there are
desperately needing to hit your company
this will also catch them but it'll
allow you to move aside the ones that
are just out for the easiest target to
make way for the ones that you need to
spend time on now there are blogs I'm
gonna show you my two favorite blocks
one is my online security the websites
are up here
it's a uk-based blog the problem with it
is that's a little wordy it's like
actual blog for style format it's very
story driven but once you get used to
the formatting you'll find amazing Intel
about phishing in there he always has
all the good trick bought campaigns and
the Han store campaigns now there is a
more technical style blog malware
traffic analysis he's also on Twitter I
know a lot of people that follow gherkin
also follow the guy that runs this blog
it's more just like straight up io C's
but it'll give you what you need to
search for phishing alright so because I
need to look for the sources of phishing
I decided that as an intelligent unless
I'm already doing all my research right
so I find all this third-party phishing
Intel and a lot of times there aren't
cases created on it with my C cert
co-workers but it did get deliver to an
end user so that email needs to be
processed and a lot of times that
requires me to type it up even though
like all my research up and hand it off
the C cert and I started thinking
wouldn't it be great if I could create
the case and work the case myself
wouldn't it be amazing if I could do all
that work and take it away from C cert
having to do double work because I
already researched everything I know
where all of the I know where all of the
emails landed in our system I know
exactly what needs to happen so I spent
a month with c-cert i sat down with him
and I became certified as a sake analyst
so in our company not only do I do a
threat until I
that's a sock you know uh that's our
senior director oh okay yeah I hear
Chris I can fish my talk alright so now
I spent the month with Caesar that's
about how long our training program is
for entry-level sake analyst that's the
people that would take most of the
fishing cases anything that doesn't
require additional malware analysis or
anything additional beyond like hey we
got this email let's pull this email
let's make sure there's nothing no
call-outs to any of the links or nothing
got downloaded let's close this case
contain it and move on so what can I do
now well I can create that case I can
conduct all the research I already have
to do that research I do all the scoping
in the case containment I create a
fishing report because we do report as
much as paperwork sucks it's extremely
important to have your paperwork
together and I'm going to show you the
template we use it exactly why we use a
template and what each section is and
it's really great and we share it so it
will be available and you guys can use
it and it's super easy alright so this
saves my see start working energy and
what is your job at a cybersecurity
office other than making sure that I are
an instance get handled quicker and
faster so this takes away their knee to
have constantly redoing and duplicating
all the efforts that I'm already doing
when I do my normal everyday job I also
allows for better integration slice that
with them for a month they show me what
literally every system does I now know
the ins and outs of my entire email
chain all of the ability like what we
have the ability to see all the logs
that we can see what we can't see how to
pull all the emails like it was a great
experience and now I'm closer to them
and that fosters the communication
needed to really create the fusion my
favorite buzzword to move cybersecurity
from a alert basis to an actual
predictive intelligence or a basis where
like you can focus on your threat hunter
your focus on predictive analysis you
can focus on automation and
of constantly focusing on the alerting
every day all right so we're gonna scope
a fish who thinks they know how to scope
a fish all the people I thought oh your
main eyes these four fish literally
every company has some way of figuring
out finding an email using either a
sender a subject line and attachment
name or md5 hash or an embedded link if
you do not have the ability to find
these logs you need to talk to your
company because you have to be able to
find an email somewhere in your system
that's how you stop fishing and tips
like proper scoping requires active
access if you do not have access as an
Intel person mirror your access with
your IR are people you need to be able
to find out what systems are stopping
emails and why it's very important that
I know which security appliance stopped
my phishing email and when there's a
point at that point stops blocking the
email or stops alerting me I need to
know why and then I can go back and be
like hey why is the compliance working
it worked yesterday but he didn't work
today and this email didn't change and
the Malheur didn't change so let's make
sure everything's working properly and
that's something that can take days or
weeks to notice and to be able to say
like within a couple hours like hey I
noticed that something's not right here
let's make sure that we have detection
let's let's get on blocking it that's
that's important that saves your company
potentially saves your company from the
initial intrusion vector start broad and
move narrow a lot people hate that
they're like oh I have this exact sender
in this exact subject line I want to
show you what I mean on this next slide
all right so we have our example email
this is an actual handset or email that
came in
and August uh dick comes in my company I
got it online cuz you know you know what
legal to get all mad at you for sharing
actual phishing emails because we all
know according to each company they
never have incidents so when I look at
this I have a sender I have a subject
line I have an attachment right I'm just
gonna search on that well with Hamza
Tora they actually use subject line
patterns they use sender patterns so
when you go to search your sender you
can't just search for Andrew C Brown and
you know the entire sender domain you
need to search the sender domain by
itself you need search partials of the
senator domain and you need to search
the sender name these are all gonna
produce different results and yes you
may get a few false positives in there
but the more you do it the easier it's
gonna be to just like section out this
false positives find the few that you
have and then move on same with your
subject line so I know for a fact with
the subject line and with this campaign
it was IRS themed there were 72
different subject lines if I search that
one subject line I would have only found
20 emails when I searched a generic
version of the subject Clyde I found
1762 emails there's a big difference
between seventeen hundred and twenty and
if you don't teach your stock analyst if
you don't teach your Intel team to
search properly to understand that the
current attackers are using patterns and
not direct phishing to every single
person you're gonna miss a huge portion
of the attack field same thing with your
attachment some people don't have the
ability to search attachments but you
have the ability to search attachment
types this is where you get boolean
searches or advanced searches where you
could be like I need someone that sent
us the subject line with IRS and also
had a zip attachments there are plenty
of out the box appliances that allow you
to do this multi searching and this
advanced searching functions alright so
we're gonna find patters that's what
Intel does Intel finds patterns and
we're going to talk about the bane of
everybody's existence right now Imhotep
okay does anyone here not know what you
want to this so I can explain it all
right I see a few okay so Emma's head is
a current banking Trojan that's been
making its around in fishing and the
reason ye motet is the current bane of
everyone's existence is because out of
all Kamali Mauer they have the best
initial reconnaissance phase when it
comes to fishing they use different
senders and different subject lines and
different links inside the email for
every single fish we're talking about
thousands to tens of thousands of fish
per campaign nothing is similar so you
start deciding how do you figure this
out there are patterns if you recognize
it over the years like I think our
current email set which was last week
had 176 subject line patterns and one of
them was literally like has the word
invoice in it which I'm sure you can
realize that for a retailer that takes
quite a bit of time to scope on to make
sure I'm only finding fishes and not
legitimate emails but that's something
that needs to happen and when I do that
and I spend the two and a half hours
scoping on 172 subject lines and then
hand oversee start the four that I
didn't see in their cases well that's
why they love me because they may have
to spend three hours of their
containment time looking for more emails
this is very important that stays on
time that they were able to look at
other alerts to process other things and
potentially save our company on our
networks from another threats okay so
here's my subject line pattern and this
leads into how I spent time with our
detection team so this is a third of the
links used in a Nima's head campaign two
weeks ago they they look all different
but if you break it down and you start
looking more into them you start looking
into your eyes you can actually find a
few patterns so out of I think there was
like a thousand actual links and the
emails I found eight subject line
patterns that produced only a motet
results in our environments so I was
like hey they only produce a motet
results in our environment when we
search on URI patterns this is something
we need to start learning on I'm not
learning on a domain I'm not blocking
the initial domain
the link that doesn't help you anyways
because that's got to change in an hour
you start looking at subject line
patterns that are gonna alert you to
newly delivered emails and start looking
at two three four steps down the line of
malware
alright so I found my pattern now I'm
working with detection are just actually
seems amazing they have the ability to
write behavioral detection and one of
the easiest behavioral detection is
right is regex now I'm going to show you
the regex I created and our detection
schemes go laugh at me so this is my
regex it does work technically it's also
not the greatest reject - well first of
all I didn't know a half of the little
symbols meant because I had only been
doing regex for like a couple months but
I wanted to learn how to write detection
so I knew what patterns to find if I
don't know what detection is in our
environment I don't know what systems we
have the ability to write detection on
then how am I gonna know what to hand my
team I could be like oh yeah poof point
came down with this amazing regex or so
and so on Twitter pass over this new
rule do you know if that's gonna work in
your environment are you just blindly
handing things to your detection team
and hoping and praying that it gets
taken care of in your environment
because that's definitely not the way to
go that's gonna cause frustration it's
gonna cause the animosity between the
teams because you're handing them stuff
they can't use and they're not getting
anything useful from you and then we
they don't implement it and it happens
like two or three days later and you ask
hey I handed you that why did you not
put detection in you know that's
defensive it's gonna come off that way
and you're gonna just keep breaking down
that relationship instead of working
together figuring out what you can do in
your environment so I went to I want
started section team and I said hey guys
look I've made this really cute regex
what can you do for me this is what they
sent me back
which is why our detection team does
detection and I don't because while I
was able to find the pattern and I was
able to show that you can write a regex
on it their detection team for a reason
but having that initial handshake them
knowing that I took the time to search
in our environment I made sure I wasn't
handing them things that we're gonna
create 900,000 false positives if one of
them did it they'd appreciate it and it
makes the detection easier it cuts off
their time to write that rule I like I
don't know probably half because the
majority of rule writing is research and
if I do that research ahead of time
which I'm gonna have to do anyways
because I'm already looking for all this
information
why would I hand them a half-finished
piece of work alright so we're talking
about our types of fishing you got
fishing you figured out your emails you
have a thousand of them how do you
figure out what type of email you have
can anyone tell me based on a subject
line what officious does anyone think
that they could do that or based on just
like one little pattern of a call-out
now I can do that because I have two and
a half years of experience and we like
to do that to the new people because it
looks like magic and they think it's
funny
but really it comes from years of
searching and where do you find it if
you're looking at malware virus total
they are your friends you can search for
a top-level domain you can search for
your hashes you can see what the common
AV detection is and we use text on it
like does it really matter if they came
from Russia or the eastern part of
Europe or Asia if what they're handing
you as an info stealer you're a gain
targeted by a nation-state can you
targeted by some guy that just wants
money from you what's important is that
you know what type of malware it is and
what that malware does and I'm going to
show you how you can structure that so
that way when you hand it back to
detection or you can hand it to a red
team or a pen testing team or a malware
analyst it helps them create a better
environment for your company hybrid
analysis is a great thing who's familiar
with hybrid analysis I should see a lot
of hands this is a sandboxing tool it's
amazing it's free
almost all of the virustotal links that
have malware and also have a hybrid
analysis link in the comment section it
provides you everything that a normal
sandboxing would all your indicators
behavioral indicators which is really
important because when you start writing
behavioral detection you need to know
why it's malicious what parent process
spawned a child process that has been
known to be used maliciously these are
things that you have to think about when
you start doing detection in your
environment any doubt run it's a
visualized sandbox so if you don't like
just Santa boxes up read your report
here's one that will walk you through
opening the document and show you
exactly what happens at every single
step it's amazing there is a free
version if you don't want them to then
put your information back out on the
Internet you have to pay for it but the
free version allows you to look up
things that have already been uploaded
and a lot of people upload this stuff
for fun and then you can find it and you
can use it for your analysis social
engineering this is a pane of people's
existence how can you tell us a social
engineering email it just goes to a
generic website maybes asking for
credentials it's important you
understand what type of credentials
they're looking for there's a big
difference if my company has something
that's looking for Capital One
credentials versus o365 credentials or
OWA credentials or Dropbox credentials
how likely is it for them to be a reuse
of what your company is using that's
what you need to think about when you
look at credential phishing not just
adds credential phishing let's just push
it aside like what impact is that gonna
have to your company because a lot of
breaches started with somebody putting
in their information and like a fake OWA
webform and then someone went to the
real OWA site the web application and
logged in and got their emails and then
fished someone else and fished someone
else and got the credentials they needed
and got into the systems that they
needed this is how breaches happened is
this how attacks happen if you're not
able to help at this beginning in or you
think automation helps with this you're
very sorely mistaken because automation
is Ettore asleep failing in social
engineering it requires your user your
in user your employees whoever you are
that you're protecting to interact with
the malware interacts with the link in
some way
Automation can't detect that so how do
you figure it out
URL query URL query jennette in scan do
URL Skanda oh these are great places
that'll show you the screen capture of
the page they give you a ton of
information an overview it'll tell you
if it's on a black list it'll tell you
if it's long block list it'll show you
every single redirect along the way
whether or not there was a get or a post
for that redirect where your credentials
go will show you a screen capture of the
page to show you what type of
visualization they're using what type of
pictures they're using what exactly
they're going after first little mode
data is something that people don't
think about a lot you can't find a
screen capture of your page you should
get a lot of information from virus hold
metadata this is on the second tab a
virus total a lot of times you can go
into a domain you can see you download
the text file you go to that text file
on the second page there's metadata this
metadata tells me that this page this
this link is going to an Outlook sign-in
page I now know what credentials they
were looking for and I didn't have a
screen capture these are things that
people don't think about that are very
useful when you're trying to analyze
what fish is actually in your
environment all right so you have your
fish you know what you had you gathered
all your i/o seeds what do you do with
it well you have a report template it's
important that you use something that is
repeatable and searchable we happen to
use a version of confluence which isn't
like the greatest now that we're up to
like three years of data but it's what
we have and what we had to use we made
it work for us for right now and our
report is very simple to to move
externally so it's just Excel blocks I
can easily copy and paste our report
from our repo and put it into an email
format and send it out externally
there's are things you have to think
about when you come up a report because
it's fine when you're doing it once or
twice when you're doing it 25 times a
day you need to have something that's
easily repeatable and easily shareable I
know it's really small I'm gonna go
through it in more detail so here's our
example report you need your Intel
source this is important when people go
back to your reports or excuse me our
entire IR team can go back and search on
the past cases using a case number
and come up with the entire report of
all the information that they need
so you need to have your source or if
they look for an IOC and it comes up as
like oh you know the financial sector
saw this two months ago or the retail
sector saw this two months ago like you
need to track where you're getting your
data from this actually is really good
to executives and I'm going to show you
how we transfer this into like some
amazing metrics too and about four
slides you need to name your pages you
need figure out a tracking mechanism we
check it by malware name and subject
line and if I had the time I would give
up on myself box and tell you why you
need to stop using threat actor names
and start tracking by malware or
behavior because I can see unless you
currently work for the
military-industrial complex
no nation state is looking at you there
might be a few financial people in here
they're snickering because they know
that they fall into that but like
Russia's not coming after you you're not
gonna have a bear or a panda or whatever
ta number they're up to now you need to
track it in a way that's usable malware
is usable you need to track it by they
behavior by the threat and that's how we
track it we track the targeting type
there's a big difference between a
campaign that's generic and spearfishing
a generic campaign and yes five thousand
six thousand ten thousand a hundred
thousand different emails can still be a
spear phishing campaign if you can prove
that they're targeting your company or
sub-sect of your company in a very
specific way versus just any address
they happen to find and your company had
a hundred in their whaling and the term
that we use when you are seeing fish
spearfishing against your c-suite now
this is you used poorly a lot of times
in the Intel community some people call
like whaling when someone spoofing your
CEO or just generically like saying hey
can you get in touch with me but like
you need to define those terms for your
company and stick with them so we have
defines that terms like BC is not be
easy unless they actually took over
someone's email if you're spoofing our
CEO then you're every constants email
because you're just looking to establish
a foothold with that person is it
communication with that person you
didn't take over anyone's email that's
not an email compromise so you need to
have these discussions you need to have
the discussion with IR you need have the
discussion with your malware analysts
with your detection team you need to
make sure that you're all speaking the
same language
and then you need to track it that way
we ever send her so we go back to our
hands tutorial you can see we have a
pattern in our senders with all the
FedEx senders now if I just gone with
the one which was the only email I had
at the time from that external source I
wouldn't have found for other senders
and who knows how many emails and
there's three subject lines but you can
see a pattern those subject lines you
start recognizing your patterns you
start knowing how to search faster you
start being able to look over your IR
teen shoulder and say oh that oh yeah
that's that's just hands at or we'll
probably get about 1,500 of them it
should stop around - these are all the
lengths Ari looks like twelve of their
companies have gotten it it's not
getting past anything that's something I
can say to my team and they're very
appreciative of it we have our attempts
so an attempt if you think about it is
one email against from one throw actor
to one person at your company that is an
attempt now campaign is however many
emails are included in those attempts
from that threat actor you can choose to
delineate having what I usually find the
ability to either connect it by malware
or type or a sender you don't want to
start putting like every credential fish
that you got in the day and one report
because you're not able to divide it out
it's really hard to be like okay this
one's Bank of America and Capital One
and this one's from OWA well those are
different to us and I would treat them
differently and you should too and if
you keep putting them in one report it
gets really hard for you to share that
in a usable format people are gonna
start ignoring your Intel and then
you're not helping anybody
we check our security appliances I know
how many security wise is there in my
environment and I track exactly which
ones eliminated my emails including LDAP
for those in don't know LDAP is an
appliance that's used to check your
email address versus your global address
list if it's not in the proper format or
that person doesn't exist in your
environment it's automatically dropped
from your environment we track that it
helps us determine how what percentage
of the emails sent against us we're to
bogus addresses so I know how valid
there's the threat list is yeah
that's in there but like we're really
looking at Demark hasn't come up for the
fishing cases that we track with the
type of malware and everything there's
really in like some averse to beyond
cases and we're not really tracking that
the same way therefore things are valid
fishes and we thought you I really want
to get to do that in this so can we talk
about it
alright we can go into it more woodsy
mark and successful to us as successful
fish is anything that was delivered to
an end-user it doesn't matter if they
clicked on it if the malware downloaded
if someone had to have a new system
isolated you had the ability to have
that happen if it reached my end user
its successful our security appliances
failed our end user got a fish we do
track clicks and we do track other
things too because it's really important
that are especially for education
purposes we know how many people fell
for what types of fishes are we to
discuss recipients when it's whaling or
when it's for your fishing I need to
tell you why we have attachment
sometimes our testbench are dropped and
that's why the email got to end-user we
still track that to our embedded links
and our header you know header is where
you find that the majority of legal gets
really nervous about you sending things
externally because there's a lot of
company information a lot of internal
network information associated with the
header what we found is a weed broke our
header down to just the sender DNS
information and our sender IP address
that's what other people need to find
things in their environment and our
legal team is perfectly okay with that
so you really need to like figure out
what is desperately needed by other
companies to allow you to share your
intelligence and then we have an email
body like you can't really see it
because we didn't have an HTML version
of it but they took an actual like FedEx
delivery email copy and pasted
everything over all the HTML all the
proper image references and just change
the hyperlink the average user is gonna
fall for this
the average user falls for really silly
things like
and and we're we just heard a talks
yesterday today about not blaming your
user it's hard to educate your user when
it looks exactly like the email they're
expecting so you need to have the
ability to find these things in your
environments and to track it and make
sure that your IR team knows what's
going on okay so we're gonna talk about
malware behavior this one's really long
so handset or Hansa tor is a dropper or
a loader which is the version of malware
that's just used to basically get other
malware onto your environment this
specific version had a link inside the
email that link change is so often like
it's not worth blocking your atomic
indicator is gonna change within 12
hours what that does is it downloads a
word document a malicious Word document
that malicious where document changes
about once a week it's an OK indicator
you're gonna have different md5 hashes
it's not really the best
well that malicious Word document has a
macro in it and that macro makes a
call-outs I believe is the powershell
call out to a situ it actually pulls
down Maur
now that's e2 is trackable we have a
whole team that spends a lot of time
looking at registering at addresses
seeing what Thrasher's are using for
their c2 and they were proximately
blocking it a day a week a year ahead of
time before it even comes to our system
that's predictive intelligence you're
able to decide what is going to be in
your system a day from tomorrow a week
from tomorrow and you're able to block
it before it even reaches you you're not
gonna be able to get to that point if
you're not tracking what those CTS are
if you look at that initial link in the
body and say oh I'm done you need to
make sure you're tracking down that Maur
if you don't understand it find your
mouth where analysts find a vendor find
whoever does that work for you and ask
them to explain it to you so that you
can easily communicate it back out we
also track our research and support
links because like any good Intel
analysts no one can trust each other I
need to see where your research came
from like I'm sure you're the greatest
researcher in the world and your your
analysis is trusted by everybody but I
better see all your supporting links so
that I can make sure that I agree with
it all right
collective analysis matters
we talked about this we talked about why
would you want those reports searchable
why do you need the historical data I
can't do time and day of week in
correlation we went through a period of
time in 2016 where a motet was sent to
us Tuesday through Thursday 10 a.m. to 3
p.m. every time every week Tuesday
through Thursday 10 a.m. to 3 p.m. I
walked in you know 10:00 a.m. on Tuesday
hey guys it's gonna start ends about
3:00 p.m. should be about 500 let me
know if you need anything else this is
important information you need to be
able to have that in your in your
security sauk easy identification the
majority of my team up here now can
identify an email the second it comes in
and that's not because our vendor
identifies it correctly most of our
vendors identify or automate systems
identify as generic malware or some
weird body pattern or something but they
can look at it and they've worked with
it and I've showed them how I identify
it and what my research has shown that
they can then do it themselves you need
to have that education going back and
forth you're right nice prevention
failures I work with our security
appliance teams every week I bring them
a prevention failure hey this email got
through if it's a vendor I for I make
them go back to the vendor hey we're
paying you and you did not block this
email tell me why and don't tell me I
need to buy something new I'm already
paying you you blocked the email that
I'm paying you for and if you have that
data they don't back down they get
really scared it's really funny it's a
good time if it's something that you
control make sure that they understand
like hey for you know a year this was
blocked by this first appliance but now
we're seeing two or three getting
through do we need to reconfigure
something is there like a new rule that
we need they finally got around what
we're currently using this is how you
provide actionable Intel okay what can't
you do with the template you have this
template you have a report what do you
do with it internally statistics for
management if you think those aren't
impressive every month I can track
exactly what type of malware was in my
environment the exact amount
when it changes I can show yearly
correlations monthly correlations weekly
correlations do you know management
likes pretty graphs this is an easy way
to show your management what the threat
landscape looks like if I can show that
you know the last month there were zero
ransomware attempts and a new story
comes out that finally makes it to CNN
about ransomware well now my sister
understands that we haven't seen
ransomware in three months and we
definitely didn't see that one three
weeks ago because I have this justice
here to prove it so now we're not
refocusing on something that you know
isn't in your environment you know it's
not a threat that's saving you time I
mean how many people here have had to
focus on something that you knew was
never gonna come back and never be in
your environment there's a lot of people
that do that on a daily basis and that's
where frustration comes from all right
you can create relevant phishing
education we have a team that just
fishing education a lot of people have
teens at deficient education or you work
with vendors out-of-the-box vendor
phishing emails for education are not
applicable to most environments because
they have hundreds or thousands of
different clients and they aggravate
that aggregate that altogether but what
works against an industrial like the
delivery vertical is not gonna work
against the hospitality vertical but
they kind of mush it all together and
just give you options you need something
that works for your environment so I
created all of our fishy
I'm the fishing expert my company I
create all the fishing that I've seen
people click on this is a nice one if
you ever see a fish you've probably seen
this this has been very popular for
about a year and a half it's a super
generic helpdesks fish comes from like
tech at helpdesk dot oh one it's like
hey we're gonna take your email away
please upgrade and so many people click
on it and input their credentials
because they're super super worried that
they're not gonna have access to email
educating your users on what you see
every day is how you make your users
better that's how you stop blaming your
users because you're educating them on
what you've seen
without that you're educating them on
whatever vendor told you was the latest
thing of 20
of teen actually share your Intel find
trusted partners sign NDA's get into the
listserv
if you are not sharing your Intel
there's no reason for you to be
producing it you need to make sure that
your industry is better doesn't matter
what your industry is every industry can
be more secure and you are the people
that need to make it more secure alright
remember a recap fishing and Caesar
detection and security appliances and
external sharing and collective analysis
and reports over time and you need to
make sure that you set up a program I
didn't want stand up here and say
everybody needs new Intel until it's
broken but not provide a roadmap for you
you need to have something that you can
take back to your company and I promise
you this can translate to any company
and if anyone wants to know how for
their specific company I'm available to
talk to them and their any questions
we're gonna talk about demarco after
this anyone else have questions yeah in
the back yeah so there's no current out
the box they automate that will provide
you good fishing intelligence not in any
timely manner all of ours is done
manually I know you think that's not
possible
I can manually evaluate about 55,000
emails a month we're working on
animation you kind of have to write it
yourself we're not the best at it which
is why I'm so faster than what we
currently have and why still manually
done but uh I'm one person one FTE one
FTE can provide you a ton of fishing
intelligence anyone else yeah
Oh our user submission process so we
used to just have like it kind of
hanging out there but a couple years ago
we got really good with our education
and we make sure our users understand
where just submitted to they submit to a
security inbox which is monitored and
then run scripts against to make sure
that we're not looking at a ton of like
spam or legitimate emails are coming in
we also use a reporter button that it's
like a one-click that allows you them to
send it in to say hey I think this is
suspicious let me click on this button
it sends it to the right place they
don't have to constantly remember which
address to send it to anything like that
there yes if we were centralizing them
to report we do incentivize during
security months we do have remedial
training and forms of Education and
additional things that happen if they
fail education test or if someone
repeatedly clicks on things like a
repeat offender type program I do
believe that this is the only way that
you can truly get someone to invest in
it is if they know that there is going
to be some kind of consequence or
something else that they're gonna have
to do if they fail we do have month I do
have incentives those are months where
it's especially present or there's like
a focus so October is to carry awareness
month we definitely do in October
there's a couple of fishy months
throughout the year that we we focus on
and gamify and try to incentivize
everything yeah yeah yes so we actually
have our own reverse engineers on staff
and so a lot of times they'll write up
reports for me and then I can see like
oh it's been the same author every time
and then we can take it to detection and
be like hey there's some metadata that I
think that we can definitely use for
different types of alerting or detection
yes yeah all of our fish analysis is in
one location at the end and I'm the one
collecting it because I'm the Intel
person so if you're going to find some
way to centralize your Intel make sure
the Intel person is the one-stop shop
that's what they're there for
yes oh so confluence is just like online
it's like a SharePoint product it just
happens to be what we use it is just an
Excel template that we happen to store
in a searchable format there was another
question here yes we do so the last one
I showed you uh here go back a little
bit that's one of our phishing campaign
emails that we used a couple years ago
so every week we have a baseline fish
that goes out to a select number of our
employees which is a subset that's what
we use to determine how often someone
would actually report to us then every
month there is a specific email that
goes out when people fail they have a
retest two weeks later if they're on the
repeat offender program they get
additional education and then we have we
have fishing education that goes out to
specific departments or teams so if we
know that we've had some vendor
compromises or like there's been vendor
compromises discussed in the Intel
forums or anything like that our vendor
management team we get additional
training or if we know that like
SharePoint or Dropbox or any other
product that we are currently using has
been used a lot in phishing we give
additional training on that
we like a little more on something he's
asked about like our detection
environment and how do we basically like
go back to our rules have been
established for years and pare them down
and stuff like that and that is a much
larger question
um one here and then I think I could
take one more so education is the best
way to reduce time to report so you
don't want your user having something
say in their mailbox for a week and they
definitely clicked on it user education
is how you get them to report faster the
external information on phishing is how
you have the ability to catch it when
your users are still not reporting over
the week so that's information I'm
getting externally where I can search
for those phishing emails and see that a
user had it in their inbox for like 12
hours and whether or not they clicked on
it and then we can take action before
they even need to report it in to us so
you need to come from both sides of that
not only externally to get that
information and it's you take it on as
the onus but also making sure your users
are educated when like how to recognize
it and when to send it in okay last one
mm-hmm yeah so we as a vendor for our
fishing right now there's like three or
four of them out there they're all about
the same fish me know before I think
there's a couple other ones there's now
go fishing which is a publicly available
get repo that allows you to set it up
internally and this works especially
well for smaller companies they don't
have the ability to pay the amounts of
that a vendor requires so there's quite
a few options out there but that they'll
say you need something that's going to
provide you the statistics because
that's how you determine whether or not
what you're doing is working bees fish
me yeah okay thank you so much if
there's more questions I am around you
obviously had miss me cuz I have bright
poopy blue hair a home thank you so much
for coming you guys
[Applause]