little late and I still see people
trickling in I'm just gonna go ahead my
name is Megan Kearney for people who I
haven't met before most of you I've been
doing this info sex stuff for 10 years
or so now
um I left my Twitter handle up here
because if you want to run the queries
in these slides and you don't want to
type them out by hand I'm going to post
them on my Twitter feed later all right
so let's get started
thread hunting um the Macintosh Edition
I've seen a lot of threat hunting stuff
for Windows I haven't seen a lot for
Macintosh I think it's something we need
to do more of and but before I talk
about the Macintosh angle I want to talk
a little bit about why you would do
threat hunting at all and I think the
last presentation in that room red team
vs. blue team was a really good
demonstration of this because even if
you have good antivirus even if you have
a really good idea even if you've got um
Network sensors running all over they're
still gonna be stuff that doesn't match
signatures that's bad and that's stuff
you find by hunting and the thing with
hunting is it's very environment
dependent so I'm gonna go over a bunch
of queries today I'm going to talk about
a bunch of stuff you're gonna need to
look at your own environment and figure
out what's normal because that's why a
lot of these things sneak through we
look at our tools and we think they must
be covering everything they're not
covering everything they're covering
what they know to be bad because they
don't want their customers to get a lot
of false positives right if you want to
define normal for your environment and
look for what's abnormal that's all
hunting is specifically this
presentation this is a screenshot I
think it's a few months old from threat
hunting net I've highlighted all of
those resources there are artifacts that
exist only on Windows so there's a lot
of threat hunting resources out there
that are not examining what artifacts on
Macs look like and I think this is a
real weakness for us because everybody
jokes that max don't get malware even
though we know they do right but how
often are we actually looking on it
looking for it and how much of the Mac
malware are we finding I would bet
there's a lot of it we're not finding
because we're not looking very happy so
I will be the first to admit that this
presentation is just the beginning of
the work we need to do as a community I
know Patrick wordles been doing some
work I've seen a few other presentations
there's actually a cool conference
that's in Hawaii objective by the sea I
think that's gonna come up in a few
months if you happen to be able to go
and we need to do some more work for
this I think we're at the beginning of
this work and I just want to acknowledge
that that this is not the end of what we
need to accomplish all right so that's
my pep talk does that count as a pep
talk I want to talk about my experiment
so I come from an academic background
and I believe in showing your work what
we have here is yeah sort of an emoji an
emoji explanation of the work I did so
what I did was I took this Mac Mini I
ran a bunch of malware samples through
it but before I did that I altered it
and I removed the Wi-Fi card this was so
I knew exactly where it could talk out
so if it didn't have an Ethernet cable
plugged in and it didn't have the
cellphone modem plugged in I knew it
wasn't talking to anything I had a
process monitoring solution installed if
you are familiar with it you will
recognize the screenshots as I go
through this presentation I don't want
you to get too hung up on exactly what
that process monitoring solution is
because it doesn't matter if you have
any sort of process monitoring solution
that's going to record what's executing
on your hosts you can use this research
I use time machine to reset between
experiments just because it was built in
and it was easy this you'll notice his
separate hardware so there are no
virtual machines involved here which
means I didn't have to worry about
virtual machine evasion techniques there
are some good things about it the way
this experiment is set up there are some
bad things I'm going to talk about that
more towards the end of the presentation
but this is the environment I was
working in
the malware samples if you are going to
do research on Mac malware I recommend
you start with Patrick wordles very
excellent collection on his site because
he has a lot of samples that are really
easy to run you can search for mono
samples on virustotal and there are a
lot of them however some of them require
I don't want to get too much in the
weeds here some of them require being
part of an app bundle to run and unless
you know how to build that app bundle
you may have some trouble getting
started I didn't want to mess with it so
I use Patrick whorls collection and it's
a very good place to start um before I
move on if you haven't played with
malware before and you're going to start
doing this research please do your
homework unfortunately there aren't a
lot of I I don't even know of a book
that focuses on Mac malware research but
there is a book called practical malware
analysis which is sort of the current
Bible for malware analysis it's got a
good overview on how to set up an
environment to safely detonate malware
and the things you need to worry about
so if you're interested in starting this
work that's where I'd start but do do
your homework or else bad things will
happen so I talked about threat hunting
a little bit I talked about normal
versus abnormal but I want to talk a
little bit more about what this
experiment is actually trying to achieve
I wasn't trying to find specific
indicators if you want specific
indicators you can get a hash of a file
you can search for specific strings in
the file you can search for network
indicators where does it call out to all
these things are useful for identifying
specific strains of malware that was not
the goal of this experiment the goal of
this experiment was to find the general
behavior patterns that indicate badness
specifically what does a malicious word
process look like on a Mac there are
word macros for a Macintosh they exist
there's just not many publicly known
samples
what does now where do to maintain
persistence on a Mac you know we know a
lot about what it does on Windows
scheduled tasks installing in the users
home directory what does that look like
on a Mac
what does malware want to hide so what
are what are the signs that it tries to
erase once it's gaining a foothold and
what is getting a foothold look like
what are they trying to do on the system
what are the system commands they try to
run
what do where do malware processes and
their artifacts live so a common place
to see malware on Windows is in the
users documents in settings directory
nothing typically runs out of the
documents and settings directory but
users have rights so you don't need to
install your malware there what does
that look like on a Mac since we're
running a little bit low on time
I'm going to go over the rest of these
questions later this is basically the
outline for my entire presentation
you're gonna see a bunch of queries and
I promise I will give you the full index
of all the queries at the end and yeah
we'll talk about some more stuff with
our later so this is a word macro on a
Macintosh you can get the sample from
Patrick Wardle site it's actually kind
of fascinating in that it's very similar
to a macro on the windows side right so
we have Microsoft Word launching a show
which launches Python which launches
that PS command
for those of you not familiar with UNIX
stuff that lists processes and then to
grep commands we're gonna find out more
about what they do later so this isn't
PowerShell right but where it doesn't
launch Python very often so these are
women this is one of the things you can
look for how would you find this in your
environment you want to look at
parent-child relationships so again this
is a specific process monitoring
solution don't get too hung up on that
what I want you to recognize is that
this solution has IDs that tie parent
processes to children so it all starts
with that Microsoft Word and then
trickles down to all these other
processes
and you can see that grip process there
grep for Little Snitch if you are
familiar with Little Snitch it's a
personal firewall so what this malware
sample is doing is saying if Little
Snitch is present it's gonna find me so
exit but otherwise we're gonna continue
oh and you can see they're using base64
which is another thing that also happens
on the windows side of the world except
this time they're passing it to Python
because PowerShell is not on Macs well
not natively alright so how can we
detect word macros on a Mac this is a
really simple question I don't want you
to get too wrapped up in the specifics
here this is actually a spunk query for
those of you who knows longer but
basically what we're asking is what
processes does word typically launch and
how many of them just to set a baseline
for your environment if you have an
accounting department that runs a lot of
specialized Word documents or
spreadsheets maybe this is gonna look
different for you but it will answer it
will answer the basic question and what
do we see I love it when you find
indicators like this because a lot of
times you start with a hypothesis and
you look at the data and it's really
messy and complicated and hard to pick
out the signal but this one's pretty
simple right there is a normal
collection of word processes at most
they're launching two processes in the
tree at most and then we look down here
and this is what abnormal looks like
there's our macro in the center it's
launched what six processes and it
includes command line that includes
Python and if you'll notice in the
normal situation
all of those are office binaries so this
is a really simple signal in your
environment if you're looking just look
at what word normally launches and then
look for variations from that but you
might want to approach this from the
opposite direction right maybe instead
of investigating an entire fleet of
machines you're investigating one
specific machine and you
want to say I know they opened this
weird document but what did word run on
that machine that wasn't from word and
that's what this query does uh so again
don't get too caught in the weeds
basically what it's doing is it's saying
look for all the word processes and then
show me everything that's associated
with those processes it's not actually
word if you are using spunk I want to
make you aware of a gotcha
this lunk has a number of settings that
have to do with making sure one query is
not going to kill the cluster for
everyone
basically it limits the amount of memory
that a particular query can use by
default when you're doing sub searches
you can only get 10,000 items so if for
some reason you have a machine that ran
more than 10,000 instances of Microsoft
Word over the timeframe you're searching
this is gonna have some false negatives
so just watch your time frames and keep
an eye on that but this is what we get
and it's pretty clear right here are the
things that were launched that aren't
word and you can immediately see that
this probably is not a good thing all
right so we're moving on to persistence
[Music]
this is the most common or one of the
most common ways to maintain persistence
on a Mac it's sort of equivalent to
scheduled tasks they're called launch
agents they run on boots they can run
you they can be installed from the
system vitamin system in the system
directory or they can be installed on a
per user basis all this command does is
it looking for all the processes that
contain launch agents in the past and
then it's going to count them and you'll
notice there's a little bit of fancy
regex there because Google Chrome is
often installed in the user's home
directory and so if you don't strip out
the user's home directory from the past
what you get is a bunch of things that
look unique but aren't because it's
basically Chrome but for each one of
your users
so this is something I didn't get to do
because of the experiment setup I had
but if you want to run this query
regularly look at using summary indexing
or whatever the equivalent is for your
sim because it will make it much more
efficient there are hundreds of launch
agents on a Mac before you even install
anything so this is going to return a
lot of data and if you're going to run
it over large periods of time your sim
is probably not going to like you very
much
so summary indexing or something similar
will help but all of those cautions
being said what do we find it's really
neat how things like this pop out right
away this is Sam loader which is more
crapware than malware but you probably
still want to know if it's on your
system if you are not familiar with Mac
keeper those names aren't going to jump
out at you but you'll notice the
frequency there it is the only machine
in the fleet that has this installed
which is always a red flag and something
you want to look out for where does
malware what does malware want to hide
this was a really cool result that I was
totally not expecting when I started
this experiment and before I talk to you
about what the result is I need to
explain something about Apple's internal
systems they have something called a
quarantine attribute it is opt in but
most well behaved browsers follow it
which means when you download a file the
file is labeled by the browser as having
been downloaded from the internet where
it was downloaded from what time it was
downloaded and which a program
downloaded it this quarantine attribute
is of course useful for flagging things
that you're going to execute that are
downloaded from the internet which is
why if your malware you might want to
remove it this is ocean Lotus a
nation-state malware I don't remember
which nation state but that command that
I've highlighted there that X adder - D
- R is saying delete the comdata Lauren
teen from this really weird file
right that starts with a dot it's in my
home directory and but really weird
executable right so what are they doing
they're deleting the quarantine
attribute so it's not flagged by
forensics and so the operating system
doesn't flag it when you open it
this command is relatively rare there
are some installers that do it
Chrome updates do it again your mileage
may vary in your environment but the
best part of this one is it's really
simple to search for there are no
parent-child relationships there's no
frequency counting here it's just a
regex on the command of course you might
have to account for some difference in
the order of those commands but that's
pretty simple what does getting a
foothold look like uh so I noticed with
the Mac malware in particular it seems
to be very busy right when it first got
on the system and so I thought well
let's look at process trees how many
process trees have a large number of
processes in them and it turns out not
many I set my threshold at 50 the
redacted stuff you see at the bottom
there is because when you start doing
this research you will figure out that
your internal inventory control system
slash software deployment system looks a
lot like a c2 because it is it's just
yours so you will probably need to us
filter some of that out but this was
fairly reliable at finding things like
ransomware right because what does
ransomware do it finds a bunch of files
and then it kicks off a process to
encrypt every single one of them and
you'll notice this one was really cute
it's using zip internally which means
the encryption key is actually like
right there doc a is nation-state stuff
but it's showing up here because doc a
phones home via tor if you do not
already have tor installed on your
system doc a helpfully installs it for
you using homebrew which of course kicks
off a bunch of processes
because it has to download a bunch of
packages and it creates a very busy
process tree um I should clarify what
you're seeing here on the command line
is the parent process sort of it's like
the overall process that kicked off all
the child processes so it's not a whole
list of everything
um and especially with that ransomware
you see that the find command somewhere
in there um she lists all the list all
the files that it's going to a crypt all
right where do malware processes live
this is one of the things I was really
interested in because if you can write a
query that says something executing from
this directory is bad it's a really good
place to find malware so the first is
process is running from tempters which
is very similar to the windows side of
the world and this one was actually
really cool because I was testing my
queries and this is not my victim
machine this is another machine that I
found during the course of my research
and it was fun floor and so you can see
that underscore update does he open
commands and then it installs this
really weird like randomly named binary
and temp and runs it so this is
something I actually found by accident
while I was testing my queries which is
always a good result another place that
I found malware likes to put itself is
library scripts there's actually not a
lot of legitimate stuff that runs out of
library scripts so this is another good
place to start
yeah I think if I remember correctly
there was some filtering you had to do
with this one but this is you can see in
that window down bottom that snake and
it's a fake Adobe Flash Player and it's
setup that install DP in library scripts
another thing I noticed that Mac malware
tends to do is it sets up a staging area
in temp and then it copies things over
to the user's home directory so if you
look for copies that go from temp to the
user's home directory
you can find some of this there's a
little bit of noise there but not a lot
and it's actually a pretty good method
so what you see here is the malware
created this underscore underscore
system directory which looks super
legitimate right and then copies it to
launch agents so this is remember
earlier I talked about launch agents and
how they can be installed on behalf of
the system or a per user it's installing
it in the users directory in this case
because that doesn't require Rudd and
it's a launch agent called system which
is now going to run every single time
the user logs in ah another thing I
noticed that malware likes to do is
change own commands and I'm not sure
exactly why this comes up so much but it
did and if it happens on user
directories that start with dots it's
particularly suspicious this one does
have some noise associated with it
because there are some like it has a
preferences directory there are a few of
those things but it's still relatively
good that's what you see there's that
filtering there and when you see things
pop up that are really malicious they
pop out right away right because that is
not user generated activity right there
so this is me filtering Oh changin um
change mod commands are along a similar
line though this one requires more
filtering for some reason and again
you'll notice you're gonna want to
filter out the user's home directory at
the beginning of it when you're doing
your results
one thing I didn't look for but I
thought would be interesting to look at
next time is to look at how many
legitimate processes actually do 777
perms I have a feeling it's not many but
it would be a question worth looking at
all right so what does c2 look like um
obviously if you have a network IDs or
something like that or if you're
counting bandwidth you might be able to
find really busy c2 that's really noisy
that's not what this command is designed
to find I apologize it's a lot of text
but all you need to really know here is
it's counting the length of the time the
process is running versus how many
network connections it's made so the
hypothesis here is if is if a process is
running for a long time it probably
should be making network connections on
a regular basis otherwise it's kind of
lurking in the background
the reason this query looks complicated
is because on this specific platform the
process creation entry and the process
ended entry are two different records so
you have to join them to figure out the
process time which is another good note
to make if for some reason that end of
process record doesn't exist
this query might give you false
positives um if you shut down a Miss
machine unexpectedly it might not get
generated for instance but this is the
result from that query which is carido
so here we have a process that's been
running for a very long time and has
only made one network connection and
hasn't done anything else of note so
there's one way you can find command and
control this one's a little bit more
complex uh that bit I've highlighted
there is just a way for you to filter
out your internal systems whatever that
means to you because as I said a lot of
your internal systems are going to look
like command and control and trigger
false positives on
worries what operating systems features
does malware use so a lot of just to
take a step back here a lot of the stuff
we're looking at with Mac malware is not
in a broad sense different than what you
see on the windows side of the world
it's just going to be implemented
differently but those implementations
are different when it comes to making
detection so the operating systems
features that malware uses are going to
be different because of the way it
installs persistence so we talked about
launch agents a little bit after you've
installed the launch agent launch
control is what launches it and one
thing I noticed specifically with
malware is that if something contains
both a shell process and launch control
it's a little suspicious because what
that essentially means is a shell ran
launch control which doesn't happen very
often it's not something users tend to
do and it's not how things happen on
boot as a launch agent that comes up
every time the user logs it which one
was this trying to remember which piece
of malware this was oh it's right in
there
I'll call me I think this is a contact
information stealer I remember right the
other thing that malware tends to do
when it has a shell is run lots of those
shells to do lots of things so you can
count a count the number of shells
within a process tree and that can give
you some useful results this particular
query at least on the platform I was
using tends to fall over if you try and
run it for more than a small set of
hosts um but you could probably play
with it and improve that a bit I've set
my threshold at 20 but again your
mileage may vary in your environment um
you just need to test and figure out
what looks like normal so here we have
another way to find ransomware and you
can see the message it pops up on the
screen and then we have been tier
is something that runs a lot of shells
to set up its persistence what you can
see there is that that local directory
inside the users home directory hides a
bunch of its art artifact and it also
installs a large agent which is one of
those shell commands oh yeah and then it
deletes itself that's that very last
shell command for event here all right
cool
think we're making good time um what
does recon look like uh just to take a
step back if you have not studied
malware before a lot of malware comes in
to do recon they want to know where the
machine is they want to know who it
belongs to
they want to know what the time zone in
is and all of that is to figure out how
valuable the machine is uh I think I
have time for a quick detour so um there
are lots of places on I'll call it the
dark web for lack of a better term where
you can buy time on computers so these
are computers that somebody else has
compromised that you can pay to take
over and there are actually cases where
criminals have gotten into a group of
machines at a specific company and it'll
be like a deal at the supermarket like
we have a bonus today here are ten
computers at Acme corporation and you
can gain a foothold on their network and
own their company right so that's why
malware does recon of course it looks a
little differently on the Mac um these
commands here uh just look at the first
line of that query network setup tells
you about the network configuration of
course who and who am I will tell you uh
the name of the user the program is
running ass and sis control will dump a
bunch of hardware information about the
machine
including some OS information and so
that's super useful information for
attackers of course your inventory
system is going to be looking at these
things too which is why you have to
filter it out
but if you start by looking for
processed trees that run more than say
one or two of these commands it's a
fairly reliable reliable way to find
malware you as a user on the system
might type who am i every once in a
while but you're probably not going to
type who am i and then list all the
hardware on your machine and then list
all the network interfaces to find out
what your IP addresses so here's our
results
this is vac a and duct a is looking for
the proxy on the machine so it can
configure the proxy to get out and that
top hit is max by which is basically
doing a bunch of hardware reconnaissance
to figure out what kind of machine it's
on
how does malware try to avoid detection
on a Mac this is where we need to take
another little detour um so there's a
something on the Mac called security off
trampolines and this is basically when
you come in as an installer and you want
to run with root privileges but you
don't have them this is how you get them
in most cases at props it pops up this
little dialog box that you have to enter
your password in and this is just to be
clear here security off trampoline at
the legitimate tool that's used by
legitimate installers and illegitimate
installers but I thought it might be
interesting to look for rare processes
that use it but before we get there I'm
going to take another little detour so I
talked about malware and how you have to
be careful with it this is what doc a
shows you when it works so when you're
playing with malware don't trust
anything the malware it tells you make
sure you're looking your artifacts make
sure you're checking what your system
what your monitoring systems are telling
you um to be sure you know what's going
on also I thought this was really cute I
should share it because this is the only
malware sample that I've seen do this
all right so my hypothesis
if you have a rare process um if you
have a process that's used security off
trampoline and there's only say one
process in your environment that's de
let's use it then maybe that's something
to look at
so I specifically looked for the da k
processes to see how many times they
appeared because some of these are
actually system utilities that Daka is
using um that are also using security
trampolines so they're not actually
those aren't all malicious hashes but
anyway it looked good from this point of
view but when I ran the numbers what I
found was lots of hashes are unique over
shorter periods of time so you have as
this conflict like the more you reduce
your window the easier it is to count
but the more things that look rare that
aren't actually rare the more you
increase your window the better data you
get and the more your sim tends to fall
over on you so how can we deal with this
problem um what well I'll get to the
deal with part in a moment this is just
some more data to hammer home the point
of the if a hash was involved in an OP
trampoline event it was owned it was
probably only recorded once by one agent
so B rarity just based on off trampoline
wasn't good enough what you have to
filter on is the rarity in off
trampoline and the rarity in the general
population which led to this unholy
query huh which again try not to get
lost in it basically all we're doing is
looking for the processes that use das
trampoline
count the number of time it's used and
then add to that information how common
is this process in the general
population and then once we have that
data
we can filter on it so that part folded
at the bottom we're searching for things
that are uncommon and we're searching
for yeah
we're searching for things that are
uncommon and we're filtering out things
we know that trigger false positives so
it turns out this sort of works right so
I've highlighted the things that should
be rare those are those doc a hits in
the red box but adobe isn't rare why is
that showing up if you are if you
noticed when I click past so if we delve
into this a little bit more what we find
is that some of these are rare for this
query but not actually rare in the
general population and the reason for
this is I have used a terrible hack I
had to do this because of the platform I
was on because I didn't have summary
indexing available to me but in this
bunker in this Splunk instance what I
could do is I could find the rarest
10,000 hashes and the most common 10,000
hashes but that left this big chunk in
the middle that wasn't categorized at
all so a lot of stuff comes up that's
not actually rare I couldn't solve this
problem on the infrastructure I had but
I think you could do this really well
with summary indexing or if you have
some sort of known good list that would
also be an awesome way to throw out
stuff that you know is false positives
all right another thing malware does to
hide itself is self deleting processes I
know this happens on Windows too at some
benign installers do this but so we're
gonna filter out on common hashes again
and I'm going to use that terrible hack
because it's all I have but it's
actually not a bad query um one of the
other things you can filter on it
so this is not a commercial but I'm just
gonna say it because I'm sure some of
you have recognized it now CrowdStrike
in their data will actually label the
virus total detection counts for a hash
they will only alert you if it hits a
certain threshold this makes sense
because some stuff you know if it hits
one probably isn't you probably don't
want that to fire to glass all the time
but particularly if you're doing hunting
maybe that's something you want to look
at so you can add a filter for the virus
total account using this query or
whatever you have in your environment
you could you know query against
virustotal and then use that as an
optional filter to help get rid of some
false positives one of the other things
that malware does to hide itself and
this is true in Windows as well is
orphan orphaned processes this is super
cool um this is crowd strikes process
tree thing and you can tell that these
look well when I looked at them I could
tell that they looked abnormal because
this is not the first process on the
system launch D is the first process on
the system everything that happens on
the Mac should come down from there
these sort of floating out in the middle
of nowhere that's not how a legitimate
process should look unless you have data
missing but this is not how legitimate
processes look so can we find that using
our data and it turns out you can
basically what you do is again this
query looks complicated but it's not
it's not all that complicated all we're
doing is looking at parent records and
joining them to child records and if the
parent doesn't exist call yourself an
orphan and here we go this is double
Rober and you see that on the bottom I
am an orphan
the tag I gave it in this query here now
to be precise what this query does is it
looks for parent records in the same
timeframe as the child record right if
you have a long-running process like say
an inventory control system that has
kicked something off and it started 10
hours ago and your query is only
covering 10 minutes you're gonna get
false positives here and that's why you
might need to filter some stuff out but
this is a pretty cool thing to be able
to look for your through your process
data for all right um if you want to
find orphan processes for one host yeah
I know this one's kind of unholy - and
I'm gonna skip over some of the details
because I'm running low on time uh but
this is how you can find them for one
host and these are some of the things I
had to filter out so like application
support the redacted stuff is internal
yeah and I promise these will be
released so you do not need to take all
this down in your notes so this was
actually pretty good right here our
orphan um yeah here our orphan processes
that we found there were some false
positives but it's not bad you know with
some research you could make this a lot
better if we add duration and that's the
duration of the process and look at
virustotal account it gets a lot better
so this is the this is the query running
and on one host looking for orphan
processes and here's what we came up
with all right so that's the end of my
queries I hope I didn't overwhelm
everyone too much I will be releasing
all that text so um so now let's talk
about just some experiment wrap up this
is what was good about this experiment
the network setup was isolated which
means I didn't have to have a big lab it
talked out on this cell phone connection
the way this particular process
monitoring solution works the fact that
I was sending data out to the central
monitoring server did not name a
specific company or person because lots
of companies use that monitoring server
there were no VMS to detect because
there was no virtualized virtualization
involved and the process monitoring
solution made things easy
mostly what was not great about this
experiment um
malware has been known to change its
behavior but based on sensing
CrowdStrike
so any of the malware samples Iran was
looking for that they would have changed
their behavior using hardware does make
experiments longer because your reset
time takes longer because of that I had
to run multiple samples per experiment
which wasn't great but you could mostly
sort things out because of the process
trees some of these samples failed to
run now keep in mind I had one piece of
hardware running one version of the OS
with one configuration right some of
this code only infects Firefox some of
it was meant to run on a different
architecture or a different version of
the OS none of those are going to run so
here are some improvements that I
thought would be fun to investigate you
could configure a slug cluster
especially for this so you don't run
into so many memory constraints using
look lookup tables instead of joins
would be more efficient if you have some
filtering steps that you can't build
into the queries there is an API for
spunk or elk or whatever sim I'm sure
you're using so you could automate those
steps you can use math I talked a little
bit about summary searches and this last
one I haven't looked at at all but I
think would be really fun to look at
it's the equivalent of permissions on
your phone but they exist in the
operating system as well on the
Macintosh laptops there's an
entitlements database it's basically the
apps saying these are the things I ought
to be able to do and if you were to do a
survey of all the apps in your
environment and what they say they ought
to be able to do it
might yield some interesting results all
right so this is the full index of all
the queries and I don't have much time
left but I just want to wrap up by
saying I really want somebody in this
audience or somebody watching this
recording eventually to do more research
and to make me look bad and then to tell
me about it because I would love to see
more done on this topic and if you're
doing interesting things please let me
know um yeah also I was not here to talk
to myself for 45 minutes so that anyone
has questions I will take them now all
right cool um you can also find me later
it asking questions in large public
forums is intimidating
[Applause]