hey welcome to my talk it's whatever
whatever Internet Explorer does what it
wants after seeing some of the
presentations here this week
I think I could have changed it to just
another HD a talk but uh you'll see that
coming out my name is Aaron hi kleh I've
been an IT professional about ten years
or so I've been with targeted for three
years there's an incident handler I
worked on the response team there I
investigated cases and alerts and see
what's going on I really like PowerShell
as anywhere that knows me probably knows
that I like forensics and Microsoft
products I specialize in those a little
bit of a disclaimer if you use any of
the information from this talk I'm not
responsible for you breaking your
environment
hopefully I give you some good
comprehensive info so that you can
actually do something useful with it and
I represent myself so this is just a
quick summary of kind of what led me to
this talk we were encountering some
issues at Target with HDA Docs and even
though we had put some defense in depth
with the with our blocking we were still
seeing alerts coming in and so I
investigated to figure out why we were
still getting alerts so that's pretty
quick and simple so I'll cover what an
HT a document is why we actually care
about HJ documents a little bit on how
you might hunt for HTA's and how you'll
want to block them because they're bad
so first an eight how many of you know
what an HT a document is all right it's
a decent number of people an HJ is an
HTML application that's what the HJ
stands for it runs with a binary called
MSHDA that's Microsoft HTML application
the normally HTML only runs in the
context of a browser so it doesn't have
access to system resources it can't run
PowerShell or vbscript or anything on
the host and that's important because if
you're browsing the web and all of a
sudden they could start detonating
PowerShell on your host it's a little
bit of a security concern so the MSHA
app
allows the fusion of an HTML GUI with
the underlying system resources on a
host and so MSHDA is a fully trusted
application that provides the access and
like I said it's vbscript jscript
powershell and javascript and really
anything on the host is accessible for
these applications a lot of people use
HTA's to make like dashboards and other
things or sis admin tools so why do we
care about HJ Docs
well HKS are standard on all windows
systems the MSHA is there and if you
double-click an HG doc it will
automatically launch with MSHDA that's
way more attack surface than even like a
word doc or something like that because
it is on every system a lot of users are
unfamiliar with what an HG a doc is so
if they see this HJ presented to them as
a malicious lure or something like that
there they might click it just because
they don't know what it is and they
might not be afraid of it because they
just don't know HDS are extremely
powerful as I've been saying they have
access to all the system resources
they're very sneaky who thought it was a
good idea for you to be able to launch
an HT a document without a taskbar icon
or a window but they made it that way
as you'll see an example coming up and
then the MS HD binary itself you can
feed it a remote URL so it'll actually
reach out to the cloud and detonate the
HD a document and that's just even
crazier and then due to the trusted
nature of the binary it bypasses
AppLocker most of the time so a lot of
pen testers and bad guys use it because
it'll always work here's an example of
an HT a document I use for some testing
highlighted I have the start with
Windows minimized and without a taskbar
icon so if you ran this it would just it
be in task manager and that'd be the
only way you could actually see this as
running on the system so if a user
accidentally runs it they're never even
going to shut it off because they don't
even know what happened with it the
example here is just downloading a page
from Google and then it's saving it to
disk
to fancy but if you combine it with the
second example here I'm doing a similar
thing I'm actually not hiding or I'm not
hiding in this one but uh this is using
WMI to detonate calc on the machine so
with the two you could download a file
and down detonate the malware and they'd
be completely hidden
so ETA documents are really versatile
for attack lures the bad guys can send
them as email attachments that's a
common method that's been seen they can
be used as drive-by downloads
that's like malvert izing or exploit
kits can be used to download the HD a
document and then sometimes on a rare
occasion you'll see it embedded in like
a word doc macro or something so the
initial malware might use the MSHDA to
download an additional HD a document and
gain further functionality have you guys
seen the attack matrix a lot of people
know what it is I think more more people
are familiar with it now a lot of talks
and stuff are bringing it up if you're
not really familiar I don't know if you
can see it very well because it's small
but uh it's attacker techniques and
they're all mapped to different
categories or phases of the attacker
kind of lifecycle and so each J's are so
prevalent they earn their own spot on
this matrix if you ever are curious
about figuring out what bad guys do just
go to the tag matrix and start clicking
through the different items if you go in
they'll give you examples of how it's
used how to mitigate it how to detect
and hunt for it and then they also
provide real-world examples and
whitepapers at the bottom it's kind of
like Wikipedia you know go to the
sources and start reading what they're
talking about so in the real world a lot
of people have been seeing using the MS
HTA or hga documents as an exploit fin 7
is a financially motivated threat group
they they've been seeing utilizing it
latent bot is a really sneaky malware
it's been around for a while not a lot
of people know what's up with that but
that's been seen using MSHDA muddy
waters an Iranian group and they use it
and then pen testers love it if you went
to Dave Kennedy's keynote talk he
mentioned how
he uses MSHDA in his unicorn framework
he's got the ability to generate random
HTA documents and lures and then there's
culture the msi sack that's a
multi-state information sharing analysis
Center claims that over 50 percent of
the malware they've seen this year from
all the organizations they've gathered
from over fifty percent have been Kufner
infections so this is a really prevalent
malware it's all over the place it might
be in your organization or in somebody
who knows organization or on their home
computers and so Kufner utilizes the HTA
document Kufner has been seen doing
fishing and malvert izing malvert icings
when they might go and watch a like a
pirate sports stream or something kind
of nefarious and the an ad will pop
before the stream saying oh you need to
update your Flash Player to watch this
and so it presents a screen just like
that it's a very real looking Adobe
update screen and so a lot of people
will go oh yeah I need to update my
Flash Player so I can watch this illegal
stream I want to watch and as you can
see it has Flash Player HTA most users
don't know what that is and just want to
update and watch the stream so other
popular sites also had the malvert izing
Forbes Facebook Skype Spotify all kinds
of these popular sites all serve up the
comforter malware and so it's also a
file of malware and once it infects the
computer it resides in the registry so
antivirus has a really hard time
detecting and cleaning it I've seen a
lot of coveter infections where the
machine will be infected for months and
it'll be a really old Kufner campaign
and maybe six months later finally the
antivirus will be like oh I guess that's
a bad file and so it detects the dropper
but the computers still infected and has
been infected for a long time so a lot
of people might not really think that
Kufner is a really threatening malware
because its primary role is to perform
click fraud and click frauds where it'll
download advertisements and then click
and generate
Avenue for the attacker and so people
don't really consider it a mainstream
threat even though it is very prolific
and infecting you know over 50% of the
malware cases so it has full rack
capability though so it can download
additional modules and get additional
functionality on the fly and this would
happen potentially if an attacker
realizes that the rat has landed on like
a important organization or government
computer and I don't want that to be my
organization and I don't want it to be
your organization either so I think it's
kind of important the there's a few ways
we can hump for HTA's we can look for
inbound attachments in our email systems
you could see if people have received a
chaise recently you can watch for HTS to
be downloaded in the proxy logs and then
you can also stack the MSHDA processes
if you're not doing this this is one of
the most effective ways to hunt for
things you stack the event execution
processes from the entire environment
you forward them to some kind of like
elk stack or Splunk and then you're able
to observe things like the parent-child
associations specifically in this case
Kufner would detonate PowerShell from
the MS HTA process and so you can very
clearly see that in the process
execution logs and that would be a very
big indication that either Kufner or
some other malware was executing on its
system you could also look at the file
names for the execution the file names
could be like Flash Player HTA or a
really random string if you saw in Dave
Kennedy sock
he was generating random strings for his
names and you could also look for it to
be reaching out to remote URLs to
detonate the HTA files so there's some
very basic blocks that people will often
put in the first one is to set the file
Association for the HT a doc they'll set
it to open with something like notepad
instead of the default MSHDA program
and you would want to also filter
inbound emails and make sure that HJs
aren't just being sent to your users and
then blocking at the proxy is also a
really effective way to mitigate the
HTA's because like I said some malware
could use the remote URL feature to
download additional payloads to the
system and so if you block it at the
proxy it'll also mitigate those kinds of
activities because the under command
line with MSHDA
if you feed it the URL and you
explicitly call MSHDA that will bypass
the file association that's occurring
and you want to push out these changes
via SCCM most of you if you're running
Windows will have the configuration
manager to deploy the configurations to
the environment there's a default
setting in GPO that you can use to set
the file associations on all the
computers so defense-in-depth is really
important the issue that I saw was we
had it configured so that no pad would
open the HDA documents but I was still
seeing Kufner infections and things
coming into the network and we didn't
understand I I knew those shouldn't be
happening because if the user opens the
hga document it should just pop in
notepad and nothing should happen so the
question was why why were we seeing an
alert for further down in the kill chain
that should have been mitigated higher
up and so I as a good analyst I went and
performed remote root cause analysis and
I could see that the files that were
being detonated were downloading to a
temporary internet cache and then
executing from the temporary internet
cache so I was able to come up with the
assumption that the open instead of save
function and Internet Explorer was being
used to execute the files so the that
allowed me to then replicate the
activity I went and found an HT a that
was sitting on the internet that I knew
was benign and I actually went and
detonated it
Leon a machine I clicked open and it
worked and I was like oh so that's
definitely what's happening in this case
but I didn't really understand why for a
long time I had to look around quite a
bit and do a lot of research and
eventually I came across what's called
the mime type database or many of you
familiar with mime types let's do some
Oh
so the mime type is the multi-purpose
internet mail extension program yeah
yeah yeah multi-purpose internet mail
extensions the the mime type is
typically thought of being used with
SMTP standards but really HTTP or any
network communication protocol will
follow like the mime type RFC s and in
this case Internet Explorer respect to
this mime type database in registry
there you can see what the registry key
structure looks like this is under the H
key classes root hive and so normally
you would think it would save the file
to disk for HTA's and then use the file
Association that's said in registry but
in when you click open it treats it like
a live web document and so it chooses
the application based on a different
registry so here's a little bit what it
looks like I queried the application HT
a and that points you to a class ID and
that class ID is a gooood that then you
can query and you can see how it's still
configured to detonate MSHDA
and you think it'd be this simple right
but there's actually more to kind of
like because we could change this key
now in addition to setting the file
Association and that would block the
additional behavior but you also need to
be sure to block it in the 64-bit or
this is actually the 32 bit hive within
Windows so you want to make sure you
change both
about it so ultimately if you can if
your organization isn't using MSHDA for
anything legitimate you'd want to lock
it down using app Locker or the software
restriction policies you have to be kind
of careful with this because there are
some underlying systems that might be
using the MSHDA like I'm Windows 10
there's some weird subsystems so you'd
want to be really careful when deploying
those configurations but this is by far
the best method if you can really
restrict and prevent anything that's not
supposed to be using MSHDA so you know
make sure that nobody in your company is
using it in large organizations that
often be somebody somewhere using it
that's it questions that's the Microsoft
HTML application so MSHDA is a native
binary within system 32 that is used to
execute right you can see the path there
it's actually in two locations there too
because a 32-bit application will run
under the SIS while 64 and then on a
64-bit system the system 32 MSHDA will
be used say it again the that HTA oh so
H key classes Roo is a set of all the
classes on a system that are defined so
I don't have an example of right now but
so there's many types of classes on a
system that they're all different types
in programming that are defined and so
HTA is both a
yes so within the classes route drive
which has a general set of classes
there's actually the subset of the mime
type and so this mind database is
special set of information within the
general class definitions yeah well and
and so this is an association so when
the application identifies oh it's this
type of mind I need to use these types
of applications to open it and it
creates that Association so it knows
where to go on disk to launch the
application yeah and there's several if
you look within this this path there's
actually a ton of applications therefore
like if it was a Windows Media File it
would download it and go oh I should
open with Windows Media Player or
something like that yes or well
technically with mime it would be a mime
type it doesn't respect the extension so
if the HTTP connection when you download
it the connection will actually have a
mime type defined within it and so you
could have different you could have a
dot txt but still provided with a mime
type and so it would respect the mime
type over the file Association yeah yeah
the file extensions can be yeah
depending on the situation they're
pretty ignored or useless cool any other
questions there's a lot of ways you
could do that you could train them to
launch it on the command line it's kind
of iffy you could create batch files
that would automatically type the
command line so they just double-click a
batch file instead of the document
itself
you could also depending on the scenario
provide entitlements where they could a
lot be allowed unrestricted access to
MSHDA so there's a lot of different ways
depending on your business processes
that you could configure it any other
questions
oh it depends whether or not you're
doing SSL intercept with your proxy
would highly recommend performing that a
lot of main proxies will do that like
Bluecoat will perform different
inspection like that for you you first
Nick I have not done that kind of
research yet but I would think that
maybe edge would do something like this
I think Skype or maybe Spotify because
the apps I think are seeing watching
those kinds of things as well and so I
setting the configuration here would
definitely mitigate those additional
applications because they'll do the same
mime type lookup in the registry and
then you already have it mitigated when
it goes oh I'm gonna resolve and still
open with no pad instead of something
else
so there's a lot of sis admin tools
sometimes developers will just make
something custom where oh it's really
easy I know HTML so I'm gonna write an
HTML front-end for this tool instead of
doing something that's more complex or
using like a different library to
generate their forms um and then
sometimes developers will facilitate
like a normal business process where
they make a dashboard or something that
automatically queries a whole bunch of
information from the network and then
presents it on the screen any other
questions all right thank you
[Applause]