um alright hello everyone my name is
Luke Corsica my presentation is nowhere
to hide a look at Network forensics so a
little bit about me I'm a native to
Jackson Michigan I live right here in
the area I work for an energy company
they didn't specifically sponsor my talk
so I don't want to say who but I'd work
for an energy company in Michigan I do
mostly system administration system
engineering type work I don't work in
security i working on servers and that
kind of fun stuff so it forensics is a
hobby of mine i like memory forensics
network forensics and malware analysis
so i all this is just stuff i've learned
on my own time this is something i do at
work so i'm by no means an expert on the
subject so this is the reason i says i
want you to take this with a grain of
salt it's not like I've perfected this
at a company doing work this is more
just my own interest so if you were
looking to do this at your company I can
give you some good information but it's
not gonna be the well all you know total
solution and for the pictures on there
the polish symbol there is my Twitter
picture so if you want to look me up
they'll help you find me a little easier
a couple quick disclaimers I am not
endorsing any of the tools software
organizations etc involved in this the
tools are just the ones I like to use
they're not the only tools available I'm
not supporting anything in particular
scenario was something I made myself I
set up all the files it's not based on
any organization real life occurrence
any famous hacks or anything any
similarity to any actual person
organization event it's purely
coincidental I made up the name of the
company I just random so if there is
actually a company out there at that
name I apologize though it's not my
intent and finally all the ideas
opinions etc are my own and should not
be considered that of my
employer so Network forensics what is it
Network forensics is this is a lot of
different ways to define it I personally
like to think of it just as observing
network traffic to determine what
occurred on that network so you might
have a capture my look at it live
captures the easiest way to do it and
you're just gonna look at the traffic
determine who talked to who why were
they talking to what where they send in
what were they doing there are some
subcategories that gets broken into this
is more academic he doesn't really apply
to actually doing it
protocol analysis is looking at the
individual protocols and the the numbers
of data that represent different parts
of the individual protocols so like HTTP
you know is it a git command as a post
command what's happening within that
specific protocol to determine what's
going on packet analysis looks more at
the packet as a whole including IP
addresses MAC addresses size that kind
of thing and then flow analysis is the
conversation who's talking to who where
is the data going volume of data is one
person sending a lot of stuff to much
people is that one-on-one is it a lot of
data one-way not a lot the other
direction is it back and forth this is
sporadic that kind of thing that kind of
gives you a good idea of what's
occurring on the network who is why are
they talking to who and what type of
data might they be sending how do you do
it you generally you have to have
there's a couple tools that need the
tools to do different things first you
have to be able to capture the network
data Wireshark TCP dump are great for
that there's a lot of tools so I'm not
trying to focus on these necessarily but
you just have to capture the data so
that you can look at it then you
actually have to look at it need to
analyze why your sharks again a good
tool for that network miner is really
handy and there there's a lot of tools
out there so this is not meant to be you
know an actual list just some examples
they make specialized tools so there's a
cool people in this industry to work on
this so things like TCP flow TCP extract
TCP extract automatically carves files
from TCP streams so that was pretty cool
there's a there's endless endless number
of tools so if you're interested you
know this github is a good place to look
at him and local tools on systems
involved can sometimes be useful if you
need to you know you can ping something
some of the inner like traceroute do not
always best to use if you're trying not
to mess with the data that's occurring
if you don't want to interact directly
with the traffic but like netstat you
can listen to you can see what they're
listening to ARP tables you can also get
local logs from like switches routers
those kind of things and then access
logs like on your network or exchange
logs can also be very handy even though
it's not it's specifically a network
related thing and finally some non
network tools like hex editors is a good
example we're actually gonna use that an
example today and the techniques on how
one big piece of advice that can say is
to know the protocols you know it when
you just start out you're really you're
not going to know them very well you
have to kind of start looking into it
but books on like TCP how it works
Wikipedia gives you a good breakdown of
how the protocols themselves and then to
just get some network traffic and look
at it and then just study how the
protocols work so you understand when
you're looking at it what's that normal
what's supposed to be there and that
gives you a good understanding of how it
operates and choosing the right tools
important you want to pick one that
works for you so just because Wireshark
it's a big one that's very popular but
that might not be something that's
really useful to you and other than that
it's basically just looking at the data
and try to determine what it does so
most people I'm sure here familiar with
encryption I just wanted to do a quick
review because it's important to
Network forensics in the sense of if
it's encrypted you can't look at it
encryption is very useful for security I
like having my stuff encrypted when I
send it but it's really hard to you know
it's impossible to look at data let's
encrypt didn't understand that but there
are ways around it
because there's a difference between
like one-way ask to sell and two-way SSL
one way as to self you have a private
key of the exchange you can decrypt it
and like a lot of tools have plugins or
they're designed to do that and you can
decrypt the traffic and look at it two
ways the different story
even if you have a key SEC at hand you
can do it after the fact it does that's
the way it works and it's really handy
the key exchanges matter - like RSA
there's a specific couple RSA exchanges
that can be decrypted within one way as
a cell if it's diffie-hellman you're
done but that makes proxies really
useful and this is where like if you're
gonna do if you want to do a forensic
investigations at a company proxies are
really useful you can set up a network
proxy then decrypt the SSL you can
either have that out put it to the side
as decrypted or like in the example I
did I set it up so that the
communication between the proxy and the
internal hosts is one way as to cell
that's decrypt a ball but the two-way
SSL occurs on the internet so that way
you can intercept the traffic determine
what it's doing and then it's still
secure going through public segments so
most this talk is gonna be a live demo
hopefully the demo gods liked the
sacrifice I made hopefully this goes
well but so here's a quick scenario that
I made up and we're gonna go through it
Cydia is Fred an employee at solid water
solutions has shown some behavior
recently that made his employer
concerned he might be unhappy at work he
has access to the company secret recipe
and some recent suspicious activity
makes them think that he's trying to
steal the company's data as Network
investigator you've been tasked to
examine what never examined the traffic
and determine what he's been up to
it's a quick piece of information going
forward they gave us in this scenario we
have Fred's
MAC address their local LAN is 192.168
to 17.0 / 24 the Gateway is dot 254 and
it's running an SSL decryption proxy the
certificate running on that proxy the
key has been given to us and for the
sake of this scenario 192 168 137 0/24
will represent the Internet
because I didn't want like actual public
Ivies going through this so we're gonna
and then in the scenario a combination
of access logs and video surveillance
has already shown that Fred was at his
desk logged into his computer so they
know everything going on from Fred's
computer unless there was malware was
Fred himself
it's gonna pull up wireshark
and there's a lot of traffic to go
through but so one of the first things
you want to do when you're investigating
is to look for anomalies so one thing
that stands out with the icmp paying is
the length of this packet is 176 bytes
normally it should be about 74 76 so
that's abnormal and so we might want to
take a look at why is that larger than
it it should be and if we look at the
actual raw data or see some ASCII text
included in the data segment seems to
spell out a little bit of a message so
says hey shady dealer its Fred I'll do
the deal the company secret recipe for
the agreed 250,000 I'm uploading it to
your site now so right off this doesn't
look good for Fred he's mentioning his
name it came from his computer if we go
back out here we can look there you can
match his MAC address to the one they
provided for us so it's zero zero zero
see twenty nine Phoebe six for FC if we
look right here the source hardware
address matches so we can confirm that
was Fred's PC and they've already
confirm for us he was logged in so he
sent this parent message in a ICMP ping
to someone addressed as shady dealer
who's obviously a law-abiding citizen so
that's not looking too good for Fred but
we can't prove
that he did anything wrong yeah other
than message this person and perhaps
this 192 168 137 139 which is on the
Internet and the scenario that could be
we could check see if that's a
blacklisted IP is he talking to someone
shouldn't be so the next step will be to
follow a little bit more onto this
communication so if we go down here we
see now we've got some SSL traffic or
TLS and technically so they're
communicating and if we go down into the
actual data it's encrypted
all the data is encrypted there's no way
for us to actually see what he's looking
at unfortunately they're running a proxy
and they provided us the key and
Wireshark has a handy built-in plugin -
or it's built into their preferences
um protocols we can actually decrypt it
so if you go to start this over so you
can if you want to follow along so if if
you're going to do this at home under
Wireshark if you go to edit go down to
preferences select open up protocols and
then just find SSL and then Horace's RSA
key list again this is only applies to
RSA key exchange so if it was another
like diffie-hellman key exchange it's
not going to work as well go to edit and
then this is one that I was using
through the CTF so also if you do the
CTF CTF three one three it actually is a
challenge that works very similar to
this so yes
it's not okay is that good all right so
if you click the plus button it'll add a
new one and so we'll need the IP address
and I generally prefer to go with the
the web server in this kind of
environment because then it's easier to
pick the the port because they're going
to use a the web server is going to be
using default 443 but the client is
going to pick a random port so one 92168
137 139 or it's gonna be 443 protocol
and this is the protocol it's going to
decode into so in typical SSL or TLS
it's going to go to http content so if
this was like FTP over SSL you would
need to specify FTP here so it's the the
protocol it's being translated into the
key file and there's two ways to get
this if you use like Anna you can
actually use like a dot P 12 certificate
but then you'll have to specify a
password because the P 12s are secured
with a password but a key file generally
has no password so we don't have to put
anything in here and a note if you're
gonna do this especially at a company
that password is stored in Wireshark in
plain text so if I would recommend if
you're going to use an actual production
cert that you would want to only put
this in here when you're doing
investigations and then remove it
otherwise it'll be stored in plain text
and that can
ruining your day so once we apply that
Wireshark will go through and decrypt
our stuff and now we have clear text
HTTP packets we can look at so that'll
give us now we can actually see what's
going on so we see a get request the
Fred specie is reaching out to the web
server and requesting a testing a
website and they got it okay
there's also apparently a picture but
according to this traffic it's not found
so through whatever picture was actually
didn't load not that that's significant
but it's you in other scenarios that
might be important depending on what
type of traffic that they're doing what
they're looking at so a really good way
to get a good grasp of what's going on
here is to follow just that stream so if
you go to Wireshark you can follow the
SSL stream and it also brings up this
thing of the data itself that we're
looking at and so if we want to find out
what Fred's doing we can look at this a
bit closer but we really want to know is
did he steal any data from the company
and in order to prove that we're gonna
actually have to get that data to
present to the companies that hey is
this the information that you're worried
about losing so like even just a file
name it's probably not gonna be enough
for like incriminating evidence so if we
go through this data here we can
actually get the file itself so the good
way to do that is to we can save this
file and as a file and you want to make
sure you do it in a raw format because
if you it translates the Wireshark
automatically translates stuff into
whatever format it picks so if it's an
ASCII code and you save it off as an
ASCII then when you try to open the
action
file that'll already have translated
into ascii code so if it's a text file
it'll we're great you can just pull the
data and it'll work fine but if it's an
actual like if it's an image or an
executable or a video or any other type
of file like that then it'll have
translated ascii and then you can't
reload it as an actual file it'll have
corrupted the code so there's a show and
save text thing down here in the corner
and you want to specify that too raw and
it doesn't look like anything here but
this is the actual raw data of the file
itself and another thing to know is this
is the two sides of the conversation so
this is the red up here is from Fred's
PC going this way the blue is everything
that came back and so on actually in
this case we can even see the web page
itself because that's just in direct
ASCII that's not any kind of special
format so if we want we can even pull
this and look at the website that Fred
saw
drop this on the desktop here save it as
HTML
and so this is the webpage that Fred
visited so it's up at the top the name
displays in the tab is digital back
alley which doesn't sound particularly
legitimate and the page is pretty empty
just to select an image to upload with
the choose file button and then can
upload whatever file that you uploaded
and as we noted earlier the picture
doesn't actually show up which if it had
showed up in the webpage then we would
have to carve that file out as well
and to put in the same folder as the new
webpage that we just saved off in order
to actually see it and even that
depending on how they coded their
website might not work because it might
be looking for a specific location
instead of the location of the site
stored in but this is the website Fred
saw so that's more evidence that Fred's
not necessarily behaving because this
website doesn't look very legitimate one
fun thing you can also if you want to
start digging through the like this is
more of the protocol analysis side you
can go through the HTTP code and
determine like what user agent was being
used to look at this so this is Mozilla
so Firefox information about the host
and then you can also see like what the
web servers like in this case they're
running high a 7.5 so this hacker
website is not very secure themselves
but there's this lot of information and
one of the things about Network
forensics is like all forensics there's
a lot of data to go through and you have
to figure out what's important to you so
when you're doing an investigation
information you wanna you want to have a
list of like so like dirty words with
dirty values of stuff you're looking for
so you know as does this contain this
person's name does it contain this IP
address does it contain this file name
because this particular file is a I made
it for this presentation and it's 182
packets and then this is not all
communication between Fred and the
server in an actual environment I'm sure
you know most of you have seen and it
could be hundreds of thousands of
packets in a minute so you can't just
scroll through it and find necessarily
find where you're looking for very
easily because there's gonna be way too
much traffic to sort through so you
really have to get that's when you start
searching for keywords and phrases which
Wireshark does have a fine packet option
you can specify a hex value that would
be in this data part down here as
various expressions string is one
that'll pull up information from the
info tab so you could search for get and
it will find all of the packets that
have get in the info tab which is it's
the basic information of what Wireshark
could find about the packet itself
so now that we have this data stream and
we've already found the website see if
we can actually find some the file that
the company's worried about losing so
they provided us with what they're
specifically concerned about is their
secret recipe which they gave us a copy
of so we'll be able to compare once we
find it the file that Fred may or may
not have done anything with and compare
it and before we do this another thing
you might search for is you know if say
like if a keyword if we used post
command because of its HTTP stream and
we can check and see if he sent anything
which there's one here and so there's a
post command of uploaded there was a
file uploaded so that might be our level
of concern that there's a file uploaded
so maybe Fred actually did do something
so we can save this and it's raw data so
it's not actually gonna have a file
extension which is I'm sure windows
won't appreciate it but
[Music]
so now we have a file stream and this is
where I like a hex editor is going to
come in because this is just raw binary
data so if we try to open this in
something else it's not gonna like it
we're not gonna be able to see anything
so I typically use the blest hex editor
from working on like a Linux box because
that's that's my favorite hex editor but
I couldn't find a copy for Windows so I
had to use coincidentally Fred as my hex
editor and a hex editor basically is
broken into two main pans there's Thor 3
there's the byte offset the actual bytes
shown in hexadecimal and then an ASCII
representation on the side and so this
is helpful for finding where you need to
get to to actually start carving the
data so part of the knowing protocols
does get taken away a little bit if
depending on the tool you use because
Wireshark is really good showcasing
areas that where the different protocols
interact and there's tons of protocols
already loaded into a Wireshark it tells
you where everything goes and so on the
post command it'll show you where your
file itself is and the boundaries
between them and also when we look at
this section here it says oh there's
also a file name see if your company
recipe dat DLC X which is the name of
the file that they gave us so starting
to look bad for this company and then it
shows that it's a compressed zip file
which you may or may not know docx files
are actually zip files at the heart of
it so it's more evidence that an actual
DLC X file was uploaded
so this is and then if you notice here
in the the hex part is that this says PK
this is the header signal for a zip file
so this is where the file actually
starts is right here so we can look at
the bytes at the side here and the
offset and determine where to start
carving
so really we find we find the matching
spot here and then Wireshark will
mention the different all the different
stuff like encapsulation protocols and
wanna so it'll say here you can also
notice it's Mima format and a typical
sine of M IME is that starts of files
are noted by this sequence of 0d 0a 0d
0a so it's another good way to find it
if if you're doing this like by hand
through data that you capture maybe
through TC tcp dump and you don't have
access to wire sharks information on
where different stuff is within the data
stream so that's again where like that
knowing the protocols thing is really
handy if you know you know that a miami
specifies with this segment then that's
definitely helpful so everything that
came before that is not the file so we
have to carve all that out and so to
start there and then we now we just need
to find the end of the file
and again Wireshark comes to the rescue
so there's a 0d0 a followed by 2d fairly
repetitively
so that that's something that shouldn't
be too hard to find once we get near the
bottom
absolutely it is so this is all stuff
that came after the file in the data
stream so we cut that away now this is
the part where this is going to go wrong
it's going to go wrong right now so
we'll just name this file captured and
it will rename it do CX fire it up and
see what looks like and so we've got top
secret recipe for companies only and
there's their secret recipe for ice
that's solid water solutions so now we
can compare this to the one they gave us
looks pretty much the same so there's a
indication that so this is pretty much
right here pretty solid of that it was
the company's recipe we can take you two
step further and hash these
so you zoom in here this is our shot 256
and we'll just look at the last couple
yell 7b to zero and that's the one we
captured I think I just closed magnifier
if I could spell here we go
so 7b to zero so this is in fact the
same file so yes did Fred steal company
information we can say the answer is in
fact yes
it's not so great for the company but we
can successfully proved by the you know
this process of finding out what Fred's
doing decrypt to the traffic carve the
files can prove that Fred did in fact
steal this file from the company so for
Network forensics is pretty useful in
that sense that there are a lot there
are other ways like memory forensics can
probably give you a pretty similar
picture of what happened but this is a
really good way to indicate this traffic
did go through our network went out to
the Internet you know some what there's
response back from the web server and we
can tell that this file fact we can
following the stream mersive post they
sent back in okay HTTP okay which means
they receive the file
so whatever malicious site this is that
file actually was uploaded to it and we
can prove what file it was and so a
quick no on the some techniques you're
speaking of hashes when you're working
in network forensics it's really
important to make sure you don't are any
forensics make sure you don't disturb
the actual data files so you might we
common practice is to save a copy of
like say the packet capture and then
hash it and that way you can when you do
your investigation you can hash the file
the one you worked on and compare it to
the hash of the original improve that
the file was not the file was not
altered and the data was not altered so
in terms of a criminal investigation
it's extremely important that the file
not the data not be changed
because then they could you know that's
evidence is now dismissible because you
could have altered it
so there we go so did Fred take the file
yes he did that's unfortunate for the
company but it's good for us we did our
job that's pretty much all I have if you
have any questions I'm happy to take
those there's a couple of resources if
you're interested kind of some stuff
that got me started forensics contest
comm is a great resource they have a lot
of practice scenarios you can do that's
how I started then the the other one on
here is just a source of there's a lot
of pcap files I recently discovered this
I'm eager to look into them but they've
got tons and tons of pcap files of a
bunch of different scenarios where
there's you know malware involved web
traffic there's some from some like
cyber defense competitions on there so
it's a lot of interesting stuff and then
at Lucas Corsica that's me on Twitter
again the the Polish Falcon is my
Twitter picture so help you find me a
little easier but that's pretty much all
I have so does does anyone have any
questions yes
they're something that they're getting
rid of that so something Fred could have
to make your job harder
yeah so the question was aside from you
know trying to avoid the proxy is there
anything that Fred could have done to
avoid detection and this is a lot of
things this is a very simple basic
analysis like for example if you try and
avoid detection I probably wouldn't try
to hide a plaintext message in an ICMP
thing but that actually though is a
viable exfiltration method people views
so you kind of depends some obviously
like if if the shady dealer did his due
diligence then he probably would have
set up a better method of getting the
file or Fred could have encrypted the
file and then sent it in which case it
would be a lot harder for us to get
unless he sent the password through the
same data stream so there's a lot of
stuff you can do to hide your tracks
this is kind of more of a simple setup
but yeah there's a lot more you can do
let's answer your question any other
questions
all right well thank you