okay go ahead the applause after I've
been talking for now Adrienne are we
good cool everyone's out there
so we're talking today about impostor
syndrome as the talk title implies but
first stuff I guess you might want to
know who I am what I've been up to I am
an Illinois state licensed pharmacy
technician anyone else any pharmacy
techs here every now and then I'll get
one and it's like let's hang out so I
went to college on music scholarships
because that was really the only way I
was gonna be able to swing it and I was
secretly studying pharmaceutical
sciences while I was there because that
was my real goal but when you go to
college on a scholarship you have to
like take X number of courses related to
or some of that actually requires a
major in whatever the scholarship was
for so you have to pretend like that's
why you actually want to go when in fact
it's like I'm not gonna get anywhere
with music have you you know I think
there's like you can be like a teacher
and that's about the extent of it
because I wasn't good at composition
like there was no way that I was gonna
be able to like actually make money
doing any of this myself and I just
imposter syndrome my life out of being a
musician so I was expelled from college
after being sued by a partner of the
college who produced the student IDs for
them and I didn't know that was the
thing but in the you know the terms the
service for the school if if you get on
the bad side of any of their partner
companies they have the right to just
boot you out and I had signed signed off
on that and it it happened after I
irresponsibly disclosed some terrible
things that the student ID company was
doing with people's private data
literally posting flyers around the
school they didn't like that and they
tried to sue me for slander which is not
what I was doing because of what I was
revealing was things that were true and
actually happened but in the American
legal system
if whoever has the most money is who
wins
and I did not have the most money
compared to a corporation with major
universities as partners and so that
ruined my life possibly forever as I
paid that settlement off so in the
meantime I was working I worked in
managed a computer repair center Micro
Center you guys got a micro center here
at the Detroit yeah so yeah it was a man
I was a manager at at for seven years of
the age of 23 like anyone I like
talk about imposter syndrome like make a
23 year old a manager and like make make
them have to do like P&L reports and
employee reviews when most of your
employees are older than them and have
to write people up have to determinate
peoples and languages it was a bad scene
be responsible for other people's
actions because you're a manager and
have to like answer to what messed up
crap Frank did
I'm 23 like I was still riding my bike
around for fun what's cool is you
there's a gap in your life where that's
not cool to do and then if you come back
on it again like that probably 30 or
something and then you're just a cyclist
and you get to wear tight pants again
and it's fine so this is during that
time when it wasn't cool
I was a systems engineer night at a nice
easy asset recycling company which was
pretty much a hey man this job I had a
buddy who worked there and I was like
hey give me a give me a job where you
work because he was making an insane
amount of money doing nothing and I was
like I got to get in on this and it end
up being at this recycling company that
would taken IT equipment and recycle it
we would audit it for does it work does
not work if it works does it have any
value we'll sell it if it doesn't have
any value will recycle it and that got
really boring really fast I ended up
teaching myself mainframe hardware
administration by way of just needing to
be able o hard at all this mainframe
equipment that would come up and they
would be like well you're the smart IT
guys all this crap goes into your pod
and then go I don't I don't
I don't I don't know what this is and
they're like what you better find out
and and I did and so that is really cool
so I know a lot of main four mainframe
hardware interface stuff I don't know
anything else about mainframe but I did
learn shell scripting by way of that
because we also would have like oceans
of these mainframe hard drives we'd have
to wipe and the company's current plan
was like well it's you just got to do
them one at a time man
and I'm like no like if I have a whole
like six racks that can hold hard drives
why wouldn't I use all of these to wipe
hard drives and they're like we don't
have anything for that so I had to learn
it and write all that I eventually
started doing other things to help out
around the facility just out of sheer
boredom and lack of work to do which
ended up in mead automating a ton of
their processes including that one and I
saved that company about 700,000 dollars
annually just based off of the
automation processes I developed and
allow them to not employ as many people
which is like that's a weird thing like
I've I've added people out of jobs and
really they say like that's what a good
engineer does is it puts himself out of
a job but like I put I put a lot of
people out of jobs because I mean they
really weren't necessary like there's no
reason you have to have 20 people doing
one hard drive at a time that doesn't
make any sense but I developed a lot of
systems for automating the actual like
diagnostic and and also like secure
ratio of just PC systems and things like
that and I learned it all myself just
just out of sheer boredom and I was
there for a couple of years doing that
eventually they built they built a new
warehouse and they needed someone to
manage all the network infrastructure as
in like create it and in which which
meant garbage pick it because we didn't
buy anything they're like we're an IT s
a recycler so it's literally like oh we
need I need a couple of more switches to
feed this new line we're building
they're like well let's hope they show
up
and it was really weird like you
couldn't get money for anything there
because yeah so anyway I I was like this
isn't getting me anywhere like I this is
I didn't feel like this was real
experience like I didn't feel like these
were resume worthy things that I was
doing I thought that I was scraping
around faking B and I being an IT admin
or a systems engineer just so they
wouldn't fire me like I'm literally here
going I have no idea what I'm doing but
like we're just gonna keep doing this
but like is is that true if I'm like if
I have like like objective metrics I can
judge that against and go look I
developed a robust resilient system that
allowed that saved us seven hundred
thousand dollars this year for a small
business like that's an insane amount of
money for a small business I realized
for some of you that's like a joke that
was a big deal
and so in the meantime I was like I got
to get out of here but I'm in this like
I thought I was in this dead-end
situation and so is like well I got a I
was I had been convinced that if I got
my CCNA I'd be able to get a job as a
network at admin somewhere which may
have been the case at the time and but
like a CCNA course it was a few thousand
dollars and so what I was doing the
meantime was I was garbage picking the
things that they would throw out that
were defective and that they deemed not
worth the time to repair and so they
would just get recycled and I was like
well I'll take these and then you get a
stack of like you know these old Cisco
routers and eventually you're gonna get
enough parts to make one work and like
you know what all used Cisco router
sells for a lot of money I don't know
who's buying these things because like
you know your company isn't going on
Craigslist and buy-in routers you know
some of you may think that's where they
came from because of how they operate
and how old they are but I ended up
fence and a bunch of Cisco stuff and
ironically using that to pay for my CCNA
class and certification which didn't end
up getting me a network admin job I got
laid off from the previous job because
they managed that company into the
ground somehow I ended up being
unemployed for about eight months more
or less voluntarily like that's when I
was taking my CCNA classes but the rest
of the time I was just kind of sucking
up my Obama
and seeing what life is gonna take me I
got an offer to be an InfoSec engineer
after talking with this guy who I played
board games with every month like we had
a board game night at a friend's house
and I never bothered to ask any of these
people like what do you do for work like
I wouldn't bring up work and that was my
bad like I wasn't using these
non-business related events for
networking because why would I
that doesn't make any sense but had I
brought this up like six months prior
the guy would have been like hey we're
looking for InfoSec engineers and
literally I can find out about that
because he called my roommate at the
time and said hey man we're really
desperate we've been looking for 18
months to fill this position do you know
anybody who's generally knowledgeable
and IT infrastructure but might really
be into like hacking on the side might
be just like generally into the hacking
scene and has kind of like a passion for
that and my roommate is like Johnny and
also you know him and then the guy it
was like I had no idea he did any of
that stuff and so I showed it the board
game night that night and I was like hey
and that guy he's like yeah we talked
forever and I'm like yeah man I've been
dude hacking for like I went to hope and
y2k and I've been speaking at
conferences since 2003 and like I never
told anybody this stuff because I didn't
think anybody cared like certainly the
people in the warehouse job didn't care
that I was going to hacking conferences
they probably wouldn't have liked it to
begin with well this guy's like oh man
you're exactly what we need like general
IT knowledge and you're really
interested in the hacking scene because
that's what we're like doing here so
they gave me a job there's an
information security engineer for a
fortune 500 company and that was that
was crazy because I'm managing
effectively like IDS's in in
distribution centers in China and like
then that's important and every day
there I was like oh man I have no idea
what I'm doing like this is gonna be
terrible like every time I had a meeting
with my boss I was like he's gonna fire
me I'm gonna get fired I keep letting
this stuff slip I cut out the entire
company's internet four times in my time
they're like like that I mean like top
down like nobody who could get to the
Internet
yeah and that was yeah and I had you
know some nice talking to with my boss
about it and that was the end of it
I was they promoted me to senior in 18
months they brought me in as a junior
with no prior experience promoted me to
senior with 18 months because I was
doing consistent senior level work and
they and they you know they go to HR
like we need a senior headcount and they
know what we can't do that said what we
got this guy he's a junior but he's
doing all the senior level work right
now can we just promote him to senior
and they're like well no that position
requires 5 years experience and I had
been there for 18 months at the time and
they're like he's doing all of the work
really well it's like we can't morally
allow him to keep doing this work
without promoting him to the level for
which that work is is you know made for
and so I that went all the way up to our
VP of security in general who reports
the decease oh and he fought for me to
get promoted to senior because of that
because I was doing senior level work
and that's how it goes and that was
probably the point where I learned that
job requirements are not set in stone
even things like this you see a lot of
five years experience and we'll talk
about this a little bit later but like
none of those are set in stone if
somebody's like really thinks you're
good for the role they'll go to bat for
you and that was insane and it's not
like he was a friend or that I knew him
that well it was that that was the right
thing to do and they did it and it was
awesome
I think my favorite thing that I did
there was I I spearheaded a cultural
shift in IT to take InfoSec near the
InfoSec team from being this like hated
evil organization that just tells
everybody no to being an organization
that they know that they need to work
with and is more compromising and
willing to help them help us help them
call it a kind of situation and just by
way of being a nice person to people at
work it's amazing how many people are
willing to work with you and accept
you say no because they like you and it
had nothing to do with you know I didn't
have to go to them and prove my
technical knowledge I you know in some
cases it was impossible when they're
fighting with me like why do I have to
put endpoint protection on our servers
tell me just shoot me the numbers on how
much malware you've caught on our
servers just like tell me how much has
it been any goat loans zero we've never
caught any ever and they're like alright
so you want me to run this stuff that
sucks up literally all of the resources
on all of my servers so you can do
nothing why would I do this and they
know they have to they know it's partly
that we were a PCI compliant shop like
they knew is required but they're
fighting with us about it and eventually
like once I got the shift rolling it was
more of a like okay I get it
we'll do it you know they didn't they
don't like it but they should stop
fighting with you and they get back to
work and it's really great and so like
they credited me with a lot with that
which I which I thought was pretty cool
then from there that I mean that that
place got bought out we all lost our
jobs and I moved on to be a penetration
tester slash InfoSec consultant after
only like four years experience as a
security engineer now I'm a pen tester
with the did I had no experience as a
pen tester I got hired as a penetration
tester well why one I knew how to do a
lot of the tests that penetration
testers do by way of being a blue team
er you know what you're doing as a blue
team er should be doing is running the
same tools that penetration testers are
running you should be performing the
same acts same activity so that you're
generating your i/o CS and your KPIs to
be able to give to your tools to catch
it when a real malicious attacker comes
like there's there's like the whole
concept of like red team blue team is
kind of weird like as far as
organizations ago because you shall be
doing well the blue teamers should be
doing the same things that the red
teamers are doing you just have a red
team order that does it full-time
but as the defensive engineer or even
just a sock worker you should understand
how these attacks work and be able to
execute them so that you can better
build defenses against them like how
else are you gonna do that that's the
only way and so I got to be a
penetration tester oh and then I was I
had continued to do my own little
research on the side or at work and
presented conferences and I'll actually
what at this point what I started doing
at conferences a lot was just doing
career based talks like this one where I
said like hey man
I found this weird backdoor in InfoSec
let me tell you how I did it and it was
through a lot of just talking to people
and learning things on my own that I
thought you know weren't important but
it actually turned out to be and so this
company that was very community focused
and like to hire members of the
community who were productive and gave
back said hey man you're awesome
everybody knows you now why don't you
come be a penetration tester for us I
said I don't know how to be a
penetration tester and then like the guy
who was hiring me it was a friend that I
had known from conferences for years and
he says you do I talk to you about it
all the time
like hey how can you say this all right
and then it turned out I was pretty good
at it I focused primarily on medical and
financial verticals which means I robbed
banks all day I don't like to say around
hospitals cuz it's it's not a great
sentence you know I did but like you
don't brag about that what do you do for
work oh man I just rob hospitals blind
yeah right take all that candy for the
baby ward
their candy budget what I transfer their
budget out is what I do transfer that 15
mil but I could say rob banks and that's
cool and that's a fun thing to do at
nine InfoSec cons like what do you do
I'm a bank robber
I literally break into and like
digitally transfer funds out of banks
and so I did that for a few years and
got really bored because penetration
testing gets boring you get burnt out
especially if you're doing the same
thing at every client which
unfortunately you are because you're all
terrible and you're all terrible in the
same ways and I mean you as an your
company ascend it I mean do you tell
them a little upset you'd go to a new
company and you would run the same
attacks and they would all be successful
and you give them the same 70 page
report be like you got to fix these 70
things I'll see you in two years because
it's gonna take you that long and then
they'd never call you back so I like I
kind of got bored and at one point an
old friend slash guy I've really wanted
to work for since since I'd I'd met him
Nick Percoco hit me up on Twitter
I got a Twitter DM for the
to get this current job is literally
literally a job offer via Twitter DM
that was hey man we're opening up some
more research positions at our company
do you want to come here and be a
security researcher with us and I'm like
I was going I was about to get on stage
somewhere else to present and I'm just
checking my Twitter and this DM comes in
and like yeah yeah and so I had to give
this presentation while I'm like super
excited about this opportunity just
happened and it was really weird
and so now I'm an industrial control
systems security researcher which is a
completely different field I asked this
a while ago when the room is more sports
anyone else you're working in ICS yeah
it's like this bunch of are you I know
where you're at
are you at the in the power vertical as
well yeah okay cool a lot of energy I
mean you got consumers sponsoring the
joint so makes sense yeah and so like
that's a completely different world like
these things they don't a lot of these
things don't speak tcp/ip like you're
dealing with separate protocols and
you're still trying to do information
security in this realm that doesn't even
speak a language you've seen before with
operating systems you've never seen
before like real-time operating systems
you're literally you're like trying to
secure robotic arms and like keep them
from killing people like safety is one
of your number what number one concerns
when you're dealing with the cyber
security in this realm and that's really
weird because I mean you know and they
and the IT side like safety is is it's
pretty darn low like it's hard to kill
somebody with a with a four you server
unless you're throwing it at them it's
really easy to kill people with like a
you know a 450 killed transformer so my
general day-to-day is discovering Oh
days in industrial systems I focus
heavily on the rail and you know rail
infrastructure but we do power
generation we do mining we do
manufacturing we do oil and gas like
pretty much anything that because that
considers itself industrial where we're
screwing with these equipment and
finding the O'Day's and working with the
manufacturers in mitre to get CVS to get
patches out but that's really only half
the problem because patching in the ICS
realm is its own issue and then the
other thing we're doing is we're using
all the data to develop an IDs
specifically for the industrial realm
that speaks these protocols that does
behavioral analysis that is also
signature based for stuff that's
attacking these protocols which doesn't
really exist yet
and so that's that's how I do now and
this holds like I like this is a career
change I mean like I said like I see s
the security that's like it how cool is
this thing I didn't know anything about
it most people don't know anything about
it like you guys who work in ot like how
often you have trouble just talking to
IT guys about like making them
understand even like how these things
operating how they communicate and how
you can't you can't do a ping sweep
against these in for this infrastructure
you're gonna kill everything or make it
do weird things if you point necessary
like weird bad things so like I don't
know anything about that I have no idea
what I'm doing right now that worked
like no idea and yet like Nick and
company said hey we want to pay you a
bunch of money to do this because you
know we know you're gonna be really good
at it how can you know that I think oh
well like you've been really good at
other stuff and I'm like it's unrelated
and they're like this is absolute you
absolutely related and so like like i
daily suffer with this problem like I
have no idea what I'm doing like I'm a
dog with a bunch of science equipment
like I've got all this stuff here and
every now and something works but I
think like I have no idea what I'm doing
it so that's that's pretty much what
we're gonna be talking about here today
as as the title implies I'm like yeah
you know you're an impostor but you have
to get back to work and I'm gonna get
who knows who this is help here on the
screen this is Vincent adult 'men and he
is he has two kids in a trench coat and
he goes to work every day and I feel
like a lot of us are him and we don't
appreciate that I feel like we're afraid
of this and like I really feel like we
need to embrace it I'm gonna get on that
a little bit later let's let's talk
about imposter syndrome get on the same
page of what exactly it is first off
imposter syndrome is not a mental
illness it's it's not recognized by
DSM as as a mental condition that can be
diagnosed and treated it's not real it's
something we colloquially invented a
name to describe a condition that nearly
everybody actually feels and oh and I
should point out I when I was creating
putting this talk together I did I
worked with a psychologist really
closely to figure out why we feel this
way why we they do this to ourselves and
what we can do to make it better and so
there's a lot of really cool insights
it's actually really easy and fun but I
needed to point out that like this is
not just like some guy who doesn't know
what he's doing telling you guys to just
the ears I used to lead your lives
actually did work with a with a
psychologist to come up with some solid
reasoning and like literally what does
she do
to help people in her office get through
these things because I know a lot of us
don't want to go to therapists and it
will cover that later too but I wanted
at least be able to put the information
in your hands so that like you have
something actionable you can do on a
daily basis to help you with these
problems that you have so like imposter
it's a person who pretends to be someone
else in order to deceive others
especially for fraudulent gain and I
think that's probably none of us like
this is a good way to tell if you
actually are impostor like are you
intentionally going out and deceiving
people for personal gain like do you
have a job where you don't know 100% of
everything you're doing and you
intentionally went there because you're
like I'm gonna scan this company man I'm
gonna get them to pay me until they
figure it out and then I'm gonna bust
out of here and do it again those people
exist for sure I hope none of them are
here but if you if that's what you're up
to
yeah you're an imposter that's stop it
that's what you do in that case is you
knock it off
and then syndrome a characteristic
combination of opinions emotions or
behavior and it took me a while to
figure out like what's one of those one
of those things because it's really just
like I feel like an impostor but we got
into I got into it with the psychologist
of like well there's a lot of causes
there's a lot of underlying causes that
put us in this situation to begin with
and here they are I'm gonna walk through
but first I wanted to dynamically build
a presentation that for you guys that
are here at converge and b-sides that's
going to directly address the concerns
that you guys had and so who saw the
index cards who was here for converge
the past day two days yeah most to you
right so I had a bunch of index cards
over my reg where I said like hey what's
your what's your imposter syndrome
trigger like what's the one thing that
makes you just like feel that like
gut-wrenching like anxiety sweating fear
of like oh man I'm gonna oh man I'm
fired today I am the worst why am I even
here and so I got man I got over 60 of
those and some of them were definitely
troll cards but I mean it's gonna happen
and we'll talk about that later we're
gonna have a talk and I was able to
average a lot of them down to a handful
of concerns and they're like obviously I
could stand up here six hours and talk
about this and never be done I'm like
all right I gotta narrow this down so
we're gonna narrow down to a like
career-focused
imposter syndrome triggers I should have
said that up at reg because I got some
man a lot of people are concerned with
penmanship like really like I got
penmanship a lot up there and I'm like
wow I never even thought of that
but here's like the main things that you
guys told me and then last night Tim
diblock Cate Vita can tell you I was up
till 4:00 or ish in the morning and
waking up in the middle of night and
even adding more things to this thing
because I like I wrote this last night
because that was just a personal
challenge to myself is like I wanted to
write a dynamic talk for a conference
based on feedback from like the day
before and crank this out and so I wrote
this yesterday for you guys this is
besides Detroit only here's what you
guys told me you're in leadership
positions and feel like you have no
right to be there which I feel is like
totally understandable like I think it's
almost odd to feel like I should be
telling everyone what to do like there's
a right way to feel
in your position but then there's like
the weird presidential thing where
you're like I am the person who should
run this country's I just feel like
anyone who like would say that out loud
should just be in prison like you hold
your presidential debate and then you
just arrest everybody and you put them
in a mental home because it's crazy like
I don't like anyway you do not have the
knowledge or skills level necessary to
do your job effectively again this is
these are things that you feel most of
these just simply aren't true this that
one really resonated for me as I was
like literally building warehouses of
automated systems and telling myself I'm
me and I have no idea what I'm doing
they're gonna find out let me just get
these other two warehouses designed and
built and then I can get out of here but
I don't know what I'm doing people call
you experts because you did a thing a
couple of times successfully I think
that probably happens who works in
InfoSec here currently how many are you
of you referred to internally or maybe
even backed by family members of what
have you is like gurus experts and you
have maybe a tenuous grasp on what
whatever the conversation even is like
how many people get asked about
cryptocurrency because you work at
InfoSec and what I what even you know I
talk a lot about cryptocurrency because
I traded a bunch and that's just trading
that's like I read this thing's low and
it's probably gonna go up so I'm gonna
buy that I've no I like I don't know
what the it's even going on behind the
scenes I go it's Johnny's a crypto
currency expert man you got to talk to
him and I get crypto questions all the
time and I'm like buy low sell high
you don't work as hard as your coworkers
and are thus overpaid for what little
you do this is a feeling you have you
like look at everybody else and they're
busting their asses and you're kind of
you feel like you're coasting like
you're not trying as hard and thus like
the amount you're paid is ridiculous and
you fear that your company is gonna
figure that out and be like why are we
paying this person so much to do nothing
when in some cases like your passion
goes a long way for making you not feel
like you're actually putting forth a lot
of work but when you like measure out
the time you spent on whatever it is
you're working on it's probably more
than most people and invest in their job
this was a big one you out right do not
apply for jobs because you arbitrarily
decide you're unqualified or you took
the requirements literally so many
people do this one they look at job
requirements on a website and they'll go
now
unqualified I don't have that one line
on there I don't have I only have two
years of my sequel experience instead of
three so well guess I can't apply guess
nobody wants to hire me anywhere I'm
garbage it's like no like that's not
your job
it's their job to tell you you're
unqualified space shooter a resume like
you're not companies have to hire
somebody and it could be you like they
just they're gonna hire the best
possible person they can find and we're
gonna talk about that in a bit like
that's something I'm really passionate
about because I've been doing these
career talks forever and then finally
like a lot of you are like really
concerned about your penmanship to the
point where it gives you impostor
syndrome and it like I laughed at it at
first - it seems wacky because when do
we even write anything like almost never
whiteboarding sessions yes and more like
more than three people wrote that like a
cig the statistically significant number
like I'm worried that once people see my
handwriting they're going to think I'm
stupid and I think I am stupid
handwriting obvious
birds to admit it but we did a we were
doing a podcast last night in my room
with Tim Duloc who was anyone listen to
the exploring Information Security
podcast that's cool thanks guys
hey there is I have drop in your podcast
name that's Tim hands up for Tim this
podcast so we were recording a podcast
in my room last night at least trying to
with like 12 people or something and the
one of the first things we did like the
penmanship Kate thing came up and we
passed around a notepad and we all wrote
a sentence on this notepad and as soon
as I had written that and had to pass
this over to somebody else who was then
going to look at it
this fear immediately set in of like oh
they're gonna see my horrible
handwriting and think I'm dumb and I
immediately understood so like everybody
was laughing right it sentence and pass
it to somebody next to you and just be
like what do you think of my handwriting
is you won't even do it you're gonna be
like no I'm gonna do that it and so then
I totally gotten like wow that's a real
thing that I didn't even think of which
a lot of the cards were honestly but
this was like the statistically
significant gist and so then I put
together some stuff to try and help us
through all of this and try and get it
down to like under an hour which this
unfortunately it won't because I've
never been able to do anything in under
an hour
because even though I'm supposed to be
this professional speaker who goes all
over the place and does keynotes like
crazy I can't even stay within the
timeframe that I have timeframe that
I've designated I am the worst I go over
every time I write that off as being a
bad presenter am i doing a bad job yeah
you can tell me it's cool Tim thinks so
but and I'm trying to wake up because I
did like I said I was up til five making
this talk for you guys so like there's a
lot of secondary what I called secondary
jerks and these are the jerks that are
in your guy's brains that are like just
being jerks to you like when you're
trying to get work done and there's this
jerk in the back of your head just being
a jerk and these are like the kind of
the things that happen to us in our life
that really spawn these jerks that cause
these jerks to exist in be jerks one of
the big ones is just a history of odor
over-critical adults and peers
house to do carrots have been trying to
do that this is really fun we've got
this this this history of like over
critical adults and peers and like who's
like who's had a life of people just
constantly telling them that their
stuffs not good enough for being are
just bullying them telling them the
stuff that they're into is dumb picking
on them for not liking sports like I get
that one all the times still at work
like there's this weird like IT thing
we're like when you're starting out
nobody likes sports and then is emu like
the further you move up in your career
the more people you're surrounded by
like sports and and you hit this point
really like why am I being bullied again
when I'm like thirty about oh maybe you
like football so like this is a thing
and it's not just like we're not just
bullied in school like a lot of us are
bullied our entire lives like our whole
careers
we're being bullied at work that's
ridiculous and it's a thing that
constantly happens like so like what
causes as bullying sometimes it's just
like it's people that are actually
fearful of you it's people who feel
threatened by how much you know maybe
how fast you're coming through the ranks
at your company and it causes this
visceral response where they want to
bring you down to slow you down because
they're worried you might put them out
of a job because they have imposter
syndrome too like we we as human beings
are terrible at being able to see
anything outside of our own you know
perception because that's how perception
works but we don't realize like this
dude who's being a jerk to me can also
be like having the same problem you know
he thinks he's an impostor - and now
here's me who knows like one thing he
doesn't know and all of a sudden I'm a
threat to his job which is crazy like
some of them just worked really hard to
get there like really busted their asses
and then here you come through because
you're just really passionate that
you've been doing like you actually been
busting your ass - but maybe you don't
feel like it and you come in and you
have all this new knowledge that's
applicable and you're you know you're 12
years old to them
and they've been around for 50 and
they're like it was this kid coming in
here you don't know what I've seen
you haven't been where I've been and
you're like they're just gonna be
extremely over-critical sometimes just
because you because you're young
sometimes cuz you're old like ageism is
absolutely a thing and that was what a
lot of the cards asked about too and I
just don't have the time to address the
actual social problems I'm like ageism
and like you know the gender problems
that are going on there absolutely very
real and I saw I had at least keep this
talk down to like the things that we at
least just generated inside of ourselves
and so like just these generally
inappropriately over critical people
picking on you can can cause us to
really feel like they're right
especially if it's somebody who has a
lot more experience like why wouldn't
you believe them why wouldn't you
believe this guy who's been there for
twenty years is gonna be like Mandy this
is this is garbage you got to do better
even they might be right but if they're
constantly picking on you and you're
succeeding and the things you're making
are working and they're working the way
they're intended and they're getting the
job done you got to take that criticism
with a grain of salt I had a lot of
people write a lot of troll note cards
like a lot and put them up there just
generally being dicks to me baby because
of what I was doing and like and I saw
that and like oh they're like they're so
threatened by their own behinds just
their own impostor syndrome or by the
fact that like somebody's calling it out
I don't know but they like they wrote a
lot of jerk cards and threw them up
they're like ah forget this guy like
who's this guy like they're mad at me
for trying to help people like that like
sets off something in their brain we're
like and it's because maybe they don't
feel like they're helping people enough
and like that's something that's super
easily rectified there is no end of like
things you can do out there to help
people like jeez and it was funny
because some of those you'd see the same
handwriting and all these cards and it
would start off with like really
obviously trolling on people being dicks
and then like it migrates to like they
start actually writing serious things
and things that bother them and it's the
same handwriting like I know it was the
same person it starts up with like three
jokes
and then it's like I've only been at my
job for four months and I feel like I'm
gonna get fired any day now because I
haven't had a review and I think that
they're just waiting to get enough
ammunition to get rid of me and it's
like the same handwriting as the person
was like Oh people named Johnny who
tweet at me give me impostor syndrome
yeah the the support role paradox this
this is the you guys gonna love this one
everyone knows the support role paradox
that's the one where if if you're if
you're working an IT and a support role
and everything works they think you
don't do anything what are you doing
everything's working oh we should lay
off some staff these guys must not do
anything but then like if everything if
one thing is broken they think you don't
do anything right
what are you guys doing why is this one
printer down what do you do all day and
it's like I called it the support
paradox cuz it's like you damned if you
do damned if you don't so all day are
just like being treated like you don't
do anything by people because they just
can't perceive what it is you actually
do especially man that's huge and
InfoSec we're like our whole job every
day is proving negatives like we have to
prove that we stopped the company from
being hacked and losing all of its money
and it's like how do you even do that
you can't like that's why it's so hard
for InfoSec to even get money it's
because like you're you can't prove that
you do anything and if you're trying to
work at InfoSec that's something you
need to like you just come to terms with
right out of the gate is that's
something that's just gonna always
happen and you have to find your ways to
know that you are actually doing
something beneficial InfoSec salaries
have increased faster than any other
field on earth in the past like since
2011 since the target breach effectively
that makes us feel really weird like
nothing multiplies imposter syndrome
like then also being given way more
money than you ever thought you would
make in the entirety of all of your life
which it's like might be a low number we
a lot of us never thought we would be
making this much for something we really
loved doing so when you combine
something you really love to doing that
doesn't feel like work like even you
like
going to work every day and doing it you
like going home and doing it you don't
feel like you're working combine that
with the fact that you keep getting this
paycheck for a lot of money like doctor
level money people the money for people
who save lives
some of us more than doctor money and
you're not even saving lives it's real
easy to be like what are you doing like
I should not morally be accepting this
money this is terrible like I'm not this
good and like it makes sense that I
understand this coming from but it's not
your job to figure out we were supposed
to be paid your company probably has
somebody whose job it is to figure out
what you're supposed to be paid they
probably put a lot of effort in figuring
that out because they want to pay you as
little as possible because that's how
profit margins work oh yeah what who
stopped shopping at Target after 2011
though nobody low candidate counts
there's not enough of us who here works
in hiring candidates for InfoSec that's
more than I expected you don't really
have your pick of the litter do you know
you're stuck with like whoever shows up
right because he's like you can only
leave that position open for so long but
if you're like I got I got it have a
warm body in here I at least gotta have
somebody doing something it's better
than the 18 months of nothing we've had
that also means that we're getting
promoted faster like when they need
leadership you know who they when they
have nobody else in the company anywhere
near qualified to be leadership in that
role like some of us have been at
companies where like they put in they
took some director from somewhere else
and put them in charge of our team this
guy's no idea how InfoSec works at all
but he's a manager so it'll be fine put
him over here cuz we can't find any
InfoSec managers but in a lot of places
they're just promoting prematurely
they're like well you've been here for
24 months that's longer than anybody and
that team needs another manager we're
gonna go ahead and move you up and oh
man especially that's your first
management role which it is for a lot of
us of course you're gonna feel like you
have no idea what you're doing because
you don't what you kind of figure it out
you know you're gonna fumble your way
through all of the way the same way we
fumbled through like literally every
other skill we've ever
learned we're all bad at everything in
the you know to begin with and so you
just kind of you got to deal with it
I'll talk about dealing with it later
but then like good old-fashioned
depression like that's probably the
primary one and nowadays more than ever
depression is becoming less and less of
a strange mental illness and more of
just the natural part of the human
condition and a lot of that has to do
surprisingly with our access to other
people increasing at exponential levels
you know we there's a lot of different
kinds of depression you have like you
have your clinical depression which is
like very long-term it's just something
that you have your depression caused by
just chemical imbalances that has
nothing to do with you know your outside
influence is it just something wrong
going on inside your brain you have
depression caused by traumatic events
like there's so many different things
that can cause depression we always just
say depression and I'm depressed like
it's just one thing and it's like it's
this gargantuan realm that has so many
influences but one of the big ones now
is just like social media social media
is incredibly depressing and it is an
incredible amplifier of imposter
syndrome because it allows other people
that we know to I don't want to say
falsely but just talk up what they're up
to it allows them to present only their
best self and filter out all of the
daily mundane crap well you know nobody
it's rare you see anyone posting
pictures of like uh spilled coffee on my
shirt on the ride to work today I'm an
idiot and I have to look like this all
day you know though it's like no but
they're gonna post pictures of like you
know cool new outfit I bought to wear to
work like I've got a great new suit like
out there's some pictures of me in a
great suit I'm not gonna post pictures
of me then spilling coffee on it like
I'm never gonna tell anyone that
happened and so like we're surrounded by
these people that look to just be like
the just like the epitome of humans just
like this perfect society and then
here's us we can't brush our teeth
without getting toothpaste on our pants
and like and like we're starting our
days thinking we're idiots right out of
the gate when in fact like
everyone does that everyone spills
coffee on themselves
everybody gets toothpaste on their pants
everybody poops you know like I get like
I used to get I was the guy who would
wear like seats in vest everyone I
always tried to be like very well
dressed and I'm the like I would talk
about like hey here's how to be a better
presenter and people be like oh yeah but
you're just like naturally this better
presenter and like people don't want to
even like like me just being a good
presenter makes other people not want to
even bother because I'm like well not
gonna be that good so like so like I
came here my pajamas today and I didn't
do my hair cuz I just wanted to be like
look man I'm like a normal guy I didn't
sleep at all I'm exhausted just in my
pajamas I'm just some guy who's up here
talking about a thing that like
literally even I suffer from all the
time you know if I came up here in a
suit and my big white smile is like let
me tell you all what's wrong with you as
an authoritative figure you're not gonna
you're not gonna go for it then I'm just
some jerk up here in a suit he thinks
he's better than everyone or who you
think is better than everyone and you're
not gonna listen to me so it's like I'm
gonna get some cool pajamas and I had a
friend of mine who made me these pants
pretzel pants I don't know if you guys
could see these they're hilarious and I
love them they're super comfortable and
I honestly it's great being able to go
to keynote at 10:00 in the morning in
your PJs and I highly recommend it I'm
having a great time up here somebody is
there any water somebody bring me like a
glass of water or something
I'm sure thanks I mean cool thanks me at
least got bottled water locked and
loaded
that's my bad for not being prepared so
one of the big things that depression
does to us is it causes us to have this
like black-and-white thinking like I'm
gonna get fired I am the worst of my job
I suck at everything I should not be
here and like that's just not how the
world works like nothing is black and
white but man like you all know that I'm
not telling you anything you don't
already know like when you're in this
rut like especially if you're already in
a rut like a rut feeds rut like it's so
easy to just write everything off as
absolute garbage and be like oh man I
gotta just quit I should just go be
homeless
because I have no business being and
like it's funny but like a lot of us
that's crossed our minds and a lot of us
that crosses our minds all the time like
for me like I think it's a bunch of us
like it's cool talking around like a
bunch of us have been homeless for brief
periods and I I was homeless and it's
like that makes it easier because I can
be like I could well I know I can live
as a homeless person so like now in my
head that's a viable option what is that
how is that okay and it's we just get in
this black and white like everything is
garbage situation instead of like oh
well you know I screwed up this one
thing and here's what I learned from it
and I can work to improve you know etc
and we'll get into that later but it's
like when you when you feel is black and
white stuff coming on like you have to
recognize that you're doing it you know
you're doing it and sometimes we just
need to yell at a lot for a few minutes
and then it gets out of our system and
then we're fine again but it like that's
direct impostor syndrome is just the
like crazy black and white like well I'm
the worst everyone knows I'm the worst I
should kill myself and like while that
is a serious problem it's something
that's at least like so divisive that
you can recognize that it's a thing and
do something about it and like the doing
something comes along later so like
those are like the secondary jerks these
are the things that are kinda I'll
contribute a little bit or kind of a
bunch to what's causing this but then
there's like some primary jerks like
really three big primary jerks what is
called the Zeigarnik effect and I
realize that's a redundant use of the
word primary but that's something we
like to do this was created by a
psychologist who isn't Freud like check
that out there's other psychologists
besides Freud this is I believe luma
Bluma Zeigarnik she was Russian and this
is the thing that we all know about and
refused to remind ourselves of which is
how we remember failure and in just
generally incomplete tasks far better
than we remember any of our successes
and even when we remember successes
we're just remembering all of the like
failures that led up to them and how
hard it was and we don't but we don't
spin that in any kind of positive way so
like
one person put it as successes so is so
common in life that it's not something
we even register as worth remembering
whereas the failures are so rare that we
linger on them because they're unique
events and that's just a theory but it's
I bet its general each I know it's it's
generally true in my life and so like
that's a big thing that that like we we
love to get down on ourselves we we get
up every day and look at ourselves in
the mirror real close you know which you
brushing your teeth or whatever and like
we see all the flaws in our faces we see
the new wrinkles that show up the gray
hairs if we don't want them like I'm
excited I hope I look like wolf one day
like this amazing salt-and-pepper hair
it's just the best I'm getting there man
but like because we spend consider Lee
every waking and sleeping minute of the
day with ourselves we know every last
thing that we even just we think is
wrong some people don't want gray hair
and we think that's wrong even if like
other people think they look good with
it
and so like we're hyper focused on
ourselves because we see it all and do
it all we we forget that nobody else
sees us that much you know with like
they're not to paying that much
attention their own life is going on
they're really not paying that much
attention to you and in this case that's
pretty great like you don't want that
much attention on you we pay too much
attention to ourselves just by nature of
having to get up every day and look at
this mess like none of us I mean I don't
want to go around the room and consider
it but I would say most if not none of
us like we look like the people in the
magazines you know we don't look like
fitness models like do you know how hard
it is as a man to look like any of the
male fitness models you know what it
takes to maintain a six-pack post age 18
it's insane the diet you have to have is
is bonkers it's untenable you can't
sustain it and even one like you talk to
these Fitness people even when you look
at you look up actors who have to play
like superheroes in these movies and be
like what was that workout regimen go
read up on it they talk about it all the
time
life is miserable miserable but they're
making a lot of money for it and as soon
as they're done filming like they're
back to eating normal and like that
six-pack is gone you have to work out
like all day and you have to like mirror
what you eat and specific quantities and
specific types of things and it's just
gross protein shakes that taste like
dust it's a horrible life to look like
that and yet like we all want like
that's how we're presented is this is
how we should look and it's it's just
it's not realistic so like the
day-to-day none of us look like that and
you know what it's fine but because we
see that every day and we wish we looked
like that it's something we like
constantly could get down on ourselves
about um we don't we don't remember our
successes but we remember our failures
but we don't I said we don't put that
like a positive spin on them the
positive spin I'm thinking of is that
failures where we learn you know you you
don't learn a lot from succeeding you've
learned that what you did you did the
thing right and then you go got it and
then you move on whereas if you fail
like you have this huge opportunity to
figure out where did I fail what went
wrong why did it go wrong what should I
do next time to make it not fail can I
go back right now and fix it are we
talking about you know writing let's
talk coding am you're coding a program
writing a script can I go like that's
the best example of failure like how
many times have you compiled some code
and it didn't compile every probably
every time yeah that's a great
real-world example is like all right
well I failed because you did you wrote
that that's your failure but you're
gonna go back and you go all right where
is this where did I screw up and then
you're gonna find are you screwed up and
then like when you fix it do you forget
why it worked
are you like next time you come across
one you have to do that again are you
going to like fail again and be like all
right well let's figure out what wrong
are you gonna be like oh I screwed that
up last time now I know this time it has
to the semicolon has to go here you you
look at your failures and you take that
in and you fix it and then you remember
that fix and you and if you keep doing
this certain type of failure eventually
you come to know like oh this is
something I keep doing and you can focus
and be like
to be mindful of the fact that this is a
problem I have and focus on that and you
can learn from that and move on and then
you become better and you'll screw up at
something else beyond that and that's
fine because failure is where you learn
you want to fail and we just keep
getting down on ourselves every time we
fail because we didn't do it right the
Freak like no like there's no skill has
been done right the first time to any
expert level by anyone ever who here
plays a musical instrument guitar even
just like as a hobby like yeah lots of
people like how how horrible did that
instrument sound the first time you made
it make noise how much was it the who
played violin like how horrible who are
his kids who play violin like how
horrible is a novice violin player
that's the worst thing I can imagine but
everyone started sounding horrible at
violin or guitar like how hard is it
even on a guitar to push the strings
down hard enough to make it stop making
that buzzing noise it takes like a year
we're all bad at stuff out of the gate
but some of us realize the failures and
know we have to do to fix it and we
stick with it and then we get better and
then we're just garbage it's something
else and then then we just we just
repeat that cycle primary jerk number
two is Michael Phelps we all agree we
this thing we do we're like we're not
because we're not the best on earth at
our jobs that we're instantly -
motivated well why am I doing this thing
like I am not as good as the absolute
just the mere fact that I screwed
something up means I should be fired
like that's that's ridiculous
like doesn't that sound ridiculous when
somebody says it out loud and yet like
we all feel like I don't not all of us
but many of us feel like this all the
time you'll you'll you'll probably never
be the best like perfection the common
phrase like perfection is the enemy of
the good like if you want to be good at
something
setting perfection as the goal will mean
you will always you will never succeed
you'll never have success and you'll
feel terrible all the time
don't shoot for perfection shoot to
constantly be getting better and know
that you'll never achieve perfection but
you might get close the chances of you
being the best in the world at any
specific skill are one in about seven
billion right well then x numbers of
skills the math gets weird
so stop setting that as like as you're
like measurement for success that's
weird like you're not going to be
Michael Phelps Michael Phelps did not
think he was going to be Michael Phelps
and that's his name he and he visualized
it like if you look at Michael Phelps's
training regimen like and that's there's
no end of interviews on Michael Phelps
like whenever you're the best did
something how did how did you do that so
that I can do it too in a lot of his
workouts a lot of his training involved
visualization imagining himself winning
and they'll tell you like whenever I
started something like I imagined myself
being the first one there that line at
first it rarely happened but he kept
trying and eventually he ended up being
the best and that's just him and that's
how it works and if we all followed
Michael Phelps his training regimen
would we all be equally as good as him
probably not because there's a lot of
other swimmers that competed against him
that followed that same training regimen
that know all the things he knew that
visualized themselves winning too and
they weren't the best some of them are
the second-best one of them you know in
how many medals does he have like 18
that's insane
is being like the second best in the
world at something a horrible situation
no that's pretty freaking cool I knew a
silver medal skier once and he always
talked it down like yeah I only got the
silver I always hoped I was gonna get
that gold one day and I'm like what's
the matter with you
you are the second best person on this
earth at that that's insane
there's only one person who can beat you
and they only did it once but we just
love to like we'd love to feel like
imposters like he like literally said it
took silver medal and he was like I just
she's not good enough man
you know I'll go do something else and
he did it you know I don't know how you
can make money off of skiing I really I
didn't look into it I'm sure you can but
like he has a day job and stuff I was
like that was crazy to me how you can
call second place not good enough and
like obviously you'll probably never be
the second the best in the world at
anything I'm not I never will I don't
the mere act of ranking yourself is
weird but like that's what we do these
like in the context of work like you
think because you're not the best that
you shouldn't be doing this job or that
you're not on the top 10 you shouldn't
be doing this job
well then companies need somebody to do
this job and you might have been the
best they had at their disposal and yeah
you can spin that and be like oh it
means I'm not very good but like they
just they only took me because they had
to and as soon as they find someone
better they're gonna get rid of me but
that's probably not the case if a you're
a good cultural fit at that company and
they just like having you around and be
you're gonna fill in the gaps of what
you don't know because they're required
for your job like I personally I just
ran you through it like I've never taken
a job where I knew how to do every last
thing at that job who here has like I
don't think I've never met anyone who's
taken a job where they're like yep I
know how to do all of these things that
are gonna be part of my daily role no
problem I got this I wouldn't take that
job because hey that sounds like I'm not
gonna be learning anything and that's
bad that means that train that's
constantly coming up behind you is gonna
now run you over because you've stopped
learning beat it sounds boring as hell
like I don't want to go somewhere every
day where like I'm just doing stuff I
already know how to do like learning to
me is exciting I think everyone who is
here is here because learning is
generally exciting to them learning how
to do new things learning tricks of the
trade like that's what we come to these
because
like we just are of this kind of person
who loves to learn so we take jobs where
we don't know how to do everything and
we don't lie in the interview and say we
do that's called being an impostor
but we're honest about it you know we
might have ways of figuring it out you
know I mean we've all heard the like hey
man don't be afraid to say I don't know
in an interview but you should follow it
up with here's how I would find out and
don't just say Google it that gets you
not hired by me I hate that answer what
are you going to Google tell me your
search strings what leads you to what
led you to those search strings what do
you you know show me your thought
process for your research like go
through that with somebody you're gonna
blow their mind that's the best I don't
know but don't be afraid to not know
nobody knows and you're not the only
candidate that they're interviewing that
doesn't know I don't know if I would
hire somebody who like met all the
requirements explicitly I would think
that they're gonna get bored and leave
soon I don't know if I want to hire that
person because I don't want something to
come in for 12 months in bust-out then I
gotta go through all this again I want
someone's gonna enjoy the job and enjoy
learning and so if they enjoy learning
and they enjoy the job generally they're
gonna come in and they're gonna learn a
bunch and they're gonna be really good
because they're passionate and that's
what I look for I look for passion I
look for somebody who is a good cultural
fit with the team of course and then
somebody's passionate about the role to
begin with because I know not
everybody's gonna know everything and I
know the requirements I set out aren't
gonna be fulfilled by everyone i but we
love to just write ourselves off and be
like I don't know everything
they're gonna fire me that's ridiculous
that's just that's just just completely
ridiculous that's pretty much that
cool I didn't even have a look at the
car really for that one I'm getting good
at this I am NOT the best I'm nowhere
near the best I'm trying to do new
things as a presenter I'm trying to
create challenges for myself to Bush
myself to become better because it's
it's hard to learn where your faults are
as a presenter because generally like
what's the measurement of success did I
convey all the information I wanted to
yeah
well great like where did I fail well I
don't know like you rarely get feedback
from the audience because generally is
the audience your job is to sit still
and shut up and that's really easy to to
and so as long as everybody shut up I
guess and then like I mean you'll get
the situations the audience everybody
starts talking to each other looking at
their phones and things like that and I
can see all of that like that like you
know you're losing them and so like well
any of the secondary requirement of
being entertaining in that you know not
necessarily you know telling jokes and
dancing but excuse me keeping everyone
engaged and you have to modify what
you're talking about based on the room
and so I'm trying to make myself better
by giving myself challenges and one of
them was at Gurgaon last year I I said
I'm gonna do no slides I had no slide
deck I had some videos behind me and
then we watched like YouTube for a while
and went through Twitter and is really
cool and did it all it did I did it all
base self index cards it was amazing and
I had a lot of fun and I learned a lot
this time my challenge was like I'm
gonna generate a presentation the day
before based off of what the attendees
want to talk about and I did that and I
may not be super confident and extremely
knowledgeable and well polished up here
right now
because this is the first time I'm
running through this because while the
second time the first time I ran through
it was 4:30 a.m. just a few hours ago
and so I'm finding little kinks and this
and that I'll learn next time if I do
this like what not to do and I thought
that would be cool to do for you guys
just just just because of that just be
like hey look I screw up all the time
too like I'm not this like crazy well
polished guide trying to tell you how to
live your life when like you still put
the wrong shoe on the wrong foot
sometimes like we all do that I don't
know the last time I did that that might
be a bad example but yeah and where my
pyjamas would be like like I wear
pajamas too we we surround ourselves
with idols and I think like that's
that's a big one like we we we create
these golden cabs in our lives these
people that we worship that we think are
the most amazing people and I'll go back
to the slide in a second sometimes
there's just the loudest people
sometimes are the people that have the
most to
you know sometimes they're the the
funniest person the funniest presenter
at a conference we put these people that
we like on these pedestals that are so
high using metrics we invented just
assuming things that about them that
aren't you know just assuming they don't
poop when in fact it when at the same
time like we're ignoring everyone who's
around us that we should we ignore our
peers and compare ourselves to these
bizarre golden calves and I put myself
there as a joke because people do this
to me all the time like they assume I'm
like some God of the InfoSec world and
it's like half the time I don't know
what I'm doing
there's that one so like I kind of stole
this Venn diagram from Jason Street I
was originally gonna like completely
lift it off him directly but then I
started looking at the one he had and I
was like I don't think that's true we've
got the industry like this is your
InfoSec industry here this huge circle
imagine this is everybody working in
InfoSec this is everybody with an
InfoSec job gargantuan and then we've
got like the community down here the
community is not entirely people who
work in the industry who here does not
work directly in InfoSec right now a
good chunk of this room maybe I should
have moved the circle in a little
further but a ton of the community
doesn't even work in InfoSec and then
there's this overlap people who do work
in InfoSec and in our part of the
community that's such a tiny portion of
the people but these are the people
you're most you're most often coming
across this little sliver here and
that's you're comparing yourself to
you're comparing yourself to like this
like elevated group of people already
who are so passionate about what they do
that they want to do it as part of their
life and they want to do it with other
people they want to come to these
conferences so you've got all these
conferences all the time or if this is
your first one hopefully you'll go all
the time just to be around other people
who are as passionate about it as you
about passionately even just about
learning more about it that's such a
tiny like you don't see these people
these are the industry like those are
the people like punching at nine punched
out at five go home don't talk about it
at home don't talk about it with their
friends it's just a job and you know
they might do a good job and that's fine
but like you don't see them to compare
yourself to like you're already going a
step further than a majority of the
industry by coming to these conferences
especially these non vendor conferences
you know this non era say this non
blackhat these conferences where it's
really like the you're coming here just
to learn to pick up on things and you
know to network and meet some new people
in the community that you might be able
to do things with later and then like
way down here like this is just this is
the scene I called it the scene this is
the hackers this is the people releasing
the O'Day's this is the people doing the
crazy research a lot of us want to be
here and a lot of us think like oh if
I'm not finding O'Day's I am worthless
at my job like why am i bothering
working information security if I'm not
dropping O'Day's and like that's crazy
cuz like look how tiny that is compared
to like the community in the industry
and look how little the overlap is you
don't even see most of these people you
never interact with them and yet like
you're comparing you're calling yourself
a failure because you're not one of them
when it's like look at look at where
you're succeeding like look how great
you're doing there so I'm going way over
like I always do you guys are gonna miss
some Rick and Morty let me play his
little clip here who knows who this is
this is David Lee Roth and he is like
you have the old mic up there we go he's
like arguably one of like the greatest
front men and rock and roll history
right just like David Lee Roth when you
list like great front men you're like oh
man that's amazing David Lee Roth he's
the best I've got an isolated vocal
tract of his from running with the devil
y'all know runnin with the devil
I grabbed a little cup out of here it's
pretty great this is David Lee Roth
greatest frontman one of the most
amazing singers in rock history check it
out he you know that whistle means he
had that whistle with him in the vocal
booth that's weird like he's clearly
drunk he's got this gravely voice he's
cracking when he's singing and this is
like this is the take that's on the
album this is the one where they went
that's the best he's gonna do let's put
that on the album and wait and the point
is that they they engineer the crap out
of this they put all these effects they
put the backing vocals they cut the
whistle down a little bit and he just he
probably didn't tell them he was gonna
do that he probably wanted this booth
with this whistle and just like at that
point is a busted-out and blows it in
the mic and the guy in the engineering
booth is like
alright now I gotta fix that so like the
point here is like when you've got these
idols these people that are just doing
things that you're not doing and like
you just feel like crap because you
watch them they're like and I'm never
gonna try to find a way to humanize them
there's always a way especially the axis
we have the social media this is a great
man I love I'm a musician and so I look
at musicians and I like to humanize them
and I have a great story about Kirk
Hammett I was gonna tell but we were
totally out of time so I'm just gonna
real quick recap like things you can do
on your own to get get through this but
like isolated vocal tracks hilarious
lookup fail videos on YouTube like those
are the most Authority cathartic things
just watching people doing dumb crap
okie though there's kirk hammett so
here's some things we could do to help
ourselves with a backdrop of people from
infomercials doing the stupidest crap
you've ever seen in your life because
that's cathartic like even if like you
don't know the people like even if you
just need a little pick-me-up like if
you're just having a bad impostor
syndrome day go watch like the black and
white scenes from infomercials where
people don't know our shoelaces work or
ovens or going to bed
what Haven happen there I don't know
watch just fail compilations on YouTube
like yeah it's just like weird Schiedam
fraud real laughing at people who are
screwing up but like it at least will
get you back out of that rut so you can
like kind of move in with it move on
with your day like make sure you're
learning from your failures you know
make sure that when you fail you just
don't write it off as man I suck
I hope nobody finds out about this look
at what you did wrong fix it immediately
if you can well write down something
make notes to fix it going forward but
yeah make sure you are learning from the
failure and not just absorbing that
failure and putting it in your failure
pile until it's just overbearing and it
falls on top of you brushing your teeth
is so hard painting your grass I mean
we've all been there change your
definition of success
like if if if you're never succeeding
your your definition of success isn't
granular enough break it down
find the little successes in that path
and then when you do succeed now let's
go and here when you do succeed tell
yourself tell yourself out loud maybe
not like in public or like in your
office that might be embarrassing I get
it say it under your breath but tell
yourself you succeeded at that and tell
one other person tell another person
because that validates it even if the
success was dumb yeah I'm good through
min I know you can fight me and it's
that telling yourself and one other
person that really solidifies like in
your heart that you did something and it
fights that fear failure away get a
therapist like I know that's that's
really hard for people to do it's great
man like you don't have to have a mental
illness to have a therapist like mental
health is like going to therapists like
imagine having an hour of someone's time
we're like
wait lumber get me dressed oh man so I'm
getting I'm getting the boot
I'm getting my cards oh man I did
threaten so like hey I hope this is like
helpful to you guys was this useful did
you guys enjoy this yeah so thanks a lot
and the bottom line is like it's
actually the cheesy stuff that helps the
most we're just you're your own worst
enemy and so stop being your own worst
enemy
you know acknowledge when you succeed
learn from your failure look back at
yourself a year later and look how dumb
you used to be and how smart you are now
because we always vidiots and now we're
all really smart some things a lot guys
see you later