hello again our next speakers are
Martina and yos who will talk about
designing implants and payloads for
embedded devices give them a warm
welcome everybody thank you that you
came to our talk hopefully you will
learn something hopefully you will like
it so quick few words about ourselves I
am a senior security engineer I'm
specializing unoffensive security for
critical infrastructures and my focus is
physical damage or how to make something
blow up crash or go bad by the means of
cyberattacks yes right so my name is
Jose Wetzel's and I'm a principal
consultant and security researcher with
Sakura Dutch security company previously
known as Madison gurkha and my focus is
mainly embedded system security and ICS
automotive and IOT and a long time ago I
used to do research on critical
infrastructure at xx University so
during the talk you will understand why
to of asked him up together and how do
we basically house these two different
skills which we have there needed to
design an OTA payload basically so this
is the agenda we will be going through
all of these points and we start of
course from the introduction as always
so this is frequent flight first of my
slides like here's a plant what's your
plan so how exactly do we make this blow
up and there are two opinions going on
in the industry typically well it's easy
because look at this there is no
security in those industrial protocols
and sir
and the second opinions is it's
impossible it's all complex nobody has
that knowledge so and typically the
understanding about industrial control
system security is about that how hard
it is to get hack into the plant and
find a magic button so basically the
complexities are revolving around this
finding this magic button which you
present then the plant goes bad but the
point is that button does not exist you
actually have to design it and program
it so this is what we will be talking
about how do we
bad evil sinks to the chemical plants
and the point is that all the process so
every play Lord have to be very process
Pacific designed to specific plant and
it requires a good process comprehension
and through this talk you will see what
that exactly means process process
comprehension
yeah and in general it's a little bit
requires more knowledge and
consideration than simply it's not
enough to know what makes the pipe to
explored you need to know what makes the
right pipe to explore it explode and
what to makes right pipeline to explode
at the right moment so that you will get
that boom so it's not that is it
strategic so are setting up the
fundamentals for all of us that we speak
about the same terms so industrial
control system consists of two parts you
have this supporting communication
infrastructure which is basically
governed by the IT security and you have
the physical process which is already
engineered inside science and it's
frequently called operational technology
or ot and the target target is physical
process so the attacker who is able
hacking to their we are not worried with
the attacker who is able to hack into
the industrial control system we're only
worried about those who able to actually
engineer damage scenario so in general
as you already understood ICS can
security consist of two parts one is IT
security yes we need to be able to hack
into the infrastructure and secondly ot
security it's basically causing impact
on the operation process or equipment
and basically that will be constitute
attack payload our topic and this is
where we work together with yours so in
order to understand so cyber physical
hacking is all about just understanding
one concept control loop nothing else if
you understand that you understand cyber
physical hacking so you have sensor so
you have so practices designed with the
set points better and it has to work
it's a specific pressure temperature
flow sensors measure those states and
send the measurements to control system
and it's adjust the actuators like
valves motors pumps to keep the protests
closed to set point but controllers
cannot do it alone because they'll have
only the local you of the process that's
why you have on top of that you have
also humans or it's called HMI and on
top of that because humans are all also
can have
small brain so we have tons of
optimization applications which make a
complex calculation to optimize our
process so basically the entire
supporting IT infrastructure follows
this structure and this is how it looks
like and you have exactly those layers
you have filled instrumentation serves
and sensors and actuators you have
controllers you have HMI on top you have
optimization and of course management
and the definition of real-time goes
from bottom to top
meaning that all equipment at the bottom
work and the definition of real-time
which is around like 10 milliseconds
sometimes one second in robotic it's
nanoseconds operators already work on
real-time which is equal like one to
three minutes an optimization
application its days weeks and months
and planning is of course like years
ahead so as an attacker now knowing that
we can understand where do we want to be
live in this infrastructure to have a
meaningful impact because if I will be
trying to do something from the HMI or
from the optimization application the
controllers which sit at the bottom they
will in between of my operations which
is one two three minutes they will try
to bring the purchase back into the
normal state so it's very difficult to
win at the top upper layer so if you
really want to cause very meaningful
impact you have to be somewhere close to
the protest so basically have to be on
the controllers and depending on which
industry you are attacking those
controllers will look slightly
differently but as it considers they're
not PC those are embedded system and
this is your specialization so I'm
breaking the stuff on the top he is
implementing what I need to do in the
embedded systems so basically as you
understood we have this concept because
this cyber-physical interplay we have
this attacks are called cyber physical
attacks and in the mass media typically
it is believed the attacker wants to
make something to explode
the point is it's not that easy to make
something to explore to explode why
because we have safety even if the
attacker is able to cause some incident
and maybe close all the vibes and valves
and pressure is growing there are layers
of safety protection which will not
allow attacker to do so there there will
be pressure relief valves which the
safety system will open and so in
basically how it looks like if you know
like there is a security
onion so there is also safety onion
which star
from the protest design that is the
first layer of safety protection which
is those specific set points you have
then control protest control or
controllers you have HMI and on top if
human if humans already not able to
prevent this unsafe state then the
safety instrumented systems are kicking
in so the attacker also have to defeat
safety systems so that he will get boom
so you see there is a lot of things to
do in that plant now the topic of this
talk which steps attack AI needs to do
actually to design the type of physical
payload how do you go from looking at
the plant was the final binary so and
the point is that now we will go through
the cyber physical attack lifecycle
which we and you know so basically the
reason why we do life cycles because
it's a typical approach to more method
to describe a process of content
conducting cyber attacks and if you know
how the attackers work which specific
tasks they need to do then you know how
actually find during the forensic or
maybe even how to stop them so we sis's
we've got to conceptualize these stages
of developing cyber physical attack by
lloyd and now that this is not an
execution attack already in the target
environment because the stages the steps
will be slightly different many of them
will go from this diagram but they will
be slightly different and maybe that
would yet another talk but this is
stages you go to design the payload and
so how does this actually relate it to
everything what we already know for
example to Lockheed Martin well this is
action on objectives of course the
previous stages are steps are also
relevant because you still need to hack
into the infrastructure but this is
actually actions and objectives
similarly its complete mission in the
main D an attack lifecycle if you see
previously seen the sun's industrial
control system cyber kill chain this is
a developed stage and there is also this
meet ray attack framework vandalising
attack attackers and they just started
building it for industrial control
systems and we just don't know yet we
just recently started working with them
how to bring our knowledge into this
framework so now we will go through the
stages of this of the attack lifecycle
and you would think like how designing a
payload like how what access stage is
doing in designing payloads like you
design in payload like what I excess is
how it is relevant it seems like it is
really relevant but it's actually not so
excess is very important and you will
see why in under the in the design so
excess could be divided into three like
basically three major groups first it is
a target facility because you need to
get into the target facility if you this
is a goal - for the discovery basically
reconnaissance process comprehension you
need to get access to needed assets like
to specific to wine I knew of course you
need to execute an attack extremely
popular becoming and we will look we
will see a few slides later extremely
popular became getting first into the
trusted search parties and from their
pivot into they are basically from the
stage and target into the intended
target it also allows you through this
third party and dedicated remote access
you can get to assets you need like a
turbine and also because majority of
work in the plants is done by
subcontractors design programming of the
controllers it's all done the
subcontractors so you go to the
subcontractor to get all the needed
information about the target plant and
there are also not targeted
opportunistic targets we will see them
later targeted so how the talk is
selected actually the target and the
point is yes we know several cases of
the strategic target it is mostly
related to the competition when the
attacker would go after specific for
example chemical plant in competition
which is competition with another
financial nation-state but mostly
targets are selected because it's the
most suitable target to achieve a goal
so if you want to basically showcase the
capability that hey I can sit shut down
the electricity in German it doesn't
matter which substation to shut down if
you just want to set a message there is
collateral victim that it's exactly
related to the short targets a third
party victims so if the attacker get
into this
like subcontractor so basically every
who is a custom of that subcontractor
will be compromised so you are
collateral with victim and there is a
per 2 NIST ik well that service just
looking into me from the internet I
guess I go there so for example just few
examples finis terrae suspected cyber
physical attack this is a logical target
it is a strategic target because it's 80
percent of the country electricity is
produced in them and Tails and the this
plant was when just an upgrade and there
was tons of information on the internet
around that open source which actually
even suggests their internet access to
their alarm system so there's like so
much detail about the Clint was put in
line that this is really max makes a
very attractive target similarly
Ukrainian cyber attack when in Ukraine
on the power substation there is no
strong indication that it was a
strategic target because they just
wanted to shut down somewhere
electricity it was not about that
specific substation but that was an
attractive target because there was a
lot of public information for example
there is a video was where you could see
all the equipment used in that
substation for example you could see
that they were used in Siemens in
product relay which were actually
targeted by the malware some companies
actually proudly released a report with
detail network infrastructure that
substation so you basically already have
everything you know to go and target
that facility this is the HMI from that
facility
similarly you probably if you're in this
talk you've probably heard about Triton
clearly and there is similarly there is
no strong indication that Triton victim
was strategic target it's more likely
that actually it was used as a live
drill or testing performance why because
it and it could be actually pretty much
every facility in that region because
basically if you search on the internet
you will see that Schneider or basically
investors has won pretty much every
contract in the petracles sector in that
region so every plant is caring try
conics equipment so just go select any
you want so and this is the point that
is you already understood so depending
on what the attacker can find about the
facility
it's actually can make you a target it
can provoke targeting and it's really
shocking we already decided we are going
to write a blog post about that but
internet is full of proprietary and
confidential engineering documentation
full full full we are going to write a
blog post to show what stuff you can
find in there so it's just quick
examples you know for example this was
from one facility they somebody put on
the internet a confidential information
at several documents about everything
about alarm tuning in that facility
which is so important to the attacker so
this is all the alarms how they
configured where they how they critical
this is actually photo from the nuclear
power plant with equipment and actually
this is a test of the some nuclear rods
inside of this reactor you can find
crazy stuff so but this is improbable
this is a big problem it make can make
you a target especially a lot of stuff
from Indonesia fry will be attacker I
would go to Indonesia so this is what
makes you target attacker select targets
but then there is we have a very big
problem is targeting third parties it
became the most prevalent like most
preferable method for the attacker to
get into the intended targets so because
you can get access to the target
facilities you can get access to new
equipment we discuss that and obtaining
necessarily information it became such a
big problem that for example UK in the
USA has issued special advisor is
talking about that the attacker is using
this stage in target in order to get
into the intended targets and while they
they as soon as they issued this advisor
is actually in Germany one of the power
substation was compromised to the
Internet service provider so through the
subcontractor and the ISP was
compromised through their subcontractor
who get with her switches so you have to
staging targets to get into your
intended target and also basically USA
or now started actually even penalizing
companies if their information is
somewhere sitting on the internet so one
of the utilities in USA was was made to
pay 2.7 million because their
subcontractor did not put on the open
survey on the internet their proprietary
for keen information so that's the big
problem and this is how the top has got
in the into the their targets so this is
the role of access stage on the design
of the damage payload is because
depending on how you got into the
facility where you get into which part
of the facility you get which
information you discovered they will
have the most pretty that will define
what damage scenario you will select to
do bad things to that facility so it's
basically it could be access driven and
information driven so now that you
understand why we have access in the
payload design so the next stage is
discovering and it consists of two parts
the one is more known and understood for
you basically network reconnaissance you
have to understand what assets do you
have on the reconnaissance and that is
and you will have this for example
mainly an attack lifecycle only that as
soon as you will reach that regulatory
control level with controllers then you
need to already have to have proprietary
tools because traditional IT tools will
not allow you help you to discover like
controllers so you will have to use the
proprietary qualities basically the
capabilities of the native protocols to
credit control hey who you are how I
tell me about you
what firmware you have what is your
order number because we even will be
looking for completely different
information about those assets it's not
like you're looking for what is your MAC
address or something so and secondly
what is happening in this discovery
stage is you perform process
comprehension so you basically need to
enumerate all file shares all important
host which can computers which can host
useful engineering documentation about
how the plant is built what's what it is
doing how it is configured all the
control logic and so on and for example
if you see below we wrote a paper we
took a very simple process with it with
just a vessel live and water and they
took stupid Modbus open source protocol
and we took men in the middle attack
everybody knows how to mine in the
middle but then we needed 12 pages
double column to describe how much recon
on that process and all of the
configuration of the controllers and
everything
to do to do simple men in the middle so
it's not that you just do it you still
need to figure out a lot of things so
the next stage is control because the
previous stage was static you understand
static behavior of the process but the
processes are actually dynamic because
they change with the time and as soon
you change some silly you're just a
controller the actuator protesters
changing so control is about figuring
out the dynamic behavior of the process
and the ability of the attacker to
maintain controllability of the process
and how much he can push it because the
attacker wants to do something abnormal
to the process
is he able to do that so basically you
will have to probe the process and see
the responses of the sensors and again
this is least understood and studied
state human all there is no Public Works
there is this work which also this is my
work and there is one talk which is not
public by Jason Larson but that's pretty
much it
public knowledge about this stage and
now we will so basically I have this use
case for you and I'm really thankful to
our guys from the Singapore University
who specifically for this talk helped us
to conduct experiments so that we could
show you something interesting so we
want to kill you our filter in the water
treatment facility you see it in this
yellow staining so and you will see the
role of the control stage in this
experimentation so this is the filters
how they look in the water facilities
extremely expensive and if they are not
working you do not have water so it's a
very good target
so if killing a filter so for example if
you look at the HMI of this specific
staging of filtration of water we will
find that we can locate the filter we
see that there is some tubes going into
it but what does it mean exactly we have
no idea so basically typically it you
might do not contain all the necessary
details so you will have to go and find
the piping and Instrumentation diagram
and see maybe if some equipment is
missing on the HMI well there is still
two two perhaps two valves hmm what do
we do with that and the point is the
documentation again will not tell you
exactly how to damage them and
what you can do is it filters so for
that you will need actually to go into
their PLC code into the controller code
and then from the controller we would be
able to figure out and you can see the
second pipe is coming from another so
basically from the bottom I had to
explain this here from the bottom you
have a normal water flow which will be
clean and on from the top that comes
from the another stage which is and it
is a process called backwash backwash is
a cleaning the filter from this
particles which is collected and we need
to know so basically the idea is what if
we put two flows through this filter and
rise the pressure because we know that
pressure is very damaging for the
membrane of the filter so now then we of
course because suddenly is another stage
of the protesters involved stage number
six you need to go somewhere else
hacking to another stage understand
every see what's going on in there get
the controller logic understand it and
from all of that knowledge from the
especially from the controllers code we
will be able to figure out that there is
three things which can trigger the
backwash process which we want it's a
preset time every 30 minutes
if the filter pressure differential
pressure in filter is already above 40
kilo Pascal's or plant shut down so and
basically the triggering of this events
will be based on the state machine state
machine it's collects know this position
of every control actuator in the plan at
current moment and it has to basically
it has to follow this specific state so
that you could start both processes but
the most important that the state
machine is only in the plc in the stage
number three but not in the plc number
six and we want to start the backwash
process in the PLC number six and the
process will start in POC number six
only by one variable which goes from the
PLC number three as you can see this is
a lot of involvement it's not important
to understand all of these details but
it's a lot for the for the attacker to
understand even to start thinking how
can i dex acute that attack eventually
we were able to execute an attack and
both flows are going through the filter
the pressure is rising so we now know
that the pressure is rising but how much
that is the point this is what no
can explain you you have to do
experimentation in the life process only
then you know if we will be able to rise
the pressure which is harmful to the
filter so for example on average and
this is experimentation from the plant
from the photos which you've seen
previously
so the typical the average pressure is
12 to 13 kilo Pascal's we are able to
reach maximum 98 kilo Pascal's which is
in 8 seconds then the protestor turn in
normal in 5 seconds and note that this
information we now know that maximum
what we can achieve is 98 kilopascal I
still don't know and they don't know we
will need to go to the producer of these
filters to figure out whether this brush
is really harmful to the membrane and
for how long we need to maintain that
pressure so that it would really break
so that is but understanding this
dynamic behavior is still very important
how much pressure we can ignite and also
this time in the parameters like 5 like
8 secconds are very important for us
because that the operator will see that
the pressure is rising so for example if
if the for example if in case the
breakage is instantaneous and we know
how the alarms are configured in the
plant so for example it is expected that
the operator will have set many
milliseconds to take a decision
understand the situation and to react
and if this time is smaller or larger
than the time we need to kill the filter
then we don't need to spoof in this
value because we will be faster then the
attacker operator will try to react so
now you understand the importance of the
control stage well damage stage is the
most interesting because and the most
complex and yes we'll talk more about in
about that in his part about preventing
response and obtaining feedback because
attack I need to make sure that no
components in the plant are fighting
with him while he's trying to break
something and also he needs to have a
feedback loop to know like am i
successful in my attack and damage can
take several forms it's not necessarily
as a social prize and it's not
necessarily only explosions you can do
of course equipment break which people
do pole
this is actually photo from Germany
isn't it beautiful and you can make
product out of specification especially
attack us now target the editing
manufacturing
so you basically mess up with a with the
parts and actually make fur it's
actually it's already happening you can
make increase production cause for
example more electricity consumption and
so on but the point is also that attack
design so for example me as an engineer
I can understand the processor can
design an attack there is still this guy
who needs to implement everything for me
and for example in this stage so what is
their main many filtration stages and
what a facility utility and for example
there is also one of the filtration
stage which called reverse osmosis and
the water has actually goes so the water
very much chlorinated in the water
treatment facility and then it needs to
be dechlorinated for this osmosis
because chlorine is very harmful for
that type of filter so you have this
device called the chlorination and so
what we need to do so for example to
shut down the de chlorination we are
spoofing the flow value if it falls
below point for the chlorinated seats
think that there is no flow and it stop
the chlorinator so basically all the
water goes through uncoordinated so like
our success success but guess what there
is this or pee meter in another stage
which which will be measuring the level
of the chlorine before it goes into this
reverse osmosis filter and there that
occur also need to prove the value in
too low but guess what it isn't another
stage it isn't another networks tape
segment it's another equipment it could
be some analog controller or something
and if the attacker is not able to spoof
that or compromise that part or
implement his payload in that part of
the process
my design is useless because we cannot
implement it so attack design is not
always miss means success so in the last
stage is a cold cleanup and it is very
also very important stage because in the
IT domain we can steal the data and
leave the
you would never even know I was there in
a cyber-physical system is simply not an
option because you had to change
physical process its visible so
basically the most attractive so after
things go wrong you want create the
forensic footprint for the investigators
so that they would think what do you
want them to think has caused this
incident so something else but not an
attacker for example you can time that
talk to the troubleshooting to bad
weather and so on modify some logs and
so on so now because as you can seen
there is a lot of tasks to do in the
plant well so which will go into the
design and the code of the payload and
therefore in many cases so you need to
live in a multiple parts of the facility
coordinate a lot of attacks for that
it's not nice or always enough just to
have a code or the payload but you also
want to have implant and yours we'll
talk more about it all right thanks
marina so I'm gonna talk a little bit
about implantation and ot payload
development which is kind of the
implementation part of this this talk so
when I'm talking about implants there
are a lot of different definitions
possible but for the purpose of this
talk I'm gonna consider it a hardware or
a software modification designed to gain
an authorized control over a specific
system functionality and what I'm
talking about an OT payload I basically
mean a digital implementation of a part
of the cyber-physical attack and these
two things can be tightly coupled in one
malicious blob of code or they can be
separate components with at some stage
work together
so why implants sometimes people will
wonder why not just modify the control
logic because people are familiar with
ICS security they'll know there is no
authentication on most of these
protocols and you can usually just just
change the control logic the set points
or send a malicious command in some
cases that might be sufficient but for
more complicated attacks you will
require a degree of coordination
feedback measurement coordination
speed and low level functionality access
that you cannot get by modifying control
logic or changing set points and you
will need access to the system itself of
course many scenarios will be possible
without implants like the attacks we saw
in the Ukraine in 2015 and 16 you don't
need any of this stuff for that
for more complicated stuff you will need
it so the first thing we need to think
about is where are we going to place our
implants so this is like a generalized
picture of an ICS infrastructure and you
can implant in various types of
equipment and where you will implant
will be designed by the requirements
that are handed down to me by marina and
by the process itself and by various
kinds of specifics and parameters so you
can implant the network equipment which
is basically your switches your routers
your modems your your serial converters
your gateways whatever and it can be
used to manipulate ot traffic it can be
used for observing and learning the
traffic so you get some insight into the
process itself or you can for example
drop traffic to cause loss of control or
loss of view or suppress an alarm signal
another part where you will need to
implant probably it's at the process and
safety controllers so these are
basically your PC PLC's your dcs
controllers your are to use stuff like
that and that might be for different
reasons you might want to manipulate the
i/o you want to measure your attack
progress maybe you want to suppress
condition monitoring alerts for example
if you have a payload that causes
equipment to vibrate you might have a
second system that does vibration
monitoring and send alerts at a certain
point that you want to suppress while
the attack is in progress before the
actual damage is carried out and of
course you want to also prevent any kind
of automated or mediated safety response
and finally in some cases you might have
to employ two implants the field devices
which are the sensors and the actuators
in order to spoof sensor data maybe at a
high speed or override digital safety
mechanisms within field devices now how
to implant I'm gonna keep this
discussion very general and high level
because it will differ very much
depending on the equipment you're
targeting but in general when you're
implanting controllers and and stuff
like that it will look something like
this so the first thing that we want is
one smooth native code execution so we
need access to low-level privileged
functionality on these embedded devices
we want to be able to talk to the memory
or port MAP IO
we want to be able to modify kernel
memory objects logic runtime memory we
want to be able to interact
some kind of persistence mechanism like
being able to write to flash something
like that and ideally we do this by
means of silent hot patching which by
which I mean life modification of
running code because we don't want any
reboots we don't want any service
restarts and we don't want to cause any
process upsets as a result of our
implementation activity so there are
many ways to get code execution in many
many ways to get code execution on many
PLC's but generally they come down to
either a firmware download which we
modify command injection in something
like a web interface a logic download
which is what I'm going to mostly talk
about or some kind of memory corruption
like a buffer overflow or whatever so a
little bit about backgrounds about plc
architectures so when you have PLC's
they generally come in two flavors
everyday or standalone on the Left which
contains like the the inputs and the
outputs and the core of it or they are
modular so you have a separate power
supply module you have a CPU module
which is like the brains and then you
have input output modules separate
ethernet module and all of these modules
will communicate over a backplane which
has an inter module database and that
can be like something like vmebus PCIe
or it can be a little bit more
proprietary like X bus or something like
that and these are generally the the
internals like highly simplified of what
most PLC's look like so at the core you
have a processor which can be more
high-end or it can be a small
microcontroller coupled to an input
interface which is either were directly
coupled to the i/o pins or to some
backplane data bus it is able to read
from flash where you store your firmware
and your your permanent storage you have
your communication interfaces like your
serial your Ethernet your wireless for
your your field buses and your
industrial Ethernet and then you have
your your RAM where you store the
programs and the data the input/output
variable map the runtime in applications
and the real-time operating system
powering all of that if there is a
real-time operating system now the boot
sequence roughly looks something like
this so you have the processor which
starts by boot ROM which is usually
one-time programmable inside this this
microcontroller it loads the bootloader
into RAM that will start the RTOS or
some custom firmware executive and these
these there can be various operating
systems which I'll mention later they'll
start basically a couple of tasks
at a very simple operating system it
will start the logic runtime as a task
which then interprets or executes the
logic program by itself and this can be
done in in in generally two ways either
you have the logic program which is
essentially compiled to a bit stream for
an FPGA or cpld
or you can have it compiled jet compiled
or interpreted on the microprocessor
itself that looks something like this so
you have your discrete inputs and your
analog inputs which are either directly
coming from from the pins or the
backplane data bus or they come into the
IO interface then they're stored in the
the input image table they're read the
program is executed over this these
these variables and then the outputs are
read to the image table which is
synchronized with the aisle interface
and going out to the outputs so if we
have an implant we won't roughly access
to this kind of functionality so if your
i/o is poured mapped you want access to
the special purpose register
instructions in order to be able to
interface with this any kind of iowa
instructions that you might need to talk
to if it is memory mapped you want
access to any memory mapped i/o
registers maybe a shared memory buffer
bus interfaces that go to the backplane
or communications modules network
controllers maybe you want to spoof
something on a display or you want
persistence so you'll need to be able to
write to flash and generally that means
that if there is any kind of privilege
separation at the level of the RTOS or
the former execution you want to be able
to live in privileged mode so that is
kind of the takeaway from from this kind
of slide now implant installation
roughly follows these kind of steps and
the ones with a little star are optional
in most cases so if there is any kind of
privilege as privileged separation you
will need to escalate privileges then if
there's any kind of Diagnostics on the
embedded system itself you will need to
disable those in order to guarantee
implant stability because like I
mentioned you don't want this controller
to crash because that might cause the
triggering of alarms that might cause
forensics to be initiated and you want
yourself while your attack is still
being carried out then you will need to
relocate your implant to a suitable
place ensure persistence if you want
because like if you only
and volatile memory that means that if
your controller reboots or it crashes
your payload is gone so if you want
persistence you will need to modify
firmer or to store logic and flash then
you need to set your hooks and then you
need to go resident in some way now when
you're designing your implant you have
several considerations and and there are
essentially two here you will need to
decide between an active or a dormant
implant in the case of an active implant
you have the OT payload tightly coupled
to your implant and the benefit of this
is that it limits detection and network
forensics exposure because you have
after you the implementation little
communication again electronically with
the with the controller or you could go
for a Dorman implant which is
essentially just a backdoor where you
deliver the OT payload later and this
has the benefit of limiting forensics
exposure in a different way because that
means that if you are detected during
your attack you don't actually see the
OT payload then you'll have to decide
between persistence and memory residents
if you want to persist this might be
complicated by by code signing so you
need the ability to write to flash and
you need enough space and you also need
if you do memory residents you won't
survive reboot but it like I mentioned
limits forensics exposure now one thing
we want our implants is scalability we
want to do as little work as possible
for as many targets as possible so
targeting different vendor systems with
similar implant functionality might be
complicated because they might be very
different but in the ICS space the
benefit is that there are a limited
number of key players out there so if
I'm the state level attacker I might
construct an arsenal of generic
templates for keys ACS and safety
controllers and then have a one-time
upfront investment with no huge turnover
because these systems don't change a lot
over time one complication is
heterogeneity anybody who works in
embedded systems knows there is a lot of
heterogeneity more than in traditional
IT you have a lot of different processor
architectures a lot of different
operating systems different kind of
runtimes different ways to to interact
with IO which might differ between the
same family of controllers memory layout
might be different so you will need to
do reverse engineering there and then
you might have security features but
let's be real and most ICS this is not
going to be that the big hurdle
another complication is in house versus
commercial
luckily for attackers this is shifting
towards commercial but you might in some
cases have for example a proprietary
system on chip or proprietary Azek which
you will need to reverse engineer in
order to understand it first then you
might have a proprietary operating
system and a runtime and you'll need to
spend all this time understanding this
thing before you can develop your
implant for example in the Tri Connect
safety system which was targeted by
Triton you have an in-house operating
system and a run time and for the
different families you have different
architectures like the first one was a
national semiconductor chip and then
they move to PowerPC but there were
different PowerPC architectures and
there are also differences in the
operating system so you need to
reverse-engineer all this stuff to to
scale your implant account for example
however is that with newer equipment and
some vendors especially in the PLC space
you see a rise of commercial RTSs and
run times so what you see a lot is
you'll see something like codesys
running on VxWorks qnx or real-time
linux and increasingly on arm or PowerPC
chips now a key note here is that you
see this more in PLC's which are a
little more open than in dcs controllers
which are a little more proprietary but
on the operating system and chip side of
things things are becoming way more
homogenized another complication anybody
who worked in the method systems will
recognize is resource constraints so the
key takeaway here is that in an embedded
system you have very very little
resources available in terms of memory
computing power all that kind of stuff
so if you're developing your implant and
your payload you better enjoy extreme
programming if you want to fit all that
stuff in there and then of course there
might be security engineering
complications you might have domain and
privilege separation which can be on the
main CPU itself between user space and
kernel space or it might be between
different chips like it might be that
you are able to get code execution on
one chip but that logic is running on a
different one and if there is some kind
of barrier like an iommu or some kind of
other thing that prevents you from
lateral movement on the embedded system
that is in the way
things like firmware and logic signing
would complicate it sandboxing exploit
mitigations and when you're delivering
your logic any kind of key lock might
might complicate things as well
so a little bit of a case study will
we'll delve into some of the internals
of the EDA Triton malware here
the Triton more well-liked like Marina
mentioned targeted a Saudi petrochemical
facility the safety system specifically
in this case that the Tri connect safety
controllers and the attack basically
went like this so they got in on the IT
side of things and then because of
improper segmentation between process
control Network and the safety Network
they were managed to be able to get
execution on an engineering station
which is basically a privileged
workstation that allows you to download
your safety logic to the try connects
controller and what the payload
basically did here is they downloaded
the logic to the try connects controller
and this logic is essentially compiled
for the PowerPC chip and executes it
directly on the CPU
without any kind of signing without any
kind of basically sandboxing so
essentially the packet that you're
sending says execute my shellcode please
which is nice as an attacker now one of
the things that people wondered is why
didn't they just modify the firmware
because the firmware downloads were also
unauthenticated and unsigned and it's a
little easier to modify that than try to
get you know code execution to the logic
the problem is that when you download
the firmware the controller reboots into
download mode and the actual safety
logic that's currently being executed is
interrupted which might cause a process
upset so if you want smooth execution
you will actually need to append to the
currently running safety logic and then
the old watchit continues running so
that is that is a very important part to
realize when people are developing
implants and payloads now installing DD
implants had one complication here the
safety program itself is executed in
user mode like there's no actual
separation but the way it works is you
have the MSL register and it regulates
what instructions you can and cannot
execute based on a privileged bit that
is being set and that is non writable
for user mode now if you want to
relocate your implant and you want to
patch the Diagnostics and stuff like
that you're modifying basically code
memory so in order for that to apply you
will need to flush the instruction cache
and that requires supervisor privileges
so they needed the privilege escalation
exploit now they find an exploit in a
system called the so status system call
that allowed them to modify the Amazon
reg
while running and supervisor mode
because you know it's saved to some
global and then when the system called
returns it restores it the problem is
that they have this supervisor
separation on for the instructions but
they did not have memory permissions so
even in usual mode you can write
anywhere in memory including to Colonel
Global's and that gave you basically a
right wetware and that basically allowed
you to essentially override these these
variables to trigger a right what we're
situation that allow them to basically
toggle the bit to supervisor mode and
that allowed them to them basically
disable the Diagnostics ramp check which
is an integrity check between memory on
drum and in RAM and after that relocate
the implant so in order to ensure
residents even with the full logic wipe
so after the implant was installed they
could then basically wipe the logic and
still continue running then they modify
the network command handler so basically
you have this network dispatched a blur
and then they modified one entry in
order to be able to communicate
electronically at a later stage with
this implant and finally allow them to
deliver the actual implant which
basically gave them arbitrary
read/write/execute
access to memory so there's no actual OT
payload but there is this arbitrary
backdoor capability why is that
important because it allowed them to
basically bypass the key lock that
basically could be turned to run mode at
a later stage so if a later stage this
key was turned they could still deliver
our Batory
or T payloads so not basically you have
God mode over this controller what are
you gonna do you deliver the OT payload
at a later stage now in this particular
case the OT payload was not recovered
from the incident but we can speculate
about what this kind of stuff looks like
and that's exactly what we're gonna do
so ot payloads right take a look at the
damage stage we'll take a sip of water
so essentially when you are engineering
this this damage States I basically get
handed down some engineering
requirements and engineering stuff from
marina and then I have to implement this
attack which basically consists of three
main prongs and the first of that is
manipulating the process which can be
done
directly by manipulating actuators or
deceiving a controller or operator about
a process state then if I'm manipulating
the process I will need to prevent a
response
you know the operators and the safety
systems might be fighting back so we'll
need to manipulate that as well and I'm
very importantly I will also need to be
able to obtain feedback because I will
need to know if my attack is being
successful or if it's failing and I will
need to synchronize different parts of
my attack payloads across these these
these implants that I'm having there so
the first kind of OT payload could be an
IO manipulation payload and that is a
simple concept
you know I'm manipulating DD
input/output the execution is actually
non-trivial there are many different
approaches here so there might be many
different kinds of cyber physical
attacks from the engineering point of
view but the implementations can also
vary and that depends on how the IO
image tables are populated how the IO is
wired to the execution logic that kind
of stuff so this is an example for most
PLC's which will be kind of stand-alone
so essentially you'll have your your
memory mapped i/o register directly
wired to the input pins and the output
pins and essentially what I want to do
is I'm going to trap access to that
particular address range and then
install a hook Handler and I can trap
that axis in multiple ways I can set a
memory break point I can patch
instructions which will be necessary for
port mapped i/o I can change memory
permissions and then you know install a
custom exception Handler or something
like that and then when my hook handler
kicks in I can see if it to read or
write operation and then for example if
it's a read operation I'll set the pin
mode to output which means that it's not
actually being read from and they can
sue the value in the image table before
instead of the value that's actually
coming in when it's a write operation
for example I can set the pin mode to
input so nothing is actually going out
or I can spool the value that's being
written out and then I can manipulate
the i/o now for example for a controller
like try connects which is model or it's
a little different because the i/o pins
are not directly wired to the CPU
instead you have the the i/o modules
which come in over a data bus to a
dedicated IO processor which then makes
it available over shared memory so if we
want to implement the same payload
unlike
modular architecture I will need to hook
access to the IO portion of shared
memory or maybe I will need to hook the
bus on low routines when it's coming in
and and that makes it look a little bit
different one complication could be
filled device limitation so I might be
able to manipulate arbitrary IO but it
might be the case that I'm saying okay
close a valve at this particular speed
and then the the fill device has an
intrinsic safety limitation in part of
its firmware that says no that is
inherently unsafe I'm not going to do
that so we'll need to be able to modify
the firmware of that filled device as
well in order to carry out my my payload
and that is something that you'll need
to take into account as well now the
second kind of payload is a large
suppression and this is part of
preventing this kind of safety response
so again simple concept non-trivial
execution but we basically want to do is
we want to prevent an outgoing alarm
being raised or an incoming alarm from
being acted upon and this might require
very different approaches because an
alarm might be raised with a dedicated
protocol message it might be out going
through some of some kind of i/o signal
or an alarm bit might be in a flag
accompanying a read process variable
something like that
now alarms can propagate throughout the
process at different stages behind it
throughout different process units a
even and then there are two ways either
we can hide the alarms when they're
coming in for the operators or local HMI
or we can suppress them at the fill
device level or at the controller level
and we're going to look at the second
approach because it's closer to the
process so an example this this is the
Tri Station software for for tracking
acts and here we have a simple water
tank level alarm if the water level is
either high or low you raise an alarm
don't think so much about it now the
safety program resides in memory s code
and what we essentially want to do is
set the output of alarm always to a
fixed false so what we have to do is we
have to find this program in memory and
then essentially find the instruction in
this safety logic to patch and and
essentially this is basically just an or
instruction and then we just override it
with an assigning of a static false and
luckily PowerPC is a fixed size
instruction RISC architecture so we can
override any instruction without and
with any other without one
worrying about any kind of instruction
alignment and the result of it is like
this on the left you have the normal
result so the water level is high and
the alarm goes out and says dude you
have a problem on the right you still
have a problem it says dude it's all ok
because it has been patched in memory on
the controller now a different approach
might be alarm relaxation and tightening
so you might wonder what do we want to
relax or tighten an alarm instead of
just suppressing it well it might be the
case that we don't want to prevent the
alarm from dream race but we want to can
change the conditions on it being raised
so maybe the limits when it is being
raised maybe the dad done values maybe
the priority of the alarm that is being
raised for two different reasons
essentially either we want to relax them
because of stealth reasons during
scheduled testing or we want to tighten
them to cause hard to resolve LARM
storms because if we are causing alarms
to be raised from this this implanted
part in a part of the process where the
attack is not being carried out then
people are going to do Incident Response
there which will be very complicated
while the actual attack is being carried
out somewhere else this can be basically
done by hooking functionality that
decides whether to raise an alarm
this can be data like DD limit priority
and deadband properties of some kind of
object in memory as you see in the
bottom and then essentially we override
these values internally in RAM well if
they query the values to the controller
asking like what is your alarm limit on
this alarm we spoof it and we say it is
the original thing that you originally
thought was going on and then they're
like there's nothing wrong here but
we're still seeing alarms that we
shouldn't be seeing or if you have alarm
logic that's implemented in code then
we'll have to modify the code by
patching instructions so there's our
basically the two approaches to going
about this then you have implant
communication and that essentially looks
like something like this
so the implants that that marina
mentioned in the different parts of the
process they will have to synchronize at
some point so essentially what you have
is that you have a process that is in a
certain state and only when it is in
that state I want to for example change
the air or the medium inflow and that
causes the process to shift to a
different state and only when it is in
that state I want to change the agitator
speed for example and I need to
synchronize the implants that might be
in different Network segments and
all be super complicated what you'd
expect especially if you come from like
a regular IT side it's like okay it'll
just be some some c2 infrastructure and
will be something that will be spotted
all over the network but this is
something people don't realize you might
actually not see that much electronic
chatter and not just because of stealth
reasons but because of reasons of
synchronization that might be very hard
it might be that you are unable to talk
quickly enough you might have packet
loss among these protocols
so in that case communication will have
to go through the process physics and
essentially what that means is that you
will need to be able to detect any
changes in the process state at a
different thing and it might be for
example I am detecting a change in the
flow rate which means that a processes
is going towards a different state and
you can do that for example with
something that is called a nonparametric
cumulative sum algorithm which you can
implement in something that is not that
big from a regular standpoint like 17
kilobytes unoptimized it's doable if you
do that like on a controller level but
if you have to implement this and
something like a few device it might be
completely impossible because you might
have like - 2 kilobytes of memory or
even less so that essentially brings us
to the conclusion and the conclusion
here is that you you have these various
different stages and you have different
kind of constraints that are essentially
being a post upon upon us like you have
the engineering constraints that are
imposed on morena
she imposes them down on us and then
basically essentially it goes back to me
and it might be that you have an attack
that is engineered perfectly and
theoretically possible but it might not
be possible because of very practical
reasons like for example not having
enough available memory on a controller
or having basically an analog signal
that cannot be overridden through cyber
means so the conclusion is that you have
this this complete complicated interplay
between engineering and hacking that
yeah that essentially complicates things
and you want to appreciate some people
who helped here and that is essentially
it if there are any questions I'd like
to take them now yes thank you
a few yos Maria
and
[Applause]
I wanted to thank also my co-speaker yes
because I used to work a lot of
programmers who were working for me and
you know like typically like can you do
that for me and the answer is always no
you know in programming the answer is
always no or it will take two weeks
bla bla bla you know and I must admit
whenever I like he was can you do that
if he's always yeah I can so I wanted
really to prize him for that oh thanks
so there are no questions oh one
question yep wait a moment
I was just wondering who hired you to do
this research so I am currently working
for Sakura which is Dutch cybersecurity
a consultancy company and we work in
different verticals and one of them is
is critical infrastructure and one of
the reasons this is important you need
to understand the offensive side in
order to properly do defense because one
of the things that you encounter a lot
is especially people coming from IT
security they'll come in and they're
like ok we compromised this network
because it's all super vulnerable and
then we have access to a PLC because
there's no authentication I can change
the logic and then you get a question
now what right and then people are like
well I guess it's bad but you have to be
able to understand how bad you have to
be able to understand why it's bad you
have to be able to understand if that
thing that that you think is possible is
actually possible in order to prioritize
your defensive efforts because it might
be that otherwise you are focusing on
the wrong thing so so part of what we do
at Sakura is try to understand at a very
in-depth level what these kind of
attacks involve in order to better serve
customers during during consultancy
engagements during red teaming
engagements during a variety of
traditional security services aimed at
this very complicated domain I've been
doing this I'm a physical damage for
about nine years so in different
organizations and again I do offensive
work because we have there is up to
almost zero public knowledge how the
offensive
raishin look like we only know that it's
sometimes happening and so basically I
and you know like we don't even have
statistics right now like what does the
most prevalent method for the attackers
to do something so we have created
statistics right now you know like we
are acting as an attackers and actually
so I do this offensive work so my
organization always allowed me to do so
because this is why I am working for
defenses I'm a security engineer so
basically in also in I frequently
participate in the incident responses
and I'm the only person on the team who
actually can analyze forensically
there's above the OT part of the attack
so for example when we look at that you
my the guy would say well I know it was
compromised IT guys and I was just like
yeah I will be starting looking at the
forensic image of the hard drive or it's
exactly the attack I have done on the
hard drive because I can only understand
I know what the attacker would probably
be doing on that system or for example
in case of Triton because it's a public
information I was on the incident
response team for the Triton attack well
being at Phii so basically I've been
looking like how the attacker was
executing this attack on the controller
because there was a lot of activities
involved and I was qualified to
understand because I'm working on the
offense of security for embedded systems
so yes organy our organizations allow us
to do so but in majority honestly it's a
hobby you spend entire weekend preparing
slides you know like we can be
bullshitting in here but if you if
you're worried about I don't work for a
government or anything like that which
is the most practitioners I guess in
this area but if for example after
DEFCON our web slides were not
immediately available
so those organisation contact us because
they want to have our slides immediately
because they educate their stuff because
clearly this is what is I think it is
valuable area for more practitioners
than just people at a government or an
ICS consultancy because it might be that
if you see a piece of malware and in the
case of Triton and you have a particular
payload you might be a good reverse
engineer but you're looking at a payload
and you're reverse engineering and
you're looking at what is it actually
doing and
don't understand it because you don't
understand the context and you don't
understand the impact well if you're
seeing a piece of banking malware or
you're seeing something like that you
might understand it because you're
familiar with this environment and you
need to understand impact before you can
understand all the the various edges of
both defensive and offensive security
that are involved in the frequent
comment which at least I get I don't
know whether you'll get is like do you
think it's ethical to present these
topics on the like to the larger
audience it's like of course it is
ethical because if we will not present
it nobody is learning from it but the
attackers will learn without our
presentation they probably learned from
us as well but they will learn anyway
and the people who are most interested
in this day they are already doing this
country series but some people think
that it's unethical to do such type of
talks
well choices I would like to underline
that you're completely right because at
some point in your life you will have
probably a piece of electronics in your
body and then you are the process and it
is fairly it is fairly important to have
a solid understanding of how vulnerable
you are at that moment so also to say
that this extends like not all the
details but it extends across verticals
so part of this also applies like the
medical devices to automotive to DDD
that's what aerospace sector so even if
you're not you know just focusing on
industrial control systems it is very
good to have an understanding of what
what what is involved in a cyber
physical attack further questions nope
so now it's time for lunch I think and
thank you again all right
[Applause]