well distributed isn't enough we're
going decentralized yeah that's my
wagons coats
hello it's Padilla fix English okay the
other German yeah yeah I'm here
courtesy of the fact I'm responsible for
inventing the the we're talking
about and funding to work on
productizing it since forever so yeah
and I'm making sure it happens right
here's the poor guy who needs to make it
happen
history
everything has a history part of the
history just arrived I spent one and a
half years of my life had a German
German venture the the toll road system
the electronic toll road system we have
in Germany and in this context I was I
was part of the security team which at
that time was pretty much only external
people and at some point irresponsible
manager presented me with a heap of
paper an ISO standard 28 28 and asked me
for opinion and I read it and had a
couple of ideas and then
years of research happened and I got I
got a bunch of people together that know
what they're doing and wanted to make
this reality because as ISO standards go
people from the industry came together
and basically rode a big wish list but
nobody actually did it and so this is
the story about how we did it and Dada
there was a new PK I'm so what is the
basic idea behind 28:28 its independence
from central CAS and connectivity as
well so why well size does matter
contrary to popular belief because road
networks are humongous
these are semi actual data from last
year we have 13,000 kilometers of
Express roadways in Germany alone and
close to 700 more paved roads and that
is dwarfed by China and China is growing
quickly she averred to reduce size
doesn't matter she lied the thing is
your road network needs to cover your
whole country so it is a big as
distributed system of roadside
infrastructure there's also a
non-trivial number of moving targets
quite literally because there's 50
million cars in Germany and 270 million
in the USA followed by almost as much in
China and for all these cars you need
efficient verification in maintenance
scenarios as in who can update my
firmware and you need certificate
management for vehicle-to-vehicle
communications so making it more
complicated
everything is federated we as Germans
are quite used to that we have a
multi-layer hierarchy we have the you we
have the federal state we have our
individual states districts
municipalities and you have well
strategy happening usually on the higher
layers that are a bit slower but actual
decisions that matter happen locally so
we have lots of in Russia infrastructure
in the field and if you don't have
infrastructure that's it basically this
goes for everything not just roads so
what's the most important part about
your infrastructure its dad that that at
that
so why them do we build our systems with
single points of failure I'm talking
about dos by design even if you have a
CA that is by nature distributed it
still has central aspects you can only
check your overseas piece and see our
ELLs if you're online and the ISO
standard wanted to fix exactly that so
now I've been talking about a normal or
a motive standard but how does that
apply to other industries because well
we have lots of other industries
automotive is just one so every
non-trivial PKI has the same problem a
push towards decentralization
exponential growth in permission levels
roles and capabilities that you need to
Express they all need to be resilient
and to be honest all we really want is
better failure modes so let's look a bit
at other industries ICS and SCADA I like
my lights to be on and controlled by me
not by some involuntary Chinese guy so
yeah what do we have we have basically
the similar challenges and if
something's not resilient enough in
SCADA more often than not it can go
actual boom so we have for example Smart
Grid what do you want you want your
power producers to allow the TSS and
DSOs that actually transfer the power to
trust them for something you want the
operation central do be trusted by the
power gate generators to control the
power generators you want engineers to
go into the field and do flexible
maintenance scenarios to update your
SCADA devices even if they are offline
then this also goes towards public
transport and charging station networks
which are closely tied and then over
here you come to the residential end of
everything where you have smart meters
in homes moving to smart meters and/or
smart city and automotive applications
here you have vehicle to vehicle
communication you have a growing number
of autonomous driving and parking
applications that are now upcoming and
you need flexible car sharing scenarios
that's the future here you have
basically that again you want cars to
trust their drivers you want drivers to
be allowed to use autonomous parking and
you want cars to be able to use
autonomous parking at the same time
autonomous parking needs to be able to
verify that you're allowed to be a
customer because you're paying and the
car needs to be compatible with the
technology used then we have bad stuff
here we have the special consideration
that IOT devices that are targeting a
consumer market are ridiculous device
numbers so the price pressure is very
high and you have very low performance
platforms what looks a bit better is a
smart home in building there you need
stuff like federated access control you
don't want to have one department that
is taking care of your access cards for
the building for all of your big company
that's what it is right now but yeah
that also means you need one week head
start to get new people on your campus
looks like that we have a smart home you
are lucky right there that Microsoft you
have a smart home where you can have
some residential power generation and
you want to maybe allow your power grid
operator to control parts of that
telling them well you can you can decide
to put my solar panel on the grid or
have it instead put the power in my
local battery backup
this nice thing comes around the current
push to ID s the new personal no F has
an Alice why's the EU citizen card the
nifty thing is there is basically just a
file or token on the NPA and to come in
US citizen card so you can use if you
really want to I guess here nobody will
use your personal as wise as a second
factor for Facebook great but if you
have a common ID you can do smart
government applications where you have
to stayed trusting some text accountant
Association to well name text
accountants they name a tax accountant
and you can then verify that this is
actually a tax accountant and delegate
access to your bank account read only to
detects accountant flexible using one
system so we want to tie that all
together because right now you have lots
of islands and lots of nasty CAS so
basically one big system but now you're
saying certificate authorities we have
x.509 right yeah about that there's a
little problem with x.509 the thing that
no one wants to talk about if you want
to revoke something you need an LC SP or
C RL and if you need to revoke something
you're pruning the whole subtree of your
hierarchy unrecoverable now ask your
thing about and the thing about c RL
certification as certificate revocation
list is they don't ask yourself is there
any company that really up their
certificate authority that's still
around or having customers dig in o-tar
is dead and even Symantec sold to did
research I'm not sure why digit cert was
oh yeah I know
bye they paid 1 billion because it's
still a ridiculous money printing
machine we're selling random numbers
great
how is the standard going to save us we
want no shared overall infrastructure
and it needs to be easily integrated
into existing systems if you break one
part because let's be honest it will
happen something will break it's never
allowed to take down everything it's an
out of node of industry standard argues
to engineers at Audi right they've seen
the problem of someone probably
out so they came up with way basically
that's straight from the standard you
have different security domains that are
interconnected within the security
domains in a standard there's ISO 15 7
64 but everything that's going beyond
that communication between security
domains is handled by 28 28 it's based
on a peer-to-peer approach you have
everyone talking to everyone else and
verifying that yes I can actually talk
to that device because I trust someone
that trusts someone that knows that this
is OK and then you can establish a
direct trust this is this is what
fascinated me about the standard when I
first read it it basically is it is
trying to model where is quite good at
doing that modeling how humans trust
each other right when you for example
you join a group of people and then you
ask someone that you begin to trust who
else here is trustworthy and for what
right so it also needs is fine granular
trust with x.509 you basically have
certificate valid certificate not valid
with some levels in between like this is
a CA and this is a leaf but that's not
enough if you have a very big system you
need this one can read my registers this
one can read these registers this one is
allowed to do a firmware update this one
is allowed to reboot me
and you need to be able to delegate all
of that or part of it and it needs to
support Federation because that's what
we already mentioned so we came up with
Trinity Trinity background is when I
read the standard I realized this is
awesome because it would look all the
certificate authorities so hence the
name Trinity was originally the code
name of a bunch of geeks in a desert
building fat man - first nuclear bomb
and yeah this is where the name comes
from so what do we have we have a PKI
basically that is fully transport
agnostic it doesn't matter where you put
your delegation data it just can be
communicated to everyone by everyone you
can basically quote everyone because
it's all signed data so you're no longer
reliable on OCSP or crl servers that are
specifically named all so we came up
with a concept called trust policy
languages to express arbitrary
permissions roles and capabilities at
arbitrary precision and make them
subdivided also this is the nice part
it's extensible in the field so you do
not need to roll out a firmware update
if you've designed your trust policy
language right and it can be
mathematically proven to always parse
correct it is fully offline capital
everything is verifiable offline and it
is designed to enable store and forward
networking we'll get to that so let's
look at a practical example how would
toe collect operate if we had trinity
back when Felix kept a standard the
first time yeah so this is how the
problem space works to give you a just
an impression of how talented collect
operates it is basically as
of keys cryptographic keys symmetric
keys that is because if it were
asymmetric it would be a total su and
that's not helpful and one problem in
this space you've probably seen have you
been on the outer button intellect
speech that is the Akane you controller
automata right as common people call it
mount poker and how does that work this
gentleman and I had the pleasure of
scrambling around those couple of times
so basically what it does is these are C
which is data short-range communication
which is basically the wireless serial
between the truck and the bridge right
so when the truck goes through under the
bridge it actually talks wireless serial
two up so the bridge actually has a
cable to the back end basically talks to
the infrastructure and there is I said
there's a zoo of keys so every every
vehicle has its own key on a chip card
in in the device that thing is for for
the Germans
we like to invent interesting terms that
thing is called a Hebron scout
so d threat actors in the scenario this
is what would surprised us when we
worked there the physical attacks on
those canals on the on about Putin
happened very very obviously close to
the Polish border because guess what
people they're shipping truckloads of
illegal immigrants from Poland to
Western Europe don't like their
trucks to be photographed non obvious
threat actors the first one obviously is
time very much like for us here right
now there is time coming so if
certificates expire it sucks so you have
to renew them the other non obvious
threat actor is the great equalizer of
the dashing field the plow so since
those connais use are somewhere out in
the country there is cables going
through the fields next to it and if if
the power happy Lee goes impose his
fields then suddenly the bridge goes
dark okay so how bastard look in
practice first of all we have a trust
overlay network we have the big cash
register that is called toll collect we
have to con a use and a truck and going
between them the cone EU is trusting the
big cash register to tell it everything
that's regarded too tall paid and the
cash register then said well this truck
paid so this one with a very obvious
license plate has paid
the other way around the truck is
trusting the cash register - well
basically trust them to tell that this
is actually valid convey you that I'm
talking to and then we have a trust edge
going back to the coning you that says
well this is a specific connie you
communication happens over the Internet
Rara that is very complicated we have
here arbitrary exchange of data over the
white edges and then trust verified
communication over the black edges now
we have adversarial conditions and we
need graceful degradation to
store-and-forward networking trust again
in that scenario is exactly the same but
there was the plow and it equalized the
internet connection to that car near you
and here we also have a mobile phone
outage because we know German Autobahn
there is no good mobile coverage so if
something changes now how do you get the
information to that Connie you the idea
is TC publishes updated trust and pushes
that to one Connie you that is
downstream on the Autobahn or upstream
depending on the way you're driving that
is then loaded in a drive-by
- whatever truck is passing underneath
which is perfectly fine because we're
transport agnostic we don't care if it's
a direct cable connection if it's
verified if it's a Russian business
Network
no one cares the truck then passes
underneath the next car you and it
dynamically deposits whatever trust it
got from the 1st Canadian to the next
one and that way you can progressively
still keep your system running even
though it doesn't have any network
connection in it doesn't need a trusted
network connection so if the truck
happens to be a Russian truck it doesn't
matter because either it has 80 tons of
computing Center on it then it can
happily try to break the encryption keys
but it is very unlikely to succeed
until it hits the next cone au and why
does this actually work all trust that
we delegate within our system is packed
into a CR DT a conflict-free replicated
data type that means wherever I get it
from whether I had an EPS plate or
several that were merged at whatever
point in time I can always decide which
information from any node is the newest
and thereby most relevant we also don't
have explicit revocations we simply
change our mind and publish a new state
of trust and the newest winds also
delegation updates our atomic there is
no such foot Canon as accidentially
first revoking all your certificates and
then trying to roll out new ones so
collect learned the hard way this
doesn't work so what's it actually good
for beside that well you can do
decentralized mesh VPN with delegation
so you do not have to name every
participant explicitly we actually have
a quick white paper on our website on
that you can do globally delegate able
single sign-on and not just for
applications for everything you can
delegate access to buildings legal
services public transport whatever you
want you can do thread Intel sharing you
can very specifically name what someone
can see what you're sharing you can
classify your data all within that one
system you can do change management you
have perfect traceability you know at
every point on verification over which
edge and delegation you came to this
decision so what would the world look
like if revocation day comes around and
we had pecky probably like this again
trust like works with humans revocation
happened and basically how does
revocation work with humans someone
tells you I don't trust this guy anymore
and that was it
you might spread the news to your
friends but it's more or less like this
no see we're all involved does anyone
here have a C or Elwood they're with
their friends with them that's it for us
thank you if you have any questions
we'll be at the dinner hit us up if you
think that anything we told you does not
work I want to hear your scenario and
discuss it with you definitely if you
think it will work talk with me that
makes the conversation easier and yeah
we'll be around we're here tomorrow and
the day after tomorrow as well
thank you
[Applause]