good morning everybody so my name is
Thomas some of you might know me some of
you has seen me around I've been in this
industry for nice shy of 30-plus years
and I started security about 25 years
ago and one of the things that I've done
is I've literally grown my career both
through end-user organizations
consulting organizations and software
organizations currently I basically work
for myself but I work for people that I
know for companies where I have contacts
in and I usually help them with
different subjects ranging from
compliance or the way to in certain
response and one of the peculiarities I
have is I tend to focus on the aspects
of protecting the critical assets right
and for me a critical asset nowadays
especially in Europe is all about data
protection unfortunately no I'm not
going to talk about GPR actually I might
but for a different reason than you
might think
I run beside London for those of you who
don't know me and but I also actively
share in our organisations and I'm the
VP of data governance for the I SS a UK
chapter so that's a quick introduction
to myself now
if we go back to part of my activity
which is insert response I go into
organisation sometimes to help the
instant response teams to help the cert
teams or to help them the analysts go
through some of their incident response
and one of the things what we start
doing is searching for the machines
right so we're going all through these
machines we keep going through the
machines we get to a site or to a
particular set of machines and there's
no frickin tooling on it okay
I'd like to apologize but sometimes I
throw in swear words and when I'm
speaking I'm if I hope you don't mind
it's just it slips out so you've got no
to Lee on these machines and you're
sitting here going oh crap now what do I
do and you find yourself banging your
head on the wall because on one side you
don't want to have to forensic Lee image
every freaking machine that you found
and I've been in situations where like
there's a mountain of machines to go
that have been imaged and that means
your insert response scale is going from
a few weeks to freaking months and like
how does why would you even do that to
yourself I really feel sorry for the
north's guys right now they are gonna
have a shitload of problems so I'm
sittin here banging my head against the
wall and I'm like thinking well how can
I actually get around this right I don't
want to install any tools because I
don't want to mess up the machines
I don't want have to reboot the machines
if I have to install tools and things
like that now I'm sitting here going
well I need something that's not
intrusive right
I need something but I can basically
when I hit a machine and when I hit a
site I can just use quick and easy to
use deploy no deployment possible
minimal cost so it's got to be something
that's either open-source free or just
there right and I'm sitting here going
it's like well you know I do a little
bit mini for systems and you like that
and hold on a second I could also use
this to do if it's right tool I could
use it to do dynamically do dynamic
investigations so I could go in start to
look things or I could even go hunting
threat hunting is one of my little side
projects and I really I kind of have
some big rants on fret hunting if you
can catch me later if you want to talk
about them and I'll sit in here going
wait a minute I hit majority windows 7
to Windows 10 machines and Windows
servers there's a freaking really useful
tool on those machines PowerShell I'm
like how shall is so great I mean just
like you've got everything that you
really need in PowerShell you know it's
like if you never use PowerShell just go
and play with it for a while you're
never you never you you never want to
leave it I mean I'm almost on the point
of starting a you know hashtag Python
sucks PowerShell raw rocks because you
can do things a lot easier in PowerShell
and you can do in Python and I'm sure
you know Carlos Perez's was giving the
PowerShell training it
he's probably he'd probably more or less
agree with me so why PowerShell well you
have built-in reg X support so you can
actually do searches and you can
actually
figure finds inside your data blobs with
the Reg X so you can do things like pull
out event logs and you can match
usernames and domains and you can
quickly easily find information that way
so you could find if a user is on admin
users have been logged on or was denied
log on things like that
you've got built in functionality so I
just mentioned you can go into the event
log but you can actually CD into the
registry so you can navigate the
registry as if you were navigating the
registry in the river with the
command-line right so see the edge PLM
then you have access to your whole local
key machine and you can search that
local key machine and you can make
changes to it too so that kind of useful
and you can also pull out property
machines from WMI so there's a lot of
stuff that you can do now once you've
done that you can then place your
information in objects so a variable can
be defined as an object so once you
define that variable as an object you
essentially have the equivalent of a few
years use JSON you essentially have the
equivalent of a JSON blob or you have
simple things like here I can get the
Akal of a path so a local path and I can
show the owner so everything is an
object so I can bait so this basically
what this does is it says get me the
access control list of the look of the
root directory and show me the owner
right so this is like heaven I could
just go in open a PowerShell command and
I can start digging into the machine
right so I'm thinking okay let's go
through this journey let's see how far
we can push this wait a second if I want
to push this I'm gonna have to write a
script and I'm going to have to download
that script to the disk damn that breaks
my one thing if I I don't want to do is
change the disk or add stuff but hold on
a minute I do a lot of fret hunting
what's can anybody tell me what the
really recent techniques have been in
most of the fishing email attacks what
do most of the fishing email attacks do
exactly but downloading we're not to
disk direct to memory right so I said
well hackers can do it why can't I
if I publish my scripts on a local on a
local Drive where it's shared across the
organization or even if I publish them
on a private website I can just use a
command like this pull my script into
memory execute it and I have my
functions so I'm like yes I can do this
this is really great so I've got
everything but I really need so I start
digging into it dig into it a little bit
deeper so I've got an awesome start
right
I got registries event logs file system
I can even pull local firewalls if the
firewalls are implemented it runs in
memory so no this changes I also have
methods of actually pushing because in
the same way that you can download you
can actually do an exit you can actually
do a network connection and push
information up into a cloud application
or into a local web store or something
like that it's generally available on
Windows 7 or greater and you have lots
of cool u-verse or scripts out there so
do you yes you do if in is there's a
site run by there's posh there's a whole
bunch of people working on it there's a
whole bunch of stuff and get the power
shark or the new version of PowerShell
is actually being it has been open
source so you can actually download it
and you can install it on literally
basically every system out there
nowadays because they've they've made it
Universal as well so you can use it on
the daily basis and you can replace it
for most shells so I started digging and
Jared I could soon developed this
framework called invoke IR which is
PowerShell forensics it's a really good
tool it gives you everything that you
need to do essentially do disk based
forensics and you can pull out really
good stuff like alternate data streams
event logs prefetch recent file cache
but when I look at it I start playing
with it you need to deploy
ll so I was like oh no but then I said
hold on a second let me go grab a drink
and I'll think about this right so you
remember that hacks hacking command it
doesn't have to be a script I can pull
up any binary I can take that dll dump
it into a base64 put it into a variable
in my script load that variable in my
script and run it in memory yes so I
have my foundations
I've got PowerShell I'm gonna write my
scripts I've got built-in access to
things that are really important like
registries and objects and reg X is I
can put pulling scripts from other
people as well so I can start on my
mission which is basically to do initial
investigation on forensics and a little
bit of hunting this is great
so I'm digging through this so how many
of you do a lot of forensics in here
okay so how many of you actually use the
system resource usage database so Schrom
is essentially the Window System
resource usage monitor there was a
really good paper that was published by
Yogesh qatari as and it was also
published in science there's been some
people who've done work on it since my
baguette I'll get to that in a bit
but essentially what it does it's been
on Windows since Windows 8 and what it
does is it provides telemetry on process
and network monitoring it's it's if you
look at your windows services it's
called the diagnostic policy service and
it's continuously monitoring and storing
data on the applications the processes
and power consumption things like that
so you have all of this data in in the
machine and how the machine works I'm
like this could be really useful
actually so I read that when I was
reading the paper and I was like
thinking about this and how do you do
this right so how can you access this
the paper goes into it
so I'm what I'm really interested in is
really these two things right if you're
doing forensics two things that you want
to know really is what applications have
been running and potentially what
network activities been going that's
been happening right so that's really
interesting for me especially to
initiate that investigation and say okay
this machine looks interesting I need to
do further deeper forensics so what is
in trunk show shrum essentially has five
core components there's a few more since
Windows 10 and Server 2012 so you've got
application resource usage so basically
what that one says is I'm going to it
monitors all the applications what it's
using in terms of network what it's
using in terms of power consumption and
how long it's been running and things
like that windows push notifications as
it sounds it's like when Windows is
pushing you information so when Windows
reports information to you things like a
crash energy usage so that's literally
energy usage right so we're talking
about how much power the operating is
operating system is drawing how much
power when an application is drawing in
things like that the network
connectivity this is actually really
interesting so basically what it does is
it looks at all in the network
connections that are being created or
torn down on the machine right so it
actually tells you when your laptop is
connecting to a Wi-Fi connection and
it'll tell you which Isis ID you'll be
able to dig out which SSID was connected
to it'll tell you if a VPN service
provider you network interface has been
created network data usage that map's
how much read and write network activity
is happening per application and that
could be very useful if you want to say
detect something like Explorer doing a
lot of file uploads somewhere or doing a
lot of alteration so network but what it
provides is an interface type an ID a
network profile ID so if you think about
in your
windows networking stack you have
essentially the interface idea which we
might be in if Ethernet why I'm leaf in
it too and then you have your network
profile D which might be home network
you know work Network a domain name
because you know most of the domain
names become the network
you've got the bytes uploaded and
downloaded process consuming the data
and it includes the user SSID really oh
that's interesting
because if I have network activity plus
application plus user ID I can look if
it's a non-standard user trying to
upload stuff or pushing network activity
interesting unfortunately it doesn't
have endpoint IP address ports and does
that have specific network activity so
you won't be able to pull out Explorer
going to FTP : ay-ay-ay-ay-ay
right so you won't be able to get that
kind of level of detail but you get
enough detail to understand which
applications and which users doing the
most network activity and you could
build because you can pull it out over
time you can start to look at building
graphics that's more of deeper into
forensics so the application that
provides is number of CPU cycles number
of context wishes IO reads writes number
of read operations number of write
operation number flushes so a lot
everything that has to do with
application memory management the infant
user information includes the s ID of
the user launched the application so you
know one of our favorite attacker
techniques is to basically n--'s
interpret you know install a install a
backdoor user you get that backdoor user
and you start running applications when
you try to escalate and then using
Benjamin's tools together and then
password you get into the Uni start you
start an admin process right so you can
actually see this because you've got the
SSID was actually you won't seen the
application it doesn't have memory
information so you don't have access to
the memory this is an if what I want is
an initial investigation I'm not that
concerned with the memory right if I
need to do the memory then I'll pull
down then I'll do the proper imaging but
I want to understand if anything's
happened on that machine before I do
that
so application history so if you look in
your windows 10 there's and you go to
task manager you go to advanced there's
an extra tab called application history
and what it basically does is it shows
you all these applications the time
that's run the network usage but you can
also go show history for all processes
what that does is it actually shows you
what processes or applications have been
created and deleted because the deleted
applications will still show in this
list I'll just show up as deleted or and
I think it says uninstalled to be
precise so those applications were run
but we're know I'm no longer available
on this so if you have a user ves
installing illegitimate software that
potentially allows you to actually see
it so how does it work so essentially
the diagnostic policy service use this
for DLL v DLL sorry but control what the
network what it's gathering so between
network push notifications and
application activity it stores it
temporarily into the registry and then
dumps it to disk so that dump happens
every 60 minutes so you can actually go
into the registry you can see the strong
extensions and all those ideas are
basically the DLL are used by diagnostic
policy services to do its work and as I
said every 67 minutes I will get through
this you dumped a disk so I'm like ok
this is cool so the database on disk is
in C Window System for two SR us are you
DB that it's an extensible storage
engine so if you're working with a D if
you've worked with Windows updates
windows search ESS is sent it's one of
the key things that you need to learn in
forensics when you're doing Windows
forensics because a lot of information
is stored in these types of databases
it's I'm not going to go much into the
extensible storage engine I hate the
dancing it's a pain in the ass
ten years
you have tables the tables are based on
your dll's so the original tables were
just these so the table name is this
horrible ID which is a real pain in the
ass to use and I'm description on the
site so the first one network
connectivity data then you have the
application resource usage data you have
the network usage data you have the
windows push notification data you have
energy usage data and you've got two so
the LT on this one means long term oh
that's interesting so that means your
top you're storing energy consumption
over a long term periods of times as
well so it could be quite useful
there is a documentation project at this
URL I'll really subside after words
anyway so don't it's long and
complicated but if you look up lib y'all
es DB yes EB B she's probably find it's
on github so he started documenting some
of this stuff so what's in the tables
well the network usage monitor is pretty
simple you've got an auto increment ID
it's a database right so we need an ID
you've got a timestamp cool that's cool
you've got an app ID you've got an
interface new ID you know got an l2
profile ID okay so wait a second these
are all IDs where do I find the actual
information so for the l2 profile I need
to actually pull stuff from registry the
app ID and user ID points to a date to a
database in the year in this from DB
called through DB ID map table we'll get
to that one later what really got caught
my eye is that wait a minute time stamp
really multiple different versions or
can't you just stick with one so I
haven't figured this one out yet but
essentially it's a 64-bit value so you
can just convert it into time and I'm
not really concerned on exact times I
just want to know rough times because
initial investigation again right so
useful this is the application resource
usage
so this is really this is some of the
interesting type stuff right so you've
got the same problems of IDs pulling
stuff off the the date of the date but
you've got things like it's telling you
how much time is spent in the foreground
how much times then background how much
face time the application has how much
so face time I think and I'm not sure
because this is not documented right
it's when it's how much time has been
used the application has actually been
used by the user versus a foreground
cycle time which is the application is
running in the foreground that means
it's got the foreground CPU cycles you
up the context which is and then you've
got some really interesting information
on reads and writes so if you dump big
data you're gonna see a lot of rights
for example so that could be let's this
is all information about you could be
useful right you can think about how you
can use the extrapolate this information
to understand what a process is doing
the shrub DB ID so this one's really
simple until you get to the ID blob
large binary data plus and when you
actually look at what the ID type
indicates so you've got four values for
the ID type 0 1 2 & 3 that actually
defines what's in the ID blob okay this
is getting complicated so if you have a
value of 0 you've got an application
path utf-16 encoded string you got i
think ID one is services at least it
looks like service definitions ID -
looks like MS apps you know the will be
the ones that you download from the
Windows Store or the ones that you see
in the in Cortana and windows 10 the
service sub process is so if you look at
a service in Windows 10 you have the
service framework and then you can
actually launch sub you know sub
services within that framework so the
service sub process seems to be those
sub dll's that you're launching in a
service framework
and then you have the s ID as an ID blob
so it's actually not even in clear-text
so basically we have to do is you have
to convert that s ID back into well the
blob internet ID so the interface new ID
is one of my pains right now because
it's essentially defined as this in code
so you have to pull out the information
to then extract the strings but also
stack the registry ID so that you can go
back into the registry and look for the
actual interface definition so it's not
it's not a lot of fun so what's the
forensics angle on this right how do we
do this how do we get access to this
information well if you're thinking
about what this is providing we have a
process map right we can build a process
map because we have the ID and the
processes that are being launched we
know who launched what so we can see who
launched what and more importantly we
can see who launched what when so if you
have a bunch of systems when were in
office and you start to see applications
being launched at 3 o'clock in the
morning you know the classic scenario
that machines probably being compromised
I've actually been in situations where
they've had to go back and look at the
CCTV to make sure that there was nobody
at 3 o'clock in the morning which is
always fun you have the network
statistics where you understand where
well how much data is being written and
from what processed on to the network
you've got a program tracking find those
deleted apps process run times you know
how long the process has been running
right most users will run the apps most
normal users will run an app and kill it
right and well exit it if you see an app
that's running for like 7 or 8 days on a
row on a you started user machines
probably something wrong because
normally that doesn't happen but then
you add usage energy usage and I
actually wrote this before the norsk
incident
hold on a second if I can see how much
energy process is pulling could we like
she backtrack this to understanding if
there's some kind of crypto minor or
some kind of ransomware happening via
one of these processes I'm thinking more
you know the Java side injections of
crypto miners which is always
interesting because you also want to
understand performance right so one of
the things that this does actually
provide is better run time processing
mapping if you think about your
traditional forensics in Windows when
you're looking at when a process has
been launched you typically look at the
prefetch information right so I mean if
the guys have done in DOS forensics in
here you're probably shaking your head
right you first thing you go for is dump
the prefetch right so but promise the
prefetch is it only shows you the start
time doesn't show you how long the
process has been running and plus it's
easy to mess with as an attacker Shrum
has a lot more visibility because with
continuously taking benchmarks on the
data right so as we have the completely
complete picture we can actually map how
long the application has actually been
running not just when it started right
so we got the start time and end unknown
duration so that's useful so the other
useful stuff is we map the processes of
the user we map process with network
activity potentially understanding
wherever we've got data exfiltration and
we have general process usage
investigation so just understanding
what's being running on the machines I
used to work in the oil and gas industry
this was the hate of my life
okay having to actually dig through the
machines because somebody ran something
they shouldn't have and showed it to
somebody else that's why some people
like the constant response indecent
response the decency response
yes I flew in for somebody shoved a derp
it's admin lock oh crap
mark Baggett's tool and the work done by
by the original researcher uses lib SC
DB to dump da SC 2sc V so again back to
my problem is that I don't want to
install anything I don't want to have to
do forensics the shrimp dump tool for
maggot actually force requires a copy of
the file so there's multiple ways of
getting that copy you can do a VSS or
you do a disk image right I don't want
to do that I want to do it online yes
I'm a sport Brett I've been in this tree
too long to actually waste my time
pulling images all the time so I want
really is a copy of the DB without
having to image it what access
to that did be without having to
image it so banging my head against the
desk again there's got to be a way
better way to do this I need to be able
to do this I want to do this I'm like so
attracted by this data now by now right
it's like the state is really useful Oh
second what are we talking about I have
a solution called PowerShell does
anybody know why I can use PowerShell to
do this remember I mentioned advanced
capabilities I can load dll's with
PowerShell but better yet I can support
dotnet PowerShell dll's so I can
actually run dotnet libraries and API is
in PowerShell cool this is this is this
is this is PowerShell 6 running on my
pixel book so there is actually a
PowerShell module and they sorry dot net
module to access these databases the esc
databases the reason is is that Windows
uses a lot of it so they have to have a
mechanism to access
that database so it's called the is is M
EF v NT interrupts DL the API it's
available in Microsoft and over version
4.0 does anybody know why that's
important
finally a Windows machine without
version 4.0 installed nowadays so this
is their this DLL is their I don't have
to touch the disk it's already on my
disk right I have access to it so I can
just load it yes we can do this now
right so I'm gonna do so I haven't I was
hoping to get further into my cut into
building some scripts and releasing them
today
unfortunately real world doesn't like me
and running B size London is a nice task
but it can take a long time as well so
I'll do is so I tend to when I'm coding
what I'm developing what I tend to do is
I like to basically step through my
lines especially a powershell one of the
advantages of using PowerShell is you
can actually before you write any code
before you write in the script you can
test your commands it's pretty simple
you can do them on the command line you
can do invite the ISE for the ICS
integrating script in just a script
editor and we'll see that in a bit for
those of you don't know it so basically
what I'm doing here is at the top I'm
just setting a variable to the path of
that DLL what's nice is you can use you
can reference back down into environment
system variables so a dollar env just
tells PowerShell to go look for the
system for the environment variables the
standard environment variables and pull
out system route
I set the path to my database so this
command add type half dollar DSN tab DLL
path that's gonna load my esc api into
memory so I now have a dotnet library
loaded into my powershell instant
session so the first thing you need to
do with these types of databases because
their jet databases you need to open or
you need to gain access to the database
right it's really hard so essentially
the first thing you need to do is find
out get info about your database and
that you need the file type the page
size and the DB type because you're
going to need those parameters to
actually open your instance and open
your database so what I'm doing with
these next commands is essentially I'm
telling the API but I want to get the
file type and page size by giving them a
default value and then I access I this
is how you access a dotnet a API in
PowerShell so basically you reference
the API we've got that API in hooks and
then the function in that dotnet API
with double double colons and then you
give the parameters and depending on the
function
you have to pass a reference to your
variable because the variable is going
to get updated within that function
right or you have to assign it to a
variable depending on the output so if
you like like line 12 you see that I'm
actually the fat once I had the file
type to get the database type I'm just
pulling out the database type so we do
that then next we have to open a jet
session jet session you have to create
an instance you have to create a session
ID and you have to pull out all the
information about the database that's
what all these temp things are so you
basically look at page sizes recovery
circular circular logging if you're
managing the database properly you need
to understand all this because there's
logging activities recoveries the
database might be in a failed state or
in a temporary state so but I don't
really care about that because I do all
I want to do is really access the data
and its raw form and get it dump it out
you then create your instance you
initialize your instance and you can
begin your session I still don't have
access to the database yet okay I've
just created a session to create a
database so if you think you know mssql
when you're trying to access a ms SQL
server you have to first create a
session before you can get access to the
database same principle right now you
can actually get to the database so you
can connect to that database with this
line you attach to the database you open
the database I now have a session with
the database alright so we can check
that out we can check for disinformation
is there that's just that was my coding
so down here I don't know if you can see
it well many far I'll take off so this
is the original tables what I showed you
right this you'll see on Windows 8
mostly this is the Windows 10 definition
you'll notice there's a couple of extra
databases in there it's like ah great to
figure out what those are because they
knew they're not documented of course so
next step to access that information is
to understand the columns because of
course it's not like SQL query which you
can do essentially when you're accessing
these databases you have to literally go
column by column row by row it's
horrible okay so you need first step is
you need to understand what columns are
available in the database and this
basically what I'm doing here is I'm
going to access this table I create a
new object or create a new object
basically provides me with the ability
to actually created create a session to
that table and then I can just get the
cable get table column names I'm
skipping the API parts because it's just
most of them are just gibberish anyway
just you just have to figure out which
ones are relevant the API is actually
really well documented the contents of
the databases is ship so here basically
what I've done is I'm using my session
and I have the table jet ID which is the
ID that's provided to me from accessing
the table so that's actually in this
table variable so I can build more to I
can attach to multiple tables at the
same time well that's good so now I have
an attack I've attached a table I mean I
know what cons there are I want to
extract the data and put it into a
PowerShell variable so what I do is I
basically put create a new table after
that new table I'm giving it because I
don't want to lose the reference I'm
putting the table name and I'm saying
I'm assigning it to the tag for the
label name I'm turning the label ID
signing the table the jet table ID okay
to reference it and I'm inciting another
P a PowerShell object inside that object
called rows where I'm going to put my
row information so I dump my columns and
now I have to go through this
so each column essentially has an ID and
a column type that column type
determines the value of the data blob
for that column so basically you have to
build a case statements which statement
as they call it in PowerShell to
actually go for each ID type and then
dump the the value that's stored in the
car in in for that column so as you can
see some of them have constants already
defined in the API right so you've got
long text text long binary binary long
binary I Triple E single and then you
get down and you get down and then you
find a value 15 okay
API no definition so okay it says it's a
date/time stamp so fine 15 is the date
time stamp we'll go for that so because
we know that it's in 64 date time stab I
retrieved the column as in 64 and then I
just do some conversions of that in 64
into into a date time and as always the
case where are crap didn't get access so
I didn't match any for column type and
then so now I have a column name and a
value I can just add this as a member to
my rows variables right so then this
next line we just move through each row
through the table and then of course you
have to shut down you don't want to
leave a database open you never know
what's going to happen it's like cool so
so I do have a demo but last time I
tried to do the demo it went totally
bonkers because I have to I have to do
it remotely so you never know so I've
got my walkthrough
I'm gonna do it so I'm gonna do my
walkthrough so first I load my variables
I learned my DLL this is the power this
is the power of using ISC when you're
testing and building is you can put your
script up here and you can go row by row
and just run the execute the highlighted
section and you can see what works and
what doesn't work
that's that's the way I do it I mean I
used to be a developer I don't do it
anymore my son is becoming a developer I
don't have the patience anymore to
actually develop proper code oh wait a
minute something went wrong oh crap
using the wrong user so if you look here
I've basically been told but I don't
have cannot access the file thighs log
to in use I wasn't in the right user
account so this provides have another
problem to me is I'm gonna have to
somehow figure out how to do privilege
escalation when I write the final script
right because I need to be an admin so
it was just a normal user come on no I
don't want to repeat this
okay so hey I have access to the machine
I think I think banjo man he was an
admin on his machine I can be admin on
my machine as well right because I have
access to the machine so I run
PowerShell as admin so now this is so
the difference here is I have
administrating the PowerShell you'll see
with my default path for system 32 I run
is see I can still run is see in
PowerShell I can load up my scripts for
my test for this testing purpose give it
a sec probably Google Google slides is
really good but I haven't figured out
how to fast forward videos in it yet so
I am a bit lazy so I actually took that
whole blob of for that whole switch
statement I put it into a function so
basically I'm gonna do the same thing I
run that had my DLL so now I'm going to
get access to the database well create
the session so I'm just checking the
values okay so DB type database this is
important this is another great features
that it basically autocompletes but
having that database type is something
that I can check on that I'm on the
right file right and the file type also
will tell me it's one so I can use this
value here to check for them on the
right farm and I've got a proper session
for a preparation and this gives me the
page slights if you remember at the
beginning I set the page size to minus
one so I know what I'm accessing
something and I have access so now I'm
going to do the jet set up in the jet
session
I'm just gonna copy everything and run
everything in one go
same thing I'm going to check the
variables what I created the the session
variable so this is important all right
so when I took just dump session it
tells me is invalid false and this is
all confusing because all you think I'll
false that means I don't have a session
but read the column title is invalid so
if you don't have a session that's
actually true right so I know I have my
session this is great I know I have my
session so now I can access the database
and I can see the instance as well which
is also saying false which is good
so I'm going to open the I'm going to
attach myself to the database and open
it
so I've attached myself to database so I
have a database ID for this session
still my session is still for so my
connection is still there and dollar
Connect
gives me nothing which is good because
it's not being used anyway so now I can
actually access the tables so here you
see that I just got getting new table
names so I can see the table names
there's that shrub DVID mat table that I
talked talking about earlier so now I'm
going to create table references to be
able to use in my script later so I'm
gonna open their tables thank you so
when I'm opening the tables I'm also
dumping I do a write output that write
output basically tells me to tells it to
dump the columns so you see here the
columns that we have so number one
you'll see that they don't come sorted
of course not then you have a column
type see the 15 I was talking about
earlier the length so for it's a
standard eight is a 64 bit 32 there's 64
bit and then you've got column fixed or
column honoring those are the types of
columns and so if you know database is
pretty standard there's the application
one well that's not that's the network
one
yeah web usage one this is the
application usage one next so yet there
you have the same table as I showed them
the slide so we have access to this
database cool okay great so I have
access to the database so I don't want
to go through all this freaking code
each time so I put that code into a
function there's one there's one floor
and this function see if anybody might
notice is it so I'm Pat the function
will pass the tape will pass the table
reference and then just go through the
row right go through the rows so that's
by doing that I now have a function in
memory right so I can
it's right there so you'll notice that
essentially it says you also get if you
coded your function properly you get the
reference to what parameters are needed
for the function okay so now I can go
back to my table so I do the table DB ID
first
and this is where I'm still working on
is actually because I have three
different values for the blobs I need to
go back and actually look at the dumping
of that table to fix the blob and pull
out the proper string and pull out the
SSIDs ID right so I can do so there I
just dumped it directly if I sign my
function to a variable I will now have
it in a variable and I can do some cool
things with it later we'll show you
later but I could format as a table so
we can see the data a little bit better
so you see now I have the index value
the type and the value and the actual
blog value right so that's the power
that's kind of like it's simple powerful
PowerShell when you get down to it so
let's dump the that new tape so this new
table this is one of the new tables in
Windows 10 but I don't really understand
what's in it this takes a while because
there's a lot the information in it
it was a good ten minutes of thing and I
shortened it in the video okay come on
so now I can do I can dump the table so
you see there's a whole bunch of ID's
here there's a whole bunch of data
coming out it's there's plenty of blank
data which is not that great so see we
have like lots of data oops
so here you see so basically what I've
done is I've this one I just form a
format table so it gives me a table I
can dump it to CSV I start to oversee so
that all the sizes the different things
so you see you've got this new table
you've got a PI D audio in audio in
timeline audio out what do you out
timeline comp dirty comp it's a bunch of
new data that looks quite interesting so
right now we don't underst we don't know
what app it is right so we have the app
IDs here right so I'm gonna pick one at
random
21:02 because it's right in front of me
so here again we have the power of
PowerShell I can just basically do a
pump that the my original DVID dump
where my object so I'm going to look for
ID equals ID index equals 20 102 then
I'm gonna format table so I know that so
these three lines are actually usage
data for a Microsoft lock act all right
so that's one of the windows apps so my
next step when I probably next few weeks
is to actually script this automatically
to be able to reinstate
fancy graphs and CSV no I don't want to
restart
I have backup so I just in case it's
always good to have backup slides so
next steps really about automating the
data processing I have to basically
extract the Shrew ID BET data better I
need to pull the registry entries that
I'm going to need to use I'm
investigating how to use PowerShell
remotely so you can actually use
PowerShell remotely if you have win RM
types built-in and build the module so I
can actually do that command where I'm
just dumping everything directly into
memory problems I have is I need to do
privilege escalation there are
PowerShell version implications so if
your organization hasn't been updating
PowerShell you might be in a two older
version of PowerShell so you only get
version one or whatever so you won't be
able to access half the functions like
the dotnet api's I so Windows servers
for some unknown reason the Shrum
database isn't there but the diagnostic
policy service is running so I have to
figure that one out and no it's not
again not documented Thank You Windows
and there's a whole bunch of other stuff
probably but then this so I beta tested
this presentation as I said in security
a few might a few weeks ago one of the
guys a university took it started
playing with it and he found out it
couldn't find anything didn't find
anything useful
there was only one month worth of data
what was it two years ago I think it was
out of Germany
basically Windows had to reverse this
whole mechanism and throttle it because
of privacy concerns and that's just it's
it's a it's a personal joke between a
friend on the Illinois it's an actual
keychain I have because I do a lot of
GPR work as well so that that's
basically where I am with that one but
so what about the hunting aspect well if
I think about the initial investigation
I've basically got usage network that's
good for user activity right so I can
start looking at hunting based on that
users of activity find my tools and I
can do it dynamically I can store
doing that hunting now if I add finding
files finding hatches because yes with
PowerShell I can do hashes dynamically
on the files so I can do file IRC
searches I can search Windows events
right
I had Florian name mentioned a few times
he's got a crapload of databases with
Windows events that you need to look for
you can dump configurations and access
WMI which you think about it the you
know these costly tools and this open
source tools what the hell they doing
they're just doing this so why should I
deploy one of these tools when I can
just do it with PowerShell built in and
that's how I came to this conclusion and
that's how I came to this work but I'm
been doing for the past few months what
was getting nowhere because the work my
real work have to pay the bills somehow
so that's me thank you very much for
listening
[Applause]