okay so welcome back everyone to the ad
security track next up we have Andrew
Robbins and Rohan as you might have
guessed by all the bloodhound logos they
will talk about bloodhound and and we
will present a methodology how you can
improve your security posture in Active
Directory
by utilizing bloodhound the stage is
yours thank you
alright I hope everyone's well fed and
starting to get into that sleepy state
so that and Andy can finish putting you
to sleep later all right so we're
actually gonna talk about bloodhound and
the adversary resilience methodology
today as you can see from our shirts
we're wearing blue shirts today so we're
actually gonna be blue teamers for once
mostly I know yeah this this comment
this hopefully is gonna be a disaster
because neither of us are really blue
teamers but we're just here for ten so
if we mess up don't heckle us so yep
that's me okay that's it hey that's me
old picture all right so we're gonna
start with the cornerstone of every
single all of our presentations this
great Court this great great quote by
John Lambert John Lambert said defenders
thinking lists attackers thinking graphs
as long as this is true attackers win I
love it when attackers win I mean no a
blue team so this is actually a really
important cornerstone of how we founded
the Bloodhound project when we were
looking through problems that we were
having on pen tests and read teams this
is kind of what motivated us to design
the project as it is just like a quick
show of hands how many people have used
bloodhound how many people have no idea
what bloodhound is ouch that hurts all
right well so Brown is a active
directory permissions mapping tool that
we use to map out lots of different cool
things in active directory like who's
admin where who belongs to what groups
and it lets you paths find from one node
to another and figure out how can I go
from Andy to domain admins or Eddy to
domain admins does it work if you're not
aware we actually very recently released
bloodhound 2.1 and by recently I mean
like three days ago
we hope that messed up Walters project
because he was presenting on stuff so we
had a few cool features the biggest one
is resource based constrained delegation
how many people here of read a lodge
tamir's post on resource based
constrained delegation how many people
understood it
if anyone raised their hand like you are
God so that there's a very complicated
blog post and thankfully we have the
great wilharm joy who can dumb it down
for us some dummies over here and he
actually did a lot of work on
weaponization using his project Rubeus
and we integrated some of that into the
Bloodhound project this is a really cool
attack primitive we've been wishing
since pretty much be released this
project that we had a computer takeover
primitive and we didn't until recently
the only one we had before was laps and
laps is kind of tricky not really always
supported however with this as long as
you have right abilities to this msds
allowed to act on behalf of other
identity attribute which is you know
such a short and easy to remember one
you can take over a computer too
the only only thing you need is a user
account you control with a service
principal name and thankfully by default
any user an active directory can create
ten of those so thank you Microsoft for
really bad defaults as per usual so in
the graph you'll now see this new
wonderful edge at a lab to act if you
see this you can execute this attack
take over a computer and go on your
merry way we added a bunch of UI
improvements there's a new database
warm-up button a lot of people complain
to us that queries are really slow and
we say well that's neo4j fault so we
actually does offload of the worked in
the o4j again because that's how we do
it so when you click the database
warm-up button we load the entire graph
into memory for you and then everything
is a lot faster
the downside is you take up like eight
gigs of RAM but you know who these Rams
like that's that's just cheap so yeah
make sure you have a lot of RAM before
you click that button once you click it
I think we saw speed ups up like 70% on
certain queries so it's pretty
significant
don't look at your task manager you'll
be really sad we actually went back and
optimized a lot of queries every now and
then we do this we just go through all
our pre-built queries everything in the
UI because we're constantly learning
cipher if this may be news to you but we
knew nothing about cipher before we
start using neo4j so as we keep learning
it we keep optimizing and we keep trying
to make it better just for you guys this
is this is all for you
not for us yeah for the people another
thing people complain to us about is how
so was to upload data
well we fix it yay that's a lot faster
now for pretty much any data type
there's a few few exceptions GPOs in
particular are to complete and utter
mess so they're still kind of slow but
GPAs were messing Windows too so that's
not really a surprise a lot of people
use the query debug mode for learning
how do you do cipher so turns out that
hadn't been updated since we introduced
the feature so we updated it now it's a
lot easier and it actually like formats
things for you it puts the query like so
you can use it like you know like you
would expect from something that helped
you learn but now it actually works I
promise there's tons and tons of bug
fixes underneath the hood not just from
us actually I would say this particular
release had more community contribution
than just about any other release we've
had particularly from people like Dirk
yon who is somewhere there yeah and the
the great crypto ml and Clement node in
and we got a bunch of other thing I I
called out a whole bunch of people in my
blog post to make sure that everyone got
credit where it was due but this this
was really more a bug fix release than
anything but we don't like doing minor
releases so we just made a two point one
there's help text built into the UI
apparently nobody knows about this
feature if you right-click on an edge in
the bloodhound UI it actually pops up a
big help window which even tells you
exactly how to exploit stuff it's really
kind of just lazy mode and it looks like
that so we actually went back and
updated a bunch of help text so nobody
can use it this is actually the help
test for Adelaide to act so when you
look at this it'll give you some general
information you know if you go to the
abuse info tab over there it actually
walk you through
how to exploit this entire thing using
Rubeus thanks to will for doing that
wonderful write-up for us we also made a
lot of collector improvements the first
one is a CEO logic sucks less I say
sucks less because the ACO logic is
always going to suck because ACLs are
really really really hard to work with
anybody who has had the wonderful
privilege of working with Windows ACLs
knows that they make no freakin sense
whatsoever and they have all sorts of
rules which they just arbitrarily don't
follow so we tried to make it work
I took the suggestion of Vincent let's
do over here and redid basically all of
it from scratch and now it mostly works
well we'll go with that we made in the
Marais ssin a lot more reliable we added
a lot more fallback code like cool
things that'll find domain controllers
for you again lots of bug fixes many
from the community we added some new
cool properties like account of
sensitive and can't be delegated that
way you can actually cross references in
the graph without having to go back into
AD we had a no rep preauth so you can do
a s rep roasting which is kind of a
different form of kerb roasting the last
one we have is a bad EER vision I say
bad EDR evasion for two reasons one our
evasion is bad second of all what the
EDRs were doing was bad
apparently dealers were looking at shark
pound bin and saying hey it's sharp
pound so we just changed the name and
now we probably won't get signature for
another like month so yeah that's that's
another little thing we added in there
at the insistence of some community
members so it's it's always fun to play
the cat-and-mouse game I think that's
been going on for two years now and yeah
I don't see it stopping anytime soon
so we'll just keep playing playing the
game until someone gets tired it'll
probably be us either win or die yeah
winner died right yeah all right so
that's all our 2.1 features if you
haven't if you've gotten to use it
that's cool if you get to exploit the
new new attack primitive like you got to
come tell us because we're gonna geek
out so hard about it we've been like
we've been like really on edge about all
the new stuff that was added so yeah
alright okay can you
hear me okay all right sweet so first
thing I want to talk to you guys about
with bloodhound from the defensive
perspective is a better way and an
easier way a more efficient way to do
basic Active Directory auditing so some
things that bloodhound really simplifies
auditing local admin rights privileged
user behavior ad object permissions
group policy control and finding very
nasty Kerberos configurations or miss
configurations if you will in your
Active Directory so first let's look at
AD object permissions auditing so what
do I mean by that what I mean is you
have an object an ad let's say that it
is the domain admins group so you pull
up a duck you pull up the well first of
all you have to have an advanced feature
set then pull up the object then go to
the Security tab then go to advanced and
then you get this view right here there
is an ace on here at the very bottom
where it says David accounting full
control and that's pretty obvious it's
like alright that that user has full
control to domain admins group that
means that David can add arbitrary users
to the to the domain admins group
however what you usually see is where it
says like cert publishers when it's
authorization access terminal servers
the access just blank or it'll say like
special so then you get to click the
View button and then you get a scroll
through this nice view and to try to
find what is the ACE that is actually
applied to this object this sucks
so this is why things like Shaun's Apple
scanning script it's why Power View has
get object a close so that you can get a
list based output of what the
permissions are but in bloodhound way to
do this a bloodhound is we already
filter out all of the permissions that
don't have a currently known abuse
primitive and so we're only showing you
the aces that actually
so to say from every no matter that we
know about from an object takeover
perspective so for example in a
bloodhound database we have our domain
admins group there on the right and then
we have the domain user objects over
there on the left if we click on one of
those users we can start looking at how
to audit this using bloodhound on a per
user basis so if we look at the inbound
object control we can see that there are
three principles that have explicit
control of a domain admin there's 47
actual users that have control through
security group delegation and then the
transitive object controllers this query
probably took like 10 minutes to run the
number is something over a hundred
thousand and what that transitive object
control what that means is that every
object in the directory has an attack
path that gets them to this principle
using only using only LDAP we're only
using like 80 object takeover so you
don't have to laterally move to other
systems you don't have to password spray
you don't do any of that garbage you can
just do this all through LDAP and only
talking to one domain controller but
even this process already is kind of
tedious because we're having clip
through each user don't have to expand
that out and really the only thing I
care about is just tell me what non
domain admins can control any domain
admin and how I don't have time to go
through this GUI I don't have time to
run a script I don't care I just this is
what I care about is what matters who
can take over a da that's not a da tell
me who it is and how they can do it so I
don't expect you to be able to read this
the slides are gonna be available
afterwards so you can copy and paste
this if you want but after you've done
your bloodhound data collection and you
have a very well populated database you
can run this cipher query right here and
what this is doing is it's grabbing any
user that belong to the domain admins
group and uh saving that to a variable
and then we're saying alright now show
me any any object that has explicit
control or group delegated control of
any of those domain admins that are not
a domain admin and show me what that
looks like
in the graph and it looks like this
super-easy this query finishes in like
three seconds maybe and so again on the
very far right we have the domain admins
users oh this is by the way this is real
data we have the domain admins group on
the far right the users and then this is
probably the administrators group this
is probably the dope this is probably
the account operators group and then we
have these like random other groups that
either were added to the administrators
group or they have some kind of direct
control of a domain admin so if you're
looking at if you if you watch if you if
you watched a Shawn's talk about like
isolating domain admins this is one way
that you can do super super easily
looking at the the object tape over
primitives are possible just using
bloodhounds this is like two years worth
of knowledge and learning that and I've
done that he just dumped on you and like
30 seconds so if you don't entirely get
it like it's not it's not your fault
yeah this well so we'll put a blog post
out about this stuff as well so you can
like read through it at your leisure
okay so the other thing I want to look
at is group policy control auditing
alright who has ever tried to get a
handle on what GPO is apply to your
domain admins and who has control of
those GPOs that is not a domain admin
okay you don't count you don't count
either all right
why not it's impossible it's really
really difficult so here's the process
looks like gonna hide a high level first
we're gonna find each domain admin user
and every computer they use then we're
we're gonna find those objects in the oh
you tree because again we're looking at
GPO and that's gonna be linked to OU's
and sites and domains then we're going
to enumerate the group policy links to
those OU's sites and domains work out
whether each GPO actually applies to
each of those users and computers which
is always really fun and then finally
we're going to audit the permissions on
each of those GPOs
so every step is pane in in this in this
process so let's do it alright here's my
administrator user so I find him
a duck him or her in a duck and then I
want to see what oh you that user
belongs to you so this user just belongs
to the the users oh you so okay now I
have a different UI and a look at so I'm
gonna look at group policy management uh
here's a default domain policy so that's
gonna apply to that administrator user
okay well is that link actually enabled
yes
is it enforced this matters in this
instance it's not so I'm gonna keep
track of that also I need to look at
whether the oh you containing that user
blocks inheritance are we having fun yet
well wait we're not done we also need to
look at Whitney filters so is there a
women filter that is excluding this user
from having this GPO applied to them in
this instance no I don't have any women
filters in my in my fake domain but in
real life you will probably see a very
long fairly long list here okay so in
this view this group policy management
view you cannot see the permissions of
the GPO there is no right-click
properties in this view to look at the
GPO so now you get to go back into a
duct and you could have find not default
domain policy but you could define 3 1 B
2 F 3 4 0 - 0 1 you know yadda yadda
yadda you gonna find the the
quote-unquote gooood which is actually
not globally unique nope for that
relevant policy now you can find a look
at the permissions on that object and
then you're back here you're looking at
the aces in here like which ones
actually matter which ones are inherited
do these actually apply there are there
any deny aces that might screw things up
like this is not good this is pretty bad
so yes of course this process can be
scripted there are several people in
this room who have scripted out this
process but this is a bloodhound talk so
we're gonna do this with bloodhound so
what do I want I just want to know which
non DA's can control any GPO that
applies to any da and how that's really
all that I care about alright so we'll
jump back
decipher this first thing all this is
gonna do is find the GPIOs that apply to
the domain admins and then we can we can
render that so all of these GPOs again
this is real data
the gpo's are linked to the domain
object chase that down the oh you tree
to the members of the domain admins
group and you know luckily these domain
admins there with their contained within
the same oh you more often than not in
our experience domain admins are like
scattered all across the the oh you
structure but this query will find them
regardless it doesn't matter okay
those queries are gonna be in the slide
deck that we share afterwards so you
know don't worry about taking pictures
or anything like yet you'll you'll just
bill a copy amount yeah
okay so then things get a little more
complicated hence why I said don't
bother taking picture slightly more
complicated but basically what this
query is doing is saying alright I now
know what GPO is apply to my domain
admins now tell me through either
explicit permissions or group delegated
permissions who controls each of those
GPOs and exclude anybody who's a domain
admin I don't care if a domain admin is
controller they're the people I'm trying
to protect here so the result of that
again this is real data looks like this
so what do we have we have two different
groups this group right here and this
group right here that have several
different permissions that give them
control of the gpo's why is this matter
because with GPO you can do anything I
can make you run a startup script I can
give your computer se debug privileges
for all domain users if you can dream it
you can do it with GPO it's a wonderful
and complicated beast then these are all
the users that belong to those groups
and you can see that we're unrolling
that out that's just a native thing in a
graph it's very very simple for it to do
and so if I'm looking at protecting my
domain admins I need to protect them
from GPO attacks now I know I don't have
to like chase out all the other attack
paths that that
end up in the compromise I'm one of
those users on the left which in this
domain
all those users are like spraying our
credentials all over the place
all I'm carrying about at this step is
get rid of those offending aces on the
GPOs that applied the domain admins so
that only domain admins can apply GPO to
themselves and then we can periodically
audit this just it's very very simple
excuse me very very simple process
process yeah thank you is this my water
yes it is now yep okay so this is this
is like this is the tip of the iceberg
of like very very easy basic auditing
that you can do with bloodhound so next
one we'll look at is finding more
systemic issues so three things that
come to mind lease privilege violations
cross domain attack paths and attack
paths to quote unquote da and I say I
say da in quotes because as Sean points
out and again a couple of us blogs
domain admin is not the be-all end-all
necessarily exclusively unto itself that
you have account operators you have
Enterprise admins you have two main
controllers you have all kinds of
different principals that can give you
the same equivalent access as a domain
admin can okay so first one way to look
at least privileged violations and two
different perspectives one is inbound
permissions so we can find computers in
the network that have way too many
admins this is really easy to do if like
domain users was added to the local
admins group that's simple you can just
run necess and find that if you have a
group that has domain users added into
it
Nessus is not gonna tell you that no
script is gonna tell you that it's not
gonna unroll that out automatically for
you or forget domain users if you just
have like the everyone principle or the
authenticated users principle or some
group that somebody decided hey every
every domain user gets to go in this
group and I'm gonna make that group
local admin everywhere we can find that
really really easily with bloodhound so
again it's two three four fits six lines
of cipher seven lines of cipher and
the result of this is we have two
columns of data we have the name of the
computer in AD and we have the number of
unique admins on that computer we can
take that data we can massage it into
whatever format we want you can export
from CSV you can put that into Excel you
can build up a chart whatever as part of
this talk we are releasing a tool that
will help you build these visualizations
very very easily and one of those
visualizations looks like this so this e
these are the computers in the network
sorted by the number of unique admins so
the two top computers there each have
approximately 10,000 users that are
local admin on there then the there's a
significant drop-off and there's like
something like 200 admins on each of
these systems this is not based on real
data yeah doing this based on real data
it would obviously be a bad idea if I
wanted to show you host names but in
reality this usually doesn't follow this
kind of like extreme and then as a huge
drop-off it's usually it's usually much
more subtle there's usually a very
subtle drop-off and so you would have a
computer that has domain users added to
the local admins group obviously that's
bad it's usually pretty easy to
remediate but then you have all these
instances where you have groups that
have hundreds and hundreds and hundreds
of users in them that are granted local
admin rights you can fare it all that
stuff out with this I challenge you to
go find this in a tuck if you can do it
it's you're an eighty god that you can
do anything yeah the world is your
oyster you are Shawn that cough exactly
so what about outbound permissions again
in a duck there is no way to say for any
given user what permissions does that
user have doesn't exist everything is
inbound permissions that you have to
look at from either local admin or
eighty objects or whatever if I just
pull up Rohan's account in Active
Directory I have no clue what privileges
he has unless I take a stab at it with
like well he belongs to a group called
server admins so I I guess that means he
has Evan writes on servers don't know
with bloodhound it's a lot easier we can
we can find
outbound permissions for any object very
very easily so what about stale object
control thanks again to our friend Dirk
Aeon over there say hello Dirk young or
say go hot thanks of Dirk now we have a
really great case study of why this
matters and an easy methodology that we
can go through to protect ourselves from
a really nasty attack or an attacker
that has access to our to our Active
Directory and of course I'm talking
about prove exchange is there everybody
familiar if exchange it was like the
most terrifying headline that that that
came out in like the last two months I
guess because it's it's an exchange o
day it's one click to domain admin oh my
god
the TLDR on this is that whenever you
install exchange actually and you didn't
you don't use a split permissions model
which nobody does exchange grants itself
severe control of the entire directory
the domain head domain admins every
object every GPO every oh you you name
it exchange has control of it this makes
your exchange servers as sensitive as
domain controllers because of an
attacker has access to an exchange
server in a lot of instances they can
just give themselves the ability to DC
sync or they can give themselves the
ability to add our story principles to
the domain admins group so let's look at
DC sync for instance this this view
again this is real data we're looking at
the domain head which is over there and
they're very far right and we are
looking at every principle that has
control of the domain head and that that
control comes in a few different flavors
it can be like full control it could be
right dackel it could be all extended
all listen to the rights it could be the
combination of get changes and good
changes all which is what you need to be
able to do DC sync whatever so here are
all the users and computers that have
control of the domain head these are all
of our clients exchange servers this is
the exchange trusted sub system this is
the exchange Windows permissions group
has the ability to change the security
descriptor on the domain head
so all those exchange servers have that
privilege the exchange installer is kind
of a disaster so if you haven't audited
exchange permissions yet in your domain
yeah you should probably gonna want to
do that yeah so we zoom in on that
specific offending ace it is the
exchange windows permissions group has
right tackle on the domain head we can
also plot that out so we can see more
visually what the impact of that is so
here are the exchange servers again they
have the right tackle privilege through
group delegation to the domain heads so
our our argument is it doesn't need that
if you look in a documentation for the
permissions that exchange 2016 gives
itself I believe this this privilege is
not even listed it is listed for
Exchange Server 2007
and a few others but our pitch to the
client was get rid of that privilege B
and you're not gonna break anything and
you're gonna get rid of an enormous
attack surface because all your exchange
servers they're just hanging out their
way to be popped and the attack path is
possible in the exchange servers in this
environment was really nasty actually
something I forgot to include in here
from a different environment from a
bloodhound user who wants to remain
anonymous the domain users group had
been given local ebon rights on all the
exchange servers why not that's the same
as making domain users domain admins
it's the exact same thing it's just one
extra step in between just just to
clarify in case this is a little
confusing if you are an admin on a
server and you escalate the system you
are that server in Active Directory
that's a piece of information that a lot
of people just don't know about and it
makes surberg it makes computer objects
just as dangerous as users know so if
you've ever told somebody that you need
to remove a permission you need to
remove eleven rights whatever what is
the number one question that you get
back what is this going to break it's a
good question it's a valid question
thankfully
wooden is eventing I can come to the
rescue and it can tell us exactly what's
gonna break if we start removing those
permissions so in Active Directory
you know we saw the security descriptor
GUI before where we were seeing the
permissions
that's the deckle that's the
discretionary access control list that
defines what permissions exist on that
object for what principles to the right
of that is thus Akal or the system
access control list and this controls
auditing for this object caveat here is
that you do need to enable advanced
audit features in Active Directory to
get access to some of this data but
again if we look at this offending ace
right here we have one group that has
one permission to one object so we just
need to add one Sakka Lace to determine
whether or not we're going to break
something by removing that one offending
permission and if if an exchange server
does use that permission it's going to
generate an event because the computer
use that group membership to execute
that privilege so we can just add one
very simple ace of thus Akal we have
exchange trusted subsystem it's a
success applies to this object only and
it's for the modify permissions
privilege so now anytime that an
exchange server modifies permissions on
the domain head
you're gonna generate a 51:36 event that
you can then ingest into Splunk
queue radar whatever you want to do
don't just leave it in the Windows Event
log on the domain controller because
it's gonna get it's gonna get purged
when that when that log gets full out of
curiosity how many people have actually
like messed with cycles on any objects
okay how many people have actually seen
that auditing tab before how many people
did it on accident that's what I thought
so the idea is we now have the ability
to see if an exchange server ever
actually uses this permission so now we
wait
and the end result of going through this
exercise with our client who had they
already had really robust web
architecture really good steam or sim or
how are we I don't think we've decided
how to say that word how do you say it
Shawn sim sim that's canonical now the
end result of this is that the total
number of events we collected in 14
months with zero
we removed the offending aces nothing
broke and we did this five months before
dirty on did his work so when the
headline hit client didn't care because
the offending permission that made it
possible for this attack to work didn't
exist so you could do the man in the
middle position you could relay the
credential for the computer account you
could do all that stuff but the
permissions the exchange servers had
we're very very limited and you couldn't
actually do anything interesting with
that so client was already protected and
they were happy we were happy super
super happy by the way one eternity
later is whatever you define is an
eternity if you decide that two months
is good enough to decide that you don't
need that anymore that's all you need if
you decide to days more power to you
it's your call yeah fourteen months in
this case because our client was very
very very paranoid about it so they're
there their exchange their exchange
admin said that this would completely
break exchange email will be down the
CEO will be on the phone a company would
be on fire Microsoft would didn't
support yeah like you're justyou're
you're killing yourself like removing
this privilege spoiler alert nothing
broke and the CEO still guys emails
what's that 2016 I think I think
correctly but interestingly be like only
be like because they're running a
current ish version of exchange don't it
was a more new one than that the
permissions that were there were put
there by the exchange server 2003
installer when you upgrade exchange it
doesn't
nothing to remove legacy permissions if
you think exchange is cleaning up after
itself you're dead wrong is not and it
is still using the same groups to have
the exchange servers end so the exchange
servers they have these permissions that
maybe we're necessary 16 years ago
probably not probably not and the
permissions are still there so leg rohan
said this is something you should audit
for all right
what about cross domain attack paths
this is kind of interesting because as
we all know domain trusts are not a
security boundary and if you go to will
and Lee's talk tomorrow you'll see that
something else is not a truss boundary
all right
so unfortunately a lot of organizations
do treat domain trust boundaries as
security boundaries and it was just
maybe a merger acquisition maybe some IT
admin thought that domain trusts
boundaries or security boundaries
whatever it doesn't matter that's a
situation they're in and the the
remediation or the fix for this is to we
architect the entire forest that's a lot
of money that you're paying to Microsoft
premium field engineering or you're
paying other people a lot of money to
react attack that and you talk about
something's gonna break
oh my god so here's an example of again
the same environment we're looking at
we're just looking at is it possible to
go from domain user in one domain to
domain admin in another domain and of
course it is others yeah spoiler alert
so we have the domain users in one
domain and they have admin rights on
four different computers they have four
different choices they can go to then
there were five different privileged
accounts that were logged onto each of
these systems and all of this was in the
same domain then these users have been
added to a group in a foreign domain and
in the domain two
and this group had admin rights on this
computer so if you're following along as
an attacker from a domain user I pivot
to this machine I steal this guy's
password I use my my group membership
here to pivot to this machine and on
this machine this user was logged on
this user was added to a group in a
different domain and this group has full
control of the domain admins group in
that other domain if you think this is
rare just about every multi domain
environment we've seen has a path like
this this is very very common with
memberships between domains or admin
rights across domains like I think
probably like 90% of what you see so
actually the entire reason we created
bloodhound in the first place is because
of because of this case huge
organization over a hundred domains in
one forest global conglomerate type
company super super good security
posture so know what meso eight oh six
seven no eternal blue which was still in
sa tradecraft at the time yeah nothing
that you could just easily like password
guess or whatever like we're only able
to abuse misconfigurations in the
directory to achieve our objective so by
the third red team that we were doing
for this company we got da in one domain
and couldn't turn that in an enterprise
admin at the forest root so we go back
we try again can't do it then we start
we start Pio seeing out bloodhound which
was called test out HTML at the time
should've had a screenshot of that in
here oh it's so bad it's terrible so a
test out HTML we used to find an attack
path from domain admin in this like
random backwater domain to the one and
only enterprise admin at the forest root
it crossed through eight domain trust
boundaries and along the way we were
never popping a domain admin along the
way it was all this like like server
admins yeah server admin
it's like the kind of the underbelly of
of Active Directory control I just like
Shawn was saying with es AE it's
fantastic for protecting domain admins
it would have done nothing for
protecting against this kind of attack
path because you have your server admins
and your workstation admins and all that
so again we're looking at this from like
a systemic issue perspective so what
what how come how can we quantify like
how bad is a situation like from one
domain to another between all domains
and the answer is with bloodhound so
little bit a cipher we can grab every
computer in a specific domain and we can
return all the admins on each of those
computers that don't belong to the same
domain as that computer so I'm a user in
domain a I have admin rights in a
computer and domain B the output looks
something like this
so the right-hand column we're looking
at for in abdomens 41 29 29 29 etc so
the top one there there are 41 users
from a different domain that have admin
rights on that one computer so that's
the way like depending on how you think
about that that's 41 potential attack
paths from one domain into another and
then that grows exponentially as you
start multiplying these things by each
other we can visualize this with the
flow chart or a diagram yeah so this is
a little convoluted to read but it's not
too bad so starting from domain one for
instance we have 23,000 users that have
admin rights on 8700 computers in domain
two from domain three we have a hundred
and eighty-two users that have admin
rights on 1,500 computers at domain two
so basically like the the pattern that
emerges here is that domain one is
basically accessible from any other
domain there's a lot of work to do with
trimming that privilege if it's if it's
strategically necessary if if
that is not an acceptable attack path
possibility domain two is like
relatively exposed domain three has
relatively a small number of computers
that are exposed to foreign admins and
that's like ten thousand fifty-three is
that right can I do arithmetic probably
not a thousand fifty three thank you
thank you Jerry yeah so we can we can
visualize this and we can see
immediately like where the big issues
are now for this we're only looking at
local admin rights well we can do this
we mate with anything we could do this
with GPO control we could do it with
control of user objects you name it
every attack path possibility that the
bloodhound database tracks we can apply
the same methodology to find these uh I
guess these links between the different
domains all right
is it food coma hidden yet am i speaking
wildly and quickly enough okay so today
we are introducing a treatment tools
that we are generally referring to them
as bloodhound analytics first one is a
power bi workbook called bloodhound
analytics P bi X this is obviously a
very creative name that we paid
marketing people a lot of money to come
up with this is a proof of concept
charting power book or workbook in power
bi and the concept here is just to show
you how power bi can be used to make
automatic connections using saved
queries to the neo4j database and then
render that output without having to go
through the rigmarole of using the
console and export into Excel and going
through all that all that nightmare
so there's several built-in queries that
are useful that with corresponding
visualizations that are already built
they're very pretty
visualization for what it's worth
they're not too bad well have a blog
post that shows how you can expand this
yourself if you have some kind of clever
chart that you want to show you I'll
show you exactly how to do that using
the power bi query are not query
which but like data massaged language I
don't know I don't know he would refer
to it as the power bi language should
have named it a test dot P bi X just
call traditional you're right yeah this
is released under gplv3 and then it's
gonna be up on github after this talk is
over and here's what it looks like so
you saw this chart before whereas
computers by a number of admins then
also if we zoom in on the upper right we
can see percentage of users with a path
of da 100% Wow things are not looking
good for you we use this in our service
line where we use bloodhound to help
people get rid of these attack paths and
we're constantly coming back to this
after we say all right we're gonna make
this change in the directory and we
think it's a killer awesome idea and
it's gonna solve all your problems and
it's gonna be like remove remove an ace
from the dip from the advocacy holder
objects or remove the control from GPO
that we were looking at before and nine
nine times out of ten this number stays
the exact same we we were very quickly
disabused of are like initial notions of
how easy this was gonna be yeah our
first our first one was not fun yeah
it's actually incredibly difficult to
defeat an attack graph but it's it's
possible so he also saw this one already
so the computers but a number of admins
there are then something else we have is
like top five highest privileged groups
by number of computers you have admin
rights on so domain admin that's gonna
be pretty obvious sometimes you have
like an HR group that pops up here and
it's like hmm how did this happen so
it's a very easy way to get like quick
wins or like low-hanging fruit that you
can find uniquely using an attack graph
that you cannot find using built-in
tools in AD and it would be very very
difficult to script this out I think if
you're not using a graph okay so that's
part one part two is bloodhound
analytics dot PI so this gives us QA
checks for data completeness one of the
biggest pieces of information that is
severely lacking in most databases that
we look at is user session data because
most users will just do one so to say
loop of session data collection and the
coverage they have of where users of
the environment is maybe like 5% and so
you're missing
95% of users or where they're logged on
and you're missing huge attack path
opportunities you jus get the best
attack pads you have basic stats
regarding the number of nodes and edges
and they're different types so you can
see you know how comprehensive your data
is they're critical asset checks so
who's a local Lebanon domain controller
who can RDP do a domain controller
things that are universal to any Active
Directory low-hanging fruit where our
domain users at as low as local admin
where does the authenticated users
principle have execute decom privilege
things that should be very very easy
wins to get rid of that if you don't get
rid of them have a hugely negative
impact on your security posture cross
domain attack piles we also look at and
as is of course also release on our
gplv3 license and will be on github
after the talk so we have one slide left
is anything anything else want to say no
I think we covered it pretty well
everyone looks asleep all right well we
have a we have a lot of time for
questions but hopefully this is a good
way to make you think about defenders
being able to think in graphs now and
how we are trying to make this more
practical and approachable from the
defensive side bloodhound is and always
will be an offensive tool first and
exclusively is not a defensive tool but
we're trying to extract as much
defensive value out of it as we can
here's our contact info you can join the
bloodhound slack there's like 30 100
people in there now and awesome
conversations are happening all the time
and so with that we'll leave it to
questions thank you
are there any questions
thank you for my questions about how to
integrate like a tech path of your stuff
like backup systems system set
management systems or operation manager
like tie this into some kind of bowl
management or a system management
process that already exists we have
thoughts about that that's great yeah
that's all I want to say right now good
question yeah yeah thanks for the talk
and also for the tool it's a great tool
you mentioned a Windows Event 51:36 and
you mentioned it the client waited 14
months let's assume I don't want to wait
14 months let's say I wait three months
if it's something happens after that
where I still see the event and so I
could monitor that maybe something
really broke or didn't show up and so on
it was so monitor you'll see it denied
so yeah then you just be able to say
like oh why did our CEO stop receiving
email yeah and you look back through
your logs and you see hey they got
denied so then you go back add it in and
prove exchange pops you the next day so
right that's a great question like you
don't want to have something silently if
you don't have some kind of a critical
procedures silently fail without any way
that troubleshoot that so yeah
leaving that ace behind like Rohan said
you'll get notice gonna deny event
excuse me so you'll you'll see the the
event pop-up so it doesn't sound like
fail I've got a question more related to
OPSEC for when you guys are running
bloodhound
how many times do you see so you know in
general in your and numerating all the
admins in the environment and all the
sessions how many times do you see your
client come back to you and say well
okay we saw this because you know we
have internal net blows or we just have
robust auditing and we saw the sudden
one guys asking every system in the
environment do you want the answers
that'll make you happy or the real
answer I want the real answer because
the real answer is almost never there
are very few people who have robust
enough net flow to actually pick up on
this some of our more like advanced
clients that we run into they're
starting to pick up on it just based on
some behaviors and stuff like that
sharkon is not quiet by any means it is
a super super loud tool when you run its
default configuration which it's only
loud if someone's list exactly if you're
not looking for that particular brand of
data then it pretty much just flies into
the radar in those places yeah may
follow up I assume you are aware of
Microsoft ata
advanced analytics and they kind of
copycat it the lateral movement we have
a good relationship with ata guys so
yeah we do yeah okay any more questions
if there aren't any more questions we
have stickers at the front but if you
take a sticker you also take a business
card because our boss makes us do
business development when we go to
conferences so the trap it's up here for
you to take there's like little piles
meter down for everybody okay thanks
again
[Applause]