thank you for showing up Jillian oh yeah
I don't know about you but I had a
fantastic ad track having all those guys
here showing messing around showing
y'all this stuff the cool stuff the
advanced stuff the dude I'm gonna
present here there's no revolution no
zero day no it's just a way to query the
Bloodhound REST API by a PowerShell
however without being a revolutionary I
really enjoyed the comfort that it
brings when you're starting to play with
the data in a database and hopefully you
will you will find it interesting so all
the stuff you saw the new stuff from
bloodhound 2.1 has been added to cipher
Dorgan away mostly demo today
so yeah the title of the graph is like
attacker thinking graph man need metrics
and this is something I felt on the
floor that no matter how cool the
picture is from bloodhound and you can
show a path and but at some point we
still need to go back to a list and make
statistics about it and make numbers and
working with bloodhound directly in the
UI or even in a neo4j browser is not for
me it was didn't fit my workflow and
since I'm a big powershell fanboy i
decided to make a powershell partial
client for it so this is me this is who
i am or not we don't know we don't care
the agenda for today a very quick recap
on bloodhound since I did a bit
yesterday but I don't know if everybody
was here and so we'll just put the
concept back then I'll just tell you
quickly the motivation and the kind of
goal I had when I was working with the
tool it was also for me a way to learn
some advanced powershell function
building and stuff and then it's only
going to be commonly demos and and all
that stuff so
quit bloodhound 101 concept and
functionalities so this is gonna be like
really fast so don't worry I stole that
one from you but this one is just
perfect so enjoy it
well the Bloodhound fit so this if this
is your attack kill chain bloodhound is
not an offensive tool itself
there's no offensive capabilities in
there but it's a fantastic record tool
for offensive purposes I think there's
been a few talks around the topics you
also understood that there's value in a
blue field for bloodhound at least to
see what an attacker sees but also to as
an admin see your any your ad in a very
different perspective credits first of
course so two of them are here
I'm Joey withered over there so I'm I've
been following these guys for a while
and I've been starting in AD by copying
tools from dark operator and these guys
so I'm really happy to have them here
yeah unique perspective on ad should be
used by defense and I hope you got that
but also regular admin I want to see
there everybody using bloodhound and
talking about it and I want to give a +1
for the community so if you're not on
the bloodhounds track it doesn't only
talk bloodhound but anything red team
Pat d'Estaing defense there's really a
great community out there ready to help
ready to share and like I said you pop a
question and these guys show up an
answer for you that they will welcome
you if you come so for real they try to
everybody joining hey welcome so that's
quite good just a little side note
attackers thinking autograph so if you
if you pay a beer - captain Jesus he
will sign you're not aware that's being
said a quick terminology so when we talk
about bloodhound you're gonna hear me
talk about node edges and paths and
these also the the alias I took for my
commandlets so when you were going to
talk about this a lot so I know this is
simply an object on the graph an edge is
the relationship between those two
object and the pass is the nodes
connected by relationship yeah different
type of nodes so originally when
bloodhound came
she only had users computers and group
and because Rohan never sleeps at some
point here the GPO and oh use and then
relationships so edges started with the
default you had the member of admin two
and half session two top ones are now in
the most expensive Microsoft defensive
to it but they don't have all the
eighteen others so bloodhound still has
a lot of value
trusted by I put a bit in Greg because
it's just between the domains so it's
not really a relationship you query in a
path but it's also here if you want to
map the trust in your in your
environment
then came the ACL and the ACL add a lot
of complexity to the graph because each
time you add an edge you multiply the
amount so it's not adding but it's
actually exploding the graph and GPO use
came with two special so can our DP
executive come the famous delegation I
think we've been talking about that a
lot and the latest addition so the ad
allowed to act and allowed to act also
in in the module if you want to play
with this this is what it looks like I
think we've seen a few screenshots and
that's about it for bloodhound 101 so I
hope that covers just the base for the
vocabulary and here we go with cypher
dog so I'm a big PowerShell fanboy so I
didn't PowerShell you could do that in
anything but the idea there if you work
with bloodhound or start while you're
clicking around clicking around and you
get this RSI and the doctor stops you so
anything PowerShell is good for me
automate all the things what I try to
put in there mostly is dynamic
parameters so I had the pleasure to
spend a few days in class with the dark
operator and this reassured me so much
that he's also dyslexic very bad typist
and I'm exactly like this I've buried
two bad hands I can type so typing the
full names for an account was awful for
me so you have tab completion everywhere
on everything and I'll demo that in a
moment and then of course biplane combo
so this is a big feature of PowerShell
if you know how to handle the pipeline
you can just chain all your commands and
start to build very complex questions in
very simple syntax the benefit of this
while to simply manipulate the data so
I'm going to show you commands to insert
no to modify the properties to about the
objects to do things at scale so you can
I don't know add note to all your DC's
in one go instead of having to click on
all the nodes and go type your text
inside automate anything at some point
last year I made a talk about inserting
your entire infrastructure in bloodhound
I don't know if it's the best idea I
found this fun and now that Metasploit 5
has a REST API I think I'm also going to
put I need to build a module first but
put it in bloodhound as well so then as
an attacker you can you see your attack
graph and the infrastructure you're in
and you can like automate from you to
and the automation will choose the
server and the agent and because it's on
the path so you can automate things very
easily without specifying anything no
need to master cipher so you're gonna
see it's almost English English syntax
but I added a cypher switch so each time
you ask something you can also see the
equivalent query that is sent to the
server and it's from you a great way to
learn cipher maybe I went a bit
overboard but this is the the full list
of commands that are available in the
module because Jeff isn't over told me I
was a bad boy because I didn't use the
pure PowerShell syntax so I changed them
on to real PowerShell syntax and I added
bloodhound in front just to be sure that
you never type the full syntax because
it's too long and you just use the alias
that are at the end and that makes your
life way easier but if you want the very
verbose you can so as of now only demo
so first part playing go fetch simply
getting data from the database and
seeing what you can do with it very
simple command let's get back how node
search bloodhound node get bloodhound
edge get Burnham edge are reversed so
you know an edge is directed so we can
query them both ways find the target or
find the source depending on the edge
and then path that would be your
shortest path and path any would be
all paths so that's morbid dangerous
question to ask because you can get way
too many data back and he will go for
them oh so first one I want to demo if
you type bloodhound
you will get all the commands and then
you find on their RTFM the help page
that goes with it my help page are still
minimal cause like I keep wanting to do
the documentation but captain Jesus
keeps updating adding new stuff so
instead of doing the documentation I add
new stuff in it so the documentation
will wait a bit but it's gonna come and
it's not pure bloodhound so if you type
cipher dog you get the same thing so
this is how it looks
I'm gonna do it once man I told you I
was a really bad typist so I won't do it
too much but everything tab complete so
I could say node user and then I don't
know there D and you would get the node
of the user with three letters so that's
quite cool all the rest I'll just f8 my
commands but you could be typing them
with a tap completion full syntax get
bloodhound node type computer that will
return all the computers but you can
also specify a name and the name stop
complete you could specify several if I
get all the computers and because you're
in PowerShell you can do cool stuff with
a normal PowerShell commands after so
our grid view is a normal powershell
command but if you want to filter all
your data in a convenient way you could
do something like this and start
filtering on properties so anything
that's in PowerShell is yours to use
with which dyfodol gets wet so I find
this a great view is a one of my
favorites so I often put it in can ask
for one computer and then like I told
you if you ask for - cipher on any
command will show you the cipher and put
it in your clipboard so if I go now back
to bloodhound and I just paste it here
the equivalent of asking for a node in
bloodhound it's not that interesting but
if I click on bloodhound and you get the
properties here this is exactly what you
would see and in the object that was
returned from the
this query here so everything is here of
course you can query multiple objects at
the same time and get a nice table maybe
even truly start to compare if you had
comparisons to do which is not
revolutionary again but way harder to do
in the UI because you have to click one
look at the properties remember them
kick the other one look at the
properties and compare so here you get a
nice table and all the command leads
have implemented pipelines so you can
push the names over the pipeline and you
would get the same result what you can
do if you're not very comfortable with
cypher is get all the users and do the
filtering the PowerShell way with the
wit aware so here I'm asking for all the
computers where sensitive is set to true
and I could format table for the
audience and you get all your computer's
which so my table set to true you can do
more complex stuff so an old computer
where operating system matched n where
unconstrained irrigation is false
select name in object set and you get
exactly what you want you asked for
search bloodhound note this time is a
bit more complex it does the cipher
query to really ask on the server side
this time for what you're looking for
this is way more efficient of course and
I would recommend first filtering on the
server side to get the maximum of
filtering that way and then filter the
rest on your powers outside but here for
example so I'm asking for the groups
that have admin in their name and I want
the name in the description of the group
in a nice table whoops let's do the long
one first and the bottoms syntax is the
exactly equivalent but for the lazy
people or the if you're in a hurry okay
now you can search by property so here
computers that have the delegation set
to true this short to syntax you can
check if your property exists that for
now probably doesn't make sense because
we didn't add custom properties but when
you start adding your own you might want
to check which notes have it which not
notes don't so
there's no property with this and you
can do the opposite so negate the query
and that's what it looks like brings
back and if I do cypher you see the
query and you see that I'm using this
and your Forge a syntax will not exist
the property of the node return XML so
again a very good way to learn your
basic cipher if you are struggling with
it like I was a few months ago before
Waldo put me back on tracks now about
edges so the way network you have the
source you have the target and the edge
in the middle and I try to make a syntax
that you could query both by naming the
edge and say if you want to look at the
target or the source it's a bit dodgy
but it was edge and edge reverse and
then I came up with alias to try and
make a bit more English but all this is
the the same equivalent so let's have a
look
don't wait so see what group the user
gary is a member of and you get your
groups and you know that in bloodhound
groups can be nested so here you get
only the direct memberships but you
could say any degree and star would be
whatever so but you can say 1 2 3
depending on the degree here I will get
all the groups with the shortest intact
doing like this so he sees the direct
member of two groups but if I put the
star you get this and he's actually a
number of seven groups and if you want
the cypher you can simply do this I
think you got that time where to makes
it sound more English even though dodgy
English but where to use a Gary Catania
member of group it's easier than the
cypher query that goes with it so if you
can remember this you should be able to
find your way and then again I'm gonna
do some filtering on on the side once I
receive the data so where the main match
sub for example and you would return all
the groups where the domain match sub
domain does support this one is one of
my favorite gets like this syntax is for
me is like pure English there's no and
it all tap complete so you can really
and you can do it with all the audio
but I just showed the demo with the
member so let's start with the I won't
do the long ones I'll just do the what
what use a member of group we windows
authentication you get them immediately
what computer has a session for Gary you
get the computers what group can write a
generic write on what group on this
group and you get the the answer
immediately so yeah I don't know for me
it makes a big difference being able to
do this completely abstracting a cipher
and returning objects and I hope you
will find some ideas on what you can
what you can do with all this now when
you start asking for path I had to
transform path into object so that's
something to get used to but that's what
a path would look like in a in an object
way and each line is an object and you
could automate start automating your
attacks for example based on these
objects and you see here I haven't
allowed to act probably I added this one
just to make an example it's my database
is probably the worst idea ever because
I I changed so many stuff in there I
don't make doesn't make sense but it's
enough for practice and for demo the
same function then the filtering that
you see here where you can filter by
edges I added it to the the demo so you
can also simply say no AC and no GPO and
you here let me do it like so with the
GP yeah so you see I have a path of four
four steps but if I say we know and
there's of course yeah there's a nice
here in their own generic all but I
could do no ACL no gpo for example and
you see I get a different path with
different edges so that restricts it's
the same filter functionality basically
and I made the groups you can include
exclude I won't go into too much details
but if you play with the commandlets
there's a lot of lot of switches you can
use to get exit like exactly what you
want and if you go back with cipher at
the end you can document your moves by
showing the path which is the equivalent
basically of
doesn't change them so this what you see
here is exactly the equivalent and
object of the one you see you right
there right
so in bloodhound you can ask for
shortest paths all short is fast so the
command with only path is actually
shortest path and you can say all to be
to make it become all shortest path so
you will get way more path here and then
you put a format table
I lost my demo so I had to rewrite
everything before the de suburbia so
what you see here and you can again go
back into your cypher in your bloodhound
and get the same graph here that was you
know slightly longer that's nice whoops
I just closed bloodhound yeah sometimes
I don't automate all the things right
even your your logging to bloodhound
because it's sometimes a bit painful
okay and then when you don't specify
shortest paths or or shortest paths so
that's where the query can get a bit
more dangerous you will you will ask for
all the path and this is the one I call
path any to make a clear difference
again here I use those queries again on
a one-to-one but on a one-to-many
many-to-one on a big database big data
set you might start making the dog a bit
tired so be careful what you do with
this oh yeah and I put a safety like if
you don't specify any hopes he puts a
hope of yeah there's a few paths in
there so they're all indexed stuff that
that's okay but you see that that
returns a lot of data and if I do the
same thing I'm not sure the graph can
handle it actually because that's
returning the object is easy where a
bloodhound sometimes gets tired is
laughing the whole stuff so you might
not be able to graph everything you can
get as an object but we got that and
then good luck
so here yeah of course because I'm
asking with any type of edge so you see
the very long string with all the edges
but you got your cypher so if you wanted
to cut it down just erase a few edges in
your query that you have now and you're
ready to start playing in bloodhound but
the cypher is already built for you so
that's again a big advantage for me I
don't know again if this makes sense in
a real ad not really worried about that
and that was it for them the easy thing
so just getting data from the database
let me go back to my slide use case for
this anybody if you have a bloodhound
you might want to do something with the
data those commandlets are just a way to
read that tie and see what's in there
more interestingly you can start to
customize stuff I don't know maybe in
your environment you have semi extension
or attributes on the object that you
would want to collect as well but are
not collected by a bloodhound run a bit
of PowerShell collect your info and
pushing it into bloodhound is easy as
pie easy as pie with the with the
bloodhound so these are the cypher dog
these are the command 8 so new
bloodhound note said but how know remove
no a new bloodhound a remove bloodhound
edge there's not a new bloodhound path
because you create a path that's
creating edges between no they're not
creating a path of course and again demo
use case here I need to put use cases as
a red teamer baby in an engagement you
find new boxes new sessions you want to
update the data along your engagement as
a blue team maybe you want to map
something in your infrastructure I don't
know jump servers that are not joined to
the domain anything you might think of
that you want to add in your graph you
can do it you can even even imagine new
type of nodes if you want or like I did
with my Empire nodes for example via the
API you can do it in the graph it's more
complicated so let's have a look at this
I'm doing bub analysis but you could do
better so I'm just
creating a node named Bob same thing tax
and I create a node named Alice and I
can have a look at those two nodes
they've been created so the thing is
here when you create them I'm just
creating it with the name and that's now
really convenient the way PowerShell
works he's gonna choke a bit on this
because he can't align nicely all your
objects because you're missing
properties so I added a kind and because
I know captain Jesus adds a lot of stuff
so you can do Alice and Bob I'm gonna do
clone and what that does simply it looks
at the properties on an existing user
node and it gives you all the properties
with TBD so you can then fill the fields
but you don't need to remember the
property so you can add what you want
I'm ready
good yeah he came up and say we got new
edges ok cool give him to me and then I
think in a reply I said I showed him a
screenshot that I was updated so now all
I need to do if he comes up with new
node types is a Dominion I'm on top of
my code and new edges so updating the
code to 2.1 was as complicated as adding
this in the code bringing on again good
waiting back to them so I created Bob
and Alice and I cloned the properties so
now if you look at them both they both
have those TBD then you can start to
update the value so no data in
bloodhound is a I use the merge behind
the merge neo4j commands so it's it's
non-destructive you're gonna overwrite
but you're never gonna delete anything
which is quite convenient for this type
of funky moves so here I'm dating a
property of an may encounter I'm setting
it to true and at the same time I'm
adding my own property that I would want
to add on the object and now if you look
at those they have the extra property my
value in there and I'm in count set to
true so you can very quickly modify the
data and new properties and the new
nodes to your graph now creating an edge
between two nodes is also very easy so
the syntax edge create user owns user
Alice local to Bob demo will create the
so edges are directional and this is
something to remember when you create
them and then you can simply again ask
okay now that I created this edge what
user owns Bob and Alice and Bob deleting
nodes I added the little PowerShell
safety switches so before you do
anything you can check and if I say
nobody beat user Bob and Alice what if
he's gonna say this is what I would do
so when you deal with a large data set
this is a kind of cool safety just to be
sure
or when you piping stuff and you want to
know at the end what's gonna be the
results the what if it is good if I do
this you ask for safety I put it in but
we like to do stuff beyond say for
yourself
I added the force and then they're gone
this is the earliest message over from
PowerShell but when you got a valid ID
set which will like when you start
cipher dog or when you update he cashes
locally the name of all the nodes so yes
for all the names and cache name locally
so now I have a validate set with all
the name and when the name is not in the
validate said he spits this error so if
you had like 3,000 or more names he
spits along here you can put a try/catch
in your scripts goes to get rid of the
error but it's here that's the most
annoying I would say make an error where
say cannot validate the argument invalid
validate set you don't need to tell me
the hole but that's more of a PowerShell
feature feature so try catch and you
don't get yet if you were scripting I
would put the try catch in there and
that's basically the for command needs
to add no it's very useful but again
find your use case depending on if
you're blue and I mean red that would
really depend it now the interesting
stuff let me go back just to show you
some slides with the title so learning
new tricks black listing nodes doing the
path cost the cheapest path the Waldo
index and more cool stuff I explain all
this but the command which you're going
to use so owned and high values have
been added up I forgot to ask how many
of you are a regular bloodhound users
that makes sense so far I should have
asked nothing before actually
yes well thanks it makes sense good
these are the commandlets you would use
and let me show you all this again
should demo the notes so that's a cool
feature Andy I don't know if you saw
that but in the UI if I take a note
let's say him up in the bottom there you
can add your personal notes on and that
could be useful in an engagement or
anything you want to keep track of what
you're doing you can do that in the UI
and there's also a picture feature with
this I didn't find any way to kind of do
it by on the command line I'm not sure
why it's stored inside no you say no
okay I didn't find it so I was like well
okay cool then I know why I couldn't
let's have a look so if I look at the
notes for Gary
he has no notes for now I'm gonna add a
hello world to Gary then I can look at
the notes for Gary and I see my hello
world I added a stamp I think if you're
on an engagement and you want to keep
track it's also good to know who did
what and like if you're sharing the
bloodhound server maybe more people in
put stuff in there and so if I do stamp
it will simply let me see do this one
now
it adds the date time you did it and
their username that was running on the
computer who did it just like an extra
feature to be able to eventually track
stuff in time I did that you can
override if you want so now if I look
the rest is gone but I only have my last
message you can clear them and now
there's nothing anymore that was for the
notes
yes you can do it at scale I like doing
stuff at scale cuz next about what's
power share is made for so all the nodes
that all the computer nodes that have DC
in their name I want to put this eSchool
in in the comments and then I can have a
look and it's already done if you go
back on the UI and let's say it will let
me find a DC
and you see my this is cool no didn't
twice
still isabetta
so it's a bet on the Bloodhound slag and
somebody if you test it and you catch
this tell me and I will fix it no
problem now where my help you can clear
them all in one go same thing and then
you don't have any more so okay I'll
have to check the note it was the last
one edge info is an awesome one if
you're like me and you you're a
permanent noob so I keep learning
everyday new stuff influenced by those
brains I'm just the guy who tries to
follow and struggles man that bad I'm
and LP talk I don't know about you but I
was shocked I'm still digesting it so so
here it gives you exactly the same text
then you would find by right-clicking an
edge like Waldo showed you yesterday but
let's do it again let's take whatever
path right click an edge and if you get
the help you can find all the good stuff
under the world member of is not the
best even though that's the bug I think
I found like the references for the
member or about delegation so maybe here
you just paste it the wrong the wrong
stuff and because like any admin is lazy
and once while not lazy is a efficient
minded so he wants to get he wants to
get to the result quickly if you say
edge in for allowed to act online pangs
and you can immediately get all the good
blog post from wedging the dog to okay
babies to so everything that is listed
in now you can very quickly pop it out
start reading get your get your game up
and apply the attack if you like if you
find it next one you remember that graph
Waldo showed you yesterday we don't ya
mean
for each computer and that nice little
curve you can get in
well it's called edge count but I like
to call it top note because we're
counting the edge but per node I make
sense when I say so if you say top node
member he gives you all who has the most
membership in the domain and if I
limited to five because I want to do the
top five but if you want the whole
database to do it same thing you can
just have your count here sort it per
count and you would get that same nice
little graph where though was getting
you can limit it to a domain if you want
that might make sense in your report so
in the way you want to grab stuff and
you can of course get the cipher for it
and go back to the UI and document your
report with some nice with some nice and
sometimes it really produces almost art
I like it there was a gallery by the way
on the Bloodhound track for the nicest
nicest stuff some of them are funky I
see I don't know I'm not going to go
into details do you guys see the same
thing very often I know I know what
you're thinking of so top node
memberships oh yeah I had to find a way
to distinguish the direction of the edge
so member and membership or you get used
to I hope it makes sense in my brain it
did so these are the guys with the most
membership these are the guys with who
admin the most computers and you can of
course limit to not every time to get
the whole scope of your whole
infrastructure these are the computers
with the most and means these are the
nodes with the most logins these are the
computers with the most sessions running
on them and so on and so on so you can
really like whatever I was planning to
make a dashboard and he came out
yesterday with his power bi dashboard so
I'm a bit like a it's done house
it's a pen so I'll I'll probably make
mine in pure PowerShell with the
universal dashboards just to make
something different next command I will
show you is the list so this one I
dedicate to John Lambert and his
attacker shrink and graph defender
sinking list I think we're all defenders
we need the list so I gave you a list
command late and we can do list admin by
Gary and you will get all the computers
that are ant mean by Gary I mean - so
you know the direct admin derivative and
min delegated and so on so you get there
in there so you can do it if I'm only
the name of the director means in this
group and then delegated you get a few
more and that's the scary bit every time
when you show are the customers who are
you real I mean so there's way more than
what you thought and I think this is
something we in many talks we saw that
you understand the the nesting of the
groups and you can do this and show them
visually what it looks like again it's
an S my ad is a mess
this is like the map of the subway so I
just like the map of the subway it's not
only for an attacker is for everybody
also so this is a this is good to see
which and you can list way more so here
I'm something but you can list the log
on of a specific users for example and
you can return only the properties you
would want of the object I think you
understood this by now it's an object so
you can do your PowerShell moves once
you get it with you I put more in there
but they all make so yeah list the
member of a group and then you can list
the membership of a user so it goes in
both directions
yesterday Waldo also mentioned the cross
domain path so where you go from one
domain to another have a command let
call get bloodhound cross domain or
cross domain cross domain member from a
table where did they come from where do
they go to and then you can start saying
from domain if you wanted to filter that
cross domain sessions out grid view
which I think you understood by now that
it's just objects so you can do what you
want with it
hoops owned and high value have been
added so in the UI you can simply go on
on the node and market has owned our
high value if you want it to just as a
shortcut you could retrieve this by you
node search property high value equal to
again in search of efficiency
I created the owned command so you can
just say own computer and you will get
your computers marked as own you can say
high value and you will get it's useful
for queries inside to keep them clear
afterwards I can say high value and type
my stuff too
there's an example a bit below cheapest
paths that's the one I really like so
when I started working with bloodhound
and understanding how this whole stuff
work
one thing that blocked me is okay we get
all those nested group and maybe
actually the path that I'm looking at
and that is shorter has actually a
higher cost in terms of attack then a
longer path that will have this whole
chain of nested groups so the ID here
and past chip is 2 I'll show you the
cipher then you won't understand but
here I'm I'm asking for the cheapest
path and if we look at the the cipher
goosh that's the the bit in cipher where
that's where I needed while those two to
put me back on track yeah the syntax is
funny but then you start to so here
we're extracting the relationship
looking at the type and when it's not
member of we don't count it so at the
end you get a count of all the edges on
the paths that are not member of and
this is why I called the cost of the
attack meaning all the rest is 1 and
that's arbitrary I'm saying some you
might think okay some attacks are louder
than others and I would want to go even
further and wait to one specific type of
attacks you could do that the easiest
way I found for now without using dice
what's the name is Dutch I can say hit
me Dijkstra's algorithm yeah so without
using this you can already like count 0
on the number of with this technique to
go further and wait every edge with a
specific weight you would have to use a
procedure I looked into it where it was
way over my head I think
dear Qian looked into it if I remember
also in Python but you did and you
managed okay good I'll have to catch you
catch you on slack man and the same
thing so the past chips you can also
specify the same type of filter no ACL
no GPO no special whatever you want and
if you say no ACL but one of the ACL
still needs to be and now you can add it
separately afterwards and I'm not joking
everything tab completes every time so
this is very comfortable for me you
could get the a that's not a next year
but let's say I don't want the ACS but I
still want January right you could you
could just say no ACL but include
generic way and you can also exclude so
at the end you can really find you and
to get only what you want might be
quicker to type your cipher after a
while which is what I end up doing now
there at least by writing on this
I don't cipher so it's win-win and
that's the cipher we showed it already
path cost so here is a commanded to
directly ask for the cheapest math but
you could also ask for a path and then
do some kind of funky stuff to get the
cost of those paths let me just show you
what it looks like here I'm asking for a
a path from the user Garry to any of the
groups that are my high-value groups and
formatted in a table and while it
returns the problem I had with this is
cuz I'm using the pipeline so he gives
me an idea of 0 for all of my path so I
can't really read nicely but you see
here it goes from a 0 to a 4 and then 0
again there on mark 0 so I have a
command late fix ID I'll find something
better but you can do this and then he
puts the ID back and once you got that
you can do a path cost and he groups
them by path and you see actually that
the tens path he was giving me is
actually cheaper than the first one so
that's what makes sense for me and then
I could select the first one and expand
the path to get back to the surpassed
number 10 was actually very cheap cost
nothing you're already in that group by
nested memberships in the group yeah and
now we move on to the cool stuff so
pipeline combos in PowerShell you can
every object passed over the pipeline is
treated as one but the output is grouped
as a one list of object of that type so
here I'm asking fall to use a member of
the group Shimon mean just show me that
if name is not a real command late it's
a shortcut I have for me because I'm I
was asking names all the time so it
would be a select object property name I
just made a command it to do that
because I can pipe to name so it's
quicker for me should you get the names
now I get these users I can directly ask
afterwards throw them back at the
database and ask where are they logged
on chunk and now so the users in this
group give me all the computers they're
logged on to and then you can filter so
where they're in the sub domain and the
OS is Windows 10 let's do a format table
so these are the computers and you can
continue like as much as you want I made
some long ones just for fun but let's
read it first so it makes sense in
English what use a member of group
shimon mainly logon domain sub operating
system match then lists admin to select
name last logon it just works so it's
quite good do it punk you got all of
them
and you can eventually sort them by last
logon and export them to a csv and do
some reporting with it and now that this
is done you can open the CSV and you
will see that you get the list so
management wants the CSV you don't need
to come up with you can make it a
one-line
I love making one right
the job to do I try to make it one-niner
Thank You Don or you could do way more
than this once it's in Excel you can
start you're making a nice graph and all
that all that stuff sorry
my mother will watch this so I'm trying
to keep my language now now all this
whole module every all the commandlets
you saw all they do is string
manipulation to come to cypher and then
shoot it to the rest API with the dog
post query so if you're like Waldo and
you think in in cypher you can use
PowerShell just as your little notepad
to test queries and stuff and just put
your whatever you want but just put dog
post on top open the GME applesauce no
quote quote yes open quotes put a
closing quote in the bottom and just use
IAC as your as your notepad for cypher
and if you run this oops
shrink maybe you won't come up with
anything there was nothing but you can
write your own queries in there and just
dog post it to the the server if you
doing path then you might have to expand
well if you're using the dog post purely
get me on slack and I explained that the
switch is to expand the object the way
you want it's not too complicated you do
expand data or expand that Akama data
depending if it's a path or a node I'm
getting too too too much in details here
oh yeah now finally you were getting to
metrics so the idea with the path cost
and the heart and there is was to be
able to find a way to communicate
something meaningful to management when
we're looking at the graph or did how do
you how do you quantify this and the one
I came up with or while discussing with
Waldo was okay how many users can access
this group and from that group how how
far or how many computers can they
access so you get a nice butterfly of
users into a group and from that group I
can reach
so many computers and then he makes a
bit of calculation over it when you seen
so no group domain admin Waldo IO so
it's the Waldo index I called it in in
honor of Waldo and that's what it looks
like on a single node so it just pops
out the the results so you see here in
this in any domain I could specify just
a single domain to have this statistic
calculated just on the domain or you can
just let it run with the whole forest
and then here I had 64 users going into
domain admin 35 have a pass that's 54
percent of your users the average number
of hop is or the number of hub is 5.2
they touch one computer on the way and I
think that touch is important for blue
team dfi are doing thats on the computer
is where where you leave anything so
that's where they will have to go look
and then calculating the cost so you
will know there's five hops but actually
only 2.8 probably some nested
memberships in there and then so we got
into the domain admin and then going out
you have 33 computers in your
infrastructure and you can reach 33 of
them so here are 54 percent of your
users can reach the whole computer
infrastructure so I think this is a very
maybe simplistic way but it speaks to
anybody even non-technical even
completely just if you tell them look 90
percent of your users can access the
whole infrastructure nobody would like
it right I hope I hope management
container that's not normal and of
course cause it's PowerShell you can do
it at scale so all my high value groups
while do i/o form a table and using the
pipeline he's gonna start doing the math
for you and that's all here and you can
do your now's nice out grid view if you
want later then he does it also in the
pipeline like this then you can here
maybe start to filter is earlier what
you want to sort them by I don't know by
touch anyway doesn't matter but you can
sort your data without grid view I
really like it and then because once you
have all of this it it's hard to read it
does
make sense anymore last week I added
Waldo average is just a way of
calculating on the whole list of what
you gave it an average again so I know
averages are bad cuz we're not but it's
just a way to represent something
quickly and here again you would get the
average for all the high value groups
with multiple group and then yeah I want
to create the out bloodhound dashboard
but that's already done basically it's
less exciting now that you did I want to
look at yours but it's less exciting and
yeah like I said custom queries all this
black listing node so I just that was an
experiment for me I so here I wrote a
little blog post about how you can do in
cipher to blacklist a node and then
query path excluding the blacklist so
same thing there are commandlets in
there that you can set blacklist user in
the name of the user then he's marked as
blacklist with an extra label not an
extra property and then you have
commandlets in your path you can say
blacklist and it will calculate the path
excluding the path that contains a node
that is blacklisted so am i I don't know
if it's very useful for me was just like
when one who told me okay i'm i'm
removing edges from the database so i
started doing that and the workflow was
so painful for me like having to like
know which one was a la i'm partially a
DD or something it was too much for me
like all those old databases i didn't
know which one to go back to when i made
a mistake and subsidy living with a
blacklist and unblock listing node was
easier if you're interested in this you
can read this blog post and find out if
you want to know more about cipher right
here on the insinuated blog you have a
link to a little that's a PDF I wrote
that will give you all the all the base
about cipher but yeah basically that's
for a workshop we gave two months ago
and it's all public material available I
still need to update for the new
Edge's the the dog whisperer handbook is
not fully updated yet and that's about
it the code will be on github tomorrow
because I have dinner tonight and I
would like to get slightly escalated
reasonably but yeah we've been here for
a week we've been preparing everything
we've been working hard I hope you
really enjoyed the ad track and all the
rest of course but for us also is the
moment to let go of it so I'm not gonna
go home tonight and update the last
stuff and put it on github but it will
be there shortly if you're really
interested the beta is already available
on the bloodhounds flagged by the cypher
dog Channel and you can always get your
hands on it and hopefully find some some
cool stuff to add I'm not the type of
guy to do like PR don't get hub and
stuff is more I put my code up there and
if I have time I'll updated so don't
like the guy is not I made a PR he's not
replying or do it you know fork fork
away do your stuff share I don't I don't
own this this is like just PowerShell
sending site requests to the database so
I hope you enjoy it and uh yeah code on
github questions on slack and that was
it and questions now if you have of
course
[Applause]