my talk is on digital forensics an
incident response in G suite just a
quick introduction about myself I'm
currently doing cyber threat research at
IBM but my background is mainly in
digital forensics and interested in
response in terms of Education and
previous role and also shout out to
Mental Health hackers I'm CFO of the
nonprofit doing mental health advocacy
in the cyber security industry so can I
see a raise of hands of who knows what G
suite is I'm guessing us can be the
majority okay um so usually what I'm
explaining G suite I just tell people to
think of the o365 of Google so this is
the enterprise bundling of Google Drive
Google Docs Gmail and all of Google
services under one roof one billing and
can be managed by administrators of an
organization so my first recommendation
when we're talking about Incident
Response is to not get compromised and
then you don't have to worry about the
investigations where you talk about and
I do online provide I've have a blog
post I can share about securing G suite
so that it does so that it does reduce
the chance you get compromised so that's
the best way and I'll also talk about
the end kind of the lessons learned and
why this organization never should be
compromised to begin with but
essentially there's a lot of steps to be
taken as with any enterprise environment
that you're securing but when we're
talking about cloud-based enterprise
services the big thing is to FA most
incidents that we'd talk about when
we're talking about G suite compromises
could have been prevented if 2 FA was
enforced by administrators so that's the
big thing I'd recommend and there's the
link to the blog post I wrote about that
so kind of some differentiations between
what I'm yeah be talking about deep
her and kind of what obviously there's a
lot of different kinds of environments
and stuff but traditional deeper I'm
kind of talking about if you were to
enter a traditional Windows domain
environment at an enterprise leveraging
exchange in Active Directory and that
kind of thing
so starting by mapping kind of the red
side of things so we can get a picture
of what these hackers doing in order to
understand what we're investigating is
you still have the cyber attack kill
train as you would in any incident the
attackers performing reconnaissance to
find out what domain your G suite is
tied to and for example when you're
setting up Gmail you're creating MX
records that point to Google so if you
are searching a company domain and you
see to have MX records for for all the
Google name servers there's a good
chance that they're they're using G
suite to handle email a weaponization
and delivery that of course is how do
you get into the domain there's a lot
more limited options with G suite since
you do have Google's defenses backing
you it's not a web app sitting out there
vulnerable Google's locked most of it
down it's it's now what methods such as
social engineering can be used
exploitation again how how do you get in
how do you get into the account and
again you're not gonna be SQL injecting
Google you're not gonna be brute forcing
the Google login so you're looking at
obtaining credentials there's social
engineering and phishing installation
there's less like actual installing
malware on the service on the server
because again it's Google servers just
Google but we're talking about achieving
persistence when we're talking
installation command and control again
you're there's less communicating back
but there is ways of more directly
establishing a foothold and making sure
you have communication with that G suite
environment and on objective what do you
do and the prime targets for a G suite
environment are gonna be that you can
exfiltrate data if you use such
you have G Drive Google Drive which is
their entire enterprise file system so
there's likely to be a good amount of
information in there than just using
those email accounts to either fish
further targets or spam other accounts
and the SlideShare link at the bottom
that is a Black Hills InfoSec talk
basically the same thing I'm doing but
focused on red team is dead blue team so
I won't get heavy into much heavier into
the red teaming side of things but if
you're interested in learning on how to
attack G Suite environments I highly
recommend that talk yeah so what kind of
incident types are we looking at in
traditional d fer we've got a much wider
attack scope you have malware on devices
you have phishing attacks denial of
service against networks web attacks and
exploiting vulnerabilities and web apps
things like that again google's
protecting their infrastructure itself
so you're not wearing about those
underlying servers we're more worried
about phishing information leak which is
typically due to just incorrect
permissions you let people share with
everyone and to make it easiest they
just say share public so they can keep
dropping people link but then your stuff
can be come across in Google + account
abuse again they've got your account and
they don't really care about your data
itself but that account is just another
weapon in their toolbox the attack
vector for traditional environments you
have a variety of access methods you
could do public-facing web app
exploitation you can go the social
engineering route through a user
malicious attachment and a document that
kind of thing there's a lot of different
aspects G suite is more of a smaller
attack surface again you're not there's
a lot of the infrastructure that covered
that's covered that you don't have to
worry about and you're almost fully led
to social engineering I do put brute
force because it is kind of possible but
obviously Google will lock you out if
your
coming from the same ip of its excessive
number of login attempts but if you look
at that red teaming talk Black Hills
InfoSec recommends the methods of like
switching up your IP doing delays so
long term it might be possible but far
less likely you're gonna get in and by
just pure brute force in the environment
traditional again we're talking about an
enterprise environment with device many
devices many device types you might have
something like Active Directory where
you can find those centralized settings
but there's also a lot more like system
independent and user independent
settings that you might have to worry
about a single registry key buried on a
single system whereas with gee suite
you're going to look at the single
platform you've got an admin panel where
you have kind of that control over the
user and you're able to see all the
settings at a larger soap obviously all
those users are using devices so but in
terms of the settings for the
environment itself it's all contained
within the cloud so at a whole we're
looking at a more limited attack service
we're looking at specific narrowed
incident types and the data is typically
and configuration is centralized to this
admin platform as opposed to having a
ton of different sources and endpoints
and stuff so the main part of my talk is
a case study of an incident that I
worked and it was a fun one it was one I
like where you have like no information
basically the customer they their
clientele list which was kind of they
they had clients who their names
wouldn't be would they prefer not be all
over the Internet
and all of a sudden all their emails all
their customer email addresses seem to
have been compromised because all those
customers were reporting getting like
random spam and stuff and it seemed
there might have been as high and
they're the only place that they thought
that those emails could be in one place
was in G suite where they stored all
their stuff so
somebody had the list of client emails
they has to be in the G suite but they
did they had no evidence of compromise
they hadn't noticed suspicious activity
they didn't really know where to look so
they contracted out to nm sspe to
perform compromise assessment and see if
they got compromised so at the start we
knew there might be a compromise but
that was based on the assumption that if
somebody had the email addresses and
that they came from this company that
they probably found him in G suite the
company had done nothing again they
didn't know they were compromised if
they were they didn't know who it would
be so even if they knew the proper
procedures for like walking down an
account post compromised they wouldn't
know whose it was and we need to find
out everything we we knew nothing at
this point the who what when where how
why so obviously where I started since
since we talked about that narrowed that
focused entry point to get into a G
suite environment they had to have
logged in via the Google login page or
via third party app I figure best shot
let's just see who logged in so the logs
look like this they're super simple
event description a source IP and a date
and occasionally you'll get some thrown
in obviously this is simplified mainly
log in log out just because I pulled it
from a test account and obviously
redacted the data but you can also
you'll see things in these logs like a
log in challenge so Google detected it
was a different company this country so
they threw up a prompt a challenge
prompt or potentially the the login
failures would be on here well we saw
all log in log out there's no nothing
super suspicious so I just decided to
start going through the list of IPs and
see if they think stood out I didn't
have this data wasn't in a sim there's
no tools on github to process like G
suite specifically and I'm not very
handy or at this time I was not as handy
with
programming so I didn't like write a
Python script or bash script or anything
to look it up I just type to is a bunch
of times until I I found what I was
looking for post-incident eric Capuano
who was working with at the time on this
incident created a tool that would
ingest that CSV format and map it and
color code based on activity type so on
the map you'll see log in log outs audit
failures pinpointed and this activity
was pretty normal they were kind of a
national company and also went to the
Caribbean on occasions so this is kind
of the activity we would expect what did
we did not expect which I found when I
was doing all the Whois lookups again
this pretty map was post-incident was
this we we asked the client if they were
in Kentucky one morning and like Iraq
the next and they said they were not so
we we were pretty sure we found our
smoking gun at that point and this blog
post at the bottom he's published the
mapping tool for the CSV on github and
it's an interactive map and you'll see
that on the blog post you can like hover
over and it'll give you the details of
different things so if you quickly want
to see who was logging in from the
Middle East you can see that information
so that was kind of the thing that stood
out and it was a it turned out to be a
good starting point to just look at that
login like who has been accessing
accounts so we found out the account and
to contain the incident we decided okay
let's disable this account so someone
can't get in reset the password
obviously so they can't use the existing
password reset all login sessions so
with Google you can basically say I
don't care if they're logged in don't
wait to time out just they're done like
clear the cache or whatever so we kicked
out all existing sessions at this point
we're also of course telling the client
like hey we should get to FA in front of
this because we don't know the exact
source of the incident but good chance
this never would have happened with 2fa
so we recommended that
so now we know whose account was
compromised we know when it was
compromised which ended up being like
three months prior like it was it was a
pretty extended act time and we were
seeing the attacker like login every few
weeks and then like just not use it no
other logins of them they log in again
so they're there for a pretty extended
period of time and there was only a
single account that we saw this activity
isolated to no other accounts where had
an abnormal login in the locations or
times or anything like that it's just
this single account and so we've we've
disabled this compromised account and
we've reset all the sessions but we
still don't really know the initial
infection bacteria so to say we don't
know what the account was used for when
they went in and we don't know if they
what the attacker again we know they've
been there for three months and we know
they've come back to the account but we
don't know what they were doing at that
time and so if there would have been
some sort of brute-force attempt we
would have seen login failures just
scattering the logs but we didn't see
any login failures that user just got in
so best guess it was fishing so we were
thinking email vector and of course we
had the user of I've never click
suspicious links I'd never put my login
information and as much as we'd like to
believe that that typically does not
turn out to be the case but
unfortunately we hit a brick wall at
this point as it turns out if you are
the on the lowest tier of G suite they
only keep email logs for 30 days and we
know that the attacker got it in ninety
days ago so there's basically no help
and again the user is like no I didn't
get a phishing email and we wouldn't
expect that any users to hold on to a
phishing email even if they did
recognize it for three months and as it
turns out GG sweeeeet I'm like oh 365
which kind of has their investigations
tool where you can pull an original
email content search or whatever G suite
does not all you're gonna get is the
headers so the best luck I would have
been a no but I have even
I had those logs from 90 days ago was to
hope that the subject line or the
sender's stood out and aligned with the
time frame that we saw the login but I
wouldn't have been able to obtain any
original phishing links and gone any
deeper besides the content of an email
header which is quite unfortunate and
the higher tiers so this is like well
they changed their pricing but at the
time this was like the $5 tier $5 per
user at the higher tiers you do get like
longer storage on emails past 30 days
but I do not think you gain any ability
from what I've researched to pull
original email samples so that is
definitely a lack a capability that is
missing that is valuable to incident
responders that I think should be added
so yep it was a premium feature so we
knew we probably weren't going to be
able to find that initial email and that
phishing was likely the cause due to the
fact the attacker got in with a user
account with no sort of brute force it
did appear that it was a because of the
login activity it wasn't some
third-party application authenticating
it was someone typing in the username
and password it was an API activity but
we wanted to go ahead and try and figure
out what was the account used for so we
essentially pulled every single log and
part of my pre-incident prep when we're
like okay we're probably gonna be
investigating gee sweet I had never done
an investigation in G suite so I just
kind of had read up about what all the
logs mean and we went ahead and went
through those specifically focusing on
this one user but then also any abnormal
patterns we might have seen what
anything else but when we looked at it
it looked like the attacker just went in
and was there to watch there was no
indication that they interacted with
made any changes to the system or did
anything significant with the platform
no evidence they sent emails using the
attacker account and since since this
incident was initially detected solely
based on it seemed some
had the emails it does appear that the
account was used in more of a
reconnaissance fashion finding that list
of clientele that could then be used by
the attacker for social engineering but
there's no evidence they tried to create
files or delete files or use use the
account to send emails or set up any
sort of trust relationships so we're
kind of with again we're at a brick wall
so to say in the sense that we don't
have any like evidence of the attacker
actually changing stuff it looks like a
reconnaissance sort of attempt so we
want to look for persistence we've
kicked the attacker out of existing
sessions but what if they could get back
in and again the the red teaming talk
we'll talk about this more but some
varieties of ways that an attacker the
the kinds of things you look for at
passwords so if you have two FA enabled
you don't want Outlook or your mail
client asking every time so you can
create an app password that just says
like okay this is a trusted application
but of course that can prevent the
attacker from being able to from meeting
to FA in the future so we made sure
there's no app passwords in place that
weren't tied to the user the API makes
sure they didn't allow API calls of any
sort that would allow them to just pull
information out will two FA devices
obviously we want to make sure that they
didn't like enable two FA and use their
own cell phones so that they they didn't
get blocked by two FA and then this the
last two were kind of like really big
that I look for in any business email
compromises email forwarding and email
filters because kicking especially in a
case where it looks like it was heavy
reconnaissance based you don't want
there's no good kicking the attacker out
if every single email that's being sent
to you has a BCC attacker at gmail.com
and similarly filters making sure that
your emails aren't being dropped on the
way in to prevent you from finding but
they did do that anyway they they didn't
seem to
hide their tracks again since they're
just doing reconnaissance it worked they
were there for three months and no one
knew and they were just using the data
as they saw fit
so like Ron Swanson with bacon
be prepared it definitely was the reason
I kind of wrote this talk was because
when I when I found out there's gonna be
a G sweet business email compromised and
I knew nothing about G sweet there
wasn't any heavy focus online about
performing business email compromised
investigations in G suite it there's a
lot on earth 365 of course the general
incident response procedures stays the
same so I wasn't worried from that
aspect but I'm glad I took like a few
hours before the incident kicked off to
just click around the G suite portal
like if you have to drop the $5 per user
like if if there is the potential that
your organization whether in a
consulting role or as a internal sock is
gonna face G sweet let your analysts
click every button in the admin portal
and see those capabilities cuz it's just
so extensive and there's all these
little nooks and crannies that you know
look in because they do though mainly
people are using it for like Google
Drive and Gmail there is Google+ for now
and all the other little micro services
that technically could be used and that
in an that wall may not be used by the
organization it's a great place for an
attacker to create some backdoor account
in Google+ when they know no one's
actually touching Google+ but it's
insight into the organization so I think
it helped me a lot and speeded up my
efficiency and my ability to respond by
just knowing where logs were what
information was when in what logs what
was the best place to find XY and Z so
it's definitely worth the the extra
money on accounts if there's the
potential to just let analysts spend a
couple hours and get a feel for the
environment and get more comfortable
about where they need to go because even
if they're skilled in the IR process if
they don't know how to get logs from the
accounts they're pretty much stuck so
kind of
plans of what I have for the future is
first I want to get kind of it automated
like I said I did manual who's lookups
and they they took it my bosses took it
to the next step and made it so that you
can do lookups import the CSV and get it
mapped and so that's kind of a next step
but because G sweet does have an admin
API
I would like to script the the whole
process of pulling those logs let's just
tell the scripts that this is my G suite
domain and here's all the API is that
logged in and hey look using geoip
lookup we found out that even though you
specified people should only be logging
on from the US there's a log on from
China type thing kind of highlight those
things automatically and so I started
kind of doing a Python script but I'm
not a programmer and if anyone just is
looking for a fun project and finds this
interesting and wants to help out from
the more programming side of things I
love hope it's it's kind of a mess what
I have right now and then as soon as the
documentation got on like oh oo --the
sort of API stuff I got lost all I've
done as basic off with Python so I kind
of moved on and skipped the
authentication and went to the actual
like ir stuff but it can't actually run
until I learn how to authenticate and
then from my background in digital
forensics and since I'm working on my
second master's degree and it's kind of
relevant I'm hoping during the degree
I'll get to do some more research into
like more file metadata analysis because
one of the questions I get a lot after
the talk is like can you see if the
attacker touched the files and from our
basic knowledge of like how how the
timestamps works and how the logs worked
it did not appear so but like there is
not enough out there that I've seen deep
on like you know how in Windows you
could say like oh well if there's this
tiny little artifact that nobody would
think about or this registry key then
there's evidence they double clicked on
the file like I don't have those for
Google Drive so I can't say Oh
well the attacker didn't download or
delete anything but he did take this or
how do you tell if they downloaded it
and so in general metadata analysis of
Google Docs but like one of the first
thoughts that came to mind as sans has
this windows time rule so like if you
copy and paste the file then these
timestamps change and these don't but if
you drag and drop then these do and
these don't I'd like to see kind of how
Google Drive reacts because they do have
the updated and the modified and they
created and so if I copy a file what
happens if I download a file how does
the timestamp change on the system what
metadata appears on the file after I've
downloaded it to show I downloaded it
from Google Drive that kind of stuff so
that's the research I'm hoping to do
especially through my new master's
degree any questions about any of this
good morning
so my organization's a heavy user of G
suite yeah it spent a lot of time
working to secure it for our particular
goals and we have not yet experienced
this but it's only a matter of time
specifically about the file metadata
changes that you brought that's a really
interesting case because initially when
you said that I was thinking about just
reviewing the audit logs yeah but I'm
not sure if that reflects cases where
someone has might use Google file stream
sink two miles locally and then done so
that's the kind of thing to the sinking
of systems because a lot of heavy G
suite users will do the automatic
sinking but I haven't looked at the
difference like what tags are added and
stuff and I know in so other things we
checked for was file updates and of
course there's like you can see the file
revisions so you have a lot of
capabilities of seeing the history of
files but I don't know what capabilities
there are to just see like the little
interactions with so yeah okay that's
fair I think that's something we
probably should chat about yeah yeah
definitely
questions
hey thank you I have a question
regarding the different pricing types
you have with G suite so as far as I
understand you have we talked about the
basic stuff for I think it's for four
years here in Europe and there are the
business and the enterprise pricing
models are you aware of any
functionalities and the other pricing
sets that make your job easier so I know
the enterprise tier I believe the
highest tier and maybe the medium tier
have like a security admin portal that
kind of has more security focused
monitoring I have not gotten my hands on
that um and I vaguely recall I've moved
out of a G suite environment and working
with G suite environments I mean I'm at
IBM now they're not exactly using Google
for their operations but uh they when I
did use it I believe they were gonna
they were Google was considering giving
that like kind of security stuff to
lower tier the reasons I focused on
lowest here was a prepare kind of for
the least capability assume you're not
gonna have the pretty dashboards and B
because at the time I was heavily were
focused on the smbs they weren't paying
enterprise pricing and in general most
people who are looking at G suite we're
not looking at an enterprise deployment
of G suite but so in short yes there are
additional capabilities but my
experience with those capabilities is
not heavy great talk
was there any help from Google or did
you contact Google to gather some
additional information uh we did not
contact them for additional information
I mean for me part of that is just
pessimism I doubt Google is gonna help a
five-person company dishing out $25 a
month to to find additional data
it would be interesting to find out if
they they have the capability to a pool
additional emails but I'm kind of a
pessimist with the big companies and how
helpful they'll be if they really wanted
to give us that capability they could
like an organization that large but
that's a great question I'm not sure
what Google can provide themselves in
the event of an incident so how much of
a problem third party apps which use the
Google API there they're actually the
threats increasing based on light
because now I've moved into research
more so I've seen recently like in a few
past few weeks a lot more reports of
that usage the real threat is like more
of the aspect of like social engineering
because you know we teach users oh look
at the domain look for those shady
domains in the URL
well when apps are asked to authenticate
it comes from google.com it's a Google
log on page when it says hey log in to
authenticate it's a Google log on page
so if it's telling you like one of them
was they name the app email security and
it was like authenticate to email
security to verify that you are who you
are and so when you click the link to go
verify it takes you to a Google logon
page so as a user who's been taught hey
look and if it's google.com it's ok then
it's good and again those those apps
send emails via Gmail saying hey this
app isn't requesting our authentication
if your user who's only been taught to
focus on who it's from and where you are
it looks legitimate and then also again
that that kind of user behavior of when
they see let me do that box they click
it they don't say hey why does this this
camera app want access to all my emails
type thing users still aren't at the
maturity that they they process that
logically and say whoa a camera should
not need to read my emails type thing so
in terms of user the way how we users
trust apps it's a huge set and again an
incident responder who's
not used to kind of that that aspect in
the environment who's not going in and
thinking okay let me look at what apps
have been added type thing and they're
solely looking at user activity that's
one way to kind of stay low and stay
hidden Thank You Megan okay thank you
[Applause]