for the next talk please welcome Ronnie
who will talk about how you can attack
Active Directory from non Windows
machines cool thank you
can you all hear me okay all right
thanks for coming I'm super excited to
be here and give this talk this is fun
with LDAP and Kerberos or attacking
Active Directory from non Windows
machines real quick
Who am I my name is Ronnie I'm from
Chicago I have a DD when it comes to
security I seem to just jump around I
started a net second did AB SEC I'm in
prod second dev set cops but a D
security was sort of my first passion
and it's still what I really really love
researching and working and doing some
tool development in work the various
companies I just started at Motorola
Solutions I'm doing app SEC over there
I'm wrapping up on Twitter and I have a
github and I blog occasionally I'm gonna
be referencing several tools and
repositories you can find them on my
github and I'll tweet out the slides
after this so first a little bit of
background about why this talk this was
actually a lot of this material was born
as a workshop I gave at a Chicago
conference last year called con and the
workshop was targeted towards like
people who wanted to get into a deep end
testing so I covered a lot of the basics
and the and kind of the foundational
knowledge for AD security so I'm going
into this talk and I'm assuming no pre
knowledge so if you just getting started
in AD Security or you're just interested
in pen testing this is a great talk for
those of you that are pen testers or
have a solid knowledge of a T security
then my hope is that you might be able
to take a few things away from this and
learn a few new tips or techniques but
really it comes down to automated tools
are awesome and when I started pen
testing I was using a lot of them but I
find that doing things manually or
looking under the hood makes it a lot
more interesting and really lets me
absorb that knowledge and to be an
effective Windows pen tester or
researcher I really strongly believe you
have to understand the underlying
technologies that are in play and don't
just rely on the tools that kind of
abstract that away and I think that
manually doing things really lets you
become more creative as a pen tester or
researcher so like I said key takeaways
for you guys from this talk is if you're
new I want you to have a better
understanding of the underlying
technologies and protocols if you are a
pen tester or experienced maybe some
more tricks for your pen tester bag the
slides are dense I'm going
have a lot of screenshots and commands
in there and I'm gonna sorry but kind of
be clicking through them quickly but I
did that deliberately because I like
slides that can be taken as kind of a
standalone cheat sheet so you can always
reference these slides if you're on an
assessment or you just playing around in
your lab and really what it comes down
to is I put this talk together as the
talk that I would have loved to have
seen a couple years ago when I was
getting started in ad security there was
concepts that weren't quite clear to me
I wanted to see things in action so this
talk was the is the talk that I would
like to see and hopefully some of you
guys enjoy it too quick agenda I'm going
to do some level studying and an intro
and background to Active Directory then
we're gonna jump right into just fun
with LDAP an overview of LDAP and some
demos for doing LDAP queries and then
fun with Kerberos and some demos of
different Kerberos tools and techniques
and then hopefully time permitting I've
kind of been buttoned up right against
an hour but we have Q&A or if not coffee
break after this I'll be around so you
guys are in the ad Security track so I
kind of I'm assuming you have some idea
of what Active Directory is but I don't
want to assume anything so I just kind
of want a level set because Active
Directory gets thrown around a lot and I
just want to have a quick overview of
like what is Active Directory when I'm
referring to it so ad is Microsoft's
proprietary directory service for use in
Windows domain networks and when I am
referring to ad I'm actually referring
to a DDS or Active Directory domain
services and AD is kind of a suite of
tools and protocols and technologies to
allow an administrator to manage objects
on their network and an ad everything is
an object you've got users groups
computers policies printers subnets DHCP
leases everything is an object and ad
gives you the tools you need to kind of
remotely manage them and it relies on
various different protocols and
technologies to provide location lookup
authentication authorization and remote
management in any single Active
Directory deployment though it really
comes down to what I consider like the
three big protocols you're always gonna
find these in play on any sort of Active
Directory domain and I think it's kind
of what Microsoft built a lot of Active
Directory up on and those three are DNS
L
and Kerberos so DNS is required in
Active Directory for resource lookups
it's how resources find each other and a
quick example is like DNS is so
important because if you want to join a
computer or you want to log in to a
domain it uses DNS to identify where the
domain controller is to begin with
LDAP is the directory access protocol
and you kind of think of it as like how
to store and access all those objects
that make up an Active Directory domain
and LDAP is a standard that predates
Active Directory it's an open RFC and so
Microsoft adapted LDAP and built a lot
on top of it and added some extensions
and new attributes but LDAP is really
really still the core underlying
directory access protocol and AD and
then lastly Kerberos the big one
Kerberos and Active Directory provides
authentication and a single sign-on
experience and similar to LDAP act or
Kerberos waiver dates Active Directory
as well it's an open RFC but Microsoft
took that Kerberos protocol or kerberos
RFC and kind of bastardized it and added
a bunch of things on top of it to make
it work but it's still Kerberos at its
core and there's lots of other protocols
and technology that I'm not really going
to touch on here but you've probably
seen NetBIOS MS RPC ntlm authentication
really all of this stuff is just it's a
hodgepodge that makes up Active
Directory but these are the three big
ones I'll be focusing on because they're
backwards compatible and open protocols
so DNS LDAP Kerberos they're open
protocols like I said and there's other
clients you can use to communicate with
them so when it comes down to is really
in the crux of this talk is you don't
have to rely on Windows to talk to
Active Directory over the network these
protocols are open and as long as you
have network access you can use any
clients that you want to talk to them so
from here on out I'm not gonna use
Windows at all
there's no PowerShell in this talk I'm
sorry if you were expecting that but I'm
only using pretty much Python and Linux
and the idea is as a pen tester you
should be able to pen test from wherever
you land if you don't have access or a
foothold to a Windows machine if you get
a web server or a container or a smart
fish tank you should be able to still do
some Windows pen testing if you're in an
Active Directory domain so these are
some of the tools you can use the talk
to these protocols here
I'm going to kind of jump into some
examples here DNS for DNS is in play and
a TDS heavily relies on it and you if
you have Digg or any just standard DNS
tool you can actually perform some
domain reconnaissance if you land on a
network DNS especially relies on serve
records to identify where the important
services are such as LDAP Kerberos and
global catalog which is kind of LDAP for
the forest and you can just use dig for
example to do serve record enumeration
and find out where the global catalog or
LDAP servers are where the Kerberos
servers are and start mapping out your
domain you can also use an nmap script
but this is just showing and my my test
domain here through DNS server
enumeration I can identify right away
that I have one domain controller and
it's called PDC oh one lab drop nap com
because that's running LDAP Kerberos GC
all of that good stuff that when you
identify an LDAP server and I'm gonna be
talking a lot about LDAP and a couple
slides but most LDAP reconnaissance
requires an authenticated bind however
if you do an unauthenticated bind to an
Active Directory LDAP server you can
still pull some valuable metadata sorry
I'm blocking it you can still pull some
valuable metadata from the LDAP server
itself and you can use any LDAP client
like LDAP search for example to pull
that data out so this is just an
unauthenticated LDAP bind and over here
on the left is sort of a snipped output
of all the attributes that come back
about that LDAP server I've bolded some
of the more useful ones but I think the
most useful ones are these three down
here
they're numeric values that correspond
to what the functionality level is of
the domain the forest or the domain
controller and if you just look up those
those values in the table over here we
can see just through an authenticated
LDAP lookup that we're dealing with a
Windows 2012 r2 functionality level MSRP
C is definitely big and play in Active
Directory and I'm gonna just gloss over
it real quickly here but MSRP C is
Microsoft's twist on dce/rpc it's
actually made up of several different
protocols but the idea is that every
computer within an Active Directory
domain can communicate to each other and
do remote procedure calls and
the most common way that our ms RPC
occurs is RPC over SMB so it's using
named pipes over SMB so if you've ever
had any confusion about like why SMB
which is for file-sharing you can get
code execution through it's because
you're actually mounting a named pipe
and doing an RPC call through the file
share functionality of SMB so all net
commands are doing MSRP see under the
hood so if you've ever run like a net
user command slash domain will actually
communicate to the domain controller and
do a bunch of MS RPC calls and it
establishes an SMB connection it drops
into Samer it does a ton of lookups at
the domain and then it displays that
information back to us but under the
hood Microsoft does all this
automatically and these are the types of
protocols that are in play for RPC now
though its proprietary there are other
implementations of MS RPC and you don't
actually need Windows to talk MSRP C and
the two big ones are the samba project
which has SMB client an RPC client as
well as a port of the net command or my
favorite which is impac it quick show of
hands who's used and familiar with
impact it before cool so about now maybe
three-quarters of the room impact it's
awesome I can't say enough of it it is a
full Python implementation of the MSRP C
stack or almost full so in packet is
like the Swiss Army knife for Windows
Network pentesting it is my go-to
toolkit if I'm ever doing a Windows pen
test I absolutely has to have I have to
have it but I will admit that
dependencies can be a little difficult
impact it requires Python to there's
some crypto modules that have to be
installed so I really wanted impact it
to be able to work wherever I land
anywhere I can get a foothold I want to
run an impact script so I released a
project it's on github I set up a CI CD
pipeline to continually build static
binaries from all the impacted example
scripts so these are standalone binaries
that don't have any other dependencies
and you can download them and run them
wherever you might land so under the
hood I'm doing PI installer and I'm
compiling them for Linux against the
oldest version of gee Lib C I could find
I'm doing wine to compile Windows Exe s
and then I'm also compiling them against
a different Lib C implementation that's
really popular in containers so if you
ever land in a container
like alpine linux you can still run
these impacted binaries and here's a
quick example of what that looks like
here I'm on a container pythons not
installed I want to run an impacted
script though so I just downloaded
directly from my github releases page
Acho mod + exit and then I have a
standalone binary with no other
dependencies and I can just run with me
exec against a Windows machine that this
container has network access to and
execute some commands that way so that
works alright enough about MSRP see it
it's hard it's gross
I like LDAP more so I guess that Active
Directory uses LDAP it's the underlying
access directory access protocol and
really every single object and remember
everything is an object they all exist
in the LDAP quote unquote database so
LDAP is kind of like your source of
truth for all this information in an
Active Directory domain and every domain
controller is also an LDAP server
listening on three different ports you
get traditional LDAP LDAP s for secure
and then the LDAP global catalog and the
nice thing with LDAP is there's really
no special privileges needed to bind to
the LDAP server and perform some queries
so if you just have the most
unprivileged user but as long as it's a
valid user account you can perform
almost all the LDAP queries you'll want
to map out the domain if you're not
familiar with LDAP I've never really
used it before the syntax can be a
little alarming it's based on X dot 500
I'm gonna give a quick overview here
essentially every single object in LDAP
has a distinguished name which is a
hierarchical path of where it's located
inside the directory but it's also its
unique identifier so in an active
directory a user object for example
Trevor Hoffman here that's his complete
DN and you can read it from
right-to-left hierarchically the DC is
the domain component and in Active
Directory you can take the domain and
you just split it up into the domain
components then you have oh use which
you can think of as folders they're
organizational units there's no rhyme or
reason it's however the administrator
kind of wants to organize his domain he
creates these folders called oh you and
then a common name which is the friendly
name you'll often just see it referred
to as and
single DN has lots of attributes here's
what that looks like in Active Directory
this is the LDAP entry for that Trevor
Hoffman user and these are all the
attributes that are stored for that user
that were able to query for with with
just a standard domain user and it
contains all his personal information
his first name last name address or
phone number email address but it also
includes things like all the groups he's
a part of some time stamps when the last
time he logged in or changed his
password is his gooood and his sid are
also stored as LDAP attributes and then
down here on the bottom his Sam account
name and his user principal name which
is what he'll use to log in to the
domain is also always stored in LDAP so
you can use any LDAP client but the
client I find myself going back to
because it's installed by default on a
lot of Linux distros as LDAP search and
LDAP search kind of has a weird syntax
also so I just put an example slide up
here if you have LDAP search and want to
run an LDAP query you basically just
pointed to the domain controller you
give it the authentication material like
a username and a password and it's nice
an Active Directory you can use a UPN or
use a principle name as the bind account
instead of doing having to type out the
full DN and then you give it the search
filter and the attributes that you want
so a couple if you want to just start
doing some initial mapping really broad
filters to see the information that
comes back and you one filter I like to
use a just object class so object class
equals user is gonna dump every single
LDAP object that's a user object and
some of the more interesting attributes
that are stored in LDAP for user objects
like we've talked about already are the
groups they're members of the last time
they've logged in or the last time
they've failed an account the number of
times they failed to log in the last
time they set their password this is ID
true information you can just pull from
LDAP attributes and this little
one-liner here will actually convert
those ugly decimal timestamps to a human
readable date object class equals group
will show every single group with an
LDAP and some of the more interesting
attributes there's common name which is
what you'll see the group referred to as
the members so the the objects that make
up that group are a part of that group
and then remember
because you have to remember groups can
also be members of other groups so you
have nested groups and if a group is a
member of another group there'll be a
member of attribute as well and you can
see if that groups part of a different
group computers are great object class
equals computer every single computer
that's joined to the Active Directory
domain gets an LDAP entry and Aldo's
LDAP attributes store metadata
information about the computer that's
useful for us if we're just performing
reconnaissance so some of the more
interesting information just for every
single computer object is we have its
NetBIOS name and it's fully qualified
domain name but we also have the exact
operating system version that's running
on that machine the last time someone
logged on to it and through sources and
what function might that that machines
serve and what's nice is you could
combine the DNS hostname that you get
from LDAP with forward DNS lookups and
get IP addresses a que like a target
list for your pentest without actually
having to scan the network because the
domain control will just give that all
to you now like I said Microsoft took
LDAP and added a bunch of cool things to
it and one of the coolest things that I
mean they added were these extensions
through object identifier Zoro IDs and
these let you craft really really
powerful LDAP searches and you can do
sort of advanced searching and filtering
as you're doing LDAP lookups and one of
them called LDAP matching rule and chain
is super useful because it allows you to
do recursive lookups and so if you chain
that with the member of property it will
recursively go into every group and find
transitive members of that group as well
so if you just drop that ugly kind of
decimal oh i d-- into your LDAP filter
the server will recurse into all the
members of a group and if that's a group
itself all the members of that group etc
etc all the way down the chain so why is
that important well net group domain
admins slash domain is probably the
first Windows command I memorized when I
started out pen testing I thought that
was the most important thing if I ever
got in a Windows machine but if you run
that on a Windows machine in this domain
you might think there's only two domain
admins administrator and a green and
that's looking it up over our piece
and Samer but if we run that nested
group query and LDAP for the domain
admins group will actually get a more
authoritative answer and it shows that
there's 13 user objects that have
transitive domain admin properties so
you should always trust LDAP and not
necessarily the net commands if you're
performing reconnaissance another useful
LDAP filter is admin count and this is
just a basically a boolean it's either
one or it doesn't exist and according to
Microsoft documentation admin count
attribute indicates that this object has
had its Ackles changed because it's
either directly or transitively part of
an administrative group so as a pen
tester or someone who wants to just
perform reconnaissance like this is
extremely useful to me because this
makes my LDAP search like the easiest
thing in the world you can filter on
this attribute so if you only remember
one LDAP search filter like leaving this
talk just land somewhere and just
remember admin count equals one and if
you search for any object that has admin
count equals one you will find every
single object that's considered
important enough to have its Ackles
protected and those would be like your
high-value targets to go after
essentially all the domain admins or the
objects that have essentially transitive
domain admin rights couple other
examples of some other oh I DS that can
be useful when you're doing LDAP lookups
there's oh I DS for user account control
which can find user objects that have
service principle names there's oh I DS
that can help you find users and
computers unconstrained delegation
so these LDAP queries you can use to
find all the servers that allow
unconstrained delegation computers with
protocol transition so Kerberos to ntlm
and then everything's an object like I
said so even Group Policy you can query
through LDAP if you just want to look
for object classical's group policy you
can find all the information for every
policy that's in that domain not
necessarily that it's linked or enforced
but you can just enumerate that but why
do that manually it's a pain to remember
all that LDAP search syntax and my cheat
sheet kind of kept growing and growing
and growing and I finally said screw it
so I wrote a Python script to automate a
lot of those common active directory and
numeration lookups
wind app search you can find it on like
github over here is kind of a quick
rundown of all the options you can just
pass it command line flags and enumerate
some of that information so just a quick
demo video showing wind app search in
action I hope you guys can read that I
apologize it's a video I can't make it
bigger it all it needs is a valid domain
name it'll find the LDAP servers over
DNS like I talked about and from an
unauthenticated perspective the -
functionality will just go ahead and
find the LDAP server and tell us exactly
what functionality level we're dealing
with but if we give it a username and a
password
then we can actually perform more
valuable information or more valuable
queries so - capital C this is
enumerated in all the computers in the
domain and explaining you know what
operating system they're running and
what patch level they're at as an
example because this has been a hot
topic this week unconstrained computers
will show me all the computers that
allow unconstrained delegation domain
control is expected but definitely not a
Windows 10 workstations so that's that's
something to target user spins will of
course show Kerberos table user objects
and I'll talk about that at the end
admin objects does that admin count
equals one so this is every object that
has its ackles protected so it includes
basically all the domain admins plus
groups plus service accounts or anything
and just to show if we come across a
group and we just want to see who's a
part of like IT admins that's really
easy to search an LDAP and we can just
quickly pull out all the group members
of that of that account or sorry all the
group members of that group and then the
last thing LDAP supports fuzzy searching
so if I wanted to just find someone
named John in the domain I can just look
up John it'll show me all the possible
matches I choose the one that I want and
then it goes and it pulls out all the
actual information for that user
so just a useful wrapper if you're ready
to run LDAP queries or you find yourself
kind of wanting to find that information
quickly and don't like I said have
access to PowerShell or just prefer
Python wind DAB search is a great tool
I've kind of in summary for LDAP LDAP
like I said consider it the source of
truth for all objects in Active
Directory domain it's really the first
stop that I would go to to try to map
out a domain and the protocol is like
fairly easy to work with when you get
the hang of it and there's lots of ways
to query it it is an open protocol so
find whatever client you want in any
language you want to write a script in
like there's gonna be an LDAP compliant
library for it and then you just start
putting those same LDAP filters in and
you can pull that information out as
long as you have any valid domain
account you can run those LDAP queries
from anywhere you have network access so
it's a great way if you just have like a
username and a password that's super own
privilege but can't log in anywhere you
can just run LDAP queries against the
domain controller and find some more
valuable information and I said
potentially stealthier in question marks
I I think a lot of security tools or the
last time I looked
we're listening on the domain controller
and flagging potentially sensitive MS
RPC calls like looking up domain admins
or protected objects but they had a gap
when it came to LDAP I don't know if
that's the case anymore but I think that
more
looking at net flow and RPC traffic than
LDAP so this might fly under the radar a
little bit more if you're concerned
about that and I'm always adding to wind
app search so if there's more useful
LDAP queries and there's so many that
are out there including Mauro IDs PRS
are welcome to shoot in my way and we
can just keep the script alive all right
let's talk about the three-headed dog in
the room so who here feels like they are
comfortable with Kerberos show of hands
okay and how many of you are not liars
are displayed every time I think I think
I'm comfortable with Kerberos and every
time I see a talk or look back into it I
realize I'm a noob again Kerberos can
seem crazy crazy complicated and so I'm
going to try to level set and just
explain enough of the high level
concepts so that we can get into some of
the fun stuff
without going into too many of the
technical details that really hurt my
brain so it took me a long time to grok
Kerberos I didn't quite understand it
and it can seem really complicated and
like I said easy to get lost in the
technical details but what helped me to
kind of put it into perspective is it's
just single sign-on and it's essentially
the og single sign-on so if any of you
and your work use like single sign-on
providers like octa or one login or
summer sale point or something like that
Kerberos is kind of like the precursor
to that and I and it's an analogous to a
single sign-on provider and if anyone
here is in web apps like I came from
that background when I started thinking
about it like sam'l or open ID it made
more sense
the idea is you authenticate once to a
trusted source it's the single sign-on
portal and then you don't have to
provide your password to any other
services in the domain the single source
delegates all your authentication and
the single source there is the key
distribution center or the KDC
so in Windows the domain controller is
the KDC and the KDC is made up of two
parts authentication service and the
ticket granting service they're not
super important to like keep in mind
right now but they just exist on the
same domain controller now I'm gonna try
to walk through kind of a flow that made
sense for me if we're thing if we're
talking about Kerberos here the first
step as a user I start my day I log into
my machine I'm gonna go to my SSO portal
and sign in with my password for the one
time that day and SSO portal in this
case is the domain controller and it's
Kerberos so I send my password to the
domain controller the domain controller
validates my password and it gives me a
session cookie I mean a ticket but it's
really in my mind like a long live
session cookie and it's called a TGT or
a ticket granting ticket as long as I'm
in possession of that ticket granting
ticket and it hasn't expired I never
need to show my password again that
ticket granting ticket is all I need now
a little bit later in the day
I want to log in to a server called
servo 1 and I want to just mount like an
SMB share over servo 1
so I go to servo 1 and I say hey I want
to mount your SMB share and I need to
authenticate myself so servo 1
quote-unquote redirects me back to the
domain controller if you're kind of
thinking about this in like a web app
flow I get redirected back to the domain
controller now I show my TGT to the
domain controller which proves I've
already logged in I've authenticated
myself and I say the domain controller I
need to access SMB on servo 1 and the
domain controller goes okay here's
another cookie another sessions are
another ticket called a service ticket
that you can present a servo one that
will let you in and it's only for SMB on
servo 1 and that's called a TGS or a
service ticket now I forget redirected
quote unquote back to servo 1 and this
time I present my service ticket servo 1
trusts and can verify that that service
ticket is legitimate and that service
ticket has all the information about me
and my user and my group memberships and
servo 1 goes ok this is legitimate go
ahead we'll set up the SMB connection
did that kind of make sense at a super
high level that's kind of the Kerberos
flow right there and it's Kerberos and
for bullet points which might be a new
I don't know but I could talk about this
and go into a lot more detail but this
is all we really need to know to
understand some of the kerberos attacks
now under the hood windows does so much
to make this seem really seamless like
it should when it works it really is
like seamless single sign-on so as a
quick example if we're on a Windows
machine wso one in this case and we're
gonna try to mount the SMB share for wso
to I can just do adder command and all
of a sudden I'm browsing the SMB share
it seems like magic but under the hood
all those steps and those four bullet
points I just mentioned actually
happened and they're actually nicely
color-coded here in Wireshark so I'll
walk through them real quick check on
hopefully let it sink in the first step
is I did a DNS lookup I need to find out
where wso 2 is so I do a broad or a DNS
lookup and I identify where wso 2 is and
that's the blue then I go to wso 2 in
yellow and I try to set up an SMB
connection and wso 2 responds to me and
says let's you need to authenticate
yourself let's do the Kerberos dance
we'll use Kerberos for that so then I
get redirected to the domain controller
and that's purple and now I'm talking to
the domain controller over Kerberos and
I'll go to the first the authentication
service and that's the first four
packets here I'm talking to the
authentication service and I'm sending
them my password and in return I'm
getting the ticket granting ticket Allah
my single sign-on session cookie then
the last two here I go back to the
domain controller and I say ok I've got
my single sign-on like TGT here I need
to access SMB on wso 2 and the domain
controller goes okay here's the TGS that
has all the information you need to do
that and then finally I get redirected
back to wso 2 I present my TGS and this
time the SMB session is successful and
we proceed to set up that entire session
and I start mounting it so all those
steps happen really quickly in
succession underneath the hood but they
are happening every time and if we do a
que list on Windows you can see the
tickets that are in your ticket cache I
suppose you could use movie cats too but
this is the preferred approach I suppose
and we can see exactly the tickets that
we would expect to see in that and that
dance that walkthrough
ticket number zero is the TGT so we got
that from the domain controller by
giving the domain controller our
password ticket number one is the
specific service ticket to access SMB on
wso - and that says it right here sips
which is the SMB service on wso to win
seven and that's what we use to actually
set up the SMB session now two things in
brutally important to remember when it
comes to Kerberos one service ticket
server specific services not hosts so
they're only good for a specific service
host combination I can't use that to
access RDP on WS o - and have to go
through the whole process again and this
is the big one Kerberos is an
authentication protocol it's not an
authorization protocol it was not
designed to be that way it only
validates who you are not whether or not
you should have access to what you're
requesting so you will actually always
get a service ticket from the domain
controller if you want it even if you
shouldn't be able to access that service
like you can usually just check it out
and it's up to the consumer in this case
servo 1 to make the decision to whether
or not to let you in with that service
ticket how does it do that well this was
a Microsoft addition to Kerberos to kind
of Bolton authorization and they did it
by attaching a privileged attribute
certificate to every single ticket in
Kerberos and this is basically like an
encrypted blob that contains among other
things who you are and all the groups
you belong to so anytime you actually
present your ticket someone can decrypt
the ticket and look up who you are and
then make the decision - and whether or
not to let you in and I think this is
sort of the source of a lot of abuse
when it comes to Kerberos is that this
pack was added to the tickets and
authorization and authentication kind of
got mixed up and we'll talk a little bit
about forging these by the end cool so
everything that I've done previously the
LDAP search commands the women exec win
the exec example I haven't actually used
Kerberos yet all of that's been doing a
different type of authentication called
ntlm authentication which is a challenge
response using an NT hash of the users
password but that doesn't mean I can't
and this is where the fun stuff comes in
because Linux can totally speak Kerberos
there's plenty of Kerberos clients and
the Windows implementation of Kerberos
is compliant so I can use any Kerberos
client on Linux to talk with the domain
controller and do the Kerberos
authentication dance so to set that up
and this is something I love doing when
I'm on a pen test or just have a Linux
machine is I would just install a
Kerberos client and set up the the
configuration as follows so a popular
one is Heimdall so on Linux if debian
for example app get install Heimdall
clients the other information we need is
the configuration information and then
we need DNS and we need time this is
what it looks like on Linux to setup
like a really simple Active Directory
domain as a Kerberos realm we have to
modify @ck rb5 conf and we have to
define the Kerberos realm in Windows
world is pretty much always the fully
qualified domain name just uppercase and
then we have to point it to where the
KDC the admin server and that's it and
then where the default domain is this is
the minimum you need and remember that
none of this information is secret like
it has to be broadcast it has to be
advertised and we can always look that
up via DNS server records to set up our
client Kerberos also so tightly is
coupled with DNS that DNS has to work
the easiest way if you're doing this is
to just point your local name server to
the domain controller and let the domain
controller handle all of all of DNS
resolution if it's unable to do that or
just point it to whatever name server is
being in use in that domain and then
time also has to be in sync and so the
easiest way from Linux is to actually
sync your local time with the domain
controllers time you can do that with
the our date utility so if you have all
that information and you have it
configure and you have it set up you
should be able to go ahead and run kay
in it which is the utility to kick off
and get checkout a TGT from the
authentication service it'll prompt you
for a password and if you Duke a list on
Linux it'll show you your current
tickets and so if it's all configured
well it should work and it looks like
this we can enter T hoffman's password
and Kay list will show that we actually
have created a ticket cache file it's in
the temp directory our principle
as who we expect it to be and we have a
curb TGT that expires in shoot I forget
what the default is it's less than a day
when we have that we're off to the races
so now any tool that supports Kerberos
authentication can be used with that
ticket cache file or that C cache file
and there's actually a lot that have it
baked in if you just look in the man
pages or the command line flags if you
see a reference on a particular tool to
gssapi that's pretty much Kerberos
authentication gssapi is the auth
mechanism that Kerberos five uses and so
you can use gssapi or if you see a
reference to it in a man page try using
it with Kerberos and most tools will
require the well-known environment
variable here krb v CC name so if that's
not set you have to export that to your
actual C cache file so here's some quick
examples like the Samba utilities work
great with Kerberos if I have it
configured and I've already gone and
done a K in it and checked out a TGT I
can use SMB client with - - Kerberos and
browse windows shares using Kerberos
authentication our PC client as well
totally easily supports Kerberos with -
K and notice in both these cases I don't
need to provide even a username because
it's reading all that information from
the C cache file and LDAP search all
those LDAP search fun queries we were
doing I was using ntlm off I can do it
in Kerberos - as long as Kerberos is
configured - capital wide gssapi will
tell LDAP search to do authentication
over Kerberos instead of ntlm and then I
don't need to provide a username or a
password I can use tickets and just a
sanity check to make sure it's all
working like we would expect it to you
can always go back and look at K list
and see the service tickets that you've
been checking out so we can see in this
case we started with the TGT and then I
ran in LDAP search query so as expected
I checked out a service ticket for LDAP
on the domain controller and then I did
an SMB mount and so as expected I
checked out a service ticket for sifts
on wso 1 1 7 so it keeps track of your
service tickets in the same C cache file
and all the Kerberos scripts are sorry
all the impacted scripts also fully
support Kerberos so if you have a C
cache file already you can give a - k -
no pass or you can just do - k and give
it a password and the impacted script
will actually get a TGT for you so these
are just two quick examples PS exec or
doe or women exec just using it with my
existing C cache file I can execute code
and do our PC calls and all that fun
stuff over Kerberos from Linux and
that's useful because occasionally you
might run into a situation where ntlm
authen is a ssin that's fully been able
to get rid of ntlm but if there's a
servers or like an O you that has ntlm
off disabled a lot of your traditional
pen testing tools just fail to work
Metasploit crack map exact a lot of
these tools are based on ntlm
authentication and you can't really do
anything with them but remember if you
have a password you can always do
Kerberos authentication so as long as
you have a password you can just drop
the Kerberos authentication and get
around this and that's what this looks
like here if you try this is me trying
to run with me exec against a machine
and I get a SMB session error status not
supported that means ntlm authentication
no problems there I land my shell all
right kind of brief detour now to
another pen test technique sometimes if
I'm on an internal network and I can't
get a foothold nothing's working I have
to resort to some password guessing
because someone somewhere is always
using password one two three or company
one two three so brute forcing passwords
in Active Directory is generally pretty
tough it's most domains on a lock out
policy it's pretty noisy there's lots of
security events and in my opinion it's
also pretty slow for example like SMB
sets up an entire connection and tears
it down every time you try to test a
password and as attackers one technique
we like to use a lot more than password
brute force
his password sprained right which is
where you just do a horizontal spray of
a single or one or two common passwords
against a big list of users like I said
it's noisy all of this traffic here in
Wireshark is the test one password if I
tried to do it over SMB so there's lots
of TCP traffic that's generated and
there's tons of logs and anyone should
probably be familiar right with the big
event ID for six to five which is an
account failed to log on so if you start
seeing your sim blow up with tons of
these event IDs someone's doing
something pretty bad so I started
thinking about like what other ways can
I do password guessing on an internal
Windows domain Network LDAP binds was
interesting it was actually quite a bit
faster but it still generated a bunch of
four six to five events but I had the
question well what happens when I do
this when I do a que in it with a
Kerberos client and I type in a bad
password and it fails and says password
incorrect this is what happens to UDP
frames I literally send one UDP frame to
the domain controller with my password
essentially it's an encrypted nonce and
the domain controller responds with like
a success or a failure so only two UDP
frames to check a password is pretty
efficient and pretty quick so I started
thinking about this and decided I wanted
to try to write the fastest brute-force
or I could so I'm happy to announce and
release I just made the github public a
new tool that I wrote called curb root
and curb root is my first go project
it's written entirely in golang which
has the advantage of being completely
cross-platform across architecture so
anywhere you land you can compile this
binary and run it even if we round like
a PowerPC or something like that
it's multi-threaded and takes takes
advantage of gos concurrency so combined
with small UDP frames this thing is
insanely fast it can auto look up all
the KDC information via DNS and it has
three main functionalities for now we
can enumerate valid accounts just by
guessing user names we can do a password
spray against a list of user names or we
can brute force a single user with a
huge list of passwords and my binaries
I'm a
piling binaries for common platform and
architecture windows linux and mac and
you can always download the latest
binaries directly from github releases
so demo gods hopefully are working and
i'm gonna try to demo curb root real
quick can you guys read this okay so I'm
on a Linux machine here and I have the
curb root binary it's curb root Linux
amd64
there's a couple things I want to try
first let's say I have a list of
possible usernames that I've
consolidated from LinkedIn or dumps or
something like that I've got like 10,000
of them
if I run curb root and do user enum I
just give it the domain and then I give
it this big list of possible names and
this is gonna do some Kerberos pre
authentication and see if these user
names exist judging by the error
messages that come back from the KDC so
it found the KDC
and it starts enumerated some valid user
names for me and it's done
and i got 40 valid user names and i
tested 10197 user names and i got cut
off there but 5.4 seconds so pretty
quick next let's say i have a list of
valid domain users and I've dumped this
may be from LDAP and I have twenty seven
hundred or two thousand seven hundred
two thousand seven hundred fifty-five
domain users and I want to see are any
of them using password one two three so
I can use curb root and I will do a
password spray I have to give it the
domain again and then I give it the list
of domain users I want and the password
I'd like to try so we'll try password
one two three do is clean sweep against
every single domain user found the KDC
there's one there's two and I tested all
2700 domain users in eight point two
seconds so really quickly enumerated
right there to ballot accounts that I
have just through some passwords brain
and then the last function that I'll
demo is
is if you're sure that there's no
lockout policy in place and you want to
just take one user and just blast a
bunch of passwords against them we'll
we'll take a the top 1000 most common
passwords and we'll do a brute user
attack in lab drop knob comm will give
it passwords dot list and then the user
that we want to brute force against in
this case it'll be Trevor Hoffman so
this time it's just targeting one user
and blasting it and I got the valid
login and I tested 1000 possible
passwords in 2.9 seconds so it's pretty
cool it's really quick it was sort of a
challenge to myself to learn go multi
concurrency is awesome UDP is fast and
Kerberos is pretty fun oh that was my
backup video but thankfully it worked oh
and for anyone who might want to give me
crap for not writing PowerShell tools I
just wanted to show the exe works fine
in PowerShell
so what about logs I actually had a
major WTF moment like a year or two ago
when I was playing around with this
because I was blasting like so much
Kerberos failed traffic all over the
place I went to my domain controller
queried the security log I didn't see a
single failure and I thought that was a
little bit odd granted I'm not like a
blue team or Active Directory security
like guru but I investigated a little
bit I think this is really important
turns out that everything I'm doing is
doing Kerberos pre authentication and
failing Kerberos pre authentication does
not trigger the traditional 4 625
account failed to log on because we
never actually logged on to anything we
just did a little pre on and ants and
got a ticket so you actually have to
enable Kerberos auditing which is in a
different area than your normal like log
on or log off events so you have to make
sure if you are running a domain that
you have that enabled it's considered
best practice but this is really
stressing the point that like you should
be enabling Kerberos auditing and not
just enabling it but alerting on it
because then we start seeing all this
stuff and the two main events that are
generated through that type of
Niq is event for 771 which is a Kerberos
pre authentication failure an event for
768 which is a TGT was requested and
when we do the user enum that's the only
one we're doing so user enum doesn't
actually count towards the failed
lockout at all because we never even
tried a password we were just gauging
whether or not the username existed so
kind of in summary there
I believe that Kerberos pre
authentication is much faster than any
other like password sprain or brute
forcing attempt live brute forcing
attempt that's out there and I think
it's potentially stealthier anecdotally
I don't have enough like evidence to go
on here but just giving this talk
internally and talking to a few people I
know that there's organizations out
there that like this is a visibility gap
for them they're not necessarily looking
at or alerting on Kerberos pre
authentication failures and they really
really need to be alright ok I'm doing
ok on time so we'll go into some more
Kerberos fun here specifically how to do
some privilege escalation and working
with hashes alright so let's talk about
spins spins or service principle names
and in Kerberos you can always request a
service ticket for a spin I mean that's
exactly what they're designed for if you
have a spin it means that you want to
accept Kerberos authentication and I can
therefore check out a service ticket for
that spin for example if I want to
access RDP I will go to the KDC and I
will request just a service ticket for
the spin associated with RDP on the
server that I want to access now that
service ticket is encrypted with the
spin owners excuse me and tail and
password hash which means that it's
actually possible to crack service
tickets offline you can just brute-force
them until you find the decryption key
generally speaking though that's useless
because for most machines who are the
spin owners it's encrypted with their
machine service account which is a super
long randomly generated password but
sometimes spins can be tied to user
accounts and when that's the case it's
encrypted with the users password and as
we know users are terrible at picking
passwords so this tech
is called Kerberos team and it was
initially presented at Derby con I was
in the audience there and I had no idea
what was going on but I think I finally
get it five years later or four years
later so Kerberos team three-step
process it requires a valid domain
account so you need to have at least one
valid domain account and then you find
spins that are tied to user accounts
which is an LDAP filter that I shared
already you request the service ticket
for the spin and then you brute force it
offline and if you can successfully
decrypt it you have found that users
password and impac it makes it so easy
with their Python script get user spins
which is one of the ones that I compile
do a static binaries so this works fine
if you download it you can run get user
spins - request the domain and the one
valid user that we have and it will do
an LDAP look up it will request a
service ticket it will spit out the hash
and that hash is like in a crack ready
format so you can feed that hash right
into hash cat mode 13100 and just start
an offline brute-force attack and if we
crack it like we can we did here that
what we've cracked is the password
associated with the user account who had
the spin and the user account we can see
here is vulner and he's a member of IT
admins which means transitively he has
domain admin so it's a way you can get
domain admin it's a way I've gotten
domain admin several times so passwords
are great but and you're usually pretty
easy to find in clear-text but sometimes
you can't get a clear text password and
all you have is a hash for ntlm off past
the hash is still around past the hash
still works great but how can you do
Kerberos authentication without a
password since I thought Kerberos was
based on passwords well it turns out you
can because the a s request to get a TGT
doesn't actually use the password
directly it derives an encryption key
from the password and uses that
encryption key and the NT hash is an
encryption key so if you have the empty
hash of the password you have everything
you need to actually check out a TGT and
this this technique is called over
passing the hash or pass the ticket I've
also heard it referred to and I'll show
two ways you can do this one is with
native Kerberos clients like Heimdall
and then of course one is with
because you can do everything within
packet so our scenario here is let's say
we have the empty hash for a user named
tony gwynn if we want to do it natively
with heimdal Kerberos passing the hash
actually documented this several years
ago and it's been in my bookmarks since
then but you can use the key tab utility
and create a key tab file which is a
Kerberos construct that just stores
encryption keys and you specify that the
NT hash is the encryption key you'd like
to use and you have to specify that the
NT hash is arced for encryption
HMH with md5 so when you do that you can
then use K in it and provide it the
encryption key directly from the key tab
file instead of a password and you will
check out a TGT for tony gwynn even
though we don't know tony Gwynn's
password and just have the hash of
course get TGT also does this for you we
can just request the NT hashes and get
TGT will create a c cache file the c
cache file can be used with heimdall
Kerberos and we can see the same result
now empty hashes with ARC for encryption
could actually flag some windows alerts
so I caution you because it's not the
best or default encryption anymore in
Active Directory modern AD is using AES
256 encryption for Kerberos
authentication or a s requests so every
user also has AE s keys that are derived
from their password and those AES keys
can be somewhat harder to come by but
they're still there if you look in mini
cats or secrets dump and here's a e s
keys for a user and for name will Myers
the exact same techniques work use KT
util just change the encryption
mechanism to AES 256 and paste in the
encryption key you got and you can get a
TGT same would get TGT within packet you
just specify AES key and you get a C
cache file which contains your chi GT
okay cool I've got a couple more minutes
so the last thing I wanted to touch on
and I could really go on on this kind of
fun stuff forever but I think these kind
of built-in nicely is abusing Kerberos
for persistence specifically golden and
silver tickets so I think we're all
you've probably heard of golden ticket
silver tickets I
they're very well documented I don't
want to spend too much time on them but
I feel like they fit in nicely here
because I want to focus a little bit
more on their practical usage and a lot
of the documentation and like tutorials
that were out there that I found were
using golden and silver tickets like
with mini cats or kikyo inside windows
and I wasn't quite sure what to do with
them if I was on Linux
so with mini cats or in packet you can
forge your own TGT Zoar forge your own
service tickets and if you are forging
your own TGT that's a golden ticket if
you are forging your own service ticket
that's a silver ticket to forge a golden
ticket we need the master encryption key
that's used by the domain controller to
encrypt all the Kerberos responses and
that's the account called krbtgt for the
silver ticket we don't need that but we
do need the encryption key for the
machine that we're trying to access so
the spin owner they have their own
password a password hash or encryption
key so practically it looks like this
ticket or PI is the impacted script that
you can run anywhere as it as the binary
or is the Python script you provided the
key you give it the domain Sid you give
it the domain the default duration any
additional groups that you want it to be
a part of and a user name because this
isn't just forging the TGT it's also
forging the pack and I talked about how
the pack is embedded inside the ticket
this is actually going to create the
fort entirely forged packed so we can
put in any user or group information we
want as well so I hope you can read this
but this is using the ticket or binary
and I've put in the AES key of the kerb
TGT account that I got from the domain
controller the domain Sid the domain I'm
just making it good for one day and the
username I completely made up and I just
made up a user called hello troopers and
ticket er creates AC cache file from
scratch and it's a valid C cache file
that can be used with any Kerberos
client so by exporting it and using it
with K list we can see the information
in here and we actually have a principle
called hello troopers which is a made-up
user but we have a valid TGT that that
hasn't expired yet for the domain and
then we're off to the races and can use
that with any
kerberos tool so I just wanted to show
you can use it like with Samba for
example SMB client - k with hello
troopers I've mounted the C shared
directory on the domain controller and
I'm a user called hello troopers I don't
even exist that's the power of golden
tickets it's really been demoed before
but that's how you would do it from
Linux and silver tickets are slightly
different they are useful for
persistence to a single host service
combination so you have to recall
service tickets are only good for
service host combos and I think there's
stealthier than golden tickets the
reason being you'd never actually talk
to the domain controller with a forged
silver ticket you can go directly to the
service you want to access and they will
let you in so you don't have to go back
to the domain controller and check out a
ticket you have to specify the service
you need and if you're trying to get
code execution in a later date you're
probably gonna want sifts and or host so
very very similar looking command would
ticket er but in this case our AES key
is not curb TGT the AES key is the
machine account password or the machine
account encryption key and we also give
it - spin for the spins we want to embed
or the spins that we want to forge the
the ticket for and so in this case I'm
requesting it for stiffs which is SMB on
wso 3 win 10 and again a made-up user
name called silver troopers to show that
it doesn't matter the C cash file is
valid if we feed it to Heindel we'll see
something kind of unusual that you
normally probably wouldn't see is your C
cash file contains a TGS but not a TGT
so we have the principle here we have a
ticket for Sif's we don't have a TGT we
never needed it we didn't we didn't
request one
and with SMB client it works fine with -
Kay as long as we're accessing wso 3 win
10 and we're using it with Kerberos
authentication it doesn't matter that
our username is made up it will let us
in and we can mount it and use that C
cache file with any Kerberos client so I
think that's my stopping point like I
said there's a lot more fun things that
could be that could be done but this was
kind of intended to just be the
foundational knowledge and I encourage
you to go out there and just experiment
and play more with this type of cool
things you can do with these open
protocols kind of in summary
there's so much attack service in Active
Directory environments I think I saw in
the last presentation Biggie Smalls once
said that the more complex the system is
the more attack surface it has so yeah
there's always things that you could be
looking at even if you were just getting
started in Active Directory security go
poking around reading MSDN Docs to
probably find something that no one's
really looked at before
you don't need Windows to talk Windows
if you do not like PowerShell don't
worry you can still be a Windows pen
tester that was the conflict I had a
couple years ago and then I found in
packet it's just been great
so DNS LDAP Kerberos MSR PC you can just
use other tools to talk to those
protocols and you can still be an
effective Windows pentester security
researcher with no net or C sharp or
PowerShell if you'd like and then more
tools and techniques will make you a
better pen tester so go exploring some
amazing research is being done like even
just this week at this track there's
such cool stuff coming out about
Kerberos I really think there's like
more to be found there and Kerberos is
not as scary or as intimidating as it
might seem because I was there once and
I really really enjoy it now and there's
still things that I love learning and
impact it is awesome and then a quick
shout out no this is not the 80s
security track speakers this was a slide
that I created beforehand but these just
big shoutouts to guys that I've learned
a ton from and countless more except
sure I'm forgetting people and these are
the slides are the three tools that I
mentioned her on github like I said I
gave this as a workshop it was a almost
three hour long workshop at Khan last
year my slides are posted for that so if
you enjoyed this I would encourage you
to check that out there's more
information deep diving into like MSRP
see for example but cool I think I've
got time for a couple questions thank
you very much
any questions thank you for to talk um
you mentioned the a lab search for the
enumeration process
did you ever discover a client that uses
search flags to as a part of a
mitigation so that you cannot query that
much from the ad a great question no but
my sample size is small so I've actually
been deferring a lot to someone like the
more prolific red teamers that are here
who work with larger organizations to
see if those mitigations are in place I
haven't personally encountered it but
that doesn't mean that that no one is
out there using it but it's a great
great mitigation for sure thanks again