hello everyone thanks for your time it's
great to be here like we have a lot of
that I will try to share today and I
hope like I will help you with some of
those questions to be asked if you come
out of this talk and you actually have
some ideas of what to ask for the next
talks I will be a read very happy
so before we start you know like I will
try to do something that is very simple
right and it's defining heaven right I
think like it's very easy right every
every future could go and and come into
a very simple agreement that heaven is a
place where the police are Britain's
right the cooks are Italian mechanicals
are German parties are in Brazilians
heads and so on right so this is like
very very easy to have an agreement on
if we had the world where this was the
world I think everybody would be happier
and we would not have a problem
unfortunately of course we live in the
reality and that's all mixed up every
country tries to do one of those things
and like everybody fails in all of them
right but I write I think like the best
definition of hell is where the lawyers
to exist I think that's like it's even
funnier when you send that for legal
reveal in a big corporation right so
somehow the lawyers don't really like it
but at the same time you know like what
can they really say right like this is
not really against the curb the company
rules so I want to apologize like an
advance that I will make generalizations
like this one of course there are good
lawyers are in there each one but then
like I will try to make some claims and
some things that are generalizations I
mean no offense to anybody so for
example if I say that the academia needs
to improve and it's to get into the
state of the art so they can actually
contribute dreamful sack I'm not saying
that there are no pockets in academia
that actually are very helpful in our
doing great work I'm just saying the
overall investment that happens in this
area overall number of things that come
out from this area maybe we are not
there yet right so then like I say that
a sentence like really really long ago
that is like if hacking is an arts
please excuse me but I will use the
poetic license right so I think it is
fine to make
certain generalizations just to actually
show the bigger picture but I don't mean
in offense and of course I'm like I'm
not speaking for my employer that would
require like huge committees agreeing
with all those ideas so instead to just
understand that what I'm saying here is
my view of something and is what I try
to drive it doesn't necessarily mean my
employer agrees with that didn't like it
recently I came up with this sentence
that I am sorry for the bad word like
but I think there like it is really
perfect to define my relation with
troopers right you do what you love and
it's like it's not that than like you
will not work one day in your life it's
actually working super hard and
everything will be personal right and my
relation with troopers is really like
that there's 12 years of the conference
it's my 11th year here troopers is the
first conference that I was invited to
give a talk right like it's the
conference where I'm at like most of my
really good friends and people that
change in my career like sergej brothers
who actually convinced me that they're
like a formalization and the actual view
of the academia was something very
important where I'm at like Edmond
Rogers who was the person who actually
brought me to us and and many others
along the years right so for me it is
like a place where I feel home right I'm
really really glad to be here so the
objectives here of the talk is really
like they're like I think a lot of the
things that I will say are just obvious
for all of you you say hey yeah but
that's like just common sense
but they're like if we don't really
define a way to like argue on common
sense we will end up arguing with people
that don't really understand or don't
have the same background and then it's
hard to actually discuss and organize
the thoughts and actually making the
convincing and then we end up with
decisions that are not necessarily the
best so what I will try to do here is
like creating these arguments and
helping do like with those questions
right I expect that in like this is more
like you doing like a discussion in the
sense that I will give you some talking
points hopefully along that the
conference we will discuss some of those
don't like don't necessarily agree with
me but use them as discussions right
like if you just go and say hey I don't
agree with that point but you're still
discussing the point I think that's good
enough but if you really need to define
the objectives of a talk with one women
I like this one right it's interesting
because Alberto Brandolini said of a
sentence and I honestly don't know
anything about the guy but I completely
agree with this sentence where the
amount of energy to refute is
of course an order of magnitude bigger
than to create it right and we see that
everywhere in info sack right someone
goes like say something and then they're
like there is like this huge like
discussion that goes but actually to
prove that person is wrong takes much
more energy than to actually make the
original claim this is going everywhere
and of course social media just made it
worse it's happening in all the fields I
think like InfoSec is one of them but
that's the one that we care about right
now so that's the one that we'll talk
but I'd like to use this image because
in or Ching you don't like we were
making fun out of like the way that
security is done across right we were
like hey you know what
when I find a bug it's like the attacker
is the all-powerful I don't know if
everybody remembers doom but the famous
god mode right you were
uncool about you have all the app the
weapons in the game you can see the map
and see all the enemies in the map I
mean you were undefeatable right like
you will win the game it is super fun
because you're exploding stuff around
but then like that's when someone finds
a bug right they go and they make this
huge claims that the bug is exploited in
all scenarios all the world is doomed
right I'm using a shirt that has a list
of those bugs later on someone will
realize which bugs are those that I'm
mentioning but essentially they're like
that's what happens when someone finds
the bag it's interesting because if you
look into the work of sometimes the same
researcher when they are actually
proposing a mitigation and the attacker
is this really dumb person right like
that really wants to dominate the world
but can't do anything really right
anything that you do to raise the bar
kills they attack completely and the
world is now perfect so it's a duality
that we see in info sack and it's
interesting because it is normal like I
think like everyone when they find
something they want it to be more super
important or when they design something
they want it should be the solution so I
think they're like it's a little bit of
what everybody does but didn't like an
info sack this is this is really big it
is so big that actually others
came up with like the same kind of idea
but different so I like to cite like the
mitigator by Harbor flake right
so it basically raises the bar and
through bugs can't be seen right so
which is actually very common right like
in info sack we hear this again and
again yeah but then like if we do this
we raise the bar but what is really
raising the bar I thought that we were
an exact Sciences right so raising about
how much did you raise the bar is this
like what you really incrementing is
this really more difficult for the
attacker is it more difficult when the
attacker is actually doing the attack or
just in the development phase what is
the proportion of time between the
development phase and the actually
leveraging that so there's a lot of
things that the raising the bar does not
really include right so as I say there
will be some points that I want you to
take out so I will give you three points
just three okay I will give the argument
on why I believe that point is important
than the actual point so the first one
is like threat modeling overall is a
well-defined process right like it
didn't like we we we learn it that like
how to do like security development life
cycles we learn it how to do security
development engineering that doesn't
mean everybody does that that doesn't
mean it's mature everywhere but there
like there is a well-defined process
there there like a people tried a lot of
things they share technology
corporations shared it like institutions
got into it researchers know it do like
the InfoSec industry kind of agrees that
there is a good way of developing like
secure software but unlike it's
interesting that they're like oh we
don't do the same when we discussing
mitigations and mitigations here I mean
above classes of issues so when you
don't know a specific instance of a
vulnerability but you want to make sure
that even if that instance exists it is
not possible to exploit for the maximum
compromise of the system so you're
trying to lower the impact of a
compromise so it's it's actually for me
it was always interesting right like the
process people they loved to create all
this SGL this big ideas all that exists
but for the mitigation side raising the
bar is more than enough right it's like
and then you're still raising the bar
everywhere so
I remember done like a professor of mine
like a mathematician actually joked with
me that engineers do not real math right
it's interesting because of course I was
super offended it came out that he was
actually true but they're like I didn't
like engineers don't really do real math
so he was like saying that like the
proof by induction for an engineer is
like if it works for case one works for
case two works for case three works for
all cases anything like while it didn't
like he was of course making fun because
I'm an idiot I do believe they don't
like I will bite and I will used his
claim and I will propose these four
mitigations if you're developing a
mitigation for a class of
vulnerabilities that mitigation must
work a hundred percent of the time make
it completely and exploitable for at
least three instances of that
vulnerability they're like I'm fine if
you go and go and find three instances
for that mitigation that that the
identification would kill if you don't
find it maybe you don't need the
mitigation because if it doesn't really
kill three because you don't know above
three instances it's really the most
important mitigation think about them
like the value like every time you
adding something to assistant it's
increasing complexity complexity means
more cost more chances of making
mistakes doing like ORS or maintaining
it and mitigation zones they get into a
system they are never removed right
because who wants to be the person who
removed the mitigation from the system
and now a vulnerability that should not
be exploit or became exploitable nobody
wants to be that person right so
mitigation makes in nobody will ever
remove it the cost is there the
complexity is there at some point that
mitigation is actually creating more
bugs than the failing and yes I'm
talking about facility notes but not
only but they're like it's really just
doing like because nobody will want to
give up at some point right it was just
way too much investment in there so
let's try to see that and and put it to
proof like sometimes someone blows and
say hey there is this new mitigation
cool show me three vulnerabilities that
it's really fully mitigated I think it's
like a very fair one the second point is
even though there are not a lot of
formalization of exploits and of course
they're like this is increasing right
like the the former work on trying to
define exploit and transforming exploit
writing from one arts to actually
something more like a scientific or more
like an engineering doing like a just
understanding how an exploit works just
because you've been in a presentation
and you had like a really good speaker
like you will see many in troupers
they're like that they really will give
you a lot of understanding on why a
vulnerability existed how it was found
how it was exploitable but then like
just having being in that presentation
doesn't mean you were really able to do
it and they're like this is like a
humbling moment because you realize that
they're like there is a lot of things
that that researcher didn't really tell
you right and the research adult it's
not like that researcher holds
information because they are evil it's
because there's a lot of things that
they don't even know they know right you
look into something and you already have
some information of some things that
will not work why would you try it you
already know it will not work
you already know things that work so we
will go for that so you are a Red Hat an
understanding on the system so you not
share certain things so just seeing a
presentation is not enough to claim that
you understand how exploits really work
I love that sound
mine is definite that way they arrived
here at the Imperial music so but it
works as well whatever keeps you awake
[Laughter]
so when one panel that I recommend that
I didn't like it's interesting because
it was like a small play no but they
released like all the notes from the
panel on stressing exploit art versus
engineering was made in a New York poly
University so I do recommend everybody
to have a look but that that brings me
to the second point right someone who is
proposing a mitigation really needs to
understand the problem and understanding
a problem can be done through actually
writing exploits for that problem or
pairing up with someone who actually did
that in the way it looks like they like
it's simple but they're like just doing
CDF's it's not enough for you to say
that you really understand that class of
vulnerabilities not enough for you to go
and propose a mitigation you really need
to get like real-life software real-life
issues
for like really modern Oh asses with all
kinds of like state-of-the-art enabled
in that OS then you are able to go and
say hey I exploited a few of those I
fully understand that problem I
understand why that problem is
exploitable now I can work on
engineering the mitigation that doesn't
mean the exploit writer needs to do the
in mitigation engineering that it can be
just a pair up right you grow you find
like really doing like excellent
designers excellent architects and
they're like each person brings
something to the table right but really
don't accept someone who never did that
to actually be the one claiming that
they have the mitigation because likely
they missing a lot of things right and I
think like didn't like on that you know
like as a nation right the technology
that is shared in a presentation many
times is not complete for different
reasons I like here to cite like a talk
that Alex ionesco recently gave in in a
conference actually in Germany and then
like his talk was basically what is my
magic right so he wanted to share why he
can do things so fast why he's able to
reverse-engineer certain elements of
Windows kernel like much faster than
anybody else like Microsoft barely
released something and he read come up
with like the internals of that
subsystem a lot of people claim that hey
he has access to the code you know but
in the end in his presentation he just
shows that there is no magic there is
just like above 20 years of doing it
again in over full time during all those
years through all the holidays that
happened during our family vacations
that we missed like missing the kids and
all right like all of that all of that
time created so much back knowledge that
when he looks into something it's just
faster because there's a lot of mistakes
that he just don't make it's not like
doing like it's magic it's not like
something impossible everybody that
dedicates the time and it's been and
actually the energy to do it we'll be
able to do it at this at some point
right I mean assuming that we are our
average right but the truth is most will
not right most will not dedicate that
time most of you not dedicated that
energy and speakers when they will share
it something that they did they will go
straight to what saves the time that
makes the presentation interesting and
explains the problem so
a lot of those other things you just
miss you don't get just from the
presentation so here is one thing
they're like do go and try right just
don't take things that I presented for
granted try to reproduce the work right
that's actually original science right
and I think that's a bit of what
academia misses it was like there's all
these great papers with a lot of big
claims but where is the actual thing for
me to try and reproduce that finding and
come to the same conclusion most of the
times you are not able to and then you
are always like in this question did I
do something wrong that's why I didn't
come to the same conclusion did they lie
that they actually got into that
conclusion
did I miss something there is some
secret sauce that I don't know only the
government can know either you don't
know and at that point that paper even
though interior has a lot of value it
don't really for science or for evolving
the knowledge right so they're like I
always say that they're like as more as
we learn it then like as less as as more
as we realize there is more things that
we don't know right so it is very calm
on that right like if you see that
they're like I did sometimes these
figures just hold something because they
believe it is so obvious that they don't
really understand too much if others
will know it or not they'd for then it's
just something natural and then there is
a key point missing there so reproducing
and doing it ourselves is really
important so one thing that I wanted to
say is that leverage the investments in
offense right like leverage the fact
that there's a lot of people spending
all this time don't just go and get the
presentation that's it but they're like
be sure that they're like people are
reproducing that the science is evolving
that we are sharing more and more but
then like use that to drive defense
right I'm not saying that to them like
offense is more important than defense
I'm just saying that both are very
important some companies will be less
mature or will have less resources they
are not able to have it internally but
they're like you can now is commit to a
conference and talk to actual
researchers and make sure that you
listen to what they have to say
sometimes they're like what they said in
the talk is not the full picture but if
you go and just do like drink a beer
with them they will share much more
leverage that right like and they're
like I really hope they don't like more
and more people realize that and the
companies are like doing a lot of it for
it's like right now there's a lot of
corporations then I
I admire a lot of work by Google and by
Microsoft on sharing a lot of this
offensive work and how this is driving
mitigations in their companies and I
hope that we see more of that so what do
I miss right as a researcher myself
didn't like other than do like what I
mentioned like being able to reproduce
certain work certain papers and here
they're like I best academia a lot
because they in theory are really
scientific right but the same applies
also to practitioners and researchers
overall right but then like I I really
miss more of them like the time spent by
the research on doing something what the
researcher knew when they started I
loved like like papers and presentations
like the pounds around where the
research is going to say hey how they
found the issue how they exploited the
issue I wish they shared even more about
how much time they actually spent right
because it's it's common that someone
goes and say hey I spent only a week on
that but then the ignoring everything
that they had as a background and you
don't know so it's hard for you to
really measure so it would be cool to
have even more of that date on how much
the research actually knew when they
started what was the premises what were
the assumptions that they went first
mistakes that they made I think this has
much more value for us to actually also
replicate and for us to actually expand
that research to other areas right so I
wish we had more of that they're like of
course they're like sharing exploits and
sharing they're like a vulnerability
research work for me it's it's key you
know like a lot of people don't
understand the importance of those
exploits being shared they're like yeah
but it will take so much time for
companies in the world to patch what is
the impact but if we don't share we
don't create the next generation the
next generation will have more and more
gaps because they starting with but with
four worlds that's much more complex
than 20 years ago
so if they start already trying to
exploit something modern Windows they
will get frustrated they will not be
able to do it because there are so many
other things that they need to know and
it will be so much time so those work
like sharing this kind of work is really
key for them to also learn and then for
the state of the Arts to evolve another
thing that them like it's interesting
because it looks like so trivial but
there is a data that is not really
easily available
it's for example they're like a you have
Metasploit Metasploit has a lot of tags
for searching exploits so you can know
hey which targets and exploit works on
do like this this exploit bypassing SLR
or not but one thing that is not trivial
to collect is like okay this exploit my
night button might not bypass a SLR but
could it right we don't know we don't
know if whoever created that module just
decided that this a SLR was not
important at that time for whatever
reason or if they just do my couldn't
bypass but maybe it is possible that
person just didn't know or you do need
another info leak primitive that that
vulnerability don't give so that's why
it does not bypass the SLR so there's a
lot of things there that is like
information that is just not provided
and as the time passes this information
is in theory very useful but it gets
lost right like how now we're going to
find the original exploit writer that
did that that working on the module what
does which kind of notes they kept alike
and the information essentially gets
lost to go and try to compile it it will
take a while so I have like simple
questions that are very hard actually to
answer nowadays so I will give an
example right a memory there is a
executable only meaning that you can
execute but you cannot read it's
something that the paging in inter
architecture do not provide but actually
in eternium we had it right army does
have it intel has a technology called
memory protection keys that can provide
that for you is it worth to enable in
browsers we would actually prevent any
vulnerability from being exploitable
it's a simple question but you need to
have a lot of experience with a lot of
different browsers in a lot of different
classes of vulnerabilities in those
browsers to actually see if any of those
would actually be mitigated by enabling
the technology and this is not an easy
to obtain information and it's just one
example right it's just on the top of my
mind there are likely many many others
many things that could be developed in
terms of mitigation there like it's very
hard to define if it would really be
effective and then like getting all this
from even the public sources of
millets is not trivial so maybe it's
time that we start doing something one
point that I like to mention when I get
really really many years ago I wrote a
blog post in Portuguese only because I
thought that it was completely relevant
and somehow it is this theory relevant I
guess but which I called like the
fallacy of the defense-in-depth
right there is always this idea that hey
I have multiple layers of Defense right
defense and that came from the military
right the idea was the enemy would like
break one layer so you'll have time to
relocate troops to a given like place
you'll have time to actually react and
you are able to detect that they
actually broke this layer defense in
depth
mostly doesn't work in the virtual world
right think about DP aslr the attacker
yes when they write in the X Y they we
spend a little bit more time but also
they exploit works it will bypass
everything simultaneously there is no
new alert because you have one or the
other
this is not defense in that yes it gives
you resilience against certain
vulnerabilities it makes classes of
vulnerabilities harder to exploit do
like there is a lot of benefits on that
I'm not saying to not use it but that's
not defense in that there are defense in
that mechanism in computer world but
they're like those are not the ones
right so be a little bit careful what
really you getting from and is that
really defense in that I would like to
also give like kudos and things like bug
bounties were mentioned right like by
you know do like at the work by Katie on
bug bounties is impressive for me like
they're like she's involved since the
very beginning since word started she's
driving the industry she's really well
where she published like really good
work and she sent devised like the
researching in other work some folks are
comparing their like but bouncing
results with like potato right so have
like very few researchers that actually
find most of the issues but they're like
the trophy is there like they go to the
very easy issues so they get to the
payouts really quickly so it's not
really helping in terms of quality it's
cool doing like there's a lot of
countries where they're like they're
like even a small payout to make a huge
difference I am from Brazil I know very
well that so but they're like that
doesn't mean that bug bounties really
bring thousands of people to look into
something more than that you know like I
think you don't like the statistics I'll
read show that it's really a minority of
the folks that are actually making a
living out of bug bounties but I think
these statistics also not counting from
a very trivial thing which is like a lot
of those corporations they don't even
have the maturity to define what is a
really a vulnerability is this really
exploitable vulnerability or not
so you see CVS being released every day
for a lot of things that are definitely
not exploitable but someone decided and
who knows right so then my turret is not
there so a lot of the bugs that in
theory are being classified as bugs are
probably not even real right so and
that's actually another problem as I
mentioned the data that is available to
us nowadays is really bad so a lot of do
CVS they are not really security issues
so then how do you really know what
you're counting or what you're comparing
that's why metrics that use CVS you
actually just fight certain things are
not necessarily very good so I talked a
little bit about the importance of like
formalization right so I want to
basically mention some work that has
been done in the past two years there
and under there like as some work and I
don't like I still believe needs to be
done right I think they're like a length
sack
they're like helped a lot in in not
formalizing the exploit side but for
analyze a big chunk of the issues that
are related like a true input and
parsers they helped for example
everybody understand that they're like
the cold is actually driven by data so
it's easier to for people to understand
why certain classes of vulnerabilities
exist why certain things are harder to
mitigate but then like I also think that
a length sack showed us that some of our
very basic assumptions are really either
wrong or needs to be revealed or needs
to be better define it because they just
don't really work as we thought we
thought they would I will I got two
examples that are essentially the same
examples but they're like they they have
like some differences but in secure
development we always say as a role
right the input should be checked as
close to the use of that input as
possible
another role in insecure development is
again we need to have functions that are
intrinsically security or secure by
themselves they don't depend on
something else actually making sure they
are secure
right that's why we say string copy is
not good because it depends on something
else checking the input right these are
like basic rules in sacred development
but they're like length sack in the
other side say that they're like you
need to recognize your input straight in
your parser your parser is the one that
really knows if the input is valid and
is your recognizer so it needs to be
straight into the moment you receive it
not spread around what they called
shotgun parser which is a parcel that is
everywhere in your code because that's
very hard to really guarantee it's
correct it's not that that you
contradicted themselves but they're like
we do see that they're like we need to
relook a little bit on the guidance and
maybe redefine that guidance a little
bit better to actually make it make more
sense still talking on on formalizations
right and and and and things that
formalizations change in the world so
Julian Vania
I am a big fan of his work doing like
hip modeling where he's trying to
demonstrate to them like all the hip
operations as mathematical formulas and
that is actually essential for us to
think about mitigations on the hip
classes of an ability that involve like
creep and auto generated like exploits
for hip overflows as is actually working
on and trying to do some of that so I
think this is like a brilliant area to
to go and work on formalizations of
course then like in that area as well we
know DARPA efforts that I didn't even
cite but then like were they putting a
competition to get they put a
competition together to try to create
like exploit Auto generation and it's
actually like a also result of coming
from formalizations right however also
recently released a paper on on the
weird machine on trying to define I
don't like vanilla billets in the scope
of like a Turing machine something that
didn't like a computer scientists will
definitely understand and I think they
like those works our great should try to
bring didn't like more folks to the
state-of-the-art of course I'm like this
is not a comprehensive list there's so
many people doing a great work right my
intention was not to be comprehensive
was just to a point where I can give
like some references but like one thing
that for me is always interesting is to
consider one area looking to something
that has similar complexity and similar
challenges are
go back I tried to compare info sack
with for like chess games right and I
showed that unlike a lot of the things
from chess that were learned from like
dozens of years ago they do apply to
info sack but then like recently I was
reading a blog post so not as recent now
maybe more than a year now on on
compression and it's interesting that in
like this practitioner guy like someone
who basically writes the compression
algorithms and compression algorithms do
I get he basically didn't like a in a
blog post he concluded something about
compression that for me it's actually
super interesting because he basically
say that a modern compressor is a bit
like a compiler the compressed data is a
kind of a program in bytecode and that
the compress is just an interpreter so
it's interesting because this is really
similar to what lengths that came with
like a data drives code and that's like
why you need to recognize that data so
even though it's a completely different
field they like the practitioners they
actually see and they realize that right
they realize the way stripes thread
compression they might not care like
this guy he just posted in a blog right
he didn't write a super academic paper
that got into a top conference and then
everybody can cite but it's amazing that
he came up with this similar conclusion
by himself in a completely different
area so there's a lot that we can learn
from from the petitioners right from
people that actually doing a good work
there they're like there is some some
some kudos that needs to be given to
Microsoft Microsoft like Matt Miller has
been doing an amazing work on showing
some of the ideas behind their
mitigations right the data that they
used to come to the conclusion that a
was more important than B why they got
there and even sharing the internals on
how they find vulnerabilities to help
others like find vulnerabilities in
their products I think that that's been
really great work coming out of
Microsoft but then like I really like to
talk about JIRA work because this is for
me the precursor of defining exploits in
a different way right which is from 2002
so er for for those who don't know is
one of the founders of core like he's
not with the company anymore but he's
kind of not human right like is that
person is that is like them like like
like he's different you know like
somehow he was always ahead of the time
right and I don't like him either to
teach new exploit writers in the company
how to actually think about the
vulnerabilities and try to get them up
to speed and he created this
presentation and then he shared it with
the world where he define it primitives
so he talks about them like what you can
do and like how you can change things
that are like those primitives to
actually achieve like your objective so
it was kind of like very informal it's
not really a formalized but he already
introduced it some of the terminology
that you nowadays are like the way of
looking to the problem so and that's
like way back I'll repeat for example
even though everybody attributes ROP to
an academic paper
I repeat existed for many many years
before it was formally defined by the
academics the formal definition was
really important because that's what
people cite is that a term that is now
common everybody used the same term
everybody knows what it what they
talking about when they define before
ROP so there is an importance that it
ended up define it but it is something
that today the actual exploit writers
already knew for a while a while back I
was in in a mathematics class with
another professor that professor loved
it to play chess so in the class breaks
we played chess all the time and then
like he always wanted he was always
interested in what I did at the time I
was an exploit writer I think we would
sketch some of that on the ethics panel
but my job was basically right to
exploit sometimes I was finding the
vanilla breeze that I was writing the
exploits for sometimes other things in
the company that I work at for at the
time we're the ones final arbiter was
just right in the exploit but that
professor like he really really thought
it was an interesting area endemic
because he was a mathematician he
challenged me to actually define exploit
writing using set theory as I said
before I met Sergey barratto's I didn't
give a crap really above academia but I
do I did respect this professor he was
brilliant like his civil life so like
his two brilliant tech but then like I
was like yeah you know what I will try
it so I did like a try for his class but
then do like I kind of like dropped I
didn't care too much I didn't really
care about publishing or anything I
present ever like to the class but that
was pretty much it but along the years
even more after I met Sergey you know I
I did try try to use the same ideas and
when I talk to people right every time I
was talking about defining like a
vanilla village I would talk about like
hey let's create a set let's define it
like the different wannabes that we need
to actually get into the into the
objective let's define any primitives
you know like I always use that to talk
to people and one of my teammates like
he convinced me that we should actually
go and write it down and put like doing
like all the formulas back and then and
we published that in the length psycho
workshop like past year so the work was
done with like three of my teammates
like the credit shoot goes all out for
then like so the idea was from my
professor the action worked well for my
teammates
I'm just here saying it so cake I key
and Enrique so I recommend you to have a
look into it
but just do like to say that like what
was the contribution in this work
essentially then like we define it I
don't I can like exploit primitives are
doing like what the attacker actually
obtained it can be through a security
vulnerability but some primitives are
just there it's just in him it's just a
way that the system was built right so
for example like some like in the Linux
kernel didn't like in the past now they
trying to fix it but a lot of pointers
of the kernel were just available for
use remote processes it was just there
it was available it's not really a
vulnerability because it's part of the
design of the system now they
considering it of an ability because it
breaks ksl are but at the time they were
not so that was just inherent but it's
this new available the information is
available right so some things are
obtained because of vulnerability so you
can get a read primitive because of our
given vulnerability on the system pea
patch right like the creator of packs
heap define it like how they look into
it when they actually defining a
mitigation and it's interesting because
they define it that there is the
primitive type that gives you read write
or execute but then they also define it
like primitive properties that is
basically when you get this read or
write or execute primitive is it fully
controlled or partially control edge
right is that for any memory area or for
like a given memory area can you repeat
it multiple times or not so we leveraged
that to define er they exploit
primitives and I will show why
formalization is actually important
because I will show there is one
primitive that escaped us right because
there was no formalization also
formalized and we start applying
different vulnerabilities in there you
see wait wait a minute I'm getting a
property here that is not defined yet
right so I will explain in a minute
then the like we define it I don't like
the exploit objective is really there
like what do you need to unite to
actually do like what you actually wants
to achieve right so for example
sometimes just want a data from a
database so there is multiple ways that
you can you can do it sometimes you
won't actually code execution sometimes
you just want the ability to buy votes
to another machine so that actually
talks about the kind of vulnerability we
need right the exploit condition is
really didn't like how many exploit
primitives you need to change together
to get into the exploit condition should
the exploit a bijective sorry that's
interesting because there like I also
moderate you start seeing that for
example chrome like scaping sandbox
there were cases where you needed to
change searching different
vulnerabilities to actually get into
your exploit objective right if you're
looking to punch around recently there
was one like a remote code execution for
Android and authenticated right and do
like the guys chained it I think like it
was 12 different illogical bugs to
actually get into the objective right so
it's it's a it's a good mode and then
exploit jiff gucci is really doing like
what is the complexity for that exploit
and the idea here is just so we could
differentiate what is the probabilistic
versus what is the deterministic
mitigation so going into that on the
probabilistic versus deterministic right
of course they're like at the empirical
understanding like like the thing that
is kind of like normal is you say
something is deterministic meaning that
like this mitigation is exact right
there is no bypasses for that primitive
in that given case for that mitigation
it's it works as this right there is no
dependence on statistics or timing or
any probability right while
probabilistic they don't like you
basically adding a probability so the
attacker still has a chance of
succeeding brute-forcing might be
possible you might need to change it
with something else it starts getting
complicated when you start to look into
actual real cases right so this is the
case analysis they don't like our we
will try to present here which is like
image like this you have encryption
right so you have a s
10:28 data at rest to generate decrees
properly using proper mode the data is
just stale someone just steals the data
they don't have the key they don't have
a way to obtain that key it will take a
really long time for them to actually
break it even though it is probabilistic
there is a chance that then like they
might find out the key right like a true
brute forcing but it's not really a
realistic attack if you think about the
probability it's so big that it gets
into like we can consider this as a
deterministic mitigation but the same
mechanism if we just change a little bit
how the system operates and now instead
of the data being at rest we say that
the data is in use by the actual machine
we completely change the way that this
mitigation works and I will show you why
okay
but it's actually important to actually
play those exercises so that comes with
this new primitive right in 2017 when I
presented in troopers I discussed a
little bit above like memory encryption
and attacks against encrypted memory I
will do a wrap out of what I presented
2017 and then we will discuss like a
little bit about like what is new and in
for today but essentially the idea of an
attack and not being oblivious to memory
changes is something that like was not
necessarily very relevant before right
think about you know like if you have a
memory that is encrypted and the
attacker issue observes that memory the
attacker only sees encrypted data but
the attacker still has the ability to
observe right so the attacker still sees
memory changing they don't know what is
really changing but the attacker has
this observation we demonstrated and
that was the presentation in 2017 that's
just by this observation we are able to
actually find a lot of things in memory
where they are where they are located so
we know for example hey this is my
processor this is a given target process
okay I know that this is where certain
date of that process is there I don't
know that data I don't really know the
content but just by the pattern analysis
of the changes you are able to determine
that and this is what we called it's
like know it's an attacker that is know
oblivious to the changes I do believe
that the like this is was kind of like
something
petitioners a red so in order exploits
right some info leaks they only give you
a notion that the state is changing and
this is basically where no oblivious to
that state change but it was not ever
really define it as as that so I'm not
claiming this is something new I'm just
claiming that didn't like it was not
really named before so if we think about
doing like a dis attacker right like a
an attacker that is able to read and
write into memory right but the memory
is encrypted
the attacker has no key so he reads
encrypted he writes it's kind of like a
random corruption that happens there
because he don't really control like the
the operation after can that attacker
really win so we proved it
the attacker came i will explain quickly
but then like at the same time like why
someone would encrypt the memory if the
attacker can is to win well it is a
deterministic protection against cold
boot attacks where the memory is not
reused anymore right someone just
stopped the machine gets the rent
somewhere else it's encrypted the keys
not even there in the new machine right
because the key is not in the rent so it
is still doing like very deterministic
protection is an effective protection
against this attack so how this memory
encryption works right essentially you
have like in a package of the CPU
anything that leaves the package of the
CPU and goes to the system goes
basically encrypted inside the CPU
caches or inside the CPU boundary
basically the data is unencrypted so
it's available right and of course then
the CPU make sure that you like it takes
care of like which process accessing or
which VM or whatever right there's a lot
of like implementation details from
different implementations just a
disclaimer there like I will show a list
of technology that's used memory
encryption I'm not claiming out of then
are vulnerable are not vulnerable right
I'm just showing that the like a lot of
people believe that those technologies
are about to come to the market but they
already exist for a while right so for
example Xbox use a hybrid approach some
memory areas are encrypted some memory
areas are a cryptid with integrity
protection and replay protection
Nintendo 3ds actually in the same
troopers we release the work against
that attacking memory encryption box
gtfo had an article against bypassing
like the security of the Nintendo DS
Apple security wave using
memory there was a good talk by 8rj
Intel M EE
like as Jax use with replay protection
and integrity total memory encryption
and mutsuki memory encryption by Intel
announced that but there is no CPUs
available in the market now they use
memory encryption a MGS cv and SME
they're like same thing use memory
encryption right so memory encryption is
a read existence in many places and it's
going to be mainstream soon right so all
your desktops with have encrypted memory
servers will have encrypted memory so a
lot of things change there the attack
that we showed in troopers was
interesting because since we can
actually find the location of stuff in
memory and we can flip bits randomly we
can do a data on attack in code that has
logic for example like this and actually
we demonstrate against the loading
process in in Linux so it supports like
a pre authentication basically than like
even if it's disabled it does support it
so you could enable it right in theory
so pre authentication is supported there
is a flag that is maintained in in
memory for actually define it if the pre
authentication actually happens so the
way that the codes authenticates you
basically it goes and say hey is the pre
authentication enabled if it is it calls
a function that basically looks for
example into your domain tor Kerberos
server to see if you already
authenticated and if you did it sets a
flag so later on the logic goes and sees
if the flag is set it bypasses asking
you for a password it just gives you the
login right
of course then like a if an attacker can
modify memory at any point the attacker
can just go even do like if the pre out
is not really enabled the attacker can
at this point modify the flag and
basically bypass their the actual
authentic ation logic can get em get
shell that's what we demonstrated and
why you D attacker is able to do it
because everything related to pre out is
in the same memory area so when you
corrupt even though you're corrupting
everything else it's not in use so it
doesn't really matter it doesn't crash
it doesn't really get invalid values and
this if it's basically checking if the
value is not zero right so any flip
there is really really low chances that
this will actually end up being zero
right so
the power of 32 minus -1 just that it
will not be 0 right so therefore you win
as an attacker so that was like trivial
and our than like cool but then do like
a lot of people say hey but what if you
go and change that code logic because
they like this code is inferior secure
code you should basically go and here
say hey if pre out equals true and do
that and then the attacker now needs to
help reroutes equals 2 and instead of
like just different than zero right it
would be completely different game while
I don't think you can change all this
software to find out those conditions I
assaulted the question I accepted the
challenge to have a look so if you look
into memory encryption you start seeing
memory in a different way imagine that
now instead of seeing addresses as bytes
write byte addressable you can see them
as basically blocks of the cipher size
right in this case most of the
implementations are a ESI 0 28 so I will
just say block size are under 28 bits so
imagine like memory itself everything is
encrypted and they are those blocks of
encrypted memory every time the CPU
fight something to the cache it will go
it will decrypt to the actual block and
it will come to the cache right
obviously the cache lines are bigger
than a 10 or 28 meaning that every time
you do a code fetch I could write you
actually pulling more than only one of
those encrypted blocks but what matters
is like the blocks themselves are just
doing like a hundred twenty eight
minutes that basically means that every
time you modify something in the block
as a property of encryption you modify
everything in that block with a random
probability right if I flip any bit in
the in the block so imagine that this is
one block if I flip one beach on the
encrypted block do like it's a property
of the cipher that will be propagated at
the decryption right because I don't
have the key I didn't really do the
proper encryption to actually do the
flip I just flip the memory CPU fetch
the value it does the decryption and
then now do like the entire block gets
corrupted it's interesting because while
the data at rest this is amazing
property when we think about them like
the data news do like we had like
different elements in that block you can
have for example variable that is 8 bits
a variable that is 16 bits a variable
that is 32 bits in the same block
meaning that if you corrupts of
something you're corrupting our of those
but the chances of you getting the value
that you want is basically proportional
to the size of that variable right so if
you have a variable that is 8 bits true
to the power of 8 you definitely going
to get the value that you want right if
it's 32 to the power of 32 right so if
the attacker is able to do the same
attack multiple times without actually
breaking the system the attacker swings
and then don't like it that's what we
call like a feasible brute force like
corruption like random corruption right
and here the idea is like doing like a
think about the primitives again it's
really powerful like the attacker like
if you look into the properties of those
primitives we give in to an attacker
that can read and write memory basically
they can do that at arbitrary addresses
they have like partially arbitrary
contents because even though they don't
control the cipher they can actually do
it multiple times and the flips are
random but they cause the flip right
they have like an arbitrary operation
right because they doing the flip so the
data is changing they do have that for
an arbitrary number of times because
they can keep repeating it until they
succeed they do that at an arbitrary
time in the program so the problem the
system doesn't even know this attacker
is there it's running besides the fact
that the system is actually processing
things and the maker the attack is know
oblivious that's a lot of properties we
give in to an attacker so they're like
there is no way that this is not
exploitable right like it's just them
like if you think about them like as an
exploit writer do you like that it was
already obvious when you look into the
int into into the problem but there's a
no exploit writer there like if we go
and start showing the number of like
properties that we're giving it starts
getting easier for people to figure out
that hey yes it's way too much power
notice that what we really change it
with like encrypted memories that
instead of fully arbitrary content now
it's an a partial arbitrary content
right and instead of giving like a read
primitive we just gave them they're no
oblivious
it's just a small primitive change we
didn't really break much right for this
attacker so I will just show one example
of this
how this rabbit can be exploited with
like this brute-forcing approach just
because you could go against against the
looking but the logging system never
changes that if not zero so there is no
point on going after that because that
is too broken with the old attack so we
decided to find some new target just to
show an example it's not very realistic
but it is one example right so the
little scanner manages structures using
like a task structure right like so it
has one per processes so then like every
time you spawning a process you will
have like a tester to associate to that
process even threads will have like a
task structure they will just share a
thread group right that search has many
elements that are necessary for
controlling the task do like for the
privileges it basically allocates one
specific data structure that's the crazy
structure and I don't like this comes
like from the small poor locator so it's
like a very specific a locator in the
kernel but overall doing like it is
something that is known behavior the
credit stripped so like has lots of
elements so I will show one that we are
interested which is the effective user
ID or ID is to make the effective user
ID of a process basically zero and then
with that we can change the effective
user ID sorry they they for example the
effective group ID we can change it like
all the other IDs and we can do a lot of
like damage to the system right there is
a lot of other mitigations that can come
in place in certain systems but then
like let's just imagine like the basic
work of the system when you think about
the data structure a lot of people are
concerned in these attacks
hey but do I need to have cache
alignment do I need to care about memory
alignment and we even ignore for now
that the actual structure is aligned it
in memory because that's good for
performance even if it were not the
blocks the adjacent blocks are all
related to the same structure for the
same process so as long as you found the
correct structure for a process that is
not in neat because if you damage your
needs you might have a big problem there
like you might create like some like
problems in the system but you're not
gonna break that system but finding your
own process is actually very easy if you
are able to respond processes in the
system I will explain in a minute why
but the good thing is you can just go
and flip and don't need to worry too
much on the adjacency itself as long as
you found the credit
the crowd so you have a lot of those
premises right if you think about the
premises that you need and you look into
this data structure we actually fit all
the premises we have all the conditions
we need to actually exploit that using
this data structure so I didn't like I
did that just do like as a formalization
but usually when you write an exploit
you start making some notes on things
that you need to pass this one actually
fits out so they're like I always think
that I'm like the babies are probably
coming out of the aliases at this point
because we will control the system the
system will do something that it was not
expected there's a lot of limitations on
that right so just to be clear do like I
assume like for example in here that I
have a local process running on the
machine that can is power other
processes that process is not privileged
yet and I want that process to actually
be privileged it I do believe do like a
dis or like make it a less interesting
right now but at the same time is not
unrealistic if you really think about
doing like a server for example if you
find a vulnerability in any of the
remote process in the server usually you
have an unprivileged
access but now you do have like uh some
access in the system and then you can
launch it the same attack so even though
it's limited then like it is an example
I think it is a valid example just true
to actually say something I will show
the video of this actually running ok so
like why do we open for questions so I
want to actually give my conclusions
before then like we open for questions
but then like as I told you there is
only three things that I really care
that you remember right forget about the
primitives of no obliviousness forget
above encrypted memory this is out to
show that there like when you formalize
it's easier to demonstrate something it
starts getting more obvious right you
see that the primitive is is still there
so that mitigation will not work you see
that the attacker has way too many
primitives they definitely will find a
way to actually bypass your security
mechanism but they're like in the end
what we really need to remember is that
why this happens it happens because
every time someone is talking about four
new mitigation they don't really go and
prove this mitigation is really
effective against real cases of that
vulnerability right
I saw it multiple times of people coming
and offering a mitigation because when
abilities found and they believe there
will be a class of do's and they create
this super complicated issue super
complicated mitigation that bring more
problems than actually it solves and
then there is no more instance of that
vulnerability even so was it actually
you like did you really need to spend
that time doing that engineering did you
really improve security maybe you
actually didn't the second is like
understanding a problem is key you know
like I out there like a rule that we
follow as a team is yes we found many
vulnerabilities and we weren't even
released to be fixed as quick as
possible so we do try to report really
fast but every time we're dealing with
something new it's either a new
technology or a new place inside the new
technology or maybe even a new style of
another ability inside of technology we
write and exploit the exploit is the
definitive proof that we really fully
understood that vulnerability it's also
we have it then we can talk about the
internals the actual impact why this
happens we can really see if other
instances of this kind of vulnerability
we really exist in that technology and
then we might be able to talk about
mitigations before that any talk about
mitigations is likely going to be
irrelevant really and then do like we I
do believe that like the investments in
defense should be driven by the
investments in offense guided by it
should leverage it
that doesn't mean defense is harder or
offense is harder I just think it's
different areas that really need to be
in sync they really need to collaborate
and work together otherwise doing like
we are not able to do security in many
of the different fields so I really
appreciate your time this is my contact
I will also be around the conference I
think like maybe we have some some some
time for questions so I will let the
video be playing on like that that
attack go into a system so the way it
goes is like we have like a victim VM
then we have like an attacker basically
the system has much key memory
encryption meaning that every time you
switching VMs or go into the hosts you
have a different key that is used so
even though the hypervisor provides a
debugging interface to the victim memory
when you actually in another VM if you
fetching things through the debugger of
the hypervisor you're using a different
key
so you actually don't see the real
memory contents the attacker basically
speller process that process start
working a lot of different process so we
can dump the memory and actually see the
changes and locate where or processes
the cool thing about those locators even
more like this is no object allocators
is that every time that they try to
avoid fragmentation so if we allocate a
lots of process when we kill one we know
where the next allocation is going to
come if we were fast enough between
creating and killing the process we know
where in memory something is so that's
the principle of no oblivious even
though it's encrypted we can still find
it and since we could find it we can do
the flips and as you can see here then
like we start doing the flips and of
course I'm not printing every flip
because this is a brute-force for 2 to
the power of 32 times right so it would
like destroy my screen so I'm printing
every 1 million or something so and then
do like I'm just reading the new UID and
and you can see the process doesn't
really crash because this the UID is and
ensign idea even though I am printing
it's a sign it so you see some negative
values but the system will not crash and
you just keep doing until you manage to
get into 0 in that machine for 32 bits
type it was 15 minutes a VM attacking
another VM with encrypted memory and
everything so it's it's it's doable as
you can see there like the brute force
will keep going at some point it will be
zero it will read a secret and the video
we will restart so questions
[Applause]
thank you