good morning to everybody as I know said
I'm one of the novel presenting here I'm
now Arriba I'm from Argentina I work for
workshop which is a French security
company basically I'm here to talk about
Philips media which is not well known
architecture and all architecture but
you can still find these CPUs on the
market and some all the prices I thought
that this could be interesting for for
you because there is a lack of
information about this architecture and
it is interesting to to see what what
about it this is more or less the agenda
the talk is divided into two main parts
the first part is about the analysis of
the device iPhone this architecture and
I in this part I will try to show you
chronologically which were the steps I
followed to try to to get access to the
camera and on the second part we are
going to see the architecture itself
this is a small introduction with me now
I work for a workshop condom bed team
previously I worked at core security
doing exploit development before that
when I was a teenager I like to to break
so4 protections well I like a lot of
stuff mostly the things where is
engineering InfoSec sorrow which is the
Argentinian barbecue beard tattoos
deidre okay
this is Richard this research sorry I
started last year basically some years
ago with a former coworker we did a
presentation at hot glue in Luxembourg
about how to
Huk different models and brands of IP
cameras basically we found a lot of
bodies in this cameras remote burner
abilities from Mughal execution and we
could hack all of them and the
interesting thing about this cameras
were that all of them were armed or or
meets base cameras since then I was
collecting a lot of cameras different
models and brands and all of the cameras
also have arm ellipse but last year I
got one the link camera that was
different to all the others I found in
the past and that's the camera that has
a media CPU as I said previously isn't
too much information on the internet
about media there are a few resources
the main resource I found was that block
which is not available anymore that you
can use a whaler chip to to read if you
want starting with this research I just
published two blog post before this talk
fair one is coming in the next couple of
days
also about the three media you can find
a more detailed information on those
blog post series done done in one hour
here okay the first part is about the
analysis of the device this is the
camera the camera and all those features
are the most common features you can
find on the cameras they you can buy
today this one in particular has
concealed some motion detection remote
control Wi-Fi etc the first thing I do
when when I have an IP camera is to
start with the film on an analysis in
this case I use a Bing work to do a
quick
few more analysis and as you can see on
the screenshot Benoit was able to
identify a lot of HTML and pictures and
web things but there is no trace of a
kernel boot loader or the file system
when you deal with IP cameras
you have like two types of few more
images the first one is the system film
or image that contains a kernel boot
over on the file system and then you
have the web fumer that has all these
stuff but this wasn't the case there
were only one image available so
everything has to be inside this image
but at least for Bing work there isn't
any any boot loader or all kernel image
here so the thing is that I started with
that version which is the one available
on the a camera and but then I realized
that there is a part of a human image
especially the first megabyte of data
that beam work was not capable to
recognize anything so that that was
weird
so I used the entropy analysis of being
work to try to identify something and as
you can see the first megabyte has high
entropy and that may be indicating that
either the film or image is compressed
or encrypt at the end we will see that
it is compressed but at that time at the
beginning I could identify any
compression algorithm or any known
sulfur so I was dealing with a not very
common Fillmore image as the few more
analysis didn't throw any good results
for me I try another thing a more
dynamic approach I try to identify all
the planning services on the camera to
try to compromise any of them and get
access to to the camera
the first three services you can see
there which are HTTP FTP alternate
server are the most common services you
can find on an IP camera and then there
were other three services that were a
little weird for me I started by
analyzing the telnet server this is a
custom tailored service with some
comments you can see on the screenshot
to dump some information about the MAC
address IP address DNS servers etc and
to clear the screen and whatever but
commonly you can also find in this type
of services running on the camera shell
that gives you access to to the file
system but it wasn't this this case so I
try to to do a more a more the analysis
on the few one and fine from sorry some
other undocumented comments which are
not very interesting there were two that
I guess they were related to to turn on
and turn off any fun inside the camera
but I couldn't find any the new web to
create a new root folder for the web
server on the suicide which is used to
restore the the camera then I went for
the FTP server analysis this FTP server
only allows you to to be on one root
folder you can go away from from there
and this web server has three main files
there the most interesting one is the
flash that bean which is the entire file
system but unfortunately I wasn't able
to to dump it has only right permissions
I couldn't extract it from the from the
camera then you have a system law which
has all the activity of the camera and
the config
file which is which contains all the
configuration of the camera I could read
that file because all the credentials
for the weather ministration planet this
is a well ministration panel it has
default credentials also a guest account
in which you can see some screenshot
taken by the camera but it's not a
negative I default that's unfortunately
good for an attacker and one interesting
thing old HDTV server is that it's the
same available on biotech I become us
so I started by looking at the CGI
applications they have because there
were some vulnerabilities on the past
effect in this web server but in the
case of the of a media camera in order
to access this CGI's you need to be
authenticated so it wasn't interesting
neither for me and finally these are the
three other services running on the
camera they're radio free at all net
which is used to broadcast audio data
the filemaker service used to stream
video on the complex thing which is used
to synchronize all your own video from
the camera so at that point I couldn't
compromise any of the of the services
running on the camera the film on
analysis didn't go any way also and so I
try another way which was to open the
camera and to see what's inside at that
point I realized that I was dealing with
a very common power and I found to PCBs
on the inside the camera
the main PCB has all the main components
the CPU Ram
flash and the other one has all the
functionality for the pan tilt zoom
feature so the cpu available on this
camera was the Phillip Stroh Media PNX
1300 it's a 32-bit processor it has 128
megabytes of RAM 16 megabytes of flash
and Wi-Fi EEPROM Sidra this is the first
easy be the main PCB on your left you
can see all the qualifier flash EEPROM
cetera and on the back of the PCB you
can see the media a CPU this is the
second PCB and also I found two peanuts
one the one mark in in red has ten pins
the other one has 12 so at that point I
thought that it would be interesting to
try to identify which those pins are in
order to get physical access to the
camera because I found on the datasheet
of the vnx CPU that in the chapter 18
you have the title functional
specification which mentioned that you
have a JTAG interface to interact with
the with the camera but it seemed that
Philips has a prophet re cable to
interact with this interface and there
were also other band on the monument
data system that they also have this PC
PCI together but are really really
expensive and are not available anymore
so the first thing I try was to see
which of the pin outs are more close to
the CPU the red ones were a little bit
far so the most interesting one was the
yellow one because
there were some Tracey's going to the
CPU so basically I thought that will be
the record ones the first thing I try
was using our voltmeter but it was the
best idea any way I could get this cool
information from that but of course
nothing worked as expected
I couldn't interact with the with the
interface in any way and I saw that the
right thing to do is to to use an
oscilloscope but I didn't have one at
that time in fact it might sound funny
but from where I am a small city it's
really difficult to find this equipment
in a store we don't have a source for
this kind of devices you can buy one
from the internet but the custom in
Argentina it's really really slow so I
was screw at the time but I had some
Arduinos and I found that it's possible
to build kind of oscilloscope with an
Arduino but they the sampling rate is in
good it's almost the same as the
voltmeter so it wasn't useful at that
time so I was a little bit stuck at this
point I didn't know what else to do with
this device so I started to look at the
at the CPU itself to see if I could find
any any good thing that allowed me to
continue with the previous steps I was
doing and finally to get inside the
camera so this is just some information
about the Troy media because originally
made by Philips then it was what's known
as Xperia
it seems that it was used for automotive
and while the races in the past now it's
all arm-based
but it seems that what's useful that
mostly for the multimedia parts or video
and audio processing this type of CPUs
are known as very long instruction word
that means you can execute multiple
operations at the same time in the case
of media you can have up to five
operations at the same time but there
are all the others that allows you to
have like eight operation has the same
times on this processor in particular
has 128 32 bits general-purpose
registers there was an effort to create
a 64 bit of this CPU but it was left in
2010 try media was shut down so you can
find new devices with this architecture
and Qualcomm try to to acquire an
exterior but at the end they did this
architecture or CPU runs an operating
system known as PS OS Vsauce it's a
real-time operating system and there
were some efforts also support the Linux
kernel all Linux kernel to try media and
but the project needs a little bit all
and you continue if you want to program
to this for these chips you have to buy
the official SDK made by Philips and you
right call on C++ on try media assembler
we are going to see a little bit later
and the SDK
is only available for big companies not
for amateurs or adults like the link or
any other big bender but I want to write
code for this video I found that there
are some remedial compliant SD guy on
the internet offered by for example
streaming network but it's a little bit
expensive for an amateur like $5,000 so
it was out of my scope and there are
some more options on eBay if you want to
try but there is no SDK available so it
would be a little bit hard to to program
for that anything surrounded by three
media is a little bit obscure no one
wants to talk about try media I don't
know why
and there are lost NBA contract sign out
there so the good and official
documentation about filter media it's
private however I was able to find some
data sheets and patents on the on the
internet that I used for this research
also I already mentioned that blog and
regarding tools you have just a few to
work with extra media a guy in 2007
wrote tray media disassembler for newer
media chips TM 32 series which is a
little bit it's not equal to 2 the one
I'm presenting here but similar I
support or have support for try medias
view starting in version 4 but you have
to ask them to give you the processor
module and right now it's not available
anymore in fact I asked for the module
and they didn't give me
so I think there are some NDA contracts
there also so I started a little github
to to put all the information I was
collecting in the past and right now so
if you want to take a look go ahead
regarding this the the CPU in this
camera as I said is a very long
institution wore a processor there are
others like the shark and AC 6000 the
have more than five digits lot honestly
if I didn't mention it before it's like
a box inside the inside the chip that
has a pretty fine functionality so we're
going to see what this has 32 beats
register 128 32 bit registers
interesting thing about this try this
type of CPUs it that they implement a
special instruction for multimedia
functions this is a diagram of the CPU
and we were in the resistor model you
have from 0 to 127 register to register
the l0 on everyone are you fully on you
can change the value of these registers
of course there is a program counter on
for special registers the program
control and status destination counter
source program counter and the C count
register the the PC as W is used as a
flag register like they won't see in
Intel 32 16 for the DBC on SPC are used
for exception handling on so and thus
account just count the clock cycles
the weird thing about this architecture
is that you can change change the debate
altering on the flag you have like five
issue slot and you can change the byte
ordering on each of them so you have
like little endian and big-endian at the
same time in different part of this view
this is this is like I don't know we the
way they they they do this is by writing
that flag the bsx flag to the pc SW
register so it's it's weird memory there
are force four regions of memory the
memory hole which is 266 bytes ready ROM
with 64 megabytes mm I owe two megabyte
all the rest is PCI this is not very
interesting this is the diagram of the
these memory regions I'm removing the
media assembler and the instruction set
this paragraph is described very well
what you will find if you start to to
look at the assembler it's like black
magic really this is just an example of
the assembler on the screenshot you see
the output of the intermediary's
assembler there are some additional
information but you can see all the the
mnemonics here which you can guess what
they do and the thing is that these
operations inside the instruction may
have different of course different size
so the instruction size of an
instruction will change
and as you can see this is not really
easy to understand specially if you have
like a hundred or thousand of
instructions it's really difficult to to
get the the Deco flow one important
thing about the the assembler is that an
operation is not the same as an
instruction an instruction may have up
to five operations inside and of course
they have automatic elaboration logical
branch and the multimedia KD the
instructions hold operations are
executed in parallel each operation has
dedicated space on the chip to be
execute if you pay attention to the
previous slide only the operations
inside instruction can be carved it
means that the ins the operation will be
executed depending on the value of a
register for example the in the last
sentence you have that if r23 is set to
1 which is true then the 13 register
will hold the result from the addition
of 14 on our channel and this is very
easy any of the registers in the CPU can
be you gotta accept for their for the
ones that have a special special use
while regarding the machine you can load
and store data using a 4 somewhere in
the exit register plus a value constant
value or additional addition of two
indexes the register or and this
ratcheted plus color indexes with with
index this is not very interesting
anyway this is the
the most important part about the media
assembler which is the compression
scheme used by Philips when you compile
remedial code this code is compressed on
a byte stream and then it's the compress
by the the compressing unit the thing is
as the older information is compressed
you have a lot of bit fields that gives
you information about the instruction
and the operation the inside instruction
so you have to understand all the the
compression process in order to to
disassemble an instruction well this is
some considerations for the compression
scheme the length of an instruction will
vary depending on the size of the
operations inside the operations size
can be 26:34 and 42 bits only can be
guarded on unguarded may have zero one
or two
LeBron's may have some result or not
immediate parameters and the important
thing here is that all operations are
compressed except for the branch
operation that has a special meaning for
nature media assembler is used mainly
for to indicate the start of a function
we will see later of this and as I said
tree media use something called former
bits to give information about the each
operation inside the instruction these
are two bits that are located before
each operation and unless you have like
five operations very instruction you
have like chain from a bits this is the
table with information about kholokov
combinations for example if you have all
the the two bits set which is the full
case there that means that you don't
have any operation in that slot so
basically you have an op operation but
if you have both pits in serial that
means you have 26 a bit operation with
with no extension right the extension
bite is additional information added to
the to the instruction that is used to
build the second group of instruction in
the second group of operation sorry in
destruction because what what Phillips
did in order to build the the phone
instruction they used two groups of of
operations the first group is built with
only three operations inside and if you
have or if you want more operations up
to five you have to add more more data
today to the instruction so basically
they are more from updates on an
extension bite well this is what I was
talking about you have 26 ready for and
for two bits the 26 bit operation are
speed in two bit part on 24 bit part the
third the 34 are into bit part 24 bits
and one by the extension and the last
one into it is divided into two bit part
24 with power and to bite extensions
this is a little graphic to show you how
this is built you have basically you
start with a branch which is
uncompressed always and then you have
the former bytes for all the former bits
for the next instruction this is a
little example
this is life and this one we have in
this way we have like for instruction
for example in the first one you have
nothing you just form a bits that
indicate that you don't have any
operation
so it's an up but for example on the
last one you have the form of bits for
the three operations you have there with
24 bit parts and up to this this part
it's the the first group of operations
in instruction but then if you want to
add a four or a fifth operation to
instruction you need to add for example
on the first one you will to out more
format bits for web to operations you
have there and the extension bytes for
each of these operations and well this
is about the the branch the branch
operation I was talking about it's
mostly used to create what is called
decision trees which is a given number
of instruction you when used when you
find a decision tree opcode you know
that it start a function and you
continue the compressing the the
instructions on the operation until you
find another another branch or T 3 bytes
which are indicated with with those
opcode
the a02 on there are basic basically
four four steps to to decompress or
disassembly actually media instruction
the the first one is to get the
instruction length which is very easy
because you
of all the sizes of the operations
inside the operation size is given by
the form of bits under the complex
mechanism is the unpack and the de Cole
operation I will not go through all of
this because it's really a mess but this
is going to be a detail on the post I'm
going to polish in a couple of days so
when I after after going through all of
this process and steps of analyzing the
film were - I'm reading about eight
remedial all they'll be tied to all the
details I wanted to know what was inside
of that first megabyte of data I was
talking about in the beginning so I just
try to see what happened if I test the
disassembly with those bytes and
magically I found this all of the bytes
for that from that megabyte of data were
sucessfully disassembly intermediate all
there as I found some incoherent in the
in the disassembly process there are
some things that don't match with was I
reading on the specs but anyway mostly
all the instruction operations are
bullied but anyway it's a little bit
hard to to get the call flow from from
this from this output you don't know is
exactly where did your your code goes so
it's not very easy to to
to get all the the idea what the co is
doing so it's like it's like magic
so knowing that I started to my own
project to create an idea free and open
either a processor module for a media
I'm still working on it
basically I don't have all the resources
to to to do the test on and to and to
what to write it in the right way I have
only the camera before coming to
troopers
I received some more media based
hardware so I expect to to continue
working on this tool more buck more
documentation of course is need for this
architecture and also more affordable
tools software on however for amateurs
because this is like a mess and you need
special tools to work and I think this
is my opinion of course Philips try to
to give I don't know maybe security
biosecurity because the lack of
information is it's incredible so anyway
I enjoyed a lot of doing this research I
learned a lot well I think I you
continue working with with this
architect so that's pretty much all for
me