okay welcome everybody to our very last
session for today we will have three
short talks in a row right now and
please welcome our first speakers Enrico
and Sebastian who are talking about
simulator which is a security assessment
tool for mobile communications and
spoiler they also have Hardware on both
that they won't show us in the end of
the talk welcome thank you for
introduction yeah my name is sebastian
we were both PhD students and
researchers at the LTH wings book doing
penetration testing on IT devices and
security analysis maybe if you've been
here yesterday or day before yesterday
you've already seen enrico doing other
toxin in that domain so one topic you
came across were security investigations
on 2g and 3g communications on different
IT devices so we always tried to
basically intercept traffic on on 2g and
later as you will see also on 3G to see
which kind of data goes for example from
phone to to the provider and what
happens for example is authentication
and all that stuff for 2g this is pretty
much straightforward as probably some of
you will know because you don't have a
mechanism to authenticate you go pirate
base station at the user equipment so
you can basically just set up a pirate
base station and then you will have your
phone connect to it if you can't forget
correctly and everything should be fine
you can take a look at the traffic at
one project we did some investigations
wanted to set up to G by station again
and we did it it worked out but we saw
that not all the data was transferred so
the firmware of the IOT device was kind
of crafted in that way that anituchi and
it only has a 2g connection which
happens kind of often and in Germany for
example specially in trains but then you
will not get all of your data
transferred to the backend only the 3G
or 4G connection everything will be
we'll be transferred to the backend so
we want to come up with an idea of a
man-in-the-middle attack course on 3G
the problem here is some with a 3G
authentication is that it's a little bit
more complex and more secure than 2g I
mean when I say problem it's of course
for an attacker general it's a good
thing of course the thing is as you can
see here it's basically in here at this
state of the authentication the further
indication nonce is sent from the BTS
you know mobile station and this
authentication nodes get gets verified
so to the through the verification here
the base station is authenticated and to
send the authentication nonce from the
base station to the user equipment you
need some secret key that is on the one
hand on the operator space station and
on the other hand it's also in a user
equipment when you set up a pirate base
station you will not have that secret
key K and you cannot simply extract it
from a SIM card as it's basically here
secure hardware device so our concept
for a man-in-the-middle attack will be
now introduced from you okay so normally
the easiest way to get 3G man in the
middle is to get a paramo SIM card for
example from sis McComb you can lock
this SIM card into your device this you
program it with your own key so it will
only be able to authenticate to your own
pirate BTS then the pirate BTS routes
the traffic to a PC which is connected
through a modem to the original to the
legitimate operator using the original
SIM card and this works
90% of the time even more on most
devices however on an IOT
which comes with an embedded scheme SIM
card out of the box sometimes replacing
a SIM card is not possible not because
the synced is soldered on the board
because that's it just a matter of
disordering it and replacing it with
wire but because the SIM card contains
some specific files in the file
structure of the simple that can be
verified and the modem or the device
will detect it in some way that the SIM
card has been replaced and it will
refuse to connect or maybe it was just
an internal error or we are not quite
sure but it's impossible to connect it
to our pilot pts using a parameter SIM
card from the device we were testing we
try to reprogramming the SIM card that
program was simple but not every file is
completely completely editable
for example this size of some files
cannot be changed some files cannot be
deleted some files cannot be created
also your side and so what we decided to
do yes sir we had to come up with
another concept since our usual approach
didn't work and everyone's you continue
with the project anyway some way so
we're thinking about building the
simulator or sim simulator whatever you
want to call it so we wanted to
basically replicate or clone an existing
SIM card with custom headers at standard
micro controller and with some software
that we have running on the micro
controller so when I say cloning a sim
card of course this is not entirely
possible because the there are secret
key and stuff like that we cannot as I
already mentioned we cannot extract it
we cannot clone the SIM card
initially I mean if you could do that we
would not have to build all all that
software here so we want to clone the
some file system basically with
everything except the key material
then we want to inject custom key
material that we also have in our pirate
base station so we can somehow manage
health indication and on the other hand
also we have the same behavior regarding
the SIM card everything is part of
indication parameters you so a little
bit here on on SIM cards on on the
protocols just a little bit scraping
surface sim cards are basically smart
cards and the behavior and the protocol
of smart cards is defined in ISO 7816
it's basically a simple arecas response
structure you have a class in an
extraction but instruction by which
basically gives you an idea which kind
of command it is that is issued here you
will see an example later on you have
payload of course then you have the
length of the data or of the command
itself and the length of the expected
response and yeah for the response you
just get the raw data and some status
bytes to tell you if there's for example
more data to come or everything is
alright and you get the complete data
just shortly on the SIM card pins you
have a VC C you have a ground you have a
reset line and the clock line of course
you have a programming voltage that is
the pin that's basically deprecated you
don't really need it the most exhaust
interesting thing pin here would be the
eye over all the data comes out and goes
in so this is where we mostly focus on
regarding the same communication as we
already said SIM cards have a file
system you have this master file as you
can see in the picture which is the root
of the file system you have directory
files data yeah basically directories
containing more elementary files or the
EFS here and the EF elementary files are
actual data where for example the MSISDN
or iccid let's say the MC or anything is
stored and you have identifiers that are
defined per standard when you want to
query let's say an MC or something you
have to use this identifier to get it
so since we
to create a sim card emulator on our
microcontroller we have to implement
everything that SIM card normally does
this is the state machine of the
operation inside a sim inside a smart
card and the card goes from from idle it
receives the header of a command and it
gets into a state where it can buy some
time by sending this new device which
are basically kept alive then when it
decides that the command has to be
executed it sends an acknowledgment then
the data is transferred in either
direction either from the sim to the
modem or to the modem from the modem to
the sim after the response data after
the data's transferred the team can this
marker can buy you some more time to
finalize the common by sending some more
null bytes and then it goes back to
being idle if an error happens the
during the header for example the common
is not valid then the card goes directly
from idle to head to the state and then
it immediately returns an error status
this is an example of a header of a
common and all the parts of a common so
here there is the header of the select
file this is the acknowledgment that is
sent this is the data that is sent from
the modem to the SIM card this is the
identifier of the main file then the SIM
card takes some time to to actually do
the operation of selecting the file so
it will have to send a keepalive null
byte and finally it returns this 61 to a
state which basically says there are -
Hey - a exit wise to read as a response
and then in the next packet the next
comma will be get response it gets
acknowledged the sim in this case it is
the same that is sending the data back
to the interface and finally it says the
status which is 9000
everything is okay so you know so for
the architecture and design of the
simulator we chose on stm32f4 three for
the lowly communication that basically
this yeah let's say low low layer algal
layer here and the JavaScript for the
driver that simulates the actual file
system on the higher layers I mean the
thing was this was just a part of a
bigger project it was not like it we say
okay let's build the simulator and we
decided to dad and dad it was basically
just we had a problem pick a project and
then you said okay we need something to
solve it so we pulled the simulator and
we use Todd whereas we had laying around
and basically Chava script because we
think it's good for rapid prototyping
for us here so the microcontroller is
good because we don't need to code any
any drivers are on our own because STM
already works out of the box as it is a
USB CDC serial device this super cheap
we are just laying around and in the lab
and it has you at interfaces that can be
configured to work basically as pins and
as I so 7816 cards or interfaces so what
you see here is the first prototype of
the simulator we just use a breadboard
and stick everything together to the
pins and attach some some connector for
the sim card the the buffalo material
here is around 20 years roughly the
second picture here is our super
professional prototype that's basically
production ready we have some LEDs
attached basically for debugging and
it's everything a little bit more yeah
nice looking and a little bit more
stable so not all the cables come off
and you have to sneeze or anything so a
little bit detail on the software we
ever no chase application we have to a
sim file basically defined defined in a
in a very very big JSON file so it's
like something like a you huge
dictionary where all the files are
are specified we have already inside the
code some example SIM cards that we used
in our projects and that we had laying
around or if for example in our phones
can be easily extended to support more
SIM cards as you just want to basically
code the file system in the Chasen you
can check that the emulation we expected
because it can be unit tested we have
some test files inside and with that we
achieved our goal that the modern the
actual IOT device to read that the
investigations can not distinguish
between the emulated card which would be
the STM Hardware here and it's actually
embedded some included so this is what
we wanted so actually yeah um let's say
even unlocked here so we are happy right
now right yes it works but it's
extremely painful to create a beautiful
sim card this way it takes a lot of time
so the whole file structure as I said
has to be defined in a JSON file and
there are a lot of files in a in a you
seem in a modern sim card and even
though yeah we wrote these scripts that
automatically does a unit test that
let's say it compares it creates a unit
test out of a SIM card log so from an
original SIM card the log of
communication we can automatically make
sure that everything our theater SIM
card does is exactly the same as the
original SIM card however we have to
write this huge JSON file for any new
card that we want to support so so we
can with another idea to basically get
rid of all that huge work so it's
another man in the middle but regarding
this sim here so what we do is we
forward all the apd used packets that
are the commands from the ISO 7816
from the modern to the original SIM card
and then we only want to trigger our
simulator on the authenticate apdu
because that's the actual the only thing
where the key
material is involved and besides that
beer anyway clay cool coming with the
same how anyway so we are using the
original sim completely we just followed
a PD use and only on the authenticate
APD you which just the authentication we
are spoofing your response using the
simulator this gives us the opportunity
of not having tear the whole file system
in a huge JSON file so which kind of use
cases which you have with the simulator
you can do penetration testing on modems
you can see what's going on there you
can also do unit testing for any
application that's has some what to do
small cuts Security Investigations of
course on SIM cards and small cuts are
possible and on the 3G communication as
was the intended use actually also no
use case would be relayed relaying a
smart card over a long distance from
from the actual reading we have a video
talking 60 minutes right now anyway ok
ok so first of all this is a three
terminals debug window HL are from the
para BTS and the actual simulator window
this is the in this case with showing it
to work with a phone not in man in the
middle mode is just a phone connected to
the simulator and it has a beautiful SIM
card reading just let it run and we
don't have to know many ways so yeah a
phone is turned on at this point it will
start communicating with the SIM card
very soon and we have yeah these are all
day apt use all the packets that have
being transmitted between the sim card
and the phone at a point this will the
phone will boot
however will be not tea would still not
attach to the pirate with yes because in
this demo we were not spoofing the MNC
NMCC and all the parameters for
the BTS this was just test network so it
will hopefully it's fast enough so here
there is the phone complaining about not
being able to connect to the BTS so now
the phone will look for for every
network in the area and here is keeping
the important part but here if I select
the text network the HLR will receive
the authentication request in the upper
right corner here the phone connects it
has a 3G connection as we can see from
the on the zoom here you you can see
there was a H in the upper right corner
and if I open man in the middle proxy
and I visit some web page I can show
that yeah the 3G money in the middle
works using a completely virtual team
and that's it it's available on github
questions
[Applause]
no question at all okay one question
from my side um testing as a possible
use case does that give you the
possibility to simulate some specific
attack that you aren't able to perform
with the normal SIM card or only virtual
SIM card for example any fuzzing attack
on the actual similar interface that
could be a use case yes so for example
you could inject ap user that are
unexpected or for example send some file
over the select file common and rich
binary send some file and then
immediately after change it and change
it many times and see if the modem gets
confused in some way so definitely it's
possible to use it for fuzzing okay
thank you any further question okay if
this is not the case please thank our
speakers