my name is Eric ving been working in
physics for many years as well as the
ITF so when we talk about potential talk
for this week and all suggest a what's
happening in the ATF I mean not in 97-98
but in the recent year so just introduce
you about the ATF structures in multiple
working groups they'll hit in one topic
are they about 30 working groups they
are grouped by areas but many many
working groups are basically working
with things ready to v6 and I'm using
here some slides coming from the
introduction to the internet area don't
isolation Pascal here of course one big
interesting working group is six-month
it's called ipv6 maintenance the
maintenance of all the existing RFC and
basically everything that you need to
change one bit in one piece expects
needs to go there you want to change an
array is to go there you want to change
the protocol timers it goes there so
they are basically the gatekeeper for
all the changes and including an address
privacy and this is basically what a
finale will talk into the second part of
this tour here there are other working
groups such as 6lo which stands for 6lo
everything which is low bandwidth pretty
much like near field for instance
powerline and everything so is the
adaptation layer between a pv6 and
another layer too because guess what not
everything is running on the 23 or
dot-111 many changes as well there into
the neighbor discovery because not all
of those Network layers in layer 2
network support multicast or broadcast
of a few of them done a net full
connectivity between all the nodes so
they need to change and anybody
discovery here
another one is six dish so very strange
name so don't be afraid right don't
panic by the name it's simply time slot
channel hopping so it's
a way to transfer data on a very low
rate but very elegant I sewed a second
matrix and pretty much like in the years
of talking ring and talking this you can
talk now you can talk now so you know
when you we need to talk so it's good
for some kind of latency and some
application but of course ipv6 has not
been designed that way so we need again
another adaptation layer but this one is
pretty big
what's nice there and what we see more
and more at the ITF is open source which
is coming there for instance the 80s
starts this Saturday in Prague like two
days of hackathon and a lot of now
protocols are designed and implemented
at the same time this is brand new at
the ITF compared to long time ago
another working group is IP wave and
quite often the acronyms is interesting
so it's IP wireless access for vehicular
environment so it's from car to car or
car to infrastructure and again if you
think about moving cars they don't have
a lot of time to synchronize and do a
few things right because if you are
driving 130 kilometers an hour or higher
here in Germany and you are crossing to
each other very little time right and
the same thing if you are hopping from
one access point to an excellent access
point there's something like that
so again sorry they got a very specific
mode of user for Wi-Fi and the
transmission of v6 packets there is also
slightly different v6 ops ipv6 operation
that's one which is really really
interesting and the job that you did
trace and I know with your student
should be present it there at some point
of time it could be looking at it even
into an internet draft doesn't need to
be when I shall come back on this magic
there that's what I say there's
real-world experience I'm meeting
academics right compared to six month
where it is basically kind of the
gatekeeper
making a change there is very difficult
on purpose while you here it's more
about dynamic and testing stuff so
really important and of course the
some implementation specific
recommendation HomeNet it's basically
based mostly closed but this is the
whole network is we know and doesn't
have a lot of success in implementation
into only device on that year and the
Linksys but it's a pity because what is
happening right now when you put an say
net gear Linksys or whatever that you
buy at the major market or other place
it basically is doing that so if you
have a router you place a router beyond
your ISP router you have v6 maybe into
the SP router but the device that you
install is only doing a PV phone that
doesn't do anything about v6 and if you
put an access point behind it it will do
not again for ipv4 so in a PV for it
works because you can do not a second
layer if not a third layer of not not
great but it works in a p v6 you need
basically to distribute all the the
prefixes and do some routing okay so if
you put multiple let's say
consumer-grade boxes in a PV for it
works thanks to nut nut nut nut in a PV
six you need to do some routing there
and this all net is basically about this
or we can get multiple access so multi
home network and now you can translate
all those prefixes mostly done by the
way software this is where the DS Lite
were coming through the map protocol
both map encapsulation and map
translation are working and coming out
of software so software is mostly closed
now I think we got all the mapping V for
the v6 v 6 over v4 mean use ago it was 6
Rd but now we are there and so this we
can repeat close anytime soon a brand
new one is this one this we did mobility
management
it's everything which is about mobile
typically into the 3gpp environment so
the handset or even with 5g it's all can
we for instance find the content
can we store some data close to the base
station rather than in the core and
suela is changing from one network to
another network and all the mobile ipv6
extension are there pretty much like the
six-man is funtastic ipv6 maintains a
DMM is also the extension for mobile
ipv6 what one ipv6 by the way being one
of my big disruption in a PVC because
nobody is using it right but it could
have been so nice something which is
also starting is this elegant
lightweight implementation guidance
it's about IOT device or very
lightweight and implementation not
linked only to ipv6 but oh can you do a
lightweight IPSec or can you do a
lightweight nat64 or can you a
lightweight enable discovery right so
not using us a lot of memory not using a
lot of CPU power for instance and power
so very interesting working through and
is basically sharing experience right so
we don't specify all to code but it's
basically a I've done it this way this
is better and brand new working group
it's about github so we meet for the
first time in in Prague next week it was
above before and it's not about study
sites on the specification the gaiter
protocol is more ok we can use at
authors at the ATF get up because that's
just a document right so we can use it
for control issue with a tracking and so
on my biggest concern there is that
these the Charter so the working group
must work about jitter but is happy
before only right so looks like you are
hinting that some change are coming but
I find it shooting ourselves in defeat
right if the 80s is working on a group
that does not support ipv6 anyway this
is was basically a quick browse through
working groups linked to a pv6
now let's go and look about some recent
RFC most robably you have seen this one
you write for a long time the previous
RFC 2460 which described ipv6 was not
understand that track
so this RFC 8200 is now on a standard
track is even a standard try 86 so there
are different levels in the ITF and in
RFC it's mainly about clarification in
the addressing for instance it also says
that fragmentation we've indexed another
chain should not be permitted and you
should discard them so quite cool that
was the biggest security issue so nice
another one is this one benchmarking
metallurgy for ipv6 transition
techniques so and by the way there is
also BMW I think it's interesting in in
Germany so BMW benchmarking working
group doing a few of those thing it's
basically if you do two performance
evaluation like dns64 and that six four
there is a DNS portion there impacting
the performance so it's not only about
the nat64 itself but you also need to
take into account establishment back or
dns64 I am that's basically it right so
there's the reason why they wanted to
get something very specific for those
techniques talking about performance
measurements another RFC and it's very
interesting one and I will grab some
water it's about the performance
measurement and the use of destination
option header so we start to see and I'm
quite happy by this we start to see use
of those extension header for good
reason so their water source routing for
statement routing foundation option is
there so it's basically there are
remember addition option is basically
when you are reaching a destination the
destination and only the destination
should look at it and by the way you can
have to destination option header into a
navy six packets one in the rear
destination and the other one and the
first up just before the routing header
again it was designed for this for
mobile ipv6 right when you go for the
first up the care of address before
going to the home address there was two
decision option as the reason why you
can use it here and one specific
decision option header and it's
standardized here can say for instance
there are sequence numbers and timers
there so it could be useful now I don't
know so many experimentation of it
though but can be used and what's nice
here you can see it's sent from very
different v6 addresses so it goes
through the internet which was quite
interesting because when it first is
designed to go through the internet so
they can be a third parties on the path
doing nothing and hopefully of course we
can cross finger that the extension
header will not be drop on the path
which is not grant it as we all know so
there is another one I owe a m2
Institute om which Eric that's the same
thing right so why are we using two
different thing to measure performance
but this one is different the one on the
slide the RFC is end to end the routers
on the path and not managed they don't
care in this case in situation this is
we've in one am assertive domain so on
operator one enterprise is using
hop-by-hop extension headers mainly and
it's require supports on each and every
router and each name we're out on the
path is putting timestamps and also can
signs that these packets are going
through this router there's very
important for security if you want to do
network function virtualization and you
want to ensure that you go first by the
load balancer let's say then by the
contamination and then to the server for
instance you want to enforce a specific
path in all Oceana V so with this we can
see the proof that yeah it's gone
they're there and they're based on
crypto so quite cool another one from my
friend Gunther and gdb we have so many
v6 addresses right so currently you are
pretty mean Chris and I know because you
give us only one share ipv6 prefix for
all of us
so you're honest and oh and Veronica we
are sharing the same v6 traffic's this
thing says a what if I am replying to
the router solicitation and I give one
router advertisement to Fernando with
one prefix to you Veronica
another unique ass with another prefix
so all of us has got different prefixes
which is quite cool because how can you
do a rogue area attack how can you do
man in the middle I mean you can still
do it but naively you will think that I
my prefix is the one used by everyone
but I don't see any other traffic quite
cool
it's a side note they are talks as well
and people are doing it by using the IP
prefix delegation for instance to give a
slash 64 for each and every host ok the
previous thing is just a hint to do it
right I'm sending you a Rotter of
attachment unicast but the O's doesn't
know get a slash 64 here the host knows
that it got a slash 64
why could it be useful simply because if
you have a lot of containers in the v6
part which is interface and modifier you
can put the time when the container
started and you can put as well the
container image ID or anything you want
into the address because you have so
many of them that the family should
create a huge amount of content
initiated on the fly thousand per
seconds we can still get a unique a pity
six address and then in the log oh you
were talking to this v6 address oh but
it was at that point of time it was
started we're using this image right for
the container so it could be very useful
for fingerprinting F so for auditing
mythically another one everyone knows
about API ball Apple and Tommy made a
version two of it it's simply
clarification it also specified with 15
milliseconds preference so even if you
get the a before the quad-a you wait 15
minutes seconds to get basically the
quad-a and start v6 it also specifies
what to do when you have multiple DNS
servers like I got a few of them right
DHCP a few of them by the array or by
other interfaces as well so how to
handle this so this one is interesting
so two guys one from intern and one from
other say a there are IP packets before
in v6 that are terminated on the
internet by some middle boxes like
firewalls or whatever and this is bad so
they specify it now right and that's
really an April Fool's name RFC so they
are we are doing this again that's two
or three every year so really look about
this first of April is coming in two
weeks time frame next Monday in two
weeks you should go and on this one they
say a for-instance packet can be
terminated and it was a views view joke
by color so racist color of the package
I deserve got pwned right the age ages
this is of course you hop limit and the
origin oh you are coming from I don't
know this control this country based on
the source address a very nice one you
you should read it again just a joke
dhcpv6 and many many people involved
there as a new revision a new document
but is the same protocol right so they
changed nothing
it's still the unique the UID which is
used and we still do the lease through
the DHCP unique ID and not to the
hardware client address it was mainly
about clarification physically this one
from German cover and Google sure I I
will most only skip I write so it's not
too to the ITF to say it use this or use
that even this right so it's there they
are saying implementation I think it we
say for a long time now you need it as
well for DT PPD for instance but the ia
we could scratch it I do agree and you
will see early trying as good also an
experiment to extend and put whatever
option you want into a route of
attachment
and you agree it's a mess and
specifically when the array is
configured by somebody which is debt
working department while the HCP is
depicted on into the server department
and they don't agree with what the
content would be inside I don't know if
you've seen this is pretty messy in this
case anyway so it's there is therefore
for living and again the ATF doesn't
recommend stuff or whatever we provide
you with protocols so genuine cover was
again using route advertisement for
enterprise multihoming Wow
so it's basically when an enterprise or
actually a consumer as to uplinks
through ISP a and is P B so he received
two prefixes so you advertising inside
your network prefixes from a and
prefixes from B and then you need to
select the right outgoing router if
you're using prefix a you need to go
egress through ISP a if you aggress to
ISP be anti-spoofing will drop your
packets right and you need to be
resilient so that's basically it right
so this is an again coming from a slide
from one gen and she likes cats and
assume that the Internet is only to look
at pictures of cats right maybe that's
right so two routers to ISP and you need
to be sure that you exit by the right
one a very very simple way of doing it
is relying both on the source address
selection and on the router the Tasman
itself so if a primary link is
operational so you have two routers
address from the other the backup prefix
should not be used so you you can say a
I got the prefix from be but the prefer
lifetime is zero so I don't using them
but I am the prefer router I am sending
you prefix a with a referral lifetime
which is higher than zero so you will
use it and now if ever the uplink goes
the
or the router goes down on route to a we
need to change okay basically we need to
send a prefix B is now prefer lifetime
greater than zero and the router itself
has got the preference
Haggar than zero so you will use both
the router and the prefix so that's
basically oh she is doing rather right
now if you say whatever language press
router prefix blah blah refer lifetime a
big one you change it into something if
some condition are true could be the
router is up or the interface is up or
we can ping on the next stop then I send
the prefer lifetime to something which
is higher than zero as lifetime zero and
then it works for the O's now you need
to find a way of doing this on routers I
don't know about no routers doing it but
most of the router nowadays has got some
scripting language then you can use to
do this and it solve a nice problem now
if you think about it it's all only the
problem for the next land because if I
go back it will solve the problem of
those host but if you have multiple
routers in an Iraqi you need to apply
the same thing on the routers okay if
you have a say typically an access
router and then distribution and then
another access router you we need to
play a couple of tricks there but it
works she try yeah that's exactly a new
perfectly right
the some condition here must include
things like you if I advertising this
prefix I need to be sure that the router
and all the ingress point and the next
stop are working as we want trouble yeah
but if you have you fail to Delhi one
it's also failing then if you have to
failure your to failure right so if
you've only to egress points one is
failing and the backup is failing
of course there is missed one so there
right
okay then Lee we've got something a Mary
see about reverse DNS for Internet
service provider you remember I reverse
DNS is my personal nightmare I can do it
in a pv4 right it's by hand but in v6
specifically when you have many many
zeros I mean I can count one two three
four and then after I need me to use a
pen to count the zeros because I cannot
do it by my brain give up so in the
sense of for service provider with
residential users it proposed for
instance to reply no such domain so you
reply right so don't like the the
resolver pending in the air waiting for
timeout so reply immediately with
basically a negative reply no such
domain or what cut much residential user
dot no doctor Telecom the de why not
DNS dynamic DNS update you can do it now
you can do it aided by the relational
gateway so the on router that will do it
on the behalf of all the hosts or you
can ask the oast for doing this as well
or you can delegate the DNS zone to the
reader shall Gateway couple of proposed
I here but no real solution there is an
RFC little come as well which replace
another one which is ipv6 not
requirements what is it about that's
basically a road map telling a please
read this and this and this mister
implementer or deployer but you don't
need to use everything but just be aware
for instance of fragmentation beware
about a source address selection and
they say to come back to Fernando's
point slack state address
auto-configuration is mandatory DHCP is
optional
it's a shouldn't capital or me I don't
know I don't know
it says you candy and I know you should
is say you must do it except if you have
good reason not to do it
I don't remember sorry
so for instance also they say that DNS
over Ottawa taxman is mandatory so it's
fixed there a few thing regarding and
your feature that comes in the last time
and even they remove a few thing from
the latest RFC I mean pv6 over ATM I
mean it goes back right a pv6 was at the
same time when ATM to the desktop was
there I mean I'm Olly enough to have
seen this on slides at least anyway
going now through the internet draft so
internet draft are just draft okay
there's not because they will be here
that they will be become error see that
they are supported by the ATF they've
been reviewed by other people or there
is even an implementation it's just to
give you some ideas that where other
engineers are working you know each and
every internet draft has got an
expiration time a few months before so
about all the internet draft at the ATF
there are about 300 of them even ipv6
inside so important isn't it this one
and basically it's coming from Bob
Hindon that's Bob is one of the two guy
implementing and specifying a pv6 years
ago it says is ipv6 wrote advertisement
before not pv6 only flag cuz when you
look about here a troopers a kids on my
Mac I still have an ipv4 address even v6
on the SSID the 168 to 5-4 right don't
link local and also my Mac spend
sometimes doing a DHCP before and I put
issue is sending the HPV 4 packets with
discovery every minutes or so so the
goal here is to send it to the router
advertisement one specific flag that
tells there is no TV for
no need to do the HCP before no need to
get a link-local right because in some
case you can even this link-local and
one again 169 2 5 4 could be blocked
because some network will only allo ipv6
packets right it's xdd and Zeta type
will block completely all the ipv4 one
so even if you have a link-local v4 you
may be if no communication with other
link local ipv4 so you need to know as
your host so obviously they cannot be
done for DHCP before right because there
were some assumption yeah what about
adding an option in the HCP v4 tele 8
there is no v6 here they mean come on
right let's be serious so we could not
do this right now the only thing is that
there are only about 10 or 16 bits for
putting flags into wrought advertisement
and a lot of them are already used so
it's just more like a smile exhaustion
of those flags into the routers vert
iseman is closing another one and if you
were there last year I think I presented
this slide that's another point of view
about the ability humming and typically
when you have one laptop can be tethered
to a mobile phone you can go over Wi-Fi
you can go over Ethernet the classical
ways of multi interface device and you
can get to ISP friends for instance and
you can get a VPN provider going back
home so you can basically add multiple
addresses and multiple exit points as I
said oh you do it with ipv4 and you have
been warned not it's solve the problem
right because if you are using anyway we
have only one ipv4 address on one
interface you looking this way and if
you select this address you go let's say
over Wi-Fi and you would go there and
this one is going not and the return
traffic will go through there as if you
have multiple prefixes in basics you can
for instance use the address from here
exit there open it you are not
and I spoof by this one and traffic may
come back by this way and you're all
your firewall and stateful device are
lost because the a no state so we need
to find a way and one way it's what we
call decision and sauce fronting or
source address dependent routing what is
this we so will be routing not only
based on the destination like you do
normally but you will also do routing
based on the sauce
so whether you use the prefix A or B or
C you will follow a different path in
your network
so we basically extend all the fifths of
the forwarding information base so
that's basically the routing table if
you want with a sauce prefix we say this
route to disturb entry is only valid by
this source address and there is any key
word which basically sends a from any
source address signal got an example
here where for instance very simple fume
entry for any source going everywhere
you use route the tree from this
specific traffic's going everywhere
again wrote a tree now a more specific
traffic's going everywhere use this exit
point so this could be for instance as
the prefix I got from my VPN so when I
using my VPN I need to go to this router
for instance now whatever
so it basically allow you to steer
traffic on one specific path and the
beauty of it and I use write a tree and
router for just to solve the multihoming
system here
you remember write a tree wrote a fall
in the previous slide you do not need to
touch the routing in all other routers
because those routers will route you
basically based on the destination but
on those two if you have source and
address decision routing they out you
don't
need to go by me you need to go there so
the packets will go for instance this
way and rot the tree will reroute based
on the source to the other exit router
oh you are using the prefix from is b2 I
know from the source address you need to
exit this way another way of solving the
multihoming issue another thing as well
the anti-spoofing that's basically what
I said here but now you also need to
know which in the case you have multiple
prefixes advertised to you
which one should I use so there is a so
dress selection that selects the closest
to the destination right
the most common bit not always we can
fine because in some case you have part
of your prefixes that are reachable only
via the internet or only we have the VPN
or only in the intranet for instance so
there is the concept at the ATF that
exists for a long time of provisioning
domain and again I talked briefly of
this last year our thing provisioning
demand has the set of properties on
configuration that you need to use which
is the interface which is my prefix
which is my address which is my next
stop and so on am a DNS server and when
you are using one of those element you
need to use all of them at the same
vendor okay I am about using my mobile
interface then I knew to use the DNS
server of this mobile interface right
from this mobile provider not the one
coming and good from Wi-Fi for instance
so we basically on this draft and I say
we because I'm a coder on this we are
again extending the router that iseman
by an adoption where there you can put
the name of the purling domain which is
actually a fully qualified domain name
it intensifies the window okay okay all
those parameters that are received in
the array and flags - under the HCP as
well needs to be considered as a bender
so when I'm using one of the confusion
item and
to use all of them one thing and we can
also use this fully qualified domain
name basically to regress over TLS a
JSON file that destroyed more oh this is
for instance for video or this is the
one for video setup boxes or this is for
low latency or whatever that's it
talking about right advertisement a very
recent one from laying yeah familiar
name right we see you know them because
it is a chairman of six month and they
are annoyed by getting many many people
coming to six money can we get another
option for router detachment for doing
this
can we get another one for giving that
so his point was to say why not doing
something such as universal wrought
advertisement which will be of course
type length as usual in the thing and
data and the data is simply a JSON file
right and then there will be of course
in the IANA which will restore all those
theme numbers in the ITF there will be a
registry IETF and then DNS or nat64 all
those keys will be into average video so
to allow the operation of course as
version 0 0 so pretty new I'm sure it
will go there but you can really feel
the working group chair which is annoyed
by getting so many requests for another
array option here yeah
so as we are in troopers so my dear
friend and I know we'll go through
progress and this that's a work we have
done for many years now in objects or
personal security and it's basically
consideration before it was
recommendation but we have to change the
consideration for a pv6 network it's a
very very known one it all started so
it's mainly focused on enterprise who is
providing as residential at touch on the
mobile data and 3gpp but nothing on IOT
because there are so many IOT use case
that's not easy to make any
and consideration here topics is about
addressing extension interest neighbor
discovery basically what are the
differences and we point to add a
document um give some consideration so
again I said we are using consideration
but for instance we talked about ula
right you remember this universal local
address because we think we need to say
a few words on this assuming the reader
is unaware about all the complexities of
everything but as soon as you mention
ula into an ATF document you see someone
non-friends write it again gyuki yeah
yeah I mean we know that right so boom
boom bazooka bazooka bazooka again
removed it and bla bla so now I think
you know we we are completely pissed off
by all those back-end force you need to
say this and this that we say usually
exist and we refer to neither the draft
so we went from five page or two page or
whatever on ula to two lines so now if
we are still block on basic yeah
so there are before doing the flow to
Fernando other draft as well I had no
time to go through it again I try to
give you a hint of multiple areas about
the variety it's really up to you to dig
further and I would love as well to
thank you not only for listening here
but please act on this IDF right the
IETF is not reserved to some super power
or super duper engineers or whatever or
God it's about engineering there are
some politics to be true but most of the
time is about playing engineering so all
of us in this room can basically
participate in what we call mailing
lists and you go to the IDF dot org
website and you will find everything you
can register it's free when I'm talking
there even with my cisco.com address I'm
representing Eric Vinc not Cisco
okay so that's not about vendors now
again there are some vendors politic
there right don't take me wrong but it's
free and you can review draft you can
Auto draft I mean writing a draft that
may become an RFC it's just writing
right now in Division two of the process
and we are moving anytime soon to
version three needs to be XML okay so
you need to understand some of the XML
but you got tools for doing something
different I don't know which shoe you
are using Fernando okay even I'm using
XML and an XML editor so basically
please participate at the ITF just
review and people like authors like
Fernando or myself or yourself
we are quite happy when we got some
review so people telling a what's there
what's there
don't blame me again about their ula do
right don't we more so Fernando up to
you well this is like Latin Americans
heaven because I get to be late and
blamed somebody else so usually it's my
fault
so now I'm going to enjoy it
first of all I'm quite glad to be here
again for me it's always an opportunity
to meet with colleagues and besides you
know the excuse of you know giving a
presentation for me the most important
part is you know when you talk to people
even not the speakers dinner I have had
like be funny and interesting
conversations well drinking beer there
so this presentation is going to be
about some specific RFC's on IDs that
are active at the IDF so it's what's you
know what the idea of if you look at the
content you might think like that so I'm
going to cover a couple of topics
there were many ideas and many rfcs go
and you know being published or being
discussed at vidya IDF and when I was
deciding what to you know which ones to
discuss in this presentation I tried to
you know group them somehow in some way
so that it didn't look like you know
stuff that didn't have anything to do
with each other so I decided to actually
focus on all of those artists rfcs and
ideas that somehow how to have to do
with addressing first one of all you
might
we have the ipv6 address in architecture
which is RFC 42 91 and there was or
there still is the project of moving
this RFC to standard actually one of the
goals of six money's to move all of the
core RFC's to internet standard full
standard that happen already with twenty
four sixty which became it which was
replaced by 8200 this was the plan for
the address in architecture too but
progress on this document has been
stalled for quite a while
discussion has been mostly about the
requirement if you want to force a / 64
for subnets okay so there are folks that
think that yeah like slash 64 that
requirement is part of the architecture
whereas there are other folks that
believe that that's not part of the
architecture okay
so essentially progress has been stalled
over there and it's unclear you know how
things are going to progress when it
comes to this document because it's like
yeah yeah like lots of people on one
side and lot some people on the other my
personal view is I don't think that any
specific value belongs to an
architectural document like it's not
architecture then you can put that
requirement elsewhere like you know in
slack and so on but that shouldn't be
part of the architecture that's my take
of course if you wonder what is all this
discussion about well the folks that
tried to or or that thing that this / 64
should be enforced in the architecture
they think I'm probably to some extent
they are right that if this / 64 is not
required in the architecture then ISPs
are going to start reducing the amount
of addresses that they are going to
lease to clients and eventually it's
they are going to run down to the bottom
and eventually lease in a single address
and we go back to ipv4 that's their take
other stuff related to addresses this is
kind of like status update if you want
you know you know that we have stable
addresses and we have temporary
addresses the stable addresses used to
at least the standard ones windows used
to do something different they used to
embed the MAC address in the interface
ad we changed that years ago with 72 17
BIA 1864
so essentially 72 70 17 specifies the
algorithm and then 86 64 tells you that
you had to do 74 17 that's kind of like
procedural stuff if you want but the
nice thing is that after a while if you
look at you know many popular operating
systems nowadays they ship with 72 17 on
by default so at least all these ones I
think that Windows still does something
else but you know a system it's anyway
it's you know good news I mean from my
perspective you know when something that
when you have work on something that is
a piece of paper standard and it
actually makes to an implementation
that's a good thing if it just remains
on paper there's no point to that so
been truly eventually you know be as
these most distributions of Linux Linux
has implemented support for this in the
kernel network manager also implement
support for 72 17 and there is a demon
called DHCP CD which is for example
raspbian uses that for automatic
configuration
they also default to 72 17 so if you do
a fresh install of any of these systems
and you see that you know the addresses
have changed well this is the reason
then temporary addresses temporary
addresses you know are widely support
they are enabled by default on some
platforms not in all of them like
Windows is one of the you know examples
where temporary addresses are enabled
but there are in
number of issues in the in the spec
itself so it's not implementation floss
but actually in the spec itself there
are things that should be improved and
this is what comes in the you know in
the next slide and the next slides so
that should there we go
so I mentioned that we had some issues
in 49:41 they are AC for temporary
addresses obviously if that's if those
are issues related to the specification
and not with an implementation of it
then they had to be you know fixed in
the in the standard itself so that's why
we publish this draft which has already
become a working group item of the six
month working group that tries to fix
those remaining issues in 49-41 without
getting into too much detail among the
things that we want to change in the
revision is first of all allow the use
of only temporary addresses if you look
at 49:41 it assumes that temporary
addresses are always employed along with
the stable addresses okay obviously
there is a reason for that
because for a general purpose system you
don't know if it's going to act as a
client or as a you know as a server so
you want to have both types of addresses
but for example for a mobile phone you
might want to just use temporary
addresses you know we want to allow the
use of it it's it's not that we want to
push for that all the things or other
yeah other aspects that we should
improve in in 49-41 for example 49:41
says that if you have different prefixes
on the same network you will use the
same random identifiers in all of the
prefixes okay well of course that's not
nice from privacy point of view because
if the ID is the same on all of the
prefixes then you know you can correlate
the addresses by looking at the
interface ID okay you have connections
coming from different prefixes all of
them use the same 64
you know bits so from a privacy point of
view of course that doesn't make sense
so we want to recommend against that so
if you are configuring temporary
addresses and you have different
prefixes well each address should use a
different interface area so that you
cannot correlate the activity of each
other there are also cases where an
implementation reuses an interface ad
when it moves from one network to
another so the interface ad only changes
as a as a function of time okay but of
course if you are moving from one
network to another the interface ad
should change
that's you know that's should be obvious
other stuff there's also a limit on the
number of non deprecated addresses that
you can have at any point in time and
what we like is that at any point in
time you can have you know multiple
addresses that are active on your system
obviously you know from a privacy point
of view that's that's a good thing and
the final one is that 49:41 recommends
to disable temporary addresses by
default and we want to enable them by
default so the default setting should be
that temporary addresses are enabled if
you don't want them turn them off
there's still work going on on this ID
so if you have the time and you're
willing to reviews are appreciated
we try to keep as much of the content
the original content as possible and
only change it and only change the parts
that we're really necessary but you know
still reviews are necessary other stuff
I will try to go faster on this one so
that we catch up yeah yeah yeah
so tell me at which time we have to ok
ok no primero
[Music]
that that's carbon that's karma but I
still have a time in the in the other
lot so it there's no problem for that so
the other one is it's this one is
actually quite interesting for you know
two different reasons which I will
discuss briefly so if you look at ipv6
or the way I look at about a type II v6
is that it's all about the extra
addresses right so you are deploying the
six because you run out of before
addresses and that's the whole point of
basics you have like I mean there's a
lot of potential when it comes to
addressing because you can use as many
addresses that you want I mean there are
plenty of them and there are also
different properties for the addresses
like for example you have addresses of
different scopes which to some extent
you have in before and there are also
addresses of different properties such
as stability for example okay so in
theory there are a lot of things that
you could do with that now problem is
that well you have all the stuff in the
standards there's not much guidance
about when to use which kind of virus
and for what okay so you have all those
services configured on a system but
still the applications are clueless
about that and the operating system
doesn't do much about that except you
know policies like you know okay prefer
temporary addresses but not much more
than that
okay this I mentioned so we can you know
talk about three different properties
there might be others
but there was that at least I found
interesting from a security privacy
perspective out are these three scope
stability and usage type which of course
have implications so let's start with
scope and this is related to what Eric
presented in his drink a stock if you
have for example in non-global
outer scope that provides some kind of
like prophylactic security meaning that
in theory it's you cannot reach those
services because you know you are out of
scope it's like if you are connected on
a local network here and you try to get
my link-local addresses at home you
won't be able to okay of course then
there are the small details and things
that you can do but you know that's
that's you know a security related
property with with the scope ulis are
one specific case of this I am NOT going
to get into the discussion whether you
know you should use them or not I mean
it can be art one way or another but you
know these services are still there and
the most important point from my
perspective is that the standards do
specify the services but there's no
guidance on what to do with them so
that's essentially the point that I'm
trying to get to like you have lots of
focuses on your system addresses of
different properties but nobody tells
you you know what to use what which are
is and for what okay
then there's the issue of stability I
mean it's obvious that you know the
longer you use an address the more it is
exposed for you know different reasons
for example if you use content constant
interface identifiers like you know the
traditional slack addresses you know the
notes can be tracked across networks
because obviously you have 64 bits that
are globally unique so that means that
by looking at the interface ID you know
you can essentially identify what's the
node that you are communicating with so
those are if you want the you know
traditional traditional slack addresses
then we have the stable / Nagar
addresses or there's 72 17 okay
these are addresses that are stable as
long or interface IDs that are stable as
long as you keep connected to the same
network but they will change when you
move from one network to another so 72
17 what it does is you connect to a
network you always compute or you always
get the same interface today you move to
a different network they interface ID
changes you go back to the original
network you get the semi interface ID
okay
that's like that's that's a design goal
okay but you know on one hand they are
nice from an Operations point of view
because the addresses are not changing
all the time on the other hand of course
since they are stable within the you
know within you know your network you
can correlate activity you know over
time then we have temporary addresses
okay which are supposed to limit you
know the ability of an external party of
correlating negativity so you have a
resistor for the most part you will use
for client like activities like you know
browsing the internet browsing the you
know the web and they are changing over
time of course it's you might argue you
know to what extent this is effective or
not because for example it's typical
that these services change for example
once a day now you might say well is it
enough to change the addresses once a
day or maybe not okay because obviously
doing that whole day that you are using
this temporary addresses it never
activity can be correlated and then
there are these let's say throw away
addresses rather than connections this
is an idea about rather than you know
configuring an address and using it for
everything that you know you are doing
just configure an address use it for
whatever you wanted to use it and then
remove the address you'll see that when
I do the presentation in the afternoon
about the tool kit which is like short
presentation I use this concept to
actually to actually do queries to
search engines which essentially write
limit you so if you're able to
essentially send each query from a
different address even more if it's from
different prefixes and you can't get
different prefixes of course you know
the search engines are going to believe
that you are a totally different client
and it's okay so at some point in time
before implementing this I had to have
like different
because so I couldn't do as many queries
as I wanted whereas using this concept I
can use a single machine and I use a /
48 chat for that machine and I just
address it from that whole space ok OOP
then there's also I mean besides the
your specific usage there's also like I
mean right now there's there's not much
of the say of advice about when to do
what
for example you might argue that you
know for the general case or by default
you might want to do these two which is
stable addresses plus temporary
addresses but of course that depends on
the type of you know platform or you
know what you expect to do with you know
which that device and so far there are
no recommendations about that like you
know if you have a let's say in mobile
device what what which addresses should
you use like stable temporary both well
it's left to the implementer if you want
and there's another one which is
interesting which is you know the idea
of having stable and temporary addresses
is that you use the stable addresses for
incoming communications because usually
you will want to you know post the
addresses from the DNS for example and
you don't want to be updating the DNS
all the time and you use the temporary
addresses for the outgoing connections
okay so that's kind of like the idea now
there was a like real wall before
getting to that now there is a problem
or a limitation that has to do with the
api's essentially if you have done any
you know sockets programming you know
that normally when you want to let's say
buying an address this is the system
call that you use or the API that you
use and essentially buying ILO's allows
you do two different things either bind
a specific address or bind any address
but you cannot bind for example like a
subset of the addresses what does it
mean that if you have a system that has
for example
using different prefixes and it has
temporary addresses and stable addresses
well either you listen for incoming
connections on all of the addresses or
on one specific address but you cannot
do something like for example just
listen on the stable addresses now you
might say well why should I care about
that and this is a real-world example
short version of the story is like this
there was a guy that had a raspberry pie
you know fresh install he connects the
fresh the raspberry pie you know to the
Internet but he didn't do anything and a
couple of minutes after that he gets a
poor scan so he said well from where I
mean how did they know that my system
was alive
well turns out that the guys had
shortened they had a volunteer to
volunteer to run an NTP server as part
of the pool of you know public NTP
servers and I guess in as a kind of
retribution to the service for the
community they decided to scrub the
addresses and use those services as
input to this to their search engine
okay essentially that meant that if you
were using let's say any any Linux
distribution that was using that pool of
NTP servers and you happen to be
connecting to the NTP server that these
guys were running well they you'd learn
your address and then they you'd port
scan you to actually you know
incorporate your system into their
search engine not nice of course now I
mean besides the fact that well this is
not nice then there is this other
question like let's say that I had a
raspbian system and I connected to an
NTP server so what I did was like a
client like activity okay so I was
consuming some service from the Internet
so these guys the guys running the NTP
server they learned but my temporary
address now obviously if that's the only
address that they learned does the
address that they are going to scan now
the question is
why should I be accepting incoming
connections on the temporary address
temporary addresses are only meant for
outgoing connections well that's the
limitation of the API so since the API
doesn't allow applications to buy to
bind a subset of the addresses or for
example specify the properties like if
you have an application you should say
well I just it's a server right so I
want to bind my application to the
stable addresses never accept connect
incoming connections on the you know on
the temporary addresses you just can't
the only way in which you could do it
and you should do it properly it
probably is you know to set up a
firewall and you allow incoming
connections on the stable addresses you
whitelist those addresses if you want
but you block all of the others if you
were doing that kind of stuff that meant
that anybody that learns your temporary
addresses because you were consuming
stuff from the internet they are not
going to be able to use those services
because you don't accept incoming
connections on those so in this specific
example these guys run in the NTP server
will have would have lured your address
but then when they scan you you just
dropped those packets because you don't
accept incoming connections on the
temporary addresses I mean that's
something that could be done but because
of the limitations that we have in the
API is the only way in which you can
possibly do that nowadays is you know
just configure firewall one more slide
yeah one more slide so the thing is
essentially that there is a lot of work
to be done in this area like you know
from my perspective the whole point of
ipv6 is the addressing the algorithm
power like you know you can have as many
addresses as you want we have like lots
of different properties but there's not
any work on you know how you can
actually make use of them now my I was
let's say puzzle in a way that when I
submitted this draft I presented you
know this document at the six bun
meeting
also talked to people in other working
groups and there didn't seem to be much
interest so I mean I it's not the ID
that is important but the fact that you
have all these thingies
specified and there's no guidance you
know for people on how to configure then
on how to use them I think that there is
something missing there so this is our
breaking point so that was the end of
the presentation about the toolkit now
I'm going to go back to the presentation
that I did today in the morning for
those that were not here in the morning
it was a presentation about stuff that
was work that was going on at the IDF
and the last topic that I have mentioned
was about the lack of advice when it
comes to the use of ipv6 addresses okay
there's a document that I mentioned
already in the morning this one
essentially discusses you know all of
the stuff related to addresses like you
know security and privacy implications
of different properties like you know
scope time frame and so on now there is
the last bit I don't know if that's
anybody of you follow this six-month
mailing list or b6 ops one okay well if
you do follow one of those mailing list
there was doing the last month or so but
a let's say long discussion about an
internet draft that we co-author with a
with a friend of mine about the reaction
of slack to renumber in events if you
didn't you know if you read in if you
didn't read about the discussion this
might be useful because I might be
pointing out a problem that you might be
having or you might have in the future
but you were you were not aware about so
let's consider this typical deployment
scenario for ipv6 okay so the scenario
is quite simple you have your ISP your
hub you have your home router here and
you have your local network okay
normally you do slack on the local
network and you do DHCP prefix
delegation towards the ISP okay so your
router requests a prefix from your ISP
and then advertises some prefix some sub
prefix of this prefix here on the local
network that's normal
hundred percent normal now the question
is what happens in scenarios for example
such as when the CPE CPE router crashes
and reboots okay
so again in the normal deployment
scenario you have this situation the CPE
router does prefix delegation with the
ISP it receives a prefix and then it
advertises on the local network some sub
prefix okay you might get let's say a /
48 from your ISP and then you advertise
some / 64 belonging to this / 48 now
this we did a comment before we get to
the actual problem you probably know
that both in slack and in DHCP there are
lifetimes or at least times involved I
even if that's the case also with the
HCP version 4 so you request an address
and the DHCP server tells you well it's
ok you get this address and you can use
it for this time frame okay the same
applies to the HCP version 6 prefix
delegation and also the same applies to
slack normally the lifetimes that we are
talking about are in the order of months
or in the order of 1 month or so ok so
it's certainly over overdone a week now
what happens for example in the problem
scenario that I mentioned the CPE router
just you know crashes and reboots
normally these devices don't don't don't
record the prefix that they had been
leased before on any kind of stable
storage so when they actually reboot
they obviously they don't remember what
is the prefix that they had been leased
before so they request a new prefix to
the ISP okay and they obviously
advertise on the local network the new
prefix that they got now the question is
what happens with the previous prefix so
if we go back here I have my router ID
request the prefix I advertise on the
network this one crashes now it receives
a different prefix and advertises a new
prefix here that's okay but what happens
with the old prefix because no no one of
these systems here are aware that the
all-perfect is not valid anymore okay so
at some point these routers said okay
you can configure an address for this
prefix you can use it for a month if you
want now when these rather reboots it
never tells the systems on the local
network that they all prefix is actually
stale that is not valid anymore now the
end result of that is that all of the
systems that you have on the local
network they keep the old addresses and
they also keep the old roads and they
are not going to remove neither the
addresses nor the roads until the
lifetime of those prefix expire now if
you go if we go back to the you know
what I mention about the lifetimes
we are talking about lifetimes in the
order of one month meaning that the
network configuration is going to be
skewed for a month
what are the implications of this well
you might be having this problem right
now you just might be not aware about it
why for example if you have a dual stack
network at home is the ipv6
configuration get screwed well because
of happy eyeballs that you might hear
about it here essentially high pile
bolts the simplified version of it is
that when you are trying to browse the
site you tried i pv 6 an IP before in
parallel and whatever works first is
what you use okay now if the ipv6
configuration is incorrect well it's
going to fail but as long as before it
is still working well there's something
that works so you probably don't even
realize that something is failing in
there I mean it would be a different
story if you go B 6 only because there's
no fallback there ok now the reason I
mentioned this is this is just one of
the many problems that are many times
masqueraded by the fact that you have
dual stack you know dual stack as long
as something is working you don't
realize about the failure now when you
start depending on a single protocol if
that protocol fails well that's that the
problem becomes evident you might wonder
well how could you possibly let's say
avoid this problem well ripe had
published a document I think it was ripe
590 if I remember correctly it was a
recommendation for the prefix Isis that
should be let's say list by ISPs to
customers I think was 500 forgotten in
90 Oh something like that so what they
say what that document says is that the
isp should least stable prefixes what
does that mean that it should always
give you the same prefix so if the CPE
crashes and reboots well the addresses
the old addresses are not going to be
stale because you're going to get again
the same prefix so I mean the problem is
still there is just not evident now
there are you know some pros and cons
for that you know on one hand you know
for law enforcement it might be nice to
give the users you know stable prefixes
because you know it's easier to identify
the user maybe not for user privacy okay
I guess it's the same thing with IP
before that if you want you know a
stable address you have to pay extra so
whatever the reason I mean at the end of
the day there are deployment scenarios
in which you do get dynamic prefixes
okay
in some cases it could be because the
you know for example I what was reported
to me by some ISP was that it was
difficult for them to do that with their
probation and system that they had there
are other cases in which they might not
be aware about this but the reality is
that you are going to have deployments
in which you do get you know dynamic
prefixes and in many many cases the CPE
routers that you have you know they
don't record the prefix that they had
been leased before of course if they do
that if they did that when they are
rebooted they could try to let's say
disable that prefix on the local network
like advertise that prefix but with a
lifetime of zero okay so that any course
that had configured an address for that
prefix will remove that address so this
is a problem that is actually around and
you know the reason for which I ended up
Co offering this document was because
there was an ISP that you know ask you
the question well how do we solve this
yeah things about but this is kind of
ipv6 history this is what happened at a
time
this was the tunnel like the strategy
will have a privacy button and have
privacy extensions and you see all that
it's a German approach very detailed and
bit complicated tries to find the exact
right balance between different
objectives there was a lot of from
effort put into this but actually never
to love this has never seen the live the
line of life kind of very much
interested I can probably I'm pretty
sure I'm allowed to share this given
this is like seven or eight years ago
but there was this whole thing around
the handling of prefixes by yeah this
and a new state they actually did they
every time you reboot is it sir yeah I
believe is there any way you can trigger
that except for rebooting okay well an
interesting part is that normally when
you call the the ISP reporting a problem
usually the number one approach for them
to solve the problem is that have you
tried rebooting the router so actually
this would break the the v6 deployment
in this scenarios there's many funny
things in there so some things have
changed for a long time but there is
exactly this look here why
next time you're on scanner very a
German thing that year that this could
leaves lead to loss of connectivity
which would then be needed for phone
calls so insane so disgusting again if
anybody interested robbing email it's
pretty hip oh but huge debate
there you go okay okay so one of the
possible ways to avoid this would be to
use stable prefixes but for different
reasons it might not be possible or the
ISP might not want to do it okay so that
means that there is a problem to be
solved the other thing because you know
quite frequently when you bring some
problem like this too particularly to
the six-month working group the attitude
it's there's no problem so it shouldn't
be solved in the protocol so they blame
the ISP because of the way in which they
deploy the protocol but there's nothing
wrong with the protocols okay now my
take is that no matter how you deploy b6
the network should be resilient anyway
okay if you use dynamic prefixes for
whatever reason you do them well the
network shouldn't break because of that
another way in which this problem could
be avoided somehow is if the cpe were to
record the prefix that was list so is
let's say whenever you get list a new
prefix you record that prophet Const
able storage then whenever the CPE
router gets a reboot if it doesn't get
the same prefix it could advertise the
old prefix with a lifetime of zero
trying to essentially disable the prefix
in practice it doesn't work because the
standard the standard says that if the
lifetime if Robert advertises a lifetime
of let's say less than I don't remember
how how long it was like less than an
hour the lifetime should be ignored so
it's not possible to actually completely
disable the prefix papa then there was a
another proposal or there was a proposal
on how to solve this which essentially
boils down to this so
there was a proposal to solve this
problem by updating the source address
selection algorithm I mean if you have
never hear about source of the solution
or about dot RFC the idea is that you
know when you have a an ipv6 cost and
you have so many different addresses
then when you want to contact some other
system you have to you know pick one of
your addresses and the decision is not
always straightforward you might have
different prefixes you might have
addresses of different scopes and so on
now
there are so there are a number of
possible ways in which you could do it
do this for example some have some
people suggested that you should look at
the value in the prefix lifetime and
always use the one that has the largest
value okay so if let's say they hope
they stay prefix Calabar you know a
lifetime off let's say two months and
now there is another prefix that is
advertised with the lifetime of let's
say three months you should use the
longer one well that doesn't really make
make sense okay then there is another
option that was proposed which was like
this these these people suggested that
you should always use the prefix that
was less advertised so in theory I mean
it this modification in theory you solve
the problem
why because obviously if we had the old
prefix now the rotor crashed reboots it
gets a new prefix and advertises the new
prefix well the new prefix is the last
one that has been advertised okay so you
use the new one and not the old one but
what happens for example if you have a
deployment in which you have two routers
that are advertising two different
prefixes and both of them are working so
when this one advertises the prefix now
this prefix becomes preferred now when
this one sends an RA now this prefix
becomes preferred so now this
ah dresses are flopping from one to
another that's normally not nice from an
operational point of view okay that is
like a guarantee that over time you have
no clue about what the address that is
going to be used because it's changing
all the time unfortunately a union B
surprise is the ietf decides to solve
the problem this way seriously my
personal view is that they always prefer
to update the most irrelevant RFC's so
it's like you know 24 60s like the Bible
you just don't touch it so this is my
world source address selection
hmm it's like not part of the core
specifications so you can play with this
one we can give you this one to play
with but obviously it shouldn't be
solved here and there's another one like
even if you prefer a different prefix
that hasn't removed the other from the
system so you still have the old
addresses you're just not using them now
for example if you keep the old
addresses you are not going to be able
to communicate with the new owner of the
prefix so if the same prefix that you
had before now has been leased to a
different system you will not be able to
communicate with it so that's not the
way forward from my perspective what I
proposed for this like the easy way to
see it or my solution to the problem is
as follows let's say that he was
advertising some prefix to me so I am
the host right
obviously my my take is that the problem
should be sold at the cost not on the
routers so let's say that he was
advertising some prefix to me
traffic's let's say number one he
crushes and reboots and now he's
advertising prefix number two now since
I didn't crash myself okay
so now I see that he's the same router
as before he subvert izing prefixes but
he's not advertising the prefix that he
used to advertise okay so you're sending
array arrays to me with different
prefixes and you're
or ties in the old prefix anymore so my
solution to the problem is that as I
continue receiving arrays from you and I
don't see the prefix that you use to
advertise for example after the second
RA or third ia that I get from you with
all the prefixes other than the previous
one you should remove the old addresses
okay so it's like you have a server or
the router that was sending the you know
the prefixes that you should use for
configuration all our of the sudden you
get different information that the one
that you were receiving before so and
you keep receiving you know consistently
new information and you don't get to
receive the information that you used to
receive well from my perspective dozen
indication that the information became
stale okay
and you should get rid of the addresses
get rid of the roads and you know you
start from a quickly clean slate was
some people at the IDF think that that's
not the way to move forward there's a
conspiracy theory about this one because
I do have one the six-month has the goal
of moving the core specifications to
full standard for me that's crap but
from their perspective if they move the
specifications to full standard that's
like an indication to the world that the
protocols are mature okay now there's a
tricky part there there's a requirement
that in order for you to move a
specification to full standards there
shouldn't be any major changes now if
you do apply a change to these which is
a slack that means that you cannot move
slack to full standard now if you ask me
I prefer to do the right thing from a
technical point of view than doing
politics at a group that is supposed to
do technical work but sometimes the
politics and the technical part are not
when they were when the core b6
specification 2460 was just about to be
for to be republish as full standard I
got comments too from many people from
like very high level at the idea that
everyone would say well it shouldn't
really be moved to full standard because
I mean there are things that are broken
in the protocol like extension headers
for example but it's like well from a
political point of view it's we have to
you know publish the core standard the
core RFC as a full standard as an
indication that the protocol is mature
okay now I think this is the last slide
you know when you think about this you
know this problem it makes a number of
questions such as this for example
normally when you look at arrays the
prefix lifetime is normally valid for
one month so that means that the
prefixes that are advertised on the
local network are valid for one month on
the other hand the router lifetime is
valid for 30 minutes that doesn't make
much sense now this is where things get
like you know very crazy if you want I
ended up when I was trying to push this
forward I I said well I need some old
guy on the you know on the on my team so
I ended up fighting and finding one of
the early authors of neighbor discovery
which we have fought other battles on
other working groups and he was the
original outer of the slack
specification and he mentioned that for
example the reason for which you get 30
minutes for the route a lifetime is
because at the time deed was specified
the IDF was playing with the idea of
using these protocols to communicate
with systems on the moon but but the
thing is now you get the value 30
minutes and somebody comes up with an
explanation of you know where does where
that comes from now the guy that
actually knows why
that body is there you know tells you
the reason I said what that's crazy
you know but the problem right now is
that you know that's in the
specification and people will you know
defend their values that they have in
the timer us if they made sense when
they actually the buys that you have
there are there for completely different
reasons so for example when it helps
when it comes to their lifetimes I think
that the perfect life lifetimes should
never be larger than the router lifetime
meaning that they should never be larger
than thirty minutes if we were to use
those values and we we had this problem
scenario at least the network would be
broken for thirty minutes but not for a
whole month okay I mean still broken but
the level of bergna brokenness it to be
smaller then there is another thing
related to okay this is related with you
a lace this is like food for thought if
you want so I was talking with these
people I know why the hell do you need a
you know prefix lifetime of 30 minutes
well thing is in ipv6 you're not
supposed to have nuts okay now what
happens if the lifetime was said to
something like 30 minutes and you lose
connectivity with your ISP addresses
expire and you don't have any addresses
anymore okay if you ask me that's what
you la's are used for so if you want to
have addresses even if you lose
connectivity with your ISP that's what
you'e leis that that's a use case for
you lays there but there was other
people that proposed that the way to
solve problem this problem is to use not
so that's well any questions the only
thing that I I like let's say yeah to
you know to keep in mind is just
keep this problem scenario in mind okay
well what I keep hearing is that I talk
to is piece and whenever I bring then
some of these things like you know how
did you solve this they are not even
aware of what the problem is so keep
this in mind I'll be around if you have
questions email me
there's be six hackers mailing list
where you can subscribe it's open and so
on and that's it for today I guess
[Applause]