all right my name is Wes Wagner I'm data
janitor a heavy sleeper
my daughter has why I put that in there
it's because I work on the cloud team
with CrowdStrike
and every now then we're on Pedro give
you rotation and right now I'm on
permanent pay tribute irrigation so that
kind of feeds into what I'm going to
talk about here in this weird way that I
don't want to actually have my page so
I'm gonna build systems that don't get
broken so a little bit of context first
when it comes to containerization
security and all of this why am I here
why is the name of the talk containing
the cloud well this just happened this
past week and so since its public I get
to throw it out there we recently were
FedRAMP ready not authorized FedRAMP
ready there is a how many of you
familiar with FedRAMP or any of that so
amazon has a special cloud that they
built out for the government that is
called gut cloud and we call everything
in order to get into it you have to pass
all kinds of audits checks pin tests
everything this was our last pin test
that just completed two three weeks ago
so now we are ready to sell to
government organizations for
organizations in general now I want to
get into that platform and I've been on
a team that's been working on this for
about a year so that's sort of the
context here what that means is that
we're using kubernetes in FedRAMP for
our gut cloud installation and we are
FedRAMP authorized a big question going
into it was how would we get to do that
when we're one of the first not be first
but one of the first companies to use
containerization in a highly secured
environment so we're also using it for
our security application so we're
helping to secure other people and we're
doing it for highly secure for security
conscious organizations they're very
opinionated
now they want things to be run so that
kind of ups the states and also didn't
put into here that Google is one of our
investors so we also have pressure from
that side too so all around lots of
scrutiny that's the context from where
I'm coming from on container
securitization so being on this team for
about a year last year I did a month or
so just reading through white papers of
what people have written about
containerization and security and stuff
like that and part of the the cool thing
about this conference the standing on
the shoulders of giants containerization
is nothing but shoulders of giants over
the years nothing new about
containerization what's new about it is
how to lose together some other points
here and these are part of the slides
that I was just putting together like
literally five minutes ago polling shows
the primary reason for people not going
into or not using containers is security
they worry about how that how that works
now that's become less and less over the
last couple of years but it's still
something that you probably have running
around on your mind in fact there's a
lot of organizations that just flat-out
no so I'm coming at it from this high
secure conscious always to let you know
that it is possible to come to implement
containerization securely and properly I
also want to point out that I'm coming
at this question from a security or from
a systems engineering perspective I'm a
software engineer I happen to work for a
security company so whenever I'm in a
conference like this I mean a lot of you
guys that work in socks and that's great
that's cool I'm the guy that runs the
stuff behind the scenes that help
support you so we um we just crossed the
billion hundred billion event mark per
day to put that in context our CIO
ourselves was saying that that was about
on par with like Facebook and a few
others large company so we're ingesting
an awful lot of data that doesn't leave
a lot of room for error that means we
need to be secure but we also need to
just get the job done
it's a lot of our containers first of
all how many of you are using containers
today anybody okay doctor containers
anybody using something other than
docker containers in any application
nobody so containerization is actually
an overloaded term it could mean like a
whole bunch of things
iOS Android lowest en windows they all
have the concept of containers that are
baked in that's where the entire
industry has been moving for quite a
while now containers I would argue are
all about application deployment now in
order to put that into context I put
that slide in the wrong place in order
to put that into context so let's give a
brief history of software development
life cycle SDLC the simplest deployment
is a self-contained binary okay you know
what I mean when I say that just an
executable everything LinkedIn we throw
it over the wall the problem with that
is we we kind of like dependencies
software engineers were a lazy bunch we
like to use what other people have
already put together so we end up using
libraries that introduces that
introduces another layer of complexity
now I have to know what library I'm
depending on after don't work first with
that librarian is and I have to bundle
that library up in order to ship it with
my application consistent deployments
this is where this really comes in
consistent deployments meaning that I
have to find that same like bitwise same
deployment every time okay I'm moving
into aiming at a certain thank you
system fueling peculiarities cause
deployments to be complex now there's
been several security related incidents
in software deployment recently NPM repo
recently someone yanked their package
and it broke like a whole buttload of
other packages more recently though
python and one of their repos
compromised somebody was public
like nefarious packages that kind of
sounded like something else that's
another issue so software deployment is
complex one author said that software
development is one of the most complex
things that a person can do today I
think that they weren't entirely
exaggerating so this is the appropriate
place Casey
so the xkcd comic here in a nutshell is
everything is a micro service if you
throw out most of the features and
that's basically where containerization
has been for the last year or two and
this is not entirely I would argue this
isn't necessarily if you want to go play
with something like elasticsearch or
Cassandra or Kafka or something like
that
horribly complex software by itself I
don't really care to go track down all
the configuration if somebody wraps it
up in a nice container that I can just
docker run and get it running right
there that's cool but that's not going
to carry us over into production that's
where the critique here is so our
deployment options first we started off
with single binaries that we did package
management systems we still use those
they still get a lot of use still have
their niche then we move to virtual
machines and virtual machines are great
that's where Amazon build what we now
know as the cloud were not just Amazon
but many other countries the problem
though is that VMs are heavy and slow
that is you have to literally boot an
entire system go through the entire boot
sequence by contrast containers are
deployments of virtual virtual machines
they boot up in milliseconds not seconds
and they give us so this is what they
give software engineers they give us the
familiarity of running in a VM that's
all of our own and they with the speed
of process
so as a software engineer I like to
occupy the entire system
just ask my kids when we watch a movie I
like to explore the whole space I like
to do that when I'm soft when I'm
engineering software - that is this
network interface is mine all one
nothing else and that's a good pattern
to to go to because that's where a lot
of software started breaking and is
where we have mixing them - so since
we're at a new folks that conference now
that we've gotten the deployment part
out of way here's the attack surface on
a bare metal machine you've got all your
apps running on the rest OS and the
hardware is accessible right there that
would be the least security VMs on the
other side have apps running on their
own OS abstraction on site on top of a
hypervisor that actually provides the
abstraction to the hardware now
containers don't have the hypervisor
containers are running in the host OS on
the hardware and you're probably
wondering well aren't we supposed to get
more security with containerization no
not at all and I want to point this out
the bar secure is running in a VM
actually the most secure is running in
your own machine it's a floating space
but because of something because we're
gonna need to pack our applications as
tightly as possible to get the most out
of all of our rack space all of our
compute power we need to figure out a
happy medium
that's what containers are the
containers so put it in another
perspective there are 12 VM escapes
I searched back all the way to 2007
there are 12 VM escapes
these are hypervisor attacks ok so ok
twelve million escapes and I want to
point out something
to you most of these are escapes that
are off of like random crap like virtual
hoppy or virtual floppy disk controller
or just things like a fusion SPG a
driver should be running that anyway you
don't need that on your videos so it
actually shrinks if you're doing your VM
deployment properly by contrast the
primary attack surface for containers is
the kernel itself okay almost 2000
kernel exploits back to 2010 okay and
that's because the kernel is a really
complex just it's really complex ok
that's what we're up against we removed
with the hypervisor layer that means we
went from 12 VM escapes now we have
almost 2000 ok that's because we don't
have this intermediate layer so that
means so a container is really just a
slogic 'el separation of a set of
processes files and other resources then
the kernel just says we're going to set
this aside okay we're going to treat an
application like a logical unity so what
we've what we've got here is a
vulnerability for all of our outdated
dependencies and attack vectors we need
to track and stand both the base image
as well as all the application libraries
that that base image has in it then now
that means that security begins at
container creation one of the first
things that we did when we set up our
entire moving into a containerized space
was we have a system for putting
together the docker files for our
developers because fundamentally I don't
trust software engineers I'm one
but so we start off with the way the
container is built up each layer our
images are built up by layers
that's the copy-on-write file system and
each layer has an operation that's
performed on the layer below so it
starts with the from of a base image and
that's where all security begins as
making sure that you're using a secure
base image and then each command stays
with that build so one thing that we do
is we don't put secrets into our build
scripts we have to trust this the build
machine we have to also figure out how
to tag our images so that we know that
they came from the build machine docker
in particular has a nice cryptographic
hash that goes with the content the
content of every image we also use the
labels for auditing purposes when
somebody says well who pushed this image
then we could go back and say here's
where they push this image on this
system at this time and all this other
stuff and then we use what's called the
Builder pattern when it comes to
container creation the Builder pattern
means that we use one image that has all
of the helper libraries all the div
versions and libraries to build the
binary and then we have a different
image that we deploy that has all the
statically linked stuff in it so we have
a fact image in intermediary
that has all the stuff that we need all
of our cool developer tools and then we
strip all that stuff out when we go to
put it in production this gives us a
unique opportunity security is actually
usually bolted on after the fact and
software development containers give us
the ability to put security as part of
the workflow in building an application
and crown spec we have the philosophy
that security shouldn't get in the way
of what you're doing it should fit
alongside it so this gives especially
application security engineers an
opportunity to come along and audit your
docker scripts your base images your
libraries and then
provide a helpful way to like steer that
into a better way so the continuous
deployment this quote I love when
healthcare gov crashed the they went out
and they asked industry experts and one
of them came back and said the first
suggestion that he would have was for
President Obama to have the team deploy
to production every day and that has
that was a software chemistry thing in
the software industry or the software
engineering that's a really good like
deep like make your software less
complex makes it make it easier to set
up and as a security of operation it has
another implication to in that the less
snow flaky your stuff is the the easier
it will be to just tear it down put
something else in its place
so continuous security is what I'm
arguing that we're going to move to here
the way to move forward is with DevOps
tooling there's all kinds of great stuff
and like I said in the beginning powered
of 30 minutes rushing through this
standardized security tool they can fit
in each part of the software development
lifecycle when it comes to container
security I do want to point out one
thing though that containerization is
not so containerization is not less
complex it's even more we get every bit
of complexity from from the lower levels
on up so it ends up being this wave of
complexity so think of every piece of
this deployment process as an
opportunity for you to inject good
security practices yeah there is all the
software supply chain issues are apply
to containers the one thing though that
you can look at whenever your managers
ask you why are we putting in all of
this added complexity at the end of the
day it will sign off when it comes to
velocity in deployments we have this
really great system set up it uses
spinnaker which is
Netflix's development tools or
deployment tool for containers and all
that and it is really complex you should
never use that for a side project but as
a engineering as a industry thing it's
really awesome because it's got all
these focusing checks and stuff built in
and in particular security checks so
here's what I mean by all the
complexities of the software build
lifecycle
you've got the developer to build things
and commits it to github or to get a
repository somewhere somebody could take
control the repository the image is
built by something usually a developer
on their laptop and they push it up to a
registry which they shouldn't do and
then that registry is what deploys that
into running containers in an
environment every every layer of that
and cannons should have eyes on it from
a security perspective so we can
automate the good news is we can
automate a lot of the security tooling
another tie into the theme of this today
of standing on the shoulders of giants
Red Hat has done amazing things with
container security not particularly
docker necessarily but they put a lot of
thought into you wouldn't believe how
many white papers and lectures Rudin a
container no longer matched a root on
the host just want to throw that out
there but it's still problematic file
ownership gets mangled between the host
and the guest read or use read only if
you have to the tight coupling between
host and a guest is a micro service fail
treat that as a code smell or a security
smell shouldn't do that if at all
possible get those off containers need
to provide a minimal containers provide
minimal protection the host operating
system actually don't so just treat your
containers your guests containers as
possible and that'll give you a good
path forward
I'm running out of time here that's what
I'm trying to talk a little bit faster
it's up to us to use additional
protection measures it's really easy to
shoot yourself in the foot with
containers you could just pull something
straight off github or docker hub and
just start using that and it's very easy
to let yourself be lazy and put that
straight into production don't do that
use app armor selinux to further harden
your images these are security profiles
that you can you can add to the
container running engine usually docker
and further secure your your containers
as they run or what was released this
week Google's chief Iser system which I
encourage you to take a look at it's
actually a shim that sits between your
application and the kernel itself and
provides additional security trace your
applications kernel calls to discover
what capabilities it really needs and
then shrink-wrap those capabilities so
that your app doesn't have the ability
to do things like access a floppy disk
which it never needs about the
possibility of doing so to wrap up
Brooklyn don't worry in your application
is route don't write to disk in
production audit your deployments in
configuration is code I can't stress
this enough the pattern for containers
is to apply environment variables to the
container as it runs in runtime okay
there's all kinds of patterns to get
away either either to get away from that
for to make that better there's a
sidecar system that LinkedIn use is
called Envoy which is really really good
I encourage you to use that pattern or
if nothing else track and version all
the configuration stuff around your
application because I promise you to
finish tonight and somebody changed some
random variable somewhere all right
because I had to run through the slides
real quick I'm sorry but the good news
is I've captured a lot of this awful lot
of this in my container security awesome
and I encourage you to go and look at it
and especially start I treat stars as
love so show me a lot
thank you guys
[Applause]