the title is a little bit looser but
what we're really talking about today
what I want to talk about is basically
humans as a single point of failure in
d'art busy people and so the how they
made these records come back around but
the info Rex set rockstars thing it's
basically about irreplaceable fate so
we'll be back without liquid just about
me did you see they don't respond to a
question like a certification I'm the
informational security architect for
United community banks all thoughts and
opinions are mine don't have that slides
anywhere has to be mentioned so
oh come on Twitter handle up there I
usually use that to kind of follow the
community not that all that stuff I'll
try to get better about that I know it's
one thing you always want to tribute
which is the reason up here so I've got
about 17 years in tech InfoSec or some
blend of the two kind of came up
organically through engineering their
training working with mostly supporting
financial institutions or consultants
working in with financial institutions
so a few of my favorite things like say
it's one National couple things I'm not
a bit of a documentation freak I enjoy
doing documentation I enjoy will
maintain documentation it's helped me in
my life I know that's not a very fun
thing but this talks let them cover a
lot of fun things but it's good stuff
and stuff my talk about nothing is
happening like regulatory guidance
god bless everybody that works in
unregulated shops
having that back to be able to take
management when I have a security
control I won't hit them in so I'll have
to argue it on my own but say this is a
good idea
we need to do this but these guys might
shut us down we don't it's always been
helpful working without that crutch
changes things quite a bit
so about this talk standing on the
shoulders of generals of things when I
thought about for submitting this talk
just have to be such Chattanooga heard
several good things maybe I've got
something
and then I jumped on the soil but this
one had a thing and it changed what I
want to say because in information
security we work as risk identifiers
it's a lot of especially blue tape you
know you're there to identify risks and
close those gaps so my mom being
positive and optimistic immediately went
what happens when you lose the jump so I
mean metaphor of the standing on the
shoulders of giants s these are the
people that got me here but what about
the actual people that we reliably do we
figure them in do we think about how
they help us and do we identify them as
risks as something that can bring your
company down
known as an insider threat but it's just
somebody that you can depended on so I'm
going to go through three quick things
identify the risks recovering from loss
and I thought recovering it there but
I'll get more to that but really what
consequences you're going to deal with
when it happens because you know the
recovery is there's not really a
recovery from it and then mitigating the
probability which is the proactive steps
there at the end and it's again I'm just
like saying we all kind of know these
things but we don't talk about them so
we don't really consider them and put
them into our processes first a
practical example so several years ago
we lost a network engineer senior
network engineer at longtime employee
cornerstone of the department
very cool grab smart tireless ferocious
when he came to maintaining that time
but mid early 50s he was a runner
healthy super fast it was always fun to
go to a half a thon or 5k with him just
to see the other guys in his age bracket
their faces dropped because you know
they knew they're gonna push down the
petitions to the
shows up so I was in a conversation with
him in the hall one day and I was asking
about its running and he mentioned they
hadn't been able to leg live because his
legs were hurting and so it was just a
little bit after that he started missing
work just sick and then we got an email
from his manager they included the word
aggressive which is not something you
want to hear so it was weeks I mean
there was no time and he's been pretty
diligent about maintaining some of the
things we'll talk about so through no
fault of his own his backup his primary
Becca had just been went on better
pastures basically found other
opportunities and so he was kind of in a
gap between replacing that talent so
that left us in the nearest inspire
learned a lot of lessons from it I'd
like to say everybody on my team did a
fantastic job dealing with it but again
you learn a lot going through something
like that we'll start off with some
massages if I say much then I like
regulatory guidance so just going back
to the examination handbook there you
should never assume that critical
personnel including center management
are going to be immediately available
during a disruption so if you're in a
position where you're missing those key
personnel and you have a day off or a
basic piece of REO has that figured into
the plan I figured in whether they're on
the road whether they're in the hospital
whether they have to deal with their own
families those kind of situations can
take those people away from you and
really complicated
humans once they put up there humans are
highly available and it's not like we
have instant replacements and sometimes
we just aren't available at all so
looking into that as a risk identifier
we need to figure out how can we look at
our organizations I mean we can
proactively plan around this but we can
look at our organizations we can look at
our processes and we can identify those
risk factors what you're looking for is
those people and organizational trends
that tend to pile up responsibilities in
such a way that they can't be replaced
so I broke it into two you've got
organizational factors so one thing
we'll get back to there's a the causes
of these and the people's responses to
these but the rate of growth of your
company or your organization for your
business if you're just need to add a
new customer base the volume of work
going up not so much change it doesn't
leave room I mean your days full you're
assuming we paid for a full day so
you're doing a full day's work so as
that volume increases if you're not
having kids and adding you know
stretching out the days or shifting
workloads so the cross training
documentation and planning around BC PDR
can be done you're going to end up with
more of a single point failures the next
one I don't know if it's good turn more
but under managed acquisition so if you
don't have the project management
structure in place so that when new
technologies are brought in or
acquisitions are made or you've got
shadow IT you know departments buying
their own stuff if you don't have a
project manager or management team that
it's saying okay we need that's not
ownership we need to plant backup we
need to make sure our vendor management
processes involve this you don't have
all those things a lot of stuff can
sneak through and that stuff's gonna
stick to qualified people that you need
doing other things and the last one it's
kind of weird one but working with some
people
I have hypertension so if you have a
cultural thing in your company or the
geography of it or any other factor you
have people like stick around I mean it
just could be a really good place to
work long time employees tend to acquire
additional dues they tend to acquire a
lot of institutional knowledge that
makes them in value so conversely
turnovers good way to highlight weakness
if you lose somebody you know you've got
a problem if you've got a high rate of
turnover you know what needs to be hand
around because you've done it so many
times it's always a good place to look
is the people that's been there a long
time to inventory what they do and we'll
get back to that near to mitigation so
the human factor and I was thinking
through this is it's how we spot these
people how we spot the people that are
just watch said their pleasure valuable
to us and there's really three risk
factors that can hand out stuff so when
there are couple different things to
call them talk about you know maybe put
a superhero reference or two in here but
really nothing to fit so just will say I
know all these people are combinations
of these people are people that are more
than these thing and so it does come
from experience but you all know anyway
so first I've got the Golden Week and
this is pretty much as someone who
everybody likes to work with so they've
been assigned a duty or something
they're supporting something they're the
guy that they go to for this particular
type against in everybody gets used to
working for working with them so even if
you assign them a backup that backup
never has to pick up the phone because
their mail columns they can I get such
and stuff or you know basically this
they'll always email trying to certain
of anything you set up so what happens
is their secondary is in everything
across drive and so if you lose this
person well I mean it's obvious but the
interesting to think about this too is
if you promote this person you promote
this person you expect him to a new job
all that crud is gonna fall along with
them because the people that's been
working with them all the time or still
don't want to go to them so that creates
one problem the next one is the
juggernaut so basically the final that
has everybody most people need sleep
food family time you know at least some
things there are some people that I've
worked with that don't seem to they will
work hours upon hours they can work
weekends if there has to do something
they won't question it then we'll
balance it out so what problem is this
great you can't replace that person with
one person everybody else that has
expectations work-life balance won't
come in can't do that job so and you
don't always know it because you just
kind of you asked them to do something
they do it just everybody some of them
complain and do it anyway some enough
complain and you just never know they're
gonna break it might be yours it might
be when they're working for you I'm not
gonna working for somebody else the
problem is it's when they go away you
come on so last one I put the polymath
now this is this is somebody with a
broad background especially you know
talking on the technology side so
somebody's but I think if they're good
at everything just give them all the
things so if you've got a guy that knows
web in programming and database and
works with people and knows how to
manage well here's a project you want to
give your pride you want to give your
important things to your best guy if I'm
in with project management and control
that if you don't really quantify what
your important things are you've ended
up giving them all to one person and
nobody can cover it unless you've got to
which is unlikely what happens up
happening is is he's got a bunch of
different systems with different skill
sets to support them so it ends up being
a lot of junior admins or sis admins or
you can help desk people or you know
junior analyst end up supporting off one
thing this thing or that
thank so when he goes away you've got a
whole bunch of junior admins that become
crime berries on something that's
important here perfect and then you
don't have the resources across try and
we'll get into that some of the
consequences afterwards but they don't
immediately know how to hand that off
and it takes a lot of planning to
recover so identifying these one good
way to get these things to show up these
type of risk factors shorter it's their
testing everybody doesn't they are
testing out the hope at some senator
been which product is but I mean it's
the first question is we found in the
list today let's do our dr test and
let's look at your PCP plan if it's only
got one name on it you people
immediately got a problem and it happens
and that's a that's a simple thing you
just test fails pick a resource training
pretense know baseball will get busy but
that right there in this problem the
second one again it's just your busy
people in you might have a secondary of
signed by might be used to go into the
primary so that's one of those things
especially an incident response as it
relates to just security and as well as
the basic paid in the art when the
incident occurs do then opens the second
areas they know how to contact them
because those first responders are going
to be contact center people a lot of
times so they might not have that so
basically if you start your BCP testing
point in student that first responder
was and say this is happen what do we do
about it and they stall is adjustable
test the last one is going to be more
common so you have a secondary but
they're not gonna be as fast they're not
gonna be as good they might have to
Google some stuff they might have to
read through the procedure so if you've
done your dr testing you're basically
testing and you've established a
recovery time objective based off that
with the primary test it again takes to
begin with secondary
figure out what that time is now again
you can retrain them try to make them
faster no way has time for that so
another important thing to remember is
you can adjust so far TOS unless you're
in a business that's so highly regulated
that you have I mean this one I think if
it's absolutely has to be a it
absolutely has to be up in an hour
you're going to have to fix that but if
it doesn't you know it could be that
management can understand that you can
say if such-and-such
is available we get to something now if
he's not
it'll take a step it's all about setting
expectations now you have to give your
regulator the longer time but like I
said what you're doing is you want the
management to have a clear expectation
of what you can accomplish with which
resources so that's all said to say it's
okay to fail on these that's how we
learned that's how we adjust and
identify these risks response so I don't
have time for questions in this talks up
at this section in because I've talked
with people about this a lot and the
first thing they pop back with is
there's no time they're giving us more
stuff we can't be cross-training to the
level where we actually have good DRB CP
we can't have this kind of coverage we
can barely document ur stuff all that
that's all fun it happens everybody
that's what they say so
it'll pop those out I'll just get a
little louder until he gets that done so
when the response comes back that you
know there's a lot of frustrated
technicians a lot of a lot of people
that I talked to just that the resources
aren't there to accomplish that that
kind of full-time coverage get those
expectations where they want to have
them so first thing is it's kind of calm
down it's not hard responsible I say
unless there's management in this room
and executive management the trim it's
not our responsibility to fix this we
identify the risk we offer solutions we
offer mitigation you know strategies but
at the end of the day it's our job to
look at that risk and setup and
management expectation about it the
staffing decisions that they make to fix
or not to fix this that's a risk
decision-making thing look at these
numbers it's a well this if if Joe is
unavailable
we're down until he comes back if he's
quit or hurt or down until he comes back
that's it they can say that's fine not
having compensate now um so flex it not
have you backups people or data it's an
option it's not a good option it's not
something you should do but it's one of
those things it's management's job for
that you know not being insured that's
not you
it's every other day is their business
burned down you just have to set
expectations so when something when the
shoe drops they know what to expect
looks at this uh this slide here you
know you can't get dressed the park back
on line with that Dennis Nedry
knowing those characters are seeing that
movie that's not the first time the gray
said that to John Hanke so the look and
surprise I'm going his face shouldn't be
there because you know this has been
explained before they built that park
they have one eye together so you know
it's one of those things set the
expectations so here's where it gets bad
consequences what happens and this
section was originally what do we do
what do we do with this what can we do
how do we respond and the answer is you
don't really have too many choices so if
not planned appropriately for this it's
not so much what are you gonna do is
here
going to happen if you've lost a save a
pillar that has a particular product
knowledge or expertise you're going to
add element consultants you're going
into cullinan resellers or that company
itself and we've got not a good solution
but it's what you have to do and it's
actually the better than the second one
which you've lost someone who is a kind
of a cornerstone institutional knowledge
where you've got a lot of weird systems
or home-built stuff and so now what's
choice if there is a former employee
that has been for somewhere you might
can lure them back they're gonna have a
knowledge gap of the time but it's
possible and it can be done and they'll
grow back into it and you're a really
good solution is if you've lost your
giant to a consulting company that's
pretty easy because they've had a
consulting company give them back you're
paying you know three times what you
work for or part-time people but you
know the systems data started down there
except it's not everybody can do this it
depends on your business model but maybe
maybe you were building a particular
application that product no longer
exists if you don't have somebody to
support it you don't want patients bring
somebody in that knows to take notes the
code you can always drop me I mean
that's cost it's a long story Kurt and
reassigning is this to resource I put
that out there because that's likely
what you're going to do but it's not a
real solution because that person's
doing a job that person is no longer
doing that job at least in some
percentage or fashion so you're really
just moving the pain points between
people so recovery steps this is just a
real quick one when this happened again
it's not recovery you're going to do one
of those four things but what you need
to do is you need to treat it like you
just had an incident or Dr situation or
PCP you need to sit down handle lessons
learn do a full inventory what got
dropped when that person gave notice or
otherwise left you're gonna have to
educate secondaries if you have handed
stuff off you might have handed stuff
off to junior admins that aren't
familiar with the project management are
familiar with BCP planning don't know
that they need a backup now and that
will just flex it push your problems
further to the road and you need to
document as an incident and the reason
for that is when something like this
happens there's a cost again management
made a decision something happened the
businesses have been impacted there's a
cost associated with that write it up
and provide a tool that will help
justify going down the road as first how
to fix it so quick notes on mitigation
it really comes down number nine which
is on the slide still you have to
properly equip the backups this will
happen it's you can leave out of here
and say okay now we've got backups we
got good documentation the key is
documentation isn't enough you have to
have job rotation I say cross train
cross trainings meets the devil to you
tell you what I do you go back to your
job doesn't work if actually we want to
be prepared for these type of events you
have to do job rotation that means
weekly monthly quarterly whatever is
appropriate annually is not gonna be
appropriate for many processes but the
reason you do this because it solves a
couple of things first off documentation
goes stale so if you're going over to
the training and you you're not driving
and showing them if they're having to do
it you're instantly I think your
documentation because they're gonna run
into snags they're gonna run into
systems have been replaced they're gonna
run into people that are no longer in
the contact list all kinds of things so
you're constantly and continuously
updating documentation the other thing
is access issues you run into this a lot
maybe their permissions have changed on
the system you know what happens if
you're not there they're trying to do it
and they don't replaces you so that it
slows the entire process down and pushes
out the recovery time objective in
addition they they might be missing
software might be browser
incompatibilities again they might be
trying to contact people in our therapy
don't know we had to contact it it might
just say there might be a job role in
the documentation and that is or that
role might not exist anymore
so going through it with a proper job
rotation is really the
would ensure that you actually have
disaster recovered this BCP capabilities
is first people so the other thing I put
here is that doesn't mean that they need
to 100% do everything that you can do
and they don't have to do it tomorrow it
can be continuous or you can
continuously improve rather than trying
to get it done the other thing is is
management expectations if they expect
somebody to be fully functional was it
fully fully armed and operational but
they don't care if there's you know they
don't care if it looks pretty they just
need to get done in a certain time they
understand that there's a difference
when this one is doing it that one as
long as it does the job it doesn't
matter
but again management expectations so
there's a couple quick notes my last few
minutes here some personal applications
and I just say this actually goes back
to the first talk there are certain ways
we can apply this into life doesn't make
getting this right attractive so first
off letting go for ourselves and the
people that we counsel it's important to
think do you want to be doing what do
you want to be that person who's
absolutely replaceable so you don't get
to sleep you don't get to go on vacation
you don't ever get to do those things if
you think you're gonna duck you into
yourself out of a job there's not enough
of us for that it's not going to happen
so that's just a quick picture that's
the when I came out of infrastructure
and was able to train my replacement and
move fully into information security I
was able to take the first two week
vacation of my life without ever logging
in so that's that's actually a main so
we crawled up a little coastal towns in
New England for two solid weeks
I checked email as it never lobby and
never touched the VP so does that mean
the company don't need me no it just
means everything good either wait
somebody else knew how to do it and so
if I was actually taken down by
something the same result Lee but it's
good for me it was
it's good to get that work-life balance
makes you better employee and the second
thing which goes back to what she said
it's nor you want to advance profession
again for your own benefit
if you can't find people to train if
they don't have the skills to cover for
you if you don't trust me if you're the
golden boy to yourself and you don't
trust anybody else to do your job that's
a problem you'll end up the same folk so
what you do is we sell for us as
information security but you you recruit
a speaker you tell people have you tried
this would you like to do this do you
think you'd be good at this and like she
said you mentor and once you do that
what's that you've got people who can
replace you
now that's the thing you're not being a
job where you don't want to be replaced
but do this anyway
because again it's competent service to
your employer because something might
happen to you outside your control but
the other thing is you're helping this
person you might train them to be your
replacement they might never replace you
but now they have opportunities and
skills that will further their career
allow them to pivot to other things that
they met each other so like I said back
to the time of Moses Mannion all my
favorite poems Brian can't go through
all that but Bryan Cranston does a great
reading of it on YouTube for one of the
seasons of Breaking Bad
mind it's good basically it boils down
to just the point that it doesn't matter
what systems you build it doesn't matter
what you write down about them all that
means nothing unless you have people
that can carry it on after you if you
don't pay attention to the people it's
just it's all gonna fall into room no
nothing nothing this runs forever so
that is the end appreciate the town
[Applause]