let me just get what we were talking
here on this slide the idea that
actually the ratio between how much this
specific place I'm visiting
under the overall ratio of all the
things that's the number that matter
right so I'm gonna throw a slightly more
complicated equation here right the only
thing I'm talking about is that on the
on the bottom there it's the sum of all
da asses or all the registrar's or all
the different things so for each
different P P which is a pivoting point
everything this slide is telling you is
what I was told
telling you on the when we were the
other you had the other slide up with
the example so no need to be afraid of
this line I just want to have things
written down because it's if people want
to try to reproduce this is much more
precise than me just blabbing about and
and waving my arms