- I'm going to talk to you
about using threat intelligence
to guide your hunts.
I think today's flow has
actually gone really well.
You're probably gonna hear a
lot of some of the concepts
that we just heard,
also mentioned here.
Hopefully that will lend
some credence to them.
All right, a little
bit of background,
I know Rick mentioned some.
Security technologist at sqrrl.
Yes, this slide is
about a week old so that
has changed since.
I also, at night, I run
Malformity Labs and yes,
you made deduce from the
two logos that the walls
of my office are
indeed orange and gray.
Little bit of background
of why I chose this talk.
Laying in bed one night,
thinking about really
what has changed, at
least in the aspects of
the industry that I
have been exposed to
over the just under a decade
that I've been doing it.
So starting as an intern
for Usizo, helping build
out the security program
moving to forensics and
incident response over
to intel, now working for
a product team that to
hopefully design a product
useful for those practitioners.
You look at then and
when I first started,
largely prevention
focused so as long as
we don't let those bad guys in
we're good to go, game over.
In order to do that
we're gonna add those new
firewall rules, make
sure everything's updated
and patch our systems.
Of course, that last one
still provides difficulty
for a lot of organizations.
And at the time, if
you asked anybody about
threat intelligence,
unless they were government
or very closely
related to government,
probably didn't have any handle
on what that actually meant.
Fast forward to today.
I think most organizations
would agree that
prevention detection and
response all have their
place in an information
security program.
Threat intelligence,
we have prevalent data,
probably more important
than data, we have
defined processes to
help take this to your
organization, things
like this conference,
who I think this morning
they mentioned, six years.
However, we take the third
point, what are we still
doing on the rule front, right?
We're still throwing in new
rules, just a lot more places,
a lot more boxes.
We've seen large strides
in the programs themselves
but we haven't seen a
whole lot of change in how
rules are used within
our defensive posture
in order to move up
the pyramid of pain,
as Rick mentioned.
I am not saying rules are bad.
I absolutely believe
rules have their place.
Probably a necessary evil.
I think right now as many
of the prior presenters
have eluded to, She-Learning
is trying to encroach
on this but I don't think
we're doing it correctly.
A lot of people are looking
for a magic easy button
I can deploy this thing
that learns all this stuff
and outputs only the bad things.
Going from current posture
to that, I don't think
is very realistic.
What does that mean?
Alert fatigue is very real.
I'm sure many of you are
very familiar with this
problem, especially
if you're in a SOC
or active detective role.
This is one of the reasons.
So everything, traditionally
when we started with the
intel focus I know many
folks mentioned already today
as well, that this conference
is very indicator focused.
A lot of organizations are
still indicator focused
in their detection, so
a new report comes out,
if they have an internal team,
a new report is generated.
What are the consumables
from that report?
First thing that everybody
does is grabs that
appendix, depending on the
source, scrapes the pdf,
puts all the
indicators into rules
into all of their devices.
What else does that mean?
Every new device, as I
eluded to, every new box
that's purchased,
they're all producing
an alert stream.
Problem with that, you're
just contributing to the
alert fatigue.
So if you put that detection
in five places, you get
five alerts, that's
not really helping.
So what do we want to do?
We want to move off
those lower levels of the
Pyramid of Pain,
we want to move up.
Now I know it seems very easy
to say, not quite so easy
to put into practice.
Experience, man-power, tooling,
maybe prevent an organization,
any combination of the three,
from working towards this goal.
In order to do that
we have a couple of
pieces here that
we're gonna talk about
that should really
play well together.
The first one you saw this
morning, the intelligence cycle.
The second is the
threat hunting loop.
I'm sure both have been
discussed in length here
in prior years.
But the reason these
should work together
what we're gonna talk
about is using the output
from your intelligence
cycle to guide the
loop on the right.
Your products coming
out of that cycle should
feed organizationally
relevant hypotheses done for.
That's really the key part.
So any intel you're
producing or purchasing
should be relevant
to your organization.
We're gonna hunt for those
and keep in mind that when
we're hunting, there's kind
of two major goals.
The first, you want to
send data back to that
intelligence cycle.
You're intel folks want to
know if you found anything,
they want to know if you
found anything else that
they didn't know about,
they want to know if you
got a lot of false positives,
if what you did find
was related to the activity
that they initially reported on.
Those are all great
feedback pieces for them
to continue that cycle.
The second piece we
want to do is implement
detective measures
on our network.
There's some discussion
back and forth about
whether or not hunting
can be automated.
I don't think it's, there's
certain levels of that.
I don't want to have
to repeat the same hunt
over and over manually.
If I conduct a hunt,
confirm it was useful,
had outcomes that were
relative and built my
security program, I
would like to be able to
implement the same hunt as a
repeatable detective measure.
I don't want to have to
run that, otherwise it's
unmanageable and you can't
continue building a library
of hunts that you
have to run manually.
You will run out of time,
there are not enough people.
So what does this
process look like?
This is a hypothetical
example that I pulled
from a secure list article.
For the purposes of this
we're gonna say that
it was from an
internal investigation.
I always suggest folks
start with internal sources
before they go external
because they're free,
you already have them and
they are automatically
relevant to your organization.
So in this hypothetical
example, user downloads an
attachment from their
personal email account,
goes through a series of
downloaders, ends with a
dropper that finally
delivers a payload which
takes some post-base
actions here and finally
communicates out to a C2.
So right now what
do most people do?
Everybody gets everything
on the left, all of your
standard indicators.
Low bottom three
levels on the pyramid.
The advanced folks get
the ones on the right,
they move up one level, or
some combination thereof,
but we are still annoying
at best for the adversary.
We really want to change
that and try to move
to challenging or tough.
The end question is
is that effective?
With everything that
happens currently,
are we taking a
worthwhile step forward?
How do we move to actually
move up the pyramid?
I'm gonna propose that
we want to generalize
all of those indicators
that we just had.
Right now each one of
those was atomic in nature,
a specific value, and then
we want to hunt for them.
This is what that
might look like.
We have all the atomic
ones on the left,
the new potential generalized
categories on the right.
For instance, take the
top one, IPs and Domains,
most every malware beacons,
or a large majority.
If we can change to
beaconing detection as a
class of detection
that is more effective
on a front of
detecting maliciousness
but anybody that has
tried to implement
a beaconing detector,
you're going to get
a lot of false positives.
Let's stick to the same
thought here with all
the ones on the right.
Given what I just said,
some of you may be saying
well, all right, if I'm
getting a bunch of false
positives, what's the point?
Isn't that just going
to give me more alerts?
Yes, if you implemented
every one of those
individually, you're
absolutely gonna experience
alert fatigue. ú
That's not what I'm
gonna suggest for you.
I don't want to look at every
one of those on their own.
I want to start
building higher-order
groupings and take those
into account instead
of individual atomic detections.
So if I have those,
that's what I want to do.
What's next?
Activity groups are a
concept, this definition is
from independent guests
actually presented this
four years ago at
this conference here.
I'm gonna talk about
the diamond model.
Diamond model's fantastic.
I highly recommend if
anybody's interested they check
out that presentation.
They have it in the archives.
He also has some examples
of using activity groups
for other contexts,
not just alerts
as well as developing some.
If we take all of our
decomposed actions
with this in mind, I
want to start to form
activity groups.
So we'll swing back
to our example.
From our example we have
two groups that we formed.
So we have the first group
which would essentially
be the generalized activity
from the downloader stages
and we have the second
group which is the
generalized activity
from the actual payload.
Now if you take these
in whole, they represent
a behavior that an
adversary is using,
specifically a tool,
so we're moving up.
In order to bypass
these it's gonna be
a little bit more challenging.
Quick review of that process.
We had the intelligence
inputs that
end up with your hunting.
Depending on your organization,
your intel folks may
be doing the hunting,
SOC may be doing the hunting.
Some of these may
fluctuate a little bit
like this first pass,
several folks have
mentioned today that there's
a desire to put things out
spur discussion, hopefully
see it expanded on
as we go forward.
So in many cases, for instance,
decomposing the actions of
the malicious
behavior may be a new
output of your intel team.
They're already looking
at it, they're doing the
analysis, why not
have them group it.
You want to take those
and form our hypotheses
and then actually go hunt.
Now, one thing that
we really want to do
while we're still
hunting is pay attention
for other characteristics
that we find
we didn't have in our
original groupings.
So we work to build
out a library.
One of those, for
instance, this would be
enriching actions,
in previous slides,
not every file download
is malicious, obviously,
however, maybe when
we're doing our hunts we
notice that near every
file download that
taught you a never
before observed domain
was malicious.
So we have another
characteristic there that we
can pull out.
We don't want to group
them now, we want to keep
it separate, keep everything
properly decomposed.
After we enrich those, we
start to form groupings
of the relevant ones
that we pulled out.
So that example, right,
uses known behavior.
We had a report that
said this is what occurs
and we used that
to form our groups.
But as a hunt team,
part of our goal is to
uncover unknown activity groups.
We didn't have a
prior report on this
but we found it anyway.
How might we be able to
do that with this method?
So all of our decomposed
actions, I would assign
metadata to them.
These are common examples
that many of you are
probably familiar with.
It's gonna change for
every organization,
what works, what
they can implement,
but these are a couple
that we're gonna go over.
We revisit our activity
group number one.
We have the actual specific
actions on the left
and their classification
for, in this case,
the killchain, on the right.
What you see here is
if we break those down,
we get three exploitation
actions, two C2 actions
and one installation action.
So what I'm gonna do, I'm
gonna form an activity
group that is two exploitation
actions, two C2 actions,
and one installation.
I cut out one of the
exploitation actions.
The reason I did that is
it gives us flexibility
so with that new
requirement it's still gonna
detect this but it's
also gonna detect if
the actor decides to
cut out one of their
downloader stages.
Example with mitre attack
from our second grouping.
Now attack is a little
bit trickier depending
on what's in your grouping.
Attack focuses pre-exploit
for their actions.
In this case we encounter
that with the first
step there of
recent compile time
characteristic of potentially
malicious binaries
and we were lucky
enough, though, so miter
more recently released
pre-attack, which is
prior to the exploit
phase, and in that case
they had create custom
payloads as one of the steps,
which is where that falls.
So you can see here we may
create an activity group
that involves those
four attack categories.
In both cases, what that
allows you to do, is use
that characterization of
the action for detection.
We're not tied to
a specific action.
An actor can sub out
any action within that
particular phase
and potentially your
detection would still work.
All right, so, before
we talked about creating
more alerts if they're
all individual,
and the elephant now,
some of you may be
saying, hey Keith, you're
eight or so years
behind the times,
these are just
correlation rules,
no big deal, can already do it.
All right, yes, basic level,
you are correlating things.
Question, though, how
many organizations have
a defined process
to take their intel,
whether internal or
external, or data or
information that they
gather elsewhere,
analyze it, pull out
specific groups, and
implement specific
detections, both at a
tactical and higher
level, as part of that.
You may have a
technical capability for
correlation rules but
how many people are
making maximized use of it?
Is that operational currently?
This is really
just the beginning.
This example produced
shortly after
notifications for this
conference went out.
I'm sure many of you
are familiar with
Jack's fantastic work on
Twitter and on his blog,
refers to this process as
dynamic signature chaining
which, I think, is a
very good description of
what you're doing when you
form an activity group.
Of course, I joked about
encroaching on my talk here,
and Rich aptly and 100%
correctly pointed out that
this is by no means a
soft science or defined
100% process and there's
plenty of room for
multiple folks to
do some research.
A couple of those areas
that would be fantastic.
The example I provided,
it's host based,
it's on one host, for any
that occurs it's on one box.
How much more effective
can we be if we can
take activity groups
across multiple boxes
and link them?
How do we do that?
What other considerations
do we have?
Does there have to be
a direct connection
between those two hosts
or maybe just 'cause
they talk to each
other, is that enough?
How do we rank them?
Can we account for which
ones are more important?
So whether that's more
metadata that we insert
which is based on confidence
level or threat level,
if we can do that
automatically or automagically,
as I prefer, with
prevalence on the network.
Maybe if it happens
more does that mean it's
less likely to be bad?
Maybe, maybe not.
Probably most importantly,
systems and methods
for actually implementing this.
On that front, during
research for this talk,
I came across Jordan's
blog, which is actually
really good.
Read the first one and
while still drafting the
talk the second one came
out and in the second
one he shows an
example of detecting
mimikatz with elastalert which
is an alerting framework for
elasticsearch and
in that he uses five
detections and creates a
rule that says if these
five fire within a
second of each other,
then surface one rule that
encompasses all of those.
That is effectively
an implementation
of what I'm describing.
As luck would have it,
in the process of that,
Roberto dropped HELK, which
is a hunting distribution
of ELK, and I noticed on
that roadmap there was
elastalert, so it looks
like HELK may become a
good open-source
option for beginning to
implement this in practice.
And then lastly, Keith
Casey and the rest of the
Carbon Black team really
put out a lot of great
content on alert suppression,
alerting at scale,
dealing with false positives,
that sort of thing,
so they're always
good to monitor.
So the important part,
that's great, sounds
good, I can't do that
fully operationally right now.
What can I do instead?
First thing you want
to do is break down
your intel sources.
Again, internal, external,
free, paid, whatever,
every long form source
should have actions that
you can pull out and activity
groups that you can create.
If it doesn't, you might
want to ask yourself
if it's actually an intel
source or a data source.
Then you want to hunt
for those groups.
You pulled the actions out.
In theory they're relevant
for your organization,
you're gonna go see
if you can find any
currently, right
now, on your network.
While you're doing that
you're going to find
data and detection gaps.
If you don't, please come
tell me where you work
and I will ask you if
you have any jobs open.
That is gonna happen
and that is actually
really good, especially
if you've been documenting
your process
because now you have
specific TTPs tied to
specific concrete actions,
you cannot detect them.
In some cases they're
tied to defined actors,
I'll say known defined actors,
but you can't see them.
In aggregate, that is
really strong backing
to say I need
tooling X or I need
four people to do Y and
you can say this is why,
because I can't see
these actors taking out
these actions against us.
It's very relevant
to your organization.
Then you want to start
categorizing those detections.
As you hunt, confirm they're
valid, build them out,
you're gonna start
building your library.
If you start categorizing
these, you want to think
about what's useful
for organization,
detection, current use,
future use, tying them
to known internal
incidents can be useful for
tracking, trend
tracking down the road,
particularly as was mentioned
earlier, you're gonna
do your own internal
data breach report,
very useful to build out.
You may not be able to
operationalize in an
automated fashion currently
but you can at least
use them to hunt
with and to work on
categorizing and defining
your current gaps.
And with that--
(clapping)