(intense music)
(audience applauding)
- This is my first time at SANS,
and I'm really excited to
be here, I have to admit
I'm a little bit
intimidated by this crowd,
that doesn't happen
to me too often.
And of course I have to follow
the most interesting man
in information security,
which is...
I gotta fire my agent
when I get back.
Anyway, I spend my time, I
do a fair amount of speaking,
I'll talk about what my
day job is in a minute,
but I do a fair
amount of speaking,
I speak at two types
of conferences.
I speak at legal conferences,
where I try to help lawyers
understand technology risks and
how legal decisions
can have an impact on
technology and how
cyber security,
how lawyers need to be involved
in assessing cyber
security risks,
and then I speak at techno
conferences like this one,
and yes, try to
help technologists
and cyber security professionals
from breaking the law.
Which actually can be
complicated from time to time.
But really, more often,
and this is really
my objective today, is
to get you to think about
how the decisions that you make
can potentially
create legal liability
that you weren't
otherwise aware of,
so that's really what I'm
gonna talk about here today.
The other thing I'll point
out before I get goin'
here is because I do
these two different kinds
of presentations, has
anyone, first of all,
is there any
lawyers in the room?
All right, good, good, good.
(audience laughs)
So if anyone, so you
probly have not been
to a legal conference,
or seen people who ordinarily
speak at these legal
conferences, but lawyers love
to receive input in text form.
So it's slide after slide
of dense bullet points.
And obviously, technologists
do not like that,
they like cartoons,
ya know, again,
great that I get to
follow a guy that created
his own cartoons for
his presentation.
So a lot of times I
find myself in between,
in fact, when I first
sent my deck to Rebecca,
who helped me, she bounced
it back immediately, like,
too many bullets, ya
know, what the heck,
this crowd isn't
gonna go for that.
So I tried to find
this middle ground,
I did put some
pictures in, but go
a little bit easy on
me in that regard.
So another point I wanna
make before I jump in is
that a lot of times,
or most of the time
when I get up and
speak, I am very,
very confident in
the voracity of,
in sort of the strength
of the position
that I'm about to take
in giving my talk.
This is not one of
those situations.
I actually think I may
not be 100% correct
in the fears that I have
around information sharing.
So the ideal outcome
of this talk is that
yes, I make you guys
a little bit more wary
about sharing, and
more aware of the risk,
but also hoping, and I'll
try to get to the Q&A
so we have some time
to get into discussion,
I hope you can make
me feel a little
more comfortable with
it, because I think
I may have taken it
too far in my concern.
But the point is, there's a lot
of uncertainty in this area.
And I really want everyone
here to think about
the potential
consequences of engaging
in sharing threat intelligence.
So this is really, this
talk is an expansion
of sort of a cocktail
party rant that I developed
probly over a year ago, ya know,
when I used to talk
about how people
are sharing willy nilly,
and there's the pressure
coming from the government
to share when really it's,
it's the government
just trying to get us
to provide them with
indicators, there's really not
that much of an intent
to share back to us,
so I tried to expand
that into this talk.
So let me talk
about, a little bit
more about my background here.
So my background,
I am an attorney,
I serve as the Chief Privacy
Officer for my company,
UnitedLex, so that's the
quasi-legal role that I have,
and then I also
run the company's
Cyber Risk Solutions practice.
And so the bulk of my career
since I left, officially,
the practice of law
back in 2002, has
been working at
the intersection of
law and technology.
So I started my
career as a litigator,
I got into the area
of privacy law,
again, spent a lot of my time
working in the
cybersecurity field,
running forensics practices
for the better part
of the last 15 years,
and really, have had
a front row seat to
dozens and dozens of
incidents and breaches
that have occurred
over the years,
which has made me a
world-class paranoiac.
When people ask me, well, how
did you make the transition
from being a lawyer into
the field of cybersecurity,
information security,
I always point out,
it's really not
that far of a leap,
when you think about the
fundamentals of what,
what a lawyer does and what
an information security
professional does, we
all are paid to assume
that calamity is right
around the corner, right,
that you're gonna
step into the street
and get hit by a bus, and okay,
what do we need to do to
prevent that from happening.
So the mindset is
actually very similar,
we just have to learn new
terminology to a large extent.
And also like
lawyers, information
security professionals
tend to be there, they have
front row seats, when the stuff
hits the fan, and you
sort of learn (laughs)
negative reinforcement,
which is to a large extent
the same thing that
happens with lawyers.
I think another thing that
you need to know about me
and where I'm coming
from on this is,
I actually am not
much of a sharer.
I am not on Face, not
only am I not on Facebook,
I have trouble understanding
why anyone is on Facebook.
And I'm not not on Facebook
because I'm worried
that I'm gonna share something
that I don't wanna share,
I have complete
control over that.
You know why I'm
not on Facebook?
'Cause I don't wanna
know what the rest of you
wanna share with me.
(audience laughs)
All right, so I just
don't understand this
compulsion to share,
so I think that colors
my attitude on
this topic as well.
I'm here to talk about sharing,
sharing, I will point
out at the outset here,
does not come naturally
to human beings, right?
Even when we're kids, we
have to be taught to share.
I know with my own kids, it's
some of the first lessons
you teach them, how
it's important to share,
and it's nice to share,
and I certainly can see
there are many, many benefits
to sharing in the world.
To form a relatively
functional society,
we can build alliances,
we can build trust
with people through sharing,
so I totally get that.
But I think we do
need to keep in mind
that there could be a reason,
an evolutionary reason,
why it doesn't come
naturally to us. (chuckles)
All right, so we should be
wary, we should be careful
about the circumstances
in which we share.
So sharing is most
effective, in my opinion,
when, especially when we're
talking about intelligence,
when the two parties
sharing intelligence
have relatively equal ability
to act on that intelligence.
If you look at two
nation states sharing
threat intelligence, or look
at the Five Eyes, right,
the reason that that is
effective, for the most part,
is that you know
that when you share
a piece of intelligence
with that other party,
they're gonna be able
to make some use of it,
they're gonna
understand what it is,
they're gonna be
able to analyze it,
they're gonna be able to put it
in the proper context for
themselves, and act on it.
When you get a situation
where the parties
sharing intelligence
with each other are not,
do not have equal capability
to act on an intelligence,
you can get some weird
things happening.
Number one, you could just have
sort of ineffective sharing,
that one of the
parties who's receiving
threat intelligence
doesn't really know
what to do with it, they
don't really understand
what it is, they need
help with the context.
And the other thing
is that the parties
who have the greater capability
tend to benefit the most
from that threat sharing.
I'm not gonna talk, it's
hard to do this talk
without talking at all about,
about Cissa, or Ceesa, I'm
not sure how to pronounce it,
Cybersecurity
Information Sharing Act.
Everyone's familiar with this
act, I assume, in this room,
if not, I can talk
to you afterward.
How many of you participate
in information sharing
under CISA, either through an
ISAC or directly in the AIS.
Okay, that's actually
a smaller percentage
than I thought of this crowd.
How many of you
participate in other,
more informal sharing
with other organizations.
Okay, so I think between
those two, we're talkin' about
the majority of the people
engage in some sort of
information sharing.
I wanna, what I
wanna focus on today
is the ways that
you can actually
be punished for
sharing information,
that this information
can be used against you.
There are three primary areas
where you can get into trouble.
One, you can share
too much information,
and/or share that
information too broadly,
with too wide of a group.
Number two, you can fail to act
on information that
is shared with you.
And number three, in
devoting time and resources
to information sharing,
you can neglect
to pay attention to
security priorities,
you know, that frankly
may be more effective
if you put more time into them.
So I would suggest
that those three areas
can create legal risk
for your organization.
I assume most of you are
familiar with the concept
of negligence, the legal
concept of negligence.
That you failed to do
what a reasonable person,
or reasonable company,
given the same set of facts
and the same situation,
would have done.
If you've failed to
meet that standard,
of sort of the
reasonable person,
then you could be held
liable for your failure.
And so that's what a lot of
civil litigation is based on,
and frankly, what a lot of
regulatory actions are based on
as well in this area,
is this question of,
did you act appropriately,
did you fail to
meet this standard.
And I think information sharing,
for these three reasons,
you can get into trouble
and create liability.
Bottom line up front here,
and then I'll get into some,
a couple of examples
and scenarios,
so threat intelligence sharing
can be very beneficial,
so I don't wanna come off
as someone who's against
sharing altogether,
but you've gotta think
before you share,
you may be inadvertently
creating liability and risks.
You've gotta think
about how, each time
you share, how that
could be happening.
Second, you've gotta have
a plan kfor how you intend
to consume and orchestrate
threat intelligence
that you're receiving, so
there's a risk in sharing,
which tends to be more
obvious, there's also a risk
just in consuming and receiving.
I know I've talked
to a lot of companies
that are participating
in an ISAC,
or one of these sort
of industry-based
information sharing
communities, and they say,
oh, no risk for me,
I'm only consuming,
I'm not sharing
anything outbound.
What I'm gonna talk about
today is that doesn't
necessarily eliminate your risk.
You gotta have a plan
in place that allows you
to orchestrate a response
to that intelligence.
And then finally, this
is obvious to most of you
who are in this profession,
the most valuable
threat intelligence originates
from your own environment
and frankly, stays
there, you don't need
to share it for it to
be valuable to you,
and frankly, a lot
of the intelligence
may only be valuable to you.
So what is CISA, I only am
gonna spend a minute on this,
the Cybersecurity
Information Sharing Act,
either the key to
combating hackers,
or a dire threat to
Americans' privacy,
just depends on who
you ask, I would have
one more possibility
here, that it's just,
could just be a colossal
waste of time and resources.
Time will tell, I
certainly have my doubts,
so what does CISA
do, real quickly,
the first piece of
cybersecurity legislation
that congress was able
to actually pass in this
sort of new age of ever-present
cyber threats to all of us.
Creates a sort of voluntary,
quote unquote voluntary,
peer pressure based system.
I get a little hot
under the collar
when I hear some of the
government representatives
talk about information
sharing and sort of
appealing to our patriotic
duty, and stuff like that,
without talking about some of
the risks in these programs.
One of the reasons it took
so long to enact CISA is that
corporations were
not comfortable
sharing information
without having some level
of liability protection,
so CISA has that.
To a point,
and I won't get
into too much detail
on this now, I'm happy to
talk about it afterward,
but in order to receive
the benefit of this
liability protection, you
have to share information
according to the dictates
and requirements of CISA.
One of those requirements
is, you must eliminate
all personally identifiable
information, PII,
from the information
that you're sharing.
The entire burden for
doing that is on you.
And if you fail to
do that, you get
no liability
protection under CISA.
CISA also protects the
information that you share
from being used as the basis
for an enforcement action
by a government, state
or local regulator.
So it does sort of usurp
any other state laws
that might, might be
inconsistent with CISA,
CISA controls, and so
CISA says this information
cannot be used as the basis
for an enforcement action.
Now the reason I'm emphasizing
as the basis for an
enforcement action
is it is not at all clear, and
when something is not clear,
we as lawyers assume
the worst, right,
assume that it
will be interpreted
in the light least
favorable to you.
So it cannot be
used as the basis
for an enforcement action,
but could it be used
if an enforcement
action were initiated
because of some other
piece of evidence,
or some other driver,
could that information
be used as a piece of
an enforcement action.
I'm not convinced that
that couldn't be done.
So think about the fact that
the information you share,
what I would suggest to
you is you gotta assume
that the information
you share under CISA
or with one of these ISACs,
or really with anybody,
can and will be
used against you,
think Miranda
Rights here, right.
Now, there are a
lot of situations
where you can ask
yourself that question
and still be
comfortable sharing,
there are other situations,
and we'll talk about this,
where you might
not be comfortable.
So that's really what CISA does,
I like to sort of boil it
down into layman's terms,
give me your threat
intel, you know,
only if you feel like it,
and we'll totally protect it
and we probably won't share
it with other agencies,
although they say that
they will share it
if it will help them
prosecute a crime,
anti-terrorism, these
kinds of things.
And if there's stuff in there
that makes you look bad,
we're not gonna use it
against you, probably,
but someone else might, right.
This is information that
could be used against you,
certainly doesn't prevent
you from being pursued
or have this information
used against you
by a regulator outside
the United States,
or by civil litigants.
So what does CISA
not do, it does not
protect you from
liability if you fail
to share intelligence
the right way,
it does not protect you in
the event of a data breach,
we're gonna talk
more about that,
and it does not
protect you against
legal action outside the U.S.
So it cannot protect you
against civil legal action, so
the information that you share
is protected from
a FOIA request,
so I can't launch a
fishing expedition and say,
hey, I wanna see all
the threat intelligence
that Company A has shared
through their ISAC,
or under CISA, and
use that as a way
to try to come up
with a way to sue them
for some sort of negligence.
But, if I know that a
company that has had a breach
participates in
information sharing,
and I'm gonna show
you an example of
a document request that
was served a few years ago
in an enforcement
action, and you'll see
the kinds of questions
that are asked.
One of the questions that
I would certainly ask
if I were a civil, a
plaintiff suing a company
post data breaches, hey,
what information sharing
programs do you participate in.
And not only that,
what information,
I wanna see all of the
information that you shared
with this organization
over the last five years.
So that information
may be protected
in that the government
isn't going to share it,
but you still have a
record of the information
that you shared that you would
have to turn over
in a litigation.
Again, the various torts,
as we talk about them
in the legal sense, not
these delicious torts
that I'm presenting
here, really are based
on this, again,
reasonableness standard,
can I establish that this
company was negligent
in the way it responded
to a particular incident
or indicator, that is
what the plaintiff's bar
out there, all the lawyers
out there that are,
that are suing, and
you've probly noticed,
any significant
data breach today
is followed by a
raft of lawsuits.
There's a lot of plaintiff,
a lot of very smart,
talented, creative
plaintiff lawyers,
painful as it is for
me to say those words,
that are comin' up
with all kinds of ways
to come after companies
and make them look bad,
and either extract
a sort of ransom
settlement out of
them, or actually prove
in a court of law that
they were negligent.
So there's also
no protection for
intelligence that you
share more casually,
and I've seen this happen a lot,
I've done a lot of
data breach work
over the years as I mentioned,
and one of the things
we very often see
when we come in, we're talkin'
to the information
security team,
is that sometime early on,
after the incident was detected
internally, before they knew
it was a breach, we try
to avoid using that word
until we know there's been
some kind of exposure.
So early on, when
all they've got
is somethin' weird, a
system actin' funny,
a strange lookin'
file showing up,
that there's a lot of
informal information sharing
going on, so you have
your two or three people
that you really trust, and
it can be a lonely job.
Especially if you've
got a small team,
or if you're by yourself
in your organization,
it can be a lonely feeling,
you're constantly worried
about missing something,
so you probly have
a group of people that you
trust and you reach out to.
We see that a lot in incident
response is that there's,
usually what we'll see
is just an email saying,
hey, Bob, you got time to talk,
I saw somethin' weird today.
And you don't know what
that conversation was,
so you go and talk to the, hey,
what did you and Bob
talk about there?
And what would Bob
say if Bob were asked
what you guys talked
about that day.
So you really need
to be careful,
it's not the main
point of my talk today,
but think about casual
information sharing
as a situation that can
create risk just as much
as this more formal
information sharing can do.
So you really need to
recalibrate your risk meter,
and rethink your
assumptions about sharing.
A lot of people would take
these statements for granted.
It can't hurt if we just receive
threat intelligence, right,
well I already talked about
how it actually can hurt.
Better to know about a
threat than not know.
We're certainly past the
head-in-the-sand days,
I get that, but again,
if you are aware
of a potential threat
and you fail to act,
you could definitely
be in a worse position
from a liability perspective
than if you hadn't known at all.
So you've really gotta
make sure that you're
in a position to
orchestrate these responses.
I can't possibly stay on
top of emerging threats
alone, I need help
and collaboration,
that can certainly be
true for most people.
It is a good idea to
seek a second opinion
from a trusted friend
when I find something
that I think might be
bad, just to confirm,
before I raise the alarm
bell, I wanna make sure.
You've really gotta be careful,
because all of those
things I just talked about,
this is I think the one,
one of the legal terms
I'm gonna introduce today,
how many of you are familiar
with the term discoverable
in a legal context.
Okay, I won't ask why you're
familiar with that term,
but it probably was not
a pleasant experience.
What does it mean, what
does discoverable mean.
- [Audience Member] (mumbles)
The opposition can request it.
- The opposition can
request it, and is entitled
to receive a copy of
it in a litigation.
They file the case against you,
you can serve a
discovery request,
and anything that is
relevant to the claim
must be produced by
the party who receives
this discovery request,
unless it's protected
by attorney-client privilege
or some other exemptions there.
Everything that I just
showed on the last slide,
all these things, this is
discoverable information.
So the information that you
receive through your ISAC
or any information
sharing mechanism,
is potentially
discoverable information
that can be used against you.
Let's talk about
how that plays out,
so what every regulator,
in my experience,
what every regulator
or plaintiff
wants to know after
a breach has occurred
is the same set of stuff, right,
obviously there's different
ways that you ask for it,
and the answers are highly
varied, but they all
wanna know how did it happen,
how did the breach happen.
When did you know
about the breach,
at what time did you first
know that you had an issue,
and as we all know,
anybody who's done
incident response
work knows that
that is a very difficult
question to answer.
When did I know what?
When did I know there was an
actual, actually exfiltration
of information, I can
give you that date,
but when did I know
that there might be
something funny going
on in my environment?
(chuckles)
I feel that way
almost every day,
so how do you trace that back.
How did you respond to this
information when you got it.
What was exposed, and how do
you know what was exposed,
that's one of the most
contentious issues
that comes up when you're
working with a regulator
post breach or you're
being sued by a plaintiff
is, they will ask you,
well, what was exposed.
It was personal information,
that's why you see
these companies having to
do iterative disclosures,
well, it was only 100,000
usernames and passwords,
but the passwords were,
salted encrypted, whatever.
And then, eh, a
couple weeks later,
actually it was 500,000
usernames and passwords,
and 300,000 of them actually
weren't salted encrypted,
and you get this trickle effect.
It is very difficult
in determining,
determining that you were
exposed in the first place,
that you had a breach,
can be challenging,
a lot of times it's
pretty easy to determine
yeah, we had an
issue, we were owned,
somebody had access to these
servers for a period of time,
but to tell me what they
actually did on those servers,
and what information they
actually compromised,
is a very difficult question.
Were you on notice of the
risk, and what measures
were in place to
prevent the breach.
This is where the information
sharing starts to get,
starts to get a
little scary, right.
Were you on notice, well,
what does that mean.
Does it mean that there
was a threat feed,
whether it was an
email from a friend,
or bulletin from an ISAC
sitting unread in my box,
I just never got to it,
or I had this indicator
but I fat-fingered
putting it into my,
into one of my security
devices, and we missed it.
When were we on notice,
this is something
that gets argued a lot in
these data breach litigations.
And then what people,
process and technology
failures contributed
to the breach.
These are the things the
regulators wanna know,
these are things the
plaintiffs wanna know,
these are things that
you need to think about
frankly, long before
there's any sort of breach,
but whenever you're
dealing with information,
and certainly sharing
any information.
I've taken an excerpt
from, this is an actual
document request that was served
by the Federal Trade
Commission on LabMD,
anybody familiar
with this LabMD case?
It's a really
interesting case study,
I don't have time to get
into it, but if you're,
look it up, look up LabMD if
you're interested in sort of
how the government handles
these breach investigations.
So I'm gonna point you to
request number six here.
So this is the Federal
Trade Commission
serving a document
request, looking for
all communications,
between or among
the Company, LabMD,
or any third party, right,
so any communications
no matter who was a part
of these conversations,
about any security incident
at any point in time.
That is standard fare
today, you will see that
in every document request
that is served today
by a regulator or
private litigant,
and chances are a
court's gonna say,
yeah, that makes sense,
it's relevant to the claim,
and you need to provide
this information,
that is all discoverable
information.
And number seven's
pretty scary too,
all forensic reports or analyses
relating to any
security incident.
Some very sensitive information
that can be turned over,
and a lot of the people
in this room are involved
in creating whatever
gets turned over
in response to those requests,
so you gotta think about that.
Am I comfortable having this,
everything that I create,
all these communications that
I have about threats, shared.
Okay, so I'm gonna go
through a scenario,
and then wrap it up here
and take some questions,
just to make this a
little bit more real.
Okay, so your crack
information security team
notices unusual
communication from a host
in your environment
communicating out
to an unknown IP,
not blacklisted,
but unknown, and an
unusual time of day,
something that sticks out,
right, something fairly,
we should go check out
what the heck this was.
You investigate, you
find what appears to be
an exfiltration
folder on this host,
you also find some
malware on that host,
you act decisively
and quickly, your team
is at its best, it
isolates the host,
and prevents any
exfiltration, so the actual
exfiltration folder's
there, but you can
conclusively show,
because of the log data,
that nothin' went back
out, you prevented
any propagation, you
scanned across your network,
you've contained the incident,
you eradicate the
malware, it's a good day
for the team, there was
only one host affected,
you're feelin' good, right,
go out and have a beer,
and hey, why not, we'll
help our friends, right,
who might have experienced
the same thing,
you share these indicators
through your ISAO,
your Information Sharing
and Analysis Organization
that you participate in.
So let's carry this
through into Scenario Two.
You're the one who
created these indicators,
you've shared them
with your ISAO,
you now need to make
sure that you're
consuming them properly,
and that you're making sure
that you're in a
position to prevent
any recurrence of this attack.
So you consume this information,
ingest them into your SEM,
your other security devices
as needed, but due to a
defective device feed,
one of the correlation
rules that you set up
in the wake of this
incident, fails,
and fails to detect a
reoccurence of the same attack.
And you're exposed,
but you're blind to it,
you have no way to know.
Four months later, a system
administrator notices
what appears to be
a familiar looking
exfiltration
directory on a server,
investigation shows that
100 gigabytes of TAR files
were exfiltrated over
the preceding months,
and this information
included personal information
for 100,000 people,
you have to go through
a public notification,
so now the whole world
knows that this happened,
you have to issue
a statement on the breach,
which usually includes
some level of suggestion
about how it happened
and what occurred,
somebody out there
on the internet connects
the dots and realizes,
wait a minute, the
indicators necessary
to detect and prevent this
breach were actually shared
via your ISAO four
months earlier.
Now, even if they don't
know that you are the one
who shared it because
you can, presumably,
obscure your identity, although
I question that as well,
how well you can do that in an
information sharing context,
but even if you're
able to, you still
have to explain how you were
aware of this information,
or your ISAO had notified
you about these indicators
four months prior, and
if you're asked about it,
again, you can't
lie, it's pretty easy
for a regulator
to determine that
yeah, actually, it
was you that shared,
you had the exact same
incident four months prior,
and you failed to take
appropriate action.
How many in this
room would like to be
in that situation, having to
explain how this happened.
I hope nobody.
So it's a bad situation
none of us wanna be in,
and it all, and hopefully,
you're understanding
that information
sharing, and the way
you go about sharing information
could actually
exacerbate a situation.
Now am I saying if you
rewind, that they never
shoulda shared those
indicators with their ISAO?
How many people think
that they should just,
shouldn't have shared
those indicators.
Yeah, I don't think
that, I think they,
what's the right thing to do,
if you're participating
in one of these things,
then yeah, that's a situation
where you should share.
What they needed
to do is make sure
that their own
mitigation was effective.
So if you're going
to share, make sure
that you are in a position
to, especially in a situation
where you're sharing
information, you gotta make sure
that you're effective
in your response.
So how else can
sharing information
make you less secure.
You all are more familiar
with these issues than I am,
limited resources to
invest in security,
and there can be wasted
time chasing false alarms,
there's a lot of false
alarms that come in
through these information
sharing channels.
Either things that would never
have materialized for you,
and there's no way to really
know that one way or the other,
or just things that turn
out to be inaccurate.
And the more, as the
volume and velocity
of sharing increases,
which it is certain to do,
that problem is gonna get worse,
not better, in my opinion.
And that signal-to-noise
ratio over time deteriorating,
I guess noise-to-signal
ratio, can lead to
erosion of trust in these
threat intel sources.
So the take-aways here,
I'm not saying don't share,
but you've really gotta
proceed with caution.
Make sure that you
have a mature program,
particularly to make
use of the information
that you're consuming,
before you start to share.
Don't give in to peer
pressure or this sorta
compulsion to validate
everything that you're thinking
with a peer that's
outside your organization.
That can be risky,
try to find someone
inside your organization you
can talk to about this stuff.
And then, do what you
do best, which is assume
and evaluate the worst
possible (chuckles) outcome.
And prepare for
it, and I call this
practicing your
Congressional testimony.
I'm guessing that a lot of
you do tabletop exercises,
if you don't, you really should
do tabletop exercise
on a regular basis,
include that as part of
it, a mock deposition
of you explaining some of
these difficult challenges,
it is a sobering
exercise to go through.
All right, outta time
here, but thanks everybody!
(audience applauds)
(intense music)