(high pitched chiming)
(applauding)
- For those that were here
last year certainly know
that I'm a World
War II history geek.
My company Digital
Shadows started in London
and I just hit my two
year anniversary last week
and I've been to
the UK nine times.
And so when I'm there over the
weekends I always go and do
all kinds of military
history things to see.
Anyone been to RAF
Duxford before?
Any of the Imperial War Museums?
They're awesome, RAX
Duxford is a live museum,
you can be in Spitfires,
they're quite expensive,
you can go up for
45 minute flights.
But I geek out there.
And some of you may have
seen in previous talks
this analogy I'm gonna
use about analysis
but it's really
relevant for here.
They have a US Aviation
Museum at Duxford.
So of course we have SR-71
and we have a U-2
kind of positioned
like Powers would've
potentially been positioned
when he was shot down.
A little bit when I was in
the army I worked with the U-2
as opposed to some
of the other assets
we also worked with too
but total geek out here for
an intel person, a
military history person
and general geek,
I love Duxford.
They also have a
land warfare museum.
Does anyone here,
maybe targeting people,
know if this is
a BMP1 or a BMP2?
So this is a BMP1.
And you can tell, as
a former imagery guy,
the size of the turret
on top is one of the
indicators for it, but I
use this to tell an analogy
of a young specialist
Holland who went TDY
or to the Eisenhower
when I was in Kuwait
and I was working
with the ISs there,
and we were doing imagery
from the TARPS platform
and we were looking
in Southern Iraq
and specialist
Holland made a mistake
and he called the BMP1 a BMP2.
Does anyone know
the significance of
what this would'a been
between the two Iraq wars?
Only the Republican Guards
Divisions had BMP2s.
So specialist Holland
basically called out
an Iraqi Republican
Guards Division
further south than they
should've been and you know
it hit the fan, things
were spinning up.
There wasn't a lot
of analytical rigor
in specialist
Holland at the time.
And so I use this as a
really good example of
making a mistake,
maybe not having enough
peer review as well.
A lot of analytical failures
didn't really turn out
to be that big of a deal,
but for a little while
it was a problem.
But I really think it's
a good way to lead into
analysis matters.
Certainly if you're in
the intelligence community
it might mean
something different
than it would be in
the private sector.
But in the private sector,
could be your livelihood
depending on what type
of work you're doing,
commercial sector,
competitive intelligence,
whatever the case may be.
So I always like to use this
as a lead in on analysis.
And my personal failure, I like
to make fun of myself a lot.
And there's a lot of
things to make fun of.
Of course, I'm not gonna go
into Dick Heuer Jr's book here,
I've had this on the slides
probably for three years now.
But what I wanted to
try to do is evolve,
is to look back, I spoke
every year at the conference,
I've coordinated the conference
with the advisory board as
well for the past three years.
And so I've had this slide up
and what I was thinking
about this year is like,
OK, enough about just
showing this slide
and telling you
to read this book.
I want to try to move
the conversation forward
on better analysis.
This book, how many
people have read this pdf?
And you can download
it for free right?
One takeaway if you
haven't read this pdf,
highly recommend that you do,
it's probably one of
the top five things
you should read in the space.
Also Thinking Fast and Slow,
but I think the first time
I saw Kahneman talk, she
also recommended that book.
And I read that as a result.
So here's, I'm not gonna
read all this to you,
I was gonna highlight some
of the important parts but
it's really about externalizing
and decomposing our thinking.
I think we have a
lot of lone gunmen,
maybe that's not the best
analogy, people that are
champions, they want
to do it, heroes,
that's what I was
looking for, superheroes.
They want to do it themselves,
they want to save the day,
they want to get all
the kudos for this
incident response
analysis or this
threat intelligence analysis.
And really what I like
about structured analysis
is you're exposing what
you're thinking about
and you're getting
more analytical rigor
into what you're doing.
There's a number of
cognitive biases,
and Carmen mentioned
some of them.
And I'm gonna go
through a couple.
You can do a whole session on
just cognitive biases alone.
But here's confirmation bias.
Facebook right now, if
you looked on Facebook,
it's probably the number one
source of confirmation bias
in these hyper political times.
Another one is mirror imaging.
Anyone familiar with mirror
imaging or Into the Dragon?
So if you've seen this
movie, it's probably
one of the top five
movies ever made.
He's being attacked,
he's being scratched,
and essentially he has
to break the mirrors.
So you actually need to
do this for your analysis,
you need to break
through your mirrors.
Mirror imaging is
basically when you look at,
and you make an assessment
through your lens
and not the person who may
be targeting you's lens.
You're not taking into context
their social situation,
their geopolitical
situation, them,
there's actually a technique
called red hat analysis.
I'm not gonna talk
about it today really
but they can be used to
overcome mirror imaging.
Anchoring.
I think Carmen also mentioned
anchoring in one context.
Is anyone familiar
with anchoring?
We actually see this a lot
with university students.
At my company we
recruit a lot of people
from King's College in London,
graduate programs in
intelligence studies and
there's a tendency with students
that go through programs
that maybe the first analytical
technique they stick with.
So you can anchor on the
techniques that you know,
and then you can
also anchor on maybe
the first assessment
that you have.
And then perhaps, it
becomes, oh this is the way
it's always been so it's gonna
stay this way type of piece.
So we don't want to anchor
either our techniques
or our assessments.
And then of course groupthink.
And I think everyone's
familiar with groupthink.
I think this is a
pretty good illustration
of groupthink as well.
And this is what
psychologists who coined
the term groupthink,
Irving Janis talked
about these conditions
that make groupthink possible.
I'm not gonna read
through them all
but if you look at
your org structure,
if you're maybe a student,
a fan of organizational
behavior, some of these things
might reside in
your organizations.
But there's one in particular
that I highlighted in red,
those are situational factors
that contribute to groupthink.
And I think it's
really important
for this audience
to be aware of.
How many people would
describe themselves
as this individual
in their jobs?
Are you ever tired?
Are you ever stressed out?
Are you ever working long
days stuck on a console
for ArcSight or looking
at packet captures?
The very nature of our
role, no matter if you're an
incident responder
or intel analyst,
anyone in cybersecurity today
in the threat landscape
we have, is you're tired.
So we really need to
be aware that fatigue
can cause groupthink, and
really try to take steps
to protect ourselves or
take care of ourselves
to try to avoid that.
Sleeping more than four hours
a night is highly recommended.
One of my New Years
Resolutions was try to sleep
seven hours a night, I'm
not doing very good at it.
It's ACH, how many
people have done ACH
in their careers at some point?
There's a fair amount of hands.
With this audience
I would expect it.
This is an ACH that we did
at Digital Shadows on
WannaCry and actually
made the Internet Storm Center.
But I don't want
to talk about ACH.
I was not exposed to
actually doing ACHs
until I've been in my
career at Digital Shadows
and I actually think
they're a pain in the ass.
They take a lotta time.
Even understanding,
as you're setting up
the assumptions that
you would have in it,
the scenarios you would have
in it takes a lot of time.
But ACH is probably one
that gets the most headlines
these days, people are talking
about them and using them.
So I want to think beyond that.
So I'm not gonna talk about ACH
'cause I actually think
it takes too much time
and there's other
techniques that you can use.
There's a whole lot of
So just a small, and
I have the reference
to this book at the end
of probably 40 different
structured analytic
techniques on this slide.
Is anyone familiar
with this book?
I've got it at the end,
it's like a 70 or $80 book,
it's probably not a bad thing
to expense for your teams
that are out there
and they break down
all these structured
analytic techniques.
I think it's very
overwhelming in trying to know
the right ones to use
in the right situation
is pretty important.
So I was gonna talk
through a couple things
that you might do in
your organization.
As you start to incorporate
structured analytics
into your programs, and I
think you really should,
I'm gonna go through a
scenario and go through
a couple here, but
you could kind of,
and what I've been trying
to do here is line it up
to the tactical operational
and strategic goals
that you might have from
an intel perspective
on different types of
structured analytic techniques
that you can use.
I'm a newbie on this.
Rob in his intro said
no one's a pro here,
no one's an expert.
I am by no means an expert in
structured analytic techniques.
But I have been
working with them,
I've done structure
brainstorming, I've done ACH,
I've done SWATS, red hat
analysis, cone of possibility.
But you probably
are gonna have some
that are gonna be
in your stable, and
you're gonna use them
and it's important to refresh
them from time to time.
But what I would recommend
is you start to try to map
different techniques
to different things
that you're gonna produce
in your environment.
How many people on an
ongoing basis in the room
actually have structured
analysis built in
to the different intelligence
products you create?
I see one hand, and
that's an Army hand.
So typically that's
what you'll find.
Unless you're maybe a very large
Silicon Valley
technology company
with large intelligence
teams, or you come from
the intelligence community
you're not doing this.
But the whole point
of my talk today is
that you don't have to
do these crazy ass ACH
that take a lot of time,
potentially take a lot of time.
Once you have them down
you can do them quicker.
There's an easy way
to do it, or easier.
And this is the common,
this is the third time
over the past six months
at a conference where I've
talked about this topic.
And I'll talk to people
afterwards and really
this is what comes back, is
we don't have time for this.
Our hair is on fire,
we don't have time
to add new things in.
What I would say is you
probably already doing
some types of analytics,
structured analytics
that maybe you hadn't
thought about and maybe
you just need to formalize
a little bit more.
So I want to go
through a scenario,
and in this scenario you have
a recently promoted CISO,
let's call him Mick.
Mick came from the
intelligence community.
So he's really into the
intelligence trade craft
and of course like all
CISOs or C-level folks,
he reads the Wall
Street Journal.
And he just saw this
headline this week
in the Wall Street
Journal and tell me if
this has ever happened to you.
The CISO comes and
knocks on your doors
and wants to know about this
article in New York Times,
Financial Times,
Wall Street Journal
and starts a fire drill
for your organization.
Has that happened
to anyone before?
Yeah yeah, well now I'm
the one doing that now.
So this is Mick our
fictional CISO's response
to this and he really wants
to know what's gonna happen
for the organization.
So I'm gonna walk through this
hypothetical ish situation.
I'm gonna do two techniques,
we'll walk through,
it's really to give
you a flavor of
how you could try to apply
this to a real world scenario
from your CISO that's
zomygod-ing the news.
So we won't go into detail
on some of these things,
others we will, but I just
want to give you a flavor
of how you can
actually incorporate
something like this
into your program.
And you could use other
techniques as well.
Just a flavor.
So one that I think is
really, really important
and actually doesn't
take a ton of time
is a key assumptions check.
I think this is really important
for a lot of different things.
For those of us that
are on the vendor side
and we're producing our super
cool intelligence reports,
this sort of stuff, if
you're on the vendor side,
you're writing research
that you're using for
thought leadership
marketing purposes,
you really should be doing
a lot of structured analysis
inside of your research.
But key assumptions check
is really really important.
It's the foundation of
your intelligence product.
And if you're making
faulty assumptions,
and in intelligence
there's no certainty right?
We don't know everything,
so it's really
important to do this.
This goes back to
what Carmen was talking about
is you need to have a culture
that will allow you to question
other peoples' assumptions.
Right we have to not have
hubris, we need to be humble,
we need to recognize that
we don't know everything,
that another perspective
could be a better perspective
or complement your perspective.
So you really want to
understand the evidence
and reasoning behind something.
So in the scenario that
we're walking through
on cryptocurrency
fraud, Mick our CISO
works for a financial
institution,
so he's definitely concerned
about the implications
of cryptocurrency in general
and then fraud in particular.
We've got a number
of key assumptions.
And so these are the
assumptions there.
A couple of new alternative
coins and exchanges will emerge,
cryptocurrencies will
eventually be adopted
by major retailers and
financial institutions.
Some of these are
trailing trends anyway,
but we're making
those assumptions
and we're making
them clear up front.
So whenever you start any
type of analytical process,
whoever the team is working on
writes these assumptions down
and then if you're
fans of Silicon Valley,
you get the stick it notes out.
And actually Carmen
referenced this
with structured brainstorming,
another way that
you can do this
exercise as well,
you get the sticky pads out.
And you start to ask
yourself these questions
about the assumptions
that you've made.
What would make an
assumption untrue?
What if it was true in the
past but it's no longer true?
Assign a confidence
level to the assumption,
and then basically,
and there's some others
that you can add
to the mix here,
but that's a high level
of what you would do.
You ask these questions
about each of these
key assumptions and
then you rate them.
This is solid, we
feel really good
about this assumption,
it's valid.
It's caveated, meaning
something must happen
in order for this,
or it's unsupported.
And then if it's
unsupported, throw it out.
So I would say for any kind
of intelligence product,
this is the type of activity
that you'll want to have.
And this is not something
that's gonna take a long time.
You could do this in an hour.
And I'm gonna talk about some
remote and collaboration tools
you can use as well.
For my organization, I have
people from Greece to London,
East Coast, Central, West Coast.
So it's a large
distributed team.
So there's some
challenges there as well.
So now we have the assumptions.
And one of the things about
the key assumptions check,
even if you were to do an
ACH, there's many of these
techniques where assumptions
are gonna be a component of it.
So this is using one
structured analytic technique
to build upon another.
Has anyone ever worked with
scenario planning or futures?
Has anyone ever done a
cone of plausibility?
So this is looking forward.
And what I like about
this, especially as a CISO,
what I'm trying to accomplish
here in this example
is how you could take some
intelligence assessments
and actually then use
them in your program.
We talk about this
panacea of intelligence
informing business
decisions and giving you
decision advantage over your
blah blah blah blah blah.
My goal here is to try
to start thinking about
how we could actually
do some of this stuff.
So cone of plausibility.
This is a forecasting technique.
Often times you'll
see it in larger
intelligence organizations
and may do them further out,
you know 2025,
what can we expect.
I like to make fun of forecasts.
Not the forecasts
but the predictions.
As Rob said I was a Forrester
analyst and every year
in October we'd do
these predictions.
And I always like to
talk about forecasts
and not predictions
because there was no
analytic rigor really in the
predictions that I would make
as an industry analyst.
I don't know that I was
blind to that fact then,
but what I like about
forecasts is at least you have
some rigor that's going
into your thought process
that you're using here.
So essentially what you're
trying to do is project trends,
events and their consequences,
and you look at
scenarios that occur.
And I think from a business
that is trying to plan out
the implications of something,
in this case cryptocurrency
fraud in 2018 and 2019,
you can start to talk about
things in the business
that they might care about
and then you start to,
I'll walk through it, let
me not get ahead of myself.
I have a reference for
all the things that
I'm talking about I've
got references at the end.
So you have one slide
that you can just look at,
it's similar to what
I did last year.
If you look at that
one slide you can just
hyperlink out to
all these things.
So there's a lot of things
in the cone of plausibility
as far as the framework goes.
Understanding the
current conditions,
so the drivers and
the assumptions.
How many people are familiar
with the PESTLE model?
So you can use the PESTLE model
to help do the drivers
an assumptions but
what's driving
the current state?
What are the key assumptions
that you're making
about the state, basically
new alternative coins
are gonna come, new
exchanges are gonna come,
fraud's gonna continue
what we went through
on the previous one.
And then you build
out the scenarios.
And so you have a
preferred scenario
which in my experience
in doing these preferred
really never
happens, a probable,
and then you have wild cards.
Now the wild cards, I
think one other thing that
we need more of from analysis
perspective is creativity.
So wild cards is you just
pick something that's
super random that you
may not have thought of,
completely out of the box,
and you have that as a scenario.
So it's really just
to kind of challenge
the thought that you
have, and basically
what you then do is you
monitor for these scenarios
and then you come up
with countermeasures
for those scenarios,
it'll be the process.
We'll walk through
it a little bit more.
But I really think
the wild card one,
in the ones that we've done
internally at Digital Shadows
it's kind of fun to do that one.
One that we did about
12 months ago was around
DDoS botnets and we were
trying to think about
how extortion
actors might change,
I'm sorry with IoT
botnets, doing DDoS,
and so one of the wild
card scenarios we had,
and we've seen a
little bit of this but
not on a grand scale was
gonna be grand scale of
crowdsourcing extortion
so instead of extorting
the brand, it's Christmas
and Rick wants to get on
Xbox Live or PlayStation,
and we take it down
and now I'm like OK
Rick, if you pay me
$100 and we crowdsource
that, then we'll bring
the service back online.
So that was just one
example of a wild card
scenario that we did there.
So this one, it's not as
bad to read on that screen,
it's kind of what it looks
like from a large scale.
You've got the drivers
that you've come up with.
And here the drivers
for this scenario is
the accessibility of the
technology, the anonymity
that you have, or
lack of anonymity
as some of the cyber
criminals are finding out,
popularity and high
reputation, the opportunity,
there's all kinds of opportunity
for fraud, the users,
the exchanges, the platforms,
regulation or lack
thereof regulation.
And then the security
of individuals,
consumers and organizations.
Again, this is just
to be illustrative
of what you could do
for this and your
organization may not have
anything to do with
cryptocurrency.
Then we have the assumptions
that we talked through
before on the previous slide,
and then we have scenarios.
And really at a high level
in scenarios preferable is
law enforcement gets
their act together,
regulations come into place
and the risk level goes down.
Pretty unlikely I think for
most things in our area.
The most probable one, and
I'm gonna walk through that
in subsequent slides,
is the cyber criminals
continue to innovate, they
target the cryptocurrencies,
the exchanges, they're
having a lot of success,
they're making a lot of profit.
You might even see
other types of networks
that may have been used
for ransomware that
are moving over to this
particular piece on crypto
jacking as an example.
And then in wild card scenario
here, heavy regulation,
decrease of anonymity,
the fraudulent attacks...
(mumbling) Water.
The number of targets
greatly decrease
and this just goes away as well.
So unlikely on that
scenario as well.
So here we're a
financial institution.
Mick the CISO he's concerned
about the exchanges
and the customers,
the employees there.
So you have your scenario
so you go through,
you understand the drivers,
you have the key assumptions.
You think about two
or three scenarios
and maybe you just
plan for the probable
because that's all
you have time for.
And then you start
to monitor for that.
You want to be able to
monitor changes over time
that indicate this
is about to occur.
And then you want, you
develop courses of action.
Of course military
people will understand
courses of action but
this would be your plan.
So for me, Mick the CISO
trying to understand
what do we need to do
practically about this threat.
So several things that
I would, trying to take
a change in the threat
landscape and tie it back
to my security program and
how I might make investments
or de-invest in certain areas.
So things that I would want
to do in this particular case,
we know that criminals
are trying to use
your Amazon Compute
for crypto jacking, so you're
paying for them to mine
Monero, Bitcoin,
whatever the case may be.
We see more Monero,
a lot of cases.
But here, do I have a
capability to monitor GitHub?
Now GitHub does a really good
job of take down requests.
There's a lot of
misconfiguration.
Let's talk about something
that in our programs
like shadow IT, GitHub is
a really painful component
of shadow IT, so here
I want to understand
what's out here on GitHub,
what misconfigurations
did someone do that
shouldn't be there
that's exposing risk
to my organization?
And then you start to see
your Amazon bill going up.
So this is one practical
thing that I might,
I may not have a
capability to do this.
How can I do this,
start monitoring that?
Another one, now
this one probably is
appropriate for
everything right?
This is web browser so
this is crypto jacking
of your users' browsers
themselves which
crypto jacking in and of itself,
using your browser
resources it reminds me of,
people remember
SETI@home back in the day
where you could my
computer to, that's what
actually I kinda think
about crypto jacking.
I actually wouldn't
mind a SETI like
if I was gonna let
someone mine my computer.
It was a non profit,
let's say it's
a cancer research center
or something like that,
I'm not necessarily
opposed to letting them
mine my browser if it's
gonna help them get Monero
that they can use for
research so it's not to say
that all of this crypto
jacking is necessarily bad.
There is some good
out there potentially.
But here we want to look
at our browser security
and the controls that
we have extensions.
And I would guess for
a lot of organizations
this is probably a weak
area of their configuration
and patch management in general.
And this obviously
helps out way more
than just a crypto
jacking scenario right?
This is everything
scenario since the browser
is such a prevalent
attack pattern.
Another one, Have I Been
Pwned, this is something
that you can do for free.
You can go out and look
at your organization.
You can also subscribe
to it as well,
but Troy Hunt puts
together these databases.
So Mick the CISO wants to
know if any of my employees
have been using their
corporate email address
to register on one
of these exchanges
that they're on, that
exchange gets popped,
they drain all of
the coin from them,
transfer it out, and then
they have the email addresses
of everyone out there.
So what kind of risk does
Mick the CISO's team have
from employees that are reusing
their corporate credentials
even just the email
address, right,
and these exchanges
get compromised?
So this also then becomes a
multi-factor authentication
conversation as well.
So again what I'm trying
to do is map this threat
that you get from the
Wall Street Journal
taking it down to how
do you actually change
your security
program as a result?
Another one, and I think this
one is an interesting one
we were talking about, if
you think about Millennials,
Millennials are more apt to
invest in cryptocurrencies.
I actually see it as
an opportunity, one is
I need to cover this in my
security awareness training.
How many people have
run security awareness
programs in their careers?
They're tough, and the way
you get people to connect,
you talk about threats
to their family,
to their children, well here,
for the Millennials that
are interested in this,
this might be a way
to connect with them,
and then you talk
about hey look.
There's all kinds of
fake exchanges set up,
fake platforms for
trading, just understand
the overall risk, if you
want to make the investment
that's fine, that's
your business.
We're not gonna give
you investment advice
but just know the risk there.
Oh by the way, here's
some other things
that you want to think about.
So this could be an
opportunity to take again
this Wall Street
Journal zomygod article
and actually do something
in my organization
to try to level up the
security a little bit.
So what can you do?
There's a couple things
and these aren't gonna be,
some things that'll
be interesting,
some are more obvious.
But one, has anyone read this
Cases in Intelligence Analysis?
This is almost like
a compendium book.
It's really good, we just
started in the Dallas office
with our intel analysts, we're
starting to take an event,
and basically it could
be something like
attempted assassination of
anti-Putin journalist in Russia,
things that have happened
historically and then
this is a workbook and
they'll give you two to three
structured analytic
techniques to work through.
What I have found to
be the most valuable is
Harrison's one of
the guys I do it with
in my office in Dallas
is just us talking.
We're in a room, we're
discussing these things
and it's just, the mere
fact that you're having
communication maybe goes
back to Carmen's point about
it's not as much about
the structured analytics
as it is about better analysis.
This has been a really
good way for us to do that
within our intel team
out of the Dallas office.
So especially if you're
a history buff as well,
you'll like this 'cause
you're going back to
all sorts of, there's
20 of them in there.
In the books, maybe 60,
about something like that.
So recommended take-home
assignment for you.
Google Docs, this is one,
now I will caveat this with
I realize Google
Docs is in the cloud.
So you could use another
solution but conceptually
either you host your
own solution but
what I like about Google
Docs, we used to use this
at Forrester, we'd
have all the analysts,
I think we had 12
analysts on the team,
and we would be brainstorming
at the beginning
of the year about
the threat landscape,
customer pain points,
what do we want to write about?
And it would be ready
set go and then everybody
just starts throwing
up ideas on there
and just seeing them pop
pop different colors.
Has anyone ever used Google
Docs in this context before?
It's a really good
technique especially,
especially for remote teams.
And I think that's a
big problem that we have
just in general, especially
as there's a trend
for more remote workforce,
and you want to enable
your own remote employees
so I really like this model.
And then essentially what
you do is you start to
group these ideas together
and you put them here
and then maybe you do a key
assumptions check on that.
So it's a way that
you can start off with
structured brainstorming,
then you do
key assumptions check,
then you can move on
to whatever else it may be.
This could be you're
brainstorming on
the threat landscape
for your organization
in 2018 and beyond.
Maybe this is on the vendor
side and you're trying
to think of really exciting
research and capabilities
that you have that
you want to highlight.
Whatever the case may be,
Google Docs is one route to go.
Then, you can go big.
Now I do think, anybody here a
developer in a previous life?
Developers, it's not
the same everywhere,
but developers do a pretty
good job of collaborating,
especially when you have
remote product management
and development teams.
But there's tools
like Google Jamboard
where you actually
have a big TV like this
and it's interactive and
I can draw ideas on it
and then I can use
it on my phone,
can use it on a tablet as well.
So it really helps with
both in person collaboration
for those in the office, as
well as people that are remote.
The TV is like five
grand so this is,
you're starting to (mumbling)
a little bit more but
if you think of a
threat intelligence team
and you want to have a
better collaboration,
and this doesn't
necessarily have to be,
this could be other things
besides threat intelligence
this could be, I want
to draw the architecture
of my environment
in a real time view
so that we get a
better understanding
of what our
architecture looks like.
And Google Jamboard
is not alone.
Stormboard has, it's
a Canadian company.
They have an OnPrem
version as well.
This is one I created
last night on my own.
And you can put
the note cards on.
So you could put
the note cards up,
everyone could do that
and then you could group
the note cards and
things like that.
So there are some pretty nice
collaboration tools out there
that you can use,
again, you can have some
that you host yourself so
you don't have to worry about
this being in the cloud.
A lot of the
collaboration tools,
if the content you're working
on isn't sensitive in nature,
they plug into Box, they plug
into all the CESS applications
and it's a really
convenient way to work.
Again, it depends on the content
and sensitivity that
you're working on.
And Carmen actually
mentioned this,
cued me up here with IARPA.
So IARPA has funded, I think
it's about 50 million across
four universities
to do research in,
CREATE is the name
of the program,
but Crowdsourcing,
Evidence, Augmentation,
Thinking and Evaluation.
If you want to put
a Google alert down
on something to track,
this, the first,
it's been in place I think
maybe it's May of this year,
these universities are gonna
present their findings.
Now I don't know how much of
it will actually go public
but this is a good one
to put a Google alert on.
And here's three of
the specific products,
projects that
they're working on.
Some of them are more
focused on crowdsourcing,
of analysis, using AI with that.
In this case, when it's
a university person
talking about AI versus
vendor marketing,
I'm more inclined to believe
their AI or maybe not
have as much distaste for it.
'Cause I am firmly in the
camp of (audio muting)
machine learn and AI all the
things is the wrong approach.
Maybe that's my bias from
being analyst, it is,
my bias from being an
analyst at Forrester
and getting machine
learned to death
from everyone out there.
Swarm is a wiki, when
you can ask questions
and get responses back.
Trace is another
collaborative tool.
I don't know what these
applications will actually
come out being, but
there could be something
that we could leverage in the
commercial sector as well.
And then of course
for our friends
in the intelligence
community, you may very well
be able to use these
types of solutions
in the next several years.
The one thing I would
say is this, SATS are not
silver bullets, just
because you have
structured analytic techniques
doesn't mean you're
not gonna fail.
Intelligence is, at best,
a guessing game right?
Hopefully we can do a
little bit more than that.
So don't think it could
be this false sense of
look at all this analytic rigor.
We had these three
techniques that were used
in the production of this
particular product or asset
and it's good to go.
No you cannot be
complacent with these,
you need to revise the tool set,
Carmen talked
about that as well.
And I think this
is a great quote.
I often ask if this
is an overdone quote.
It depends, is this an overdone
quote for this audience?
OK.
I like it.
Tell me what you know,
what you don't know
and then most importantly,
what you think
is most likely to
happen based on that.
I think this is what's really
really important for us.
I think if you look at the
way we've been focused,
very much indicator
focused over the years,
some of this stuff isn't, this
is an abstract level above
where we're at but I think
just knowing what you know,
knowing what you don't
know is the tough piece.
This goes back to the Rumsfeld
analogy a little bit too
right the unknown unknowns.
But at least for the
things that you know,
what's your confidence
level around
that realm that you do know it?
We know it really well or
we don't know it that well.
I think this is a really
important one to go off of.
That's a picture from last year.
I just was gonna throw up
a thank you slide on there
and I found that was
our monument walk
that we did last year.
I did put as a reference, a
number of different things
that I put on here, and
if you want to go through
an actual painful exercise,
that second to bottom,
PARC ACH Software, has
anyone ever used it?
Do you like it?
- It's so old.
- Yeah yeah.
Might just be better to
go with the spreadsheet.
It could be a little
bit easier but
actually PARC's got some
other tools out there as well.
There's different references,
some stuff from Rand,
a couple different pdfs that
you can download as well.
The one call that I
would have on this,
and I don't know if a Slack
channel's the right way
to do it but I really want
to foster more conversation
about better analysis
in our space.
So if you're interested in this,
if you're passionate about
it, if you have experience,
please reach out to me.
I'd like to form some sort
of group where we can talk
and collaborate on this and
then further it for the field.
I don't know what
it's gonna look like.
These may not be the right
things for your organization
but I do think as we look
to mature where we're at
as an industry
and practitioners,
we need to be doing
better analysis.
Thank you.
(applauding)
(upbeat music)