(light music)
(audience clapping)
- This talk actually is
about how can we move
from the reactive
chasing of IOCs
into a more proactive approach
and understand how the
bad guys are operating
behind the scenes.
I'm gonna start backwards.
I'm gonna propose
some takeaways,
and you need to
hold me accountable.
Will you learn these
things at the end?
If not, then you'll have
to press with questions.
The first one, we want
to learn something
about the business model that
bulletproof hosting providers.
I'll explain what that is.
And then I'm gonna
propose a taxonomy
for BPH operations.
And then we're gonna look
into the bulletproof
hosting providers
behind the current
malspam campaigns
that I'm sure a lot
of us are chasing.
Finally I'm gonna propose
some repeatable techniques
and signals that can help you
track these BPH operations
as well as some current
malware campaigns.
Some of you know me,
some of you don't.
I'm @DhiaLite on Twitter.
I'm the head of
Security Research
at Cisco Umbrella,
formerly OpenDNS.
My background is network
security, network
traffic analysis.
And then I got a PhD in graph
algorithms at SMU, Dallas,
hence Rick's mentioned there.
I've been in the US
for like 15 years.
At the bottom, you have a hint
of where I'm from originally.
To the left, that's like
one of the finest generals
in ancient history.
He used elephants as a hint.
And then the next two are fine
generals from World War II.
They fought one of
the fiercest battles
on my home country soil.
You must have
figured out already.
Here is like a
typical in a SOC life.
Basically you're
collecting a lot of data,
some of it useful,
some of it not.
From your internal network,
your endpoints, firewalls,
proxy, a variety
of other devices.
And then you collect a lot of
feeds from external sources,
some of it you pay, some
of it is open source,
some of it is
through some ISACs.
But then you're trying to
make sense out of all of this,
so you pump it into a SIEM
or you build your own,
and then you try to
take advantage of a TIP
to help you enrich and correlate
and make some more sense.
Eventually, hopefully
you can have
some actionable threat intel.
Again, what is threat
intel, to be honest?
It's that insight and
information, post analysis
that can help you make
some good decisions
tied to your requirements
and your needs.
It's not like something off
the shell that you can get.
You have to tie it
to your own needs,
and you have to do some effort
to get the right intel.
This talk is about
how can we move up
from the tactical intel,
which is like chasing IOCs,
pushing them into
enforcement devices.
Try to get some
further understanding
of proactive insight
into what's behind the scenes
in all of these
crime or operations.
Hopefully maybe we can
get some strategic insight
that can help us in the long
term in terms of investments,
how can we grow our teams,
what type of feeds or
collaborations or partnerships
we should do in the long term.
Here it is.
Let's learn about the enemy.
For that, I'm gonna
propose to describe
like the threat intel
production cycle we have
in my research lab.
We start with a requirement
of protecting customers.
This is basically
what everybody does.
We need to find like
some high-fidelity IOCs,
domains and IPs typically.
We start with our
worldwide collection system
of recursive DNS resolvers
but also a variety of
other big data sources.
After that, you have
to do processing.
You have to basically
summarize this data, index it,
and make it searchable,
so you can test hypotheses
and ask questions and
get answers quick.
That's how you can do analysis,
whether it's machine-based
or human-based,
and get deeper into the
investigation you're carrying.
Finally you'd have
to disseminate that
to your customer,
and he will have
to give feedback,
so you know if you're succeeding
and if you're failing.
With that, you can
adjust and adapt.
With our lab, actually we
have done a lot of work
in the analysis phase where
we find a lot of these threats
with different signals.
Now you ask me okay,
why are we talking about
bulletproof hosting and criminal
hosting infrastructures.
It's because practically all
of the threats we see nowadays,
they had to use or they have
to use some sort of hosting.
It's the fundamental technology
that enables everything
around there.
Malware, phishing, dump shops,
crimeware forums, you name it.
In fact, if I step back,
and now I propose a way
to break down the
cyber crime ecosystem,
and you realize that the
offerings in the underground,
they are broken
into three classes.
You have the goods.
Those are your items you
can consume right away.
You can buy and use
like the dumps, the
credentials, the PIIs.
And then you have the products.
These are your tools that allow
you to infect organizations
or individuals at scale.
And then in the middle, you
have like the core technologies
that allow everything else
to exist, your services
such as the ransomware
as a service
or the bulletproof
hosting providers,
which are the
focus of this talk,
hence the definition.
What's a bulletproof
hosting provider?
Simply put, it's a
criminal hosting company
that will shield the
criminal customers
against abuse complaints
and takedown operations.
How do they do that?
We'll see a few hints.
Now actually I want to go back
and describe the spectrum
of hosting space.
You will see that you have
the good stuff to the left.
These are your legit
companies doing hosting.
And then unfortunately
a lot of them get abused
because they don't
have enough staff,
because they have not
defined a clear TOS,
or because they're lax
and they are in countries
that allow this type of thing.
And then finally you
have the pure criminals.
Those are the ones
living in certain areas.
They are leveraging
certain technologies
and certain regulations,
and that allows it to
thrive and to succeed.
That's the topic of
this presentation here.
For that, I want to
propose a taxonomy
that we can all use to
classify bulletproof hosting.
Here, what I'm proposing
is that we have a class
we call botnet-based, I'm
gonna have an example,
and then the other
one is host-based,
and I'm gonna have
an example as well.
Before that, let me
describe the business model.
There is an interesting
recipe we came up with
after doing a few
years of analyses.
We saw that the barrier
of entry is quite low.
You could spend less than $2,000
to come up with a dedicated
bulletproof hosting operation.
You basically have to
register your business
in an offshore country,
I'll describe that,
and then you have to acquire
an autonomous system number,
get some IP space, do
peering relationships,
and then you set
up your website.
You have to bring in customers
so you can have a public site
or you have just the presence
in the underground forums,
whether open or closed
or just stay private
to a VIP clientele,
and then you generate revenue.
People will start using you.
They will host traffic.
They will send spam,
generate bad stuff.
And then if you're
really bulletproof,
you'll be able to handle abuse,
but if not, you'll have to
shut down your operation
and move somewhere else.
And then hopefully you
can repeat the process
because the recipe
is quite simple.
I'm not saying it's trivial,
I'm saying you have
like some set steps
that you can follow to succeed.
So then now how about detection?
What can we do about this?
These are some of the
technical features
we have used in
the past few years
to identify these
different infrastructures.
The first one is what we
call a leaf ASN model.
I'll describe that.
The second one is you
register your business
in offshore countries.
I'll describe that.
And then usually they will
use anonymous payment methods
like the Bitcoin,
the Perfect Money,
and some of the new
ones we see nowadays.
Also, they will
use small IP space
just for flexibility
and for low cost.
Finally obviously if
you follow the traffic
hosted or generated
out of this IP space,
you will see it's purely toxic
and most of the time
bad and criminal.
For the outgoing traffic,
it's usually SSH brute
forcing, DDoS attacks,
sending spam, that
type of thing.
How about the leaf
stub ASN idea?
We came up with this
concept at Black Hat 2014.
The idea is that on
the public internet,
an organization needs to acquire
an autonomous system number
to identify their network.
They have to have some IP space,
and then they will do
peering relationships
and advertise their IP space,
so then now they become
visible to the global internet,
and now they can route
traffic in and out.
In this case, we can see
that the relationship
is directional.
You have arrows pointing up.
SINARO and HOSTSLIM,
they happen to be having
an upstream in SERVERIUS.
Usually you'll have either
upstream or downstreams,
but the leaf is when
you only have upstreams.
You don't have any buddy
below you relying on you
because if you have
relationship up,
it means you have to
advertise your IP space,
and that person will have
to advertise it for you.
So if you don't have
anybody below you,
it means no one depends on you.
Now why is this interesting?
It's because it offers you this
like nomadic flexible setup
where you can just be as a leaf,
set up your operation,
do your thing,
and then if you want
to move somewhere else,
no one will be affected.
You can just go away,
and basically create
another kind of link
with another upstream provider,
and it's as if nothing
happened, in fact.
This is not
necessarily criminal,
but we noticed it oftentimes
with this criminal
or suspicious
hosting operations.
The offshore countries,
these are the ones we saw
in the Panama Papers,
Offshore Leaks.
They are not necessarily
used by the BPH guys
for tax evasion but
mainly for an extra layer
of a resistance because
in these countries,
they are not forced to give
away the private information
of the customer, so law
enforcement has no clue
on who is behind
the BPH operation.
That's the advantage here.
In fact, we realized after
further analysis of that,
these bad guys or
these BPH actors,
they leverage the
best of three worlds.
The actors will be,
the operators will be
mainly from Eastern Europe
like Ukraine or Russia,
and then the servers
will be using
the best connectivity
in the world,
North America and Europe,
and finally the business
will be protected
in offshore countries
like the ones we saw.
So you basically have
an ideal recipe here
and no one practically
can touch you.
I'm not saying no
one or impossible
because we had some
successful takedown operations
like the Avalanche
and a few others,
but you realize they
last like a few years
because it takes a lot
of work and collaboration
between law enforcement,
countries, local agencies,
security companies, private
sector, and government.
It's not an easy task,
but it's possible.
Now let me talk about
some major BPH operations.
Let me start with the
botnet-based points.
In this case, this
is a known one.
We have been tracking it
for, I would say,
like four, five years.
We call it the Zbot
Fast Flux proxy network.
Some others in the industry
call it Fluxxy or Darkcloud.
It's typically around
20 to 30 to 40,000
compromised
residential machines,
typically WiFi, access
points, and routers,
and mainly Ukraine and Russia,
and they are used as a CDN
or reverse proxy
infrastructure for criminals.
The idea is that you
come to the actor,
you have a site you
want to protect.
It could be a phishing
site, a malware C2,
a ransomware payment site, a
dump shop, a criminal forum.
And then you tell the guy
for a few hundred dollars,
"Hey, I want to protect the
origin IP of my server."
It'd be like, "Okay,
give me the domain.
"I'm gonna change the name
server setup of your domain,
"and make it point to Flax
Flux IPs from the botnet."
So then everybody who
resolves the domain
will only see Fast Flux IPs,
but in those bots
controlled by the actor,
they will have like a
redirection via Nginx usually
to the origin IP server,
and then back and
forth, you have traffic.
It's like a criminal Cloudflare
or Akamai in a sense.
This guy has been
very successful.
Currently he is powering the
Gozi ISFB banking Trojan,
and in the past,
he's done practically
everything under the sun.
Now the other model or the
other class is the host-based.
We saw an example where
it was mainly botnet-based
like compromise
people's machines.
Now it's host-based,
meaning he will either have
his own ASN infrastructure,
or he will lease
servers and VPSs
from third-party companies,
or he will combine both.
These are examples
of known hosters
that are rogue or criminal
that are using the
host-based model.
You can take a picture
or you can ask me later
for these examples to study.
Now let's talk about one
of the most prominent guys
in the host-based BPH space.
This guy is named Alex.
In fact, this is a
very interesting and
close relationship
with Intel 471,
so they track the
actor-centric intelligence.
They are the experts
in the field in that.
From our side, we are like
the worldwide telemetry guy,
so we are able to track this
thing all over the place
and kinda pinpoint
where they are
and what they are doing.
This guy actually
now is powering
practically everything you see,
the malspam campaigns, the
phishing, the dump shops,
anything, you name it.
He's been successful since 2016.
In fact, all of the activity
that we see nowadays,
they have used this guy at
least once or a few times.
He has a presence in China,
but he's a Russian-speaking guy.
The other interesting thing
is that he also abused his
third-party cloud services
such as Amazon and Google Cloud
although they have cleaned
up their act recently,
and now he's focused mainly
in European hosting companies
like in Russia,
France, Netherlands,
and a few other countries.
This is the interesting
slide I like here,
which is the one we came up with
by studying his dedicated
internet infrastructure.
The guy owns and operates
three ASNs of his own,
the three ones in gray.
In fact, they have that
leaf-chained ASN structure
I described earlier because
they have no downstreams.
They kinda link to each other,
the ones to the left,
and then they share some handles
with another ASN to the right,
and that's the Alex,
Alexander, Volosovyk,
a name that we used in,
like the way we call them.
In fact, that's his name,
and then he has another
handle in the underground.
What's interesting is
that the chain there
of those two to the left,
they can sever their
relationship with OBIT,
which is a typical
hosting company in Russia,
and move somewhere else
like nothing happened.
I'm not saying
they do it easily,
but then that's the
setup I described earlier
that makes it very flexible.
Finally the guy in
gray to the right,
that one is sharing
some credentials
that appeared in
the Panama Papers
like the address in Seychelle,
that one, if you look it up,
it's the same with maybe
tens or hundreds of companies
that are in the Panama Papers,
so they use like
some front companies
to protect their identity,
some for tax evasion
and some for bulletproof
hosting operation.
The funny thing is
that you can see
that, I would say, different
worlds will overlap
for the same, I
would say, evasion
and money laundering purposes.
Now let me go with
a use case here,
which is one of the most
prominent malspam campaigns
right now, are leveraging
the Alex infrastructure,
and I'm gonna describe
those signals and features
I described earlier to track
this type of malware campaign.
Your typical malspam
campaign infection chain
looks something like this.
So you have a phishing email
or like a few phishing
emails sent in large amounts
to potential victims.
In this case, they spoofed
performanceair.com.
That's the legit domain,
but it has been made
look like it's the one
who is sending the spam emails,
and they're trying to lure you
into thinking it's a Delta
Air Lines, like a invoice,
you have to click on a
link to download whatever.
The next step is
that when you open up
the body of the email,
you'll have some phishing
URLs that you have to click on
if you make the mistake.
And those will go and drop
a malicious Word document
who will bring in
Hancitor dropper.
It's not the malware itself
because the Hancitor
dropper will call out
to its own C2s, which
are in step four.
And then the Hancitor
dropper will now call out
to its own C2s who will bring
the actual banking Trojan.
In this case, it's been
Zloader, Pony, Evil Pony,
and then Panda Banker.
Finally those Trojans,
they will call out to
their own C2s in step five,
and now they bring in like
extra modules for infection.
They will exfiltrate data,
or they will just
announce their existence.
Step six can vary
depending on the purpose
of the malware being
dropped in step four.
This is your infection chain.
Now how can we track it
with our worldwide
signals intelligence?
We're gonna see.
This is how the email looks like
when you just receive in your
spam trap or email mailbox.
Now let me start with
a signal analysis here.
This is from our
global telemetry.
This is, I would say, an
interface we use for research
but it's also offered
for our customers
for their own purpose,
but the point is, the spike
in traffic to performanceair,
remember, that's the
spoofed sender domain.
It's legit.
They just made it look like
it's the one sending the spam,
but then you see a 50K spike
in queries, DNS queries
from all over the world.
Those clients
scouring this domain,
they could have been spam traps,
email appliances, mail servers.
They could have been
the potential mail
servers of the victim.
It varies.
But the point is, here
you can get the idea
about the volume of the attack,
so you have like 50K queries
that might give you like
the extent of this campaign,
and this is done daily.
That was the first step.
How about the second step?
Can we have some signals
intelligence around it?
In fact, we do.
We can see that some those URLs
in the body of the email,
they also have spikes,
but the spikes are lower.
They're around 1,000
to 1,200 DNS queries.
Here it tells you how
the funnel tightens,
but then you now
become more focused
in your potential infections
because by the time you
clicked on the link,
you're about to be infected.
Potentially it's a spam trap
or like in a mail appliance,
so there is no real victim,
but then if it happens to be
a real person who clicked,
then you got an idea
about how many potential
victims were infection.
Now think about it also is that,
what you should
think about as well
is that you have
six URLs per day,
per malspam daily campaign.
So you multiply
that by the volume,
and that tells you around,
1,200 times six or seven,
that's around like the
number of potential queries
to that domain that
might lead to infections.
In fact, another interesting,
I would say, signal
is that not only the volume
of the spike is interesting,
it's also the duration.
When we zoom in,
or zoom out, sorry,
whatever the right term is,
you'll realize the spike
will last for a few hours.
It's like seven hours.
It's not just like
one hit of a button
and then everything happens.
So you basically have
potentially victims
who will spend seven hours
to get into the flow of
this infection chain.
And then if you calculate
the area under the curve,
you can kind of come up
with a potential number
of how many infections
this campaign is yielding.
Now let's do our typical
passive DNS exercise
that everybody likes.
I'm gonna look
into one of the IPs
of the phishing URL
on the 30th of August,
that IP 52.14.
Fun fact, it's on Amazon.
It's one of the IPs from Alex.
Remember he was abusing
Google Cloud and AWS?
Now this was like
several months ago.
This IP is not used anymore.
It has been cleaned
up by Amazon.
But then back then
in the summer,
this was being
leveraged by Alex,
and being offered for
his Hancitor actors.
Basically you have Alex
operating on his own,
he's catering to
variety of customers,
and the Hancitor
gang were using him
for their first stage infection.
Now if I dig deeper
into the passive DNS,
I'll see that that IP
is hosting like a
lot of other domains.
In fact, a lot of
them also spiking.
I took one of
them, heymamaradio.
That guy is also spiking
at the same volume.
Remember the 1,200
queries, not the first one?
Now I pivoted from the IP
and now I get a domain with
the same signals intelligence
or signals feature.
That's the interesting fact.
Now I can tie in together
a few domains via the IP
that are part of the same,
I would say, spike,
malspam campaign.
Now an interesting fact
here about the passive DNS
is that not only should you
look at the IPs themselves
but also look at the Flux,
and who do they belong to,
and tie that with other,
I would say, insights.
In this case, that
domain, the top one,
the phishing URL is in fact
a compromised GoDaddy domain.
The IPs surrounded by green,
those are IPs from
the GoDaddy IP space.
Initially on the 29th of August,
it was a GoDaddy legit IP.
Sorry, yeah, the domain was
hosted on a GoDaddy legit IP.
And then all of a sudden,
on the 29th of August,
it switched to an
IP that is 47.74.
That lasted for like
the next six days.
So all of the IPs in
red, those are IPs
under the Alex bulletproof
hosting infrastructure.
This is kind of the point here.
The malspam campaigns are
leveraging Alex infrastructure
by weaponizing
formerly legit domains,
switching them into
the new criminal IPs,
and then using them.
As we saw, they spiked
because you had a lot
of victims go into them.
Finally they de-weaponize them
and bring them back to the
GoDaddy previous space.
That's another interesting
signal we need to look for.
Now the classic approach WHOIS.
Everyone can do it.
I look into the
registrant email.
That one happens to
be using GoDaddy,
so we can see here it's
a compromised registrant.
It's not like a dedicated thing
that was registered
in August of 2017.
We confirm that because the
domains under that registrant,
they were not malicious before,
but once the account got
popped by the actors,
or it got acquired
by the actors,
they're not necessarily
the same people,
they weaponize all
of those domains,
and now they use them
in similar campaigns
or campaigns of the same day.
In fact, if we
pick one of those,
the .info, we can see
that it also has a spike.
Same volume, 1,200 queries.
You can see here I found
three different domains
from different avenues
that had the exact same
signal feature here.
Another interesting
feature we have
that we use in our
research and analysis
is what we call a
related domains or
co-occurrences concept.
The idea is that we build
like this internal
large-scale graph
where we take all of the domains
queried by the same IPs
during a short time period.
It's almost like
locality and time
based on who queries
those domains.
With that, you can build
a very interesting graph,
the co-occurrence graph,
which will tie domains
that are shared
between the same infected
machines like DGAs typically
or like machines following
like the infection chain,
so usually you'll see
the compromised site
leading with the
iFrame injection
leading to the exploit
kit landing page
to maybe the C2 domain.
Oftentimes it's also
used for tracking people
who browse the same topics
like crimeware forums, you'll
see co-occurring altogether.
Jabber servers, they
will co-occur together.
VPN, proxy, SOC servers,
they will co-occur together
because the customers
who go there,
they will tend to have
the same topics or
interests altogether.
Now in this case,
the phishing URL
that we see here at the top,
that one co-occurs with
the performanceair.
Remember, performanceair
was the spoofed sender.
It was stage one in
the infection chain.
The phishing URL is stage two.
And then the bottom
one, the three there,
they are also stage two.
Those are like phishing URLs
who are dropping the
Hancitor malware.
You can see here with
the co-occurrences now,
you can also recreate the
infection chain somewhat
because you have stage one
co-occurring with stage two
and also some other
guys, some other domains
from the stage two
of the same campaign,
or a campaign from
a following day.
That's kind of the
interesting thing here.
Now you might tell me okay,
how can I do this on my own.
If you have like your large
DNS collection infrastructure,
you can try to create
this sort of analysis
like you'll have to
collect the data,
you'll have to process it,
create like the right
data structures,
use the right technology,
and then now maybe
you can come up
with this type of analysis.
These are like some recipes
that you might be
able to reproduce.
Some of them might
require, maybe use
like some third
party or whatnot.
But I guess the takeaway
is that a lot of these
things are worth looking at
because they give
you a lot of insight
beyond just like the domains
and IPs and running around
and trying to push
them and block them
and all of that stuff.
I guess one of the final slides
is an interesting recap
on the exploration
graph I described.
And then I can go
over it in slow-mo
if you have questions later.
We started with stage one,
and then we were able to
find the related domains,
and then we found like the WHOIS
helped us find some
more malicious domains.
We looked into the hosting IP,
which happened to be on Alex
that we described earlier.
And then from that hosting IP,
we found domains that happen
to resolve to other IPs
under the Alex infrastructure.
And then I could have also
looked into the hashes
that are tied to that
malicious domain.
I didn't show it.
But then if you look
into the network trace,
you can also find some more C2s
that are part of this
entire infection chain.
We found it very useful for us
to map out the
exploration paths we have
because that gives you
a visual perspective
of how things operating.
You could do this
with some visual tools
or you can just draw
it on the board.
We found that very powerful.
Now we do this with
pencil and paper,
but then oftentimes if
you have the expertise
and technology, you
can build the systems
who will do this at scale.
That's the fun part.
How can you transfer
your human insight
into something scalable
and repeatable.
I think that's
one of the lessons
we can learn from
this conference,
which I found very exciting,
is that can we make all of
this knowledge we have here
into something scalable
and repeatable,
so we can save time.
Finally one of my
favorite slides
is that it's a summary of the
TTPs across malspam campaigns
covering a few months, I
would say six or seven months.
I just put like
two here for space,
but then we see that
the first stage,
which is like the
spoofed sender URL,
the spoofed sender email,
they happen to be using
legit unfortunate
innocent domains,
but those happen to have a
very distinct spiked volume.
It's around 50 or 60K.
Whereas the phishing URLs
in the body of the email,
they happen to have that
spike around 1,200, no more.
But then the other
cool thing about it
is that all of the phishing URLs
like the stage two in the
infection are using Alex.
They never divert from that.
Why?
Because Alex happens to be
one of the most successful,
reliable, fault
tolerant, et cetera
bulletproof hosting
infrastructures
we've seen nowadays
in the ecosystem
of a cyber crime.
The actors behind Hancitor,
they chose, for
practicality, to use him
because they were like okay,
let's guarantee the best
infection rate we can get
by using the best guy very
early in our infection chain,
and the rest we can,
maybe we don't care.
In fact, the next C2s,
they are all using like a
variety of smalltime BPH
and abused hosters in
European countries,
in Russia and
Ukraine especially.
This is shows you how,
like we saw earlier
with the talk about AlphaBay,
where it's a very
opportunistic ecosystem.
They will try to use
the best expertise
from different groups, and
the goal is to basically make
money and be the most successful
in the cyber crime ecosystem.
I know I had a lot of material.
I went a little bit fast.
But then if you want
to get more details,
I invite you to check some
of our previous talks.
We had a few talks at
Black Hat 2014, 2016, 2017,
Defcon, Virus
Bulletin, you name it.
You can take a picture or you
can get those from the slides.
But if not, then I'll
be more than happy
to talk offline
about any questions.
Some acknowledgements, some
good friends helped out
with a few things.
Thank you again.
I appreciate it.
(audience clapping)
(tense music)