so we're going to try and present some
research done at the tue with the spice
well research which is basically a thing
that the tea we organize and we're
students from the true masters in
cybersecurity and next slide please so
hopefully you guys are a little bit
aware of what run somewhere is but if
not here's a quick little grievance
reduction so ransomware is basically
some malicious software that is trying
to take the files of a user as a hostage
and then a user can try and get back
their files by paying some ransom
oftentimes this is done through
something anonymous such as with going
on stuff like that and the most common
one uses encryption to basically do this
and also it tries to do this as fast as
possible it's just kind of a major thing
of our solution as well as that it tries
to do it so fast as possible and it's
also kind of the modus operandi of
ransomware can I get the next slide so
this is basically something that a lot
of companies know what this is a basic
computer interface with some samba
shares and the Samba shares usually hold
some sort of information
that's all right so yeah so much here so
a lot of people should know and probably
know what these are and a lot of
important information is stored on these
and you expect them to be backed up but
what if that's not the case or for
instance your backup failed or whatever
something went wrong like technical
issues happen like you've seen today and
so we thought well maybe we can make
something that is like a passive
listener and could perhaps step in once
ransomware attacks these targets because
they are really crucial resources that
ransomware good attack and it's possible
that they actually already attack these
because we've seen these cases happening
can I get the next slide so this is just
a simple example where one hosts and
some stuff to another hose through SMB
packages nothing really going on here
and now something else is going on and
I've marked some packages in red and
these indicate some encryption going on
and still this is not a big issue
because encryption happens because it's
a useful tool to secure some of your
files but what if something like a
network where you have a samba share and
a lot of hosts and some people are
sending some encrypted information and
it's all fine and dandy but what if
there is one actor that actually sends a
lot of encrypted data and this could
still be fine but in theory it could be
fine but in the most cases this is
actually a problem for us mostly because
we expect this ransomware to display the
sort of behavior of mass encrypting
stuff and so we figured while we can
make some sort of system that can detect
mass encryption and to do this we built
some exchanges
based on the message features that we
extract from the SMB data and then we
try and figure out whether these in
exchanges are encrypted and if they are
then well we can actually say well okay
encryption is all fine but is this is
the behavior that the traffic is
displaying is it actually a user
encrypting some stuff or is it for
instance ransomware so here is our first
first step we get some network traffic
we parse it through we as in be parted
and we extract some message features and
these features are used to build
exchanges and also to detect encryption
and these exchanges are basically
multiple as and B messages that we link
up through message identifiers and
here's this really simple and why we
create or open a file and then someone
tries to read some stuff and then it
also writes back this is a kind of
normal when you are working on some
files but we often notice that
ransomware often read a file and then
actually use another process to write to
the file and this is hard to link up
because it's different processes doing
this and so we had to build some file
pattern detection system that actually
looked at the file identifiers and
looked at the actors that are actually
working on the files and this way we
could build some exchanges that actually
just are sort of like a history of all
the file manipulations on a single file
by a single actor so now that we have
these exchanges we actually have to try
and detect encryption and we do this
using entropy which can be done on the
file data and what actually entropy
means is something that far as well
explain yeah
they sound yes thanks yeah so on the
file system don't build the exchanges
for us which means that we can consume
manipulation of the files and we're
looking for encryption now if I have two
example files here the one on the right
or your last story has a regular pattern
has words as some structure and will
recognize that as a normal file the one
on the right has no such structure and
most likely is an encrypted file we can
see this but in order to build a
ransomware detector we actually have two
pc computer how to see this and what we
use for this is a first step is n-grams
which you all in all language processing
is making histograms of all sub strings
of text well in our case we're just
going to look at one grams which are the
bytes represented in a certain piece of
text and then we'll make a histogram for
that so we count the occurrence of each
ascii character which we have done for
both files presented the one on the left
the structured file shows Peaks shows
some regular occurrence of characters
and some that are less regular the file
on the right has very flat profile which
means that it's it's very hard to say
which characters are using this file
because they all occur about as frequent
what we can do with this if you go to
the next slide if we turn it into
distribution and actually express the
probability sorry of of the the
occurrence of a certain character and
for encryption it is important that a
cipher texts text is hard to predict
even if you have a plain text or if you
have a key and no plain text sorry can't
go to predict this and in order to build
our encryption detector we have to turn
these distributions into a number that
represents something about how easy or
hard it is to protect the
it bites in a file and what we use for
this and don't spoil a little bit on
purpose is called Shannon entropy and in
the next five slides which will contain
a bit of mass I'm going to try to
explain how this is computed for some of
you this might be old hat for some of
you this might go a little bit fast but
bear with me well we already have seen
probably how to turn a statistical
distribution into a single number
because in the second grade of high
school we all got the assignment of hey
if you play the lottery what is the
average result of playing the lottery so
what is your expected value and in our
little example say if you have a lottery
with also one in a million of winning
grand prize $100,000 and a smaller price
that of course one in thousands of one
hundred dollars then computing the
average of of playing the lottery is a
one in thousand occurrence of the grand
prize plus a 1 in thousands occurrence
of the smaller plot price meaning that
if you play in this lottery you'll get
20 cents for every time you play which
of course usually is not nice if you pay
more for the tickets so the numbers are
meaningful and every one of you of
course already has tried once to convert
a distribution into such a number now if
we generalize this then the formula
mathematical formula for expected value
is the sum over all the probabilities of
a certain events times a certain value a
pair of attached to these events now
indicate the distributions we created
the next slide we cannot say anything
about the certain value of design but we
can evaluate this in terms of
probability of this event occurring and
as we've seen in the slide earlier that
we're looking for the difference between
distributions that have very high peaks
and very low peaks and are also very
flat so what we're going to do for this
payoff function we actually want to do
something where we calculate 1 over the
probability of an event occurring so if
we have a very rare event a very flat
peak then we're going to attach a high
value which means it's hard to predict
and we
a very high peaks we're going to attach
a low value and freshen LNP we also take
the two log of this if you click to the
next slide visit this has nice
properties such as that the the entropy
of a binary experiment say a coin flip
is exactly one bit so the level the
entropy of predicting whether a bit is a
1 or 0 is 1 and if we fill this in to
the expected value formula then we get
what is called Shannon entropy and
that's what we're going to use to
convert the distribution into a number
that is meaningful in terms of
encryption now if you got distracted by
the math you can also consider the
entropy as the lower bound and the
number of years and no questions you
have to ask about a certain experiment
in order to guess a result that came
from the experiment in which case if you
have the bit flip the coin flip again
and it's one question you have to ask
whether it's a one or a zero and then
you'll know which is the lower bound for
guessing so we had these distributions
from the histograms that we converted
and then on the next slide the strategy
again is we have text we turn that in a
histogram the different ASCII characters
have distribution user entropy
calculation and then we have a number
that's meaningful which of course now
becomes filling in exercise to have
three peaks here of of rare occurrence
which we calculate here then add two
peaks of more common occurrence maybe
get a number two points to something on
the right side we have seven very small
Peaks which will also add together
according to the formula and then we get
two numbers that express what we
originally saw that in the next slide 23
the one on the right is a lower number
or the one on your left is a lower
number and on one on the right is a
higher number and with some probability
and encrypt text so we now have a tool
to say if a certain text is encrypted
and then we need to move on to a
behavior analysis of that in order to
convert that into an actual detector
that helps
to find ransomware so we need to make a
prediction about what kind of entropy
values are associated with encryption
well we're looking at one grams so we're
looking at the Husky occurrence of ASCII
characters in our database those are
made up of eight bits to a bite of an
ascii character so if it is necessary
can go back yes so we expect to find in
the theoretical ideal case of proper
encryption eight bits of entropy for
this distribution and of course that the
files will use all the available
characters about equal is often so if
we're going to the next slide and we're
going to build a detector we're
measuring the one grams of these files
exchanges and this is going to be a
number between 0 and 8 bits of entropy
then if your radical model will say that
on top thank you perfect will I have all
the encrypted files well real world is
slightly more noisy so we're going to
add some bounce to this and then this is
the area where we'll find the encryption
yeah so we ask Gretchen is this actually
a good way to predict encryption so we
measure the entropy of a lot of
different files including encrypted
files which is bit noisy bits column on
the Left which indeed adheres to the top
of the file you have HTML files text
files programming files like biting code
or C++ code which is very regular as
words is better in two spaces use the
readable character so it's neatly in the
bound of sixty percent entropy about 5.5
bits but then there is this one file tab
which we found in our experiment that
really adheres to the top even better
than our encryption sample which are PNG
files which are media files and those
files are compressed files and
compressed files of course will also
have very high entropy because if it if
there's an easy way to predict what an
compressed file looked like then there's
probably a better way to compress it so
we need to find a behavioral methods
that takes an account entropy that will
indicate whether something is
but leaves out the false positives your
next slide of these compressed files and
that is where we started implementing a
real detector and dot's got to tell more
about this so the detection of
encryption is so something that we can
do but like we saw some basic high
entropy values aren't going to actually
help us so we know that we need to
actually find some sort of increase in
entropy in these exchanges that we've
already built and we also know that
encryption doesn't really change the
size of a file unlike compression which
is trying to compress a file and so
using these two characteristics we can
actually try and build some sort of
detection rule for just a encryption so
we did that and we found some
interesting numbers so here we have some
ransomware samples and some true
positive rates which basically mean only
encryption and these numbers aren't too
high only for jigsaw we had a really
nice true positive rate the reason that
the other ones aren't as high as mostly
because there were some files that were
too small and the increase in size was
marginally enough so that you would jump
over the detection rule threshold that
we had and for instance this users
actually really aggressive user that
does compression encryption some random
high entropy stuff because we scripted
him to be really aggressive because we
really wanted to test our our detection
rule but the important part here is that
we have no false positive rate and this
is because we pretty much excluded
anything but encryption or really random
stuff and that's only when you have a
file for instance that's has
really low entropy and then actually
increases like thirty percent and this
didn't occur so that's really nice so
I'm going to get the next slide yeah
thank you so now that we can detect
encryption on exchanges we can actually
try and see well okay is this traffic
that contains encryption is it actually
run somewhere or is it actually just the
user that's performing some encryption
and we can do this based on the rate of
encryption which is a fancy way of
saying the number of encryptions per
second and then using this we can
actually distinguish between run
somewhere and just a regular user so by
analyzing the rate of encryption of each
of these samples and using some
different time frames wherein which we
which we started with the first
encryption that we detect and then kind
of measuring until the time frame well
the time frame stops we can actually see
well okay is this transfer is a user
based on the number of alarms that went
off because they exceeded the required
number of encryptions so we have another
table what's interesting here is that
the user had mostly zeros this is
because the encryptions that the user
did were either far apart or just not
enough encryptions were performed within
the time span there's only one that
actually instance where we can actually
say okay the user is detected but if we
go to the next slide we can see well the
difference is so much that we could do a
second filter pass and then we would
still only have run somewhere that is
being detected by this detection rule
and so we can actually distinguish as we
can show here between a user a really
aggressive user and rent somewhere based
on this rate of encryption so what can
you actually use this for well first off
and somewhere and intrusion detection
system is
is a really obvious one but you could
also for instance block traffic from an
infected klein because SMB actually
contains the data from where the
messages are sent so you have an IP
address that you could block for
instance if you deem it as run somewhere
and another interesting feature that
could be implemented its backing up the
data that has been recently attacked
because you can store a buffer on our
passive listener with the files because
of the SMB data actually going through
our passive listener which also includes
the unencrypted data and then afterwards
you get the encrypted data you go back
you can actually back up the data and
then as soon as you block off the
infected traffic you can actually get
your files back without any hassle
because you already have the unencrypted
files so yeah next slide please any
questions also make sure to visit no
more ransom org and the spice web page
of the tue yes think we manage time
pretty well despite the technical issues
we're regressing on first row of things
let's see if listener did you use bro
yes or a battle we use silent defense
which is a it's being developed by a
company that's related to the TV I think
it's called security matters but it
could also be implemented in bro because
I actually also looked at bro but it was
kind of handed to us by the by the guys
that also work in the Department
this question over there I see that you
you guys are having done this in the
network level of detection have you
tried and the host based level since the
ransomware will basically hit the either
maybe and use the rocket station or
server do you think this can be done and
like in part of the antivirus or any
there's already some solutions that do
it on the host based level the reason
why we do it like this is because
network drives obviously don't have
their own host software so and also
ransom rack with for instance interfere
with the end of antivirus solution and
so by doing this having a passive
listener which can't really be
interfered with because you setup your
network as such you actually kind of
avoid having to deal with the rents from
are attacking your listener and
furthermore you can actually easily sort
of the we have a professor at the TV we
are always actually like an advocate for
just plugging something in and then not
looking at it again in a whole space
solution usually need some maintenance
and you would also have to implement
furnace for a company with 300 posts you
would have to deploy it on free honored
host while this could serve like a
single entity however your point that
the mechanics will work on a house based
system are completely correct that if
you find a way to find the exchanges
with in your house then our detection
rules would also apply to doing it on a
single machine to fight the infection
there another question when you compare
the like in like between the normal text
or statement and the encrypted one is it
going to be any difference if you guys
are if there is any other languages
any other like let's say I don't know
Chinese or something well you know they
have Ural probably not assuming that the
Chinese language and character set has
structure what what distinguish regular
files from the encrypted files is that
the encrypted files have bites
distribute distributed uniformly or at
least very close to uniformly which is
something that you're going to see very
rarely in normal files even in different
character sets it might happen
particularly for Chinese where for short
messages you will use only a limited set
of these characters and probably will
have messages with a lot of unique
characters that you might come across
some higher entropy files over there but
then it will still hold for a smaller
alphabet so it probably won't go to the
full eight bits of entropy but if your
messages hundred and twenty different
characters and only 120 different
characters long then you will probably
have seven bits of entropy and of course
across the threshold in our system move
there yeah thank you and suppose that
the developers of ransomware know about
your research would it be easy for them
to work around this method yeah actually
it's quite easy I've actually tested
this myself because this was for my
thesis and if you actually compress
before you encrypt you totally avoid any
detection at all because the entropy
will go up but the data size difference
will then avoid any detection because
we're trying to avoid detecting
compression and then if you encrypt
afterwards the entropy will not change
that much and the size won't change much
either but you just kind of avoided any
detection however if you're going to
defend against this thing usually you're
going to
do things that slow the rate of the
ransomware down which is advantageous in
combating it and our system in generic
sense is able to adapt to these things
so doing basics you for compression
which will make file longer and lower
the entropy is something that's very
well we find if you study the entropy
thing so it is adaptable to this
situation but of course your request
your question applies to any sort of
malware vs mt malware battle of which we
know it is incredibly hard to defend
against and some clever guys to come
around and do one change and he'll
change the system our advantage probably
over some of the things that exist out
there is that it is more behavioral
based and not based on some blacklist
where you just skip out of it so you
really have to find something to either
lower the entropy of your encryption
with this which either means using weak
encryption which is to our advantage or
doing something that is going to make it
more noisy or more slow to deploy your
end somewhere which probably is going to
be a better situation for defending
against but your point stands and
applies to most malware research I think
so any last question then we can go to
the next speaker no questions anymore
okay thanks very much cloudless and dawn