let's start the presentation I think I'm
the last one the presentation scheduled
today I'm Simone Han and I'm very
excited to share my research research
video this is my second visit to head in
the box as a speaker thank you for
inviting me again
in this presentation I'm going to talk
about the right to wait hypervisor rates
the color protector sheriff buck I'm a
senior stood with such a a-10s era of
South Korea and I was a speaker at
taking the past last year and
blackadeshi are in this year
I'm also an operating system and former
developer and author of a book series
titled 64 bits multi core operating
system principles and structures 41 and
volume to my goal of this presentation
first as I mentioned earlier I share my
right to eight hypervisor based color
protector Zarafa sheriff as concerns
less resourced and previous researches
and I made it from scratch second I also
share lessons learned from deploying and
operating shadow pass in real world many
epsilon researches are only focused on
laboratory environment so when you try
to apply them in real world you could
have many problems I have been operating
sheriff us since last year and I share
my experience third I introduced a
future plan Sheriff pass version to
sheriff was version still can support
and a very suspect on concurrently this
is the content page first I will tell
you a background of my researches and
second I will tell you how I design and
implement the sheriff up third iris
share the lessons learned and show a
demo finally I will introduce Peter for
official flame and some of my
as you know this color is everywhere
from suburbs and titties to mobile
devices and credit cards and you know
Connor suffered from Nauticus and
security vulnerabilities unfortunately
devices which use risk Connor could
share the security threat and the street
stress often combined with other threads
to take control systems although you
already have a protection mechanism in
color level fundamentally the mechanisms
do not protect Connor from the security
threat and the mechanism often easily
bypassed them neutralized by color
objects cooking and direct color of the
demonstration technique therefore
protections need an even lower level I
call this link minus one this is very
litigious and resolve color objects
which are modified by row ticket revenue
to keys normally change code system
table function pointers process list and
module is the descendants of Vera Lucas
are also similar have similar patterns
he exploits tend to get looted privilege
and little kids tend to hide their
malicious behavior as you know the
attacker means Ruta frivolous towards
good kid therefore I often that the
attacker already has has beautiful
ability using exploits and in this
presentation I only focused on Logic II
to take the higher ground than Connor
level I reverie fossilization technology
in processor
polarization technology separates a
machine into a horse
Chico word and of gas normal world the
horse has a link - one label each and
can freely accept and control the gas
intel vt-x and AMD be an oxygen
kekeke are 50/50 hardware this is
traditional architecture leveraging
fertilization technology the whole
monitors and controls the gas through
the photon radiation technology and the
murmur of the gas can now move to the
hole because of fertilization technology
work unfortunately I'm not the only man
who find the benefit of fossilization
technology there were so many researches
using it for protecting color from
warriors so things that I did not need
to research on this field but after
studying about previous works I thought
that they droop like these object 7 and
15 and t1 link can you get the common
points of the these objects yeah the
common point of this object is a myth I
heard and knew about them but I cannot
find in real world I agree that previous
worlds are excellent and I want to use
them but I don't know where they are if
you know about them please email me
thank you
so I think that they become zombies
because of these reasons first many
researches have preconditions which RV
which gr has to be prepared in
real-world environments they change
color code or hypervisor code directly
and need whereon hashes of loadable
kernel module and connotative liquor vm
and so on second many researches
consumers research they run OS is in
each word and consume many features
occurred to introspect the gas because
of cement
gasps semantic gap comes from the gap
between a logical address from all the
gas and sister page of the point the
whole can only access this core page of
the gas therefore if the horse wants to
introspect guests object the horse
should convert the test roster draft to
host teacher page this behavior causes
many table services and consumers
research in conclusion previous
researches and a suitable for real-world
environment as you know real world
environment is totally different from
laboratory environments and you even
don't know the actual environment before
your software is in third so we feel
like that dear world this is the real
world environment - like Serengeti I
think that practical and lightweight
mechanism is needed for real-world
environments and I started to make it
from scratch through years ago as I
mentioned previous security conference I
should not have started because it has
been a hard work so many problems are
there and I should serve the problem
alone so I regret now anyway this is
designer of my color protector fourth I
focus on lightweight loser Kitty textual
and protection mechanism and I also
focus on super memory problems second I
try not to modify code directly for
deployment and I designed the colored
protector to load any time design page
this is shadow play UTA dings early
childhood and yes everyone knows about
it the burbs and lied to the actors and
the shadows of actors are reflected in a
screen over there my coworker and I
watched the shadow and understand the
story of shadow plane one day suddenly I
realized that this architecture could be
applied in security can you guess how
can I fly yes I will show you the verb
is Lin minus one protection mechanism I
call this light box
and the actors are activities in OS and
I am the secret monitor I curled his
shadow watcher so I named my color
protector shadow box because I was
inspired by the shadow plane this is
more detailed architectural shuttle-bus
like the box lightweight hypervisor
creates a gas which alone OFDM is and
creates a horse which share this color
with the gas
conceptually like the fact that
read-only permission to most part of the
gas Connor and then leader right
permission to the host Connor
therefore shuttle faster the real Connor
between the host and the gas
the color modification of the gas can be
prevented and cannot affect the host
Connor
shadow water over there the key to
monitor controls and monitors OS in the
gas using right back right the path like
the weight hypervisor isolate the gas
from the horse by using memory
protection techniques in 3t
for writing for errors the color between
the host and the gas therefore is shared
it has 4 memory 15 due to sharing color
the right path
easily notes the logical address of
Connor objects and easily convert the
gas protocol address to hope to teach
her pain in some case you just use words
to Phoebe's color function to find the
pitch carpe to not to tremor the page
table so like the facts have narrow
semantic gap
additionally like the passage loadable
kernel module so it can be loaded
anytime therefore you can load it when
you need it
shuttle water monitors the monitors dog
gas by using right back any of this
event-driven ways and theory ways to
monitor the gas event-driven way is used
for checking static immutable objects
such as code system cable and IDT tables
filigree is used for checking dynamic
and beautiful objects such as process Li
modules from a lot of O'Connor modulus
and function pointers this is summary
page of design so walking shuttle back
to fourth shadow box protects color from
static color objects attacks i defined
static color objects are immutable in
long time
therefore technical objects of tests can
be code modification attacks and system
table modification attack second solo
passage protects
color from dynamic color objects attacks
i define dynamic color objects are
immutable in runtime therefore dynamic
color object objects can be processed
hiding module hiding and function
pointer modification attacks from this
page I will show you how i implement
Cheryl facts as you know no Mary
implementation pack had so many detailed
information therefore I share cool
information of sheriffís because of the
time
if you want to know more detailed
information about the fraud please check
my paper as I mentioned earlier
shuttlepod is a rotary color module and
shadow pass is loaded after setting
name's Connor therefore because of these
boot sequence I use another mechanism
secure boot to ensure integrity of boot
process deeper shadow past efforts
secure boot and shadow paths are rowdy
like the pass code is cos and prepares
an environment for virtualization after
that it separates the gas from the horse
and like the past vision the guest OS
lastly it such Sharon watcher shadow
water monitors and the Immortals of
Michael zucchet after sheriff of this
lorry or process is long within the gas
not the whole technical objects are
immutable
therefore technical objects protection
use uses specifically protection
techniques to protect escapades
efficiently if you keep as long as
extended page table in Entebbe TV and
DMA remapping reporting table as known
as eMAR table in integrity XR cues I'll
show you if 81st and DMARC a greater
like this apt math test physical address
to host the peach coral dress and set
new permission
sheriff us says leave a mess to the
permission to set the color objects like
this and I Curtis platinum sheriff a
said no permission filter
I call this hiding as you know oh sorry
ed you know Luke Sookie can modify
permissions of page table in the gap but
the gas cannot change the permissions of
EPT so as a result
Lucas cannot modify the Seconal objects
this is a detailed view of memory
protection length of the part of the
page shows address translation between
cash flow through Dresden get the peach
color dress like the five lights right
I'm sorry right part of the page shows
all the translation between Catholic
Easter addressed and hosted redress if
the kids impact the system they affect
physical face like directory or paste
favoring the gas to change coding system
same idea
this is typical effect but
permissions of ATP over eyes permissions
of gasps episcopate like this
therefore these objects are presented by
EPT this is another memory protection
technique using DMA are traveling on the
VDD DMA our table is more complicated
than a PT however basic structure and
concepts are same as a PT DNA our table
and the DAR table map DMA or DMA address
to physical address and set euphemisms
like the fact that no permission to set
color objects and Shadowfax for
presenting VMA attacks DMA our table can
be prevented by EPT so write the path
last eMAR table to prevent unauthorized
modifications dynamic color objects are
mutable therefore sort of a standard use
memory protection techniques so instead
of a shuttle bus monitors dynamic kernel
objects and check them periodically
process and module is our typical
dynamic color objects and Lucas modifies
the reads to hide themselves to protect
lists like this so nobody uses Hardware
breakpoints to on create and delete
function of process and modules when the
research change set of paths catches the
event and synchronizes with in it then
it compares these of the gas we had a
list of Zarephath periodically using BM
preemption timer
function pointers could be also dynamic
Connor objects and little kids modified
them to hide themselves and to manage
these behaviors to protect function
pointers sort of apps check if they
point to the barely the color of the
website or not periodically the concept
of general policy to protect loaded
color and this means that function
pointers should be sure to point to the
inside of color code of a most model
code if the function pointers point to
the outside of them like this for
example module code which is loaded
after Cheryl fact they are invalid
function pointers that you can dynamic
color object protection are important
but for ensuring operating system
integrity interactions between color and
user prevalence should be also
protecting x86 processor has many
clearly related registers and system
table therefore shadow pass protects
them using VT and memory rot technique
to be honest these are minor techniques
so if you want to know them more please
check my paper and ok this is the result
of Welland escape detection so we just
showed that Shannon Fox can detect all
of variants of the kid successfully and
yesterday is the performance measurement
history dirty this is the result of
performance measurement of prototype I
use test machine which has entered I
seven four seven nine zero CPU and 32
gigabyte RAM and 512 s SP for
measurements set per sec and color
compiled research shows from 1% to 10%
overhead in comparison with bare metal
machines in color compare case which has
wear mix the iota
suja 5.3% in single core processor
environment and it's point two percent
in multi-core processor environment I
think these are redeliver overhead and
he's over has to another affect the user
experience all right so let's the London
demo I think these are the highlights of
my presentation so when I finish this to
implement from type of shadow box I was
proud of myself and I thought I was
ready to run shit so credibly I deployed
shadow box in real world and I'm at the
feast of real world such as - as you
know the first positive slow down and
system hang and ATP previously purchased
did not tell me something important and
I have struggled against the Beast alone
time he's our resident long from
deploying and operating Shadowfax in
year world
last one Cody area and when Connor is
not immutable previous research is often
that cold area is immutable but it is
not true I don't know you know Connor
has config jumper every option and this
option is set by default in measuring of
the throat if this option is dead
feels Conor passive is def on long time
freak entities and this code is complete
with Connor protector so
one solution of this program is that you
add exceptional cases for mutable
contain but this may cause another
ticket program therefore I recommend if
possible to love consistent labor option
and rebuild your color right now lesson
2 cache type in if it is very important
and you should be attached I carefully
depending on the physical page type
previous research is only focused on
page permissions of EPT but if you have
test type field for page and you should
also consider at least every system has
its own memory map and memory memory
mapped i/o area should be handled
carefully memory mapped i/o area
interacts with the hardware therefore
the data written in this area should
transfer to Hardware immediately because
of this reason memory mapped i/o area
except uncatchable type if you miss
configured this type it's among the feed
from the health such as the system hang
slowdown and some undetectable errors so
solution is that you set on cacheable
type to all physical face by deferred
and LED light effect i-26 emblem area
system lam area are typically used for
code and data and this should be set
right back type for system performance
this is the memory map of my testimony
it shows many information of our memory
area and almost memory area except
system lam our memory mapped i/o so many
memory mapped i/o so let's catch type of
apt depending on system memory map like
this lessons we multi-core environment
is very complicated each core modified
process leads and modulus concurrently
when how do we were at appointed section
or the impression timer interrupt
occurred and Shannon Fox tried to check
them other course could be changing them
already therefore you need a mechanism
for synchronization as or so sorry
synchronizing this data solution is that
you use has gridlock and module mutex of
the cache for incrementation so now I
have been operating shuttle button near
word successfully as a matter of fact
sheriff us is not for effect because it
had some compatibility issues but I have
been upgrading general fact for years
and I will continue to update shuttle
pass all right I will show some demo
video to videos
the first demo shows typical taxable
tickets
demo motion has only color level
protection mechanism such as light
protection and the little key can
utilize some mechanism and do malicious
behavior the attacker prepares our
little kid as you can see the little
kiddies in the ticket directory and now
the attacker opens that door
super command negative reduce the fifth
command and however this is not perfect
because the user can find the process in
process Li like this the attacker was
solicitous to hide the better process
for our research I operated order a next
generation little kids to support the
recent color version and I also added a
new horrible I stared binary the better
process is invisible now
and the attacker hi sorry to keep
directory for perfect crime this is the
command and command it's finished
successfully
students after death row ticket
directory is also invisible all right so
so we must attack her as you know do
everything through the actual port the
motorcycle can connect the vector cross
and he can control the beating you see
as you can see he that the most
privileged and that's the shadow vessel
from the PC yeah this is skip the demo
and the next one is slightly front
all right the second demo is almost same
as previous demo except shadow-puppet
learning so user clicks are Shadowfax
and I mentioned earlier shadow passes
loadable kernel module therefore you can
load the user can load shadow box using
in some of the comments like this now
sort of box is activated and the Conner
protection mechanisms of the static
Conner aesthetic and dynamic color
object protections are working the same
as previous demo the attacker also
prepare the rootkit and the researcher
is in the root directory and the second
is opening effect or
and process in perfectly
and finally the attacker Rose educates -
hi vector process but the rooted kids
cannot be loaded and accommodation for
to occur before though before because of
shadow fun shuttle flights also draw
information in kernel log for shuttle
pass detected memory otech of Sentinel
objects like this the desire of address
of second object and second shadow pass
detected the serum process backdoor over
the effector is hidden and binary
Shadowfax detective student module like
this although our next generation or the
ranging as you have seen general facts
can protect your PC from no tikis
future work and conclusion mr. work this
is current status of shallow path and
this is necessarily a robot I have been
making shadow path version to forearm
and I have almost finished it so far
forearm platform serves the architecture
of shadow box for inter platform
typically and processors are ready
powerful than desktop processors and AM
processors are used which are used for
mobile environment therefore sheriff ask
for arm has new features such as walkers
concerned monitoring mechanism and
limits of hesitation for the best check
state of check
yeah this is super architecture of
shuttle bus from Shadowfax program uses
open source trusted execution
environment which follows the Cee
specification of global platform Samsung
and Kirkham also follows it therefore
the architecture of shadow box version 2
can be ported various Vee oh my god the
right path consists of trusted Conner
and trusted application and
shallow-water consists of trusted
application and number world application
the right apart shuttle water client
over there collaborates with a right
path and shuttle water application in
sitio world through the SMT curve as
inch core is for path of the unfrocked
journey so I hope to present the sheriff
up version 2 and platform and massive
speed conference and then the detailed
information and for source code will
observe as we will be options alright
conclusion
aho yes first current level threat
should be protected in more privileged
level such as hypervisor and second
shuttle bus is lightweight and practical
solution for protecting your corner from
the second and third
your word is guarantee so you have a
strong mentality for defeating your not
sufficient obvious if you don't have
some mentality you will shut up but
instead
oh yeah this is the last page of my
presentation thank you for reasoning and
these are my email address email address
and projector link presearch shuttlepod
for f-86 at github.com
my project Shadowfax is open source so I
always always welcome your contributions
such as Public Works or more for patches
and so on if you have any idea of a
shuttlepod
feel free to mmm you thank you thank you
again
Oh so any caption thank you check out
thank you any questions from the
audience
hi yeah do we use this shadow box on
your own machines - yeah yeah ah this
machine unfortunately its emotionalism
back so Shadowfax is version version 1
only support Linux distros so you can
use Ubuntu or Federer or something
server that you run it on for example if
you have a v-neck shirt from somewhere
this double ah you could run a shadow
box on it ah
unfortunately so this version of shadow
box
target target is the desktop version of
really froze so I just only tested you
know polymer desktop and notebook
any other questions
thank you hi so it's only for x86 not in
32 bits or is dosa for x86 64 om de 64
yeah good question
this version of shadow path only support
X 60 64 not exit next 33 X 8 32 P is not
the 49 last one anymore
thank you guys for more plus for
shipment