thank you
foreign
younger
Bionic reasons
you're right we give you uh your tax
money get out of my head
I like what those things um
come on there
[Music]
foreign
and do the hosted q a so as always you
can go on slido I will pop that link in
Discord as well and we'll have the QR
code that comes up and you can add
questions from now as the speakers talk
and then
they will kick in after the talks so our
moderator is
a long time North SEC volunteer with
more than 15 years of experience in
information security finance
uh so that was that was very bilingual
awesome
impressive thank you welcome everyone so
I will introduce our first speaker suira
who has been doing malware analysis and
reverse engineering for the last 10
years in addition to that she's also a
volunteering in her community both
participating in cyberages and black
hoodie so welcome and
so thanks Miramar uh yes so hello
everyone uh hello North SEC thank you
for having me I'm really excited to talk
about my research on tracking
Bumblebee's development
as you know my name is Sue I'm a
security researcher at crowdstrike
so our talk today we are going to look
at different timelines on the
development of different bumblebee
components
some may not be a parent right now what
we'll notice is that the developers they
like to focus on different EDR evasion
techniques some of which are worth
mentioning so we'll talk about those as
well
and then finally at the end we'll draw a
conclusion about what these timelines
can teach us about the developers and
how they approach developing a malware
I do want to note that crowdstrike's
name for the malware as seen in the
intelligence reporting is called shindig
but I will continue to use bumblebee
throughout this talk
so before we're going to look at Dev
timelines we are going to first get a
really quick history about Bumblebee so
quick uh just a quick chronology
timeline here so how did it all start
so it was first reported in March 2022
by the Google tag team the researchers
they observed this new loader being used
by Affiliates Kuba previously associated
with conti and that's also how they gave
it its name the string bumblebee was
seen in a user agent header when it made
requests to the server
now these same Affiliates they use the
similar loader in a campaign they were
targeting in August of 2021 that's the
cve they were targeting and it was later
reported by Microsoft in September of
that year but that loader though it
didn't have the bot like capabilities it
was only used for spreading cobolt
strike so when we're looking at our
timelines we are going to focus on
bumblebee when it started off as a bot
so the start date we believe to be 31st
Jan 2022 and for the purpose of This
research it's until first of March this
year
so as you see here shortly after the
first report bumblebees activities
started picking up three major
Affiliates who have been seen using it
from the beginning more major Affiliates
joined down the line and there were some
smaller ones but it's not shown here on
the graph
and you also see that they're used by
the likes distributed by the likes of
smoke bot and batloader so it's quite a
popular malware
so what is Bumblebee like right now when
it infects a victim's machine like what
does that life cycle look like
so as with most malware it starts off
with the loaders the way uh top there
you see in the flow it's encrypted it's
packed it unpacks on malware in
Bumblebee's case the unpacked file is
always a dll so once unpacked it can
communicate with the server to receive
commands that it needs to run on the
machine bumblebee calls these commands
as tasks they are abbreviated
three-leaded strings and they're
lettered in such a way that you can
deduce the meaning behind each task so
take for instance the one in the very
bottom here sdl stands for silent delete
it's yeah so it removes the malware
removes itself from the machine
I won't go through this list yet because
we will touch on tasks again at a later
point
now I'll unpack dll2 it has another
embedded file in it it's called The Hook
module it's using conjunction with two
of the tasks and we'll see that later on
in the talk as well and finally
bumblebee is modular in nature that
means it can run different plugins on
the machine that it gets from the server
and those plugins too can communicate
with the server
so from this image we are looking at
three different timelines our first
timeline will look at the development
that's been put into the loader and the
dll the second one you know changes that
we have seen to the communication
protocol over time and then finally the
third timeline is just going to look at
tasks
so here we have is a first Gantt
timeline chart so the way it works is
from left to right it goes in
chronological order so starting from
31st Jan 2022 until first of March this
year and from top to bottom you can see
uh the list of techniques that the
malware uses in in part of its loader
where it's bought I didn't list all
those techniques here because it would
be impossible to fit it all in the slide
but this is just to give you an idea of
how long those techniques were used and
the duration
now before I talk about you know this uh
timeline here I do want to mention about
Bumblebee's binaries uh just in general
so Bumblebee's main dll the unpacked
file and its plugins they use you'll
notice they use a lot of functions from
the Boost Library boost is an open
source C plus plus Library it is header
based that means any program using boost
ends up statically compiling a lot of
those functions in its binary and it
also explains why Bumblebee's files are
quite big in size
so as you see here from the start when
bumblebee started it didn't have a
loader it was actually quite it didn't
have anything packing it was unencrypted
it was unpacked this now might likely be
it's um like a way for the developers to
test the bot and the loader actually
came much later into play by end of
March and as we saw in the previous
timeline it was around the time the
malware was picking up activity
so despite you know even though they're
just testing the malware they did though
have what we believe to be an EDR
evasion technique so this technique was
where it would hook the API RTL exit
user process
so the API was only hooked if there was
an existing EDR or AV hook on that API
in this case the malware's trampoline
code would make sure that bumblebee
finished executing its thread before
control went back to the EDR likely to
prevent the you know the antivirus from
scanning or analyzing the process any
further
they did though Swap this technique for
another EDR Vision called thread
execution hijacking by end of June 2022
um I think yeah but in my opinion a much
better EDR evasion we'll see why in the
later slide
now when the loader was introduced it
wasn't only like useful encrypting a
packer Amino dll it too had an EDR
evasion it's called remote Library
injection and that too we'll see again
right after this slide
the developers as well they played with
a different form of a loader and and in
fact it also gave them another EDR
evasion so they would use power sploid's
reflective dll injection and this was
something they introduced after they
came back from their first break but now
we see it more when they came back from
the second break and it's more used in
cases for SEO poisoning and malvertising
finally I want to touch on Alcazar so
alcazer is this repository in GitHub it
contains all these different techniques
and one can use for doing anti-analysis
checks on the machine and Bumblebee uses
almost all of those checks and so they
were using the alcaza report quite
aggressively like at the beginning of
the malware's execution and as you can
see like for a really long period of
time but then interestingly they just
dropped it like two weeks before going
on their second break it wasn't really
clear why but then after coming back
from the second break they they
reintroduced it but in a completely
different context so we'll see that more
when we look at the C2 communication
now we have our first EDR evasion here
this is used by the loader
so the purpose of this technique is to
actually masquerade bumblebees unpacked
dll to appear running as a legitimate
dll in memory here you see the
screenshot or process Explorer you can
see the active threads of bumblebees
process the one highlighted there the
active thread it's pointing to this
Library called dim's room it's actually
a Windows system library of Windows now
it's in this case it's not the system
Library that's running behind the scenes
is actually Bumblebee the One giveaway
here is it's referencing that export
function called setpath that belongs to
our malware
now this technique is done by first
hooking apis that are used by ntdll for
loading and mapping libraries in memory
generally those apis perform the
operation against a file on disk but by
hooking the API they can control it
against an unpacked file in memory so
quite clever
but this you know proof of concept isn't
new it was introduced back in 2004 and
there's a link to it at the bottom for
those that can see the slide
and which goes into detail explaining it
and and also the only other malware that
we were able to find using the same the
same technique was ramnet and it's also
pointed out in one of IBM's blogs now
this is not all to say that you know the
developers were necessarily aware of the
POC or were the same group as ramnet but
it's quite common in e-crime to see a
lot of these groups borrow techniques
and reuse techniques and um yeah so it's
nothing necessarily new but it seems to
work for their case
next off we have is the thread execution
hijacking so this is the EDR evasion
used by unpacked LL
now this technique's purpose is to
masquerade bumblebees start offset in
memory to appear under a decoy offset
and and they point that offset to that
of this really long named API that's
part of ntdll so similarly you have the
same screenshot here and you have one of
these other active threads it's showing
that the API is running but as you can
guess it's actually a malware
now this technique is done by first or
it creates the API as a thread in
suspended mode and when the thread is
suspended the malware can modify the
thread's context structure in that
structure there's a field that specifies
a start routine it would normally point
to the API it just swaps it for the
malware so it effectively just spoops
the edr's call stack so it appears that
an API is running but actually it's the
malware that's running behind the scenes
now this technique is generally used for
process injection and there's a really
good entry in miter attack that shows
other malware families using it
in my case I was trying to find a
similar POC where it's used in within
the same process because it wasn't
really injected into any external
process I had no luck I actually thought
this was something novel by this group
but then I come across this other blog
where they show cozy Bears a Dropbox
loader using the same technique and
coincidentally they use the same decoy
API name so of all the API names that
could be out there so again you know
clearly they borrowed another technique
here
now that we've learned about the load
and dll let's look at the C2
communication so before I show the
timeline I just want to explain what
Bumblebee's protocol is like right now
so the malware uses secure web sockets
the messages it creates to the for the
server and receive from the server then
Json format and they're rc4 encrypted
the key of which is embedded in our
unpacked dll file
here's a description of what these
messages look like they're very
truncated it's not the full version but
just to give a sense of what it is and
I've labeled them as ping hidden tasks
just to understand and the flow better
as I explain it but these are not the
names given by the malware
now bumblebee they have a beaconing
style communication so these messages
you see they get sent in a loop
constantly this is quite common in a lot
of e-crime families you see it also with
bog Bots and CAC Bots and so the payload
is not immediately delivered to the
victim machine it's delivered at an
undetermined period of time so that
makes it harder for analysts like us to
pull down any payload and also makes it
just harder for the victim to realize
that they were infected
um now so let's explain what these
messages mean so now the whole point of
Bumblebee's ping request is to send
across the Bots ID to the server and in
turn from the server it will get a
session ID
that session ID is used in throughout
the other request messages and likely
it's for the malware's back end to keep
track of what messages get sent out and
finally if there's any commands for the
malware to execute it'll arrive in the
task type response message and as you
learn task is the three-lettered command
and along with any payload for the
malware to execute
now what about the hit request here in
the middle
that is where alcazer comes into play so
okay sir as we learned from the first
timeline you know is this report on
GitHub contains different Tech
techniques one can do for anti-analysis
checks well uh bumblebee don't do those
checks at the beginning of execution now
they will run those checks only when it
receives the go-to from the server that
go to is in the Ping response there's a
Boolean field in there called Hit if the
server sends the hit value is true it
will run these checks and then it will
send
um you know the out the results of those
checks in this really long Json message
contains different Boolean Fields across
to the server and accordingly the server
will drop the connection if it thinks
there's any if it's running in the VM or
any anti-analysis artifacts now the
developers they didn't only settle with
using alcazo they do some of their own
checks like the classic trying to look
for active processes in the machine and
and this one in particular this field
here called binary DB
that one contains a base64 encoded SQL
database of browsing history that they
query from chrome and Ms Edge in
particular so now you have a really
clever way of checking like if your
machine is indeed a Sandbox or Victim
Because uh you know sandbox is less
likely to have browsing history
I don't want to note that now we see
these new bills in April where this
check has been dropped but not
completely because we still see
Affiliates using older builds so not
every communication will necessarily be
exfiltrating browsing history
now in the event that bumblebee gets a
task from the server it will it will
also send a result of running the task
in a separate type message sorry it's
right behind me here and that just
contains you know any errors that may
have been encountered by running the
task or any information that was
exfiltrated by running the task
so looking at the Timeline is actually
being quite a fair bit of changes over
time till it got to where it is now it's
a bit harder to follow so I found that
just by grouping it on these certain
properties here again right behind me
it makes it a bit more easier to follow
so let's go from the beginning at the
start
so when bumblebee first started they
used actually an https protocol and of
course it's Infamous usage and string
bumblebee now the messages that was sent
across it was only the task message so
not the Ping and the hit that we saw on
the previous slide
the client version number was one you
know of course first iteration and the
endpoint string that I made a request to
was called gate
Now by mid-april they decided to
randomize the user agent pattern and
this was also the time you started
seeing more public blogs coming out
about Bumblebee and Bumblebee was a bit
too obvious of a user agent name but
that was clearly short-lived because in
early may they decided to switch it up
so they randomized the user agent they
started encrypting the task message and
we see rc4 Keys come in play the
endpoint string it changed from gate to
gate s s may be their way of saying
secure no idea
um and then okay so now the next stage
so a month after they came from their
first break they switched the protocol
this is now where they started using web
sockets and we also see the introduction
of the Ping type message the endpoint
string a change from gate s to gate w
and the client version number was two
and now where we are at and something
they've introduced after their second
break is you know we see the three
messages the only difference is the user
agent string is this hard-coded value
here the bottom of the slide uh it's not
randomized anymore and maybe it's like
the attempt at trying to make traffic
look a bit more legitimate
that brings us to the final one tasks
so
here on the left hand side okay the
screen is like gone off here but on the
left hand side you can see is a
description of what the three-letter
tasks mean and on the right hand side is
a really high level overview on how they
get executed by the malware now our
first four tasks are what are
responsible for executing payloads the
post three of which does injects the
payload into processes so bumblebee can
either inject shell codes or dll and if
it is a dll it could be either secondary
payloads in the dll format so like
Cobalt strike blockbot or or it could be
dlls of their plugins which are also in
the dll format
now if it's injecting payloads it uses
the apcq code injection technique and
it's also injected along with the hook
module both of which have an EDR evasion
role behind it so I will expand on them
at a later slide
now bumblebee can execute payloads just
by itself no injection needed that's the
Dex task gdt allows the malware to run
commands likely for reconnaissance
instead of invoking it directly through
command.xc it's passed to command.xe
standard input output nothing malicious
is actually a common programming
technique but it just prevents the user
from getting notified that these
commands are running in the background
the malware can install itself on the
machine AKA create persistence it uses a
wmi to do create those artifacts and
finally sdl silent delete the malware
can remove itself and it uses Powershell
to do that
and now we have a final timeline
so let's start off with the persistence
task install ins
so now when this task was used in the
beginning it didn't use wmi it used your
regular Windows API like create
directory you know they create those uh
artifacts on the machine uh the switch
to wmi came about early May and it was
actually quite a clever shift because
now it will create those persistence
files uh using command line strings but
with wmi it could it would create the
yeah it would create a command.xc using
wmi a result of doing that ends up
showing command.xc's process as a child
process of the wmi parent process rather
than of the malware process so
effectively they achieve parent PID
spoofing so quite clever and it's a bit
more harder to monitor
now this same task the weight is
implemented to deferred based on which
loader is being used so as we learned in
the first timeline you know it's either
power sploit so it starts off as a
Powershell file or it could be an
encrypted loader so if it was using
power sploit
um the malware just uses Windows DP API
to encrypt the contents of the file so
this likely prevents antivirus from
scanning the contents and you know and
being like oh whoa this looks like
Powershell like commands and from
blocking it then accordingly bumblebee
creates a task that will run a script
which uses DP API to decrypt it before
running
none of the loader was you know
unexecutable to start off with it was
already encrypted already packed it
didn't need DP API and then you know
just used a living off the land binary
or ABC conf to execute the dll
next off we have is gdt the one that can
execute commands they introduced this in
early may as well it was a it was
implemented pretty in a simple manner in
fact it was so simple that it matched
exactly that with the msdn's example on
how to achieve the same technique but it
only allowed them to run one command at
a time so I wasn't aware that they were
testing it but then by end of May they
switched they started using boost dot
asio library to implement the same
technique the only difference with using
boost was it allowed them to run
multiple commands asynchronously
so here you see it's just a screenshot
of what the pipe name gets created as a
result of using boost.asio so not
malicious again but quite useful for
hunting and also at the end of the name
you'll see concatenated to it is the PID
so it's the process that invoked this
technique to start off with
and then finally let's touch on plg the
task
so plg is what allows
which introduce plugins for the malware
yeah and that was also introduced around
the time they switched to websockets so
they made quite a big changes after
their first break nothing too fancy but
they needed a way to get the plugins to
communicate with the Bots and so they
created an RPC endpoint we are named
pipes that allows for inter-process
communication nothing malicious popular
programming technique but you know it's
just useful to be aware of now the
plugins via this endpoint they can they
can query for the active C2 address
fine okay
okay for the active C2 address and Port
that they need to connect to
okay so try and go as quickly as I can
okay so let's talk on this injection
technique that's used by tasks so APC is
actually getting quite popular uh among
malware authors and there's a miter
attack at the bottom of the slide if you
can see it that lists other families
using it so why is this popular so every
thread in a process has an APC it's a
queue anything that's at and anything
that gets added to that queue is
executed when the thread thread enters
an alertable state
so Bumblebee as you can tell and most
other malware families they like to take
advantage of this so in Bumblebee's case
they'll just create the process in the
suspended mode inject the payload and
add an offset to the payload to the
threads apcq so then as the thread is as
the process is resumed it ends up
executing the code and also they modify
the entry point of the process by adding
instructions that call sleepex in the
loop because sleepex helps to uh set the
thread into that state into the
alertable state
and in addition these processes are
created with wmi and as we've learned
achieves parent PID spoofing
next off is the hook module that's
injected along with the dlls so the
purpose of this is module is to remove
EDR hooks on apis it comes with a list
of hard-coded apis in the binary and it
looks through all those apis so it
Compares those apis instructions in
memory to its instructions on this
physical file on disk because AV is
likely to hook on an API more in memory
it doesn't hook it in disk so it
Compares it using a length disassembler
which calculates the length of each
instruction and it also compares the
prefix and accordingly you know the
length or prefix is different it means
it's hooked in which case it just copies
over the bytes in the physical file to
the to its instructions in memory
effectively removing the hook finally it
uses remote Library injection to load
the payload to appear running as a
legitimate dll so this was the very same
technique used by the loader as well
so I'll quickly expand on this uh the
the function that uses uh the length
disassemble function it borrows a lot
from this open source Library called lip
splice I just wanted to point out it's
quite popular among other families that
have been seen uh and again just to show
that you know it's nothing something
they've implemented on their own and
they're just using some existing code
out there
and that finally brings us to our
conclusion speed mode
so what do these timelines teach us so
from these timelines it helps us to map
the activity of bumblebees software
development life cycle
so clearly the developers they have an
agile methodology with how they go about
building this malware so we see that
right off from the beginning especially
that period in the start 31st Jan until
31st March 2022 that was uh you know the
first release of our malware it was
quite simple it didn't have the loader
was an encrypted and packed and this is
an agile tombs would be called an MVP
which is a minimal viable product and
that's where you know they're testing
out you'll also see this in a lot of
forums underground forums when authors
are trying to sell their malware product
they're like they have some beta version
or an MVP version and it's kind of
hilarious it's kind of like the
crowdfunding for getting the malware
project off the ground but not to say
that we saw the same activity with
bumblebee but just by observing the
bills over time you can see this you can
imagine what that's like
and it's also clear because the second
phase of their release was what
introduced EDR evasion and that was you
know at the end of March when they
introduced the loader and it also had an
EDR vision and we even see three major
Affiliates using it and makes sense
because if you're going to make your
malware live you want to make sure that
it's not detectable
now apart from all of that we also
noticed that these developers they like
to focus on the C2 infrastructure during
the Hiatus in our heads we think of
Hiatus as a break but no they are not on
a break they're on a break from
Distributing the malware this makes
sense because if they're going to you
know
build a new malware they want to make
sure that it's able to communicate with
the back end that works and so it makes
sense why they're going on a break and I
believe right now they're probably on
their third break because I haven't seen
much activity
the developers too they seem to step out
of the norm with how they've gone
building out this malware we don't see
the use of API hashing or string
obfuscation that's actually quite common
now that might likely be the result of
how they are using EDR evasion so as we
saw with the loader and without dll it
spoofs the Edo's call stack and makes it
appear that our malware is running as a
dll or as an API so you know if your
antivirus doesn't think that that memory
space is malicious because it thinks
it's a dll API it's less likely to scan
it and then Yar rules in this case at
this point would be quite useless
um and then finally you know they
clearly have some mature Dev practices
on how they go about doing things
especially the fact that they're using
boost boost you know it's it's open
source but it's very popular in the C
plus Community but it's not commonly
seen in malware and uh useful building
malware there are a few out there but
not common you don't even see them using
Game cheats and and you can guess why
it's quite big in size and quite bulky
but the fact that this is mature is
because they're clearly familiar with
something that is quite common for a
community and they use it I mean they
communicate with the C2 and with the in
the gdt task command and also the fact
that they're using the open source
Library lib splice that's quite common
in splicing you know it's been around
for almost a decade and it makes sense
like if you're going to modify an API in
memory you better know what you're doing
so might as well use something that
works and is quite capable to achieve
the task
so yeah that's about it hope you all
enjoy it and I look forward to questions
during the panel thank you
[Applause]
thanks everyone we will start again in
roughly five minutes so if you want to
change rooms or even move a bit forward
in the room so that you leave more space
for others coming in
see you in five minutes
[Music]
okay
foreign
[Music]
come on there
foreign
morning for for about a week and they
give more detail and say that there was
a malicious uh
attachment with the macro and then it
led to a lower based malware dependency
so according to our visibility most high
profile targets for this cyber spinach
campaign were located in Eastern Europe
around Ukraine and we noticed that the
group was especially interesting
interested in diplomats and people are
working at Ministry of Foreign Affairs
in various countries in this region
so here are examples of malicious
documents that the group has used so the
one of on the left is use some
traditional VBA macro while the one on
on the right that was used if I remember
correctly in June 2022
um against
[Music]
um
growing staff of Moldova so this one was
using the Foreigner vulnerability which
is CV 2022
30190 so it's a vulnerability that leads
to code execution in Microsoft Office
and this one was discovered just few few
weeks before it was used
um so it it shows that the real zombies
schedule is like looking for for new for
new compromise vector
so what's the infection chain first
start with a spearfishing Imaging
um as I just shown then it's a manifest
Office document for example XLS
attachment with a VBA macro
that then download the MSI installer
that will drop the sunset downloader
which is a Lua bus
downloader and then the resistance is
established by dropping a lnk file into
a startup folder
but there is a chain doesn't stop there
so Sunset is a downloader and can
download additional scripts in in Lua
and one of those scripts
is responsible for downloading the next
stage
which is
more or less the same thing as Sunset
but in ottawatki so it's again a
downloader in Auto add key and see this
time this one can download a spying
plugins also in Authority so for example
to take screenshots to steal password in
browser or some
kind of hidden VNC and there are many
more
so this is sunset it's a bit ugly but
onto the obfuscate it
um
with
bit of manual work this is what you what
you obtain so it's quite simple first it
takes the serial number of the C drive
and then it send a HTTP get request to
the CNC server
so there is a IP address of the C2 that
is directly accorded in the code and
then it's a slash under several numbers
that was retrieved and then the read the
reply of this request
um
is lower code that will be interpreted
so this is the the plugin that will drop
the autoate key downloader so it's Lua
script that will just download first
this uh Ms core e uh file so this is the
automatically script and then second it
download the autoot key interpreter
because most of the time the victim
doesn't have the automotive key
interpreter installing the machine so
they need to ship it
this group really like scripting
language for example they develop a
variant of sunset in TCL it was first
time I heard about the the script
language but as you can see it's almost
the same thing except that it doesn't
retrieve the C drive cell number but the
logic is similar like it's an request to
a server and ever the reply
so this is the automatic key downloader
as you can see it's almost the same as
Sunset again
um yeah first it will take the C drive
server number which is put them in the
HTTP request and then it evals the the
code that it's written by by the CNC
server
this is an example of a plugin in
autodesky this one will install a
remote access tool
which is called remote
remote utilities so it's kind of
legitimate tool
but it allows to like to fully control
the machine so actually like this auto
key script just download and execute the
exit tab for remote utilities
this is the full list of plugins that is
available to hkbots so I won't describe
every every single of them but maybe
just just a few so there is a desk
screen plugin to take a screenshots the
screen on the screen office to take
screenshot in Loop
um
then we have this hvnc so agency stands
for hidden VNC but actually in this case
it's not really a
it doesn't use the VNC protocol it just
add less Chrome browser that can be
controlled remotely
not sure what's the exact purpose but it
might be to browse websites that are not
available
[Music]
I mean two two Bros um uh website on the
Internet or on the local network uh
since they don't have any proxy maybe
it's like their way of processing
focusing traffic
there is a key logger uh pretty simple
uh browser password stealer
and the root server on the road server
of plugins that I just talked earlier so
it's quite
typical like
implant used to spy on on a machine
and there is this plugin which is called
delete cookies which is interesting
because for Espionage it's not very
useful it's
delete cookies on the victim machine for
very specific domain including so it's
hard coded the domains are coded here
mail.eru and td.com and as you might
know TD is a Canadian bank so why were
protector want to to delete cookies for
Canadian one so we think that this uh
this plugin is in is aimed at deleting
authentication cookies so that the
victim has to re-authenticate to the
records and then if they run the kilogue
at the same time they can grab
credentials but
existed.com doesn't make sense if you
target
diplomats in Eastern Europe
so let's go back a bit in time and I
found this blog post by a training micro
and that says that it's a group that
targets us and Canadian Bank customer
and if we scroll down a little bit we
have this
nice figure and as you can see the
infection is the chain starts with a XLS
file with a VBA micro
then we have a automatic key downloader
that can download additional scripts so
probably sounds quite familiar
and then we scroll down again and there
is an example of of a plugin so this one
is a browser password still
and if we compare to the plugin called
passwords that we that that we found in
our Spanish campaign it's actually
exactly the same thing
so it seems that the toolkit use in this
threat micro article from 2020 is the
same that was used to Target
government Staff last year
so easy to acquire a group that switch
to espionage during the war
actually not because uh we did we dug
into older campaign and we found we
found that since 2020 the Roman biscuit
have been targeting government officials
and people working in state-owned
companies uh mostly in Central Asia and
also Armenia so it means that they have
been doing uh cybercromb and cyber
Espionage since the beginning of their
operation
yeah so I answered to to the question
a bit early but uh
yes they do Cyborg and cyber spinach
we also noticed that so at the beginning
of last year they were mostly doing
Subway spinach but then starting October
2022 we have started to to see more and
more cyber frame companies
um
we we found our own a bit more than 4
000 victims since the beginning of 2022
and as you can see most of them are
located in the US Canada
and also between in Europe as you can
see Germany but what is interesting is
that there are also quite few victims in
Russia
yeah so we considered more than 4 500
victims since uh January last year and
interestingly there is a big spike of
infection uh almost uh once a month so
these are the the latest one we observed
was in early March I didn't observe
anything like another campaign since
that time but maybe the complete change
the toolkit I'm not sure
and most victims for cyber Queen
campaigns are cryptocurrency Traders and
also small and medium businesses I don't
think they are specifically targeting
like anyone
um
just random small businesses in U.S and
Canada
so how is the
malware delivery for the cyber crime
companies so they must use a traffic
direction system to redirect targets to
manifest pages
unfortunately in our Telemetry we did
not observe how people landed on the
first note of the TDS but open source
reporting suggests that the attackers
are selling sending specification emails
with links or PDF documents with links
to these first nodes of the TDS and it's
also possible that visitors from
compromised websites are redirected to
this TDS
so it's an example of a chain for the
studios that I found on urscan.io so the
target will first visit the the website
local kitchencodes.com
um then they will be redirected to a
second domain which is a bit odd to
pronoun so I won't do it and then there
is a third redirection to take for
solutions.com
and on this one there is a delivery of
malicious JavaScript files in that case
it was named document one December some
random number.js and it's almost every
time the same pattern for for the
manifold JavaScript so it's always like
document or notice or something like
that and then the date of the campaign
and then some random number
in some other cases there are also fake
so people are originated from the TDS to
fake Zoom pages and then from the zoom
Pages if you click download then you'll
also get a malicious Javascript file and
there are also some for uh TeamViewer as
you can see there is some typo new
version and I think it's written
it's actually it's not team viewer in
the title it's 2v if I remember
correctly
um
so this is a another Trend that that we
found with uh like
necodilemation.com is part of the CDs it
redirected to this document.js
um
manuscript and then it downloaded HK
button so this is clearly like part of
the realm of biscuit operation
but if we look for this domain on on
various total for example
we can see that the same domain was used
to to deliver like a different like MSC
file with jobs actually a partial script
and this partial script will reach out
to download cdn.com and this domain was
apparently controlled by another
cyberpunk actor called ta 505 in 2020 so
it's possible that the domain change
ends but in any case like this uh
professional downloader it's actually
not part of srmometers guide operation
so what it means is that the TDs is not
exclusive to the realm of biscuit so it
was probably used by CA 505 we've also
seen some cubot distribution for for
from it so it's probably some paid
underground services that that the group
is using to distribute and install the
malware they're probably like paying
someone else to to do some yeah to
distribute their tools
there was also some mention of Google
ads uh many shoes garage that redirect
to this to those many shoes websites so
we did not really observe it in our
Telemetry but there is a blog post on
the sun's website and you can see like
this is fake ads for TeamViewer and
actually it redirects to one of the
[Music]
um
uh fake pages that I mentioned just a
few slides before
um so in in any case either like the TDS
or the man issues Google ads they lead
to a Javascript file which is a bit
obfuscated
um
but we can like reconstruct the URL and
actually it will call it install product
to download the MSI to to download and
install MSI from from this URL
so probably uh the realm of biscuit was
providing this MSI and even the
JavaScript was controlled by same group
as as rotds
if the target executes the jscript it
download the MSI package that drops this
VBS downloader and again it's similar to
sunseed or ahk bot you can see that it
gets the C Direction number and then
does the HTTP get request in this case
it will not download
VBS scripts but download and install
another MSI package
and this MSI package can contain for
example hkbots or new python screen
shooter
and also in the latest campaigns we have
seen a few more plugins for for the
autoot key downloader
so this is a python screenshotter uh
it's it's quite simple like it just take
a screenshot and infiltrate it
[Music]
um
also the feeling how it's it's written
it's always similar to in every
scripting language so I believe like one
person develops all these tools in all
those in all those different languages
there is also a
so if you remember there was this
more or less a Don VNC but now they have
something that they call hcmd and
actually it's a reversal written in
not.js why not
and
yeah actually there are a few functions
but the goal is just to execute some
some comment with cmd.exe and send the
result back to to the CNC server
and there is a new password stealer and
it will
and what is interesting is at the end so
they download and execute another like
executable which is download address
here and what is interesting there is
some common inversions saying that here
it is not known what the function should
be written so it's
probably referring to see that they
don't really know what what they are
doing
and the last one that they have added
probably because they started to really
compromise more and more
like companies is that with this script
to to gather information about the
active directory
so the execute a bunch of of comments
like another test or net group or domain
computers slash domain extra
and then again the actual thread to like
this part is very similar in all
programs
and what comes after of course cobal
strike
um
then after cover track we haven't
observed any further activity but it's
likely that attackers are deploying
other stages or reselling the infecting
machine to run somewhere Affiliates for
example because
yes they can monetize their activity
with the password Stealers or I don't
know they can take screenshots and
and
get some private information but
I think that there are really monitoring
monetizing uh also the infecting machine
after
cobal thread configuration is quite
typical so yes you have like your
domains know that.com I believe they
control that it uses a jQuery malleable
profile and if we scroll down there is a
watermark and it's non-watermark used by
many many cyberphone groups so it's
probably some leak cover swag Builder
from long time ago
and then two months ago they did some
retelling
they decided to redevelop everything in
not.js so including ahk bots so this is
the new back door that we name not Bots
but it's
as you can see the same that c drivers
are number get request and then execute
the results
difference is that everything is in
JavaScript now
and they have started redeveloping the
plugins from Auto add key to JavaScript
so they haven't finished like developing
redeveloping everything but some of them
are already known done for example the
browser password still
um
or the screen shutter this one actually
it downloads another tool which is
called ear fan view it's some
tools to to do to to edit pictures but
actually it can be used in command 92 to
take screenshots
um
some other experimentation that we have
observed like in March is that they have
started playing with a lnk file
um so since Microsoft disabled by
default macro downloaded from the
internet and care if I have have become
some very very popular uh last year
among like all two attackers and other
remote biscuit is no exception and
they're also starting to play with the
dot pip file which are
like just office
file for Microsoft Publisher
so as we can see here for example uh one
of the
operator uploaded a bunch of file on
various total probably in order to to
try to to bypass the detection so we can
see at the beginning there was one
detection then a few minutes after five
detection and finally zero detection
after 27 minutes
some words about the attribution uh so
there was again another blog post by
proof point which was published early
February
and so what the they have named the
group here ta86s but actually the cyber
crime project I was describing
so now the question is between Espionage
and Cyborg Prime clusters is it the same
group or is it some Network it for sale
um so we think it's it's the same group
because the level of activity is is
quite low we we considered like a bit
more than 4 000 victims it comes Sons I
but if the if the toolkit was shared on
multiple cyberpunk groups it will be way
higher
and second the network infrastructure is
very similar for oral cyber explanation
cyber open campaigns for comparison
server usually located at same hosting
providers so it's likely that a single
person manage all this infrastructure
and third the tool set is Razor basic
and in comparison to other cremor black
doors that four sets that we have seen
so assessment is that it's a rhyming
biscuit is a cyber coin group that is
doing Espionage on the side for
for some some reason like we don't know
for who they are working but they are
clearly engaging in Espionage as well
um
so lastly uh why they will do
financially motivated activity
um since Espionage is not like addressed
a few operations and not their main
operations it's unlikely that they use
cybercom to fund the Espionage operation
which is likely that it's for the
personal profit
and during our investigation we found a
few ends about origin of the attackers
so first in
most plugins or most marvelously
developed there are Russian strings and
most of them like the restraint language
is like really good quality so it it was
written by a Russian native speaker
so this one says my number for debugging
so it's likely that this two number are
the C drive serial numbers of the
developer
and also if you remember the targets of
the server is finished campaign it was
first Central Asia and then Ukraine and
its neighbors so it really suggests that
attackers are somehow connected to to
Belarus or Russia because they are like
the two main states that are like spying
in this region
so let's conclude this uh this talk
first back to the original question so
our Russian cyber criminals targeting
European and its allies so yes and no so
the realm of biscuit is a good example
of that it's probably a Russian
operation cyber criminals that are
that were doing Espionage in Central
Asia but then they moved to Eastern
Eastern Europe at the beginning of the
of the war but on the other end it's
only one of the few it's only one
example and we we haven't seen like a
very big trend of cyber criminals
starting to Target Ukraine or Poland or
such countries so we should be careful
when trying to link every cyber crime
incident in Western countries to to the
war in Ukraine
I believe there are cyber criminals
doing a bit of cyber spinach they have a
basic tool set but it seems to work even
against Ministry of Foreign Affairs and
they really like to redevelop the same
thing in different scripting language uh
we will see what scripting languages
next
uh thanks for your attention and
frequently finishing to write a blog
post that will be published on our blog
with ifsecurity.com in a few weeks
thanks everyone Thanks for attending we
are right on time so what we will do is
that before taking any of your questions
we will re uh we'll bring some chairs on
stage and we'll have a panel with Sue
and matter so if you have questions
please uh ask them you can ask them over
Silo as well and we will start in a bit
less than 15 minutes so please stay
tuned thank you again
foreign
[Music]
mountains
foreign
all right
[Music]
foreign
with the panel with our two previous
presenters so it matters so thanks again
for presenting
um I really enjoyed the presentations
while the topic were completely
different I think there are many things
that were similar
in reverse engineering and technical
analysis to understand how attackers or
managed actors are behaving how they're
evolving over time I think it was also
interesting to note that it is likely
that both actors are operating from the
same region of the world
and while at the same time the
motivations are different so I think
this was really
good um the first question I have for
you and actually we have a couple
questions from the audience already
thank you if you have more we will have
microphones you can ask them or you can
ask them on Silo as well
um
so that's it please uh yeah please send
your questions if you have them but
before that I'll start with two of my
own questions just to warm you up warm
you up and get you accustomed to the
microphones
um yeah so my first question and I'll
start with you sue if you had unlimited
resources
and you had to do that research again
in unlimited resources in the sense of
both money but also reverse Engineers
contacts in the government is there
anything you do different or you wish
you had the resources to do something
more
a question
I track at work
um it's it's very like unlike apt you
know it's a salon was widespread you see
a lot of them uh what and and it's also
something I touched on the slide briefly
but you know what a lot of these malware
use a beaconing style communication
so that makes it a lot more harder to
pull down payloads that they're trying
to spread so if money wasn't an issue it
would be actually quite fun to try and
infect as many machines as we can and uh
track all these different Affiliates and
how they and what payloads they choose
to distribute because I think that's one
thing that's missing in a lot of our
industry so we do track some Affiliates
but not all of them it's impossible like
you can emulate up to a certain point
but then it comes to a point where these
Affiliates are installing tooling on the
victim machine that requires Hands-On
keyboard activity so at that point
emulation is useless and you do need a
machine and if they don't find anything
interesting on a machine they're less
likely to you know load anything
so yeah money not an issue in fact as
many computers out there
that's a really good answer what about
you Matthew
yeah I think that your idea about having
like full environment to see how actors
are behaving will be a pretty good idea
even for apts sometimes uh
I would like to to have that like big
Windows domain like a fake one with a
machine with interesting documents Etc
just to see what they are doing
um this is a good point
um
and specifically for my from my research
I didn't have much time to to focus on
the first part the the traffic direction
system
um like if I had more resources I would
definitely look at that to try to find
out how these trade actors where they
are selling their services uh exactly
what other traductors are are using it
and trying to uh to separate the version
among the the different protectors
um yeah I think that that's what's
missing in the research
cool thanks and by the way I didn't want
to highlight anything that was missing
just more we always have limited
resources in limited uh time so cool one
thing that I'm noticing in different
research teams looking at cybercrime is
that there is lots of similarities with
tracking apt actors but sometimes there
are some things that are harder in my
opinion one of them is to is how we
organize
multiple researchers tracking cyber
crime in apt I think many research teams
will split between Russian actors
Iranian actors Chinese actors maybe
North Korea
how do you think teams doing cyber crime
research should be structured or do you
have good experience in your own
organizations that you'd like to share
I guess I'll go with that since it's
cyber crime
that's a good point that's true I mean a
lot even I believe crowdstrike has a
similar structure like that where apt
focus is by country and ecrime is well
everything you have like in my case I
work on certain families and some other
analysts they work on it by Family basis
but we are starting to notice things
like tooling that is shared across these
groups and uh and then this does make it
a lot more harder I mean as far as it's
concerned I mean we could place all
these most of these malware groups under
say one country in particular because
that's where they tend to arrive but of
course you do see malware coming from
other country
I don't think there's any clear solution
but the key thing is to distinguish
these toolings as much as possible and
then you have so from a low level
perspective active and then from a high
level perspective you have threat
intelligence analysts come into play and
try and make that connection with how
this tooling is used across groups so I
don't think settling with countries is
enough because it's clearly not targeted
and this is a whole different Financial
sort of a ball game here yeah
yeah I think the problem with
cybercrombies that it's a war ecosystem
so you cannot really you can make
clusters but everything is connected so
you cannot like work on on something and
it's not separate from everything for
apt so until you can separate by
countries because apieties they don't
collaborate with with each other
like if you track Russian apts they will
never never collaborate with Chinese
deputies or North Korean actors or it's
if you work on some apt you can just
work on that and it has no relation with
anything else so it's it's quite easy to
separate the job even like we don't
really we are not
how we are organized like uh any cities
we don't separate by by countries like
for example I work mostly on Russian
apts but also on Chinese apts and same
for for other people but we tend to
to track like different groups and one
people are responsible for for one group
and it's
very aware that we have to someone as to
to collaborate with another researcher
because groups are sharing something
except for
Chinese apts which is a big mess but
um yeah it's it's really easier to to
Cluster things
research it was really hard to
understand like the the infection chain
and the traffic direction system and all
this stuff because there are so many
different protectors using the same
like same TDS so it's it gets messy
quite easy
so when bizarre Laura was using this
Bazaar call type campaigns a lot of
these call centers were opened in India
but we know that bizarre order did none
of those developers are from India and
uh you know based off what we've seen in
the Conti leaks so clearly there's a lot
of international collaboration here and
it's a lot more
he has a lot more organized than we
thought you know before another good
example I have with e-crime is uh so for
bachbot so publicly it's called ice ID
they use this hidden VNC tool you know
um Matthew talked about like hidden vncs
so they've been using this tool since
2019 but now we're seeing the same tool
being distributed by bumblebee uh we
even see like a catbot using a similar
tool and it's it's a bit uh
it was a bit like Curious it's like is
this just another group building this
tool like where are they getting their
hands on this tool from so clearly
there's a lot of organization Happening
Here uh Something That We're Not privy
to yeah
yeah thanks
um I would like to ask you Lily you had
a question and if that's okay with you
I'd like you to ask it live because I
think you will deliver it better than
myself
I assume
um so a question in regards to bumblebee
um so with the API unhooking module in
that particular malware when it detects
that
an API is hooked in memory is that it
overwrites that with the bytes on disk
and my question is what happens if
there's a memory pointer at the
beginning of that particular API on disk
and for example in memory
um would it just right the raw bytes
from disk and that memory pointer would
be invalid and potentially cause any
type of Crash do you figure what are
your thoughts there
cool thanks lady for the question
um so yeah so this was uh I think it was
a slide I just quickly went by it was a
slide that talked about the lip splice
the splicing library that does the
unhooking so essentially when it's
trying to remove any hooks on apis it's
copying over bytes from the instructions
and its physical file so Lily pointed
out the fact that you know you might
have instructions in memory where it's
referencing addresses and that could be
a potential problem because does this
malware take care of rebasing those
addresses uh long story short no they
don't they just they don't even do
anything different they just completely
use this Library as is the thing about
this Library it is almost a decade old
so it's not something new not something
that was aware of rebasing so they just
come in and it ran like it there was no
problem so maybe they tested it maybe
not there's no clear idea why but it
seems to work but I believe like also
like Lily's done research where we have
seen like other families now starting to
look and Implement those checks for
rebasing so you know a lot of these
groups are probably becoming aware of
the faults behind some of these uh
cooking libraries yeah thank you
thanks again for your question is there
any other question in the audience we
are not ready to take some questions
um yes please go ahead and if that's
okay with you I'll try to rephrase your
question for the ones listening online
so please step in correct me if I didn't
understand your question properly the
question is in the Bible in bumblebee
why are the developers why did the
developers choose rc4 instead of
something maybe more efficient or more
modern like rc5 or double fish
good question
it's not clear why they've introduced
rc4 and rc4 is like this it's like this
go-to thing with a lot of e-crime
malwares a lot of them just use rc4 but
there is also a bit of a hidden meaning
behind it uh and not something I've
talked about
um so with Bumblebee a lot of the
samples based on which Affiliates is
using the malware each affiliate has
their own rc4 key and so even though
it's communicating with the server you
need to make sure you're communicating
with the server that can decrypt
messages with that proper key so in a
way it wasn't only just encrypting
traffic it was also used to track uh
communication for certain Affiliates so
you couldn't just use any you know
bumblebee malware and just take the c2s
from that malware and just communicate
with it if you don't know the rc4 key
that's associated with the C2 it makes
it harder to see what the response is so
it's in their way slightly tricky like
unless you have the malware and can't
use it but I mean yeah they could have
carried it forward but they clearly
didn't bother yeah
thanks thanks for your answer
um maybe we can explain why protectors
like using rc4 so I don't really know
about sc5 and rc6 but for sc4 there is
no constant so if you compare to AES for
example in sc4 there is no constant so
it's harder to
to detect sc4 with like a byte buttons
you'll need to to check like the the
decompiler who have or have a signature
on some some disassembly graph so that's
why trade actors are like using sc4 it's
just hard to make a signature on it
thanks and thanks for this explanation
um I'll go with one question we had
online for you master which was
um can you elaborate a bit on the
um
what does it mean that there was a
watermark for the Cobalt strike sample
that you described
so the watermark is a number that that
is linked to uh to the license link to
the Cobalt strike Builder the problem is
that first it's quite easy to change if
I remember correctly it's just a number
in the text file in in the directory of
like the cover track instance
um
but generally trit actors don't care
about changing it so it can still be
useful to to Cluster uh different uh
um Cobalt swag beacons you extract the
config and then you cluster by by what
your map the second problem is that
there are a lot of copper strike
builders that have been leaked online so
you can find like cobal strike builder
of like previous versions and
a lot of protectors are reusing those
leak Builders and that's why there are
the they end up with the same Watermark
at the end
thanks I'll continue with questions
online I I like that everyone is able to
vote and upvote them so it helps me
prioritize
um the next one I think is for you Sue
and the question is
could you abuse the beginning system in
bumblebee to affect the attacker in
order to infect the attacker in order to
unmask their identity
uh you seem to be expecting that
question I like it
well
uh unfortunately I don't have any good
answer because uh uh you know part of my
work is we do not attack back
so uh it may be possible but it's not
something uh you know we allowed
um to pursue or look forward and so I
just really only monitor traffic
and I will yeah that's it that's all I
can answer to it
awesome I think the next one is for you
master did you need to enable macros in
Word and Excel and Microsoft Publisher
files in order to get a successful
infection
probably yes but to be honest I just
extracted the macro and didn't trying to
didn't try to run the document but if it
was downloaded from the internet I think
for
few years now so before uh
so
before July 2022 you add some some just
some message and you can just click to
enable macro but now it's just not
possible to run macro from the internet
if you have like up-to-date version of
uh of Microsoft Office
thank you
next one is is crypto still very in
fashion in the crime world or as hype
died down like in the mainstream
and if so which cryptocurrent I guess
cryptocurrency in this case
so maybe I'll start with Tuma too
because I think you did mention that
some of the targets for your uh for the
group you're tracking were looking at
crypto cryptocurrency
yes so we noticed that uh attackers when
they were collecting like from per uh
browsing stories or like doing like key
logging they were um very interested in
uh taking credentials to to Logan poop
to log in popular uh
cryptocurrency exchange for example so
we haven't observed them stealing really
stealing those uh
these cryptocurrencies but I guess if
they are collecting uh wallet addresses
uh login password for crypto exchange
it's just not to to look at the number
um
and what was the original question not
sure answer is the question I think he
did answer the question uh maybe the
other part was is there anything you can
share about which crypto exchanges or
which currencies were mostly targeted
mostly big Bitcoin if I remember
correctly and like the exchange is it
was
very random so it mostly depends on what
exchange the victim was using
okay
um
so it's not with
OS malware a lot of Steelers So lately
we've been seeing it's a kind of an
interesting question because we've been
seeing a lot of Steelers that Target
Gamers and like social engineer Gamers
through Twitter and to get them to
install Steelers on a machine which end
of the day just steals wallets and an
extensive list of wallets and it's all
related to the metaverse because some of
these games they use crypto currency
exchanges for and trading and stuff so
they look at like um
Finance
Bitcoin there was a list and I don't
know the entire list off my head but uh
I think it's more common in the gaming
world yeah for sure
great thanks for the initial additional
context this is uh really appreciated
um the next question is something we've
already touched on but I will I will go
through it again and then please feel
free to chime in if there's something
else you'd like to add how different is
it in uh studying geopolitically
motivated versus uh the ones created by
criminals is there a significant
difference or pretty much the same
I'll start by summarizing what we what I
remember from what we've discussed so
far
um I think we've discussed that
state-sponsored attackers are going to
be mostly not sharing their tools or
techniques they have their own things
and they the Chinese and the Russians
rarely exchange tools while for the
cyber crime we see a lot more of
exchange and common pieces being used
anything else that you see that kind of
stands out as geopolitical versus
criminal malware
maybe how malware are developed or
protected
like January Kramer malware are very
well protected there are like big
Packers which are very annoying to to
reverse and they do a lot of check like
to see if they are running in some
virtual machine or sandbox or stuff like
that on the contrary apt malware
generally they are not packed
very little obfuscated like from time to
time like strings are obfuscated but
that's pretty much it so of course from
time to time there is some very big
change that are very uh to understand
but
generally like it's
I'd say
maybe not easier to to reverse because
the mirror are very big uh like a lot of
functionalities are generally in C plus
plus like network communication it can
be quite hard to to understand but there
are really rarely used Packer because
they want to stay under the radar and
looks like any other file on the system
when you have some pack sample it's
start to be suspicious
I guess what I could add to it is uh e
crime these days they are a lot more
ransomware focused I mean that's the
easy way to make money
um it's uh and of course if it's
targeting Gamers it's you know stealing
cryptocurrency but uh like gone now the
days you see banking Trojans and and
most apts don't
um I could be wrong they may be doing
ransomware or not but that's what's
clearly defining and what the you know
what defines e-crime and apt
um and also I find that ecrime they tend
to focus a lot more on EDR evasion
because they are targeting companies and
companies most likely have some EDR
solution and and they just want to
bypass that and especially with
ransomware you're seeing a trend with
the vulnerable drivers so the by OBD and
so you know they clearly it's they want
to prevent edrs from seeing that they're
encrypting files so vulnerable Rivals is
the way to go apparently these days
so yeah I guess hope that answers the
question
I think it does thank you
um I'll start with mature for the next
one have you seen this situation in
Ukraine generally increased malware
threat activity
and what do you think those people
working on malware will do if the war
ends
um so we did see an increase of marrow
attacks in in Ukraine but those are
mostly State sponsor attacks
um so the people developing those those
malware were most probably working from
for the same organization before the war
and will continue to work for some
organization after the war so
not sure if it will change anything
um and we did see like some some
increase in the context of the war but
it's not like crazy and
in the last few months it's it's really
more quiet that it was one year ago
anything to add soon
I think Matthew has heard it well
perfect the next question is also a bit
apt oriented have you been involved in
nation state apt identification for
diplomatic allegations for example
blaming Russian FSB for attacks
um so from time to time we will like say
that the group is most likely right
brochure like no China Airline but we
never go as far as naming The Entity of
the person who is behind it it's quite
easy to to make mistakes and it's more
political job to to do that
right
I agree I mean yes
cool and we have time for one last
question it is also a bit uh politically
oriented how much work is going on with
groups blaming each other
recently was discovered to be actually
tied to Russian apt is are there other
examples
I can start because I see you looking at
the sky I think
I do remember one case
um of another Russian operation at the
beginning of the war with Ukraine where
they changed the
um they changed some of the metadata in
some pictures to make it look like it
was coming from Poland but it was very
maturation not super convincing so I
think fast lag operations are not
uncommon but to say they are increasing
or there are recent examples
um I would need to ask our experts
um any crime
well with group blaming you you normally
see a lot of within the group a lot of
them sometimes they can be tensions I
think that was quite clear with Conti
leaks with something political comes up
and but of course it was a Ukrainian
researcher that released the logs but uh
um you don't see it too much you mostly
see it maybe among ransomware groups
like especially if there was a
ransomware that targeted a hospital and
then they immediately try to post on
like the data leak site that it's not
them it's someone else and so it's
oftentimes that that case because they
do not want to be liable and they are
you know actually worried but otherwise
like it's hard to we haven't seen it
elsewhere like in the crime about apt
I'm not sure maybe there's a lot more of
that happening in that end
I don't think there are a lot of them
another example was the one in Korea
during the winter Olympics uh
I don't remember exactly the details but
there was something with the rich
Shadows from like North Korean group and
actually it was like
sitting it was beyond like the attack
like a Russia line group
[Music]
it's it's a bit old so I don't remember
exactly the details but actually like
this group setting it make it look like
it was some like no score North Korean
online group that was behind the attack
but like it's it's not very common or
it's too good and we we don't we don't
realize it but I don't know
but you do see it in forums you see a
lot of sometimes arguments sometimes
when an author like some group has
developed a malware and they're selling
it to Affiliates the Affiliates can
sometimes backstab or do something that
they're not meant to do there's always
rules among them that they allow
Affiliates to do not do so that is
actually quite common in ecrime and so
especially again with ransomware they
try to tell Affiliates that because of
you uh you're targeting hospitals you're
no longer part of the program but so
that's pretty common or sometimes you
have Affiliates that will buy a test
build but then end up using it their own
way and that you know quite frankly
upsets the developer and then they just
release it or they go into Cahoots with
someone else but yeah so it's a as long
as there's money there's always
something to be upset about
these are really good examples thank you
and we are at times so thank you very
much for your presentations for
everything you've shared and then for
joining this panel
um it's great having this discussion
with you and thanks to all of you for
your questions
[Applause]
oh
foreign
wow
the people
foreign
we're gonna get started I'll let people
wander in and speak slowly
so we've got three more talks uh in this
room until the end of the day and uh
we're going to be doing a couple of
questions after each of them so there's
no final panel
um so I'm thrilled to be welcoming Sarah
karanik to the stage she's a long time
hacker and she spent the better part of
10 years as a software engineer with a
keen interest in security engineering
specifically she also had a foray into
entrepreneurship and now for the last
five years or so her main focus has been
on cyber security primarily offensive
her research interests include
cryptography malware reverse engineering
and apparently cyber warfare
Sarah is currently working towards her
ciss-p-i-s-s-e-p and in the future she
hopes to finally get hers Masters so
welcome to the stage really excited for
your talk
awesome thank you can I just go ahead
Roger all right
um my name is Sarah krainik uh thank you
for coming to my session I'm very happy
to be here and I would like to thank
everyone who got me here because it
wasn't quite a straight route
so yes here we go first a disclaimer
this was uh needed so before I get
started I'm solely here on my own accord
and I do not speak or on behalf of my
employer I do not talk I will not talk
about my work or about my work or who I
work for this topic is a very personal
interest in mine so I just need to make
that very clear
so uh to get started some goals of mine
today is to talk to Define and convey
the meaning of hybrid Warfare and how
it's used to date
how why cyber operations by a sizeable
war or part of hybrid Warfare
how we can as red teamers pen testers
utilize the lessons learned so far in
the conflict of Ukraine and Russia
and the opposing side of that is by
learning how the defensive side can also
learn from you
okay background
a little definition I'm not going to
read it verbatim so I'm just going to
give you 10 seconds to read it quickly
all right Tim all right
all right everyone good
so several components of hybrid Warfare
as you can see here so one diplomatic
pressure
electoral interference migration
actually Force migration we actually saw
this in Ukraine where they recently
deported children back to Russia to
Russia let's say uh we have what else do
we have cyber attacks corruption fake
news economic manipulation
that's right
oh sorry
so it's not my laptop whose laptop is
this
foreign
so this happened quite recently it's
still unclear who we can attribute to
but we could all figure out what it
might mean
I'm not going to fill in the I'll let
you conclude what it'll be
either way it conflates everything and
we get to the point where we confuse
who's done what and why
we're going to watch a few Clips the
first clip is
um
a Russian official who's denying I don't
know if you know about Little Green Men
but they invaded Crimea quite recently
or when in 2014
so this is the denial
well of course we don't have audio
okay sorry I don't know how to audio for
some reason anyways he goes on to say
uh basically we're not there what
why we're not there
of course not we're not there
well not too long after
of course the commander from Russia
yeah we're there of course we are we
actually uh played with the system got
people to vote vote in a proxy war or
proxy vote
um yeah and so
it's it's p if you can get people to
choose to vote for you
and choose to have a referendum by force
then you don't need to invade them right
so
so here's a perfect example of plausible
deniability if one can get International
Community to believe that people voted
for something themselves AKA a proxy
vote then there is no Invasion right so
you just you're invited you voted you
voted as for it to come another unique
aspect of this conflict has been the way
drones have been utilized
uh more traditional usage of bombing and
surveillance but also a so-called
Kamikaze emissions the types of drones
has varied as well both purpose military
hardware and the use of publicly
available Hardware the uses of aus shelf
Hardware has gotten to the point where
some manufactured manufacturers like DJI
have refused to sell it to Russia
Ukraine because it might be used in the
act of War
this is actually a clip of an example of
how they're using drones in particular
Kamikaze so you'll actually see it come
in in just a sec
okay get on to the interesting part
cyber warfare so some some examples of
cyber war attacks in 2022 this graphic
is interesting from the perspective it
marries kinetic attacks and cyber
attacks so this is on the ground attacks
as well as in the Cyber Realm
the magic can agricult cyber operations
as a theme we'll see uh come quite
regularly I'll highlight two events in
particular one cyber one connected they
happen to happen on April 11th so you
can actually see April 11th no sorry
March 11th my my bad so if you see the
Russian strikes in dinitro and then we
have the matching government attack and
the Cyber Realm
so we're working closely with Kinetic
operational command often makes for more
effective use of cyber capabilities this
is just not relevant for Warfare but
also when conducting red team
assessments for example you will need to
coordinate all groups involved with your
engagement physical social engineering
Network everyone needs to coordinate
together your talk must be coordinated
super coordinating okay
so these are some attacks that let up so
we they start in 2014 which is if
everybody's aware of their timeline is
when basically Crimea was
annexed
um
so we start there we go for a DDOS
attack and then it goes to activists
power grid attacks and you can see the
succession of attacks up till about 2022
in February was the official invasion of
eastern Ukraine
uh so we'll talk about two of those
attacks
um in particular we'll talk about
nepecha and we'll talk about the power
grid attacks
but first Russia so what do we know
about Russia
their focus has been on disrupting
Society through information Warfare and
cyber attacks on businesses and critical
infrastructure Dutch intelligence report
suggests that other incidents such as
malware and disrupting Ukrainian power
supply are probably mainly aimed at
undermining Ukrainian morale rather than
all-out like achieving a military
objective this boosts the point that
Russia is focused on disruption
rather than a cyber physical damage
rather on Cyber physical damage
but what's quite interesting even though
they're trying to avoid like
um
not damage in the Cyber realm they have
gone after Targets on the kinetic side
like on hospitals and other targets like
schools so yeah it's kind of interesting
that way
but there's also this question if they
do goes in the one interesting about a
Cyber attack too is many of you know is
you can't really Target as well as
kinetic and it can get out and this is a
theme that we'll see coming up
so a few viruses that you might know one
of the earliest is earliest that got out
of the uh realm was the Morris worm if
anyone's familiar with that it was one
of the earliest viruses if not the
earliest and another one more recently
was a wannacry
after that and that was based off
external blue which is interesting
because we'll just get to nepecha which
is also built off external blue
so nepecia now betcha was composed of
two separate components external blue
and mini cats and now Petra was a
derivative of the Petra malware so blue
is a leaked NSA Hocking tool which
exploited a no-bound ability of the
Microsoft server message block so this
is smv V1 protocol an infiltrated window
systems with outdated security the net
Petra Attack originated from an update
to the Ukrainian tax software called me
Doc during their talk radiation monitor
even at Chernobyl went offline sub
recreated Ministries Banks Metro systems
and other Enterprises were also affected
um
I don't know if you know about net Petra
I think hit at about 10 billion in
Damages around the world too so not just
in Ukraine
um
though initially label is ransomware due
to Ransom message that was displayed
after infection it was soon proven that
neppetch functions more like a
destructive wiper tool rather than
actual ransomware
the attack came on the Eve also at the
Ukrainian public holiday
um uh called Constitution Day
now Petra was a destructive and spread
quickly but many accounts who was also
an act of cyber War which is interesting
because there was a an insurance company
called zerk that actually denied claims
in the hundreds of millions of dollars
because they claimed it was an act of
War so it was one of the few attacks
that were actually labeled from the
start as a cyber act or a cyber War Act
because the Cyber War didn't fall under
the purview of the insurance policies
um yeah they took it to court and I
think just recently they settled and I
don't know what the settlement because
it wasn't made public
so nap Petra overwrites
and encrypt sectors of the physical hard
drive and the C volume but it does not
contain the ability to restore the files
rendering the recovery of possible even
if the ransom is paid this is why it was
not attributed to ransomware using the
windows API device i o control the
malware is able to direct to direct read
and write access to the physical hard
drive without an interaction with the
operating system
this allowed the code to determine the
number of disks and partitions on the
system unmount and mounted for volume
even if it was in use I determined the
drive geometry for the drives on the
system the number of sectors bytes and
per second sector the malware uses the
access to destroy data critical to the
operating system the Petra also had the
ability to replace the OS bootloader
with custom code embedded in the binary
so the next attack I chose as well
because it went after OT systems rather
than just it systems
and so the power Distribution Company
sustained a Cyber attack and Western
Ukraine on the 23rd of December 2015.
although although the attack was
triggered in 2015 it was carefully
planned networks and systems
were compromised as early as eight
months before in the spring of 2015 a
variety of black energy malware was
triggered with an employee of the
opened an Excel attachment of an email
if you don't know black energy is a
malware Suite that was first hit the
news in 2014 when I was used extensively
if to infiltrate energy utilities
its a was to gather intelligence about
the infrastructure networks to help
prepare for future cyber attacks during
several months into summer of 2015 black
energy malware was remotely controlled
to collect data hop from one host to the
other and detect vulnerabilities and
even make its way out to all T networks
and perform some of the reconnaissance
activities the afternoon two days after
Christmas as stated by the operator the
mouse started to move
on the HMI system so that's a human
machine interface and start switching
off Breakers remotely
when the local operator attempted to
regain control is super the supervision
interface he was logged off and could
not log in again because a password had
been changed
additional malware in particularly to
custom develop export was used to
prevent operator from regaining control
to the network by wiping out many disks
using killdisk
overwriting external to serial Gateway
firmware with random code thus turning
devices into basically scrap
but the attack was too fast to allow any
reaction indeed a critical
infrastructure environment operating
actions may cause safety issues
therefore
uh they really could do anything because
they have predefined actions in a lot of
these places
and so he had the operator had to follow
guidelines and to take action and if
those actions don't include such things
as a Cyber attack
while your Sol
this is exactly thing that happened in
Ukraine
um
so it was it's great to have Sops or
what we call Standard offering
procedures but we also need to account
for when those actions arise and Sops
can't handle that or are planned for
them
considering attackers are constantly
coming up with new ways to attack our
organizations our saps need to find a
way to adapt as well obvious actions
could have stopped the attack but like I
said it's OT and there's really standard
ways of doing everything so you could
just let's say unplug the system
okay so what what do we know about the
Ukrainian operations this is where my
talk really came from because I was
really addressing interested in how
Ukraine was expected within days to fall
to Russia right so no one expected to be
here in 2023 in Russia's or Ukraine
still fighting on both the Cyber realm
and the kinetic Realm
so why
I had I came up with two things in my
mind
um
one was the the
Russian actions failed to materialize
and distribute those attacks
and Ukraine had better than expected
defenses
most Russian digital attacks attempts
were directed prematurely or mediated
quickly thanks to far-reaching Ukrainian
monitoring detection and response
measures Ukraine receives receives also
significant help from Western
both companies and governments
one Center for strategic and
International Studies reported
what apparent weakness of the Russian
cyber operations has been the lack
between the Cyber and conventional
attacking but I've talked to elect level
cyber attacks provide benefits plan to
combined with other weapons including
conventional Delivery Systems Precision
guided Munitions augmented aerial
Vehicles like padrones and electronic
warfare interesting Ukraine had a better
ability to deploy these mechanisms the
combination can command networks
and advanced weapon systems that
contribute to addition of opposing
forces however when it used in an ad hoc
manner or went on coordinated with air
and ground actions cyber attacks proved
less useful
the one area Russia seems quite
successful and talented at has been what
we call you know information Warfare
right their propaganda
they could go after more physical
targets but they would have to really do
it in such a way that's very convert
comfort me
and they must do it in such a way that
they're careful because the Russia
doesn't uh enjoy the reputation that
Ukraine does Ukraine has this
aura about it right so they can do
pretty much anything without getting
into Harm's Way whereas Russia
they do something they get a deep
trouble especially if they start
attacking NATO countries
another part of this I don't know if
anybody's heard of the it Army
but Ukraine Idol utilizes this it Army
concept which is a built off of
volunteers
it
there's a lot of argument to get it
against it but we'll get to that quickly
or soon
um
they there's a lot of theories that they
just keep
Russia busy while the ukrainians can
focus on their defensive and offensive
cyber operations
any any other actions is just a bonus
that being said they do have some
standard
um rules
but there has been some criticism
because they have gone after
targets that maybe are not
just military targets let's put it that
way
and the problem is controlling what
people do so if you have a bunch of
volunteers how do you control them
and Mike and but another aspect that we
can think about is if you have a bunch
of voluntaries you can also have some
plausible deniability of a bunch of
volunteers doing stuff well it's not us
right we're not doing it
um so you can re uh remain at arm's
lengths and have that plausible
deniability
they have used telegram to organize and
they also have this called MSHA dos I
don't know if anyone knows this Library
it actually does like Mass DDOS attacks
you're not supposed to use it for
nefarious purposes of course
um
so the it Army has these rules of
engagement or
um yeah their rules engagement but
um if you work with hackers at all it's
hard to control what they do so it's
better to say hey here's a bunch of
tools hands off and interestingly at the
beginning of the whole it army they were
just giving them a bunch of targets and
here have fun now they've gone to the
point where they're using this mha dos
to build a bot and you just have to
connect with their bot and you can
participate in their actions
as I said before people are just going
after targets and I have heard stories
of people actually on their own accord
going after things like OT networks
ics's and scada systems and taking out
power plants and various things
but before you do this I have to say you
are might be act in an act of war and
hacking and we all know that's illegal
so I have to make that perfectly clear
you do that you're in deep trouble
before the it Army uh there was an
entrepreneur who was also doing some
voluntary activity
uh cellular tooling as I said is the mha
Dos framework which forms the basis of a
bot they built that the Cyber Armory
volunteers can use to participate in
efforts
not so shockingly there has also been
cases of Russia building tools and
distributing them to
partisans if you will and taking
advantage of them that way so if you
don't know maybe what you're doing
exactly and you download this tool
there was some Trojans on it
okay planning and launching a Cyber
attack
let's shift our Focus we have learned
Lots about what's happening in the
tactics and technique so what does this
mean for us
most of us in this cyber world are well
aware of the kill chain
by Lockheed there's also the miter
attack framework which is also which is
more exhaustive but for the use case at
hand
I use the Cyber kill chain
um
cyber generally doesn't happen in
isolation although the rule has been
broken previously like stuxnet
although it's ducksnet
there was a huge component on the ground
is the theory because they would have
had to get all that information prior to
the actual event
but this is especially when you're
talking about critical infrastructure
and other
um
OT infrastructures uh the the amount of
information that you need
is hugely important
especially when we're talking about
critical infrastructure cyber attacks
could have real world consequences
wouldn't take much to cause harm for
example stopping the water treatment
or targeting a local hospital
sure there's civilian targets but let's
be serious nation states might shy away
from
reasons touched on already
what about motivated partisan group or
individuals or nation-states who don't
care about International decorum or laws
concerning OT systems are widely under
defended and rely on outdated Tech
with more being connected to the
interwebs it is it's not inconceivable
that a bad actor Will Target these
systems neither inadvertently or
advertently Target civilians it is
shocking that it hasn't happened more
than we've seen already
attribution would be hard and like many
breaches may not be detected for a long
time before being remediated like we saw
in the power of great attack
rolling out of serious attacks and
making it innocuous enough to not create
waves and alert the authorities and true
nature and scope of the attack is key
sure it takes planning and organization
and all that is lacking is a current
climate is a motivated party
staggering attacks would help to hide
the true motivation or hinder
attribution added some disinformation
about who might be at fault and blame
the official opposition for example of
the ruling party and you're on Off to
the Races
yeah
so lessons for offensive teams
uh for all the fog and questions over
the I.T model Ukraine creativity and
Ingenuity can nonetheless have created a
model for their new kind of warfare
drones trackling troops movements with
purpose of spilled apps like EPO EPO is
an app for distracting drones in the air
telegram for talking troops there is
bellingcat uh Twitter feeds like elit
there's another one as well
brings a whole new meaning to a militia
not just democratizing cyber warfare but
it's democratizing War similar to
partisan activity in World War II but
with modern communication my tools
organizing can mobilize thousands it
would not be it would be interesting to
look at this issue in more depth with
further research
militaries and other organizations will
learn from the conflict and no doubt
shape the future of conflict
it has also provided example for
businesses and indeed countries how to
stand and keep running under constant
pressure in cyber attacks countries like
industry suffer from talents shortages
for companies in Orcs who could afford
specialized units like this U.S cyber
command the accredited model
demonstrates a way to develop a cyber
capability that can swiftly to be
deployed
having training pipeline is critical
preparedness
in the primary focus you might be able
to have highly trained team on hand
full-time
but you certainly can build a
partnership with industry and
governmental orgs to build a network of
tools and people to deploy when stuff
gets real
is definitely not the great approach but
after years of cyber at Tech preparation
this type of preparation is often in the
norm something happens we react it's in
every pre-planning for something that
might happen we'd let it happen and then
we figure out how to not happen again
it's a strategic planning
your team is tasked to infiltrate uh so
some takeaways
[Music]
so your team is tasked to infiltrate a
secure building now what what do you
know about the building access points
how about when the security goes to the
bathroom changes shifts for example do
we know what type of access systems they
have can we spoof the method of Entry
you need to know your enemy at Target no
matter if the if you're attacking a
country or a company Recon is important
and planning a stop severe attack
we use Frameworks for a reason run
through your plan I go back to uh I I
fight and wait I when we train for a
fight we train to fight in training so
you win the fight in training same thing
with this you prepare and prepare
prepare
you walk through what will happen at
each stage of that attack
this is this is starting to sound
familiar it's not by accident the
interesting thing even with knowing all
that we know teams and organizations
appear to get it wrong more times than
they get it right
if you're running an offensive team take
no practice war games and blue team red
team exercises should not be just the
purview of intelligence organizations
and Military
but I realize that that takes a lot of
money so you can do what we call in the
security World tabletop exercise a
whiteboard tests this kind of thing walk
through everything there's no reason why
an organization even with three people
can't walk through your attack steps and
figure out what your adversary will be
doing
I could tell you who your enemy
attackers would be power plants maybe a
Target by terrorist banks by criminals
it doesn't matter what organization
you're a part of you are going to be in
a talk at some point
even an Insider discover ex-boy for
example it could take time and effort
and take time and effort to step back
and be in a system like an outsider or
even an Insider who attends to harm one
of the values of the tabletop exercise
to let players consider the system as a
whole
organization without the idea who is
doing what
the flow and tasking of your efforts
will be haphazard at best so we have a
CTF going on this weekend even though
eight eight people team
if nobody knows what each other's doing
or how they're doing it or what you're
doing
you're not going to get anywhere
this goes to uh
we'll get to communication
so yeah so when you're building teams in
your organization has to be there if you
can't coordinate you don't know what
each other's doing it's going to fall
apart pretty quickly talent management
may not seem relevant but if you utilize
your people properly no amount of team
members will get the tasks done right we
you can have a thousand people but if I
was just sitting around dust bunnies
collecting dust bunnies
it's not going to matter
I have seen Team Dynamics and lack of
organizations take down the smallest of
teens because people are not sure what
to do
and leaders don't delegate
figure out what your people are great at
and divvy up tasks
keep the chain of command in the event
situation this doesn't have to be your
chain and command at your normal
workplace but has some structure in
place at the event or at your assessment
but don't forget to listen to your
experts right now everyone's a security
Hue topic you can't specialize in
everything
figure out what your people are good at
to be up tasks keep to the chain of
command
this leads to communication how do we
pass up and down information
and this of course leads into the topic
of opsec
so when we talk about opsec
there's a well-known story I don't know
if you're a fan of cryptography but when
they broke the Enigma they couldn't
actually use the Enigma to the extent
that everybody wanted because what
happens when everyone knows what you
know
people stop using that tool right so
um it's this is sort of the same thing
with cyber you gotta you gotta plan if
you have these attacks and you know you
have these attacks let's say you have a
zero day which I hope nobody has and not
keeping it to themselves but if you do
you would want to use it at once because
then that whole idea of having that
people know you have it it's gone that
that Advantage is gone
so this the opsec applies to both cyber
exercises as well as security
assessments
and um
so yeah
so one of the other things that when we
get into talking about when to use these
attacks is this idea of probability and
what's called strategic Randomness so
again you've got to use it
if you're going to attack somebody
you've got to make it so it's plausibly
that it's not yourself doing the attack
um
so
I lead on this side for so when it comes
to Russia and I lean on the side why
they haven't done so well as they have
is I lean on the side of tactical
coordination or Russia's military and
intelligence organizations not
coordinating as we know large
organizations all have to get in the way
and are paralyzed by bureaucracy this uh
one of the advantages I think Ukraine
had is this sort of ad hoc ragtag team
sorry that ground fighting attitude
and because they don't have this big
organization apparently before the the
all these attacks happen they didn't
really have any cyber capacity within
their organizations already
and as we all know large organ Nations
get in the way and are paralyzed by
bureaucracy
um
so you might not you might be in a
situation where you might not know in
terms of another aspect we need to talk
about is tooling so you might be in a
position where you don't know what
you're using in a event this happens
quite often you go to event you don't
know what you're doing but you'll have a
set of tooling and this is very
important to set up your tooling before
you go a lot of organizations if you
work in a bigger organization you might
not have a choice of tools so if you go
into an assessment you might be stuck on
something because
that's proprietary that's what you use
so stick to it it's unfortunate but it
happens I don't think it should happen
because you should use tools to match
your tasks
as always it's like this famous question
of the programming languages what's the
best programming language come on what's
best programming language right it's
python right who uses python right yeah
okay I don't think so I'd like C so
there you go
um
so you know this pain
I I could make a whole talk out of the
scope of the session adaptably and
tooling is something to address
so yeah don't let your tools dictate
what you do
let what you do dictate your tooling
before moving on I would like to address
the human element but fill with building
effective teams is a huge topic but does
need to address briefly here we must
build teams that are mixed and in every
way both in skills and makeup to think
like the attacker and to find ways to
attack and Achieve our objectives as
offensive folks you need to you need
team members that have different skill
sets and viewpoints to complement the
team obviously the team
obviously the team
obviously you can't have everybody who's
good at one thing so if you have
somebody who's really good at malware
ready malware you what's the point I
have a really good malware person if you
can't have somebody who knows how to get
somebody to click on that link right it
doesn't it's not effective anymore
all right so unfortunately I think my
time's coming
to a quick end
Maybe
um
so I have a few final points just to go
over uh never enter underestimate your
adversary
it is a massive mistake Russia's made
and organizations continually make
plan for the worst hope for the best
over plan
your worst case scenario if Defenders if
on the offensive side run through your
workflow for your attack well cyber and
nine cyber aspects the Ukrainian
conflict will leave a lasting impact on
Cyber world the lessons learned
will all will be important going forward
and
not only at the nation state level but
also for individual ngos and companies
and that's all I have for Planned
content
so I think I have some time for
questions
so we do have
we have time for questions so
um feel free to use the QR code that may
or may not be appearing
somewhere such as on the stage and
um I'm happy to read some questions out
or since we don't have any yet uh if
anyone wants to jump in and say
something
you
you can do so and I will translate for
the Stream
s
thank you thanks so much
please come talk to Sarah afterwards if
you were too shy to ask in front of
everyone
we're gonna take about a 10 minute break
and then we'll be back
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
oh
foreign
come on there
now
foreign
all right okay and we're back
um welcome everyone so I'm super excited
to have sushaka Sharma on the stage uh
he is a repeat speaker he's been here
before we know him well he's the chief
scientist at bravado where he helps
build code analysis tools for data
privacy and data security he completed
his PhD in computer engineering from
Polytechnic where he worked on ebpf
technology and Hardware assisted tracing
techniques for OS analysis for the last
six years sushakra has been working on
enhancing static analysis tooling for
fixing security bugs at scale and he is
also quite a prolific conference speaker
including norseck thank you so much
hey everyone
so
um thanks a lot uh for for this very
lofty introduction
um you know but it's just me and my
humble mustache which is here
so
um uh I welcome you to this talk
um we're gonna discuss a lot of Concepts
which have not been discussed in privacy
before and I guess it would be one of
the first times we are gonna do a deep
dive into it and uh just let's uh get
into it then
so I'm this guy uh you know about this
so no need to read this uh privacy in
modern times is uh actually something
like this you know uh you click yes I
agree and you sign of your soul or you
burn your money and go to the Himalayas
so I mean there's no choice in between
at this time
so um and why why do people feel like
this is because uh they see a few things
they see the mistakes every day you know
they see news items like this uh you
know Twitter advising all 330 million
users to change their passwords uh uh
gas state agency in India you know leaks
millions of aadhar numbers other is like
uh SIN number here so so it's like that
so and all of these things when you go
to the root of it is very basic you know
for Twitter it was actually plain text
passwords and logs and something as
simple as that and for this it was an
unauthenticated endpoint which was
leaking Pia you could just go and you
know do the increment ID thing and you
suddenly get all the information
so the other reason is that people know
about this also now you know they they
did not used to know this this dark
cloud in between but now they know that
they're data brokers who are you know
you trust a few of the services you put
all your data there some Services you
are you don't know you should trust or
not but I guess you know maybe just give
some info to them and then you know it
goes on gets into this dark area and
then everything gets collected and
suddenly there is there is the service
which has everything about you you know
you never even expected this random ABC
numbered Corporation having all this
information about you because but they
have it and and people know about this
now so so there were it they are
genuinely worried
um it's very difficult to solve you know
these these problems because there are
economic incentives around them because
like you know for some businesses they
are only going to run if they you know
take in your data
but some legitimate businesses they have
to actually solve this stuff so the
theater of security and privacy looks
like this right now and and I'll start
from the perspective of privacy we'll
see the csos mind you know it it's kind
of like this it's not blank we are going
to fill this
so uh I think the first thing is is like
this RSA log 4G Big Ticket items they
really are worried about all of that
stuff but then you know behind there is
something else also in the back of the
mind you know there it's important for
them to understand what's going on
so we'll zoom into it and then we see
that there they know about some bugs you
know which are gonna own them somebody
must have mentioned them in some board
meeting you know a guy walking past uh
so they're worried about them also it's
not like they're not worried about it
and at the same time
there's another human you know they know
about and this human is that sharply
dressed colleague which they have and
and they have like the cippee ETC on
LinkedIn okay this person is the privacy
officer the Chief privacy officer so we
we started looking at their mind also
now okay and and the Chief privacy
officer is worried about gdpr you know
you talk to Chief privacy officers okay
gdpr is is my stuff GDP compliant or not
are like CCPA you know and then they
also worry about some conferences like
iappp organizations like that and then
compliance these are you know is the
data fine they're worried about that and
then there's this nagging question that
they always have so in Paradigm of a
privacy policy we say that we don't
collect precise location but on the
random Channel I saw this map of our
customers doing SBB Bank runs okay and
people were joking about it so how did
this information go there so I I think
they are worried about stuff you know
it's but but they just don't know
exactly how to tackle it uh but there
are reasons for it and and during my
movement from security and privacy and
security all together throughout these
years
I have realized that privacy operations
work like this there are three buckets
of people who touch privacy essentially
so I think the first is the lawyers on
the side uh they they they do high level
gdpr type mandates uh very important uh
they're more reactive so they look at
privacy events very carefully on on what
has happened what is going to happen and
they have a very compliance kind of
mindset are we compliant with this law
is it is it fine or not this is very
important for large organization to run
efficiently not get into trouble uh and
then they also rely very deeply with uh
security data or privacy operations uh
which actually own in putting those laws
in action they try to implement what is
going on uh you know they're tracking
all the changes flows to all the data
inside the org run privacy assessments
data subject access requests these are
these are all these terms you're going
to hear in privacy they come from a very
safety kind of mindset we we have a
responsibility to save Safeguard the
data that is coming in and then on the
other side are developers they are very
decoupled from from other orgs as I have
observed they are actually these are the
people who will actually solve a problem
so so if if some change has to be done
in the code to keep the app safe uh to
implement privacy respecting features
and it it goes to them so so really the
problem the solution of the problem is
there okay and and then a lot of people
are revolving around these buckets uh
Gathering or or not having the
developers you know get into the I would
say say the same table I would say
so uh there are common grounds in
security and privacy uh you know I tried
to put them in this nice Venn diagram
because Venn diagrams always look cool
so uh security folks you know you can
see they care about injection or bypass
Network stuff some CV CWS you know they
care about you know that path reversal I
guess and then uh they also care about
some other stuff like they care about
data security and sensitive data leaks
there's a huge whole section about that
you know like CW 200 they care about
information leaks it's not like they
don't care about it but they look at
this from their angle as if it's one of
the points inside the thing that we have
to fix and and we are done uh the other
folks privacy folks care about a lot of
other things that these folks don't know
about at all like these are dpia privacy
impact assessments you know so their
privacy impact assessments are run on
spreadsheets right now in a lot of
organizations I've talked to a lot of
organizations to folks working in
forsake they would think how can you run
a whole thing like this you know like a
provable thing where sensitive data uh
like are you recording precise location
it takes like two to three months for
them to get this information from
Engineers it's it's it's weird but this
is really what happens so they care
about this and there is a common ground
that is there uh the goal is that we
need to understand that Common Ground so
right now the pull is is too much on the
other sides but you know eventually we
are going to fix this
so the conundrum is like this there's a
lot of code it produces a lot of data
you know so the data that is coming in
all these databases going from one place
to another place going in the log you
know getting leaked somewhere it's
coming from code code is responsible for
that and privacy operation is like
someone with a broom trying to you know
brush this water spilling on on on on
the surface you know it's it's not going
to work they try their best and going a
little bit deep this is kind of like an
example of an actual code where you can
see that uh there's username you know
it's it's something that is coming from
the user and eventually if you look at
the code you will see that it gets
logged uh you know in a log and in
reality what's going to happen because
I've seen some operations inside is they
go to some 10 databases here and there
one other log service you know running
somewhere else and then some innocent
human you know who never even cared
about it they have access to it and they
just don't tell anybody you know because
they don't care about it but uh
technically it is bad because because
that's data that gets leaked and it's in
front of someone who should not have it
so privacy operations are going to look
at many places and trying to understand
this they will look at databases trying
to remove stuff from databases if they
find private information there
but the reality is that the developer
really knows where this data is how we
put them there so so there is an
opportunity here to try to fix it at the
left layer and this is the whole thesis
of this talk we haven't even begin you
know so uh we will begin and uh the
thesis is that if we can analyze code
properly we might be able to fix a lot
of vulnerabilities that are in security
and also at the intersection of privacy
so making everyone happy
so the goal is to develop uh privacy
tools for developers and Engineers we'll
see how we can build them we use the
technical static analysis age-old
technique we'll see how it works so uh
static analysis is analysis of a program
or a piece of software before it even
runs and then predicting what's going to
happen when it runs so it's kind of like
magic so so that's what it is uh you
have to understand a few concept sources
so if you look at the look on the right
hand side interesting points where the
data can begin so here is here is data
coming inside this little function and
then trying to track it all the way to
syn sync so tainting it all the way so
that you can do like a nice data flow
analysis so these are some some sort of
Concepts you'll you'll have to remember
sources saying stains and data flow
um and you know like why why we try to
do this is because how humans understand
you know code we also understand it like
that you when I told you about this we
is of code you started looking in your
head about HTTP then seeing okay it goes
to location and then it goes here so
computers also understand it exactly
like that so why not we just leverage
this so so that's kind of like the
thesis behind this
so looking at the same piece of code
this is how you would think inside your
head you would look at this HTTP
variable you will tag it in your head
you will mark it as source and then try
to see where it is going and then see it
goes to an info then you try to look at
what is the type of this info okay this
looks like the logger you know from
Apache log for J okay this is
interesting for me I should start
tracking it so
um after this mapping is has been done
you can ask this question so this is
your goal you know when you try to
analyze software so find a flow from a
variable which is pii geolocation to
sync log function of patch package
Apache log project so you might have
this you know thinking in your head
trying to understand a piece of code and
that's what you do mentally so uh so the
goal of static analysis is to try to
model this you know uh using computers
we have been doing this for ages uh
compilers have been doing half of this
work all the time so we are just going
to leverage that
so why should we do this because code is
actually the true container producer
mover of data so why not just analyze
data from that layer rather than just
looking at it when it gets stored
somewhere so we can find bugs early in
the software development life cycle you
know try to fix things very early rather
than trying to be you know reactive and
trying to look at things at runtime
so uh how do we do this so before we do
this we'll have to do a deep dive and
understand what is even code so
existential questions like this in
computer science can be solved by
complex things like this so I'm not
going to go through all of it but
essentially what you need to know is
that this is how computers are going to
understand this little line you know end
Y equals X plus 50 uh it converts it
into this nice tree format just remember
the name AST and then eventually through
this AST we are able to get this control
for graph on the right hand side how
control passes between different points
inside the application inside the
function remember we are not even
executing anything it's just statically
analyzing the whole uh you know piece of
code and trying to understand that and
take a good note at this yellow thing
there orange thing so so that's
essentially where our data is so with
this information embedded in these nice
trees and graphs that you see we are
able to to get a dependence tree so that
we know that the value of Z depends on
the value y depends on the value of x so
by doing this you can see where we are
approaching we are eventually building
like data flow of of a complete
application
so but programs are more complex they
are not single lines of code uh real
programs look like this and they have
more abstractions in in them so so there
are class and types which have been
introduced a variable can be a member
variable it can be a local variable
there is a package now or namespace
based on what language you have I mean
procedure function methods I mean these
are all variants of of things uh so so
we have these new new abstractions that
have been added and then there is a
relationship between them so
for example this method get patient that
you saw before
is defined in in this class patient
controller which instantiates another
variable and the method also contains a
call which is find body so you can see
programs will become huge you know when
you convert them to a graphical format
and that's that's essentially what we
try to do we try to achieve so uh to
embed all this information and Abstract
syntax tree the information about calls
information about data flow we use an
approach of building a graph like a
massive graph which has all this
information and the base layer of that
would be an abstract syntax tree so it's
a tree which has all the little little
information about uh for example here
you know X plus 50 equals y so so this
kind of information is embedded in a
graph like that we'll have that
information of the whole code embedded
as one of the base layers and then we
enhance it we try to build more
information over it so we have control
flow and data flow information over it
and then eventually build more
information over it where you know we
can have a human kind of question that
we can ask okay give me all the methods
which have patient in their name so this
kind of information is now embedded
because we have this nice graph this
whole thing is called as a code property
graph a colleague of mine invented this
you can go on the Wikipedia article and
you can read about this
uh so so a big graph and it's a
queryable graph you can query it and ask
questions so uh languages different
languages whatever code is written in
different languages that's front end and
then the front end uh you know creates
this nice graph and then you can query
the graph using a query engine so in
real world it would be like how it would
how you can operationalize is is there
is a Java app you have and then it
converts to this graph and then you have
this question a human-like question that
you had you can ask this question and
then the graph returns an answer it says
okay I found one flow you know starts
from HTTP ends to the first parameter of
info uh on this line on this file so you
have a lot of this information embedded
completely in it
how we can use this
so what if we could run thousands of
these queries on millions of lines of
code okay it's not AI it's just it's a
simple stuff okay we are not gonna do a
lot of llm AI stuff it's very simple
thousands of these queries formulate
these nice queries and run this on
millions and millions of lines of code
it's gonna throw out interesting flows
which you can see which are provable
that this data went from here and ended
up there so that's essentially the way
way we can solve this
and to do this we build this tool called
Privado scan which starts scaling static
analysis and and tunes specifically for
privacy
uh Privado scan is open source uh you
know there are three components of it
there are three repos Privado Privado
core and provada CLI uh There Are Rules
which are defined in nice yamls very
easy to remember very straightforward uh
the engine uh it generates the cpg
converts these rules to actual queries
so these millions of queries and then
runs these queries on on uh you know a
lot of code and then you can view the
results by default there's a Json and
something on the CLI but then you can
also visualize it on a community
dashboard that we have
Privado is lgpl so you can download and
play with this
how does this work so source code
converts to this graph we talked about
yaml rules query and then results as I
just told you you get something like
this so five flows where data is Flowing
from flowing to AWS S3 so so you can
even embed these kind of you know syncs
in in the system so it's flowing to a DB
it's written to a file and then you can
go through the system and understand
where the data is exactly going so you
can try this out uh there's a simple
curl command here to try this out
you should not do this because you know
yeah so uh and then you can just run
provider scan
um
we'll go to a demo now uh I hope the
demo Works uh because we should start
praying to the demo Gods now so uh
system is set up here it's very simple I
think I should uh make this a bit
smaller I guess here is this good
okay
okay uh can everyone see this
awesome uh okay I need two hands but one
is occupied so the brain has to think
okay uh
so I have some commands already added it
says Privado scan banking system back in
there banking system backend is a repo
it has some sensitive data and then
we'll try to discover if it flows
somewhere
um you know I've already scanned it so I
know what happens but it's for you to
see what happens
so uh let's run this and this is uh so
Privado is packaged in in like a Docker
container so now this is this is running
here uh you can see that
um you know we detected that the
language is Java you know it looks at
configuration it's trying to download
some dependencies which might be there
so for example Imports Etc that you do
in Java it's trying to understand all of
that uh and then you know it will start
parsing source code so static analysis
takes time so it's it's gonna take time
but uh surprisingly it's very fast I was
told that uh in in some organizations
that were doing static analysis that
they used to run there's stuff on
weekends and then go back and on Monday
they would come with like thousands of
things in the list and I never
understood how people can do this but
you know this is pretty fast for for the
size of this code so we ran a lot of
passes over this graph uh people working
in compilers would understand what
passes are so we ran a lot of these
passes over this nice graph and we were
able to detect a lot of things uh
related to privacy here so so you can
see there there is some data elements so
we have uh 11 data elements total uh you
know one third party and then you know
two storages and then information about
those data elements so they are also
classified so we have a way to classify
those data elements also
um you can see we have some passport
information age phone number date of
birth and where it is going so for
example date of birth is getting
collected in these routes it's also
going to this database htfc bank one we
we understood because there was this
information was in the configuration uh
for some place some things we can we can
also detect third parties so this is
getting shared to this fast to SMS thing
uh you know and then uh there is a nice
dashboard to view this also I'll try to
open it let's see
okay so so uh this is how you know it
looks so you have these data elements on
on the left side and and then you see
data going uh all the way on the right
side so here we can see like phone
number we were looking at phone number
we can see where phone number went uh it
it went it was getting shared to fast
SMS goes into the storage and then you
can click on code analysis and see this
literally line by line how this was
going from one uh place to another uh
and then you you can see eventually you
know you created a URL connection and
then maybe you know the string in url
was fast to SMS and then that's how it
detected that essentially you made a
call to that and the phone number was a
part of that message that went there so
so this is a this is an example uh
contrary to a lot of what people say I
find this thing very interesting you
know like stuff going into logs uh is is
one of the interesting things that I
find here so uh that brings me to the
end of the demo uh you can try to play
around with it with your own
um with your own
repos also try with Java python is also
there python is beat beta at that time
at this time and JS is also beta but I
think Java is working very well so
please play around with this
um where do we go next so I think if if
someone asks me what we should do you
know in privacy this would be something
very golden for me you know a privacy
policy very high level stuff that you
know lawyer folks would understand much
more better you know with cippe stuff on
their LinkedIn uh we want to understand
how they translate to gdpr violations
you know gdpr or any other law so gdpr
is like a you know kind of like a larger
term that I'm using for CCPA or any
other kind of pip Eda for Canada so so
these kind of regulations which are
there so any violation connected with
the policy that you already have in your
organization and then an actual bug
inside the code so so this would be this
would be like the the golden you know
kind of like the Holy Grail of of
getting privacy done properly it's very
difficult to do this we can do half of
it you can do one piece of it but
through and through it's very difficult
but people are trying
um there's a research paper below you
can see see this I mean this this has
been talking about a very similar
approach and they are also doing
something like that
um and then you know find these exact
privacy violations and suggest some
automated ways to fix them you know we
can we can definitely leverage uh AI or
the advances in AI right now for that I
think the time is there the models are
just not yet there but I think they are
almost there
um and then build a complete
organizational data flow not just by
analyzing code but also databases apis
document or your complete infrastructure
so so like a large complete large map of
where data can start from where it can
go just by doing scanning on of all
these individual components so till now
we have been scanning something some DBS
here and then someone looks at a
document puts it in a spreadsheet sends
it to somebody else a lot of manual
processes going on right now we can
do everything by just scanning all of
these pieces one by one and then
correlating them that would be pretty
interesting
okay uh I think we are almost at the end
of this so last comment you know which I
would want to say that if your clothes
had as much value as your private
information I can bet some privacy
policy would be there and they won't
mind asking you to send them your
underwear before you order a cab I mean
this is the state that we are in right
now related to privacy so so please take
care of your private information that's
that's all I would say uh here are some
additional links for docs rules engine
for Privado uh I I also recommend you
reading the nist Privacy framework and
not just the security one the Privacy
one here and there's a tool by Microsoft
data protection mapping framework which
which maps all these different you know
these uh we we all know the miter attack
framework or over top 10 Etc I mean in
security we know this but in privacy
there is an effort to map all these
different uh kind of Standards into each
other so that that's essentially what
this is
okay uh and so questions
thank you
okay so um let's start with ah there we
go amazing magic so do you think this
approach could encourage organizations
to retain pii in a dangerous way uh and
should we focus on privacy by Design
good question
so I I I think this is actual privacy by
Design I mean yes they they are
retaining your information anyways you
know you would be surprised to know how
much information they retain on you and
you'll be surprised to know that they
have no clue what to do with this so
it's they're already retaining it I mean
there's no uh question about it and and
every time someone says that we are not
going to collect this or we are
compliant with this uh you know
I I think I can bet I I don't know maybe
it's too dangerous but I will still bet
that they have your information okay uh
and in somewhere in some of the
databases and they don't know about it
so they're not wrong in it it's just
that they don't know about it but since
they are collecting it anyways through
these various you know means a marketing
person came in and then said I need this
thing in the analytics can you put it
nobody else knows about what they asked
and where it where the data is going uh
the better thing is to get to have an
understanding that it is going there and
then stop it so so this I believe is a
way to do privacy by Design By Doing
static analysis of code and actually
understanding where it's exactly going
does that answer the question or I was
just going around you know beating about
the bush
we will never know if the person who
asked the question is actually in the
room
any other questions I'm not seeing
anything popping up yet oh never mind
that is a lie uh so here we go
how such is it even possible for this
kind of analysis to help with the
confused Deputy problem your example of
the incrementing ID revealing adhar's
numbers
uh can you remind me the confused Deputy
problem
All Right audience
I don't know the confused Deputy problem
so I'm lost
okay got it yeah so
um
so I think when you actually do code
analysis and try to understand how this
information was collected for example
let's take the other number so so if you
look at the system you will see that the
other number was collected in this
certain variable and we see that it went
all the way here to uh you know populate
this template in this you know jsx file
you know and here it was going you would
actually you would have a complete flow
of where the data went to and if in
between that there was no check or
authentication you can actually prove
and find it that this was missing this
uh authentication was missing so this
person is not authorized to view it so
you can find it but if you didn't I mean
obviously the flow is supposed to be
there it's it's a data that came from
somewhere and you know is supposed to be
shown on the site but if it's not
authenticated you can prove it that this
was not authenticated so it's a
violation
okay and we've got another one
let's see uh won't companies actually
want to stay away from tools like yours
so that they can keep claiming that they
did not know hundred percent
hundred percent they want to be away
from us as much as possible uh but
hundred percent they will be slapped
with like you know 60 million dollar
fine you know because like last week
there were three uh you know
um in in EU so EU is very strict on this
right now you know last two years they
have they have started you know clearing
court cases which had been pending for
quite some time and they are going to
get fined so it's the same thing that
happens in in cyber security so you know
like fear-driven fixes which should not
be there people should intrinsically be
motivated to not leak information but
they don't do it so the other approach
is they'll get fined and then they will
come to us to either detect where the
issue was there or you know bake privacy
by Design the way it is supposed to be
but I I would not be too pessimistic
about it because I'm interacting with a
lot of companies and and they are uh you
know really coming to us from any
engineering perspective for the first
time never experience this like somebody
uh a large organization coming to us and
saying oh we know that all of the stuff
is fine with us but we actually want to
bake privacy by Design so it's it's a
new thing you know and privacy buying
design privacy by Design and these
techniques being pioneered here itself
in Canada I mean it's it's a big thing
all right going once going
twice all right I think I think that's
all we got thank you so much sushakra
okay appreciate your time
[Applause]
and then we'll be back for the next
presentation which is the last of the
day well
there's the uh North Seck 10 years panel
and then there's a cocktail but the last
in this room
[Music]
foreign
come on there
[Music]
foreign
we're good to go so we're going to get
started with the uh last talk of this
track
um so we've got some guests today who
came from halfway across the world so um
on up on stage we have a Hagen vardanian
uh he's the CTO of red rays and his
expertise includes protecting vital
business applications including Erp CRM
SRM Banking and processing software he's
a well-known Authority on Enterprise
application security including sap and
Oracle he's published many
vulnerabilities and speaks regularly at
conferences across the world as we can
see and special thanks to these folks
for for making it here
um and as you can see the youngest team
member is over here and really awesome
so thank you so much
um uh hello I'm excited to share my
presentation with you today uh which
focused on the vulnerability chains in
the sap softwares and today I will
demonstrate how to possible to escalate
privileges in sap and jump from
on-premises networks to the sap clouds
um
here is the oh sorry
yep
um here's our agenda and
um
I I think it will help help you to
understand the flow of our presentation
my name is vahagan I'm CTO of red race
and rpne she's a CEO of Red race a few
words about red race red race is a
research and development center in
Armenia we founded in two years ago
and since 2021 we discovered over 50
zero days in Enterprise software
especially sap Oracle Etc
so what is sap
the sap is a multinational software
corporation that's specialized in
Enterprise softwares developing
including enterprise resource planning
softwares
and Erp software is used by businesses
of all the sites across
all Industries to manage the uh today
operations okay
um a short story of the research last
year one of our customer request us
um
to
analyze their sap landscape
the sap landscape was very hard but here
I I wanted to show very simple Network
structure
the customer give us an access as a
regular user in the user space and the
request was
uh Hey guys is it possible to find out
some vulnerabilities or is it possible
to get information from sap cloud
from the user
user environments user Network
environments right
so we started to analyze and first of
all we built this map as you can see we
split the map by three parts the first
one is a user environment the second one
is on-premises sap servers environment
and the third one is sap Cloud
environment
um the end users didn't have access to
this AP Cloud directly so they have
connection only to the sap servers on
on-premises network right but the main
components was a cloud connector that
was connected to the zip cloud and was
connected to another saps in on-premises
so it means that if you if if you would
like to compromise the sap cloud or get
information
in sap Cloud we should compromise the
sap Cloud connector right
but to compromise the CP Cloud connector
we can we should compromise the sap
servers so we need to jump there there
and in the cloud
okay when we are compromising the sap
servers usually we can have
four type of access the first access it
can be admin user in sap application
and the second one we can get access to
the sap database the third one is
vulnerability or access when we can read
application we can read files from the
sap application using some directory
traversal just for example or we can
execute some code or command in sap
servers
okay before we will we'll
um I will demonstrate the vulnerability
I'd like to mention that all the
vulnerabilities has been discovered by
Red race during the that assessment
only except one the CV from 2021 we just
rested it
um
uh and all the screenshots that I will
demonstrate I will show you it's from
Red race demo server as as you are I
think you can understand that I can't
show the screenshots uh from our
customer servers
okay
so first of all we analyzed we scan the
sap applications and as the our customer
was from gazunt oil industry
we saw that he used sap manufacturing
execution model
the sap manufacturing execution model
is you um is using in many many
Industries
and the the me sap me model is a Java
application that is deploying in Java uh
Stacks application Java stacks
so uh as the redress is a partner of sap
we could download that component and we
started to analyze to discover some
vulnerabilities there
um we had a lot of low privileged user
and
um we
during the research we found vemo
deleo.jsp file in the sapme component
and as you can see from the this line
um this GSP script is receiving file
path
um some file path parameter and
um
using file parameter value he's reading
the file and he's printing that content
of the file in the page right
uh
um the payload of the execution is
here
and I'm showing this this payload here
the first time after the fixing
so
right now we have a access to the sap
application server as I mean we can read
the files from this API application okay
then we need to try to escalate our
privileges in sap to get access to
another levels
the Privileges collection number one
the main thing is that sap is stored
some critical information in the file
system and under this screenshot you can
see two files so extort.preps and sex
store.key
sector.properties file
contains in encrypted mode application
admin password and gdbc connection
string with username and password
as we are in the sap cyber security
industry over 10 years we know the
encryption algorithm and of course we
know we have the key of the encryption
and the encryption algorithm is the
triple Dash we decrypt it
and we got the
sap admin application password here and
gdbc connection string okay
so right now we have a admin user of sap
application and we could connect to the
sap database
so what what's next we need to but if
you remember the network map we should
compromise the sap cloud
we try to escalate our privileges again
we escalate privileges by two ways I
will show you here the first way because
the second way still is not fixed by sap
and I could show it here you can we
analyzed the exist other vulnerabilities
and we found CV 2021 from 2021 and as
you can see from the screenshot the
for execution this vulnerability you
need to have privilege uh high but we
already have it okay so
if the sap admins is not updated this
component it means that we can execute
this vulnerability also
um again we download this component we
made a diff and we found that the sap
fixed
the vulnerability in handle save
function by uploading some file
and they are checking dot JSP in
lowercase and Dot JSP in uppercase
file extension a small tip
tipping trick from me if you have some
Java application and you are trying to
upload the GSP file and the Java
application is telling you hey you can't
upload.gsp try to upload with uppercases
it can be work
um you
information we of the vulnerable servlet
name function and others we built the
proof of concept
and again I I'm showing the proof of
concept first time after the fixing and
we sent that this the following HTTP
request to the sap server and it works
it works sorry
um
here we can see that we executed the
tasks list command
and we can right now we can execute the
command in the sap servers but
if you see the screenshot on the shell
script is not displaying the username of
soft processes it means that the user
which running our shell script doesn't
have enough privileges to show that info
right
so what what we need to do
we need to escalate privileges again
um
after
um we we started to analyze the sap
processes by Proto soccer
and we discovered three processes
that
um
running under system user okay
for us interesting was the following
processes sap host exec and sap OS call
exit files processes sorry
um
we
use the process monitor for
uh tracking the activities of that that
processes and
um we started to analyze and we started
to
um tracking what kind of file they're
creating executing modifying Etc
and we saw that there are a few
activities but the most interesting was
that the sap host exec process this one
is executing every two minutes sapci
mb.process.exe process after analyzing
permissions of that file we found out
that many user sorry any user from the
operation system of sap server could
delete that file and write file by this
name in the folder so what we did
we built
who created the Shell Code in.net built
and uploaded to the Windows machine
the Shell Code was opened
should open the port 444 listen any
interface and when he received the
commands he should execute that command
by CMD
okay we'll upload that file and we
replace the sap
cimb.xf file
and it worked
the sap host exec is executed our shell
file and I don't know why I don't know
what was wrong but our shell file was
has been signed but by sapse
maybe it come from sap maybe it's back
in process hacker I need to investigate
but
you can see the
in the screenshot that our shell script
has been signed
so after the executing netcat
netstat sorry you can see that Port has
been open
and we should we could connect to that
shell and execute it with my command and
yeah where system
so that's it
but
um
again you remember that we should
compromise the sap Cloud right
we need to jump to the from the one of
the sap sap servers here from sap Java
to Cloud connector
uh to do that we decided to
dump memory of LSS process
our customers say that we couldn't as we
are system we could disable the
Microsoft antivirus and use mimikas
there but he said we couldn't disable
the antivirus we couldn't extract the
jump to our
Windows machine to analyze that dump so
uh
we had another way only we downloaded
the
um
c-sharp mini dump from the GitHub and
build that program
to dump the process
the dump memory of the lsas process
right
but
of course this program is detected by
antivirus and by any antivirus included
Microsoft antivirus so we try to modify
that file
and the source code of the
sharp mini dump we modified it we
replied some screen strings we replace
strings by Charles Rice we compiled
again and uh
we again has been detected by Microsoft
antivirus and you know the bypass was so
beautiful
we just
uh set some file extension uh to we we
used file extension that is not has been
registered in videos machine
and we executed by CMD C minidump
bypassmas.exe dot PPP and it has been
executed and he dumped the password and
hashes of the processes okay
so after that we had
the
uh
admin users and password from
application and from operation system
and right now we should jump to the mic
sap Cloud connector sorry
and you know how we jump uh it was so
easy
because
in the last game there was over 100 sap
servers
and the sap admin said
the same password for all the sap
servers landscape
so we jump to the sap Cloud connector
we connected to sap Cloud connector by
SSH and started to analyze the system
as the sap cc is based on the page
Tomcat the password was in users.xml
file
here
in Hessian mode in hershit mode
so we continue to analyze the system to
get other ways how it's possible to
discover the password
um we found sap ssfs file the ssfs it's
a modern sap
a Secure Storage
and
um
which we should try to decrypt this
Secure Storage
um
after some researching
of ssfs structure for sapcc we found
that
the sapcc ssfs contains the following
properties should contain the following
properties
but
the encryption algorithm has been
written in binary files and reversing
that binary files can be take a long
time for us
and we
choose another way
uh we
with so that there are leap sap
scc20jni.so file
and that file had
one exported function
sex store access get record
and what we did we just used that so
Library
as a native function here
we use that function in our mini Java
got and
um
as argument we passed the properties
that we discovered
this one and this one and we got
the password for Java case storage and
admin
password for the sap Cloud connector
so what next we open the sap Cloud
connector UI
and log in there and right now we can
manage the sap
um connections we can move the traffic
from the cloud to our servers or we can
move traffic from on-premises systems to
ours to our another server and we can
manage the traffic we can listen the
traffic we can discover some private
info
Etc
um
so as a conclusion
you the sap admins should install the
sap
security notes that we discovered and
they shouldn't use the same password for
sap
operation systems they should use
different passwords for different
systems I know it can be so hard for the
admins but it's another is the is the
one way for protecting the sap servers
for password reuse attack
so that's it thank you if you have any
questions
[Applause]
all right folks you know how this works
at this point
um priority to anyone who submits via
slido will also give it a couple minutes
and if anyone is feeling brave you can
also ask and I will repeat the question
so I refresh
it's supposed to be real time it's not
that real time
okay
anyone with questions
I'm gonna
call it a day shortly
all right
um I guess we we're done in this track
for the day thank you again so much it's
a pleasure having you and thanks for
walking us through that that was
excellent
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
come on there
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
come on there
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]