it
hey hey
Thunderbird
attack
hey hey
[Music]
hello we hey we're about to we're gonna
be starting quite soon and now I would
like to invite on the stage three teams
team 34-6 in Bravo
saw the door exor and uh system
thank you
[Music]
we're gonna get some refreshments for
our great people on the stage
brave people
um
[Music]
foreign
for the 10th or 11th year in a row
[Music]
he's welcome your host of hacker
Jeopardy
every year the wonderful it's crazy they
are exuberant Olivia
[Applause]
hello hello everyone how are you
forgot to turn my tie on let's wait a
minute
already [ __ ] it up
okay
let me grab my cue card so welcome
everyone
by now I think you're used to some of
this isn't that okay
so we decided to bring the team up on
stage early so that we will
um have them uh have drinks in advance
uh on stage now I'm not sure who is
where so on the stage we have 34 6 and
Bravo
razor glass yes thank you
we have zorbed the all
and we have system de torch
all right so
this is a a semi-serious competition and
competition means that there will be
prizes uh our prices uh tonight so the
prices are at the end of the three games
so we will have a ladder so this game
will create a winner that winner will go
on the third round
what was that
play that again
okay you lost the button I guess
um and so the the second rounds winner
will also reach the third round and in
the third round we bring in the north
SEC crew against the two best teams and
the second place of that round will win
one bottle of Club mate
[Applause]
wait wait wait there's more one bottle
of Club mate each
on top of that a UB key
yeah we felt cheap with one bottle of
Clemente but those who were there last
year remember that that was the second
place uh Prize last year so we're not
innovating that much we're gonna get
more money we added the UB key but
Jokes Aside or you know trying to be
funny aside uh the first place is uh we
have so for each individual we have uh
well I should step back here because you
you think this is crazy so we have three
prizes so the three person one price
each it will be a flipper zero for one
of their contestant Bazinga a uber suit
one and a UB key for another of the
contestants accept that yes and a covert
luck pick starter kit and USB rubber
ducky for the Third contester
and of course North SEC can't win so
this will go to the winners of the
rounds
okay well oh my God I will not wear that
jacket the whole time it's hot here
um we uh I'm gonna just go quickly
through the game rules for those who
haven't been with us for 11 years
um
so the start of the game is picked
randomly you remember our famous random
number generator
any team can answer you smash the button
Jeopardy is negative scoring so an
attempted answer that is wrong uh
means negative points
the winning team team that answers
successfully keeps the control so they
will tell the next clue that they want
to have that they want to see
um uh yeah and then so it's you know 100
Point 100 is worth 100.200 is worth 200
points and all that and it's summed up
and you'll see the score as we go I'm
gonna recap the scores from time to time
I'm not going to tell these rules every
round so here we go
and we don't have a final Jeopardy since
uh six years I think this didn't change
president now
didn't get time to do that
all right so I
um let's are you ready
[Applause]
okay okay okay so cheers everyone
let's get this over with
oh yeah true true thank you thank you so
contestant you need to answer in the
form of a question obviously which I
always forget but our wonderful crowd
always remembers
so we'll get that sorted out now I
realize my cue cards are not sword they
are bundled together by round but I
didn't put the round in order so when we
will reveal the category I'll take a few
seconds to order that and then we'll
start
we have
I can't I can't like
um succeed at all of the little things
right so we have better lighting than
last year
but the cue cards are [ __ ] up
okay let's reveal the categories please
so we have it's over nine thousand it's
over whip
sqli techniques name that key and Mark
now we're lucky because it's the first
set of clues that I have here so I
should have not tell anything and I
would have done okay
yeah let's go with that all right
random please
36 and Bravo you are in control
oh no no no we forgot something we need
to test the buzzers
so please uh one uh Team One please
buzzer okay unlock them please
team two
excellent unlocked
oh you're not sitting in the right spot
switch
you have there is an order to respect
so
um
you sit here and 346 in Bravo you sit
here
so let me explain
allow me to explain what happened
we tried to go faster so I was like why
don't we bring the team on the stage so
that they can have the drinks prepared
and so we can go faster in the game and
now we turn that upside down obviously
okay now we're ready but we need to test
the third buzzer
excellent all right so the random picked
who do we do you remember
pick you guys
but you moved so it was them right
just kidding just kidding all right you
guys pick a category please
uh we'll do Mark for 100. Mark 100 a
lightweight markup language for creating
formatted text using a plain text editor
six what is hypertext markup language
what is hypertext markup language is
wrong
what is markdown is correct
[Applause]
system
yeah
Mark 200 mark 200.
a security feature that prevents
malicious files and attachment from
being executed or opened
the name of the category is Mark
system detached
where is Matsu level where is incorrect
what is the mark what is what the mark
what is the Mark is incorrect
awesome
do we have anyone who wants to pick it
up
because I'm sure the crowd knows
anybody else no
no
so we can time that one out
there I have it oh yeah
Maca spam is incorrect
what is Mark of the web is correct
step Microsoft tags this and adds this
and blah blah blah okay so let's let's
do a random selection for who is in
control of the board
system detosh
you are in control you're on the board
you guys can look uh over there or over
there 300
which one Mark 300 a uniform resource
identifiers that is stored for later
retrieval in in any of various storage
format
urm what is a URL is incorrect
again
you [ __ ] it up
again the category is named Mark
hi Mark
okay anyone else want to try it no it's
a it's so simple and it's that it's like
we forget about such a basic feature
what is a bookmark is correct
[Applause]
what's up
sometimes you explain things in such a
way that they are more complicated
all right so let's do a random to figure
out who's next in control
no another one
Mark 400 no it's not your turn anymore
foreign
okay kind of marker coveredly embedded
in noise tolerance signals such as audio
video or image data
the category is Mark
[Music]
what is marker what is a marker is
incorrect
he's trying he's trying
what is a watermark
what is a watermark is correct
bazinga
right excellent you are in control
Mark for 500. Mark 500 the act of
running a computer program a set of
programs or other operations in order to
assess the relative performance of an
object normally by running a number of
standard tests and trial against it
what is Benchmark what is a benchmark is
correct
[Applause]
I'm not you can spam but you need to
allow before answering you need to let
me finish but they're not locked
all right
still down 300 points but congrats on
that one
you are in control
what is with 100
with 100
346 on Bravo what is a Json web token
what is a Json web token is correct
[Applause]
you are in control
wit for 200 with 200.
[Laughter]
all the developers in the room are like
why is it this long oh who is
all right the crowd do you have any idea
I've heard it over there Google web
toolkit it's an old technology but
all right
um let's do a random and it must be
exhort the ah who has the control
33 34 6 and Bravo your turn
over 9 100 over 9100 a series of Intel
processors that are above that level
what is I9 what is core I9 is correct
you are right
we'll accept that yes
[Applause]
the model numbers of the core I9 series
is live they are models over nine
hundred thousand and nine thousand uh
plus so the first one being
9080 20x
zordo you're in control uh name that
Q100
name that key 100
34 6.
what is a USB key what is a USB key is
correct the correct one yeah
the Fateful one terabyte USB key
all right we're gonna go uh wit for 300.
with 300.
kwt
okay it is it is more commonly known as
KW
but the category is width so it ends
with WT
KW
any electrical engineers in the house
[Music]
what is a kilowatt is correct thank you
doesn't have always to be web Frameworks
all right so um
you can you can hit the random button
many times until we get the theme that
we want remember
you're in control
name that key 200
name that key 200.
yes
what is a key
unfortunately I am expecting a specific
answer here apparently this key is
really well known not a bad guess but
it's bananas
like really well known
34 6 in Bravo
what is a male key a mailbox key what is
a mailbox key is incorrect
all right I'm gonna answer this oh no no
no anyone has the answer
so
the famous name of that key is What is
ch751
I was told it was an easy question
I
[Music]
I mean you guys should wait for the rest
before doing that right
it's not gonna be any better
all right so let's do a random selection
oh yeah yeah oh yeah we need to uh you
need to score the people and no one uh
did anything so you just submit the
score enter
or Summit score
yeah okay
yeah yeah it's although it's ue2 no
worries
we uh we uh has got mode on the software
we can do whatever we want
so for
300 messages
okay I'm gonna accept a broader answer
than the previous one but a key is not
it's too broad I need like an in-between
or some of some sort
it can be the purpose of the key or
where is it commonly used like very
commonly used
I never thought I would be in a room
full of key enthusiasts
so no one come on you're at minus
anyways
let you just gonna be back to zero
you're gonna be
paper in the hole
all right
okay I thought it would be like elevator
key or something like that this is not
what I heard but this is an elevator key
or
the f-e-o-k-one
[Music]
yes yes that's what's ha that's what's
going on
both thank you I like that
all right we're back to the board and
let's do a random pick
you're on the board the 34 6 in Bravo
will do it's over 9000 for 200 please
over nine thousand four hundred this
transport layer protocol has meme like
RFC number
some would even say it's related with
the web
thank you
all right I wanna I just want to say
this um
this is the RFC questions and hacker
Jeopardy are almost always
I don't know what he has with rfcs but
it's a thing really
[Music]
nice one all right so anyone knows
no that's not the one great attempt
though the avian carrier TCP over event
carrier no it's a quick so quick which
became or is the father of HTTP 2 so the
quick protocol uh was uh is actually RFC
9000 and do I have I think I have
exactly so it's not over nine thousand
but I would have accepted TLS
integration of quick protocol which is
9001.
I didn't say it in the form of a
question either you guys didn't get it
okay let's do a random
sqli
this is a spicy one oh no no no no
more kids
you [ __ ] it up I did I didn't
you [ __ ] it up you [ __ ] me up
it's my new board operator he's getting
fired after this
[Music]
the uh the amount I pay well I will be
able to uh to go back to it we have god
mode
um yeah what are we gonna try remote
it's over 9 000 for it 300 over 9 000
the name of the Dragon Ball Z character
who destroys his scouter
34 6 who is Vegeta
who is Vegeta Vegeta who is Vegeta is
correct bazinga
all right
you are in control
uh it's gonna be uh 400 for the same
category please
which one for it's over nine thousand
over nine thousand four hundred
this CPU broke the 9 000 megahertz
barrier when overclocked
I will accept uh uh a broad answer
but it's not like
your uncle's CPU like experimental CPU
it's a it's a product an actual product
all right timeout anyone has any idea
so it's the I9 13900k
man you're gonna hate the 500.
all right let's do the Roundup please
it's your turn
what is uh no what is
sqli 100 sqli 100.
what is union-based SQL injection I
think that's it
yeah you got it
football bosses let's go
sqlite they need 200 please sqli 200.
Union select load file
load pile
this was supposed to be a quick one like
everyone
34 Sig what is the injection
what is injection is incorrect
oh you're so close very incorrect
so this category we like the the
beginning of the first character is like
the the injection point if you want
maybe the single quotes is not showing
here I don't I don't have it my notes
but here the the the the focus is on the
load file like this is a technique
allows you to do stuff
you're done you're done
no no
[Music]
all right so the answer is
arbitrary file read I would have
accepted lfi although it's not an lfi
but I would have accepted the NFI I
would have accepted it but it's uh
arbitrary file read like uh ATC past W
whatever there's an SQL track don't you
guys try it during the CTF
anyway all right so let's pick let's go
with the random
you're on the board
name that key for 400. name that key
400.
yes
so it's a bit small we'll have to look
over here
so it's uh four e nine nine zero six e
eight
fcb66c9 hard-coded key and this is
um
this is uh
here it is so this is a screenshot of
Microsoft's website
they they they they had some hard-coded
keys in there apparently
documented anyone
what is gpp is correct
[Music]
GBP stands for group policy preferences
password password
this is clearly just for pen testers no
one else gives a [ __ ]
[Music]
all right let's do the random I'm no pen
testers I don't give it you're on the
board
guess what name that t500
let's do it
[Laughter]
I guess I hang out with the wrong people
they tell me no no it's a little bit
hard but it's obvious
so this is a hard-coded key in Hardware
which means that you know a whole class
of devices are [ __ ] one this once this
is exposed
uh it's related I need to have a eye
contact with someone to not say anything
stupid but it's related with a key card
access am I right yeah
it's related to key card access
I would accept only the company name as
a correct answer
no shaming we all made mistakes we all
hardcoded the keys and you know secure
building access systems
all right we're gonna time this out
um this was
oh I hear it in the back
so this is the hid eye class master key
which means you can derive all key all
that type of card if you have it
all right so let's do random
you're in control
sqli 300 sqli 300.
so we have the injection point where
which begins with a single quote
or one equals one
divided by select frag from Flags
it looks suspicious
what is an error based SQL injection
what is an error base is going injection
is correct
so I'll take a second here to explain it
it's
uh yeah
so what we have here is that the the
division by a string will generate will
throw an error but in the error will be
the result of the select so this is y is
an error-based sqli
a little bit of Education here
now go do that track
all right stand that thought you're in
control
sqli 400
yeah I I uh it's okay it's clipped it's
missing a little bit here and there but
everything's there yes what is a
time-based blindness good injection
what is it time
[Applause]
here was the sleep function obviously
so you guys are good at sqli oh you're
back on in positive scoring
congratulations
[Applause]
uh leading oh oh the score was not there
yet okay okay so now you're leading
sorry about that
you have plenty of opportunity to [ __ ]
it up though
oh I'll take more beer too
thank you
okay assistant
sqli 500 sqli 500.
this is a spicy one
Caliente
so we have a load file
uh concatenation
way too many backslashes
then there's some information
and oh why are we concatenating like why
didn't we just put it all beginning yes
what is a remote file inclusion
no this is incorrect
[Music]
I didn't hear it speaking the mic
you accepted local when it was clearly
not an answer earlier and now it's the
same thing but I didn't accept that no
one solved it
so here what's happened oh no anyone
else want to try
after this not in that ground just yet
pass okay pass is good pass is good
so yes in the crowd
no
out of bounds so DNS X fail is kind of
the side effect but the name of the sqli
is an out of bound injection
out of band sorry out of band
so here there was a domain name and it
was related to our domain name in the
CTF so I kind of mixed some CTF stuff in
there you know we're only Excel trading
the version but still the the the whole
concept is expressed here
for actually doing this track with me
all right so let's go back and do a
random
system with 400.
with 400.
any um pts yeah
Amazon web token Amazon web token is
incorrect
yeah he [ __ ] it up anyways
[Applause]
Amazon web token was incorrect though
it is uh we are in the case of acronym
Clash uh but I will not accept the
answer although it could have been good
I'm uh I'm in douchebag mode right now
so anyone else want to try
okay I'm gonna get a slide a couple of
hints here and there anyone did Java in
the 2000s
[Music]
now you need to remember that yeah
yeah no I'm sorry no it's SEC is 11
years old so we are like uh we uh we
need to work on
on newer Technologies
no
what is Apache web toolkit what is
Apache web toolkit is incorrect
[Applause]
foreign
no it's not even close like it doesn't
it's there's no like Apache there's no
web there's no there is toolkit there is
toolkit did you say toolkit yeah two Kit
is there no so what are we looking for
abstract Windows toolkit awt it's a Java
technology that no one used except in
universities in the 2000s
sorry about that it's a 400th question
all right let's take a look at the score
we're near the end of the game
34 6 and Bravo zero zorda or minus 100
and system detosh minus 400.
[Music]
we'll do it live all right
what will web team
we'll pick what
you're on the board you're in control
it's over nine thousand over nine
thousand
this geological Epoch saw the last major
ice age
it's over 9 000 years ago
the game can be played right now what is
the younger driest the what the younger
driest the younger driest sounds very
scientific and correct although it is
incorrect
[Music]
thank you
all right do we have anyone who want to
try
okay anyone any uh Ice Age people in the
room
I never thought I would say the the
phrase ice aged people before
the answer is and I should have double
checked actually Francois but um it's
the Holocene period what I had it
oh my God interesting so what is the
Holocene period
he said it like a mouse
no he didn't get the point because it
was a second answer but he was the
second best guess bruh
okay
[Music]
we are though everyone's ready we're
gonna jump right into the 500. all right
it's gonna be a quick one you're on the
board
easiest question of the board by far
go ahead
no no no no one needs to pick just click
on the 500 points ah [ __ ]
[Laughter]
346 in Bravo
what it what is what
what is what is incorrect
unfortunately
thank you
we have no choice all right so I think
people are now trying to play strategic
here I don't know if you saw that
happening but there is some like you're
not the game they say here so that they
would like try and then slide right
under we have a clear winner at minus
100 point so
all right
[Music]
what's funny like I'll take a couple one
minute to explain I was looking for like
of course something ending with WT and I
was like ah what what does and I I tried
chat GPT it completely sucked at it and
in the end I just like framework WT and
I ended up on a framework I have already
bookmarked before in my life
and listen to this I mean you can't make
this up it's a web GUI library in modern
C plus plus
who's gonna do that
anyway so this was WT
and this ends our game
we have 34 6 on Bravo at minus 1000
exodo at minus 100 winning and going in
last round
and system detached at minus 400.
we
there's a cup there's a leftover cup
here guys at uh 34.6
okay messy
okay don't move don't move we're we're
jumping back in right into next round
you'll be back in the not the next this
game but the next one so don't don't go
too far
I'm calling on stage right now cyber
Aegis
we're gonna where are is cyber ages
gonna sit you know
cyberages here
look at me
cyberages
next one is
cold root
cold root up on stage here and now
that's and friends
and navits and friends on the stage here
so we have cyber Aegis
cold root cold root
and navits and friends please
for round two
of our corporations theme building
activity hacker Jeopardy
so you
you are you are navits is it Neves and
Friends X
C
cold root
and uh cyberages correct excellent
all right I'm excited
I have my little notes we're about to
start but not quite yet
we'll wait till everyone is settled oh
my God shots on stage I'm glad our
license allows that
what is it like Fireball
is everyone ready no no no ah why not
oh
so we do we do it like before yeah yeah
it's like priming this is not bribing by
the way in any sense or fashion
sequence
foreign
it's like I uh uh what is bisali in
English
the yellow flower dandelion it's like
biting dandelion Roots like
drinking the juice of it and I know I
was raised on a farm so I know that what
that tastes like
okay
you guys are ready
ready
yes excellent let's reveal the board
[Music]
in the cookie jar
child GPT ATM
the internet Iceberg and famous authors
let's do the random
you're on the
boards and friends you have control
Chad GPD 100
so this is a prompt to chat GPD last
year's nordsec theme was a startup
cryptocurrency company dealing with
mushrooms
this year's theme is a dystopian
Corporation with hints of Freemason lore
suggest a theme for next year in one
sentence
so you need to guess what chat GPT
answered to that
and remember answer in the form of a
question
it just saying like it's it's uh he went
with two with straight into the obvious
this is why it's the 100.
also another another hint or like this
is the hundred points it's the time to
try and fail like later not the best
time now why not try something
I also will accept Loosely like anything
that is in the realm of what it answered
I'm gonna accept of course
no we'll do it live [ __ ] it
all right it's gonna be a boring one
people
it's not uh it doesn't know about Rao at
all
no
not not Chad GPT I don't think so no so
it went straight into cyberpunk
rebellion in a post-apocalyptic City
ruled by a sentient AI
he went straight for it I would have
accepted cyberpunk Rebellion you know
post-apocalyptic any of these would have
been good you see sentient AI all themes
that we explored before also
so we have a theme I guess
all right let's go back to the board and
do a random
you're on the board and friends
um ATM 100 ATM 100 can you please not
stand in front of the monitors we use
them as uh I I reported the word all the
time okay ATM 100. what ATM stands for
what is automated teller machine
what is what automated telomercial what
is automated you're not the team who
punched look at the so this is this is
these guys
what is an automated teller machine
I'm gonna wait for it to be really
specific just give me one second because
I'm French so I need my little cue cards
where is it
so go ahead
what is an automated teller machine
teller machine is correct
automated teller machine
all right now that's some friends you
are in control
you're on the board ATM 200 ATM 200
the name of the attack that makes ATM
spits out cash cold root
uh what is jackpotting what is Jack
potting is correct
you are right and you're back on the
plus side
jackpot
all right you're in control go roof uh
the
SE bird for 100. internet iceberg 100.
the txt file used for indexing the above
water part of the iceberg
you host it on your website and you tell
it not to look at the dirty stuff
foreign
[Applause]
it's a bit small
ER
I have text one second
okay
what is it I need to read the text we
want you to have the best possible user
experience on our website we use cookies
to analyze how visitors like you use our
website
so we can make improvements and we use
cookies
to make sure that the website functions
normally for more information see our
privacy policy what we're looking for
here is why do we have to go through
this hell what what what triggered
this
nonsense the the body of the European
Body of law
bro created
I come on
I [ __ ] it up
I'm okay I'm gonna live through this yes
so uh what is gdpr
no uh
bazinga
so what is gdpr or gdpr cookie prompt a
whole industry got created just out of a
lot all right you want to control navits
uh famous order 100s
famous order 100
I think you you all understand what
we're looking for here right
I mean it's the 100
this person is so famous but at the same
time he hasn't been publicly researching
recently so this makes it maybe a boomer
question
but if you think this is a boomer
question wait until the later ones
you're not gonna like this track
all right anyone
one person
who is HD Moore is correct
excellent let's do a random
friends oh no wait no we spam that at
random another time
they've been in control the whole thing
cyberages
the internet Iceberg 200. internet
iceberg 200.
it's the night the 70s the sea sea is
the place where this type of digital
content is being distributed the FTP
protocol and hacked servers were usually
used for Content distribution cold root
what is the Juarez or where's what is
Juarez or where's or as we said in
Quebec oh that's good
well I don't know if anyone else said
that but I was saying that alone
yeah cold Road you're in control uh the
internet Iceberg for 300. internet
iceberg 300.
a website facilitating access to indexed
binaries from Usenet
I realized my track my rounds are
unbalanced there's a lot of Boomer uh
stuff in this one
Emilio is nodding
I'm surprised you're here and not
playing Zelda right now
it just came out
no one
I don't have the card ready yet you
could have waited longer
nope
yeah news group is kind of the there's a
specific service with this was better
than the others can we get a guess with
immunity Usenet is written in the
question
can we get a guess with immunity use bit
you wrote The Question come on news bin
is correct
so news bin website indexing binaries
from Usenet so basically you could see
you download a lot of stuff that exists
because they were indexing it hard to
find stuff I don't know about any of
this
um let's do a random for the next
question cyberages
what is child gbt for 200 which one
Chad Chad GPT 200.
do you see a future where humans are
identified only by numbers and member of
a large worldwide Corporation why would
that happen in one sentence
cyberages
what is cyberpunk
Cypher calm cyberpunk cyberpunk what is
cyberpunk can I can I
okay
[Applause]
we'll do that
so I'm gonna read I'm gonna read the the
answer and you guys will decide how
about that we already know what the
result would be but so
what is
is this the question
no it's not okay
[Applause]
thank you
you're also fired uh what is in the
future dominated by the consolidation of
power and erosion of individualism
humans may be reduced to Mere numbers
and members of a global Corporation as
control and efficiency supersede
personal identity and autonomy
[Applause]
cyberpunk resume right
let's go they good answer
right you are
you are in control
what is in the cookie jar for 200. in
the cookie jar 200.
the default name of the PHP session
cookie
what is a PHP session
no I I mean
ah sorry it was the other team that yes
is it one sec
it needs to be pretty uh on it because
it's uh you know it's a string
oh here it is okay what is PHP says ID
what is PHP says IDs correct
[Applause]
I wasn't sure if I wasn't
an o or not so I had to use my cue cards
uh now that's you're in control sorry
about that
um well famous authors do other famous
others 200.
[Music]
it's in the URL on GitHub
like you get clone the tool it's there
uh cyber ridges
what is spider labs
uh this is the yeah it moved since then
but it was the original author
so the spider Lazar bursary is archived
and and it's he used to work at spider
labs but this is not the answer we're
looking for unfortunately
anyone else
anyone knows in the crowd
who is correct
or uh
LG and X not sure how I would pronounce
that actually
uh let's do random
cyberages you are in control
Chad GPT for 300. Chad GPD 300.
right now here are the top three themes
of our CTF cold root system detosh and
Hoover hacken who is going to win based
on the team name alone
you need to choose one and answer in one
sentence cold root
uh who is cold root because
um they drink malord
do you think the AI would have said that
yeah like I wrote this this afternoon
they didn't know yet that you were
drinking like dandelion juice I don't
think that's accurate
I think they know yeah oh you think they
yeah they know all right I like that I
like that okay so let's do this of
course it's wrong
hahaha
anyone else want to try
oh one sec
the buzzers are lucky
yes
who are cold root and probably because
they have the word root in the name of
their team
but but it just said cold root and it
was not the answer
oh I mean yeah the name is pretty
important for the whole thing to work
right so it's not that
I'm leaking some information here
anyone else want to try
what is Uber hacking because they're
hacking
you are correct
[Applause]
okay listen to this listen to this this
is I you can't make this up
what is Hooper hacking is likely to win
because it suggests a combination of
technical expertise and a playful
determined attitude
[Applause]
yeah
praise the AI Lord
they are not no longer top three I think
anyways so
AI is wrong cyber ages you're in control
what is in the cookie
cookie cookie jar 300.
um yeah now that's what is the Json web
token what is it Json web token is
correct right you are
Madness you are in control
uh in the cookie jar 400. cookie jar
400.
the cookie attribute name and value that
prevents sending the cookie on any cross
site requests
cold root what is same site
I don't recall
okay yeah name and value so oh same side
uh none
what is safe site none is incorrect
anyone else want to try
so close
so inside what is same side strict same
side and strict is correct
[Applause]
unfortunately so close
you want to control navits you're on the
board in the cookie jar 500. cookie jar
500.
uh underscore underscore CF underscore
BM
that's the clue
it's a difficult one
it's 500 points
we're gonna time it out
anyone knows in the crowd
cold fusion default cookie incorrect
great attempt though CF
clouds there but what specifically
what
but management cookie is correct
cloudflare butt management cookie
you know
stuff you deal with every day
all right let's do a random please
again we're playing for maybe one Club
matte each
think about it uh the internet iceberg
400. internet iceberg 400.
a very secure net punching and Anonymous
system allowing to reach the very bottom
of the iceberg cold root uh what is UPnP
what is UPnP is incorrect
never reached the dark net through UPnP
navits
what is tor what is tor what is Taurus
correct
um
the internet Iceberg 500. internet
iceberg 500.
the anonymity Network gained popularity
after the Silk Road takedown in 2013. it
implements this food related protocol
named garlic routing
cold root
what is the onion router what is the
onion router is incorrect
it's a trick question
onion router was the answer of the
previous Clues
it's kind of a trolling like garlic
onion like these guys are playing games
right
it got popular after the Silk Road
takedown which was on tour so
they were like come to our Network it's
better it's more anonymous
sponsored by the Russians maybe I don't
know
don't quote me on that
no one
crowd
what is i2p is correct
thank you
[Applause]
it's pretty intense techno right there
okay let's look at the scores so we have
cyber ages at 400 cold route at minus
1200 and navids and friends at above
1200. it's over nine thousand pretty
broad range of scoring here but nothing
is done yet everything can go in all
directions
so uh cold root you are in control
uh let's do famous authors 300. famous
author 300.
who is gentle kiwi
gentle kiwi gentle kiwi also or also
Benjamin Del p is correct
[Applause]
famous authors 400 famous authors 400.
so North SEC is 11 years old I remember
I attended Defcon you know around the
beginning of northseek and I I sat on a
talk that he was giving I was really
close to the stage and and back then the
room was used we were lineups and stuff
and I was just like in awe in admiration
of this person who created nmap uh you
know build a business model around the
GPL you know security software but uh
his uh he's using a handle everywhere
trying to give some Clues here and there
but uh he he is not
he's running very important stuff but
he's not about the the fame so it's a
harder one to know but he's super
important like he's hosting critical
mailing lists and doing a lot of good
service for the community
that doesn't give any hint but he's a
good guy
anyone
who is Theodore is correct
not in the form of a question
[Applause]
all right random
navits uh ATM 300.
ATM for 300.
so we're talking attacks techniques you
know you describe what you see cyberages
what is card skimmer what is a card
skimmer is correct
you got it
cyberages you are in control
what is ATM 500
500 jumping to the 500 400. you could
you can there are no rules
[Applause]
all right ATM 500
[ __ ] it the full name of the standards
body governing the xfs standard
cyberages what is
the full name
not the acronym
so you're close I think
all right so nope
anyone else yes but it's bananas
trying the
track would probably have come through
this several times by now and we're
probably embody that name I've come
across the xcf but I didn't read the
name of the it's going on the top of the
document yeah but that was not important
all spelled out all right so anyone
anyone playing the ATM track who is
grinding xfs right now and struggling
their name is a European committee for
standardization the acronym is c e m
big climax here
[Music]
all right thank you so no one succeeded
and let's go back to the random
now and friends let's go with ATM 400
ATM 400.
what issue caused by poor Bank coding
practices are most exploited to skim EMV
cars
it's a ongoing problem right now
oh I see our badges are
having a similar pattern activity now
there's someone messing with them
interesting look around
we're all like
it's not really into the question
that's cool
I wonder like don't have I Security on
this thing
maybe not
so no one's trying all right so they uh
the the answer it's a pretty tough one I
realize now uh
it's the lack of CVV validation so they
validate a lot of stuff but not the CVV
or the icbv so it causes right now it's
a big problem foreign
thank you
all right back to the the board and do a
random
unfortunately uh Chad GPT 400. Chad GPT
400.
which is the superior annotation format
tab spaces or no characters
answer in one sentence and don't be
nuanced you need to choose one
cold root uh the answer was tabs and it
there is no justification it's just tabs
you wish you would be through but it's
not the case
wrong answer
so anyone else can try maybe it's null
characters
we don't know it's a computer it's an AI
I I can't believe you guys are not like
spamming the button right now
so there's like tabs
Paces or no
they tried tabs
and it didn't work
[Music]
cyberages
spaces because it could be used across
multiple uh coding platforms
[Applause]
oh
what if it was not in the form of a
question unfortunately
I'm sorry
it's wrong
I can't tell yep they had they can't
take the answer
anything
[Applause]
what are spaces what are spaces is
correct
bazinga
and that was it
no explanation
uh let's go it was tough to make it
decide like we had to really like drill
it down to like
shut the [ __ ] up and choose
yes navits let's go with charging PT
again four five hundred chat gbt 500.
be ready what is the most important
software vulnerability in one sentence
navits what are humans
that's
[Applause]
thank you
but it's incorrect
[Music]
anyone else Hawaii he [ __ ] it up
anyone else
I guess I should have wrote I this is
the exact prompt we're not playing games
here but I guess I should have added
class of software available
you see
can help you choose Maybe
and it's not Exorcist
look guys
surprised
look I want several of our early
competitions solely with xss back in the
bulldogging style days
world
all right
what do you think
remote code execution is correct
this was like easy
disappointed
ah shut up
um sorry about that
we have one question left so I guess
already
we're gonna show it and we're gonna play
famous authors 500.
uh we I think we can straight jump to
the crowd
I knew all the other ones
but like before looking or researching
but this one I didn't
but now I will forget I will remember
all my life because it's easy Once you
know it's a nickname
taking a souvenir
what's that
uh no I'm not gonna go there
all right anyone
net Gap it was in 95. come on
thank you uh so it was who is Abit
Hobbit
a bit
I'm French
so who is a bit what a climax to end
around
[Applause]
we have
cyberages at minus 200. cold route at
minus 1300 and now that's and friends at
[Applause]
[Music]
right here we're gonna bring back on
stage the winners of the previous round
right now we're gonna have uh the people
from North sec I hope you were briefed
because you're coming up here I don't
remember exactly who has been chosen
[ __ ] uh and we're gonna start right away
for our final round for a chance to win
a club methane foreign
that's not the good sound for that man
come on
[Music]
yeah okay so uh where uh
we see
uh
and
[Music]
nabbits and Friends around the
navits and Friends
Lots
of
foreign
oh I'm back excellent thank you
bathroom break their problem
break your problem
I don't get the bathroom break you don't
get a bathroom break
all right so we have people from North
SEC who are gonna suck at this game
probably
I'm gonna take a a few seconds to stay
to say honestly like stage fright is
real like a lot of the smartest person
in the audience and we did this with
Alex guidon and not too long ago he was
like always answering in the back all
questions no matter how hard and then
one year he came up on stage as nordsec
and he totally sucked
it was a disaster are you here Alex
Alexander there
is it true
here we go I'm not lying
so we have fine members of our nerd set
crew
Lambert and andrean
Lambert Lambert is on the is the the
co-lead of the badge design team
he's the one who said we should have two
badges and we're the ones stupid enough
to say yes of course
to make up for last year I don't know
why we did that it's complicated to
handle though
um yeah uh oh uh is a part of the the
CTF team and doing a lot of the Discord
integration and infrastructure and
Adrian
and Adrian is part of the Outreach and
volunteers team
and they will not win the Clemente
they're not eligible
so we have these fine folks here who
will
all right so we we've waited long enough
your friend is gonna arrive when he's
gonna arrive
or maybe we should wait for hydration
we
okay without further Ado let's reveal
the board
oh we we're still having the
god mode is uh it's good but it's
complicated to uh
handle
I will
um try to do some small talk
you Francois
look up sounds and to prepare okay oh
excellent what a great timing
we
I was told last year I was not drunk
enough
enough let's make it up
okay we have Skynet
off by one
unstable diffusion Hardware acronyms and
we fee
let's do a random and start this game
oh see and suck who wrote this this is
I guess you're gonna have to go through
this
enza okay you're in control Hardware
Hardware acronym 100 Hardware acronyms
modern firmware interface available on
x86 and arm 64 systems
I should
say that x64 is also included in this
navits what is UEFI what is UEFI is
correct you've got it
right you are
all right navits you are in control
uh Hardware acronyms 200
Hardware 200
this component in its 2.0 revision is a
requirement for Microsoft's latest
operating system navits what is TPM what
is TPM is correct
TPM 2.0
now a requirement
s Hardware again for 300
hardware for 300
computer and you're a computer commonly
used for Server management
what is ipmi
should I accept this who who are you
there
no no all right so this category was
contributed then I think I recognize the
voices uh so uh it's ipmi is incorrect
unfortunately
there's another way
so anyone else
nope all right anyone
word management controller what is board
management controller or BMC is correct
all right
let's do a random you got it
another one
they've been in control long enough
and suck
Skynet 100. Skynet 100.
Discord but to interact with an AI
generating pictures zor
[Music]
what is mid-journey what is min journey
is correct
[Applause]
[Music]
that's right you are
so no no you're in control I guess
I guess yes you have to play this game
now
you're there
of buy one 100 off buy one 100.
what is QWERTY what is QWERTY is correct
North six ten year anniversary is also
one by one because it's actually our
11th year thus this category
off by one two hundred of by one two
hundred
thank you
think about it
picture the keyboard
and suck
what is adj
what is sdj I don't know what keyboard
layout you have but this is incorrect
anyone else
now take a good look at this and
remember the answer because it's going
to help you on the next one
all right anyone else
what is SSH is correct
[Laughter]
I live for moments like this
all right so uh let's do a random please
navits
let's go with up by one three hundred
I'll buy one 300
I love it
let's compute
we don't really know our keyboard do we
we just know how to type
I use the tool to generate this because
I was not able to do it by my mind
I was tired
okay it's taking too long
[Music]
so
wow what a success is correct
oh my God you should move away from that
category
uh you know what no just finish it now
it's gonna you know the rest of the game
will be better
uh random please
navits
uh unstable diffusion 100. unstable the
fusion 100.
take a good look
these are two images generated
we need to figure out what it's talking
about
it's very simple what we're looking for
is very simple
and suck
poor what is tor what is Taurus correct
[Applause]
[Music]
so it was an onion with a router like
inbred together on one end and the other
one was just weird an onion on top of
some Hardware
so we're using like here we have like I
think stable diffusion and mid-journey
side by side
all right so you are in control
don't overthink the whole thing just a
simple diffusion 200. stable unstable
diffusion 200.
navits what is netcat what is netcat is
correct
it's pretty good one right
okay I like this one so unstable
diffusion again unstable 300.
what is Warrior shark what is Warrior
shark is correct bazinga
[Applause]
good
let's go
down 400.
[Laughter]
don't don't like keep it to yourself
like they will hear and it was we'll
ruined the game
I'm surprised you didn't figure it out
already to be honest
uh and suck bus pirate what is
ah
it's true yes zordo
[Music]
what is
what is the problem
[Applause]
I mean you're gonna faked the word you
didn't understand and do the other one
right okay but what is bus pirate that's
good enough to be accepted as an answer
he actually did say bus pirate this is a
hardware tool that is well known so
congrats
great this is fun
you're in control
we're waiting we'll take uh we fee for
100. we fee 100.
IEEE protocol name
802.11
[Music]
[Applause]
.
you suck
what is 802.11
you are correct
Bazinga I was I was afraid I was afraid
we're gonna say what is what he said or
what
you're in control
you need to speak in the mic
unstable diffusion 500. unstable 500.
let's go
what is Tomcat
what is Tomcat is correct
[Applause]
the second one is wow
yes
we know
that's uh let's go with Wi-Fi 200.
um
uh two you said 200 so we feed 200.
a band shared with microwave and suck
what is 2.4 gigahertz what is 2.4
gigahertz is correct
and suck
300 we feed 300
.
now that's what is a Cantina what is a
Cantina is correct yes success we have a
battle of the Wi-Fi right now
okay one second let's take a stop look
at the scoring at the score sorry and
suck minus 200 Zelda 600 and navids in
France one thousand and two hundred
points you're on the board all right
navits 400.
[Music]
in what frequency does Wi-Fi operate
navits what is 60 gigahertz what is 60
gigahertz 60 gigahertz 60
is incorrect
ends up what is six gigahertz what is
six gigahertz what is six gigahertz is
correct
hey
[Applause]
and suck
Wi-Fi hundred we fee 500
protocol name for fine time measurements
probably only one person in this room
knows
he's the one who sent me the question
you might even need the Google hint
himself
do you usually
no you know by heart
do you read it
he read it
all right uh anyone
it's a 8 out of 11 something I'm looking
for
so like with the extensions
so it's
802.11mc is the fine time measurements I
don't even know what it's used for
come on it's good you suck it's a good
question
or clue
all right let's do a random
almost done navits and friends you are
in control uh Skynet 300 200
which one China
200 thank you
a dungeon and dragon class which is also
an AI navitz
what is a Bard what is Bard is correct
or a Bart
[Applause]
some fine DND action you know suit
cleverly sued into the Jeopardy
uh now that's you're in control let's go
again with Skynet 300. Skynet 300
tool used to automate pen test by
leveraging artificial intelligence
Panthers
you basically just
make something up and add GPT to it it's
like now a thing
like a toilet GPT
Facebook GPT
all right anyone
Panthers GPT is the correct answer
they're not clever yeah it's true it's a
tool I'm not saying it's good yeah I'm
just saying it exists
all right random please
or
the oh I'm having a hard time reading
the phone from far
Skynet 400 Sky NF 400.
a cryptocurrency AI leveraging llm to
increase profitability as a co-pilot to
optimize your trading what could go
wrong
I guess if you hang out in the right
Reddit uh subreddits you know about that
one otherwise you don't because it's
probably a fraud
nice
nice another another one another time
all right so uh anyone
it's probably a better name than this
one so you should register that domain
or whatever
but so this one was called Satoshi
pick the right one yeah
all right so let's uh do another random
uh navits and Friends uh let's go back
to the off by one 400 off by one four
hundred
it's not gonna get any easier
listen carefully
we talked about this before tonight
um
Overlord of the of the necktie can I can
I get a color change please Overlord of
the necktie
[Music]
thank you
anyone
and map is correct
okay that last one you're never gonna
have it was a bad idea navits you're on
the board
Hardware acronyms 400 Hardware hacker
names 400.
computer memory design in
multi-processor systems exposing
Hardware nodes to the operating system
for proper handling of latencies
it's for a big ass computers
no multi-processor system
Hardware
all right anyone
what is pneuma is correct for
non-uniform memory access
Numa nodes
all right random
and suck
you are in control Hardware 500.
Hardware 500.
in modern AMD CPUs this component holds
one or more core complex as well as
their Associated L3 cache what are ccds
what are ccds no no he didn't [ __ ] it up
bazinga
you [ __ ] it up
correctly so what are CCD what is what
are CCD uh core complex dye is correct
oh wow
a big 500 points this late in the game
they're gonna be careful now okay let's
try again last one off by one
The Last of Us by one 500.
I think I'm gonna give hints until
someone figures it figures it up
it's an important piece of
hacker lore
it's uh it's a flag
yes what is hack the planet what is hack
the planet is correct
bazinga
[Applause]
congratulations this is amazing
great stuff
yes you are in control
I mean there there's one there's one I
know I know I know but you're in control
the last two rounds no one was in
control so now take the control you know
yes grasp it
Skynet 500.
according to a bird tweeting billionaire
this AI will understand the nature of
the universe
for someone tired of AI he sent me a lot
of AI question this year
didn't you love him
he's tweeting so much crap then it's
like just like filtering what makes
sense what doesn't make sense
now I want to try
this is this could be a game changer
right if someone strives and wins or
loses can change the outcome of the game
[Applause]
what
should I
oh Lim oh
all right okay let's time it out it's
been long enough
anyone
what is true GPT is correct
all right congratulations everyone good
luck
we have a clear winner
now that's some friends come up on stage
get up on stage
we're gonna give you the prizes
um and uh stay here right here where
you're gonna get your uh you're at
Clemente real soon and uh
suck you know you live the name yes
basically we're gonna see each other
soon though
uh but so yeah thank you for playing and
uh congratulations on winning
[Music]
[Applause]
so we have
the
um lock picks and uh rubber ducky you
can then figure it out by yourselves
later
uh uh hubertooth and the UB key and the
flipper zero
I don't want to let it go uh
all right so congratulations
[Applause]
that is all for tonight and enjoy the
CDF uh we're up we're open until 3am
uh do some more points