but thank you for being patient thanks
for uh thanks for sticking with us all
that is branded traffic stick i do
engineering and stuff or a company
called side work yeah Bertolucci count
security and so I'm a little biased in
some of the things I'll be chatting
about but we're kind of look at that two
themes as part of the conversation today
the first is really I guess three same
time I don't know how to count I see
that a little bit
not that kind of engineer the first
theme is how things have changed in
terms of the security landscape more
poorly the threat landscape how things
are shifting a little bit in some cases
I'm leaving us oh hi I'll talk a little
bit about cloud workflows how incredible
the cloud is even though it's just
somebody else's computer somewhere else
but also how it has a potential of
making us more vulnerable than ever
I'll then move into some discussion
around DevOps just the CICE pipeline
some of the assumptions that are made
out there and also all across those
three themes so tips on how we can
crease acuity with the minimum amount of
effort and then I'll end with maybe just
a couple of free things for you but as
with every good presentation we'll start
with a never never have I ever
so in dealing with with security in
general but also security that exists
now both in cloud environments and CNC
beam pipelines we see some of the same
concepts right we see SSH keys still
being manually copied to servers we see
access PC cookie pair is existing in
notepad documents on users desktops we
thought we were done this back
we're not you may have never talked with
developers who are doing this they may
not be as aware about security as we are
so the same thing is happening out there
even though we trained our
right this never happens anymore
we are also still doing this if I even
in my day today if I have access to it
UID 0 level account even though I don't
get it I'm gonna use it ah like why
don't I use my own stupid account and I
can use UID 0 some of the things we'll
look at is how this is exacerbated in
larger environments that are being stood
up with more automation than ever and
then none of these things apply to you I
can tell you there is still one left and
is that you've ordered Taco Bell to
drive here and your teeth in in the
parking lot I personally have done every
single one of these items over over my
ears so these are things that are
happening all the time of course now
what does that's also happening is that
the world is changing environments are
shifting we're seeing through the use of
more cloud focused workflows as well as
the preponderance of automation the
increase of environment escaping back in
the day you stay feeling really good if
you provision 10 new virtual machines in
a day
now with containerization I can
provision thousands of entities in a
very small amount of time and I use all
the extra time to figure out how I'm
going to secure that pipeline right now
of course I don't do stuff lead it's 5
o'clock we gotta go so in the increase
in scale it's something automation we're
seeing there's a larger risk surface
more importantly they're just more stuff
that we can break more stuff that we can
potentially into more PII data that's
being stored and containerized snakes
that just gives us a larger place to
land in terms of threats we see
environments becoming more dynamic to
write the concept of ephemeral
environments ones that are temporary
you've probably heard the phrase virtual
machines are like pets
like Catherine house lottery for me we
all just a Chipotle so I mean if you're
feeling that but it's also clean XD but
you don't think about me using Linux
you're spitting up a container really
think about what sort of security impact
it's going to have you think I've done
whoo what the virtual machines you care
more I care about security patching I
care about this it's gone but don't have
a snapshot I'm heartbroken that
attachment I do a lot of back in the day
so that attacks but that we felt back in
the day with these VMs it's being lost
very quickly in these more elastic
processes we're also seeing a move away
from homogeneous infrastructure couple
years ago you could come and say ask
someone hey what cloud provider you use
and they would say I use Amazon Web
Services that's it it's not anymore
there's no brand loyalty yeah got some
developers over here and then user sure
we hate them let me have some folks over
here using Google cloud platform do we
got the pivotal folks over here to the
far more things out there next security
team is a little bit more taxed when it
comes do a little bit of your site in
that ground
finally you see more non-gaming like the
old adage used to be for everyone human
privilege to count you had three non
human account service accounts that
we're out there now ten hey you
conservatively we could say five or six
but no he's got tons and we're giving
them tons of privilege too because
applications can't do what they do like
the lowest amount right so we've got to
go back and change it figure out
permissions there's no time for that
anymore why they the humans that are in
charge of these processes world were
privileged in them too I'll talk a
little bit more about that concept in a
few moments before I ran
about that here so we're seeing the
world change and what's driving this
changed typically is top-down
initiatives right so let's see so maybe
the organization maybe have ones if you
work with consult with they're trying to
break into they'll go to a show like
black hat and then they'll be surrounded
by four years ago clap clap clap you go
yeah cloud when they come back they say
developers cloud security cloud figure
that out and then we go cloud right we
have a top down initiative doing
everything we can to cloud by 2017 2018
we try our best then next year comes
around see so goes to this event he
seems so she sees DevOps DevOps
we got to get off making my colonists
come back same thing happens the most
recent one this year was the last year
rather was analytics AI so the same
thing can happen over and over again and
the security cyber task being able to
figure all this stuff out now we are
seeing more exploits that are targeting
these elements I'll be talking about a
human it up I'm not going to read the
two but we see access you see who
compares being placed in paintings build
squares we see cloud environments being
compromised laterally but still happens
vendor based access that all still
occurs it's probably you'll notice less
and less newsworthy to the point to
where there was a time period back when
ransomware was the hotness where the
advanced persistent threats you hardly
ever saw those in the news not because
they weren't happening it just wasn't it
much of them this is a personal
observation so later let me the
challenging on that one but I haven't
seen this ship kind of rocking food
environment so the attack lifecycle
changing a little bit right used to be
compromised in environments somehow get
in escalate privileges dump hashes move
laterally compromised rinse and repeat
now I'll submit to you it's becoming
identities here because we've
centralized way more stuff we never have
before
in other people's environments right so
the old way hack system now if I can
true level access into
environment whoo I meant no more lateral
movement that's it it's very similar to
a hypervisor reaches in the passage
right into access I went and you've done
this in practice so cyber-ark does a
that's the red team operations for our
for our customers I imagine you've done
something very similar to where in one
case we worked with the financial
institution who said show us what you
got the cloud site that use case I
mentioned earlier compromise an end-user
system find the notepad document that
has an access key secret key pair use
that to attach to set customers as three
buckets blind delicious PII attached
those buckets to our AWS instances this
took a matter of days to achieve
correctly we're also seeing access easy
to keep air is being hard-coded in
scripts things like that I'll talk about
that in a bit but if you use an AWS CLI
and some capacity and many of you
probably know this there's a little ego
of login hash up indicated hash BOTS
really has actually in plain text that
has in stores login data or that
particular session so it's not a notepad
document like this one is in cases it's
somewhere consisting on that same user's
system so we have less movement that
needs to occur we can do more effective
breaches less amount of time and this is
one of the reasons why if you look at
the stats the amount of time living in a
customer's environment keeps going down
it's not because you're not performing
the same level of reconnaissance before
it's because you don't have to you'll do
it proactively over here but once you
get that done that cloud key
boom BAM you're done you can go and I'll
submit to you one of the reasons this
happens is that when we work with one of
the cloud providers we assume that they
handle a good bit of security for us the
security of the cloud and that's true
they're responsible for all the backend
stuff the plumbing so to speak the stuff
that you don't see the compute storage
networking all that business of that
what we miss is that all the stuff
that's in the cloud all the stuff that
belongs to you still your responsibility
we still have to make sure we're
challenging our providers on their side
of the house but we also need to make
sure we're securing this area too now my
recommendations for that start with the
obvious start with the people sitting
around you the ones and you can identify
the people's whose desk you can go to
and light it on fire they're not
listening to you
human access with fruitless accounts in
the cloud console is easy to identify
look it's typically there's a built-in
right humans probably shouldn't be using
yeah that's why we have Federation
within AWS and sure that's why we have a
student role these are things that you
should use this is why every single
cloud provider says y'all better use
multi backer and pry that room in
account what that's hard try the
multi-factor a shared account
it's no fun because why send a challenge
do it's probably gonna end up being a
group having multi-factor for a group
its purpose a little bit better than it
should begin ups but it's not mapping to
that single person that single identity
like would like it to also we have the
potential of losing accountability with
any shared account this root account is
right up there so my suggestion is you
would be number one if you're working
with folks consulting with people
working with your own security divisions
if there's no NFA get in that back if
there is or if there's kind of an
argument internally around how we allow
users accessing can't use roles for
whatever reason there's solutions out
there that let you vault that root
account rotate provide human access
control workflows putting a multi-factor
in front of password vaults out there
some can even do things like isolation
and monitoring so you can see what the
user is viewing with that shared account
there are even open source solutions out
there that let you do this very thing so
starting with the human access that's
what I would start
or as well simple because humans access
kept using human accounts unless they're
developing rune applications for people
this is a great place to start the other
recommendation I was making I would make
rather is don't assume that you have
only one cloud platform in your
environment you may standardize on
something like AWS there is a very good
chance there is an offshoot team whose
leveraging GCP and they're hoping you
don't find out about it because then
there is now security or consultative
oversight and they have to change the
way that they're doing that people are
going to have multiple environments
there's no way around that it will occur
even with folks who look at somebody
like Amazon as a competitor there's
enough competition out there where they
can simply stand up where your Google
cloud platform and never touch AWS looks
good from a competitive standpoint they
have because now for us we have to look
and assume there's going to be more
stuff living out there now many of you
and this is a little bit of a tangent on
all it's been too long here many of you
are probably moving out of the thing
okay well the root account yes
don't want to use the root account but
I'm also using a lot of Federation today
and what could go wrong thank you so
much sample to ATO or any other
Federation well let's look at so typical
sam'l 2.0 client talks to the service
provider provides a logon oppressed
service Rider says whoa buddy I've no
idea who you are
so I am going to talk to my identity
provider however that is done through a
client system service provider does not
talk to identity provider see where our
government is right identity provider
says oh cool cool cool that user you're
fine right fine authentication identity
provider identity provider provides a
signed sam'l response and then it's nice
enough to the read Rev redirection back
to the service provider and everything
looks good responses son the user is
logged in problem
we don't talk service provider and
identity provider in this case just one
he would with Active Directory if it was
a standard 80 or LDAP authentication we
trust the identity provider and the
service provider level and we are very
naive over here because we don't do
anything the validate except just look
on that scientist Long's and now there's
a element of cyber are called cyber-ark
labs we do a lot of proactive security
research back in November of this year
we released a cool called shims and
shineth is used to fraudulently sign a
sample response in order to bypass the
identity provider altogether because it
looks kind of in practice very much like
a golden ticket attack and because the
name sounds kind of cool and we like
Charlie at the Chocolate Factory we
decided to call it Little Salmon now
I'll tell you where to find that to
learn more information about it a bit
but the cool part here is it's not
technically above the ability just like
golden tickets aren't technically about
abilities doing what it's supposed to do
doesn't mean there's brokenness
how did same is true here we can
generate that altercation from anywhere
once you have the appropriate data
two-factor authentication who cares
still approximate sign requests the
private key doesn't get renewed and a
password change in this case is not a
bad sin so good news from your
standpoint we talked a little bit about
how the authentication flow works so I
won't reshare that again but the way
that our gold and salmon will operate it
assumes a couple of things we did our
proof of concept with the good old 80 FS
the way the operates is thing one we
make sure we compromise ad FS first if I
gain access to an ad FS box with the ad
FS account I can now dump the private
key that I need as well as the public
key and also some additional details
around the roles that may be listed so
we assume that ad FS is compromised in
this case it's an on-prem solution but
your cloud-based solution a little bit
more secure than that so once we've done
that we execute shim it on the end users
with the public key be retrieved and
comprar gently sign that request so user
comes out to thank me AWS or whoever our
truster is takes that project response
with all the appropriate information
inside allows the user to authenticate
and now get more information about that
is on our github page
I'll have that kind of air again please
give it a go it is very very excited
that there are some limitations but most
important part here is never ever ever
ever ever trust your security our
identity vendors just don't we're all
selling software it's what we do
Kalen just to secure our platforms -
this is a simple example of something
that can be done quickly but the ones
that exist in a hosted snake you now
have zero visibility into what's going
on there which means that if those
systems are compromised - you now can
dump the private keys needed to sign
those problems toget passes so cuban
access i did by your boot accounts make
it hard for humans to use them if they
do need to isolate modern close
connection is a never trust where and
any providers or security vendors but
what about non human processes right it
is very the the ten to one thing i was
mentioning earlier the problem with
application application has been around
for decades old 1978 IBM CBM mainframes
have a full configuration file that
contains a whole bunch of different
potentials and applications used to
communicate with I gain access to that
system and it's pretty easy sometimes
right because then it's spring for
security packages and communication is
all over telnet so I'm there it's
probably the built-in administrative
password but they're not being rotated
which by the way rotate those just
because the system is old doesn't mean
we're not important
PLC's for instance I know there's a
stuff to that conversation so many of
you are probably here because maybe
you're not too hot into those real
control systems but see we're all
devices that are internet facing
recipe for a little bit faster but in
any case the problems been the same
what's changed is the level of
automation it's moving things around and
make the other little bit more
complicated from a security standpoint
now what you're looking at here is a
Jenkins build script it has a lovely
access key secret key pair living right
inside of the Ville information and by
itself writing the dev environment
that's not so bad
but what's happening is is we're
automating our pipeline we're moving
code around or promoting it using tools
like for instance Jenkins I'll talk
about that then if we're not careful
this little fella ends up in a public in
hub repository Wow we forgot to scrub it
why because we're focused on velocity my
developers don't have time to go back
and scrub this type of information their
revenue generated entities they need to
build patches fix code promote new
features so we're seeing this you're
probably seeing this quite a bit as well
and the interesting part is whenever to
let one of these rip what will happen is
it'll take around an hour maybe an hour
and 15 minutes for a bot that was
specifically designed to scour github
grab credentials like this use them to
attach to your s3 in your compute and
leverage that for cryptocurrency mining
operations there are tons of crypto
mining bots that look for stuff just
like this and they're committed pretty
good we've seen cases where this exact
thing is played out while it may have
been Deb environments and it's still
money the organization that's filled
potential PII accessible should these
minded thoughts become smarter just like
rent somewhere it became smart again
dumping hashes and louder
so it's problem they're hard-coded
credentials everywhere we do about I'll
talk about that a bit but when we look
at the whole pipeline we see a ton of
different potential authentication
events that could exist in a hard-coded
state if any of your of your companies
use Jenkins which everybody uses Jenkins
it's important to know that it is a
voracious
Zoomer of Secrets Jenkins authenticates
to everything really nice and polite
while he's doing it but that makes it a
perfect target so standard workflow
right Jenkins is authenticating to a
github repository that then creates
information to work through a docker
bill which is the variable ization the
hard coding the secrets that dr. bill
isn't promoted another secret exchange
happens when the promotion occurs when
the container is instantiated right
there's an application doing its job
widely it puts in the docker trusted
registry or authentication calls using
for potentially different sets that you
probably don't ever change it could be
your certificate exchange if so those
are probably static do so and one thing
that we're seeing and kind of the I
guess the hard part is when we look at a
traditional kind of view of what
security looks like right this is a
bunch of suits and bad people and people
wearing goodies preventing me from doing
my job instead of this is what's helping
me keep my job and helping my employer
run and this has been the traditional
logic so if you move that's talking to
your devs and your ops engineers or even
your DevOps practitioners they may have
even more pedantic of a beauty what
security means to them so adoption is
very very difficult we're dealing with
these these DevOps unicorn elastic
several other adjectives based processes
- now as I mentioned earlier we see
hard-coded credentials we also see kind
of move away from auditing something
tells us when you go bats don't need to
worry about logging what's happening
anymore now we also see over privilege
and we still see a lot of stuff
happening manually even though
automation is supporting things right
I'm not going to build the new ansible
playbook to do this works I just have to
do it once before the weekend any kind
of human puts their hands on something
you have potential security grips so we
still see manual stuff happening we also
see that because we just don't have the
resources to build an automated process
for it just yet so we'll do this thing
manually we'll figure it out later so
this is kind of a mismatch where we want
to do more automation but you have so
much automation over here so much time
over here that we're going to do things
manually over ears or just creates from
a mess of an oddity standpoint but also
in terms of kind of centralized stuff
now the good news is many of the tools
out there have some kind of secret
bolting capability look look
you can put your secrets at relatively
secure location and then have that
application pulled the problem into this
we don't just use one tool so now we
look at it from a potential secret
storage standpoint if we're using puppet
ansible and chef we now have their
individual entities and have a new
storing these secrets same is true with
containerization containerization
automation platforms like docker page as
well as the openshift as well as with a
number of cloud platforms too so we have
this kind of island of security effect
that means if I wanted to instantiate
some sort of oversight on all this now I
have to go in there every single one of
these figure out what I want to do and
it just becomes such a burden that I
said you know what developers handle it
you guys figure it out it sounds good
and they say ok but there's no
operability
you have no insight on what's going on
so do we let them handle it do we do it
well that's an answer no patty you guys
Verity if you're working for a set for
one day
the goal should be find something free
pay for something that allows you to
store these secrets securely make them
available to applications making
short-term right to look for strong
api's to help you do this make sure
they're not over privileged so
instantiating lease privilege as well as
doing these live auditing what these
nonhumans are doing that should be the
goal buying a place to store these
things and a way to deliver them so that
we can rotate them we have the audit
trail but developers not engineers are
happy don't hate us know trying Bernardo
sits down and it doesn't come without
the Nirvana State is to do this without
slowing those developers down do this
without creating a heartburn that comes
with additional configuration as well as
isolated tools so we want to make sure
we're identify the nonhumans out there
managing them in some way but doing it
so that you don't lose all of our
credibility with application teams and
it's pretty easy to do if you're great
at that
so looking at a pretty common
orchestration workflow and this can be
done with with on Krim orchestration
tools this could be something that's
being done by shell scripting PowerShell
scripting it could be something that's
done in loud something that your DevOps
engineers are doing it more velocity but
when you break it down you have some
process of orchestration that needs to
authenticate to do its job it uses a
hard-coded furniture not going to do
with low privilege so it's definitely an
added level for interest to in many
cases they're named in a very good way
ansible master ssh keys are called
ansible master ssh equal pay and like
that domain level account to being used
on a window cipher automation are
probably called something along the
lines of automation underscore SBC
underscore NSA which is great easy to
identify that one we see the same thing
with things like vulnerability scanners
all right so koalas fun ability scanning
accounts are called koalas underscore
SVC I love those but the orchestration
thingy authenticates somehow once it
does maybe it's building new
Virtual Machines it was now a brand new
credential early on that virtual machine
they're probably the same for all the VM
simple putting together so that's hard
coded to then finally your application
its provision out there it also has to
authenticate and do stuff so it now has
its own credential and now they all
exist in their their isolated States and
nobody can access them and do bad things
we'll know if I'm true they're out there
so like I said find something put them
in replace every single one of these the
API calls back to a secure store now you
keep rotated now there's the audibility
that's the goal easier said than done
it's great you just put a three-step
process up on slide just hope it's all
people work out like it never does but
there are things out there that can help
but I'll talk to you about some of those
three things a little bit now when we do
this kind of thing though we run into a
bit of a problem and I'll talk about it
and the real problem they probably a few
moments yes there's kind of the idea of
the problem when we look at identity
securing these identities out there we
tend to be a little biased when it comes
to that identity just like when it comes
to putting in on a proactive security
controls because we identify with people
it's easy to come to me and say he's
probably a speaker I could've just got
this from somebody else or not somebody
out something from them so you asked me
for my ID no okay this is Brent
fantastic I know him
he hasn't roll I know what he's doing
that's how you're supposed to say words
he's doing that I can do multi back I
can give you multiple things to verify
that I mean and I'd like to think that
both myself both bill over here we're
warm and friendly these are the
identities that we gravitate as far as
our security practices this is the one
that I like best though application note
W a113
if you just look at that account from
outside what it does maybe it makes
sense it's probably old it's the
innocent who knows you know so we can't
identify the role applications can't all
be back but not due processes can
and the cold unfeeling so my challenge
to you would be start looking at these
things a little bit closer to the way
that you look at a person for instance w
a113
Wally he's happy look I know what he
does I've seen the movie maybe you ever
go he has a girl I know that too I don't
need to know him to know that he's got
that job if I give him least privilege I
could give him a defined role he still
can't multi-factor I'll talk about half
a minute
when we start comparing the two when we
start holding our applications whether
it's the owner of the application or the
application itself but then there you
get it from to the same standard we hold
our human users life becomes a little
bit harder now for applications to
authenticate to identify that identity
we run into a chicken before the egg
kind of scenario secret zero if I've got
a nonhuman process that needs to
authenticate over here what do I get an
API key
but I'll dictate for the API key to pull
another secret what do I both of all the
API key I gotta know so we got to kind
of have that whole inception kind of
thing going on so I've indicated the
patient's not based on what they have
because that's hard-coded it's based on
what they are actually based
authentication for non-human process
this is the way to go as you deal with
more than the monolithic applications
that could be hatch runtime user violent
path trusted system with containers
containerization solution there are all
kinds of nifty api's that let you
authenticate based on things like pavan
entity container ID in it or sidecar
container support as well as actual
authentication api's that can be used by
authentication API I mean to confirm a
container not to up indicate the process
so again this is something that does
exist out there and in doing this it
does still help us inside the role
things like
make identity provisioning for
applications see those things that I
personally feel a lot with but again
there are multiple options out there
don't just take a hard-coded
API key as the only way a nonhuman they
stuck with me
technical difficulties through all my
rambling so I got one more thing two
more things I do have some free stuff
now if you're looking for those service
accounts you want to know what's going
on out here
you want to know what exists hard-coded
ansible playrooms websphere config files
are in web doc config files there are
tools out there that have very pointed
functionalities like for instance
bloodhound you better use bloodhound
okay check it out
they announced it at the Def Con before
last it's a tool that visualizes 80
trusts of open source it reaches out
there and says here's all the stuff that
we found here's what your multi-domain
trust looks like here's where these
accounts happen to live cyber-ark offers
a free solution that we call DNA
discovery and on the AAT sunrise it
works
what does is scans the environment pulls
back all the privileged accounts
identities it finds and it makes a scary
report you can use to mitigate risk but
also if you're looking for funding just
out of people there are orphaned hashes
here here here here here we've got 8
million SSH keys that have been sitting
out there for 10 years in our next
segment sorry next guys but you know
there SSH keys they're going through the
system now while you do have to ask us
your license once you've got it you
never have to talk about you but again
this can be used to mitigate risk
immediately just a quick anecdote I ran
this as part of a proof-of-concept we
were doing for a financial institution
in South Florida we found a lot of scary
stuff a lot of accounts out there one
stood out it was a domain admin level
account so no cloud stuff
anecdote wrong crowd Dobin add the level
of calories password at that point was
old enough to drive and belonged to an
individual first initial last name not
even an essay ABM whatever you want to
call it I said who is this joker what
person is this I was working with a few
so at the time it got put his head down
and said that's a CEO come on hurt me
but rough be the most visible employee
in the organization has action
everywhere and as member of the domain
admins group what look I want you to
find it okay okay
well they change it they took down the
domain admins group and they set it to
expiring slogging champion that's fun
and then I got out of it's like I want
to be responsible with this so we
mitigated risk right there next day
gives you that we go back in the next
day we can't get start over okay hang
out the lobby
whatever you do in lobbies so we're
sitting there finally come back and give
us 40 minutes later it's about 10:30 and
I hate what happened production issue
what happened so my private
disappointing by doing that well turns
out the CEOs account was being used as a
service account for butter building
scanners crepes where were they so most
visible employ at the company and hashes
over there and the reason why that was
was because he used by your butter
building skin account which means that
if you get access to it
you can now fly under the radar be the
exact same naughty stuff about a really
scanner does the CEOs okay so mitigate
that to he's even better six months
later it working with iOS if you have a
custom
that point somehow they had led for two
days and still they bought soccer marry
we're actually asking how does it what's
good
so we found out later on that the CEOs
account was also being used as backdoor
service account for our helpdesk that
explains the other axes but why well
they said it's because the password was
so easy to remember okay by the way they
had not been breached
you all missed your opportunity on that
right so DNA helped us mitigate that
risk right away they don't have to pay
any money they said Oh another free
stuff free thing right I mentioned that
there are open source solutions out
there for storing and even rotating
secrets we provide one of those
solutions it's called conjure it's in
that hole it's a bunch of like wizards
read names conjure has a process called
whoa and we have a process that reads
secrets from back in and writes them to
sub environmental parameters that we
call some so even if there's no budget
there's no money there's no project
developers say well I want something
that runs as a container you can say
okay fine
got a place for you to put this stuff
and of course there's enterprise
versions of it as well but this is
available out there free to use it's
eight gplv3 license integrations have
done under Apache too so if you've got
folks using puppet Jenkins chef ansible
in their Creek capacities this has
integrations that are already built and
license our community continues final
thing just some details about the stuff
I talked about you can find contra at
Contra org or you can head to docker
helping to search for exists there
please play around with it join our
slack if you have any questions or want
to understand some of the work we went
into and securing that solution shim it
the the tool used to execute the golden
sample I talked about as well as
documentation is available
get up some github.com cyber-ark there
are a number of other neato tools that
we put out there as well and finally if
any question is common to the servants
or grievances past the ones on asking
for a moment please don't hesitate to
reach out to me so with that said any
questions at all or course comments
concerns hey thanks again we made it out
five minutes before the top of the hour
so if you do have questions you didn't
feel like asking them I'll be hanging
out around here just written a couple
minutes so come up let me know throw
things at me whatever makes sense but
thank you all so so very much