cool how's it going everyone I'm Jimmy
uh I know in the program it says IOT
assessing IOT surveillance as this talk
kind of progressed it turned into more
just meat taking apart the our low
security cameras and base station I am
gonna talk about the process I followed
taking these apart so this is gonna be a
pretty beginner an intermediate level
talk I think there's a huge lack of
presentations that go through like
actually tearing down devices and the
thought process of someone like actually
doing this I see a lot of beginners told
over and over again just pick a target
and try harder I don't see that as being
very helpful so hopefully this gives
someone more insight into how to
actually like take one of their devices
and start going at it this presentation
was put together like a month or two ago
and I haven't looked at a sense this is
my second presentation of the weekend so
I apologize for any repetition or
stumbling over this I do because the
order of these slides is as much a
surprise to me as it is to you so
hopefully we get going on that a little
bit about me I'm a security researcher
at tenable thanks to them for you know
like letting me do those kind of stuff
for my day job it's really all you need
to know about me these are my dogs this
is my cat he's the favorite all of this
is irrelevant to the talk so I'm just
gonna go ahead and get moving on a
little bit about we're gonna talk about
this talk is not gonna last the full 50
minutes since its beginner oriented like
I see a lot of people kind of drone on
and on and fall asleep but for talks
that actually last the full length
especially like post-lunch coma and most
of you look hungover from last night so
I'm gonna talk a little bit about like
past surveillance systems more recent
trends and surveillance systems for IOT
devices and like the cheaper stuff that
we see everywhere these days then talk
about the actual research process I took
taking apart the arlo cameras so past
surveillance systems we're talking 5 10
15 even 20 years ago
wireless cheap cameras haven't really
been mainstream up until the last like
maybe five or six years it used to be
anytime you went to like a gas station
or a small convenience store it would
cost like five six thousand dollars just
to run a single CCTV not only that you
can actually buy that equipment or you
couldn't at the time yourself you have
to call someone and have them install it
and then set up your VHS player and TV
in the back to actually monitor it so
none of this was actually accessible to
everyday consumers I remember when I
worked at like Cold Stone Creamery as a
Creamery as a teenager any time we
needed to monitor the security feeds we
had to call an external company yet even
today for enterprises you can't actually
go out and buy this stuff yourself you
have to contact a third-party
distributor have them come and install
it and then if you ever want to update
that software you have to call them
again they charge you like a ten
thousand dollar fee just to update it so
a lot of this equipment was very old
very much hard wired connections that
you had to run cable for not really the
most consumer friendly so you didn't see
security cameras on you know people's
doorbells like you do today
moving into like the present time the
stuff got really really popular devices
are now only a couple hundred bucks
they're pretty much accessible
everywhere in terms of new functionality
there's nothing new the devices that
existed five years ago exist today
there's just shitload more of them
mostly because they're only a hundred
bucks
200 bucks for an entire kit of two or
three cameras to assess your entire
property they're all Wireless they're
easy enough to set up that my mother can
do it so that's saying something and as
proof that they're everywhere both
neighbors on either side of me in our
new house have simply saved cameras the
guy down the street has an entire
bippity setup I have Arlo the neighbor
across the street uses the blink
security cameras I can't think of anyone
that doesn't have a ring doorbell
monitor anymore so these things are
very prevalent in our everyday lives now
targeting our low why did I pick Carlo
well I need his security camera it was
Black Friday so I bought one of these
that's really the entire story of how I
picked this it also is really popular
and there wasn't much research on it so
I saw an opportunity there just to kind
of start taking this apart the last
published stuff was back in 2015 up
until I started taking over these and
there were only two CVEs which is kind
of odd for a big company like net year
to only have two CVEs for one other like
biggest products so I was kind of
curious what was going on there did they
actually put a lot of money into
securing these devices or like was there
something else going on and
unfortunately I can't actually talk
about that something else but if you
look at our disclosure timeline you'll
get a big hint of what's going on there
so first taking apart the device after
you buy it take it out of the box all it
is little base station camera some
cables in order to play with it all
there's a web application which is flash
based so don't use it but the mobile
apps are actually pretty solid and
pretty easy to use it really is as easy
as plugging and pressing the sync
buttons and letting it go as soon as you
turn everything on and sync it it's
working very well very high-quality
images the motion detection was pretty
flawless and it does something
interesting that I hadn't seen in many
of these devices before it actually does
all the network segmentation for you as
security practitioners we tend to have
this you know mantra of put it on its
own VLAN or make sure it's not on your
main network the base station here
actually does that for you it segregates
all of the cameras onto their own little
wireless network so obviously still put
your base station on its own VLAN but
it'll handle all of the actual like
segmenting for you
it does sync via WPS one thing I don't
mention in the talk we all kind of roll
our eyes when we see WPS but they did a
good job and have all of the
brute-forcing stuff disabled so it is
actually pretty solid and they have some
Mac filtering which easy enough to
bypass but for the typical user you can
only pair Barlowe cameras with it it
will eventually kick you off if you
don't have like a net year registered
mac address so before I actually dig
into the device myself I wanted to look
at what was published before me the only
information out there aside from like a
few tear downs on Chinese websites or
like the SEC ID dot IO tear down images
where two things from new sky security
they really had three big
vulnerabilities they published but only
two of them were assigned CDs and it
dealt with password flaws so when you
originally bought the device if you
reset it after the initial setup it
would just reset that internal Wi-Fi
password to one two three four five six
seven eight and then anyone could
connect to that Wi-Fi network and start
man and milling your cameras so when
they reported that Netgear their fix was
to make it very predictable it was
literally a word list on the device that
you could connect to and like all they
did was pull a random word from that
file and that was the password so if you
had access to that file you could still
connect to any network just by trying
all of the passwords after going through
their information I'll talk about the
manna milling they did on the camera
networks here in a little bit I kind of
want to take a look at what our actual
external attack surface is scanning the
device externally there's only a single
port open 5061
that's for encrypted sip traffic which
is typically used by like voice over IP
network phones unfortunately there's not
a lot that can be done with that port
I'll mention that again at the end of
the presentation we know all
communication
happens the Wi-Fi there's no other
radios or antennas all devices we can
tell that one by looking at the hardware
and two by seeing what the device is
registered with yeah FCC under and then
there's the obvious cloud connection
these are always on devices in order to
actually access your camera streams you
have to go through Arlo everything goes
to them I think we're all familiar with
that process by now looking at the
device taking it apart there's a couple
of antennas through a couple of shield
cans that cover the you know wireless
components to prevent interference then
there's this magical thing here that's
an open serial port on the device with
no other protections there's nothing
funny about it it conforms to the SPI
spec directly so all you got to do is
just you know connect to it and what
prior research to me did was connect to
this and it drops a roof shell no
authentication no nothing unfortunately
for me these devices have been updated
since then I'll talk more about actually
connecting that and how I wound up
getting access here in just a second
but let's review the attack surface
really quick since I'm looking at
primarily the base station since the
cameras aren't exposed on your own
network there's that sip interface port
we'll talk about again later there are
binaries that we can hopefully get to
through the serial interface there's the
internal network and then the actual
networking components the device so it's
a pretty lockdown attack surface there's
not a lot we can really do with this so
new sky security did write up their pin
out after figuring these out I'm a big
fan of trust but verify when it comes to
hardware especially since there are
several different models of the base
station when Netgear actually acquired
Arlo there was these old like tacky
plastic round hubs that they used
nowadays they're less than glamorous
plastic mat hubs so the hardware is more
or less the same
just in case they changed the pan out
it's helpful to figure this out yourself
not going to go through the process of
figuring out the pin out I do have a
write-up separate from this talk that
you can use to find find that but once
you figure out the pin out and solder up
you can connect to it if your connection
is right when you boot up the vise
you'll start getting a bunch of boot
logs and output will come to this slide
again later but you can see all of the
mounted memory addresses from like the
flash chips they're so like zero to
8,000 or 80,000 it's like the boot
partition then you've got some nvram
you've got the route FS whatnot
unfortunately after it boots you've got
some authentication this was not present
in any other research that I found it
was just like a busybox login prompt
that didn't accept anything there was no
single user mode I could do it into so I
did figure out a way around that if you
you know control see when things booting
up you can actually access the
bootloader this thing uses the CFE or
common firmware environment bootloader
pretty common among most Netgear and
like home consumer routing devices and
you can use it to show all of the
connected flash devices you can monitor
like nvram values just kind of pull
things apart and try to see what's going
on so they had the special values called
UART username and you our password just
written like this in the NVRAM these
look like base64 values that decode to
md5 hashes they are not so had to come
up with a different way to do it
see if he has a safe command if you have
a TFTP network or server on your network
you can use the save command to transfer
arbitrary memory from the device or any
flash region to your own home server so
once you have these memory regions you
can just write them to your own server
and then have the firmware that way a
lot of vendors will disable this
feature in their bootloader Arlo does
not so after we get that and run strings
they literally have the decryption
routines in plain text in the firmware
image so the username and password is
just ng root and ng base and you're good
to go
so all you do is have to login we now
have a root access to the device so once
we're in the filesystem is pretty simple
there's not really a ton on it there are
a few like configuration commands we can
use and run just to get like version
information network information there is
an HTTP interface that's disabled by
default but the username and password if
you happen to enable it as just admin
and password
super secure and then there's the WPA
key which is encrypted in the via nvram
and very difficult to decrypt just based
on its length and I'll mention that key
here again in a minute but taking a look
at the service is running on the device
this light isn't super helpful because
it's just a jumble of addresses but we
can see that there's only one service
listening globally and then everything
else happens to be listening on the
internal network interface that we can't
access without being on that network
looking at like what bye
or what processes are actually running
that run on these ports there's VZ
daemon X Agent X agent watchdog the X
agent stuff totally irrelevant all it
does is monitor to make sure the rest of
the like VZ daemon is running correctly
if it's not it just reboots the device
there's the SIP interface that I keep
talking about I hate it I have no idea
what it does still again I'll keep
talking about that later there's these
internal stuff port 4040 140 200 they
are only listening on the internal
network they're what the cameras use to
connect to the base station that's what
all the video streams audio feeds will
actually go over
then it's listening internally on port
80 which was weird because the cameras
never touched this port as it turns out
this is running a like hidden
administrative console it's got an inner
it's got three little API commands one
is file one is pass-through and one is
version version just spits out model
information on the device but
pass-through and file allow you to
download and upload arbitrary files to
the device since beezy daemon contains
all functionality for the device it'll
periodically run ping just to check the
like network access isn't working so if
you overwrite ping with your own file
because you have root access you now
have full execution on the device moving
a little bit quick here but I'm just
gonna go ahead and start jumping into
summary of the findings we've got
insufficient UART protection so really
not the biggest deal in the world but
it's very helpful for the home routing
community or home automation communities
to be able to kind of connect to these
devices read the configs themselves one
thing I see on Arlo forums a lot is the
range of the base station is really
really short so if you have a long
shotgun home or just a large property
you can't really run that many cameras
too far away but if you have access to
the configs and you can get your
password you can set up your own range
extenders that are low still doesn't
provide themselves it helps you just you
know expand your environment a little
bit there were a lot of plain text
passwords in there there were I don't
have them all listed here and the
corresponding blog post I have them all
spelled out for you but like let's and
let's at flats and guest and gear UCP
your guy your dog some of those are
already public but some of them no idea
what they go to but there are a bunch of
pppoe services that go on since I don't
own those or access them I didn't try to
do like push any further since this was
you know company related research if
anyone wants to look at that feel free
but please tell me if you
actually find anything through the
disclosure process Netgear and Arlo said
they didn't do anything take that for
what you will the main finding I found
though is there was a big Network miss
configuration that internal network if
you specify the main router as or like
the main interface as you're like
gateway you can access that internal
network since the entire base station is
based on a previously released netgear
wireless extender it's still just a
router itself so you can ping the
cameras you can access those internal
administrative consoles so if you're on
the same land as the base station you
now have a root access on the device
just kind of as proof of that just
specifying my routing table to go to
that internal interface from LAN I can
access the syslog and just view anything
on the device mainland million cameras
all configs passed on that internal
network since it's a Wi-Fi network
that's pretty hard to connect to if you
don't have the password
Arlo assumes everything there is safe so
everything is sent in plaintext video is
not encrypted if you man in the middle
it's just an RTSP stream so you can live
stream any video from any of the cameras
I didn't want to include the picture
here just because it's obfuscated and
like I didn't want my own home stuff
broadcast publicly also in the image all
of our lows private keys for firmware
encryption and decryption are included
within the binaries on the device so if
anyone wants to download their firmware
like it's all there you can use these to
decrypt it none of these have been
previously released except in a couple
of blog posts I've made the disclosure
process this was one of the longer
disclosures I've ever done that was I
know you can't really read that but more
or less I disclosed in March and then
had multiple weekly follow ups with the
vendor there was a lot of back
fourth than a lot of silence from the
vendor then a lot of back-and-forth then
finally they're like we're working I
we're working on it so we waited and
then we finally published after they
like surprise released on us that being
said they did a great job
they actually patched the issues the
UART stuff they can't fix without
recalling devices so that's still a
problem but in general they actually did
a really good job especially since the
device in general the attack surface is
pretty limited yeah now getting to that
sip interface my fury is this sip
interface is for the doorbell cameras
and microphones I can tell from the
mobile app that it may have been used
for device enrollment at one point in
time it doesn't appear to anymore but
within the mobile app the passwords for
the actual sip console are hard-coded so
the username and password are just one
zero two five for both so if anyone has
one of the doorbells and wants to try
connecting to it with any of the pj sip
utilities please do because i'm really
curious to know if they actually work
other things that could be looked at the
clock muezzin communications they do
certificate pinning and verification
everything very very well it's all very
well handled
i didn't try to do any testing on the
cloud networks myself i just really
don't like touching things that i don't
own if you do please let me know any of
their extra credentials no idea what
they do still so if anyone wants to take
those and go forward that's all fair
game again the goal of this talk was
more talking about like my process of
like what did i look at what did i find
important and kind of walk through in
terms of security posture this is one of
the better devices i've looked at i
expected this to be like a really easy
target with like cds just to fall out as
I choked it
unfortunately that wasn't that
the case the biggest downside with this
kind of stuff for me is I don't like the
always on always connected devices I
don't like my data going somewhere out
of my control that being said it's cheap
and very easy for consumers to use so
there's a little bit of give and take
there in terms of non security related
stuff it's great that we can like
contribute to like the open source
routing communities by releasing the
decryption keys so they can modify this
firmware and hopefully make it a little
bit better and more accessible in terms
of more control over like your
information I kind of blitz through all
of that so are there any questions
that's an automatic process so since
they're always on if you the camera
pings out constantly to check for
updates as soon as it sees one it will
like download the update and bring it
back all of that process is very well
pinned and secure
I couldn't man in the middle of it I
couldn't do anything to kind of like
intercept those updates anyone else
awesome well thanks for your time
[Applause]