Oh coming can you hear me great
so um servos hacking 101 about two years
ago I got a phone call from our CEO all
right how about now
one is that okay I can get closer okay
so about two years ago I got a phone
call from our CEO
I told me hey we're we're building
something for a server less and we want
you to come and help us make it secure
and defense help us defend our customers
of course I said let me think about it
then the minute I hang up went to Google
and said what is server less and there
wasn't too much information out there
two years ago there was some basically
mostly around lambda functions and other
cloud functions so then I went and said
server less I wrote server less security
and there was none really
nothing so I did some research and I
found it that it's interesting because
it's a little bit different it's similar
to what we might we might be familiar
with web applications and cloud but it
has some other angle to it
and in this talk I'm gonna show what is
the difference and how we should
approach serverless applications okay so
I'm working at a company called proteger
labs we have a service security solution
if that interests you come find me after
the talk if you want to find me on
either of this make sure that if you
like the talk to follow me on Twitter
all right the agenda will start with
some basic information about what
services several a security how it works
so we'll have some base ground to work
with
that will see some demos about how we
can hack into serverless applications or
have some fun exploited get some
information out of the cloud account
gonna mention some related work I've
been working for on and then if we have
some time for questions although my
hearing isn't that well so if you have
questions please shout them okay so just
a disclaimer before we start in this
presentation I'm not going to tell you
or show you
vulnerabilities inside the
infrastructure actually server less
would probably make your application the
most secure that possible up to date of
course you'll have to work around with
some constraints and configurations but
it could really work well as in term of
security most of the examples will be on
AWS because it's the most common one but
most of them also apply to other service
provider that way or another if you're
interested come talk to me after the
after this talk beg for forgiveness you
might see some other con logos here and
there on the videos because I was
prepping them for multiple ones so let's
start with some basic ground what is
service why people are moving to server
less so we started in the late 80s or
90s on-prem where everything was where
the company that developed the
application was building was having to
deal with all the the resources and
configurations skipping ahead
we have containers everyone knows about
containers nowadays but we still have to
deal with some setups
patching the environments making sure we
don't have open ports open services we
don't actually know what in there if we
downloaded
container might be some things that we
need to configure of course the scale
and of course we have to take care about
applications so when we move to the
cloud we don't have to deal with any of
that it's all given by the service
provider all we have to do is write up
some code which is the logic of the
application and make some small
configurations about mostly about
permissions and environment variables
and packages but that's it everything
else is taken care of so that means you
don't have to patch you don't have to
scale you don't have to do anything else
okay right so is service really a thing
how many of you heard about service ok
that's about right how many of you
actually dealt with lambda functions or
cloud functions ok cool
so what we see from our customers and
what we see around is that many
companies and very big companies and
also startups are starting at least
experimenting with server less and we
believe this is the future of especially
of cloud computing so this is why we
were there
ok so his server less security a thing
it wasn't until recently on the last
three invent AWS showed this this
presentation where they mentioned that
service was the most hot topic over the
whole event and right after that was
security so of course from a nature as a
security person I don't trust them so I
went ahead and I went on Google trend
and I checked so let's start with
serverless computing I'm just setting
some configurations let's see the world
wide and the past five years and you can
see that there is a constant rise
in dealing with surveillance and we
believe it's going to grow and grow so
then I said of course the first thing
that you do when you develop survey less
is going to check about serverless
security because you don't want people
to hack your service applications and of
course this is the result constantly
from zero to one in three years and I'm
pretty sure the one is me so I don't
know if you're dealing with server less
because you raised your hand at least if
you're not in the attacking side make
sure you're you know there is a
difference and you have to do something
different and it not gonna work for you
to keep your currently security controls
I mean at least not all of them so let's
see how and why okay so what do I mean
server less applications where do your
application leave so when you want to
have your code running because there are
no servers well there are servers of
course it's just not not yours you have
to write your code somewhere in has to
run somewhere so the provider gives you
a single purpose container that will
take your code just for the execution
time we'll run it and when it's done
it's supposed to go away so it doesn't
leave anymore so we have this container
and we have some some of the providers
inside so iws Google IBM SAP all the big
ones so this is another reason why we
know it's a thing everyone goes there so
what are these containers first of all
they're read-only except from
slash temp sorry except from the slash
temp like
folder which is where you're going to
write your data into so everything else
if you read only during the the
containers and within the containers
your code
they are spin up on events triggered by
events so it's not necessarily calling
them directly I mean you can use API
gateway and rest api is to trigger your
functions but that's not the only case
it might be 70% of the current cases at
least pretty much what we saw but it's
not the only case you have emails that
triggers functions directly you have
logs the triggers function you have
files you have IOT like I like MQTT
protocol you have sorry for the typo you
have authentication services that will
automatically trigger functions in code
in your background and there are some
many other events that could trigger
your function your code so in the
development perspective this is crazy
interesting because you don't have to
actually wait for a request coming in
you can trigger your code to run on
various of other changes of a database
so your database will change and you
want to trigger a code that will process
that so that is very nice in the
development perspective but it also has
of course its security perspectives
which we will talk talk about so I said
the environment is read-only the older
data that you actually want to write
which is not permanent your right into
the slash temp and when the code finish
the container dies and within all this
data so it's a temporary data of course
this is not entirely true because to
keep on performance what's happening is
that the providers will keep your
containers as long as requests are
coming you're not going to know on which
container you're going to land but
they're probably going to
be some data inside if this is a
container if this code writes into slash
tamp and it is triggered pretty often
that if you're getting access to this to
this container you might have to you
might find some information inside slash
data a slash temp so this is something
that you want to take into account okay
the source code also reside in a
container so what happens is that when
your first trigger comes up and triggers
your code what's happening is that the
container spins up and winds within the
container the code is mounted from
taking from other cloud resources and
then your code will run on this
environment it's all Linux environments
or if it's as your as your it's it's IAS
or different containers so this is where
the source code leaves and again if you
have access to the container and we'll
see you want to get there also another
link to that same directory is proc one
and you can also get there the source
code from that directory another
interesting thing is that your
environment variables also leave there
and you can get them by either of those
why is the environment variables
interesting so a part of the fact that
you might want people or companies might
write their own keys into these
environment variables for different
resources there are built-in keys inside
these environment variables especially
if you're using AWS your Landa function
keys will be there and why do I care
because these keys have the permissions
in the account in the cloud account of
the function so if I manage to get them
out i from my home or my computer or
wherever I am can do the same thing as
the function in the account
and more of course depends on the
permissions and we'll get into that okay
so I said it's ephemeral it's also
stateless when a code runs it doesn't
know automatically there is no session
usually so it doesn't really know what
was before what's happening after these
are all different micro services or even
nano services depends that runs
individually into a big picture of the
application and as a developer you have
to somehow connect all the dots but also
make sure you can make them secure so
you have to take care of the for example
your access control on each of your
functions or each of your resources
there are ways to do that authentication
you have to make sure each of your
functions is taking care of
authentication but it's not that easy
because if you're not coming from a from
a REST API and you might not have the
authorization header if it's an it's
it's a lambda or a code that runs
because an email was sent
how do you make sure the user is
authenticated or within the organization
because emails can be spoofed of course
so we'll see a demo about that as well
okay so this is example an example this
is manipulation that has an internal
service environment were developers
commit codes into a repository and in
order for the manager to or the whoever
the leader team leader of the
development to review the code there is
a triggered email that is sent directly
to the manager saying hey new code was
there is a new PR go and check the code
to approve it but if if the email if the
attacker has some
internal knowledge and it once he wants
to send oh he knows the email that
supposed to be sent to the environment
to the access to the manager he can send
it directly it spoofed email of course
this will trigger code and then a
function will rise will take actions
according to your email I don't know
it's just a scenario that is triggered
by email so how do you take care of that
another very important aspect in service
applications is the I M roles the access
control so as I said each function
within the account within the cloud
account has a different permission
within the account and you as a
developer have to make sure your
function has the right permissions in
the account guess what they don't we
found that more than 95% of the function
has some level of other permissions
because it's hard there are ok this is
easy for one function but if you have
hundreds of functions and they
constantly changing how do you do that
how do you choose if we're talking about
AWS they have more than 5,000 different
permissions so think about the developer
he knows how to write code of course his
function goes works now you tell him hey
make this function secure so he goes
into the documentation and gets lost
because there are so many of them so he
probably go into the Stack Overflow or
something like that and we'll find the
right permissions and I'm gonna tell you
he's gone sorry he's gonna have some
apologize
he's gonna have some wild cards inside
which means that if you get these keys
as an attacker you want you can do some
damage in the account so this is how in
AWS you define permissions this is
example of permissions to buckets
bucketz a3 cloud storage this is very
common
there were many there was in the news
lately many attacks or many breaches
that occurs due to that specific
permission so f3 we have two things here
we have the action and the resource so
as you can see in this example the
action is set to a3 wild card which
means that the permission of this
specific function can do anything any
action that is related to three buckets
that means creating buckets deleting
buckets changing permissions to buckets
so making internal buckets public for
example which happened recently adding
resources reading resources whatever you
want and the second part which is the
resource tells you that the specific
function can do not only any action but
on every bucket in the account so that
means that if you get that access you
can not only poke into a bucket relates
to this specific application but you can
do whatever you want to any cloud
storage within the organization you can
do a lot of damage there you can find
all of it a lot of interesting
information there there is actually a
website I think it's called
grey warfare it's like the showdown of
the a of the buckets so if you go there
I do not add the links or about that if
you go there they have lists of I don't
know I think it's millions now of
resources and back heads that are public
so you can see a lot of sensitive
information over there okay so your
developer did that but you know
something about security so you tell him
that's not good enough
go and find me some better permissions
so he goes and finds that you can limit
the permission to a specific bucket so
in this case the function now can only
do oh you can do whatever it wants but
only to a specific bucket which is nice
but if you really want to go into
security you're going to do something
like that if your function only reads
data from the specific bucket you can
give it a specific permission that tells
tells the function you are not you are
only allowed to get an object one
specific object or any other object but
only get one object at a time from this
specific bucket so this is a huge
advantage if you think about it in the
app SEC perspective this is crazy this
is so nice you can really limit your
permission and attack surface within
your cloud account but this is not
really happening too often and you can
find a lot of functions that are over
permissive this is because for one
function it might be easy but for a lot
of them it's gonna be hard okay so we
know where applications there are one
way usually an HTTP could be a tcp or
any other protocol but there is usually
one way in where the attack goes to try
your application to exploit your
application and you're probably gonna
put all your security controls and all
your guards on that entrance but when
you talk about server less it's not the
same they can come from a REST API
gateway but they can also trigger code
from files from analytics from emails
from logs how do you defend against that
so we'll see what you can actually do so
I said rest api is okay we know them but
we can also use three party applications
and we'll see that in a second Cloud
Storage can trigger authentication
service logs
can trigger code IOT emails
notifications and of course code changes
like commits etc okay so now yeah now
we're gonna see some demos of some
examples that you can see why this is
different and what you have to do in
order to exploit service applications so
this first environment we have a slack
channel that an application the
organization wrote chat bot that
interacts with the user so you can be a
sale a support chat bot set user rights
some messages and about chat bot
responds according to the messages these
messages goes to a slack the slack API
of course then it goes to the API
gateway and triggers a function the
function takes the messages writes them
into a dynamo DB table which is a no
sequel database and responds back
according to what you wrote so let's see
a demo
okay so a lot of screens here but you
can see on the top left the chat the
slack chat and the bot that responds to
the user
so first I'm interacting with it but now
I want to know and check if it's
vulnerable let's say I already know that
it uses some vulnerable dependencies so
I found in the internet this exploit
which relates to a specific
vulnerability inside this application
again the attacks will probably be the
same as on web application but there are
two main differences the first one is
that you can trigger them differently
and the second one is the information
that you want to get out and how you
exploit because if you're gonna do a pen
test for example and you're going to
come with a report hey I hacked your
container
here's your Etsy password file no one
cares about that in service it's a
template that resides in to the parent
in the container and no one cares about
that so what you can do about it
is something else so you want I told you
were sensitive information is in source
code you can find environment variables
and how then you can go and further
exploit the application so here I have
some an exploit that I found in the
Internet and I just want the first
example I'm doing a child process exec
and I want to see if I can get
information out of the container so I
send this request through the black
slack and I can you can see the bottom
left that I got it into my HTTP tunnel
so this is just the first one now I want
to extract some sensitive information so
I'm adding an LS to see what's in the
environment and you can see that there
is a file called in there's a yes so
that's interesting now I want to get the
source code maybe so think about it is
like you got the backend source code so
I'm doing cats index J s I'm going to
wrap it in base64 so I can send it over
HTTP and then I'm going to take the
source code into my own computer
and further go over it and see how I can
further exploit it so let's see so it's
just basic c4 at the moment
okay so echo decode and I get the source
code the source code that runs in the
backend so I go over the code and I see
that information that helps the function
interact with the slack and I can see
that the function has a dynamo DB a
dynamo DB code their line SDK AWS SDK
that does if you look one line after
that dynamo DB dot put item that means
that the function writes into a dynamo
DB database but I don't want to write
into the database although I can I want
to try and do some other and see what I
what else I can do there so what I'm
gonna do here is I'm gonna write a code
because I found that there is code
injection here and I'm going to use the
AWS SDK in this case to run different
code that will give me access to
different resources within the cloud so
if you can see here I'm doing require
AWS SDK and HTTP because I want it and
then I'm going to do a dynamo DB dot
scan now the difference between scan and
put item is that one writes into the
database and the other one gives me the
whole database it scares the database
for the data so I'm going to send that
but now I don't need a channel I don't
need the tunnel there the end work
tunnel because the function itself
interacts with slacks so I can send
myself the information through the
select channel right and I don't need to
know even the the information because I
can just use the same code so as you can
see I wrote I sent this slack message
and I got all the data base inside the
slack channel and I also just for the
fun of it change the icon of the slack
bot so as you can see this is it might
be the most similar way to attacking
regular applications although in this
case you have to you want to know what
to take out of it which is source code
and try things like using AWS as
case or other cloud providers SDKs
in order to exploit the application
further okay moving on right moving on
we have another attack this time in the
environment setup we're gonna see a user
or an application that triggers code
based on files that are uploaded into a
bucket so the user send a request into
the api gateway receives a signed URL so
the user can then directly upload a file
into the f3 bucket this is a secure way
to do direct uploads because okay the
bucket isn't secure it is not public and
you get a signed URL which is valid for
five minutes and only for the specific
item that you are going to upload so
that is very secure but it depends what
happened after wise so we're getting
secure signed URL and now we don't need
the API gateway anymore we can directly
upload of course the file into the s3
bucket which is okay but when I upload
the file into the bucket what happens
behind the scenes is that it triggers
another code could be the same function
could be another function but it
triggers the code the code the function
then goes pull out this file that i just
uploaded it upload uploaded and then it
processes it so if this function is
insecure or has some poor code then I
can take exploit of that so again let's
see a demo
okay so I have an application here I'll
discuss that application later so you
can also have fun with it
it's a devious say application they're
vulnerable service application and you
can see that in the feedback section I
can write up some feedbacks into the
application but there also there is also
and it allows me to upload file to
attach file into that feedback so I will
upload a specific file and I will see in
the request that I got the signed URL in
the response for this specific file I'll
go ahead and send that okay so now that
I learned that I can do that I'm going
to use a different file this time the
file will have a curl inside the file
name because the function is vulnerable
to command injection which we all know
so it's a Linux environment so what I'm
going to do now if you can see I'm going
to try and steal the environment
variables which will then allow me to
further exploit the account from within
my computer so I upload a file
okay
and then on the right side you can see
that I got some requests coming in I got
the base64 again I'm gonna decode that
base64 this time I'm not gonna see code
but instead I'm going to see the
environment variables so as I said I
created now I can create my own AWS
account with this or not account a
double your session with these keys and
you can see i just opened the AWS slash
credentials file where i can put all my
AWS credentials I created a new section
and I put in these environment variables
they are temporary at least the session
token is temporary but they live for a
while few minutes which can you can do
enough damage in a few minutes and of
course you can continue to get new keys
with time if they if they expire so now
I used it and you can see I'm from my
own computer now I'm not attacking the
function anymore from my own computer I
can write AWS in this case AWS CLI
commands and I can get information
outside of the cloud account into my own
computer and if they look at the logs
they will see the function that is doing
that so it's not gonna say hey there is
another user using your credentials
they're gonna see the function doing
some weird stuff maybe but the function
is doing that and you can see that I ran
AWS s3 LS which give me the list of
their three buckets inside the account
I'm interested in one so I'm going to do
LS into a specific bucket with my
profile and I get a library folder I'm
gonna get inside a folder
and then check and see that there are
two files there these are receipts so I
will try to get the specific receipt out
of this environment and then I was able
to get that sending is storing it on my
computer and then of course if I want to
do damage then I can change those
receipts
maybe then upload different receipts
with my name and then call the support
and say hey I put up an order it did not
get I did not get it they will go and
check and will see the receipts and then
or you can send them to send it to them
and then you you you might get your your
fake ID purchase and you can see that I
upload a new receipt into the account
okay s3 an API gateway are still pretty
standard they're not may might not be
the most common in web applications but
they're pretty standard so now we have
another scenario where emails that are
sent trigger a code so this is an
example of C call for papers where you
send an email with your proposal there
is a lambda function or a code behind
the scene that parse your your
attachment and responds back so let's
see how that works okay so I'm setting
up I'm sending an email that I attach
with my product proposal and then I
attach a normal in a certain submission
and I get a response back saying thank
you all right that they this is a
confirmation email thank you for your
submission okay so once I did that now I
want to do another one
only this time I will send an evil
submission so this is just malware okay
I'm trying my best here so I'm sending a
malware here but I get a response saying
that they identified this malware and
with a link to a verse total that
specify that they caught me okay so
that's not going to work but I prepared
a treat for you so I created an exploit
that if you can see here what it does is
doing some AWS code to send an email in
the name of the organization or the
event and also I want to hijack this
big bucket that holds all these
submissions so then I upload this I wrap
it I upload it to my own host doesn't
matter where I used s3 but it doesn't
matter you can upload it to any host and
then I have a file named attachment that
has will cause the lambda function to go
and fetch this code from my remote host
bring it down and run this code so this
is the payload you can see this I'm
going to try and hack this bucket here
which is denied at the moment because
it's it's at with the right permissions
the bucket itself is set with the right
permissions but the function name so oh
sorry
so now I'm going to upload this
malicious file I send some notification
along the along the way so I can see
that things are happening and you can
see the efficient email sent and the
bucket was hijacked well don't believe
me but I got a message that said the
minute hey thank you for your submission
you are accepted you can do that of
course whenever I want and of course to
get your honor rmph money click on this
phishing site and the recipient that I
sent set it to my own account so I can
get it but I can set it to different
people so if I know that someone was
accepted I don't know he published it
really early I can go and send him an
email with a phishing website and then
this is the first the the nicer apart
where I modified the permissions to this
bucket so now this bucket is public and
it had some sensitive information but
now anyone can get that that information
because I just changed the the
permissions of this bucket the reason
that I was able to do that of course is
because the function that processed the
function the the submission
did not have the get objects permission
but it had a wild card allowing it to do
whatever they want whatever it want okay
so we see that we can we can exploit
applications through emails which is not
so conventional in the regular web
applications that we know so now we're
gonna see a live demo hopefully it will
work and we'll finish with that so I
have Alexa here
let's hope it's gonna work Alexa I'm not
sure starting me demo
welcome to Alexa the hacking assistant
demo please identify by let me just a
pleasure to assist you okay so I have
the mysql here connected it's live if
it's not disconnected it probably is
okay okay so I have this MySQL database
I forgot to mention that and there is an
application that what it does it gets
some information through Alexa and gives
you back information from the database
so that could be of course I said it in
the demo to something more juicy but it
can be anything it can be a service that
you want to check the weather it can be
a service I don't know a Netflix service
or whose service that tells you what
episodes are available to a specific
your own TV show not your own your
favorite TV show so it can be whatever
if it deals with my sequel in that case
it might we might be able to hack it so
there is a limitation here because Alexa
will translate your voice into text but
it will not translate special characters
because there are special characters and
it doesn't know to send them as special
characters in order to translate them so
there is a big limitation here so I did
until until now the demos that we saw
was something things that we saw in real
application this is more an experiment
but there are ways to do SQL injection
without special characters and we'll see
that in a second so let's try that again
Alexa start hack me demo welcome to
Alexa the hacking assistant demo please
identify yourself what is your secret ID
the balance for account ID 2018 is
$15,000 you'll have to excuse me for
this demo I didn't want to deal with
larger numbers what is my balance
Alexa what is my balance please identify
yourself what is your secret ID sorry I
can't understand the command please say
again please identify yourself what is
your secret ID 1 2 3 4 sorry you were
unauthorized what is my balance please
identify yourself what is your secret ID
1 2 3 4 or true the balance for account
ID 1234 or true is 1,250,000 $419 okay
so there are ways to do some SQL
injections injection without special
characters if you're using int integers
you can deviate from the original I
integer and continue with another
command so I was able to bypass that
with an or true or of course something
more like I don't know I could do even
one two three like 1 2 3 it still
returns true so why is it different than
in regular application because if you go
into Alexa development let Alexa skills
you'll see that there are two ways to do
that either using function
lambda functions that are triggered
through your voice or you give it if you
have a server a real server god forbid
that you can give it an API a REST API
that it can communicate with but the
most common one will be using the AWS
SDK for for the lambda function that
will be triggered from the Alexa so this
is something that you want you probably
won't be seeing with regular
applications so and this is unexpected
if you are a normal application you live
in the abstract world for 4 years 10
years 20 years you don't think that
maybe someone can trigger your code
through voice this is not something that
you would expect so you need some other
perspective when dealing into
insecurities ok I saw I showed some
examples there are many other things
that you can do that would not probably
not gonna work on regular applications
for example if you deal with analytics
AWS gives you kinases which gets a lot
of information do some analytics and
gives you out the output it has asked
you it has SQL so when you want to get
your information you actually write a
dot SQL file which the Kinesis will use
so if you have a dot SQL file you
probably were not probably but you might
have SQL injection so if you can send
some weird commands into the application
even through doesn't have to be directly
to the application but anyone anything
that will trigger logs you might
actually be able to run back-end code
from different locations in the account
of course to know that it's pretty
difficult and you might need to have
either have some prior knowledge
knowledge or you are inside or you found
a vulnerability and you are trying some
lateral movement there another example
could be codes so if you have an open
source code that
has some lambda functions behind it that
is triggered whenever someone commits a
code you might be able to hack it with
some metadata or even lines in the code
depends of course what the function is
doing again this is not so common on
regular application how about cross-site
scripting we all know that from web
applications does it exist
yeah it might be less common if you're
using more advanced JavaScript you know
frameworks like react or jQuery because
they help you some in some ways but you
can actually get SQL XSS through MQTT
which in this case will push you the
exercise to your environment
but again the payloads will be the same
payloads the only thing that changes is
what you want to get out of it and how
you interact with the with the system
you can trigger XSS through SCS emails
or notifications
how about xxc I don't know if you read
the news it really exists in serverless
so again XS e XX e the the payloads
sorry the payloads itself would be the
same it's still X se but you don't want
to get that C password file because it
not doesn't interest anyone you want to
get the of our task handler Python or
index J s so this is the only thing of
course there it also depends on the XML
processor there and if they use
vulnerable libraries or vulnerable
versions of libraries then you're still
gonna be able to extract some data
through x XE on lambda function you can
get the handler
lowered sorry the source code out of the
environment it will be pretty hard to
get the environment variable because
there is some null bytes when you're
gonna get that and it's gonna trigger an
error or throw an error through the
parser okay some related content it
might help you to get to dig more into
that so I started the server stopped
always server less top ten project the
current there is a final report ready
which the current state takes the
regular OS top ten and go one by one and
discuss how's that relevant to server
list and what the attack vectors are
what the pillows and what the
mitigations are which are different we
are kind of course working on getting
tailor tailored service top ten for the
service environment there is an open
data college you can we would love if
you can contribute another project is
the ulnar ball several application it's
an application open source application
that I wrote that has dozens of
resources that you can exploit and you
can install that either from Geetha or
from the AWS repository with three
clicks and you have it don't install it
in production please I warned you live
it's going live it's recorded don't
install that in production I warned you
it's not gonna fall under me when your
company fires you other talks if you're
hanging in DC or in sector Toronto
you're welcome to see some other talks
thank you very much for coming I really
appreciate it
[Applause]