listen to this talk this is not gonna be
as deep of a dive as the last one
this talk is ipv6 consider security
considerations and for when just turn it
off isn't good enough and that quote
just turned it off
it's one that I've heard from a lot of
people when you mention ipv6 and
security they just shrug and say yeah
you're not to call anybody out you're
all here because of that I'm pretty
confident most you're here just at the
end you can say but I'll just turn it
off anyway you know okay I got this the
idea for this talk I'm talking with a
colleague of mine you know I was having
this big existential moment and turned
home and I said dude do you think we're
ready for ipv6 security and he looked
over and said does it matter man we'll
just turn it off and I'm like we're not
in charge we don't we know oh we don't
have switches we can't turn anything off
our job is just security so before we go
any further a little bit about me my
name is Jason Lewis I have a company
called route 6 security this is my
security job just full disclosure I'm
also in the Air Force Reserves and
disclaimer none of the opinions are
theirs they're all mine so don't be
affiliating me with anything but my my
background is primarily in business and
I spend a lot of my time thinking about
policy which is probably way different
than most you guys in here this
conference is not policy and business
but I heard to me when I was 7 talked to
my colleague before that it is the
reason you can't turn stuff off I
believe is gonna come up is that as you
move forward here's here's what I see
things moving is that there's so many
ipv6 addresses and so few epi v4
addresses there right now some companies
make extra money on the side just
selling their unused ipv4 space it's a
it's a revenue producer for some people
and ipv6 on the other hand there's given
away Aaron will just give you chunks of
it if you want it and for that reason
eventually what's gonna happen is it's
gonna be so cheap the startups are gonna
start using it it's already happening
some places starting to start using
they're gonna make cool applications
that do cool things and your company
whoever you work for whatever
organization you're in is gonna want to
use some of this stuff at some point or
another they're gonna run into a wall
right right now you have some places
that only do ipv4 you can't you can't do
anything about v6 it's gonna flip at
some points and it's just it's not going
to kill a rap it's not be something the
one thing that you have to have it's
just going to be subtle eventually not
being able to use these things or if you
are in a an organization that produces
some sort of consumer facing product
you're going to want to be able to
capitalize on that market share right
you're gonna want to be able to get to
those people who are using those devices
or that application that only takes ipv6
and someday somebody's gonna come down
and say you know what we're gonna do
this this is our new business model and
they're look at that you can't turn it
off even if you physically could go to
the machines or you can click around and
turn everything off and even if you were
able to track it on every instance of
ipv6 on your network and shut it down
your bosses would fire you all right so
your job your point your position at
that point will just be go on a new job
or adapt and so hopefully here today we
can I'm just gonna try to get you a
nudge in direction towards adapting if
that's where you're at so we can move on
so the intended audience for this this
for security personnel a lot of the ipv6
security stuff out there is how to
configure your network as if you're an
administrator and again it's great stuff
to read but if you're like me and you do
a lot of blue team type of things or
you're you're looking through Network
you're looking for bad guys on your
network you're not really concerned
necessarily with how to configure your
network although you will recommend it
to people you are concerned with ipv6
special considerations and how to make
that work for you I also assume that
everything here is passingly familiar
with ipv6 that you at least recognize it
as as a thing if I showed you an address
with colons and you'd be like yeah inset
v6 move on that's good and finally like
I said at the beginning I assume most of
you guys in here or the turn it off
folks or at least people who are
familiar with that position and thinking
hey maybe I should position myself to
take that guy's job whenever he finally
butts heads with the business people and
loses
so all right an overview just give you
an idea we're gonna talk about here I'm
going to cover extension headers logging
addresses attribution and by with
attribution I mean figuring out how to
associate the network traffic with a
host is producing it not necessarily a
behavior with a apt or something of that
nature we're talk about slack and if you
don't know what that is that's it's good
we'll get to that as well some toolkits
are out there resources that you should
be aware of in a few takeaways in
quotation marks at the very end of this
you should at least be able to walk away
with a couple things in a meeting you
can interject at the right point so he's
gonna look at you nods they exactly give
that man a raise or woman
so extension headers you guys were
probably familiar with the issue of
fragmentation in ipv4 right and it's
been fixed by and large and most devices
on the network fragmentation being able
to bypass firewalls because you're able
to hide what is actually inside the
packet is something that is still an
issue with ipv6 so the extension headers
are very very long potentially long
chains of information that are right
between the extra ipv6 header and then
the underlying data so these long chains
could potentially be too big to transmit
in one packet and therefore you might
need to fragment them if that happens
then potentially you could put together
especially if you don't have a state if
you have a stateless firewall instead of
a stateful one then some of these things
could slip through in traffic into your
network that you don't want so what you
need to be aware of is that these
extension headers are new to ipv6 but
they create issues similar to what you
experienced ipv4 and Wow the best
practice is in common sense say don't
let that happen we don't want to have
fragmentation sometimes it's just the
way things work and in particular
there's an issue with turning off
fragmentation for network devices that
are in between other devices that aren't
aware
that fragmentations not allowed if you
break that chain now you break the whole
system and that makes people unhappy and
once again people will tell you you guys
with your back so keeping that in mind
you it'd be nice if everybody could
agree on one standard to implement ipv6
implementations of the RFC's very widely
we get kind of accustomed to ipv4 and
how everybody just does what's supposed
to happen they teach it in classes as if
there's only one way to do networking
and that is what the RFC say well in
ipv6 there are competing RFC's there are
deprecated RFC's and if you have any
networking device has been built over
the last ten years which some is not
uncommon to find in many places you
would have a wide range of
implementations of best practices and
deprecated best practices in alternative
best practices implemented there so if
you're not tracking on these things and
you're not asking the questions like
what are we doing here then you might be
surprised one day to find out the people
are evading your ACLs and potentially
tossing you as well whenever they send
these potentially unlimited extension
headers through your software or
networking equipment the hardware
implementation can't handle it cuz it's
too big so it sends up to your software
and now you're unpacking these extension
headers in software and dossing and
getting dosed so be aware of extension
headers another thing I spend a lot of
time digging few logs
I imagine you guys do to everybody
everybody digs through logs and an ipv4
there's only one way to write an address
and you guys that's great it makes it
easy even ipv4 so all three of these are
one way or one address now the bottom
one I don't think I've ever seen
anything record an address that way
fully written out all the zeros all
those things if for those who aren't
familiar you can use double colons once
in the middle of any of that to get rid
of any number of zeros altogether and
then you can get rid of all zeros to the
left within the semi colons themselves
you can so you can make a big address
smaller check that is at the top of
there
missing semicolons apologize for that
our colons anyway so you're unlikely to
see the bottom example but the top
example in the middle example where you
have F E in lowercase and F EE
capitalized that seems like a subtle
difference but the best practice that
I've read and the one I believe in is
the top one where you use lowercase but
there are RFC's that are published
current RFC's out there that use the
middle one as their examples so even the
ietf can't figure out exactly what
they're doing it seems small but
whenever you go to use grep you're gonna
miss stuff if you're writing a script to
pull stuff out of these logs then you're
gonna skip miss things now there are
depending upon what you're using to go
through your logs they might take care
of this for you right Splunk has a
plugin that makes it all go away but if
you're regex was base it was written by
somebody in your shop and it was based
on the idea that everything looks like
one of these and then it's not you could
run into issues as well you might not be
logging what you need and you certainly
might be missing information all right
and now we're gonna talk about
attribution as I mentioned before this
is not attribution to an actor this is a
tributing network traffic back to a
machine
classically ipv4 addresses are pretty
simple they'll either be statically
assigned or DW DHCP leases that are
renewed on a regular basis and it's
fairly static if you look at a week's
worth of network traffic you're gonna
have a good idea of who is talking to
whom and not a lot of issues there
however with ipv6 that's more
complicated so one way to give ipv6
addresses is to just let the machines do
it themselves you can do stateless
configuration and they'll make up their
own address and that sounds dangerous
and it can be but that is why they
sometimes check it against other stuff
and they have the clever idea to use the
Mac these eui-64 extensions what they do
is they take those last 64 bits of the
address and then they use the MAC
address and then make it long enough
they shove fffe in the center of it and
then they flip a bit and the seventh bit
from the left if you're looking at it on
pay
and that is their new new address that's
great
because that tells you which machine it
was if you know which which computer has
that MAC address in it then you should
have a good idea and so that makes
attribution fairly easy and that also so
when you take away from this is that if
you are lucky enough to have just be
using these kinds of addresses on your
network that if you see a bunch of FF es
in the middle of your addresses you can
probably reverse that back by reef
lipping the bit pulling out the fffe and
Ingle know the MAC address and that's
how you can figure out who was once you
also recorded the MAC address in your
logs
however that's not the best thing to do
if you're using those addresses to go
out over the Internet to conduct
business some people didn't like the
idea that people could be tracking you
by this address everywhere you go and
they wanted more privacy so they created
privacy extensions the privacy addresses
and these are actually a couple ways to
do them but the net result is that there
look fairly random they are randomized
and these addresses provide the the user
with a little bit anonymity which is
great unless you're using these
addresses to try to figure out what's
happening within your network and
privacy addresses are great to go out to
the wide world or from a security
perspective they're annoying much the
way that I pee second can be a problem
so these privacy addresses are difficult
and but one of the only ways are going
to be able to figure out these things is
by keeping track of the neighbor
advertisements and if that's a new word
to you what you guys need to be aware of
is that ARP is dead and ipv6 it's been
replaced by neighbor advertisements and
the neighbor advertisement or then sorry
the neighbor table so what you need to
be doing is recording these neighbor
tables because some of these depending
on the implementation again everything's
in varies widely
Ubuntu has a 24-hour standard a life
span for privacy address there are other
devices that go as low as four hours so
what this means is that even if you look
at one day's worth of traffic the same
same machine could be using multiple
different addresses to be able to
conduct whatever behavior it is so if
you are not keeping track of these
addresses if you're not
logging them and retain those logs long
enough to meet whatever look-back
responsibilities you have if your
organization wants you to be able look
back three days you need to make sure
that you're keeping these neighbor
advertisements that long if you're in a
situation where like I sometimes find
myself in where I'm not actually able to
affect how much logging is taking place
I am a guest on somebody else's network
and while I'm there I have to do the
best I can you can also pull these off
the wire and it's a good thing to retain
as well just capturing them because what
these neighbor advertisements are like a
narc
it's how that client whenever the
informations come back in is able to say
I am at this address
go ahead and send it to me and in that
that's gonna be your only clue unless
you were able to to find it on the host
itself and then finally I will talk
about the do its DHCP user IDs which are
they're interesting because you get
multiple interfaces on your computer
these days right like I've got Wireless
I've got an Ethernet connection
I've got Bluetooth all of these are
network adapters each one of these has a
different burnin address and the thing
about the DHCP so if you choose to use
dhcpv6 on your network instead of this
stateless Auto configuration that I was
just discussing then these DHCP logs
will retain this information and they'll
be able to associate this do it back to
a machine but one thing I want you to be
aware of just a fun little tidbit for
your information you never know when
you're gonna need any back pocket is
that the do it assigned to a machine is
based only off of one of those
interfaces and it may not be the
interface that was being used in order
to to go out so even though the
connection was wireless it may be
referencing the MAC address from the
ethernet card when this is going to
matter to you the most I don't know I
don't know but someday you might think
back to this talk and be like ah got it
that was an obscure piece of trivia he
pulled straight from the RFC's alright
so slack strange things with slack all
right you have router advertisements so
stateless auto-configuration and most of
us used to DHCP where a computer host
comes on and says hey I need an address
and the ECP server goes back to it and
is like hey here's your address here's
your default gateway
here's your dns information you have a
good day in Internet well well if you're
not using a DHCP server then you don't
get that kind of stuff so to fix this
instead now routers just advertise
themselves they say hey guys
these multicast addresses and they just
say I'm a router anybody out there can
use a router hit me up with like a
bulletin board in a coffee shop or
something like that and just like a
bolts on board in the coffee shop you
don't know what you're getting and so
some of these it's it's very easy to
fake your router advertisement and there
are multiple sources out there multiple
scripts have been written to just
generate these router advertisements and
what that will do is allow yourself to
allow you to be a man in the middle and
this man in middle capability is of
course one thing that secure people
don't like but assuming that the the
router advertisements not coming from
malicious source it could potentially
also come from just a miss configuration
a host gets on the network and says hey
this is this is my default gateway you
should try it the other host pick it up
picks it up since it's dirt default
gateway and next thing you know no
traffic's leaving your network and you
can't figure out why this is less of a
security issue but more of a problem I
run into and then this is particularly
an issue if you think you turned off
ipv6 on your network so you stop
worrying about it and now you have the
occasional rogue advertisement going
around all right
so toolkits sudden you guys are pen
testers as well you're a little less
worried about how to track logs as much
as you are worried about doing stuff and
also if you want to be able to figure
out what your networks posture is you
may use some of these the the best one
the one you if you type in ipv6 toolkits
the hackers choice is gonna show up it
is it's in Cali nowadays it is robust
and it's never let me down and I so
there it is
I recommend it but another one out there
is the si6 Network ipv6 toolkit and
those guys they do classes
Parris coming up here pretty soon if you
guys have funding it is also pretty
decent and then finally Scapa six is
it's not really a toolkit it's just a
tool everything thats capi can do it can
do too so you should try it
craft packets to make sure that your
network is actually responding the right
way make sure these router
advertisements are not being picked up
and they shouldn't be making sure that
you don't have other issues that spoken
about so this is from the si6 toolkit I
don't know if you read that back there
it looks a lot better on my computer but
there are all sorts of things that are
in this toolkit and I chose the si6
toolkit as my example because the the
hackers choices actually has far more
than I could fit on the screen and be
multiple multiple slides worth but you
see here that there are things like IP
address analysis manipulation tool tool
perform a tax based on icmpv6 error
messages router advertisement forgery
and then what I want you to look at down
there is the scan 6 which yeah near the
bottom
it's an ipv6 scanning tool I wanted to
hit on real quick bonus ipv6 scanning a
lot people think that the obscurity that
having that large address space will
give you some sort of security which we
all know is the fallacy right that's
obscure security through obscurity so I
want to let you know that there are
people out there developing algorithms
to make it easier to scan these large
swaths and those are getting better but
even then sometimes your admins that you
set your security posture for failure by
doing things like incorporating the ipv4
address it used to be into the ipv6
address so with any knowledge of the old
ipv4 scheme tebah you found it and even
then scanning the ipv6 space for a 10/8
worth of addresses is just as easy as
scanning in an ipv4 another thing is
that you use a service of the suffix so
that would be an NTP server right there
and that's one I mean people will try
that Oh your DNS server let's just try
your address 53 and mmm too often that's
exactly what it is so if you're able to
advise people against this I recommend
it and the last one is using using words
in there and there are a lot of cool
words you can create with the 0 through
F and finally take away if you guys are
going to take anything away from this of
all the resources I
use all the resources I've read just
read this one this is a draft RFC
written by a guy named binky who also
was a co-author of ipv6 security from
Cisco press who's he knows a lot he's
been working on this for a long time
this is about 20 pages worth of reading
total and it's like a full primer on
ipv6 cuts out a lot of the baloney and
it goes deeper into the security issues
than like I am here so that's it one
resource all right so finally the
takeaways this is it so if you get
nothing else out of this each one go
back and you want a sound with a little
bit more like you know it's been on ipv6
you want to be ready to take the
position of the guy who retires because
he doesn't want to bother with it and he
just wants to turn it all off ask some
of these questions like how does our
equipment handle extension headers oh
good question we'll make sure we include
that whenever we're purchasing equipment
you're a manager now how are we
standardizing our addresses all right
are we using capitals we're using
lowercase R we're using both do we
download the plug-in for Splunk yes good
look at me I'm considering things are we
maintaining neighbor discovery
information long enough to meet our
obligations you know will I be able to
attribute activity I see on my network
to an actor 12 hours from now are you
relying on me to be able to go back in
there and most the addresses still be
the same no well we got problems
sometimes you depending on who you work
for you might have legal and regulatory
obligations to be able to attribute
things so make sure you're keeping these
neighbor neighbor discovery logs longer
all right does anybody have any
questions I think a couple minutes left
all right
yes tools yeah do you make one of these
webpage this
No is there one yeah the question was is
our way to there's our standard way to
communicate ipv6 addresses and I have
not seen one yes ma'am no III do think
that for now don't get me wrong like I'm
not the kind of guy who goes home and
sets up an ipv6 home network just for
the fun of it I mean like I have my side
network with my production internet my
internet went out my wife would be very
upset my kids too it's just easier to go
with the default ipv4 if it's easier and
cheaper just do it that way I am a
business background guy but I do you
think that one day that there will be a
business case for not doing it and
that's what's going to drive it so yeah
right now in the military to you know
the Stig's they they also say turn off
everybody saying turn it off except for
the people who aren't you know like
Facebook and Netflix and Google and
Android so so yes it's great until it's
not and really all you're doing is
avoiding technology I do think that as
security professionals it's better for
our jobs and our future to prepare
ourselves for whenever that's not the
case anymore but yeah whether whether to
turn it off or not it really depends on
your business use case yep all right yes
sir yes as of two years ago their
adoption rate was 50% well internally
and I've seen little exponential graphs
that show more a lot of people are
working ISPs and tech giant's are going
towards straight I peepee six now
they're gonna the dual-stack for a long
time I believe but but definitely want a
job there good stuff to know and also
yeah that's gonna be what's driving a
lot of this in the future probably I'm
not sure how they're implementing it to
make it to make it work I think if
they're tunneling it it's probably the
way that it's happening and ya can't
speak more on that for them so I I
believe that startups will lead the way
where they can't afford to do ipv4 and
and then eventually so everything's we
tunneled at first and then somebody's
gonna be like why are we tunneling all
this stuff every OS every major OS
supports ipv6 natively every networking
device major networking device supports
ipv6 natively why are we spending the
extra overhead and resources to tunnel
this and then there it is alright guys
well thank you my time is up I
appreciate you guys hanging out for the
talk