operations on kubernetes a little about
who we are
yeah I'm Larry sudo and and I do a lot
of cloud security testing and some
Windows pen testing as well and this
talk is kind of about how to take DevOps
skills and and integrate it with your
Red Team operations you know I am
Jeff Holden I work at the largest
college system in the United States
assist so by day hacker by night
currently living in an RV with three
dogs one wife and one kid much fun so
the goals of the of the project is
basically to have the cube read working
in all three of the major container
systems are cloud providers AWS Google
cloud engine and Azure we're starting
with AWS is we have experience in so we
have it working at this point in AWS
want it to be automated you basically
put all your configs into one config
file run a script push it out and you'll
have your CTO infrastructure up and
running within about 20 minutes portable
in scriptable so you can make any
changes you want to and do it the same
each time on even different cloud
providers so if you've been in a coma
for the last five years and just woke up
what is the stalker thing similar to
virtual machines but now it's sharing
the kernel much more efficient less use
of memory and disk and i/o and that
stuff so it's you can fit more stuff on
one machine there's an old example of
whoops example of a docker file you you
know pick the the docker image you want
in this case it updates every time it
runs installs engine X on this file
alright so docker is great and all but
what happens when you have hundreds of
docker images you need a way to organize
a organize it and get everything up and
running in a organized fast fashion do
deploys all that good stuff
so that's where kubernetes comes into
play so it's the orchestration engine
you can deploy hundreds of different
images at once do rolling deploys make
changes all the good stuff that the
DevOps people want need is built into
kubernetes here's a little example of a
Koopa a simple kubernetes file that
deploys a team server that we're using
the cobalt strike team server service
for its re so you have different files
for services deployment of images
pushing out configs to the different
docker images and that good stuff so
yeah that's basically with the different
kind of files that you'll see is
deployments for for the docker images
services you have to define those what
what service will port you're exposing
all that stuff helm charts are optional
which we're making heavy use of that
helps us push out services all right so
what is the cop saying it's basically
the heavy lifting on it works in AWS
right now and into Google container
engine you run it it sets up all the ec2
instances for you assets of the VP sees
load balancers creates your access list
for you so otherwise you'd have to go
through and set all those up manually
here's an example of how easy it is to
set up a high availability cluster and
to availability zones in AWS you
basically run one command and then just
wait about 15 minutes and you have your
cluster up and running all in one shot
so once you have your cluster up and
running you do need a way to access it
we're going to be using external DNS we
don't have this implemented quite yet
but this is what we'll be doing it's
basically just the pod you send it a
yeah mol config file and it will
automatically update route 53 to push to
your
load balancer automatically for you
should also put point out that within an
AWS the native commands you can register
domains on the fly and set all the zones
and everything up that you didn't need
to do and will be supporting that in the
future as well
so SSL cert manager we're going to be
using the built-in server manager
function of docker you can use let's
encrypt so you basically request a
certificate puts it in etc D secrets so
then you can just reference that in your
docker files that your your deployment
file sorry yeah and there's the link to
that will make that available and so
that was the easy part the overview
since I'm the CISO I'm gonna hand it
over now to the real engineer okay um so
yeah so now I'm we're gonna get into the
discussion of like so once you have your
infrastructure up what do you do and how
do I get my c2 up and running how do I
get traffic into it and the background
on that is basically if you if you done
c2 infrastructure before a lot of people
use you know you know for reader it's
basically a redirector to a back of
back-end and a lot of people use the
Apache mod rewrite and then those with
rules in mod rewrite to route stuff and
to do filtering and rewriting and stuff
like that so but if if you look at you
know that was traditionally done with
the V pcs but if you look at it now you
the there's a lot of advanced proxy
technical proxy technology available in
cloud native environments and it's kind
of what we're focusing on we've seen a
lot of adoption of docker by Red Team
red team's for Red Team infrastructure
but not so much in container management
and service mesh technology
and then service mission technology has
a lot of promise for sophisticated situ
operations it was just the just the
nimbleness of your ability to deploy
redirect or change things on the fly
redeploy stuff is just amazing yeah and
then again with with kubernetes in the
mix it's really easy to to like
literally deploy redirect errs like at
almost that will that's that's the
background and then so we'll talk a
little bit about what how to get your
situ containerized
this is kind of the simple part with
docker what we're supporting initially
is cobalt striking in Merlin and then
you know we're gonna we're gonna do as
many as possible in the coming months so
this is just built building a docker
image for cobalt strike from a docker
file this is an actual docker file for
cobalt strike so we actually in in the
in the github there's gonna be a section
for doctor files and for each see -
there's gonna be it a docker file so you
can build an image for it for coulis
right you need a license so it's it's
kind of like some of the images won't be
available online because you'll have to
build it yourself and stick it in this
um you know right and then this is a
sample docker docker file for Merlin and
then so then um okay so that's a sad
suit you got your docker image so where
do you go next so you're gonna want to
just have this concept so you're gonna
have one as concept of a config map and
and then also the concept of secrets if
if you're doing passwords and
certificates a lot of this stuff we're
automating and in helm charts but I just
want it for completeness discuss what a
config map is and basically it's an it's
it's kind of like a set of key value
pairs in an object that
um the container deployment can
reference and then this is actually
pulled from the helm chart we're making
available for cobalt strike this is the
actual deployment file deployment
template in in the helm chart as this
what this does is it this gives you
everything you need to deploy your coal
strike image into into a kubernetes
environment and then this is then yeah
this is just the rest of it that so that
was the whole entire deployment template
and then what the template does is
there's a there's a values file by using
a mo file that you populate with the the
values that these variables in pick up
and then then kubernetes handles all the
the you know container creation
deployment IP address and everything you
know one thing is really cool is if
people work with the team server
traditionally you have to when you start
it up you have to provide that I
password IP address and then if you're
using a valuable situ profiles you have
to provide that with this that it's
that's all automated you just put that
into a file on the values that yellow
file and then you with the helm command
you can just deploy it at will anywhere
you want basically as many copies as you
want you can actually if you look in the
previous slide you can actually create
replicas so if you get a lot if you have
a lot of implants running you can
actually scale it so you could have
multiple cobalt strike servers running
simultaneously and then and then yeah so
now this is a this is something that's
that's I'm going to get into ingress
controllers so this is actually a
service stuff in it so so when you when
you start up the team server the by
default you have port 554 for just for
connecting to and managing it creating
the
the beacons and all that stuff you
probably want to make that private so
what in because the UM for initial
ingress control are going to talk about
the doesn't support non HTTP HTTP ports
you're gonna have to basically create an
ingress controller load balancer and
soon and guess which is a load balancer
for managing the team server and this is
just a sample of how you would create a
service that spins up a AWS load
balancer connections so you can connect
to the team server and you know in a
private in a private VPC yeah so that's
that and then this is a this is the
server's definition for the Kobalt
listener this basically is the port 80
that you that the beacon checks in to
and then if you use certificates in like
for this case in the case then the
merlin c2 server you'll need
certificates because it's it's it's TLS
but pretty much by default so you want
to create a certificate for it the nice
thing about kubernetes is it'll mount
this you just have to create these
certificates as objects and then
communities will mount this stuff into
your container and then as we discussed
earlier cert manager cannot can automate
the actual
acquisition and updates of these
certificates and you can just create
multiple certificate objects secret
certificate objects and in the community
in your kubernetes cluster and then all
your different SI toos during the as you
deploy them can just pick them up yeah
and this is the amount of how how the
certificates mounted into the container
okay so now I'm going to get a little
bit into ingress controllers this is
basically how are you gonna get the the
traffic into the c2 server or phishing
server whatever whatever c2 and first is
c2 or Red Team infrastructure you have
ingress controllers basically are are
the are the routers there like what used
to be edge routers but they're like
software soft it's also off configurable
software now they're basically like
reverse proxies and this is the engine
x1 and this is just the way you install
it and you want to install it as layer 4
so you can you can use TCP so the load
balance or it it it creates this can be
used for layer for not just layer 7 okay
so config Maps it engine it so nginx
ingress control is very configurable and
if you're gonna do rewriting and
filtering in your in your c2 profiles or
whatever c2 server you have and you're
gonna you're gonna want as see if the
beacon or the implant checks in you're
going to want to read some something in
the headers or that that's coming in and
you wanna if it if it's not correct you
want to redirect it or sinkhole it
you're gonna want to be able to do that
and then with the nginx English
controller you're gonna have to do some
annotations and all so if you're using C
Tuesday or h2 to base your Lobby
to add add that as well and then this is
the actual service definition for an
ingress so the ingress is this is how
the ingress control is actually
configured and this is basically saying
that you're going to allow in the
traffic through the load balancer and
through the nginx ingress and then you
put in the annotations and any anything
that's any type of custom logic that you
want that and everything is everything
that its traditional nginx server
reverse proxy supports you have access
through through these these annotations
and this basically what this does is
this is saying if something connects
that to this service that we set up as
cobalt listener which is basically the
the cuomo strike team server just if
something hits URL slash this is what
one without a now you will see two
profile just route it directly to the
cobalt the team server and then now
we're going to go into a little bit of
the details of redirection i'll focus on
nginx ingress first because that's
really popular in in in kubernetes and
and then the the one we like best is is
is ISTE oh we've had a lot of success
with that so i'll spend quite a bit of
time on that so this is basically
running engine X as a redirector so you
have your implants you have your load
balancer you have the nginx
english controller which when you when
you install it automatically creates the
load balancer and then the ingress
resource is where you can figure the the
routing and the filtering and the and
yeah whatever redirection you're doing
and then and then this that's your
back-end stuff your c2 server team
server
and then you know if you have like a
payload dropper or phishing server you
can actually route route to that as
needed yeah and these are the
annotations for for in the ingress in
the ingress object that an ingress um
definition or manifest as you as you
call it and you could you have to
reference this and then I'm sure some
examples but but just to point out that
the annotations to do rewrites and
annotations to do what's called
configuration snippets which is actually
how how you specify stuff you know
rewrite and well very specifics nginx
directives so if you if you have some
experience with mod rewrite you could
actually and there's a lot of examples
on the out there on using mod rewrite to
create filtering and redirection you can
actually convert it to nginx rewrite and
then drop that in into your ingress
manifest and then you can basically
reuse stuff so then if you if you want
to do sink holing and stuff you'll have
to create a back-end and that's that's a
back-end so basically that's something
outside of the cluster and so if you see
if something doesn't match on the
ingress inbound on in your filtering
rule then you can send it to what's
called the back an external name and
this would be like something like Google
com yeah then this would be the fine
this would be the final definition this
is an ingress definition which does a a
match on that that this the regular
expression on the user agent so that's
like you parse out that what's important
to you in the user agent and
and if that if that doesn't happen then
then you basically redirect them to
google.com 404 so this is this is just a
very basic rewrite redirection filtering
rule that you can customize for you know
your your situ environment and then this
is just the rest this is just the rest
of it yeah this is just another example
of a rewrite rule this just check this
is a server snippet as opposed to
configuration snip and this just checks
to again the user agent and then if it
that's not in the user agent field then
it just read returns it to a different
URL and then if you're using TLS in your
situ you'll want to do SSL pass-through
so basically if the c2 server is TLS
configured for TLS you're gonna need to
let the the TLS traffic go hit it on the
back end and and then this is just the
way you set up the ingress controller to
do that and then it will have this stuff
a lot of most of automated though in the
project this is for the details for
completeness and then once you get it
all configured you have your ingress
rule you have all your rewriting
filtering a redirecting setup then you
can use this kubernetes command to in
that it's actually the pod so you'll see
you you'll have your Inga's controller
running as a pod and then you basically
can check its nginx Kankan comp to make
sure that you all your all your rules
are correct
okay so now now I'm gonna talk about a
service mesh a service mesh is actually
under under the it's basically a a proxy
that sits on on each each container
cluster or pod as they call it in
kubernetes and it's fully fully it's
fully controllable by llamó policy so
you couldn't you couldn't actually have
it on the edge as an ingress controller
or you can have it on every single pot
in your in your cluster and do very
sophisticated traffic management traffic
analysis redirection and all that stuff
so so initially we we were working with
nginx ingress but then when we realized
that you know service mesh is probably
has a lot more functionality and it was
actually a lot it's a lot easier to set
up initially it's a conceptually a
little different but once the just the
the this geo projects the ability to do
very sophisticated traffic management
it's very impressive and it's really
useful for c2 infrastructure and then
yeah the basically way it works is
you've got the Envoy proxy sitting on a
node that that is actually an ingress
node it allocates a load balancer and
then you configure that and and you
configure the routing the filtering the
redirection all that stuff on there and
then you have your your c2 services
deployed in the back and then you route
to them based on the ingress traffic
yeah the Envoy proxy is basically the
core of this I don't know if people are
familiar with envoy yeah envoy it comes
out it comes out of lyft it's probably
the most advanced edge edge proxy
available and you can use it by itself
but this what this CEO project did is
they created a whole
sort of management infrastructure around
it you can now you know deploy as many
of these envoy proxies as you want and
just in this control the policy from a
central location using using the the
Amal and yeah and in and it's fully full
another nice thing is the kubernetes
kubernetes ingress is kind of focused on
ingress definitions are kind of focused
on HTTP HTTP with SEO and on boy you
have full TCP HTTP layer seven layer
four you can actually if you have a c2
and you want to do DNS no problem yeah
you can actually you can actually do DNS
you can actually yeah do HTTP eighty
whatever you want simultaneously in in
one configuration so this is it this is
installing Sto this is actually um we've
automated all this but I just just is
just to show you what it what it
involves and then once you install this
do this is what this is what the UM
ingress controller looks like this is
the ingress controller that's the load
balancer that's attached to it and then
then you can actually specify what ports
you want the ingress controller to have
available and these are just some
default ports that are there but it's
all configurable and you can have
multiple ingress so so let's say it
translate that to your e-reader actors
so with with this you can you can just
basically script out all your redirect
errs how many you want you can have as
many as you want as long as long as the
cloud provider and you can has has been
you or you have the resources you can
spin up as many of these redirect errs
as you want and if they get you know
blocked you can just spin up another one
and it's just just from a very simple
yeah Mille configuration
and then so when you when you do
configure a read redirector there's a
file is that a eminence in this geo
distribution and then you can in there
you can go in and you can set the knee
then you just basically cut and paste
this thing in mode and just as long as
you give it a new if the ingress gateway
a new name so this is it's doing your
scripts away that's the default ingress
gateway as long as you give it a new
name a multiple of these ingress
gateways and you can have them listening
on different ports and each ingress
gateway will have its own load balancer
so will have its own unique IP address
so if you need multiple redirect errs
and different with different different
IPS if things get burned then you can
you can kind of set it up that way and
then you can also deploy your deploy
your own in ingress gateway that way
that was the values that yeah mo that
drives this configuration from a helmet
art but you could you can actually
deploy your own as well but like a lot
of this stuff is we're handling we're
automating so you so will be you'll be
able to just from the cube read command
line just deploy an ingress gateway just
tell what you know what what his
properties are and it'll create a new
one for you and deploy it and then so so
now you have your ingress gateway
launched or multiple ingress gateways
launched now you want to configure it
and this is basically how you configure
configure it you create what's called a
gateway which actually exposes the ports
on the ingress controller load balancer
that you're going to bring into the
cluster that you're going to attach to
your c2 environment and then you create
what's called a virtual service which
actually is
is the mediator between the Gateway and
your pop in the pod the actual actual
running container and then with with
that you you connect the traffic to your
situ and then so this is a gateway
configuration this actually takes the
traffic from the ingress controller load
balancer and exposes it to the cluster
and basically exposes it to sto
management of on boy
so then through through and this is
basically the entry point to the mesh
and so in this in this case this is an
example of what then the entry point to
a mesh that's kind of focused on COBOL
strikes team server looks like so we're
bringing in port 80 we're bringing in
five 150 to do the administration and
then we're 443 if as pass-through if we
were doing SSL on this on this team
server for the beacons the nice thing
about is it's much easier to configure
it than the nginx
ingress and so I think it's it's a
better way to go but we're gonna support
nginx ingress and and and this your
service mesh in this project and then
the virtual service as I mentioned
before it defines the traffic routing
rules to apply when was the one that
when the when the implant or beacon
comes in it's going to it's gonna hit a
hit a hostname and then so the virtual
service will get notification of that
and then and then that that specifies
the routing rules to access the actual
running container and then here you can
do the like what we talked about in
nginx ingress here you set up your your
matching rules to do you know rewriting
filtering and etc and it's another nice
thing about
about this do is its support fully
supports HTTP TCP HTTP to UDP I mean
whatever your c2 is you can actually
specify routing rules for it and then
you can also attach to each each ingress
controller you can attach multiple
domain like you can register a whole
bunch of domains on one ingress
controller and depending on which host
of beacon or implants checking into you
can route it to a very specific back-end
yeah and then this is this is a virtual
service for a team a team server which
uses the a team server gateway which
which we saw before which which exposes
those three ports and then this this
matches on port 80
it'll if it matches on port 80 it'll
just send it to the team server also if
it if you have a malleable c2 profile
enabled you can you could this isn't
this for example in the in the what
we're releasing and we just have a
sample of a very simple map of c2
profile and this is just matching on
that user agent in that manual c2
profile and if and if so so basically
the way it works is this is a and rule
so if it matches on the user agent and
it matches on a prefix a URI prefix oh
if you'll if you have worked with my BC
tours you know you know as you can set
your I prefixes for where the word the
beacon connects to to send send data and
so if you match on that then it'll send
us the team server if you don't it'll
it'll send you to Google calm so you can
do all the whole you can all work out
all the all the filtering and
redirection with there's a whole there's
a whole language if you missed it you
can go to the sto site there's all
there's a whole bunch of functionality
you can use in these matching rules you
can get very sick
educated and it's in it's in it's very
simple planing the she Amal much easier
than you know you're messing around with
all those annotations and nginx ingress
so we found it to be a lot easier and
also TLS if it's a TLS connection coming
in they you know then you just basically
check to see this TLS and then send it
if it's TLS and it's hitting that host
then send it to the team server service
if not then send it to Google comm so
you can do all that stuff yeah this is a
string matching so all the matching
rules you can do an exact match string
match a prefix based string match or you
can do yet ECMAScript cell right reg X's
so you can do full reg X match on
anything in the HTTP requests of the
beacon so just some tips on its yo
ingress gateway we have a selectors used
by SEO to select the ingress gateway so
so basically when you when you when you
create a virtual service to do the
routing rules you'll you'll want to
basically select which ingress gateway
you're going to receive the traffic from
and basically which is the gateway is
really your basically your like your
redirector for that particular virtual
service which which is your routing
rules for whatever containers that your
you're using for for you know the c2 and
yeah so that's it and then then there's
something with port naming and when you
when you when you create ports to bring
in in the in the gateway config you have
to give it a name and and the name has
to be prefixed with the type of protocol
that that particular port is running so
these are just and then you just made
that suffix doesn't really matter so
that's just some something to think
about and then so so when we took what
we saw in the the previous configs we
were saying that if it if if there's if
there's no match to certain prefixes or
certain user agent properties or values
then send it outside the mesh send it
somewhere outside but maybe back to the
target out to some other external site
by default is do let's envoy pass
through so you don't you don't have to
really do anything you can just specify
those those those destinations to
wherever you want based on your matching
rule yeah it's on by default but you can
you can test it on here and with this
command get config map its do - and SEO
system and that'll that'll it'll allow
any is there then then it's allowed then
the interesting thing is and this is
maybe not for for red teaming but the
service special allows you to control
access out of the cluster so you can
actually set set set this to you know
just turn this off and then no traffic's
allowed out of the server special unless
you specify egress points and you can
have a single egress point you can it's
called the service entry and you can
specify these these places that that the
the services in the mesh are allowed to
talk to okay so yeah some notes on
ingress capabilities a mesh can have any
number of gateways and multiple
different implementations of the gateway
can coexist yeah so the router routing
API expresses the routing needs of eight
of ISTE oh and it's yeah kubernetes
ingress is kind of
focused on on HTTP and then yeah so
that's why that's why this you know sort
of fish is better because that you have
the full gamut of of TCP and if in your
c2 infrastructure if you if you're using
like fishing servers you're using DNS
and stuff yeah it's good let's see what
else here okay all right yeah actually
we have a little demo to show so just
gonna gonna do the demo all right so
here do a video because I don't trust
the demo gods and plus it takes too long
bigger alright so here is the script as
it is in its present-day starting it up
now I'm giving it a name for this for
the cluster called the legit situ now
we're just going to deploy the cluster
this is running cops to deploy
everything this in particular is just
not it's not an hea cluster it's got one
master and two nodes and here it's going
through all the AWS things that it's
setting up so it's running all this
fast-forward through this a little bit
here cuz no one cares then it waits for
the nat gateway coming up is the thing
that takes the longest up to five
minutes and then what happens up then i
pause the video you have to wait about
10 or 15 minutes i'm gonna have this all
scripted where it will automatically
check the status of the cluster and once
it's up then we will go ahead and do the
deploy so here's me checking that the
cluster is up as you can see it's ready
to go then the next step we're going to
do is actually run in deploy sto and the
cobalt strike server or pod so it's
installing tiller
[Music]
the Helmand right now it's super hacky I
need to this code will be probably
released on Monday at the earliest
because I need to go in and actually fix
it and make it pretty and right now I
have really bad sleeps in between the
commands so that everything is coming up
instead of checking the status and then
running the next command so but it works
right now getting sto all set up before
here a little bit just a few creates the
namespace first EO created the secret
for deploying to the from the private
docker image and now deployed the team
server
and then there's two more steps where it
creates the routing for the ingress
controller and then I switch over and
run a command get the pods to grab that
team server ID tag right there this was
two main history there's actually two
containers running on this team server
pod so the reason that is is because it
envoy proxies in there as well and in
stew I'd injected an envoy proxy into
the team server pod so now you can see
you've got a fully deployed team server
here with with a malleable c2 profile
okay so got that covered and then just a
few more things to discuss so as you
pursue automation there's there's some C
ICD you might want to put a C ICD
pipeline as you build you know you're
different c2 deployments images there's
this thing called drone
it's basically lets you build containers
and lets you deploy stuff into into
kubernetes you can pretty much automate
you see if you have certain
configurations of of C - you want to put
just deploy out really quickly you can
you can use you can use drone you can
put in our cube read script and then all
your containers all your deployments and
then you can just kick them off as you
as you need them and it's just very
popular in DevOps and could really do a
lot of automation and also you can stick
everything in a get so you can put all
your all your stuff and get and then
have drone pick it up from get and then
deploy it into the cluster and then this
is kind of a bill pipeline in drone so
this actually builds a docker image runs
a helmet art yeah deploys everything now
also covered this briefly here you could
actually monitor your situ and Coover
Nesbit's with something called
prometheus prometheus is basically a
time a time series based system so it
focuses on events time-based events
we're actually working on a
configuration for the team server so
we're gonna part we're gonna this is for
so you can see the implants checking in
and you so you can do the real-time
implant monitoring too so if things you
know if the implants is not checking
anymore you can
if people found your that your your
particular redirector you can quickly
just spin up a new one so this this will
basically writing a rock exporter for
for the seat for the team server now if
you have your own situ that you're
writing or or there's an another situ
author they can actually instrument
their code with Prometheus such that
it's automatically supported so any
events they generate inside the inside
the their situ server that Prometheus
can just pick it up and put it put it in
a graph on a dashboard or something like
that so you have a very nice at ollahm
telemetry of your environment and then
gmx is for java it's something we're
trying to see is does does cobalt strike
support JMX we don't know but if it does
it makes it a lot easier yeah so there's
there's a couple ways if you're a like
is if the if that particular situ server
doesn't support prometheus you can use
google em tail which is basically a way
to extract time-series data from a log
and then you can also use grok exporter
another way it elects to pull pull this
time series data into Prometheus and
then it's a I said so we're gonna make
something available in rock exporter to
so you can so you can monitor your team
your beacon check-ins and then you can
this is a this is a dashboard from a
company called cystic but this is the
kind of stuff you can do you can have
one you can watch all your your beacons
and implants and where they're checking
in from how often they checked in
performance and everything so I think
it'll be pretty nice down the road and
then that's that's pretty much it
these are these are some references I
think of worthwhile taking a look at
and this is basically this should be up
over sometime over the weekend or Monday
on Monday and this is gonna have the
basic cube read script it's going to
have the full cobalt strike deployment
the helm helm chart for cobalt strike
and maybe more the Merlin chart as well
if I can get it done but that's coming
it's almost done and then over the next
few weeks we'll try to do some more c2
and yeah that's that's basically it
sorry yeah the question was this the
delete function and the cube read tear
down all the infrastructure and the
answer is yes it does take down the
whole infrastructure in AWS alright
thanks you one more question I mean
right now we're just we've just been
testing