all right let's get going so this is not
a security boundary breaking forest
trust we're gonna hit some Active
Directory stuff trust this is a very
interesting bug that has now since been
patched by Microsoft we will explain the
patch and kind of behavior and
everything that fixed it but we're gonna
walk you through all the components that
are going to be needed to really
understand what this issue was how we
kind of went about finding it and how it
got fixed so my name is Wil Schrager my
handle on Twitter and github is harm joy
I am a Technical Architect at Specter
ups right a lot of the code over the
years helped out veil framework empire
power sploit bloodhound whole bunch of
fun stuff and the one project that I've
written that will be used in these demos
is Rubeus for a lot of c-sharp kerberos
exploitation and my name is lee
christensen I'm also a Technical
Architect over at Specter ops I do a lot
of red teaming I do a bunch of tool
development research a lot of Windows
internals stuff as well and a bunch of
training there as well for the Red Team
class in general I just love shiny
things
anything that's interesting in security
all I'm more than happy to dive into and
research all right
so force and security boundaries
security boundaries is a concept in
Microsoft that's actually pretty pretty
well defined to wear outside of
something that might be a security
feature like UAC to wear fixes or
bypasses won't be serviced security
boundaries are supposed to be serviced
if there's some kind of violation the
classic is going to be like local
privilege escalation so four years in
documentation Microsoft stone docs
this is the water domain some forest
Doc's they explicitly talk about forest
as security boundaries to where all the
objects from one forest if you
compromise everything in forest day
you're not supposed to be able to then
use that access to compromise say
something in another forest so there is
some I think confusion about exactly
even on the Microsoft
about how they were going to treat
forests as actual security boundaries
and if this is going to be treated in
the same way that they would for
host-based local proves escalation and
things like that but we're gonna explore
this kind of in the journey and we're
going to explain exactly why forests
were thought of or function as security
boundaries and how we violated some of
those assumptions so this is kind of the
general scenario is what if a computer
in forest a authenticates to a computer
and force B where there's a two-way
force to forest trust in the terms of it
and the realm of Active Directory and
what if full ticket granting ticket
stege ETS could move across the trust
boundary between forest a and force B
and what if we had a way to easily
extract and reuse these ticket granting
ticket sand the forests we control bonus
points if we can force the
authentication steps instead of just
waiting where we are what if we could
coerce a domain controller or another
system to then authenticate to us on a
capture target this is essentially the
mad recipe that we're going to go over
that has to do with unconstrained
delegation delegation T GTS flowing over
trust boundaries and specific types of
waves of or specific trust and we're
going to wrap everything up with the
printer bug that we talked about orally
talked about last year and we're on
stage but first we have to explain
Kerberos in 60 seconds or maybe a couple
of minutes so that there's no way that
we can go into the detail that we really
want to to explain all of Kerberos you
know it's not that complex really wink
wink
but it's a dense topic well we're just
gonna rush through it really quick we do
highly recommend Sean Metcalfe's post
online it goes into very good detail
about how Kerberos works so that's there
for reference when you log on to a
computer the very first thing that you
do is you send essentially you take a
time spin you time you take a time stamp
and you encrypt it with the with a hash
that's associated with your password
password you send that timestamp to the
domain controller and it validates that
it was encrypted with your password
assuming that the timestamp was
correctly encrypted the domain
controller is going to return to
you what's called a ticket granting
ticket once you have this ticket this is
proof that you've been authenticated it
within the domain this this ticket also
contains something inside of it called
the PAC which is essentially a piece of
information that identifies you so it
has a your unique identifier and the
unique identifier of all the groups that
you're a part of within the domain these
are your SIDS your group SIDS and your
user SID this pack you know you may be
thinking in your head I have it this TGT
was sent back to me from the domain
controller why can't I just modify it
and claim I'm anybody and in the
environment well the reason why you
can't is because it's encrypted
using the krbtgt accounts password hash
which is only present on domain
controllers so you know an attacker with
access to a TGT cannot just you know
decrypt it and start tampering with
these SIDS the user said and the group
says because they're encrypted with that
TGT account which will need the domain
controller has so you have this TGT and
now you want to access another resource
in the environment so what we do is we
issue what's called a service ticket
request we present our TGT to the domain
controller saying hey I would like to
access some service so let's say like a
file share we present the TGT to the
domain controller it validates that it's
correct and if it is correct it returns
to us a service ticket and then we use
that service ticket to authenticate to
whatever service we present it to the
service it also contains a pack that you
know that structure that identifies us
and so we present that to the service
and it looks at who we are the groups
were a part of and depending on you know
if we're authorized or not like do we
have access to this file share it'll
grant or deny us access to that service
there you go you're all experts just as
smart as us yay I wish it was that easy
this is a slightly lied it's not quite
that easy it's there's a few extra steps
especially
we start talking about inter domain or
multiple domains and and forest trusts
in particular so this is another way of
looking at it you know step one here
we're talking about using the you know
that's when we send the timestamp to the
domain controller step two it returns
our TGT step three though is when we're
trying to authenticate to a service in
another domain a different process
occurs here we say hey we want to access
this file share that's in a different
domain and rather than returning a
service ticket immediately our domain
controller returns a referral TGT that
referral TGT is encrypted with an inter
realm trust key so when a trust gets
established that key is generated and
then we receive a TGT that's encrypted
with that and we present that TGT to the
other domains domain controller saying
hey we want to access the service in
your domain and then that domain
controller returns a service ticket for
that file share so a little more
complicated but not too bad
there we go you're experts now right so
that's the Kerberos 101 there's a second
part in Active Directory that's a really
useful or needed thing in a lot of
operations called delegation meaning
when you need to pretend to be another
user impersonate them to a different
service for example the canonical
example is when a you say a web
application and that web application
needs to impersonate or pretend to be
that person to say a back-end database
so this is a common scenario that arises
in enterprises and arises in these
architectures because we've talked to
some people know why is delegation even
enabled Nady just for the same reason
you can do token impersonation on hosts
like this is a needed primitive where
certain services need to be able to
impersonate and pretend to be other
users to a different service ok the way
Microsoft implemented this is three
different flavors
there's unconstrained delegation
traditional constrained delegation and
resource based constrained delegation
unconstrained was their first take edit
it's been in Microsoft Active Directory
since Windows 2000 or a 2000 domain
functional level
shanell constrain was in 2003 and
resource base constrain delegation was
in 2012 all three of these delegation
types have different attacks or not
vulnerabilities but different kind of
operational attacks that are associated
with them
we're not going to cover the constrained
and resource-based constrained though
they are quite interesting we're only
going to hit unconstrained where if you
have a server configured for
unconstrained delegation then when a
user requests a service ticket for it
they have a forwarded version of their
ticket granting ticket that's stuffed
into the request and presented to the
target this means that if an attacker
controls a server with unconstrained
delegation than anyone that
authenticates to it their TGT will be
cached in memory on that unconstrained
server and you can extract it out and
pretend to be that person so this is
dangerous because control of an
unconstrained server along with a couple
other primitives can result in complete
domain or forest compromised
Microsoft knew that this was like
unconstrained delegation it's needed
just on domain controllers by default
within the domain so there's always at
least one system you know in a domain
that has this but we've seen many times
where people had like provisioning
problems or they just didn't realize
like oh all workstations of these
servers all have unconstrained
delegation because there weren't fully
weaponized attack chains until this past
year that actually let you abuse this in
a really really effective way but again
compromised them an unconstrained server
you can extract out the TGT of anyone
that connects to it it's kind of like a
waterhole
you know titan type type of attack and
again we can mention DCs are the only
ones configure by default for this but
there are often miss configurations you
can see in the field for this we've been
in environments where we've seen every
single computer for whatever reason
being granted on constrained delegation
rates so we've been able to use this to
elevate just from a normal workstation
and we talked about this combined with
the printer bug which we'll go over like
we talked about last year we realized
that control of a unconstrained server
can result in a compromise of the entire
domain but then we started researching
this a bit more in Dovan and realize
there's implications for forest raus
well and this is just kind of what it
like looks like from like an ldap
property type level you can really
easily enumerate any systems that have
unconstrained delegation it's just a bit
flag in the user account control
settings for any computer object it's
also very very difficult to flip this
bit like if you have control of your own
object you can't just go in and flip it
and something I'll take over the domain
there's a very special privilege that by
default only domain administrators have
and that privilege is needed SSA enable
delegation is needed to modify any
delegation settings in Active Directory
objects because modification of any
delegation stuff could result in
complete domain compromise let's say
we're on you know this primary machine
is trusted for delegation unconstrained
and say someone who's a da just like
list the file share on that remote
server and their full ticket granting
ticket is going to be ATS for at least a
period of time will be in memory on that
primary system cool alright that's the
second part Kerberos and then delegation
now we're gonna hit trusts so domain
trusts what are they
so trusts all they are is they are a way
for them to link authentication systems
in Active Directory so you may have
several different domains and all the
trust does is it allows you to link
those two domains together
so essentially users from domain a can
now authenticate to resources in domain
B there's various different kinds of
trusts and how this you know how this
how a trust actually works underneath is
when the trust gets created there's this
thing called an inter realm trust key
that's that's created and that's used to
encrypt the Kerberos referral tickets
that are you know that are created so
essentially I'm trying to access a
resource in another domain I'm going to
say hey domain controller I want to
access you know the file share over in
Wills domain and it's gonna send me a
TGT encrypted with that inter realm
trust key and then I'm gonna use that
referral TGT and send it to Wills domain
and he'll return a service to get to me
so that's that's essentially the
referral process that occurs whenever
there's trust this only occurs when it's
going between separate domains when it
comes to trust there's this constant
there's a couple different concepts that
we want to talk about the first is the
direction of the trust and transitivity
so there's the first one that we'll talk
about is a one-way trust so this is just
saying you know I have a domain we'll
has a domain and I say I trust will that
means any users and Will's domain can
you know authenticate into my domain
because I trust him likewise trust can
be bi-directional or two-way that means
you know I trust him and he trusts me
therefore the users in my domain can
authenticate to resources in his domain
and vice versa then there's the idea of
a transitive trust so you know there's
me there's will and then there's another
domain over there
well since if I trust will and will
trust that domain then by transit by
transitivity that domain trusts me
so that's transitivity in addition to
direction and transitivity transitivity
there's different kinds of trusts
so there's intro forest trusts which are
typically like parent-child or cross
link and then there's the inter domain
trust so if you have two different
Active Directory forests and you want to
link them together let's link them
together you'll set up a forest trust
likewise you could also have an external
trust creating their and that the thing
about you know with external trust they
are non transitive so you can't just
immediately access into them so recall
that when we receive a TGT from a domain
controller inside of that TGT is a
structure called the pack the privileged
account or what is it attribute yeah
privileged that should be certificates
pack yeah there we go
what this actually looks like on the
inside is there's a few different fields
that were really interested in so like
the very first one is the user
that's identifies who we are within the
domain it also contains the groups that
were a part of those are the SIDS of
each of the groups and then maybe the
extra says and this is you know if we're
attenti cating to enemy remote domains
this is going to be any you know
potentially in the extra SIDS it's also
used in sid history and so idea of being
here you know this is how we are
identified with in active directory
using Kerberos this identifies us and
our privileges as a user why this is
important and why all these SIDS that we
mentioned here are important is because
when it comes to setting up trusts
there's a protection that Active
Directory has called CID filtering so
whenever you authenticate to another
domain this CID filtering process occurs
essentially when we try not fennec eight
to another domain the other domain looks
at the SIDS inside of our pack and will
potentially remove some of those sits
before granting us access into the
domain and which SIDS get removed
depends on the type of trust that's
created so inside of a domain the SIDS
are filtered differently than if there's
a forest trust so the type of filtering
is gonna change depending on the type of
trust and so a good example of this is
you know let's say I have my own forest
and Will has his own forest if I try and
authenticate into wills forest you know
I could claim that I have SIDS from like
maybe the I Enterprise administrators
group for wills forest but when I try
and authenticate over there
Sid filtering is going to remove the
enterprise admin SID from my group SIDS
or my extra TSA's and that's due to this
Sid filtering protection that's inside
of Active Directory
that being said like you can still
pretend to be any I could pretend to be
any user inside of my current domain I
mean if those users have been granted
access to resources and wills domain you
know yeah I could potentially escalate
privileges but I can't instantly become
an enterprise administrator because that
is SID
is filtered when we crossed that forest
trust so that's why when we're talking
about you know what is the the boundary
the inside of Active Directory the
reason why the forest is the security
boundary is due to this CID filtering
it's gonna remove any of those SIDS when
we go into a you know a different domain
a really good overview of CID filtering
Dirk Young has a really good link down
there at the bottom if you're interested
in what actually looks like like we said
the ultimately CID filtering across Russ
trusts is to stop a compromised you know
trusted forest or domain from
compromising a trusting forest so what
do we mean by that you know we'll may
trust me there may be a trust between us
but if I'm compromised if my domain is
compromised Sid filtering should the key
word is should there should prevent me
from immediately compromising his domain
and that's why again that's why it's the
boundary inside of Active Directory
alright so for a long time
Microsoft has explicitly stated and told
anybody that the domain itself is not a
security boundary the reason it's not a
security boundary is because of how Sid
filtering is applied for domains within
the same forest this is a screenshot of
some of the SID filtering rules that we
had linked and there is a specific one
called for specific where SIDS are never
allowed in a pact that originated from
outside of the forest but they are
honored within the same forest so if you
have domain a B and C within the same
forest then the enterprise admin SID is
allowed to cross those boundaries as
long as the domains are in the same
forest so this seems like a weird nitty
gritty subtle type thing but the reason
that this is awesome
is a couple years ago Shawn Metcalfe and
Delpy realized the implications of these
types of things which are cover in a
second but again city of enterprise
admins not filtered out by default for
inter um tickets at both domains are in
the same forest so it
you can somehow set either your Sid
history which is a property on Active
Directory users that allowed for like
different migrations and stuff but if
you can set the sid history the extra
SIDS in a ticket to somehow be
enterprise admins in your in a child
domain you can instantly compromise the
forest route and everything in the same
forest and this is exactly what Delpy
and sean figured out and weaponized so
for a long time people knew this is a
vulnerability because if you could
somehow modify that property on an
object and child domain you could have
complete forest compromised but there
wasn't weaponization for it really
because it's very very difficult to
modify the sid history on any active
user or group in an Active Directory
domain database until Delpy realized and
Sean like oh if you're creating golden
tickets why don't we just add this extra
Sid and then we can hop up immediately
we have a obligatory like don't be
jumping in right so when I first learned
about this attack it kind of blew my
mind I've been doing a lot of trust
stuff this happened several years ago
and it allows us to where if you
compromised domain administrator
credentials for any child domain in the
forest for five minutes you can then
compromise everything in the entire
forest but sin filtering for sensitive
groups does protect acrost
forest trust boundaries this is why
forests were established as a security
boundary at least as far as we can tell
obviously you know we're not from
Microsoft so but there's a couple more
site notes so now that's most kind of
some of the technical backgrounds
there's a couple of side notes we
noticed in documentation that let us
start putting this cool attack together
the first one is that when you're
authenticating from forest a to 4sb
you always receive a new identifier
called authenticated users in your new
token when you're authenticating against
the other forest so if Lee's and his
forest and authenticates and gets a
referral to mine he's gonna
automatically get the authenticated
users SID for my forest put into his
referral this is important or it comes
into play later on so any user in either
trust can perform any action that domain
authenticated users can
for example query an LDAP or doom
whatever else and also side note on
delegation and Trust this is until
recently until a couple months ago is
that when full delegation is enabled the
server can use delegated T GTS to
connect as any user to any server
including those across a one-way trust
so what this means is that delegated
ticket granting ticket could flow across
trust boundaries so like why should you
give a crap about all this stuff like
what is this matter so delegated TG T's
can be used across forest trust
boundaries and a compromise
unconstrained delegation server means
that an attacker can extract TG T's of
users who authenticate to that machine
even if they connect from another forest
up until a few months ago and what if we
could coerce particular accounts and one
for us to authenticate to an
unconstrained server that we control I
wonder if this would be possible yes we
can so that's where the printer bug
comes into play so you know our problem
here is we want to be able to coerce you
know any you know a privileged account
to authenticate to an unconstrained
server and so the the printer bug is a
nice little thing that I discovered it's
a well it abuses an old printer protocol
the MS are PRN protocol and what it does
is inside of that RPC protocol there's a
couple different methods that I saw our
PC Remote find first printer changed
notification I mean doesn't that sound
just like such a great method but
essentially what I found when looking
through the protocol spec is that when
invoked when you use this method what
happens is you know I say I call this
method against wills computer and upon
doing that his machine immediately
connects back to me and that's this is
because it's essentially what what this
method is supposed to do is supposed to
be used for printers to allow to notify
me of when like things happen what
that printer so like like saying wills I
want wills printer to notify me whenever
a new print job occurs then it would
connect back to me and notify me but you
know you know that's the legitimate use
case we can of course use that to coerce
authentication that's what we're
interested in as an attacker so it's
worth noting that this is just one way
there we already know that there are
other ways to do this I don't think this
is the only way so like we said MSRP RN
just a little few details about it it
uses the SMB RPC protocols using named
pipes there's some of the details around
around it but the important thing here
is that we can invoke that method as an
authenticated user so remember
authenticated users you know when you
authenticate over a trust boundary you
are granted the authenticated users SID
so you know I we can query we can use
this method against machines in other
forest forest and course those machines
to authenticate anywhere we want also
want to give a shout-out to e latch
Sameera key also independently
discovered this a little bit after me as
as far as I know this bug still works it
doesn't work less than eight because it
was enabled you know as far as I can
tell on Windows 8 and above it works
just fine
we Ted we used it on an op just a couple
weeks ago to compromise a forest and
still worked on a twenty sixteen server
so should still work don't know about
2019 yet so this is so in order to
exploit this I created a tool called a
spool sample the spooler come on
but anyways spool sample is a it's got
an example of it running here so on that
first line you can see that we're on a
machine called wind 10 I'm running as a
marketer which is you know just a low
privileged account in the network and
I'm saying I'm running spool sample
against domain controller the lab DC and
I'm saying please authenticate back to
my Windows 10 machine and so I go ahead
and execute it
and then I use seatbelt to just list the
logon events and as you can see on the
Windows 10 machine we can see that the
domain controller did indeed try and
authenticate back to us and we can see
you know there that it's using Kerberos
when it did that authentication we could
also force it to use ntlm but in this
case we're just gonna use Kerberos so
that's very cool that's an extremely
powerful primitive especially in this
scenario all right we're gonna put all
the pieces together so in this scenario
say an attacker completely compromises
force B so this is also going to include
by like guarantee to have the compromise
of at least one server with on
constrained delegation which would be
the domain controller for force B let's
say force B shares a two-way forest
trust before a stay so theoretically
based on this being a boundary
compromise a force B should not be able
to facilitate compromise of any
resources in forest a we're going to use
in this demo we're going to use a Rubeus
for TGT monitoring and extractions pull
sample for the coerced authentication
and then me me cats with DC sync it's
actually not there's only a few few
steps there's not actually too many
moving parts so okay where you have our
victim force which is a and we've
compromised everything in force B first
as a domain attacker the via that the
print spooler stuff the MSRP RN i'm
going to tell the domain controller in
forest a please authenticate to me on
domain controller be domain controller a
with its machine account will
authenticate to be this is these two
parts or what compromises the printer
bug and it sends its ticket granting
ticket because of unconstrained
delegation it'll send a completely
forwarded ticket granting ticket over
the forest trust boundary then all the
attacker does is extract that ticket
granting ticket of DC a domain
controller they can resubmit it to the
local security authority on their box
and now their RDC
they can just DC sync any account they
want in forestay because now they are it
is if they are DCA's rtca the domain
controller
worth noting here that nowhere DC said
filtering take place so that's the
entire attack kind of laid out and we're
gonna show a demo video of this so again
AAA has a two way trust would be we're
just proving it and I promise you no
we're not lying
we didn't fake out the demo we're on the
domain controller we control we are
gonna start monitoring for new ticket
granting ticket scumming in this will
just actually monitor the 464 logon
events then we're gonna trigger the
printer bug against DCA saying please
connect to DC be you get DCA's take your
granny ticket let's extract it out as a
base64 blob we're gonna take this ticket
out just remove the newline so we then
we can resubmit it
you could automate this even more I
suppose if you'd like and just as an FYI
we will post the slides for this and
tweet it out right after the the talk is
over so we get that base64 of DCA's
ticket granting ticket we can verify
that this is real by parsing the ticket
structures with Rubeus and then
verifying the information within it so
okay this is for DC a dollar sign for
the machine account of the domain
controller we're gonna submit that
ticket granting ticket to LSA now it is
as if we are DC $1 the Machine account
then all we have to do left is DC sync
any account we want say the krbtgt of
that trusting forest dope that was the
entire attack this is actually the demo
video for proof of concept that we sent
in to Microsoft when we filed this so
the TLDR of this is if you compromise
any server with on constrained
delegation domain controller otherwise
you can use that access with the printer
bug to compromise the current domain all
domains in your current forest and until
recently all domains in any foreign
forest that there's a two way for us
trust with so some people didn't really
think that this was a big deal some of
the public reaction we posted this was
still a security boundary as long as
there's not a two-way trust which
okay I guess I kind of disagree our step
one have force root domain admin
credential step to have things grossly
misconfigure because I guess having a
trust is a Christmas configuration or I
don't think I've heard anyone claim that
boundary still exists when a two-way
trust is in place to which we kind of
respond with the way people come were
thinking about this or like why call to
force a security boundary if like why
even have it as a security boundary
unless it's in the context of trust with
other domains so we kind of disagree
with some of this but we understand why
it's a complex issue with a lot of
subtlety so we understand why you know
people kind of eat it this way yep and
so like the big thing here is you know
in an active directory's default
configuration this you know this is it
is vulnerable so you can if one forest
trust another forest then the compromise
of one is going to result in the
compromise of the second forest so the
the issue here is like you have this
dependency now on the security of this
you know untrusted forest that you
you're just assuming is okay or is
isolated off but that is no longer the
case you cannot assume I can't assume
that wills for us is you know completely
trustworthy now so even if you know I
had perfect security I did everything
right just by virtue of having a trust
between us if wills force is compromised
and I am also compromised or it could be
compromised so the reason that we think
this matters or is impactful is
especially with larger corporations that
you say acquisitions where they bring in
new Active Directory resources and then
in order for things to intercommunicate
we'll just hook it up with the trust and
based on the guidance from Microsoft for
years okay we're doing this right we're
doing a forest trust because that's
gonna that's a security boundary so
we're not gonna be able to be
compromised and then if a single server
single unconstraint server is
compromised and that new domain they
hooked up the entire thing comes
crashing down we've seen this more than
once in actual environments so we knew
from practical you know experience that
organizations were doing this so we
reported this last fall to nsrc um
initially the engineering teams got back
to us and they they claimed it was not
an issue we fight and it was by design
this is how it was designed and you know
we responded saying no we really do
think this is an issue like you should
reconsider sure enough they they did not
patch it they said maybe we'll think
about doing it in the future and a V
next patch but you know no promises
so we went ahead and we you know decided
to disclose to the public so we
published this along with some really
great defensive guidance and sure enough
the they decided it was a mistake at
that point so soon after that an
advisory was released talking about the
issue that was at play here
um and months later in March a patch was
finally released so while we do like we
didn't agree with their initial
assessment we do applaud Microsoft for
you know actually it meeting their error
and
doing it and they ended up coming up
with a really good patch which we're
gonna talk about but to their credit
they did admit it and they owned up to
their that the mistake and so in March
of this year that's where CVE twenty
nine twenty nineteen oh six eight three
came I'm just talking about how there's
an elevation of privilege between Active
Directory forests so some of the details
and what they actually did and why we
think this is such a cool example of
like really killing the entire
fundamental issue instead of just doing
like a little band-aid over it so after
they officially recognized it they
rolled a patched out over the next are
the over several months this year
and they did it in multiple steps so but
in general what it does now is it
disables TGT delegation across forest
trust boundaries by default and the cool
way they did it is there is an opt-in
period where if you wanted to still
allow this behavior in your environment
you're able to flip a bit and still have
this existing type functionality and
then early a few months after that they
completely disabled and like killed
stuff by defaults where unless you opted
in to preserve this behavior and all
modern patch domains now this this thing
is completely killed so they Microsoft
very rarely breaks backwards
compatibility by default usually the
option would be we're gonna give you
something in this scenario that will let
you disable this behavior they very
rarely go back in and then change the
existing established architectural
behavior of a system in a way that
breaks backwards compatibility so
there's a very big deal that this
happened and as of July they add a new
safe configuration from constrained
servers delegations across trusts so how
did this patch actually actually work
under the hood how to roll out so
they're in modern 2012 domains there was
an option that you could disable TGT
delegation across trusts it was an
opt-in it was an optional thing that you
had to set it was not turned on by
default so in March of this year they
back ported that functionality to Server
2008 of a step 1
then in May they introduced a new trust
flag so trusts are actually represented
as something called trusted domain
objects
in Active Directory so in Li's domain if
he trusts my domain there's going to be
an object of wills domain represented as
a trusted domain object and Lee's doing
so everything is an object in AD it all
has properties this is how it knows like
should I do this filtering or not all
these different settings so they
introduced a new flag that was cross
organisation enabled TGT delegation
this was the opt-in period where if you
still wanted to preserve this behavior
you could flip this they also for any
new trust they flipped the old flag on
by default so cross organization no TGT
delegation so new they let you opt in
and then they disabled the behavior by
default and how it currently was then
the big step is in july 2019
they started enforcement of the new
trust flag and they're completely
ignoring the old opt-in one so if you
did not in that short period of time
flip this existing flag to preserve the
functionality now on patch domains this
just does not work anymore delegated TG
T's will not flow between forest rust so
forests are now again a security
boundary so the operational guidance
though from offensive or defensive
standpoint is if this one particular
flag is set the issue will be mitigated
if that cross organization no delegation
is set the issue
completely is mitigated if all DCs are
running Server 2012 or if you have 2008
DCs if they're patched as of March 2019
they got that update and you have this
flag set if you have the cross
organisation enable te GT flag set then
the whole domain set up is still
vulnerable but someone had to actively
opt in to preserve this risky behavior
in this risky setup and if neither flag
is set which is going to be the most
common then you're vulnerable
if the may 20 19 update is not applied
to every domain controller which is kind
of the trickier part so once this kind
of flipped on we started seeing it
slowly rolling out to different domain
controllers or different environments I
think most environments are going to be
protected now as long as people are
updating their domain controllers
they're good there is a technical
reference in some of the github issues
for vinson the twos pin Castle project
that we have a link down there or
someone actually reversed the patch and
figured out
flags I'm figured out exactly what was
happening so I know we went a bit quick
but that's that's the talk so thank you
guys for coming out
we always love talking to Derby con and
if there's any particular questions we
can take them or if you want to come up
and chat with us after definitely can we
have a bunch of references and stuff and
again we will upload this slide deck to
fly chair and then tweet out the link
here and within the next hour so so
thank you guys
[Applause]
you