oh yeah we have audio cool welcome to
the last session all day this is called
fishing past male protection controls
using aster information protection so we
will try to be short because we know you
want a party afterwards so so do we okay
cool so my name is Alberto I work as a
red teamer for trusted SEC for doing
that for the last year yeah I blog I
tweet I hacked not necessarily in that
order
yeah so that's my twitter handle and
that's my that's my blog right there
alright my name is Hans Lakhan
that's my bio which is a lot thicker
than what our head but I do basically
the same stuff just not as well as he
does
alright so what do we want to talk about
after information protection in
particular so the reason is because we
had a really tough engagement where we
kind of had trouble getting mails sent
into the organization so I started to to
try to create macros that sent data back
to me so I can like figure out what sort
of sandbox environment that we were
having and in that process I started to
think there should be a way to like do
something that just slipped past
everything so I ended up finding that I
could use a sir information protection
to encrypt files and send it away and
bypass every sandbox every mitigation
they had and it ended up in the inbox to
the user that's the story behind it
we've also written a blog post about it
so if you want to have more details
afterwards there's a blog post at
trusted sitcom so we will quickly cover
what ask your information protection is
go over some of the licensing parts also
the features and then we're going to
cover a little bit about detections and
in the end of course exploits how to use
this to our advantage as attackers
so what is AIP
it's basically a way to label content
and make make things happen
automatically so meaning that if you
label thing confidential you can get as
information protection to automatically
encrypt the files or tag them in a
special way and the mechanisms behind is
called as your rights management service
or as your RMS
back in the days when we didn't have
clouds we had something called Active
Directory RMS that's the same thing just
on pram and the problem with the
unprimed was that in order for me to
share RMS content with another
organization I had to basically set the
rate with them in order to them to
receive the content and decrypt it and
stuff so it was it was really difficult
to like implement this in a good way
back in the days so now we have the
cloud so everything is cloud-based and
it can basically be consumed by everyone
and it's it's free for everyone to
consume or a mess protected content
that's the part of the strategy from
Microsoft so if you send something to an
inducer if the organization or the
receiver has an azure ad account and
most organizations do these days so they
single sign-on and they open the
document it gets a licensing or a
decryption key from from the cloud it
decrypts it and you can open it and it
it doesn't trigger any additional
pop-ups or whatever if he doesn't have
an aster 80 account they are actually
asked to create one and you get a link
you click and you open its su de you
have to create an account in order to
access this content and the last is if
the receiver is on a gmail or a hotmail
or some specific services they need to
go to a special link there's a
cooperation there between Microsoft and
the others to consume RMS content if you
want to know more about how the user
experience this there's there's a link
at the bottom where it shows the
different
types of setups so if you have a nicer
ad account that looks like this if you
if you don't have an accurate account
this is what it what the experience is
like and so on and so forth yes so here
are the different windows you will
encounter when playing with a
information protection it's basically a
client to install then you will get this
little lock pad here where you can
protect the content in any way you want
it could be predefined or it could be
custom and that's mostly what we use we
use custom and here is the labels that I
was talking about that's how you label
content so you can label content either
private or confidential or highly
confidential and it can have
automatically actions based on those
labels but the clue with extra
information protection is of course to
protect content no matter where it is
because like traditionally when we had a
file servers we still do we protect
files by setting ACLs on folders so that
so people doesn't get into the folder
for instance we have an HR folder where
only the group HR is allowed to to get
access to but the problem is when
someone from HR takes that file and
sends it away on the email or tech puts
it on a USB stick
everyone can open it because the D
rights doesn't go with the file so
that's the problem that as your
information protection is solving like
no matter where you open the file it the
protection you set will always be with
that file so that's pretty awesome yeah
so here's a screenshot of the same file
with and without encryption so here's
the size for the first partners you see
the the empty file is like 11k B when
you protect it it increases in size of
course because it embeds a lot of
information and it equips the files so
if you know if you open the files in
7-zip sorry 7-zip you can see that the
content changes so if you open this
information here you won't see anything
it's just random mess basically in an
encrypted file you can still see
content like with a notepad or whatever
so it's really it's a beautiful thing in
terms of the file types that are
supported it's basically all office
files XLS xlsx and so on
it also has support for other extensions
such as PDF txt and the list is yeah you
can see it here
the problem with the other extensions is
that it it changes the name of the file
so if the file is called file dot txt
when you encrypt it with a information
protection
it changes the extension to P txt and
you can only open it using the ass your
information protection client viewer so
that's useless for us as attackers
unless they have the client and you're
not sure so that's yeah you have to be
sure of that at least
PDF is an exception because when you
send a striated PDF document it will
actually show like - like like it looks
like a phishing page where you need to
download an IMSI file in order to enable
a plugin so that's something we we want
to further investigate later on
hopefully all right in terms of
Licensing and costs there are basically
three levels you have the standard you
get bit uh normal office 365 license I'm
not a licensed expert but basically this
is what you get if you have the normal
III license with office 365 you get all
the way up to document tracking and
relocation you don't get those last
features unless you have premium 1 or
premium 2 so if you want tracking you
need the premium editions
there are some details on their blog
it's it's really good document basically
every feature what sort of level you
need a license in order to get the
different features in terms of costs a
normal year 3e license at least when I
checked it was 20 bucks to user and if
you want to premium one it's an
additional six dollars per user
if you want to premium - it's an
additional nine dollars so yeah and as I
said at the bottom here
ask your licensing advisor because I'm
not a licensing adviser i hack stuff
right so features are basically tracking
that's really cool when you send a fish
and you can actually see if someone
tried to open the document we also got a
demo of that in the end so I can see if
the email itself was opened or viewed I
can also see when a user authenticates
and tries to open the payload itself I
can see if it was a success or if it
failed so if someone are from the IRA
response team is trying to reverse it I
can see that they are denied access for
instance that's that's pretty useful and
also of course the main feature that we
use it for is for encryption of payloads
and emails right the girl handed over to
hunts detection I can sorry yeah so in
terms of detection there's a if you
unzip the file there's actually a clue
inside one of the files that will tell
you the tenant ID so that's pretty
useful in terms of when you're
investigating if you get such a document
and you need to further to response on
it you can at least find the the tenant
ID and that's useful yeah in terms of
blocking it or getting an alert you can
in exchange you can create something
called a transport rule and that's
basically all I have found that you can
use so basically there's this option
here
called only it's called content can't be
inspected so you can create an alert if
exchange cannot inspect the content and
that's typical when you have Astra
information protected documents because
it's encrypted so you can get it to
trigger an alert or you can get it to
trigger an action like blocking it or
quarentine it or whatever so that's the
best advice I have at least so yeah cool
one of the things that we didn't mention
too much in here is document revocation
so if you're doing a phishing campaign
and you know it's burned or whatever you
just know that it is you can literally
revoke the documents so that way the no
one else can open it even the legitimate
user who was initially authorized can
open it anymore which is great like say
you land it once you don't need to have
them click it again just revoke it
anyway so we have a few demos here of
what this looks like in action ok so
here we are
nope that's the wrong one I can hold
this for you all day long
alright so here we are have a regular
document in this situation here we've
are logged in to office on a workstation
with an account that has the premium 2
version of AIP and we also and we also
have the client as well the client is
needed in order to install our right
I'll run this action to encrypt the
document so it adds in a function when
you right-click to classify and protect
as oddvar mentioned on the top there you
can set the classification manually if
you want in this case we're not going to
use it but we are going to do is go
protect with custom permissions
in the permissions that we have here our
view reviewer co-author or are you sorry
view edit view only and so forth in our
case we only want them to view the
content we don't want them to do
anything else beyond that and you can
specify the email address that you want
to send to in this case here we just set
up a domain in 365 a IP demo but again
as Ivar mentioned this can be a Gmail
this can be at whatever domain that you
want in this case it's going to be an
office customer attendant last thing
know know is that you can also set the
expiration so that way even if you
yourself forget to revoke the document
you can have it automatically fail to
open at a certain date and that's it so
that's how you encrypt it and this here
is how you would send a document in that
situation so now the documents been
encrypted we're sending it to a guy
named receiver with the convincing open
me you attach the file just fine no
issues whatsoever all right so we have
attached our totally safe doc now one
thing we wanted to point out here is we
have the ability to do not forward which
is great because when you send this fish
to a the target we don't want them
forwarding on to the team that would be
actually doing instant response this
will disable on their client to their
ability to Ford this attached email so
cool
all right so this error message here
it's just talking about the permissions
relate to it's like here's a warning for
it so are you okay you want to do this
yeah we are
and sure enough it goes ahead and sends
it all right so now we have in this demo
here a situation where the document has
been moved from the recipients email
maybe be a USB stick or network share to
the incident response team that doesn't
have the legitimate credentials to open
it what does it look like for them so
they'll open the doc just by
double-clicking on it
Microsoft goes and checks or a result
realizes that it's protected attempts to
communicate with a server saying hey who
has rights to this ass oddvar to enter
his credentials now he's not the
recipient so it's going to fail it's
checking checking and boom you're not
authorized to access this document so
this is what any ir person would receive
when they tried investigating this
document interacting with it normally if
they try to run it through like vipre
monkey or any of those other tools
they're not going to get anything either
because it's again it's encrypted
yep then maybe the legitimate user a
recipient to view it alright so this is
the last one I want to show you guys
here if you do open it legitimately it
just opens like editor doc if they're
logged in if they're not logged in it'll
pump them to log him just like he did
before and then just continue on
forwarded and we have ten minutes left
so this will be quick all right so the
last thing here I want to show you is
that we have two documents and a P demo
message box and a P demo message back
protected these are the exact same
document however one is protected the
other one is not so they had the same
malware or the same VBA in there and
what I wanted to show you guys is what
ends up
happening oh no nope sorry last one
sorry first one the tracking feature
sorry so we have when you right click
and view protect this is the same window
that you saw before with the settings
and and so forth we also have the
ability to view the file permissions
that you currently have set and you can
only do this because you're the owner of
the file other people would not be able
to see this can we see that the owner is
user sender and what rights they have
okay a really awesome all right so but
here's what happens when you actually
true the tracking so we have the
document here it brings it to the
website and you actually see all the
documents owned by this user so I'm
logged in as the sender right now as a
viewer or recipient you do not have
access to this portal only the document
creator has this you can see how many
times it's been views how many times
access has been denied and how long has
it been since the last activity on that
document and so cool
all right so we can see the people who
have attempted to authenticate to this
document and the actual access that's
happened so we can see that oddvar and
his different mailing addresses fail to
open the document and the last one where
it was successful so not only do you get
to see who did it and who opened it and
who failed open it but when it happened
you know you have a new target it also
has a timeline built-in if any of you
guys use Go Fish I mean this is great
it's like how many people have clicked
it over time you even have a map of
where they tried to log in to access it
so we can see oddvar in Norway attempted
to access this document and you also
have the ability to get notified when
people attempt to open the document with
if they were successful open the
document if they failed and open the
document or just not get a notified at
all so you can get notified when someone
actually opens your finish alright so
this last video here what we did is we
took the same document just duplicated
it called one protected one not
protected and what we're gonna do is
we're up load both into virustotal I
want to show you the results just based
up for that litmus test of what you can
expect when doing this so we're going to
go ahead and classify protect I feel
like we're in Norway oh yeah
then we'll be drunk yeah it's good all
right so we protected a document yeah
I'm gonna go ahead and upload it by
trying to drag and drop fails because
they don't know html5 all right so this
is a normal one that will get flagged a
ton and this tab here the second tab is
our protected one so it's going to go
ahead and chew through it on our
malicious one
sure enough it's going to light up I
think we ended up with 31 detections and
this is your basic message box that you
need to see from Metasploit whereas the
protected one nothing there zero
detection x' just fine so that's it
that's our demonstration
if you guys have any questions oh sorry
one last thing we wasn't as I mentioned
competitors so Google has a similar
function they have the ability to send
confidential information it does not
encrypt attachments but it does keep it
so only authorized people can open it
and can't be forwarded it doesn't have a
cool dashboard okay sure yep oh and so
when you do receive it in email what
ends up happening is it's a stupid dude
your email do want to open it yes you
click view and they have the ability to
what ends up happening is that when you
click the link a new window opens up in
the browser and then it proxies the link
that you actually are using as your
phishing campaign so the initial email
doesn't have it the link once you are
authorized you have to kind of go
through step by steps it does have the
ability to go the other direction in the
sense that Gmail can be sent consent to
an op 365 user and it signs in to via
OAuth so you don't have to you know be a
little easier to open a protected
document from Gmail alright that's the
last one and now we have questions okay
is it smart enough to know if I remove
the email from a user's mailbox that
like you said it disables like you can't
forward it so if one of my users
forwarded it to me said hey this looks
wonky and I go in and remove the email
which pulls it out of their mailbox puts
it into a dump mailbox it's still to the
user
would would the security team be able to
open it hold your response so you have
to authenticate as that user in order to
open it at all that's the whole point
so you have to login to the best an
actual user in order to open it that's
the beauty of it because that's how it
works
unauthorized people to open it so I saw
on the on the outlet client you could
click don't forward is there a way to do
this via PowerShell because this makes
sense for like a Red Team engagement
when we're sending just targeted attacks
but if we're sending it to like 50
people sending 50 emails is great
drinking yeah I mean you have you can
initiate
I like calm object for PowerShell that's
a process and you can like create me
emails and put on whatever you want so
yeah you can for sure do that with
PowerShell so you guys showed that all
office Doc's won't get renamed or
anything like that is there any
notification to the users that they've
received an AIP
encrypted attachment other than the
authentication box that pops up so what
you're asking is do you get an alert
that's an admin or oh yes so okay there
are two things that give it away so if
you protect an email there's a padlock
in the inbox as when we send it in fish
it's it makes it more look more legit I
think because it's in the inbox subject
field we don't have a picture of that
sorry so that's the thing that gives it
away and also when you open it it it
starts the pop-up box that sets
configure RMS so that kind of gives it
away and also you cannot preview it in
Outlook so if you if you single click
and try to preview it able say it's
blocked because you need to open it in
order to decrypt it's basically a nice
presentation questions just clarify what
was the content label that that is the
attribute for secure encryption and
that's transmission and storage or one
or the other
here yeah yes yes right there yes so you
want to know if I can't remember the
defaults but I think I think if you use
confidential I think it's better higher
I think it's encrypted both the content
and also in transit if I'm not mistaken
but I'm not an % sure so you have to
look it up but it's it's it's a guide on
Microsoft where you can look it up so it
shouldn't be hard to find so it's great
is once you get the licensing for it you
can create your own and you can create
whatever rules you want to do based off
of that so this is all the stuff that's
baked in but if but if you want to go
overboard you can yeah in addition to
that if you have a file server and you
have premium one or two you can also
automate the labeling and protection on
file servers as well so if someone tries
to steal document it automatically is
protected when someone tries to grab it
know from the file server you establish
an extension on the file server I knew
you were able to protect it from from
within the file server since the
attacker has to have an Outlook account
or Microsoft account how would a threat
hunting team basically report that to
Microsoft and shut them down so how do
you okay I'm not sure you have to let's
say you have to in order to you have to
block it basically that's I'm not sure
how to I would block the count
interesting I'm not sure how would you
respond yeah I mean you can go into the
document and see the tenant ID but I
don't know if you have to decrypt it in
order to see that in the first place and
see the time ID so maybe you could
report it through like an abuse but
yeah I mean it's a phishing email yeah
yeah let them deal they love it
good question up how whoa sorry how
difficult is it to rotate a IP for
different campaigns for different
domains that you're using
oh so that's you have two answers so I
think from an object
perspective I think I would create a new
tenant each time yes but it's a lot of
work but still the tenant ID is in the
emails so if someone snacks that and
reports it it could get blocked if you
want to rotate I think you can bring
your own key so you can like wrote that
the key at least other than that it's
basically just domains that you use or
do you have anything yeah nobody said as
well but from if you've done any
licensing assignment in Xero when you
create a user you can create different
licenses that apply to that user so what
we've done is we'll get a license for
like maybe four or five and then we'll
just unassigned to that user and
reassigned to a new user and so forth
and just reapply the license or the
subscription when needed so you don't
need to get 20 or 40 or 50 user license
just get a small set and just remove one
you need does that change a tenant ID
have you tried to monkey with the tenant
ID or any thing in the file or I'm
assuming it probably would break it that
does a good good thing to investigate
but I think if you manipulate too much
in the file you will invalidate the
signature somehow but that could
possibly be a thing you could do I'll
try I haven't looked at it but that's a
good suggestion Thanks
okay we'll wrap it up if there's any
more questions just grab us Thanks
[Applause]