so we're gonna get started Oh derbycon
tell me this isn't the best conference
in the world yeah by the I the absolute
privilege of giving my very first
InfoSec talk at Derby con 4 and it is my
absolute pleasure to be here before in
my own review before you but you all are
here for a naked look at my methodology
so Who am I and why do you care just
really briefly my name is Jason lang I
am a proud trust asset consultant I get
to do fun things like like red teaming
and all kinds of function in against my
clients networks it's all authorized of
course they they sign the statement of
work but you find me on Twitter my
hobbies absolutely nothing to do with
information security because I got
unplug just like everyone else so let's
talk about what this talk is about what
this talk is not about first of all I
want to give you an unrestricted look at
one red teamers consultants methodology
again I'm a consultant this is important
understand and the reason why I'm
putting this out there is because red
teaming in the consultant world
differs from red teaming in the internal
world and so if you're an internal red
teamer I need you to understand that
your mileage is gonna vary a little bit
on this okay you know I'm gonna do my
best to make it as applicable as I can
however understand that you're getting
this from the perspective of somebody
who has to operate on say and from a red
team your perspective save six to a
tweet okay as opposed to an internal red
teamer your operations can go a lot
longer alright unfortunately I don't
have that luxury to be fantastic but it
is what it is okay to foster learning by
example and failure as well as to drop
some some handy stuff these stuff that I
think is handy but it's important to
understand the perspective that this
talk is coming from it I'm just gonna
give you just a little bit of high-level
context in terms of red teaming in terms
of target maturity when I say rate team
I'm not talking about a pen test
mouthing about a vulnerability
assessment I'm talking generally right
about here okay so when we talk about a
red team I am making a few assumptions
about my my target a few assumptions
about my client and some of those
assumptions might be for example that
you already have centralized logging if
you don't have a a sim and you're just
kind of you know oh yeah we want a
routine because
Max's Red Team and it's all sexy now
hold on let's actually talk about what
you have going what you don't have going
in your network and then we'll see if
your if you're in the right position for
red team and the reason why we do that
is because we don't want you to waste
your money
hybrid teams can be costly all right in
fact they are costly Who am I kidding so
I I do not want you to be wasting your
money unnecessarily if you're not ready
for that kind of engagement because the
worst feeling for me as a consultant is
to go into your network there's all
kinds of vulnerabilities we get da in
the first day and it's six week
engagement we're just like that's not
the best use of your time or your money
okay so we're making certain assumptions
here but in terms of the difference
between penetration testing red team and
things like that there is a key
difference and the key difference is the
ability to slow down and I need to state
that a little more emphatically because
this was a difficult lesson for me to
learn I came from the pen testing world
I I mean first of all how many red
teamers here it's yours but there's like
20% of you how many of you blue teamers
get out okay so I I came from a
penetration testing role all right where
a pen test was a week long you could
send three phishing campaigns in that
week and still get to Maine mmm by the
end of the week and those days are long
long gone all right so now in a Red Team
now it's like command paralysis where
I'm afraid to type anything because I'm
gonna get caught
all right so the the point of this of
this talk is to well give you some
perspectives and some insights and
stories about failure and some successes
some things that you can use in your
network but why why this talk for those
of you to raise your hand and you're
like yeah I'm already a red team or you
know why am I here why why you care uh
let me put you this way some of the the
best talks that I attend and the most
valuable talks to me are the ones where
I go and and I'm not I'm not expecting
to have you know that just his grand
unveiling of knowledge what I'm
expecting is to pick up about 10 to 20
percent new knowledge all right if
you're a red team and you've been doing
this for a while chances are the vast
majority of what you're gonna see in
this deck you already know okay there's
a guy I was talking to OD Lee he was
hoping this talk was about assembly I'm
sorry man it's not okay but that's like
I don't know next door or something but
if that is is where you're at I want to
give you a little bit of hope because
the the point of this talk is
to maybe steer you in a slightly
different direct in slightly different
direction or maybe change how you think
just a little bit about red teaming and
give you an additional 5% an additional
10% on top of your methodology that
might make you a better red teamer
that's the whole focus of this okay all
right so what's the agenda and it was
about well I'm gonna break this down
very much like I would break down a
standard red team engagement we're going
to talk about what happens before the
engagement the external portion the
internal portion the social engineering
and then finally the reporting looks a
lot like a pen test but I'm gonna break
it down from a red teaming standpoint by
the way these are not my animations just
FYI
all right so every section that we're
gonna talk about I'm going to include
core principles whether it's the pre
engagement whether it's the reporting
I'm going to give you red team core
principles this is not just a tools talk
okay and one of the worst things I could
do for you is just to drop a bunch of
tools and then turn you loose that
doesn't help anyone it doesn't help your
clients alright so from from the
standpoint of methodology one of the
best things that I can do is give you
sound principles or at least what I
think are my sound principles you might
look at me and be like you're all wrong
and that's fine you're entitled your
opinion and I have the microphone so
number one adversary simulation not
necessarily emulation what's the
difference when I go into a target
Network I'm simulating an adversary
which means generally speaking I can
choose the path adversary emulation
means I'm emulating a PT X X okay and
that's generally not in at least not in
my opinion the best value because if I
can simulate an adversary I can tailor
the attacks based on the vertical I can
tailor the attacks based on the client I
can tailor the attacks based on their
maturity I can do those things instead
of being kind of locked in to this box
of a specific adversary number two the
goal is data trophy systems not domain
admin it if the goal is domain admin it
shouldn't be and if I ever go for domain
admin on a red team it is only as a
stepping stone to get where I need to be
all right one of the things I always
asked her in the kickoff is give me a
system give me an application give me
some piece of data that means something
to you and would put you in the news if
it walked out the door and that changes
things nobody ever says domain admin to
that ever okay so that that is the goal
emphasizing stealth over speed there are
certain tools that I do not use on
team any longer it's not their bad tools
and I do call out certain tools in this
talk it's not they're bad it's just that
for the purpose of a red team it's a
it's it's not the best fit maybe they're
a little too fast maybe they're a little
too well-known maybe there's too many
signatures etc speed is not the emphasis
stealth usually is the emphasis all
right active defense I do encourage it
so for example if I'm gonna send a fish
I want to see the actual response of my
client all right and I will encourage it
to a point in other words if there's
like all right you're coming from trust
sex IPS we're gonna block everything and
if they ask me for a status update I'm
like all right I I got in my connection
is coming from here and they just shut
everything down okay hold on wait we do
need to suspend realism to a certain
degree because I only have so much time
here all right so you kind of have to
bear with me in that in that part the
scope should be as open as possible
including physical you know maybe it
should be cuz it works really well okay
cuz lots of people get in with physical
it works alright and this is red team
not black team we're not gonna we're not
gonna kidnap you so I mean we're just
talking about you know we're just
talking about getting a device in the
network this is it's not a big deal okay
so you know let's expand the horizons a
little bit it's gonna be fine and then
last there should always be a tip your
hand moment and and sometimes I'll ask
my clients hey is it okay I got
persistent access I achieved trophies
one and two is it okay if I start making
some noise no we we don't want to make
any noise well why not
well because I'm on the Audit Committee
and the InfoSec committee doesn't know
that we're doing this then like okay um
it would be better if we did because
that way they you know I could kind of
coach them through some of the incident
response we could take a look at that I
could report on it'd be better for you
as an auditor but anyways there should
always be a moment in the red team where
the I lay the hand down everyone sees
what's going on we deconstruct the
entire path and then put together solid
defenses based on that all right so
before the engagement even starts core
principles on on the pre engagement
cycle I steer the clients towards open
of a scope as possible which I talked
about clearly defined what can be done
versus what will be done nod your head
to this if you're a red team are you
under
and this pain because what goes into the
statement of work is something like we
may do things like physical intrusion
wireless social engineering internal
testing external testing and the client
looks at this and they're like oh man I
could all this not necessarily we will
do what we have to do including these
things if necessary and so I'm always
defining that in other words if I call
pay user ask for password single-factor
my a my way in through VPN I don't have
to fish you I don't have to Wireless
that's you okay so I always define what
I can do versus what I will do said an
assumed breach target date this in my
opinion that this is best practice and
the reason being is I've only ever had
one client one where I've said hey can
we talk about a date for when we cut
over to assume breach scenario soon
breaches really when we just pivot to an
insider's perspective and the client was
like no you're gonna fish and you're
gonna fish and you're gonna fish until
you can't fish anymore and I'm like
alright fine
so I spent four weeks fishing I didn't
get in and now with ham an empty report
I'm like I fished you won
congratulations secure check the Box
move on but they're not right and that's
that's a problem so we're always trying
to set that that assume breach date all
right and then I am not ashamed to admit
this all right I asked for the clients
lockout policy not necessarily a minimum
password length okay but I asked for the
lockout policy well why would I do that
all right specifically those attributes
whether they're setting Active Directory
where they're simply a password filter
whether it's of you know a third party
product doesn't matter I asked for that
because chances are if I'm not gonna see
chances are you brute force on a red
team right you brute force on a red team
you brute force on a red team what's the
first thing we do we look for a sure we
look for oh through 65 we look for
bootable services okay and so
understanding what their lockout policy
is you're saving them headaches and
you're saving yourself a black eye
all right in terms of like my average
rate if they refuse to tell me I'll
generally do about one every four hours
and maybe that's slow maybe that's fast
I'm not entirely sure and I'm trying to
take it easy and not lock anyone out you
guys make her way fast you may go way
slower but that's what I do when I
haven't had any lockouts at least in
recent memory so but again on the
kickoff call I kick I asked that
question all right so the question when
is the red team engagement actually
is it on the kickoff call is that when
you start euro sent the answers at least
to me is the minute I get the the
assignment email from project manager
the very moment I do that I'm out on
LinkedIn why because it's the best all
right go to LinkedIn
you must have a recon account by now in
other words an account that is not
associated to your real account that is
not connected to your real account right
you your your accounts are separate I
sure hope so
all right I said a repeating task to add
connections and I do this frequently
about once a month I go out to LinkedIn
I click the network button and I start
he and connecting that connect and I'm
gonna give you a shortcut for that all
right and it's easy it's great because
well I can't say what dad's against
linkedin's Terms of Service in fact it's
impossible to scrape LinkedIn all right
it's number one you built decent profile
be thorough okay this is not the time to
be restrained in in your personality or
in yourself you choose attributes about
your fake persona that you think are
going to be attractive to your target
audience
intent okay number two you click my
network you click my network you see
something like this all right you see
those connect buttons this is the best
part of LinkedIn so good man you guys
gonna love this all right you scroll all
the way down and fill up the page and
then you scroll all the way down again
and you scroll the way down LinkedIn
does this Ajax thing we're like as you
keep scrolling it keeps adding
connections right yeah you did this guy
who's laughing he knows exactly I'm
gonna do all right you keep filling the
page and you keep filling the page I'm
talking like a thousand of these things
you scroll fix up your coffee this is
great all right and then you open up
browser tip tools you run that little
chunk of JavaScript code you connect to
like a thousand people connect to start
rolling in you do a dance cuz you're
awesome
all right so LinkedIn do it do it today
domains I age my domains for a long time
sometimes months sometimes days but
mostly months all right and and the
reason being is because there are really
good security controls like domain tools
out there that will take into account
the age of domains when you are sending
your phishing campaign are on your
callback domain and that'll be a red
flag so get a hold of some good domains
and start the aging process like a fine
wine or a good cheese you
just want those aged friend good long
time it did they just taste better okay
reusable if possible some some groups
burn all the domains this is burned to
the ground and then they start over in
the buy new domains where they go with
expired domains and that's great and and
if that works and you're you're doing
that that's awesome and I'm like why
ruin a good thing if you have an awesome
domain and it doesn't get caught keep
using it and so I go out and I check
I'll - oh I check check point I check
force point I check McAfee blue code I
check those places to make sure that my
domains are still healthy healthy
because they're in the health category
client name - portal com is not okay do
not put your client I'm in the domain
anymore why because at least the vast
majority clients that I test they have
services that that send an email to
security saying Jason registered a
domain that has your name on it so block
it and then block him and he's bad so
normally i if i want to put my client
name anywhere i will put it in the
tertiary level domain the third one over
not not the secondary level yet the
tertiary level so client dot help -
portal comm normal do that but just FYI
be careful because search transparency
logs can burn you on this and if you use
multiple clients tied to the same domain
this is generally a bad idea so be very
very cautious with putting your dome or
your client name in the domain much
rather have domains that are that are
more reusable more widely open and not
associated directly to a client okay see
to efficient domains never overlap this
one is kind of obvious but I just ate it
I might burn through five or ten domains
on an engagement of the payloads going
one place persistence is going another
place c2 short long going different
places you know so just keep those
things separate and then I submit
domains like I said I gave this list
Palo Alto Blue Coat checkpoint McAfee
those are kind of the top four and the
magic categories that I'm shooting for
is health financial and government
well why those three okay though and in
fact I was working with one of my
fortune small number clients that told
me about these magic three categories
and and they said these are the three
that you want to get if you can get in
any one of those you are golden well why
is that well in fact on Palo Alto's
best practices website for SSL based
based encryption their number one wreck
Commendation is do not decrypt health
finance government military and shopping
why would that be HIPAA PII pan data
nobody wants to see that you certainly
watch a Palo Alto inside your PCI scope
you don't want people the defenders
don't want to be anywhere near that awed
it doesn't want to be anywhere near that
so all that stuff gets left I encrypted
and it's good you know like I said
healthy domains we like that all right
tools I'm not gonna get too much into
tools but I will give you this slide and
of course I will make these slides
available on Twitter so you can you can
take pictures or you can just follow me
on Twitter now I'll drop them out there
tools for a passive recon hard cider
that was made by Jason Ashton at trust
SEC amass for certificate transparency I
use tool that I wrote sir SH - parse PI
meta is good for searching metadata get
up searching with truffle hog or repo
scanner or you can just send a NAT
request to hacking LZ he is he's the
person who knows like you just find
anything on github so feel free to hit
him up and then authenticated LinkedIn
scraping for contents you could use a
LinkedIn there and then Google dorks for
everything else and these are some of my
favorite google dorks i love these the
top one you know you're looking for
amazon you're looking for you know
pastebin things like that the bottom one
is my favorite because service that's
people and help this people generally
hit their job and so they want out as
soon as possible through this is gonna
litter their profile with all kinds of
awesome information so definitely one of
my favorites breach data breach data is
a treasure trove of information the
email format the pastor format new user
passwords i group these by countin and
throw them in the report very very
helpful and if you're not sure where to
get started if you haven't gone down
this road there are people in in the
place where i work I'm not sure if Hans
is here but he has done a tremendous
it's incredible what that guy's done
with password breach data and crack and
stuff like that it is very very useful
to a red teaming organization to have
that kind of data so if you're not sure
where to go well there's a I'll get you
stare don't say an every day anything
good for you alright external now we
starting to fun stuff right core
principles on the external just a little
bit I always root out to directory
the external perspective never internal
and always through VPN if you get
internal access if I get internal lag
this is my methodology not yours if I
get internal access
I do not Groot Active Directory with one
exception that might be curb root which
is going to throw a different event ID
47 71 as opposed to 46 24 in in the log
don't quote me on that but I do know
that Kerberos brooding is a different
event ID than like auntie LAN brooding
or things like that so that is still a
reasonably new technique otherwise I do
not brew it after directory from the
internal perspective number two and your
mouse is gonna vary on this one maybe
you're a web app genius and that's
awesome but generally speaking from a
consultants perspective when I'm when
I'm unlimited time Web Apps are not
necessarily my focus I will look at your
web apps however it's not from a web app
testing perspective and Trust like we
have an amazing group of web app testers
and that's all they do they don't do red
teaming and what I might do is bring in
somebody with that specialty on to the
red team at least for that engagement to
look at those web apps but it's not
necessarily my specialty because they've
grown extremely complex in my opinion so
not necessarily the thing that I'm most
gravitating towards and I do make
liberal use of credential stuffing if
you're not familiar with that we're back
to bat password breach data get a hold
of those credentials and start trying
them I one of my targets this is an
assessment two weeks ago I went and took
their brand name it was a popular brand
name and grabbed the credentials from my
password breach store and threw a mat at
their website 350 valid credentials just
like that so it does work very very well
active recon these are our do it aqua
tone through search and map typical
tools that you would use in a Red Team
engagement but just understand and
thanks to I think Scott pointed this out
for like the end map user agent that can
bite you because if you didn't know this
and I didn't know this until a little
while ago
nmap has its own user agent and it has n
map in the user agent so talk about
getting blocked right away you can
actually change that with us with a
script parameter if you use I don't now
you can't see it but if it's dish - -
script args and then you can paste in
the the user agent that you want to see
and if you're interested I wrapped all
this into a tool
that that I used on my engagements
called initial recon that it fires a
mass at front hires a LinkedIn scraper
fires metadata scraper fires all that
stuff and the code sections are up there
if you want to get them I get up it's
helpful at least I think it's helpful
it's good for my methodology might not
work for you if you don't have something
like this it'll be a good thing to get
you started and then lastly on the
external part ntlm brooding is still
super hot office 365 exchange Skype link
a good place for testing what a client
has is a test connector via Microsoft
com
otherwise I will go out to Outlook
Microsoft com put in admin at target.com
and I'll get redirected to whatever
their ad FS instances and that's always
really helpful speaking of ad FS
these links were dropped at Troopers 19
these are some less obvious sources
friend teal and burning so if you go to
like a TFS target comm and then and and
that those are valid URLs so that that a
TFS is a valid domain taking you to an
ad FS instance those you are eyes I'm
blaze reporting at my screen those your
eyes at the very bottom are open ntlm
portals so you can send your brute-force
attacks they're very very helpful social
engineering does everyone loves a bob
core principles and social engineering
fishing this is how I get around proof
point in fact I went for point is good
at it's probably very it's probably very
very good at stopping a lot of spam but
if you are going to be targeted and this
is true of a lot of controls right yeah
as red team as we understand this the I
never as much as I dog I'm like
antivirus I never told my clients to
uninstall it because it serves a very
very good purpose which is blocking like
kamat commodity malware achmadi
ransomware that kind of stuff it does
serve a good purpose Proofpoint serves a
good purpose
it just doesn't serve the purpose when
i'm sending the email and here's how
that works you send five at five emails
max at a time all bcc'd works great with
fifteen minutes in between sends and I
send from office 365 a little caveat
there when you log in to office 365 to
send your fish
the IP that you are connecting from gets
put into the headers of that message so
be sure you are connecting from a VPN
tunnel okay send links not attachments
you do those things and you just kind of
take it slow
you're not blasting out 100 emails a
time you're not gonna make worries about
Brooklyn I lead off with my my latest
tradecraft and then I downgrade as I get
a feel for the target environment okay
so if you have like all custom c2 and
you're just shiz you're all this hot
stuff but you know there's like
PowerShell version 2 in the environment
don't necessarily burn all the stuff
that you spend a lot of time writing
okay adjust your attack path to the
maturity of the client right because if
you're so far ahead of them you might be
giving them things that they can't
necessarily remediate at least not in
any meaningful fashion if they even
understand it so point being is adjust
your that your turn that dial back I
guess if you will to compensate for
their sensitivity and eventually
eventually your clients will all pace
you and you'll be like shoot this I gave
you everything I had and you caught me I
fish tonight fish tonight fish and you
caught me and that's kind of a good
place for them for them to be alright
and once again eventually pivot to
assume breach I do this about 50% away
through the engagement time that's a six
week engagement it'll generally be about
two and a half weeks maybe three weeks
maybe two weeks going into that just
because that provides better value
provides a better value for the client
and you know what if you're done
evaluating the perimeter then you're
done evaluating the perimeter so some
move on infrastructure automation
automation is getting to be or actually
infrastructure building it up and
tearing it down is getting to be a pain
especially when you need different
servers for everything and whether
you're doing AWS or whether you're doing
a sure were they doing on Prem what I do
is I use ansible if you follow me on
Twitter for any length of time you know
I'm kind of an Ansel junky I just gave a
class pretty much under Hansel Bowles is
you know ton of fun but what answer was
just really really brief primer it's an
open source platform put out by Red Hat
maintained by Red Hat that gives you
really saw configuration management and
application deployment purposes it uses
the ammo files it's really easy to get
into even if you've never coded it if
you're not even coding any ammo you're
just like typing in the animal it's it's
really really straightforward there's no
agent it's totally agent list you need
Association pie
that's it if you can get Python on the
target you can even even have to have
Python target you can use ansible to
install Python on the target which is
fantastic and then modules make up the
functionality so for example these are
some these are some tasks that are
inside my create c2v2 server playbook so
the name of the task cloning a packet
installing a packet cloning carbon copy
etc etc the modules that we're using so
in this case the module is called git
command and then get I'm calling the get
module twice and then I'm passing the
argument it's actually really really
straightforward then once you have all
that put together you run it inside a
playbook
so in this case I'm running the new c2
server playbook against the host file
and it goes out and builds all my stuff
ansible is multi-threaded so you can run
this against five c2 service at once and
they all get billed out the exact same
way to the desired state configuration
that you're looking for really really
really good tool if you want to geek out
about that I'll be happy to do that with
you and the macros chat and attachments
for sending payloads safe payloads
generally speaking a modified cactus
torch will is reasonably safe in terms
of getting in the door if you're looking
to get code execution immediately
otherwise safer might be registry only
mods so for example if you're looking to
land with like persistence or something
along those lines registry key mods are
generally very safe we've it we have yet
to be caught yet on that at least as far
as I know VB is stomping and evil Clippy
the Walmart folks they did a great job
Herald in his team did a great job on
this evil Clippy the outflank guys I
know this is Stan's work primarily
fantastic tools that we all use that or
they're really really good in terms of
making those macros even more evil and
less detectable and that's we want and
then lastly a template injection which
I'm a huge fan of template injection is
great because you can actually send a
doc X in the door and then when the user
opens that doc X it goes out and pulls
in the doc M or the dot gif or whatever
and it all works great okay so really
that evil template give is just a doc M
that's hosting on my web server it pulls
the template in the user gets prompted
they click enable content and then you
get your shell or Y or Z or whatever is
you're looking for all right as you
information protection
oddvar and hans give a fantastic talk on
this yesterday leverages though office
365's rms to encrypt the office
document to specific recipients which is
really cool it's impossible for
defenders and sandbox is to evaluate
without the users credentials need to
read that again when you send an AIP
encrypted document and it reaches their
environment and and the users like this
is spam and they forward it if they can
if you haven't marked the do not forward
box if they if they forward it over to
security secur is gonna open it they're
gonna be like I can't open this it's
encrypted
I need your password and you just be
like I'm never supposed to give you my
password secures me like I need your pet
and freak-outs great does not require
your target to have office 365 you can
send this to a gmail account and let's
get prompted to an installation here's
what it looks like you you install the
Azure information protection agent you
go out to protect it you select the
email address your targets email address
sorry
that's permissions can you guys even see
that yeah you can't okay you can you
selected permissions this case view only
you put in the target's email address
and then if you're feeling if you're
feeling especially naughty you specify
an expiration which is just great you
know cuz like if you only want that fish
to be live for 24 hours
then you can just put in 24 hours and
send to me after 24 hours it's gone like
Mission Impossible stuff self-destruct
alright so as your information
protection watch this talk I got a look
in there right for this this this talk
happened yesterday those guys did a
fantastic job and then the internal side
really work it's fun right core
principles on the internal on a red team
this is what I'm prioritized once I get
access into the target environment I'm
not just invoke masked me me catching
everything alright as fun as that is who
isn't like treads just raining back in
ok but seriously though cookies
bookmarks file shares SharePoint
remember the ability to slow down what
are you doing with this step you're
gaining valuable knowledge about the
targets environment ok you're not just
you know spraying and praying your
you're looking for things that are of
value because how many times on red
teams have you found documents that have
career
documents that have Network diagrams
document said have sensitive data open
file shares that have sensitive data do
spend the time in that due diligence you
might be able to achieve the trophies
just with that you necessarily have to
be moving laterally and why move
laterally if you don't have to that's
one of the noises things you could do in
the target network so if you have the
right access to those data stores use
that access and accomplish the goal
because that's what an attacker would do
that's what I would attack all right
Kerberos thing I love it I love it but I
got to dial it back okay you got it you
got to pull the reigns back on a
Kerberos if you're just firing get users
SP ends all right from a packet then
what's happening is you're sending those
events to Active Directory a ton of them
and if the defender is on top of it
they've written a threshold alert so
anything more than I don't know what
four or five I mean a day if ever so in
my case generally speaking I'll start
out no more than one an hour and that's
after doing research on the account okay
now this is obviously assuming
credential access okay but you're doing
the research on the account to see if
it's even a viable target all right and
when I choose Kerberos IDs the Kerberos
I'm not going for domain AB okay true
story
I was I was Kerberos ting user accounts
and actually I shouldn't said I was
doing reconnaissance against user
accounts that had service principle
names and it was like all all the
account names were like SVC underscore
every single one and then there was one
that was John Smith like J Smith right
and in the description it said InfoSec
come on oh that's and so I sent emailed
my content like this is a honeypot he's
like yeah great alright so I was
actually chatting with a with a friend
of mine about this last night about how
to do like Kerberos deception make
twenty accounts and make them all with
different user IDs and then if you want
to be really evil in your twenty fake
accounts that you have disabled with or
that you have enabled with ridiculously
long passwords that will never crack go
ahead and make your J Smith user account
because the attacker is gonna show if
you like out that's honeypot I'm not
gonna grab that one and they're gonna
grab the rest that's like pure evil but
this is a red team talk shoot okay
I do purple teams - it's fun all right
initial landing callback of 5 to 30
minutes depending on the time that I
have and the sophistication of the
target ok so there are some times when
it is fine to just throw the barn doors
open so to speak and like go full
interactive mode on your beacon okay but
that's after you've done a little bit of
analysis that's after you've had your
shell for a little bit and you know you
maybe you've downloaded some stuff
you're taking your time for a day or two
it's not a big deal
slow down and then once you've figured
out that they're not catching on to your
c2 then yeah full interactive because
that's the best all right I test all my
commands in my lab before firing live at
least as much as I can ok just a little
bit of a word about my lab I went out to
ebay I bought at Dell our 710 $500 ok we
have an Emma stand license which I
imagine a lot of you probably do and I
built full Active Directory lab ok I
installed the fantastic the one and only
Splunk through hunting app bye-bye Olaf
sis Mon and Windows Defender and and I
configured all this and and it's it's I
cannot tell you the amount of times that
I have used my lab on the engagement to
produce better results say for example
this I don't I hope you guys can see
that so this is my shoot that's not open
nope alright use empty my word for it so
this is all the window systems in my
environment and what I'm doing is I'm
looking at the system on event logs to
see which processes are establishing
connections out to the internet and on
what frequency well why would this be
useful because as a red teamer if I can
get into one of those processes well
that's that's more real looking right
and so do that take that step of
investing in the Splunk license
seriously all you have to do is go out
to spunks website and request the
developer license right the the free
license is 500 Meg's the developer
license is 10 gigs a day and they'll
give it to you because Long's awesome
like that ok so go out there request
that license is valid for six months and
then you can import all the stuff and do
your own research on this because this
is what the defense is saying and once
you know if the defense is sitting is
saying you know how to manipulate it
okay you know how to work around it and
then you know how to help them with it
all right tools let's get into a little
bit of tooling on a red team okay so I'm
gonna divide the room
alright brace yourself this is what I
almost never use on a red team crack map
exec much as I love it I love it or
cello you're awesome
okay I love it internal brooding like I
said I don't do it curb route might be
an exception there if I think their
defense is not going to catch that power
sploit I've generally do not run much
for PowerShell unless it's something
that I've wrote that I know from a
sysadmin perspective is relatively inert
for example coring active directory I'm
not gonna use Power View I will do
something that I've written myself okay
tools that I sometimes use on a red team
bloodhound depending on the switches
thank you to Scott and the bloodhound
crew for pulling me up to speed there
and not getting caught mess boy
auxiliary modules are still fantastic to
run run slowly modified me me cats and
it's and by the way I don't mean like
logon passwords please do not run that
on your under my team please don't do
that please don't start flipping the W
digest keys don't do that you know just
kind of pull back the reins on that
because maybe Katz has so much more to
offer than just log on passwords Carlos
gave an incredible 2-day training on
that just on me me cats like Mew cats
and Kiki oh that's all it was okay and
then cobalt strike obviously I'm not
running anything stock everything's
gonna be all modified malleable profiles
things like that okay and when I'm model
first FYI when I modify
my COBOL straight profile I go out to
rafts blog and I grab every single
attribute that I have and modify every
single one okay so I will go out to and
I will make an authenticated call out to
a service that I sign up for okay so
like me personally I like health so for
example like my an old health insurance
provider or something like that that I
might still have an account for fire up
burp grab all that traffic and then I
configure the gets the posts the stagers
all to look very very close to that I do
not rely on automated tools for that I
liked I like handcrafted artisanal
farm-to-table malleable profiles that
way so that's how I like to do it okay
and then what I always use all right I'm
pretty much every engagement I'm gonna
be using these things all right I'm
gonna be using a socks proxy I'm gonna
be using proxy chains I'm gonna be using
LDAP search Kerberos manipulation and
literally anything from dirty on okay
however understand that those tools are
gonna be modified alright even in packet
and packet is fantastic impacted is one
of my favorite toolkits of all time I
just love it okay but I will still
modify it why because the defense can
see this stuff all right they can
actually see the parent process chain
when I fire W my exec that is what
they're seeing on the command line
they're seeing cmd.exe slash capital q
/c echo blah blah blah and it just looks
bad it looks like somebody just barked
all over the command line it's horrible
okay and it sticks out like a sore thumb
if you know what to look for
alright and so what will I do I'll go
into the script and I will modify the
the command switches if I'm feeling
adventurous I'll try and modify the
communications okay but I will change
every almost everything that I can
change about the tool all right and
here's the good news about that as a red
teamer what that will do is that will
lead you to writing better detections
for your own stuff for example I wrote
this for impacting this is spun query
that detects about three or four
impacted tools that are just you know
stock and that's great because if I can
detect it then I know what I can change
and this is the the greater loop that I
think he blogged about or talked about
right you you write better detection so
you know what you have to change you can
write better tools all right and that
loop is priceless as a red teamer if
you're not doing that
if you're not modifying tools and then
the writing detections for that so you
can change the tool you're missing out
on actually a lot of fun it's a lot of
fun because that why do we do red
teaming it's a puzzle right why do blue
teamers blue well it's a puzzle we like
we like to solve puzzles all right and
this is a really fun puzzle and a really
fun challenge to solve so I encourage
you to give a shot okay even if you're
low privileged on a target there's still
some awesome stuff that you can do that
involves me me cats okay if you're
reasonably certain that you're not gonna
get caught you can run me me cast it's
not going to target else ass because
you're not running log on passwords
which you are running is DP API to hit
the chrome process okay so you make a
copy of the login data because that's
where the the plaintext and it's not
plain taps is DP API so that's where the
current roles are stored you make a copy
and then you fire me me cats at it and
you can pull plaintext credentials back
and when I say plain to exercise I
should say decrypted okay you pull those
krandalls back to the screen and
whatever the user has stored in chrome
you now have access to sometimes it's a
lot of personal stuff all right but
sometimes it's a lot of corporate stuff
especially if they have chrome rolled
out so there's very very useful to do
that and you can do it as a little
privileged user if you do not want to
fire me me cats in the targets memory
understandable you save off the cookies
file or the login datas file you acquire
the users password and I mean this it's
not not too hard to do red teamers right
my last engagement my physical guy
called up someone it was like hey I'm
closing on helpdesk tickets do you have
any open ones and like ah the printer I
hate the printer blah blah blah just
went on and on about the printer my guy
was like yeah the printers are awful
here and you know it's not a big deal
but I will take care of all that for you
I just have to verify you are who you
say you are
oh yeah sure my password password 1 2 3
it's it's actually not that hard easy
password alright follow steps here for
decrypting the use of DP API keys and
here is on wills blog here this was a
ton of fun I his entire blog went
through it step by step and learned a
ton about DP API I would strongly
encourage you to do that it's a it's a
worthwhile exercise to do ok persistence
and and movement for persistence
honestly just really anything that's on
hex the corns website you just target HK
Cu and there's all kinds of just
fantastic stuff some of it is like
really third-party
civic some of it is fantastic that that
I that I love using so if you're not an
avid reader of hexa corn you should be
common DLL hijacking there's a fantastic
talk that was given I think this morning
about comm hijacking I really went into
the nuts and bolts of it and even how to
weaponize it with a calm proxy and that
is that's super important otherwise
you're going to fubar the environment
proc monitors your is your absolute best
friend there Wow even got a bullet point
on comm proxy okay so read the article
from from leo he did an incredible job
on that and what will get you into proc
saying calm calls so you don't break the
system because truthfully come hijacking
well it's cool and say it's it's sexy it
can be a little risky to do on a target
environment because you can trash the
system if you pick the wrong class ID so
do your testing use a comm proxy and
you're in a much safer position for
weaponization alright and then blend in
blending in that's kind of more of an
art than a science right so like this
and this is again where Splunk is
amazing so we talked about blending in
so on a target system that's runs Splunk
universe before i'm gonna pick on spawn
for just a minute okay the these sub
processes for Splunk like spunk -
powershell and spunk - a-team on and
spunk - in that mod they run every
minute they pollute the the security log
with 46 eighty eight's that meet that
that kick off this starting process okay
so if this process is running all the
time all the time it's kind of a safe
bet kind of it's safer than not doing
it's kind of a safe bet that if you take
your naughty process and make it one of
those processes that have probably been
excluded from Splunk congestion then
chances are you're a little bit safer
alright you're not gonna get caught at
least not as fast okay and so now
obviously I'm picking on spunk here you
need to have an race to do this stuff I
mean I'm I'm not gonna be s you you know
in order to do this kind of stuff you
have to have an admin presence on the
system because spunk actually did a good
job locking down the privileges on their
target directory but the point is is
that if you see processes running
continuously on a target system find one
of those processes
stick your payload into that directory
rename it or just call it that name in
another directory because if they're
excluding that process only by
name and not by path you you're not
gonna get caught
all right deal a hijacking still awesome
I sat down I opened a proc Mon I just
kind of monkey with spunk for a little
bit and there's like there's like a ton
of calls in the spunk Universal
forwarder where's its name mouth found
and you can just kind of you know pick
your deal all poison and just mess with
it again you need ever right for this so
I mean it's you know your mouth as my
very but point being is that deal
hijacking is still very valid and
because the it's not like cmd.exe
calling this process it's a legitimate
process that's probably been whitelisted
calling that you're probably safer to do
that so difficult to detect okay come
hijack in just a little bit this was fun
the the the si host process anyone know
what the si host process does see so the
SI host process in Windows 7 and Windows
10 is responsible for looking at Windows
activation status and so right when when
we were when we were giving our blackhat
training two years ago we were using a
Windows 7 image and I I kind of I turned
the students loose for the comm
hijacking modular I'm like I just find
something awesome just go to town
because they get super excited and they
tell me what the class that these are
it's great don't tell them that okay so
but then what they do is they find
something like this in the si hos
process okay name not found and and they
stick a comm hijack in there well what
happens that when Windows boots up you
ever use the trial version of Windows as
always says in the lower right hand
corner says you know you must activate
Windows right so a student came up to me
all excited and he's like hey I found
this comma hijacking this pro in this
process called si host and I really know
what it does but I don't get prompted to
activate Windows anymore uh I was like
are you kidding me and I went over to
his system and sure enough the message
was gone and and so I was like alright
well I was it's Windows 7 you could
hijack anything in Windows 7 right so so
we changed over to Windows 10 for for a
black hat a month ago and and I told the
story and a students up to me is like
still works in Windows 10 I still do it
and I was like sweet free windows right
you know that's great alright so
reporting all right
Hey reporting communication okay
I'm gonna divide the room a little bit
once again it's my methodology all right
on status updates to clients use caution
okay this can bite you and it has bitten
us a lot all right and that's not to say
that you should lie I am NOT saying that
what I am saying is that you need to
take a us on the client because some
clients are amazing and some want to win
and that's not the point of the
engagement it's not for the red team to
win it's not for the blue team to win
right it's the test controls and make
recommendations based on your findings
all right this is it's not necessarily a
game or a contest all right and so when
I share status updates if I think that
my client is gonna snipe me with this
I'll just be like yeah you know we had a
great weekend
ransom port scanning and you know I've
seen a lot of great controls and you
know normally that's just kind of a
response and needs to go back to a
committee or something like that if I
can tell the client loves security and
wants either wants us to find new attack
paths or things like that I'll tell them
everything that we're doing but the
point being is that I use caution I
don't just go into it like well ran me
me cats got da you know it's like I
don't necessarily do that all right in
the report that is where everything goes
everything and by everything I mean
everything especially in the narrative
because when working with clients and
doing a red team this is not you know
your Grandpa's pen test where it's just
like okay take findings give to audit
committee I take things that give them
to the engineer and then the engineer
does that it's not it's not that
generally speaking and doing red team's
you're working with interested clients
okay and so the in my experience the
findings are important but they're
important from an audit perspective the
the security team who wants the
narrative that's what they want and they
want everything spelled out and they
should and I encourage security teams to
actively break down every part of the
engagement because that that's which
should be done to develop better
detection and so do not withhold the
secret sauce in the report
please don't okay gives everyone a black
guy don't do it all right findings I
tell my clients this out of the gate
every single time we kick off a red team
do I'm not gonna give you an ssl fine oh
no SSL version two I'm
not gonna do that okay unless I unless I
actively exploited somehow alright at
the findings that I can that I'm going
to give are probably going to be fewer
in number higher in quality and but what
I mean by that is they are going to be
directly connected to the path of
exploitation or the path of compromise
okay so that's that's my personal
methodology for giving findings so far
it's worked very well all right and then
consultants this is the best seriously
if you're not doing this if you're just
shipping a report and then moving on or
it's an ear steak house okay you're
you're you're you're doing it wrong
alright the best moments are when you
followup with the defense and the way
that I always end my my last call with
the cut with with my client is I use a
system like this I will never ever leave
you hanging out on a limb if you have
questions about the report if something
isn't answered if somebody puts your
feet to the fire they want to know how
Jason did this or this
just call me call text signal email
anything and I will be there I will get
on the phone with schedule a meeting
I've flown out to clients and then in
person debriefs point being is that
always be there for the defense and when
you do that report read out and and you
start to see the light bulbs go on there
is no feeling there there is no shell
that produces that kind of high okay so
do not withhold when it comes to giving
the defense all of the goods that you
have because that's that's frankly what
you're being paid to do okay that's it
folks
[Applause]