ready morning everybody thanks for
coming I know it's hard to get up after
partying so hard last night
and my name is rich Rumble a little bit
about me I'm curious and Naughty by
Nature and certifiable
I've even gotten certified I'm driven I
am humble if I do say so myself and I
have a great sense of humor and my mom
told me so so brief intro into RFID I'm
not going to get into the weeds too much
about the protocols or anything you need
to really understand other than it is
super easy to clone badges and these
days sure sorry about that so use RFID
all the time in your hotel bed your work
badge even the running bibs when you go
to a marathon often you'll find that
they are equipped with an rfid reader so
that when you cross the start line and
the finish line they can keep track of
you again these are some of the details
of RFID like what the ranges are on
reading them and the different tags you
find them reading the I'm sorry the the
animal tags the badge tags window tag
does anybody have a Mike's or a crew car
wash tag anybody familiar with the car
wash tag there you go
and those read at a different range and
they're much much better actually so
near field communication I'm going to
talk about that briefly now it's what
you use in your phone for Apple pay
Google pay it's very passive and it's
often what the badge readers or the new
the new access control systems are
moving to these they're still very short
distances
Bluetooth is something that is not
really used in RFID or badge reading or
authentication but I wanted to mention
some interesting facts I found out while
researching this topic you are tire
pressure sensors in your car
actually use a Bluetooth signal and you
basically have four unique trackers in
your car that could be used to track you
all over town if someone were to equip
your town with enough readers all over
the place you could actually track
someone using that so I thought that was
a little interesting how your phone
gives off a Bluetooth signal so you
could track someone by your phone I'm
sure that's all been covered prior so
since my talk is on RFID badge skimming
I wanted to talk about a few people who
have done some great work in the area
and and inspired me to do the same or do
something similar over here on the right
you see the tastic RFID thief what he
did was Francis Brown took a RFID reader
it's usually what you find in the
parking garage it's about a foot in diet
or you know in size either way its
square and you see the large coil of
wire there that reads your card from
about three feet so he thought it would
be a good idea to put that in his
man-bag slash man purse and walk around
next to people and read badges without
having to get so close that it's almost
the game of grab-ass if you will because
you usually do have to be very close to
people and they don't like you like you
know doing such things some other ID
ideas that people have had are these two
devices you see at the bottom one in the
middle is the Wi-Fi tool it's a great
little tool it basically does the same
thing that Francis did with his reader
although in the middle of his reader you
can see he put an Arduino reader and a
small memory card again watch his talk
it's it's it's very good so the Wi-Fi
tool will vampire tap into the the
innards though the wires that run from
the reader to the controller and the the
wires that talk from the reader to the
controller are not encrypted they use a
Weigand protocol which is essentially a
plaintext protocol it's very well
understood and ease
to to tap into and and and get the data
off of it
the tool to the left is called the
bleakie so instead of using Wi-Fi to
communicate to this tool you would use
bluetooth and the next slide I'll kind
of show you what that tool looks like so
this is another reader it's a little
smaller and someone has basically taken
the wires and you can see how they push
them down through these little will call
them vampire taps and these dig into the
wire and are making contact with the
wire and as a badge is read you can it
will start to write down what the the
number of the badge was and you could
walk by with your phone after it's
stored up these badges and you could
download over bluetooth all the badges
that were read and you can actually send
a signal to the phone with this little
app you see on the right this can replay
the badges it can again download them
for you to then place in a cloner and
you could clone the badge so this is
what inspired some of this talk here
there were some of these devices and
again the communication is plaintext
from the badge reader to the controller
so I just want to reiterate that that
will come up later again acknowledging
some previous work so as far back as
2003 hackers have been cloning badges
and making it easy for the public to do
it Chris pageant and these other two
gentlemen at the top they even showed
their congressman how easy it was to
clone the the badges for the government
and they were up in arms back then about
it and some changes were made and some
improvements were made to the cards as a
result and I wanted to call out some of
these other people as inspiration for me
and this talk and I'm sure I'm missing
quite a few so our idea started with
going to a client's engagement we're
doing a follow up engagement not related
to RFID or pin test or I'm sorry
physical pin testing at all and the
client on day two of our
returned their the clients RFID badge
readers had changed and we took note of
it and we asked the client you know why
did you change your readers who upgraded
them and what's the reasoning and they
actually had no idea they didn't control
the readers they were just one tenant of
many in a building so the the readers
are actually controlled by the building
what do you call it the yeah the
property management and so they were
just badging in blindly and just going
upstairs even though they're bad readers
changed and nobody informed them that
they were changing so this this gave us
an idea and so with the with the readers
notice or I'm sorry with the employees
notice if the readers changed again and
so we had a light bulb moment and we
asked the client please please please
can we can we can we make some skimmers
for your badge readers in there like
yeah but we don't want you to actually
get the IDs we don't want you to
actually get the numbers so in these the
memory cards that we were going to use
there's a config file and in that config
file you tella what baud rate to expect
what rate of data is going to come to
that and if you give it the wrong baud
rate you will get a bunch of gibberish
but it will put it at it will do it line
by line so you can count the lines
rather than counting you know that we're
getting the actual card data so we're
getting gibberish but we're getting
gibberish once per line and so that's
how we counted how many people were
coming into the building or using the
reader without actually getting the data
off of it and the clients we're happy
with that that solution well that took
us actually a couple minutes to to
figure out how to do on Brian Krebs I'm
sure you've seen ATM skimmers that are
similar to this they just fit over the
the unit and your badge or your I'm
sorry your credit card is read twice
so once by the unit and then once by the
the actual reader the ATM behind it and
then we saw this one on Krebs in at
really blew our mind
yeah that's what I said
and so they basically took a laptop and
made entire and housing over the the ATM
reader they took a laptop and readers
and they mimicked what was gonna happen
on the screen behind it once you put
your card in and once you put your PIN
in and there's cellular there's a cell
phone also up in all those electronics
that sends your phone or I'm sorry your
card over the phone real time to the
attackers so they can be across the
world and know what your credit card was
instantly but this was somewhere in
Brazil I believe and yeah that that was
this is really the inspiration for for
our our card readers so we called this
project cosplay because we were just
making a little costume it seemed like
for the badge readers so what we came up
with was $15 we could get off of ebay a
card reader and we could to make a mold
of the card reader and essentially we
made a mold of it made a plaster
positive we we poured in the mold some
plaster and we built up around the
plaster and around the plaster we put
some ABS plastic and made another mold
of that and here in a second you'll see
what we kind of came up with so this is
our first attempt at making a cloned
badge reader you can ignore the sticker
on there that's just stuff we stick all
around the office but this was this was
the reader and we got some really good
success with this clients did not bat an
eye these were the readers they were
using these are the new readers they had
these really old grey ones that really
look a lot different than what what
these do so this was the reader we came
up with the client was pretty pleased
with it you can't tell from this picture
but there is about a quarter inch gap
between the the back of this reader and
and the actual reader so you can fit all
the electronics you need to and after
this talk I'll be over here to the right
of the
towards the windows and you guys can
come up and see all the electronics and
how small everything is and how it all
fits in inside these readers so please
see me after the show then we had to
make another cover because the client
thought this was too effective we left
it up there for about 48 hours and they
were not that pleased so they thought
okay if the readers change again then
they're sure to notice somebody's bound
a tournament or somebody's bound to
hesitate so they asked us if we could do
something like carbon fiber and we're
like okay sure maybe so we bought some
carbon fiber and took us about 2 or 3
days to figure out how to do it we use
bar resin instead of like the real
resident cuz my wife is very sensitive
to smells and she would have killed me
if it smelled like polyester resin so
essentially we took a Lego brick for the
the light section we cast that in in
silicone we poured bar resin and that
made a nice clear piece and stuck it in
there and these were the readers that we
came up with the first two on the left
are not not that great but that was our
first attempt at doing it but you can
see this is eight Legos wide on the on
the eight dots
I guess eight dots of Legos wide on the
reader itself the one on the right is
our probably our third attempt and is
much better and again come see me after
the show and you can see how thin and
small it is none of these were adhered
to the wall in any way anyone could have
tugged them off there was actually a
note underneath them that said
congratulations you found an implant
please come get some extra credit at
work you know that kind of thing
no one hesitated so for about a week
their badge scanners changed constantly
and it's their external badge scanner on
the outside of their building
there's nothing internal yet
so now we had to make one that was
really crappy we used a plastic resin
and then we cracked it with a hammer and
then we glued it all back together and
stuck some wires out of it and that one
after 10 people had used it got pulled
off the wall and that person got a
little attaboy she thought it would be a
shock hazard stret current I don't want
to get into it but it wouldn't be but
yeah we had to basically make this thing
look like a can of smashed ass to get
somebody to notice that it's not right
and they were constantly changing so
that was fun we had another client who
got on board with the idea and they
liked what we were doing with our other
client they had actually heard about it
and not through us but through the
grapevine I suppose and we made these
ultra-thin ones these do not cover the
entire scanner these are just like a
fascia that goes over it and again
you'll probably have to see me because
the pictures don't do it justice they
also did not want it to look exactly
right so I don't know if you can notice
at the top there's kind of a dip in the
top and I actually used hot glue for the
the the window there so it's really dull
it's really hard to see this one's
really scratched up the hid again the
picture doesn't do it justice but the
hid that's the branding at the bottom is
not very clear it's it doesn't look
quite right even the color is off they
had blue scanners I want to say and we
put black over them and nobody seemed to
notice on those okay so what else could
we do so the second client really liked
the scanner but they thought maybe
there's something else they could do
because the other stuff had been done
and we knew it was probably going to
work with their their clientele as well
so we took the reader that we used to
have for our mold-making we took one of
the RFID tools they weren't okay with us
writing down the the badges so this time
we use the RFID tool to
- the Weigand protocol we double-sided
tape that to the wall next to the reader
and putting out of order sign on it and
that worked so people would badge on the
evil twin over there on the right and
then that wouldn't worry it would beep
but nothing happened at the door so they
would then badge on the out of order one
sometimes I got both and it did work so
sometimes I kind of went in the middle
of the to split the difference and they
didn't know which one it was so the it
worked we had one lady who we gave some
extra points to she moved the out of
order sign from the left to the right so
she was real nice so we're we're happy
to have her she's a good egg
all right so people didn't seem to know
what to do with these scanners nobody
batted an eye as long as they worked so
what could we do to actually break the
scanner without breaking the scanner so
we used our entire covers our
carbon-fiber ones at the second client
and we put a piece of metal mesh the
screen door mesh you get at the hardware
store it is dirt cheap and it blocks the
the scanner from working I then put on a
navy blue blazer and when the badge
wouldn't work I would come out and I had
a laptop with me and a scanner because
we didn't have their badge scanned yet
so I needed to get a bad scan so I had
my laptop and a scanner and we'd ask
them to scan their badge and I'll say no
it's still not working
what is your manager's name what is your
ID what is your what is the answer to
your secret password or your secret
question rather and they I don't know
what's my secret question is it a mascot
no yeah you know that and we just say
big things like that and they would say
oh the Wolverines okay yeah sure all
right go ahead go in we knew they were
actual employees before doing that we
also had a secondary
the company has secondary traps inside
so we knew we weren't just letting any
Joe Schmoe in but yeah we were able to
social engineer the people into giving
us information they wouldn't give there
is no security staff at this entrance
they've never seen a security guard
probably before but here I am coming out
of the building asking them these
questions so I got pretty I was pretty
excited at first and then I really
started to feel bad for for the client
yeah because everybody was just giving
me anything I asked for as long as I had
the navy blue blazer and it said
security on my lapel so they had to do
it but nobody questioned me nobody asked
me anything but I figure you could
probably take me out of the equation and
just put some sort of call box on the
the side of the door and maybe a cell
phone that's in speaker mode and just
stick it in the box there and you could
ask people through the little speaker
there those same questions and it looks
official it's on the building so what
supposed to be there right so it would
probably work I have not been able to do
this and you could break the the RFID
badge reader in the same way we were
doing with the Faraday cage or you could
use one of these RFID tool or I'm sorry
yeah the RFID tool or the Bleak key they
can actually Doss the Wiegand wire and
keep people from badging in so you
wouldn't actually have to make a cover
you could actually break the the readers
without actually having to break the
reader you can kind of daus the the
command-and-control
that way so other people have noticed
that there are plenty of room for
activities inside these readers so at
first we showed you the the tastic rit
thief that he put in his man-bag
gentleman on twitter silas noticed that
you could stick what this device here
which is a proxmark three
revision four reader you could stick
that inside of a reader and no one's
gonna know so you don't have to make a
fancy cover like we made the ones we
made are filled with epoxy and gel so
you do have to make them but and this
reader which is very common and I've
seen on plenty of buildings you can
just pop it in there there's actually no
tamper or theft evidence with the with
this particular reader other readers do
have a little light on the back and they
let you know when someone has taken it
off the wall or tried to mess with the
wires you know that kind of thing
this readers not one of those however I
will caveat the tamper light and and the
alarm that it can send a lot of people
don't have that hooked up a lot of
people don't monitor that and even if it
is hooked up yet again they probably
don't even monitor it so you might want
to test if you get permission at work if
you can take your badge reader off the
wall and put it back on and see if
anybody notices because that will trip
that should-should trip an alarm for
someone so what could you do with I
wanted to come up with worst-case
scenarios for badges if I had this thing
on for a week could I
Ransome your badges could I sell your
information to a competitor could I
threaten your company by releasing them
to the public if they didn't pay me some
money now you're gonna have to re re ID
all your people but could I in the
meantime get a little extra money while
doing it probably not I think they'd
probably just step up security if that
happened but I I kind of like to think
viciously and and that's the most
vicious thing I could think of with RFID
badges I do want to talk about some
solutions because badges some patches
are very hard to clone and some badges
are as of yet not able to be cloned so
the CIO's corporate 1000 badge from hid
these are very good badges they are
exclusively from hid I don't believe you
can buy them anywhere else somebody may
have to correct me if I'm wrong we have
clients with these so they were not
interested in our RFID ideas our our
badge reader ideas but they were more
interested in the cloner or I'm sorry
the the implants that go behind the the
reader
because that protocol from the reader to
the controller is essentially plain text
and anyone can read it so they were more
interested in that so now you have a
secure card but you have an insecure
reader so I just want to point out that
there are secure cards but sometimes the
reader is the weakest link
[Music]
again I this is just talking about the
CEOs corporate card and the fact that
hid is the only person who is an
authorized seller of them you have to
apply for these cards they don't just
let any Joe Schmo off the reservation
buy them they actually bet you for these
cards and then yeah so researchers I
think have had a hard time getting their
hands on you know spare equipment and
things like that but I'm sure it's
available somewhere on eBay if somebody
who looked hard enough it's also a
proprietary format and this has not
served HID well in the past so I would
implore them to get that publicly
inspected so that other people might
find the chinks in the armor the holes
that that may exist in it and so they
can get them patched
I want to talk about some of the
competitors that they have because
they're not the only game in the market
but they're the one I run into the most
and dala AGC asset al boy has bought
door makers lock lock makers badge
makers if you want to get in the
physical access control a game alsa a
boy will buy you your mileage may vary
Johnson Controls Honeywell Vanderbilt
open path and Kesey I'm running a little
short on time so I'm just going to talk
about open path I think with these
slides because it's something we've been
evaluating and they took into
consideration most of the security and
problems that have plagued RFID readers
in the past so the pros you know
encrypted from the reader to the
controller and from the from the
the badge to that the reader itself so
they have encryption all the way through
which is where you want to be they
integrate with everything you can
schedule the locking and all this great
stuff they're pretty cheap as well so
our client has been evaluating them for
about a month and I think they're going
to go with them over some of the others
but there are some good alternatives
Kesey is another one that is on par
photo IDs are something that so that
this technology works with your phone so
you had the phone in your pocket you
actually go up and touch the reader just
with your hand just to let it know
you're present and then the phone sends
the signal I'm sorry the reader sends a
signal to the phone the phone replies
you're either led in or you're not some
places like to have the old-school badge
on on a person or a picture ID and and
won't be satisfied just with a phone in
your pocket if you were issuing phones
to your employees that might get
expensive when they lose their their
badge so I think that that might be a
con most people have a phone I think so
you might have to buy phones for people
if that's gonna be your only badge I
don't trust the cloud it's actually
hosting I don't know if anybody's aware
but that's just hosting and lockdown can
be enabled by anyone's this is where you
suspect something is happening at the
building and you push a panic button on
your phone and it seems like anyone in
the the organization who has the the app
can can do that so maybe you get a panic
situation or someone sitting on the the
phone or your kid and doing it while
you're at home who knows your cat walks
across your phone you know you know how
it is some access control alternative so
it's not just RFID that's out there
there's actually QR codes or laser laser
you know reading the QR codes with your
with an app so you show your phone to
the the UPC you know the scanner and it
reads your phone and you off you go you
can print out these visitor badges I've
been to a few places that have them
this was the name I was going by when I
when I visited there and that's what I
put up there and so it was effective I
wouldn't say it's great and again the
the I'm not sure how long these these
live or if they're one-time use kind of
kind of things I haven't investigated
them exactly fully deviant olam I want
to give him a shout out he talks about
door fitment and the way things should
fit properly on the doors there's a lot
of lock-picking I'm sure we've all seen
it they can go over the door they can go
under the door RFID is gonna be the last
thing on your mind if you watch this
man's talk he he gets into buildings
like nobody's business did anybody see
when Dave Kennedy blew the vape smoke
through the doors and then there's a
little sensor at the top and a little
exit sensor that goes off and he pushes
the doors open into a big cloud of smoke
you know what thinking back on it I
should have put it right up here so
tonight yeah so it's it's
well-documented again francis brown's
tastic our ID thief rfid gimme are two
good talks by him I cannot say some of
these other names
jaesik so this guy understands rfid on a
level that I could never hope to and he
he talks about all the pain points all
the problems that they've had with RFID
in the past and he really addresses them
well he even brought up something I
never knew about was there's a crime
scene card for hotels so if you go up to
a hotel something happens to the hotel
the police have a crime scene card that
will disable the reader for I don't know
how long but nobody can get in and are
out even the hotel staff you know unless
you have this crime scene card so it
basically locks down it seems like a bad
idea if somebody were ever to figure out
that crime scene card it may just be the
same key over and over I'm not 100% sure
but you could probably just run down the
hallway and crime scene card the whole
thing
and then the police I have to show up to
undo it right so maybe you can threaten
the hotel with I'll crime scene card
your your hallways if you don't give me
some money or the honeymoon suite
whatever
so for mold-making and the things that
we we took on and the things we didn't
know how to do YouTube was a great
inspiration or you know helped us
understand what we're gonna do and
that's why some of those turned out so
crappy and when you come outside and and
and see you'll you'll see how crappy
they are in real life actually but they
fooled people left and right it was
amazing we did we expected to get caught
and we weren't chris hag natty does a
lot of social engineering and it kind of
inspired my security guard idea and my
my call box idea that we haven't done
yet but I wish I wish we could have so
basically that that's the talk come see
me for your touch and feel session and
then you can also see the devices I've
made so I'm ready for questions and
answers if anybody wants one yeah sure
have I dealt with personal
identification I did I'm sorry
personal identity identification I don't
think I have
cat carts no I have not been up on that
this is more I guess the generic like
private sector kind of stuff yeah anyone
else sure sure yeah so obviously you
could use them the you know so the
question was could you use the badges
just for a pen test and absolutely you
could definitely do that and that's kind
of the point of why we started it right
if you catch the right person maybe put
them on after hours and maybe the
cleaning staff shows up late at night
and maybe you get the cleaning staff
you're more prone to get the cleaning
staff at that point maybe and the
cleaning staff usually has access to
about everything
anybody else it's going once going twice
yes have I tried the brute-forcing of
identities yes so we have clone cards we
have done the brute-forcing we've used
the Wi-Fi to land the bleakie there they
make everything so much simpler and
again very smart people put those
together I just AM standing on the
shoulders of those giants yep
right so maybe replay the card over and
over now I this software does not so the
software can trigger when there's a the
same badge one after the other but I
think that I don't know where that lies
but I know there are organizations where
if you give you know you badge you hand
it to your buddy behind you and they
badge then it's locked out so for two
minutes for that badge other badges can
can read through I'm not sure where the
logic lies in that but yeah that that's
a good question all right well thank you
guys
[Applause]