ten gig IDs anybody ever try to do this
whoo all right first of all what are we
doing here
but a focus on performance so not not
necessarily outputs the visualizations
integrations or rules just trying to get
our performance up above this this old
but theoretical 50 megabit per core
limit anybody who's tried it probably
knows yes you you can jump past this but
and in this talk we'll try and get focus
on the big knobs um simply because it's
a stable talk and they said get to get
you started here because packet sniffing
is fun I give you excuses for doing yr
sniffing you know the who is it strand
and and and then we'll say all the
packet or the wire doesn't lie that's an
excuse I love sniffing packets I've
always loved sniffing packets I'll use
any excuse to do so and then also you
know things you can get from this
obviously running a signature based
detection flow data can come out of of
sericata pretty easily so your DNS and
your your cert and foe say even if we're
getting in the point where it's more TLS
in encrypted data we can still extract
value out of out of doing this I'm also
not going to to cover the brover snort
verse sericata conversation or Linux and
BSD why worried over a few missed
packets this I actually found surprising
when I started doing this um I was
watching Eric I'm not gonna try to say
his name he's one of the main thefts for
for sericata and he was giving a
presentation that dev I was watching for
the xdp part of it and he took a peek at
sabotage did a little bit to try and get
these results and it was kind of
surprising to see this this 10%
missed alerts on just 3% so it does
become a big deal quick my observed drop
rate was 9% with just 1.5 5% packet loss
again he mangled the the P caps that he
was running for mine I just destroyed
the sensor and sent it well above
capacity to force these drops get out
the lab codes be scientific about this
honestly I should have made this slide
before I even started the whole
scientific method don't don't wing it be
very measured in your approach you
you'll make Mis assumptions very very
easily a couple years ago I was first
doing this I thought oh geez jackpot I
found a couple settings I play with
these I get awesome performance all I
was doing was relying on buffer to
account for for a packet burst in a
sustained environment you quickly find
out no you cannot rely on memory to to
save you
buffers will fill you will start
dropping packets and once you force
yourself into this packet drop scenarios
you're you're really hurting your
performance and it's hard to recover
from I figure out what you want to
measure and how I did not use perf in
this case just because I didn't want to
get back into watching what the CPU was
doing but if you're going hard or
definitely look into that I focused on
packet drops most of my stats will be in
in bandwidth rather than the more
appropriate packets per second and then
the amount of alerts generated off of
off the test because ultimately that's
truly what the deliverable is you're
trying to get alerts into a sim so
people can review it and take action
and then part of them one another
mistake I made which I'm trying to head
you off on is think about what you want
to measure first so you don't have to
retest because that kind of sucks in one
of the things I failed to measure
memory consumption so I could at the end
I'm like all sweet let's throw some
memory utilizations and show you which
settings really impact memory and I did
did not have time to retest all that for
you resources this is probably the most
critical slide for anyone who actually
wants to pursue this start here start
good especially you know obviously
you're gonna have to do the sericata
documentation start there that'll get
you a good feel then go to the next
arakata extreme performance and tuning
there's two guides one and two it
consolidated a lot of the research that
I had already done into one place and
they had better explanations for what I
had found in other places and and the
explanations were specific to what we're
trying to do one of the big mistakes I
made here was with the sea states on the
processor they I disabled all the power
saving stuff the call that out no you
actually want to in key power saving
states available somewhat because you'll
over a call me as you you need to take
advantage of turbo mode on your cores
and if you're all your cores are running
hot and you won't actually be able to
get the core is going in the turbo mode
and so build a good theory for what you
want to do first before he starts
spending money on a box alright so this
slide is I'll explain quickly this is
actually I don't know if you read that
command at the bottom the LS top oh it's
a top its topology view of your of your
hardware especially around the big boxes
are the the CPUs which is going to be
your focal point this will help you make
decisions on where you want what
processes to run obviously these are two
very very small boxes and then I
it out where I'm using the Intel x5 29
capture cards here I'll jump to a bigger
one this is a much much bigger box this
is actually screenshot is cut off
there's no device huh the small box is
going down those are the devices that
are associated strictly to the to that
CPU what's hanging off on the other side
is just the rest of the CPU and then
here's a another big boy this one
actually had a mirror come in it ran ran
quite well force which surprising when
you look at we were reading through the
documentation you will want to to
actually test the theories one of the
big contradictions I found was Nick quit
it was hyper-threading there there you
getting into argument about whether or
not you should use hyper threading on in
this application because it's eerie they
could fight with each other but your
results aren't consistent this box loved
it hyper threaded a burn every core and
everything runs great this box
no only runs single cord or a single
thread autumn the the performance was it
was a remarkable impact on performance
so that's why again don't run with
assumptions start testing these to your
hardware and your then the settings
themselves let me see
oh and I also tried on this one a lot of
times I'll I'll increase the buffer
sizes this was one of the only ones
where it actually hurt horribly
increasing a peak at buffer that because
it's a mere comet instead of AF pack and
use PP cap increase the buffer size on
this one destroyed performance so let's
start building up what we'll do
isolate your cores first this is the
primary box I used here was a a core box
now no
I did not get 10 gig on an eight-core
box but I would wanted to prove that I
could get a gigabit per core so that you
could easily scale up if so if you when
you have access to this tube larger
boxes you're easily reaching for for a
10 core and you'll see the all the
different settings in here a lot of this
is all called out in the documentation
especially on sericata tuning odd but
yes that sea state setting setting them
to 3 I did that wrong but the critical
ones here are the isolate CPU you're
telling the task scheduler don't put
anything else on those cores so we'll
leave core 0 that's normal stuff you
know Linux you're going to need your
cell running you have to leave one for
in that state from there surprisingly
spend a lot of time here don't really
pay attention these are just settings
that were randomly used I can give you
the full ones how I was doing this I had
I would set up or configure the the
driver based and just have a shell
script run all the commands for this
configuration run all the commands for
for that configuration for my testing
most primarily using AF packet and
another set up using the extended
Berkeley packet filters and a next EP
they utilize the receive size scale and
completely different with AF packet you
want one processor processing all the
interrupts from the card and let it bear
that brunt while the other cores are
working processing the packets as they
come in for the xdp configuration they
want you to spread it out get that
workload distributed and if you're going
to do that xdp route the two on the
bottom are the board ones that's going
to actually enable what you the the the
driver to do the interaction or sericata
to you interact with the driver and the
method needed and then the other thing
is overriding the default hashing key
come
by default our Microsoft developed RSS 4
for web servers which is completely
different application your when it's
with an IDs you need the complete flow
bi-directionally going to the same core
with a web server you can spread that
out that will not help here we need it
bound to the same core and that will
help account for this by default our SSO
will break you next look at what
sericata is built to do this is less
important today but a few years ago that
critical go the jail stop was not in
there and a lot of default packages you
really really need to have hyper scan
that was the single biggest benefit you
could get across the board but hyper
scan requires sse3 that which is an
intel command minor was it micro kind of
camera blinking outlets or instruction
set and then AMD came along in 2001
adding it again I'm using AF packet for
the Intel cards B cap for the mirror
comes and then my supposed saving grace
for another issue we run into is the
extended Birkett berkeley packet filters
and XDP now I get to find out who was
paying attention to the last slide I
know everybody wants to know what you
can do with a PI but anybody gonna tell
me why this ain't gonna work
winner winner correctly arms do not have
the required instruction set but I tried
it anyhow with a brand-new PI 4 with 4
gigs I had to move it
that was really warm so I put the IR
probe on that's a hundred and fifty two
degrees on the surface of that board so
I quickly said how do we check the
internal temp yeah we got 84 degrees the
PI's max is 85 Celsius so here's what
happened pushing the gigabit to it it
did not take it would not receive a
gigabit it maxed when it was cold at 723
as the tempers the packets per second it
would ingest we started dropping
considerably yeah the results were awful
and and the PI suffered little so yeah
in a small small workout breakout this
will work fine in your house like not
pushing packets yes at home it works
that but 100 Meg watching your internet
traffic for this for real now here's a
lot of the critical settings inside of
the sericata config that I found the
most beneficial AF packets there's we're
running eight core so I went ahead with
seven keep that in mind these numbers
were specific to my box
you take these numbers and change them
adjust them up and down some of these
numbers I have here completely
contradict the documentation
specifically that max pending packets
they want you to have it low
some of them I've put it as high as
possible the detect profiles I that
that's very consistent going with 200
groups there and then on the right side
coming down that's how you set up the CP
to see for the core isolation and the
xdp config that's another thing to note
here the documentation does not match
this but this works what's in the
documentation doesn't another possible
consideration we could do here would be
using the Burke just not not extended
Berkeley packet filters with a regular
Berkeley packet filters in excluding
traffic on the command line is for Sarah
it took me a while to get to the point
where this would be beneficial because I
was dropping packets earlier on you
could also do a pass role in sericata
too to just make a match and jump but
you're you're you're hurting yourself
because you want to get rid of the
packets as early as possible now let's
get to some results here my this might
actually be the third box we did the
first one didn't have the ssse3
instruction set which is how I found
that out the hard way this is the
smallest box I had that that was
successful with the hyper scan this is a
crappy Celeron box and yeah once we make
a few small adjustments here it starts
doing it pretty well and there you can
call out the the difference with having
hyper scan and veil available leaving
that having that not available to the
engine I'm dropping 33% enabling it it
goes 0 at at one gigabit so that's why
I'm giving you a full stop get hyper
scan going this is where I did the most
of the testing I did it with a couple of
different ways I was I've intentionally
I was instead of doing live peak apps or
coming off the live wire the problem
with doing that you'll start making
assumptions based on your traffic flow
different times a day you get different
traffic I was using peak apps being
pushed with TCP relay so I could get the
same consistent push and use that to
either throttle up throttle down the
traffic and then also to keep my
expected alerts consistent so I know how
many alerts I'm dropping started off at
one gigabit wait hang on oh I'm sorry
and I intentionally used one of the peak
apps was intentional to cause an issue
your biggest problem with doing this is
going to be an elephant flow so getting
a single flow that's over 500 megabit
that's what's gonna hurt you you do you
turn these cranks you will easily be
able to handle ten gig worth of traffic
except for that elephant flow and that's
that's what I was working in this eight
core box I could not get it below three
and a half percent but this was on older
desktop this was not a true server um is
the documentation will lead you astray
with the Intel cards they will say don't
use the drivers from Intel it won't work
you have to use currently you have to
use the Intel drivers
and then also I ended up when they both
go through these quits so you can see
with hyper scan going on oh and and you
also cranked up I cranked up the loops
for my testing because I made a bad
assumption early on I was pushing the
peak apps but I wasn't filling the
buffers so in production you want to
have buffers to to safeguard from
dropping packets when you're testing
unless you want to really drag out how
long you want to - to run your tests you
need to keep your buffers as slow as low
as reasonable so yeah I did a happy
dance pushed six gigabit yay didn't drop
a packet then realize nope everything
was in the ring buffer a few of these
tests I would stop TC TCP really it
would be done after five minutes of
traffic but sericata is still burning on
two cores because it's playing catch-up
processing with the ring buffers that's
cool if you want to just show off but if
you're going to sustain at ten gig you
cannot rely on memory and then I
eventually dropped started dropping how
many cores I was using this
configuration I ended up getting using
one for work one worker one completely
idle and I was still and then well six
I'm sorry one for management one one
idle and six actual doing workers to
give me
the one gigabit per core that worked
fine however when I cut it to five cores
actually working
I started dropping packets again so even
on this desktop quality hardware I'm
still processing one gigabit of traffic
without drops now the last part was the
disappointing the XDP versus not next EP
xdp and the BPF is supposed to drop the
the flows even earlier so you start
watching the flow you get to the Signet
normal signature depth you're not going
to have a match so go ahead and just
start dropping that Pat that that flow
and don't try and get it down if you get
the right card and doing the firmware
otherwise you're doing a driver laughs I
really thought this was going to be the
Silver Bullet yay at the end of the
presentation this old this will answer
all our hopes and prayers it did not it
actually performed worse unexpectedly
yeah with xdp now the statistically from
the alert standpoint because of the peak
apps I used the number of lurch
generated was the same but the the flows
that were being dropped were later in in
the the peak apps but if you look at the
actual drop rate of packets I'm running
over four and a half which is getting
getting too high mera kaam if you're
going to use a capture card you must
recompile the mirror comes against the
sniffer library for one two don't follow
the documentation snap this this worked
what didn't what they lead you to do in
the documentation to configure it does
not and then on a later Debian system
with with system D this is where I chose
to put in the Lib system DS systems
sericata service file to get and
basically you need to pass environmental
variables into the process when starting
up to configure it and my data ring size
if you go by the documentation there
that's completely contradicts what the
documentation says again
just these settings test them for your
hardware and your environment because
your traffic flows will make all the
difference in the world and you have an
H top screenshot there that is I think
that was taken at eight gigabit so of
live live traffic and yes this is the
one that does not like the
hyper-threading but it's it's processing
no I don't want any questions questions
sorry for doing this is a stable talk
this really could have been full length
talk for every Derby con but we ran out
of Derby Con before I got started come
on somebody's got to call me out on
something here there's a lot of room yes
Mick surprisingly no on you getting the
current of the for Colonel tree I'd
found it not necessarily using the the
Debian in straight up you you do an app
get install sericata even and you can
get a good ways up this tree but make
sure your but if you do this a few
Debian built our versions ago no
absolutely not compile your kernel you
have to compile sericata because you
won't you won't have hyper scan anything
else not saying that the kernel compile
one couldn't possibly yes sir
[Music]
I was using TCP relay to to replay pcaps
for this that was that was my primer
because that like said I wanted to be
the same repeatable test otherwise again
I made that mistake before by by not
really controlling the packet flow and I
made bad assumptions one of the big bad
assumptions you can make is yeah
everything works in the afternoon will
it work in the morning when the users
all logged in that actually did work out
it was fine
where I got hurt was in the middle of
the night what happens in the middle of
the night on a network guess what a
backup counts as that's where I started
learning about these alleged elephant
flows that are the bane of your
existence yes yes but you want to try
and keep up with scans especially
because a lot of them seem to be short
and sleep but either way I already got
the stop sign so if you want to keep
talking we will talk outside
[Applause]