[Music]
[Applause]
hi everyone foreign Guardians on the
head of my team operations and also
senior security consultant I've been
specializing now for a few years in red
teaming and investing previously I used
to work with in health care and
financial industries and too many
circuits there the list but feel free
[Music]
so why am i doing this talk a little
over a year ago I will just working on a
pen test thinnest Network segment where
I only had four four four five I was
able to do some those sessions on the DC
couple the users for the domain and I
actually only account I recovered was a
backup operators account which had
backed up operations so that's how I got
to where I was once I actually got there
what I did is I actually planned set up
my own lab i simulating the same thing
to figure out how I could use the backup
operators account to do some damage
against the domain controller what I
could do
so a little bit of history for my
experience most organizations usually
have at least one account backup
operators if not more I've seen as many
as twenty or thirty and when I ask why
no usually it accounts been around for
quite some time and password usually
haven't gotten changed since the account
actually activated scene accounts get
migrated from one backup solution to
another no password changed everything
still around sometimes even the old
banking system so number of systems
across that entire domain not just it's
a little bit of history of directory and
backup operators can override security
restrictions on vials for backing up and
restoring files something you need to do
some of the things you can't do what I
was trying to do was actually that sort
of the basis of this talk that I was
trying to do everything over the network
without physically going to machine if I
could so don't have remote desktop
access with a little over the back of
operator count no local admin
permissions on the system and you can't
launch processes from over the net so I
sort of stuck at this point thank you a
lot to do anything else so I went and
start digging in for what I was allowed
to do you can log on loosely at the
console if you're lovely of the system
log on it's batch job on the system shut
it down where you can backup for files
and directories honestly that's what
things are getting a little and from a
high integrity session the command
prompt you can pack files from the
system I started the band prompted and
you running as with men only do it from
across the network nice and says login
as another user and you can either copy
single files from domain controller
using robocopy and the /b flag there is
what's important that book it actually
gives you the back you can also copy
entire directory slash evil also copy
directories they don't actually have any
files in there you can do slash s but
popular empty folders on the version
system
so little video here
[Music]
and start up a command prompt now I'm
gonna use the backup right there oMG
backup be that easy we're now running
across the network through the back so
now I'm actually going to use robocopy
to go on top T now policy from one of
the domain controllers put in the path
you can't also put in the domain name
there and copy from it I was working in
just on targeting the one domain
controller to see how things replicated
when I was doing this so you can put in
there just /b u slash Messier and then
copies down everything from doing
[Music]
[Applause]
don't know exactly from high integrity
shell you will not get that air so even
if you're running it past the back of
the count low of medium integrity
session you will get that error I think
it's the way it's processed people only
on the client that you're on
[Music]
to restore files it's as easy as just
changing the source and destination
restoring the GBC ini file and in fact
[Music]
Microsoft made by default has the same
good wood for default of a controller
unless this is change which I have not
seen it or basic issue yet that's
changed it for the default domain
controllers this will always be the do
it within the directory seen below out
the group policy configuration files for
everything in effect policy are stored
within that floor you can go and take a
look dr. wood you'll see they separate
do it for every GPO that there is within
the domain
I've been started to actually go on my
tests to pull down policy from the
entire organization and then take your
offline and edit what this file does
pains all the permissions that you have
the various different accounts right
here this is from the default domain
controller group policy have to take a
look as we discussed earlier the
operators account NZ five five month and
we have not got privileges the ability
to log on the ability to log on
interactively restore files and shut
down the system this is the default
[Music]
one thing to note is the suit will
always have portion specific to the
domain and then the actual user 1:09
either the user specific this is this
can become
[Music]
once I was done 2016 so it's actually
when those 10 points we're throwing
errors that have the same first number
that I was putting in the GPT in her at
the GTI and I
[Music]
probably took about 30 minutes or so for
the domain controller to update access
[Music]
restricted system you want to get access
to something far away we can actually
[Music]
applied to that system so that you know
what GPO is going to take a look at back
to directory we also need to know the
city account that we want to use so I
was hours looking to go to the ing bleep
and that is a member of the finance
station and it gives us it's gonna team
that do it as well where this is fervor
that growls here
just using get domain user again here
from Power View together with the City
of Calgary
[Music]
so now I'm gonna go this is the default
see here that we have Sid of the local
administrators account what I'm gonna do
is go and hand our accountant we want to
add to this now I tried thickness
initially and doing like I was doing on
the domain controllers taking the user
account Sid and then they get a member
of local administrators account and that
was failing on the end who's treating
infest this account the SID of the user
account as he so hot the works issued
after the proofs it first and then put
the sitter
[Music]
once that was not this is the policy so
take a look we have just administrator
ing station
once group policy updated on the system
so now we do whatever we want on the
system we have that been accessed to any
of this
so doing this up you can end up
generating a good amount of noise in
administrators and the machine that has
policy object lights get pretty noisy
and alerts all the sudden there's this
trigger on all these systems
[Music]
[Applause]
problems you this is now want something
done with that can be smart effects left
them yet we will stay so there's some
manual
let's start talking about that something
that can be enabled look what it's gonna
be different on every domain I haven't
run into that are the same yet actually
locks Lisa's just long successful some
lock failures so luckily for us we can
easily go and think look it let's
actually figured brought it into the
domain it's stored in the CSV file so if
you take a look here we can see audit
directory service access for success and
failure down there first bottom
this is I just want to check all the
boxes for everything in 8d in my lab to
turn on auditing for everything and
you'll see they give it up to talk it's
the same give it as earlier from leave
all the week
so I'd recommend if you're going to do
this little copy that file down go
through it everyone in the domain read
it and pull it down this is really
geared about to the settings the
detailed file share auditing and the
directory server status the detailed
files you're auditing the lot all file
share access on the system this is the
link of every system in the domain is
going to be going and flowing down
through policy whatever really moves
here every 90 minutes it's going to
generate a lot of laws so successive
failures enabled directory service
changes that block any changes to groups
or users within Active Directory
and if it's large domain there's gonna
be a lot of hogs there on a daily basis
so let's just go back to for second all
the settings are controlled by a CSP
active operators
that's disabled of audit so I literally
just my name we'll leave it at all
[Music]
so I restored the vial main controller
actually updated replicated this fairly
quickly because I'll show you changed
replicate that constantly and I went in
through the GUI and it shows that none
of the so everything is off
and he respects the changes we made
okay so now we've turned off Group
Policy also stores lot of registry
settings in the registry not all times
this contains both user settings in
computer settings
[Music]
you can't just pull out all the settings
that are in there
so we can use this get out the Machine
settings and the user settings and pull
them down a little bit different format
that you see going in through regedit
[Music]
these are from my lab one so now that we
have it sub wooden a power so one liner
straight there to go and run whatever
use your lock once I added that I just
combined both blue machine and the user
settings to single file and once that's
done I'll GPO that Exe it also allows us
to generate the new registry at Pala
file so I use that
[Music]
this was previous to the actually run
key getting cooled down if you look down
at the bottom there we only have two of
the settings are to run keys within HP
for security health in VMware once group
policy refreshed on the machine and a
user logged in I got a show now keep in
mind this will generate a shell if you
go this way for every user in that oh
you when they log into the sheet so once
that was actually on the machine but
look just make sure the registry key was
there and it's there also did learn what
going and removing these that registry
keys even though you may have restored
reduce registry dot all file is still
attached on the endpoints will stay
there
[Music]
my jackets but it's something you can
actually give and this is a way that you
can use policy you can use some of the
previous techniques that I just went
over to go and actually get at been on
one system that you're looking for drop
a dll on that system move certain paths
and then modify policy to do that for
that pop hijack whatever you're going
after there and when policy processes
registry that Paulo file it'll be there
and only if that ellos on the disk for
that machine will actually pop up
effective so it's weighted toward some
specific users within the domain now
there's also a lot of third-party
plugins Centrify is one that I've seen
wasn't able to get a copy for my lab so
I don't have screenshots of it but it
those we're all good settings and
registry Dabhol files that configures
little admins for Mac's as well as
whether SSH is enabled in a number of
other service lumens so you can actually
use the same technique to go and change
all the settings for Mac's
there's a number of other third-party
plugins out there as well that extend
Active Directory I haven't gotten played
with Lachlan so see what's out there
I did actually enable SSH on some end
points and then get little ended up on
those systems using the reversionary
down
[Music]
now I didn't go into too much depth here
but I just copied all those files
locally I modified them I wasn't trying
to be steeped in every sport my
concerted time stopping them match the
original last time for those files when
I pull them down from the domain
controller then restore them there
I just want to stress restore the
originals half here though
some other things I tried was trying to
do and failed I was trying to pull copy
[Music]
would have been great to be able to pull
that down to get all the user hashes but
did not work there's also you can use
some other third wording programs that
are going to be installed will actually
pull it down get a copy of that I wanted
to try and edit that file and there's
not much out there to actually edit
incorrectly and when you go to the store
it's gonna be locked
now some little be there clean it up
registry entries need to remain you may
want to actually go and just modify
their registry so that it on the systems
it doesn't will actually run and group
policy will accept all our changes as
you saw before they act correctly otter
day when I restored that file back to
see that
[Music]
but should it be pocketed during regular
business hours or should it just be
logging in backups
some other things you can do for
detection hot typically an account yeah
buddy
4728 reading in 3d account luckily for
us when you had GPL INF file it's not
generate a login on the domain
controller so you can actually push that
out this is from the puck detailed files
your honor and it will actually take a
note here that we wrote data to the
audit none CSV that's one take a walk if
that happens outside the bank policy
updates and some of these modifying
policies are over the network should
probably just becoming the main holders
themselves but they do requirements use
their editing group policy on that
sinking in DC not sure how that look up
so that's something take a look at
[Music]
now one screw policy does update this it
will act correctly auditing it does lock
that audit policies were changed further
than me
and go in if you open up the log files
it will tell you whether it was changed
to audit successful failure a lot of
success or if it's now disabled but we
have had
[Music]
we're learning unanimity 5135 followed
by 57:19 this would be a fairly good way
to know that it was modified that policy
was changed to alert on the faculty role
fact controller in the policy settings
actually we're changing the system Walt
auditing settings are disabled to figure
out what was actually changed none of
your domain controller turned off
auditing no longer tracking any changes
you can start adding users created users
[Music]
what she just got the attractor of your
users in theaters what was missing you
can actually collectively and probably
not get noticed any changes in that way
you recommend file integrity monitoring
on the system would actually and you
would alert in miles have got cheese on
the domain controller and that's all
that you could trend over time watching
see what not change when luggage change
from a regular basis that maybe just
configure it will give the sysvol
directory
what is this beautiful there are number
of miles on the main controller related
to that small version of all those miles
I can find the way to go and get it
keep it what's out there you go through
all those miles and see what there is is
that by modifying a lot of these systems
through the file system in restoring the
vials was not able to blog a lot and by
the fury of the logging that was in
place
[Music]
some conclusions that I had monitoring
your back we're logging on outside the
regular back of the windows I'm making
changes to the file system that they
should just be back
that block any files on your domain
controllers highly recommend click on
file integrity monitoring so that you
have that in place and any of those
changes that are not expected in file
changes and little the afternoon under
DC go things with that change but he's
going to be able to see maybe
historically keep at backup what it
looks like before what it looks like now
it's you know wait
other than that let's figure out if
anyone has any questions one of HIV
[Music]