okay cool all right everybody welcome to
my talk waking up the data engineering
you so I'm Jared Atkinson a quick bio so
I don't have much time but I'm the
technical director at adversary
detection inspector ops do a lot of
PowerShell developments I'm really good
at minesweeper on Windows little school
game 56 seconds on expert if anybody
wants to challenge me is my record used
to be an air force that kind of thing so
what I'm planning on talking about today
is a specter ops one of the things that
we get to do is teach teach training
classes and one of the training classes
that I'm involved in really focuses on
detection engineering right so how do
you how do you build robust detections
to focus on technique level attacks as
opposed to very very naive detections
that would focus on things like hashes
URLs that type of thing so how do we
build really robust detection in in our
experience as instructors oftentimes
students students teach us as much as
we're teaching them right and so we get
to learn learn from kind of different
things that they're trying that we had
never considered and so through the
through the process of this talk I hope
to kind of like share with you some of
the things that I learned and how how
like that student instructor
relationship really helps to kind of
inform some of the detection engineering
efforts that we do and kind of reinforce
the idea of how you can leverage an
understanding of data the data or
telemetry that you're collecting to
really understand better ways of
building detections okay so just kind of
set the stage of tell a story about this
interaction with a student and I'm going
to talk about some strategies that you
can use to to kind of build on it right
so in the class one of the things that
we do is we talk about you know how do
you select the different attack
technique that you're that you're
focusing on to build intersection so
you're building a hypothesis which says
I think that the attacker is going to do
X attack technique right and so I'm
going to build a detection for that so
one of the ways that we present to the
students is to use threat intelligence
right and so this is just a snippet from
a threat intelligence report Katie Katie
Nichols from mitre
she wrote a blog post that's referenced
down there at the bottom and this is
this is taken from that right and so
just to kind of show an example we see
that there's a lot of
formation here we see for instance four
one one three PDB we see that there's
SCH taps with the command line we see
cmd.exe slash see who am i a lot of
times we find that students or clients
or just people in general and better
ability detections focus on those very
like specific details when they're
building detections right so like maybe
I want to look for sch tests being run
with like slash creator in the command
line or something like that or maybe I
want to look for this bad IP address 191
five seven one nine eight one or three
right or these specific ports one one
nine one three right so we see people
that are building those but ultimately
what we want to do is we want to treat
this as a narrative that's just giving
us concepts right and so what Katie does
in her blog post is she really like kind
of builds out and says you should read
this narrative and as you're reading and
say how does this relate to different
attack techniques right so I assume most
people are familiar with the mitre
attack framework right so these
techniques that are being referenced are
all techniques from from attack
framework and so for instance instead of
SCH tasks let's look at it as you know
the schedule tasks technique right
because they're not limited to just
using SCH tasks that exceed a build to
create scheduled tasks they can they can
use PowerShell they could use a third
party binary they could do it they could
kind of do whatever they want right and
so we want to kind of get an
understanding of what techniques the
attackers will use it and then we want
to go from there okay so in our training
class we kind of have a similar
situation where we present them with a
fictional threat report they read
through it and then they pull out the
different techniques that they come with
come up with and so this is kind of an
eye chart on purpose but this is a tap
navigator which is just a way to that
might or is it provides to kind of
represent the different techniques and
so everything that's highlighted in
purple are what we expect the students
to be able to pull from that threat
report right and so in this case and
basically the reason why we really want
to focus on the threat report is because
the lab is recorded and we want them to
be looking for things that they're
probably going to find real bad stuff in
the lab right so this particular team
chose remote services as their as their
technique that they wanted to look up
and then they wanted to start building a
detection right so
the first thing that we like to do is
kind of point you to the attack
framework and say okay well you want to
look into remote services let's go see
what mitre says about that right so this
is just a a really good starting point
probably not comprehensive but it just
gets you an idea of what's going on and
so what they actually say is hey remote
services is used for lateral movement
and what it actually what they they say
it is is chapters Tucker's end up using
legitimate credentials to access these
services that are mentoring remote
administration things like ssh telnet I
guess
wmii or PC windows remote management
those types of things
attackers are just connecting to those
and being able to run some sort of task
on the remote system for lateral
movement right and so once you're as
you're reading through that what we want
the best kind of most overlooked
features of my air attack framework is
this data sources piece right and so
that's that's them giving you a hint of
maybe where to start right so you want
to detect remote services maybe the
place that you should start is looking
at authentication logs this is this
feature of the attack framework is not
like the most comprehensive or
full-featured but it's just a kind of a
good starting point so if I were to like
ask somebody hey I want to look at
Windows authentication logs can anybody
help me figure out like where's the
first place that you would think to look
Active Directory so okay so that's
that's kind of a thing that manages some
endpoint logs yes so like the Windows
Event log anybody know what you've meant
log is like the canonical for 6to4 yep
so 46 24 and so this again probably not
the easiest thing to see but 46:24 as an
account was successfully logged on and
so just walking through their process
right they said okay well we want to go
into Cubana which is where our data was
for the for the sixers exercise and we
want to look at 46 24 events right so
let's go ahead and check that out real
quick okay so this is this is what they
were presented with there's 1.1 million
events whether that's realistic to your
environments I don't know but just kind
of work with be the thought process here
and so what they what they did is they
decide to search for
even ID 46:24 and they came up with 3850
90 minutes in real environments with
clients that could be millions or you
know hundreds of millions different
events but even even so four thousand
events is not something that I'm going
to go through one by one and start
looking through it right that's still
too much for me to kind of go through
and authentication in and of itself is a
normal feature of like an operating
system right so that there's nothing
malicious here yet
and so what they did is they they start
looking around and you could kind of dig
into this and maybe somewhat difficult
to see but you can start to look at the
different fields that work that we have
right so one thing that they keyed in on
based on their their experience let me
find it here was this logon logon type
field anybody familiar with the logon
type yep so so the idea of logon type is
it tells you like what's the context of
that the logon happened in so like
there's interactive log ons which is
where you're interacting at the actual
like console right there's Network log
ons which is where you're doing a
connection over over the network remote
interactive log ons which would be like
RDP something long about lines and
there's quite a few different ones right
and so what they decided to look at was
where logon type equals three which is
that Network logon remember we're
thinking about remote services that kind
of leads us to think about network log
ons and so that's where they ended up
going so just to kind of reiterate we're
at about 3,800 3,900 different events
and they decide to log on type 3 to
their query and they went down to 3200
and they're like well you know that
doesn't really narrow it in all so like
you know just because somebody logs in
over the network doesn't mean that it's
necessarily bad right so like one
example of a benign Network logon event
would be when you mount to share from
like your share drive right so that's
that's not necessarily indicative of bad
behavior and so they're they're kind of
like okay well what's the what's the
next step well in the fictional scenario
that we provided them we said hey one
thing that we should be worried about is
that there's or that you should be aware
of as like a detection engineer within
your company this fictional company is
that every system has a shared vocal
admin accountant and that has the same
passwords right and it's called test
admin and so what
they did as they said okay at first we
were trying our focus of our detection
was to detect remote service abuse but
now like we can based on what we found
we want to kind of narrow and I'll focus
a little bit right and this is a really
good strategy a lot of times is say hey
I'm gonna make an assumption but I'm
going to document that for future
reference right and so their assumption
was now we want to look for the abuse of
the shared local admin password in
remote Services context right so they
they went forward and they specified hey
we want to see where you know logon
events are happening over the network
this logon type 3 and the user username
is test admin ok and so by doing that
they came up with 16 hits right and so
this was the point that the students
they kind of called me over as the
instructor and said hey like based on
what I've learned over the past three
days and my experience in this lab
environment I've identified that this is
bad right well I can't I can't explain
to you why why I got to where I got it
right like it like why is this bad like
I can't really explain that to you so
like I'm missing some sort of context
that allows me to definitively say this
is in fact bad right and so this is the
point at which I kind of told them like
we need to take a step back and start to
understand what the data is that we're
dealing with right so one of the things
this is where we're going to from like
we have detection engineering right
which is where you're building detection
in a robust manner you're documenting
those that type of thing and then we
have data engineering which is where
you're understanding the data or
telemetry that you have available to you
and how it interconnects and how it
relates to one another right so Windows
Event log there's hundreds or thousands
of events those different events can be
related to one another in different ways
and so what we what we did is we started
looking at one of the projects that one
of our former colleagues made called
OSEM and what he does is he goes through
and documents all the different data
that can be that can be ingested and so
this is Windows security events even ID
4624 just as an example and he comes
down and he starts to say you know hey
what's the description of this event and
this is really this is just a really
good practice in general so if you're
running a sock a lot of times we go to a
sock and we say hey what data do you
have and the analysts say I don't know
we have like Windows event logs and we
have you know Proofpoint logs and we
have system owned or whatever
and I'm like okay well like what windows
event logs do you have and they're like
no idea right and so what we what we try
to work with them on is like hey let's
let's actually start documenting this in
a very like intentional way and so what
we come down to is okay well we have 46
24 events here's kind of like an
understanding of what this is and this
really helps our junior analysts right
so like there's always a guy that knows
everything about everything and all the
data that you have but that person is
not sharing that information in a like
repeatable way with the entire team
right so we want to we want to raise the
bar of kind of like what's our most
junior person so that they have all the
information they need right so so we
come down we start saying what are the
different fields that this this even has
so there's like a subject user CID
target user CID there's a logon type
field right we saw that there's a
workstation name there's a logon good so
on and so forth and we're actually like
documenting the entire part of the
process right and kind of going through
we also have for instance we can go and
check out the Microsoft Microsoft has a
github page that kind of keeps track of
this as well and so they they go into
what does it look like in the XML format
that you would be receiving it at your
sim they also actually describe in
detail every single field that's in the
events right so we could start to
leverage that and understand and so to
go back let's say let's say you didn't
know what the logon type thing was right
and I talked about you come here and it
says hey logon type is a type of logon
that was performed here's a table that
tells you all the different types right
so type two is interactive user logged
onto the computer type three is network
so on and so forth right so you're able
to kind of like get into that and start
understanding it okay
all right so one of the things that we
as we're going through this that we we
identified trying to find it here okay
so we have the user logon ID and so what
that ends up being is this is kind of
like an understanding of Windows
internals a little bit but when you log
on to a system there's what's called a
logon session that's created right and
so every logon session has what they
call a locally unique identifier or Luud
and that represents that logon that's
like the identifier for that that logon
session 46:24 have that information and
what we could actually do if we've
documented all of this and all of this
stuff is we could take this name user
logon ID and we could actually search
through our repository and we can start
to see all the different events that
have user logon D four four seven nine
nine four six six two five three seven
seven and we could click into these and
you know start to learn more about them
I think an account was logged off for
six three four right and that has a user
logon ID and so what I told them was hey
we have these 16 events what happens if
we take the user logon ID that's
associated with it and we actually just
kind of search for that alright so again
we have oops not ite Qabbani of course
puts commas in the output but you can't
have that in the actual query and so we
end up having three hits right so these
are basically all the events that are
related to this user logon ID we have a
four six to four right so that's that
logon event we have a four six three
four which is a log off event and we
have a four six seven two which again we
would be able to come in here
search for four six seven two because
we've documented this data and then we
would be able to see what that is what
that ends up being a special privilege
was assigned which every logon is going
to have that event associated with it
okay
but we don't we don't see any additional
context that might be interesting you
may see that I have this command line
field highlighted over here so that
might kind of tip tip my hand at what
what I'm looking for but as we kind of
go through these and notice I'm doing it
very manually right now kind of on
purpose to demonstrate the point we run
that and we have a different event that
pops up for this specific logon session
right that's a four six eight eight
does anybody know two four six eight
eight is yeah process was created is the
name of it right so see if I see
anything that might be worrisome to them
if they were to come across this no yeah
of course in that gray vs. no yeah so
okay so
I mean the the most obvious one I think
is probably this powershell with an
encoded command maybe what I would do is
you know come down here I mean this is
what it really looks like right so I
don't know about you but I don't like to
type that in myself typically when I'm
answering systems but you could you
could go and decode this and go see
what's actually happening some other
things that you might look at or like
Who am I which is kind of something that
an attacker might use for situational
awareness to know what user they're
operating as they're doing some sort of
group enumeration domain group
enumeration for domain computers and so
that that's starting to look like
something that's suspicious right and so
then then we kind of like I only have
you know twenty five minutes so we're
not going to go through each one but
basically we went through all sixteen
and we said hey what context can we pull
from all of these right and so they said
hey that's that's really awesome like we
were able to document our data
understand the connections between these
different data points and then we were
able to start to like see at context the
problem is is like we did that manually
right and it was kind of a pain in the
butt when we did it for sixteen but like
in a real environment there may be
thousands or hundreds of thousands right
so I'm not going to do that kind of in a
manual way right so what we end up
having I'm going to go back to the
slides and skip a few we end up having a
situation like this where we end up
seeing a user authenticated to a host
we're building all these connections
that host had a process that received
that connection
it ends up spine in a process called WMI
prpsc
then there's this logon session that's
created and then a process and a
nondescript process we don't care what
that process is but we just care that
there's a process that's associated with
this type three logon session right and
so again we have this 46 24 one thing
that we really like to look at is this
concept of a force is like a Windows
Event log is really just a storytelling
device right so really like I look at it
as what can I get from this a lot of
times we look at it as a unique entity
like this is a 4624 but really there's
there's quite a few different concepts
that are really at play inside of the
46:24 right so this is kind of what i
end up look
so 46:24 I created data model Ford and I
kind of in my mind and so we have a
source computer right that well in
context of a type three logon event we
have a source computer it authenticates
to a target computer all right so that's
what's happening that target computer
creates a target logon session and then
that target logon session is running as
a target user so whatever user logged
onto that that destination or target
computer brings similarly we have a
forty six eighty eight and that tells us
a process process created a new process
to think of this is like the parent
process this is the child process or the
process that was being created those
processes are running on a computer we
have a subject user who is the basically
the parent the the user that was running
as the the parent parent process and
then we have that new process the child
process it's associated with a target
logon session and it's also running as a
target user right so that's that's the
context that this is telling us one
thing one problem is the 46:24 let me go
back up here that doesn't give me any
context about what that logon session
was doing right so like how do I
differentiate using just a 46:24 how do
I differentiate a it's somebody
connecting to a network share from
somebody that's running a PowerShell
encoded command rights or like you know
Who am I and doing a bunch of post
exploitation type stuff the the other
problem is for 4680 a that's just
telling me the context of a process so
how do i how do I actually like
differentiate between two - like our
process that was created as parts of a
type 3 logon session right so this is
where we were doing that manual process
to go back and forth and copying copying
that logon session ID right okay so yeah
so again was this logon session created
via Network logon well 46 88 doesn't
have that context and and one of the
things that we run into especially
within like Cabana for example is Cabana
is not super great at like relational
it's a document data elasticsearch is a
document database it's not real great at
like building relationships and allowing
us to query for those right so we're
able to look at 46:24 we're able to look
at 46 88 but it's relatively difficult
to
be able to look at both of those in the
same context to try to build build
relationships okay
and so what we end up with is trying to
build out this like greater model here
where we have a source computer that
authenticates to a target computer right
so we'll just say there's an IP address
called 1 9 2 1 6 8 1.5 it connects to a
system called target dot local target
all local it's connecting as domain /
attacker so domain is just the domain
name and attackers that the attacker
named and there's a logon ID of 1
through 37 and there's a logon type of
of type 3 right and so that's that's
kind of the extent of what I'm really
Glen from a 46 24 bench right so we have
a logon type 3 we have a logon ID we
have the user we might have the system
that they were being connected from but
then we also kind of like on the second
half of this this image we have 3
processes that were created and those 3
processes are getting information about
them or contexts develop them from 46 88
events and so for instance we have
PowerShell dot exe Who am I and net dot
exe which is what we just saw song
Cubana and those are being created but
they're also telling us hey these are
part of the 1 1 3 3 7 logon session
right so now I'm thinking okay well like
this is what the student was really
asking me it's like hey I did all this
manual stuff it's really awesome it's
kind of cool to be able to make those
connections I learned about logon
sessions and power and and processes
kind of residing within a logon session
but like how would I do this in
production like it like in real life I
can I can't just go one by one and check
each one because that's that you know we
don't have the manpower to do that and
so really what they were asking is how
do I add that context that logon type 3
to these process events spring and so
Roberto so what we're using here is as
anybody familiar with the health project
if so health is ELQ is elastic elastic
search log stash and kimono help is
basically a flavor of ELQ that's built
for threat hunting might use cases and
so one of the things that it has is an
apache spark back end which is just
allows for like distributed computing so
you could run a query across a number of
different notes and try to like increase
your computational performance
and it also has the ability to do
jupiter notebooks and so oh boy that
might not be good but we have the result
okay so let me zoom in here okay so this
is called jupiter notebook and this is
just a way for us to like kind of save
off different queries that we're making
so we could we can make a series of
queries and like kind of save that off
so that it could be repeatable and that
type of thing so there's this capability
called pi PI spark and there's spark
sequel that allows us to actually run
sequel queries across the data that's in
this elasticsearch database right so at
the beginning what we're doing here is
we're just kind of like setting up a
spark session which allows us to like do
that that distributed computational
workload and then we're going to
basically reach out to our elastic
search right here right and we're
basically trying to connect connect to
it right from there we have this this
index of the logs endpoint windows win
event security index which is where our
security event logs are stored in Cabana
let me just kind of show what that looks
like here so in Cabana you have a bunch
of different indices for instance we
have a system on index we have a Windows
security event index we have a
PowerShell event logs index system
system index so on and so forth you
could have like a network like a bro
index so on and so forth okay so we're
really only interested in this Windows
security events so then what we end up
having to do is kind of like basically a
spark to pull from that index the the
events or the data that we're interested
in right so we basically are saying hey
we want to select and so anybody
familiar with sequel should be somewhat
familiar with this but we want these
properties so even ID host name source
IP address user logon ID user name logon
type and timestamp from security events
right which is basically that all the
events that we pulled out where the
event ID is 46 24 so our logon event the
logon type is 3 so a network logon the
source IP address is not null so we want
to we want to be able to tell where that
event was coming from and then we just
have a timestamp to to narrow in on
specific data for
for the for the use case here okay so we
run that and that ends up giving us back
all those events right and then we then
we basically do the same thing for 46 88
we're interested in host name parent
process name parent process command line
process name process command line user
name user logon ID so on and so forth
where it's 46 88 here okay then we store
those kind of in a variable here and now
what we do is we actually do a join like
a sequel join across this these events
and we end up with user logon ID
basically where the user logon ID from
4624 is equal to the user logon ID from
46 88 and just to kind of show it's not
an instantaneous process here but this
goes this goes forward and it's actually
kind of like running running our query
on the backend okay maybe I might have
just messed everything before I did that
did everybody see it there was output
there okay good okay
all right let's see if this okay that's
a good sign so this will show how long
it actually takes just so that there's
okay so this is the part the part that
takes a little while for this doing that
kind of like correlation there and
basically what we're trying to output is
just show me every 46 an 88 event that
is spawned from a logon type 3 is that
that's the general idea right because we
want to see that now there when when
we're going through this process 846 88
event is not necessarily that spawn from
a logon type 3 is not necessarily bad
right so like a situation I could think
of as maybe you have you use Altiris or
some sort of other you know like system
management type tool or like
vulnerability assessment type tool and
it's it's going out and running these
remote commands on systems that's going
to be you know benign in this use case
or a false positive and so so you would
have to kind of like go through and
figure that out but what we
obscene and this is from a different
data set here but we see that this P
Gustavo user ended up spawning net dot
exe right or from net dot exe they spawn
con host and then they use net Med 1 dot
exe right so and then added a user
called backdoor with a password of PA w0
r d1 right so the funny thing is is this
is from the mordoor project and the
Mordo project is based on Roberta's dog
name is Pedro P Gustavo spot Pedro and
so Paul Paul is his dog's paw anyway so
that's that's generally the idea of how
we would go about doing this in an
automated fashion to be able to build
those correlations based on
understanding our data in the first
place cool that's all I have if anybody
has any questions I'll be outside
afterwards too to chat about