look at her bio has more four letter
acronyms that she's involved in leading
and guiding than I think anybody else I
know I always find out absolutely
fascinating to listen to and to talk to
and she's got a great title for the
morning after the conference dinner so
medica good morning everyone and yeah it
was very interesting when Andrew asked
me a year ago literally it was June of
last year whether or not I'd give a
keynote I was asking you know do you
mind I mean can I do it in the morning
the beginning of the week because I'm
heading off to the ICANN meeting in
Morocco
well he said absolutely no problem and
then what happened a couple months later
was I was asked to do the keynote at TNC
in Estonia I'm Estonian and so I pleaded
and very kindly asked can I do both and
he then slotted me today and little did
I know how appropriate the title would
be even for the day after the the social
so waking up the guards and it's kind of
interesting as I see people trickling in
it really reminds me of security I've
been doing security for about 25 years
networking for 30 and you know people
have slowly slowly trickled in and under
understood how important security is
right and I think in the last five years
it's gotten a lot of global attention
because things are just so bad so my
talk really is about looking at the
fundamentals that really we should never
lose sight of and that deals with also
protocols but because the criminals and
the nefarious actors are getting smarter
and smarter in terms of how these
protocols work together to stay under
the radar so in the beginning right
thirty years ago Trust was inherent and
as I gave my talk in Estonia
I had looked through my archives and I
had done a small part when Estonia was
first getting connected to the Internet
and I have email archives of that and I
was looking through the old emails I
mean I think one person here is Estonian
who can read this but basically what
this email has said was you know because
I was helping them said you know here's
a couple of addresses where you can log
into the devices because at times I was
asked to log in to check whether or not
they configured things correctly and so
it's interesting right this is an email
like here's username here's password
it's guest but oh if you can't use this
then here's other credentials that you
can use to get into the system now this
isn't just in Estonia right this was
1992 1993 I was also on the inner up NOC
team in 1991-92 and I had met some
people and I was working for the
National Institute of Health where I got
a phone call one day and they're like oh
your Medicare care you got FTDI working
on Cisco routers so I'm like why yes I
did because well we've ended to this
problem would you mind logging into our
routers so he gave me the enable
password I logged in and I said oh yeah
you gotta upgrade to this micro code and
then I'm like well what did I login to
this is 1992 the Apple backbone router
okay it was fat I was like that's kind
of cool all right in two years later I
met the guy who actually hadn't had
phoned me but I mean the the point that
I'm trying to make right when we were
first starting to do connectivity it was
the focus was on getting connectivity to
work right and when people say nobody
thought about security that's a fallacy
because you already had username
password but you had some basic access
controls you didn't have all of the
nefarious activity I mean nobody would
have ever thought how much crime and and
other nefarious activity is going on so
privacy and online safety wasn't yet a
big concern but you know there was a
little bit of thought there now roll
into today and we have a lot of blind
trust issues by protocol standards well
it's a protocol it sustained
right I mean it's gotta work correctly
right but nobody takes into
consideration is well what is the must
shoulds and maze right how how secure
they if you have a must use you know
encryption algorithm that maybe has you
know only forty bit ciphers i'm making
this up right now
right but you know like paul it's a
standard so it's fine and as an
implementer you're like well the
standard says i can't implement it's
okay i'm gonna do it and then when you
think about implementation guidelines
right i was asked the other day well how
do we how do you deal with best
practices and i just kind of started
laughing i'm like that's a really good
question because there's so many to
choose from right there are and you know
what do we do with best practices that
are online that are dated right and
somebody knew like i I get very annoyed
when experts okay
experts tell newer newer folks that oh
well it's all online just look at the
best practice right because I remember
in the days a couple of years ago when
you had a large issue with amplification
attacks and open recursive DNS servers I
mean you're looking at the best practice
documents for setting up and open
recursive resolver a lot of them are
recursive resolver a lot of them have
have it in a mode where you know to set
it up to being open recursive resolver
right how do you get rid of that online
I mean it's okay to have managed open
recursive resolvers but not unmanaged
once so that there's a lot of
implementation guidelines are they
really good practices or not but we
trust them device certifications right
this is also interesting because who
actually created their criteria for
device certifications and who's actually
doing the sanity checking of that
compliance mandates I have a love-hate
relationship with compliance I mean I
see where they make sense because it
really gives people a guideline for what
do they need to pay attention to but
then for some folks you know it's
mark yep I'm compliant I'm good well we
still have so many breaches so I don't
think you're good
documented policies don't even get me
started into that one I've done so many
security assessments and I see policies
and this one always sticks up in my mind
I had a job quite a few years ago at a
large in a large environment and I was
asked to be part of the policy team so I
took a look at their standards and you
know I actually do read them and give
comments and there was one that I looked
at and I said wow this is really
interesting let me do some research
because it was a mobile environment so I
started looking at all of the mobile
standards because what the policy the
encryption policies that said that
everything every equipment in this
environment must support TLS with I mean
sorry
AES 256-bit encryption fight for TLS
that was in the companies mandate and
then when I looked at the actual mobile
environment
there was one must-have algorithm for
TLS which was aes-192 so I went into the
next meeting and I said you do realize
for all the equipment that's compliant
with the standard they're not compliant
with our internal policy and ever you
want Ren oh right and I mean I came into
a late in the game and there were
already 15 people that were supposedly
creating this policy so I you know I
always wonder like who's actually paying
attention to the policies do they even
know what they're creating right and
there's blind trust everywhere there and
then the human factor right I mean I do
believe that people inherently want to
do good but we're human so we do make
mistakes that's okay right I hate when
somebody gets vilified for a mistake if
they do it again or don't care fine
you know then that's a problem but
otherwise right you can do and try to do
everything right but quite frankly
you'll still screw up somewhere right
that's just life
and a much bigger issue is
organizational silos and I mean
everybody loves to make fun of different
teams like they don't get it
well of course they don't get it they're
not in your field right and where we are
today with security we have to have
cross-functional understanding by the
executive teams have to understand not
the nerdy details but absolutely the
risks right in terms of what gets
introduced if they make certain business
decisions now they're the ones that are
liable right and so I'm okay if my
recommendations of Amma see so I make a
recommendation and they decide for
whatever reason that ok we'll accept
this risk right because they're liable
especially if there are trustees of a
company right but you know I'd like to
think that they're making at least an
informed decision and then legal
departments right they have to
understand like what is actually
compliant I mean from the legal team
might their job in a company is to make
sure nobody goes to jail right and so
and we're still all learning all over
the place in the global environment what
a security mean what does privacy mean
there's still a lot of work to do
and then with technical teams right you
typically have research architecture
operations and this is what I'm going to
touch upon later we still have silos in
terms of that's a DNS team that's the
routing team that's the email team you
know these are the application people
and what-have-you and we need more
cross-functional understanding of what's
going on then government and policy is
becoming more and more important because
now you also have state actors getting
involved in nefarious online activities
right so I mean in the last five years
I'd say ten years right really the
government's moved from not a what if
statement but you know when will the
something happen and there has already
been
activities right that have been
attributed to specific state actors but
what do you do about it which is where
cyber norms come into play and I really
like the panel that there was this
morning because they kind of touched
upon some of the things that I'm going
to talk about this morning
and then there's law enforcement but
we're actually starting to put criminals
in jail right because cyber crime is
crime I and that's something also that
we always have to keep in mind that the
virtual world mimics the physical world
right and the physical world is not
perfect there's still a lot of issues
there and so sometimes in the virtual
world and with you know online security
I see people always vilifying folks for
not being perfect well nobody is perfect
and we absolutely need to have this
cross-functional education and
understanding I had a question a couple
of days ago when I was a TNC and they
said you know you talked about not
having backdoor encryption so how do we
get the government to understand this
and I said reach out to them right
because if you're waiting for somebody
to reach out to you that's not the
answer right it's also up to us to make
the first move to help educate somebody
that maybe is not as knowledgeable and I
had this just as a reminder because I
want to talk about this it was very
fascinating to me when with the Snowden
revelations everybody started to be on
this bandwagon of let's encrypt
everything and I remember being at
different conferences and one time I
just had to stand up and say I'm not
against encryption right
I mean cryptography gets used for
integrity which means that you know if
I'm sending data to somebody that you
can be fairly certain that nobody's
twiddled the bits in transit it's also
non-repudiation
that you can be fairly assured that it
came from me and then also the third
thing is confidentiality but everybody
started talking about confidentiality
then I started thinking about the fact
that you know cryptography has
consequences I mean how many of us have
created numerous PGP keys because one
that we created and haven't used we
forgot the secret pass phrase to get at
our secret keys right all of us have
done this especially if you've been
around for 25 years or 30 years and so
it's really interesting because when you
say encrypt everything I'm like well
have you really thought about the risks
of how you do credential management and
the fact that you can actually lose data
and lose access to it if something
happens where you lose how the
credential that gives you access to that
encrypted data right I've always been a
proponent for 20 years because this
started with my when I started working
with IPSec I care about using
cryptography for integrity I think every
single piece of data should be integrity
protected encryption not so much because
you're also losing visibility of certain
data so you have to think about what is
the impact of when you're actually using
encryption and we really have to think
through the consequences for the future
so another example of cross functional
brokenness right so a protocol developer
comes up with CSP a cool security
protocol all right and typically under
standards bodies right I mean they do
think about different use cases and a
lot of times there's a lot of different
options to handle every conceivable use
case the software implementer then looks
at the standard it says you know there's
some ambiguities but I will code CSP to
work this way and I'm gonna choose these
defaults hopefully some of these
developers will talk to each other by it
implemented and will actually choose the
same defaults not always the case the
security architect and
corporation says yep this is going to
save us and we have to use CSP so
absolutely let's implement that you have
the network operator for simplicity all
right you want to use defaults as much
as possible so that kept I'm gonna use
the defaults the executive right they
all care about being compliant hey we're
using CSP great more compliant because
that's what the compliant
compliance mandate says and then the
security researcher comes and says you
know this corporation is really stupid
because their use of CSP can be
exploited and the one word that I will
say is heartbleed right because it was
fascinating I've done security workshops
for a very long time and I used to
always start with crypto 101 because I'd
say you know cryptography is important
you have to really pay attention or at
least be knowledgeable that you know
random number generators may not be the
best right this means that you could
have compromises in what you inherently
believe to be trusted by your public
private keys or the fact that you know
what are the defaults right there were
some vendors that still had 768 bit keys
for their IPSec defaults for way too
many years right so the reason that I
loved heartbleed was because everybody
took a little snoozer while I was
talking about crypto nobody really paid
attention all of a sudden with
heartbleed people like wow I need to
understand what my defaults are well I
got to pay attention to like the
different modes in crypto and you know
what the key lengths should be now yes
it's a pain in the butt it's details
that maybe some of us really wish would
be better in defaults but they're not
right so we live in a world right now
where you do have to pay attention you
do need to know what your defaults are
on your equipment
you do have to understand some of the
ramifications and you know one of the
things that I really really want
everybody to be aware of is that all of
these folks need to talk to each other
right this is why you also in companies
and in different organ
even in governments you have
cross-functional security teams so that
everybody can understand each other's
viewpoint and then figure out how to
mitigate the risks in a better way and
you know we're in this world right now
where we have so much data when I was at
TNC it was so cool because these are
research networks and there was some
really interesting interesting research
going on in an article you know other in
healthcare regimes and whatever have you
to really make our world better it's a
lot of data but then you have to think
about where is that data going right and
how is it getting secured so while we
want all of these new applications that
you know track our health we can know
how many steps we take and you know
whatever else have you I mean there's an
app for almost everything but really we
have to figure out you know how do
people have access to this data right
who's authorized to have access is there
any kind of access control is there
integrity so that nobody can twiddle
with the data in some way and then
there's the confidence yeah ality aspect
and if I need to have access to the data
will I have access and that also has to
be balanced with privacy human rights
right in the UN quite a few years ago
but it was decreed that Internet access
is a basic human right then online
privacy as well as freedom of expression
and so it's a very very complex thing
that we're dealing with when we're
looking at online security right
security and privacy and then
everything's broken right how many of
you actually track reaches ID I mean
it's kind of scary every time I give a
talk I put on a slide like this on and
then I look at the latest breaches so
that I can put in some newer headlines
and then I just shake my head and I'm
like okay okay don't think about it it's
kind of like when I fly on an airplane
and I think about the comp
city of what goes into an airplane right
it's the same thing like I don't want to
think about it because then I'll go nuts
right but you know when I look online
and I look at how broken everything is
and how many breaches in every single
sector right it's it's interesting right
because why is this happening all right
there's a lot of people that care
there's good protocols out there there's
good equipment out there like what is it
and yes I know it only takes one right
to actually do a breach but sometimes
they're not detected for three years
right and it's really it's it's an
epidemic
right and and a lot of breaches are not
even even reported or they're not seeing
in the news and so it's it's very very
very interesting times and why are
things so broken like remember the
trickle effect right like as I see today
two people coming into the room it's a
trickle effect of people saying oh yeah
I really do have to pay attention to
this thing called security but we've now
reached the point where there's billions
of new devices online right and as we're
all aware is that you know some of them
don't even have the fundamental security
basics that you can configure they're
not even implemented and there's large
amounts of bandwidth now available
globally right I look at India India is
exploding in terms of getting online
because there was an effort you know it
took ten years but you know they they
built out the capacity and now they're
making it very inexpensive for a lot of
folks to get online that's billions of
people then the criminal sophistication
and this is what I'm going to touch upon
much more on is the criminals are
getting network architecture clue right
it used to just be endpoint devices but
in the last few years they've gotten
much much smarter to actually utilize
networks to do much more sophisticated
attacks so it's much harder to detect
and it causes a lot more impact I
attended some really great talks
yesterday right there's there was one on
tunneling I mean there is a much more
tunneling going on for nefarious
activity and also use of encryption and
of course social media has been
weaponized for quite a number of years
and the information that we put out
there sometimes fascinating to me and
then you have a lot more automation so
data sharing also has opportunities and
risks right the opportunities are vast
so social media greatly simplifies
sharing I was on a panel it was about
2005 about how social media is changing
the security of companies right because
you're working for a company and you
might be putting out on social media
that hey yeah really cool I'm going
through a conference and or a meeting in
London and some people that are watching
the industry might say oh they work for
so-and-so company I've heard rumors that
there may be an acquisition and you know
because of the data that you're putting
out there people can piece together that
oh yeah there's talks going on all right
so this has been going on for over 15
years
but the simplified sharing people just
love to put information out there
without any thought of the consequences
and digitalization also enables sharing
across many sectors right the banking
sector the healthcare sector oil and
energy travel sector what-have-you and a
lot of times it gives you time and cost
savings and of course instant
gratification right I love looking at my
app and going wait what time do I fly
again oh where are my bags right some of
these airplane bags that so I know that
oh yeah my bag made it on the airplane
so when I arrive I'll have it yeah I'm
happy I mean but with all of this theta
what is what are all the risks that are
introduced and I think with gdpr I have
a love-hate relationship with it but
what I really love about it is people
have to start thinking about what data
do we have and how do we protect it and
a lot of people found out that wow we're
not really protecting it as well as we
should so who has the data where is the
data going what is done to
protect the data and how is the data
getting abused or what is the potential
for abuse so I do want to spend quite a
bit of time talking about the
fundamental building blocks where we
really need to think about how can we
better protect ourselves and have better
visibility before more damage is done in
surrouding the domain name system the
public key infrastructure right these
are fundamental building blocks where
we've have blind trust for a very long
time
also credential management right you
create a key or you create a password a
private public key pair do you really
think about the entire credential
lifecycle management right in many
environments people don't and then also
think about what the humans are doing
and for me there's I always think about
a couple of things for any security
assessment I do anything I look at any
new protocol I'm thinking of well how do
you establish identity because it has to
be hard to impersonate and also how has
identity actually validated right in any
kind of scenario and then do you have
integrity of data and confidentiality of
data like is that capability possible do
you need to do it and then a very
important component is auditing right
who has seen the information and looking
at early warnings right so in DNS in the
last few years people have understood
that if they start getting feeds for
newly observed domains right and then
see whether or not their their
reputation is good or bad they can
actually have some early warnings in
terms of some potential malicious
activity right so there are capabilities
around it's just are we utilizing them
effectively so this is where I get into
some of the sophisticated infrastructure
attacks so this happened back in April
2018 and it was really interesting to me
because it showed that by doing
a routing hijack that somebody was
actually able to poison the DNS cache
and they were putting together how
routing and DNS was working and there's
other such attacks also this was just
the most publicized attacked which
happened to take over if the Aryan
crypto current what's so basically
Amazon route prefixes were hijacked so
Amazon's route 53 DNS traffic for the
authoritative nameservers were rerouted
towards a malicious DNS server so the
malicious DNS authoritative server that
was set up had a legitimate IP address
due to the route hijack right so if you
were looking to see whether or not your
authoritative nameserver
had changed IP addresses right you
couldn't tell right you're staying under
the radar and then these malicious DNS
authoritative servers sent DNS answers
back that basically caused the cache
poisoning because they pointed to
malicious sites and then the intent
overall was to take over a theorem
cryptocurrency wallets so I have a
picture of this because sometimes a
picture is much better so the router on
the left is the the correct let's say
Amazon one where it announces a bunch of
slashed 23s
right and then most routers and this is
the point I want to make don't do
filtering effectively okay filtering has
been around for ever since the router
was created right and there's been talks
for 20 years about please do prefix
filtering or AES filtering and people
still don't do that as much as they
should so what happens is that somebody
that about on the left will hijack the
route they will send a more specific
slash 24 if you're not doing the correct
filtering you will just pass it on and
then everybody will utilize the traffic
and redirects it to the
router that hijacked the route now some
security folks have talked about well
what are you just since last 24 is
everywhere alright cuz imma solve the
problem and the routing people are like
are you nuts right because you don't
understand how a router works right and
you're gonna explode the router I mean
because it doesn't have enough memory
and then start thinking about ipv6 what
are you gonna do have slash 64's
everywhere all right I mean that's not a
solution right so filtering will help so
we all have to work with each other
right I mean the hierarchy and routing
was created for a reason and so rather
than say well it's your problem or it's
your problem or it's your problem it's
all of our problem right so doing some
prefix filtering will really help and
people really should pay attention to
this so you know what happens now you've
got this route hijack so then somebody
will set up the malicious authoritative
DNS server right with the right IP
address they will poison the recursive
server to send to point to a malicious
site and then the victim client you know
when they ask the question hey how do I
get to the etherium site then the
recursive DNS server will have the
malicious site in its cache and say hey
you know point to point to this
malicious site and I saw it wasn't
widely advertised or talked about in the
news but there was it happen in a
banking environment also alright so this
is not the only use case this is just
the one that was most widely you know in
the press but this is happening today
and so the criminals are becoming very
very sophisticated in terms of how to
stay under the radar right they've been
doing that for decades but we need to
understand that wow you know they're
really starting to understand network
infrastructure and figuring out how to
how to how to bypass even our current
alarm systems
so as I mentioned right the basic of our
hijack would not have been possible if
there had been affected BGP prefix
filtering so most varmints do not filter
effectively and then there's also
something that people are now starting
to promote more and more and I do hope
that people are paying attention to this
if you're a security person and don't
know about any routing security
protocols please do you know look them
up and talk to the people in your
environments that are doing routing but
rpki the resource public key
infrastructure does help mitigate
routing hijacks as well and I have a
slide on that just to give a little bit
of fundamentals in case some of you
don't know it and then also DNS SEC
right now the interesting thing about
rpki and DNS SEC is that they do rely on
a public key infrastructure and so you
have to know that as well right so all
these things tie together remember what
I said about technical silos right
you're the security people so you know
about certificates and rpki and you know
PKI infrastructure sorry PKI
infrastructures you're the routing
people right you're the DNS people right
even from a technical side we all have
to start communicating with each other
because there's inter dependencies so
when you're looking at what our PKI is
it provides for origin authentication so
basically if it says that I am
authorized with my ASN to route these
prefixes so I'm not going to go into too
much more detail because I've got a lot
more slides but basically that's the
premise and then also in the Internet
Society right because really people
aren't doing the fundamentals to protect
the routing infrastructures they created
something called manners I know that
myself and a few other people in this
room were part of the early meetings on
that and so it's it's it's kind of a
norm for Internet service providers by
to agree to
you know help each other and protect the
internet by by by paying attention to
routing security norms so one is to
prevent propagation of incorrect routing
information by doing BGP filtering
preventing traffic with spoofed source
addresses by utilizing pcp 38 which is
an IETF standard for ingress filtering
and using something called also unicast
reverse path forwarding and then
facilitating communication between
network operators which basically says
yes I'm going to make sure that I have
contact information for my upstream and
downstream and then also facilitating
the validation of routing information by
using rpki
so the ISPs that have signed this
manifesto right are the ones that are
agreeing to actually implement these
four norms so it's a great great
initiative by Issac DNS right we've
heard over the last five years right a
lot of issue aliy ten years all of the
the reasons why DNS is used for
nefarious activity so this slide I
actually asked permission two years ago
to use in another conference and I loved
the slide because it really helps to lay
out threats related to DNS and we
actually had a DNS sig meeting yesterday
but we're starting a DNS sig I'm one of
the co-chairs along with Carlos Alvarez
and there was a discussion about well
how do you categorize DNS abuse and I
didn't want to preempt this right but I
love this slide because it talks about
DNS protocol attacks DNS server attacks
and categorizes DNS abuse now it's not a
standard anywhere but I would love to
start proliferating this terminology so
with DNS protocol attacks you have the
man-in-the-middle attacks DNS spoofing
DNS rebinding DNS server attacks you
have server DDoS and daus's server
hijacks cache poisoning and then under
DNS
Buse you have a whole bunch of stuff
right which includes covert channels
malicious DNS tunneling malicious
domains and IPS and what have you but
it's it's a really compendium to shows
you to show you how much DNS is utilized
for nefarious activity and the folks
that came up with that are from Georgia
Tech led by um and it's there was a
paper that was written called detecting
intern abuse by analyzing passive DNS
traffic right but DNS is widely widely
abused and because of all the talks that
I saw yesterday and there's one today
also I think this community absolutely
is aware of all the DNS issues that we
have to pay attention to and of course
why do criminals register domain names
well because it's very easy to do
phishing and spam right well more
fishing right it's a phishing we care
about ransomware because these are the
the ways that people start or a criminal
start with getting access to information
where they can then do more
sophisticated attacks so basic hygiene
right it's all about the basic building
blocks now none of these things are new
but this leads up to something else
because there's more and more attacks
that are also starting to utilize more
sophistication within the DNS and these
are not new concepts these concepts all
deal with don't have faith sharing right
make sure that you have backups if
somebody's attacking this server make
sure that you have another server that
can then take over you know make sure
that you have access control because you
want to limit the views you want to
monitor activity to see whether or not
something changes but as I talked about
just earlier but even if you're
monitoring authoritative nameservers to
see whether or not there's a new IP
address because that might be somebody
trying to imperson
well if it's the same IP address and you
don't see a difference then what right
so again there's never one silver bullet
my security has to be done in layers and
going on further but you want to do
auditing you want to review the log
files to make sure that nobody has
unauthorized access in an environment a
few years ago when I was a C so we were
starting to really look at you know
which logs do we want to start paying a
lot of attention to I thought about it
for a while and I said my number one is
unauthorized access attempts you know
that to me was primary I mean there's so
many things that I needed to look at and
pay attention to but my primary one was
unauthorized access attempts because
this gives me a way to see who's
knocking on the door and who might be
getting in right I mean you guys might
have some other perspectives but you
know to me that was really really
critical yes I wanted to make a point so
the very last bullet I voted this way on
purpose because sometimes people use
terms and if you're not familiar with
them and don't know what they're used
for then you know gets a little bit
convoluted so this sentence use
techniques to assure authoritative
answers come from expected source and
that no one has been able to modify the
answer in transit I could have used one
word what would it have been DNS SEC
exactly so I always like to talk about
what does it do because if you talk to
the executives and say well we have to
use DNS SEC they're like whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa yeah right I mean what is that
it's like so yeah I mean I just want to
let them know that look there's
techniques right well you know that the
answer comes from the authoritative and
nobody's modified it or can't spoof or
cache that makes sense to them so that's
not difficult right and so we have to
remember that we need to create context
around some of the technical stuff we
speak about all right so I'm not gonna
go into what the NSA is because I'm
looking at the timer here and there's
still a lot of points I want to make but
DNS SEC is important right and there's
another protocol Dane I which also
relies on DNS SEC and so DNS SEC relies
on you understanding public key
infrastructure right and doing
credential management so there's a lot
of interdependencies and it starts with
the building blocks DNS SEC is a very
very important building block for
securing DNS and you know what are the
criminals after all right they're after
information so that they can impersonate
you so they can create fraud right this
is why they're going after the medical
industry the the banking industry your
social media sites right there's so much
fishing going on last year I started
getting phishing from 3 supposed
individuals right that all looked to be
on the homeowners board that I'm on
well it wasn't from them right I looked
at the actual email address I'm like huh
some gobbly from you know whatever
country right whatever top-level domain
but what was really interesting is that
I've gotten in the last 4 months
probably 20 of those phishing attacks
all different right all with different
kind of links or documents that I'm
supposedly you know supposed to click on
way to infect my machine but the names
are the three other people that are on
the homeowners board and I'm like who
did this research and the other people
got it as well right and I told them
right away don't click on anything send
me the information because I'm
consolidating the information and
sending it to law enforcement because
they might be building a bigger case on
this but it's interesting to me because
they're targeting specific groups and
people are doing the research
right I mean homeowners association
board what
right and and really it's starting to
get to the laymen and they're really
looking at groups of people right and
being very clever in terms of the emails
that they're creating but this is what
they're after and so the thing that I'm
I've been on the bandwagon for for 15
years is credential management right and
I'm on the security Advisory Council of
ICANN and we did a report about three
years ago so now it was published sac 74
which talked about the life cycle of
credential management because nobody or
very few people I should say are doing
it effectively and this is one way that
many many many sophisticated attacks
start by getting access to credentials
and there's many ways that criminals get
access to credentials right being a
victim of phishing attack attack a
laptop gets stolen and you haven't
encrypted your device and you've got a
file with credentials on there I use a
password manager if you can you always
should be able to sharing your password
with another person right it still
happens
all right I've been on elevators and
conferences in the back of me there's
you know two people talking that oh yeah
I need access to this oh you know I
don't know my password or you know
whatever the excuse and the guy's like
I'll just use mine you know username
password I mean I could very easily
glance at the person's like badge and be
like oh that company oh you know maybe
start some of the various activity to
see if I can log in somewhere right
airplanes people still talking airplanes
or on restaurants about things like this
and I've been a witness so sometimes
depending on my mood I'm like hello do
you want me to log in maybe I'll look at
your a s number and your IP address or
something I'm like oh you're from
so-and-so company you know you probably
shouldn't be talking about what your
passwords are right or you should be
doing two-factor authentication but
anyway so sending credentials and clear
text emails that still happens by the
and so sometimes there is a breach and
the very very helpful customer service
people you know want to renew the
credentials in a really speedy way and
want to send them an email right they're
not stupid they're just not experienced
enough okay and this is where we have
education to do and we at least have to
have a process in whatever environment
you're in so that they know and they
learn not to do that and of course
unpatched security vulnerabilities are
exploited right again the panel
yesterday was excellent because you
really do have to do the updates and
patches as quickly as feasible
so this slide is a synopsis of good
credential management practices so
whenever you're creating changing
renewing credentials you need to think
about how are you distributing it ID ru
integrity protecting it and keeping the
credentials confidential if they need to
be how are you storing it right is it
integrity protected does it have
confidentiality recovering delegating or
transferring revoking destroying and a
lot of times why these devices are
awesome right but what people don't
sometimes think about is that if they
have credentials on here because they're
logging into certain systems why do they
automatically back these up to a cloud a
cloud is somebody else's computer right
somebody else who's running that
computer what kind of security
mechanisms do they have to protect your
data I'm not saying don't do it I'm
saying make sure that you understand how
they protect that data I do so we have
to understand exactly what's happening
with our credentials and we want to
avoid surprises so these are just a
couple of things that I've come across
where people are not paying attention
configuration files that store passwords
are shared secret and clear text right
even in routers like here here's one
exam
I was in an environment I was doing a
security assessment and I was looking at
I'm very familiar with Cisco Cisco
router configs and so I was saying you
know why why did you decide to do this
and they said oh well because some smart
person told us to and I'm like well
that's more persons and so smart because
for any of you that might know this
right
Cisco has this way of protecting secrets
in their configuration files where you
say username password something or
username secret something if you use the
key word password when you encrypt that
using a password service encryption
command it creates a bit shift if you
use username secret so the key word
secret it doesn't md5 hash right and so
you could use one or the other
I wish they'd get rid of the username
password because doing the bit shift is
something that years ago was put out on
the web and the minute that they
announced the functionality it was
reverse engineer and I think an hour
right and so you're not then and you're
enable password but you could say enable
password something or enable secret
something so if you're sending that
configuration file was supposedly
encrypted
you know confidential information by
confidential credentials then somebody
could reverse-engineer that really
quickly so you need to think about these
things all right
validating identity so crucial right I
have made statements sometimes and
they're always taken out of context that
sometimes I don't care when somebody has
my password right but if I had to factor
authentication I have less of a risk of
somebody trying to impersonate me
because I have that second factor so
even if they have my password they still
need another piece of information before
they can actually impersonate me all
right of course I care if somebody has
my password but my main point is that
today in this day in
because there aren't better mechanisms
available we need to do multi-factor
authentication absolutely so here's
another case and you know this is still
ongoing but this is what started
happening last fall so an attacker
gained access to a victim's registrar
account I when you want a domain you go
and go to a registrar to then say hey
you know let me by Medicare com
and this was done by compromised login
credentials so the attacker then changed
the DNS record right the a record change
the IP address and the authoritative
server and pointed them to the attacker
servers and then once the DNS zone
content was changed the attackers
impersonated legitimate services hosted
by the victim and it gets more
interesting
the attackers then executed a
man-in-the-middle attack against users
by generating fake X out five of five or
nine certificates so now we've got
impersonated certificates in play and
certificates also is one of the main
building blocks all right years ago I
was involved in doing a security
assessment of the 787 airplane ok this
was back in 2007 and I was looking at
their peak PKI architecture and you know
looking at how they do cross
certifications of airplanes and access
to airplanes and what-have-you and I'd
never really looked that deeply into PKI
before and boy did I get scared because
there was a vendor that had a whole
bunch of trusted boots in there right
and and I don't like to name and shame
so I'm pretty careful about this but
yeah so and so we decided that we don't
need all those routes and we want to be
more stringent so we took him out out
well the really sophisticated vendor
decided that we probably didn't know
what we were doing that they were
smarter than us and they just
automatically be populated all the
routes right and it was really difficult
to go into the the bowels of
the configurations to actually change
this right so after a while you know
they changed that it took about a year
or two and then I started looking at the
different implementations I'm like this
is so broken it's not even funny
people were not validating what you're
supposed to be validating in a
certificate alright so you're supposed
to look at the validity and they weren't
like you know they didn't even say that
oh look you know it's a year later than
the validity period but the certificate
is still valid why is that because the
software's not checking it right and it
was awful
I mean it was worse than awful I'm like
what are you guys doing you know and you
started having you know ssl/tls
everybody was depending on this right on
the certificates yet the software wasn't
checking what it was supposed to be
checking for and this is what twelve
years ago and I already started thinking
I'm like huh I can either be depressed
every single day of my life where I can
just slowly try and help and make change
right and it's all about education so I
see that I'm already in the red and I've
got a couple more points that I
definitely want to make so I'm not gonna
go into detail but with certificates
right again this is what you're supposed
to be checking on the right you know any
software I hope they do that right and
so how do you validate
I don't know right I mean who has time
to validate everything but this is the
responsibilities of the vendors so it's
getting better over time
but again you know you got to check your
implementation at times and so
fundamental security so why does
fundamental security matter this is a
slide that I took by Jeffrey's which is
an identity theft Resource Center
breaches are just increasing increasing
increasing this is from 2005 to 2007
teen and you know how they're increasing
in businesses medical environment
educational environment there's a lot of
universities getting attacked other
schools government's financials and the
thing is as your privacy gets violated
as people get access to your PII
personally from
but what what are criminals doing with
it
extortion bullying embarrassment
financial rule identity identity theft
fraud and it does lead to loss of life
right with bullying right I think we've
all seen in the new suicides that that
you know people have and you know with
the healthcare industry being attacked
right there is absolutely loss of life
that comes into the equation so this is
not just fun and games anymore right
this is extremely serious which is also
why governments are getting involved so
we need to get back to the basics all
right to me security is always about
these points on the left and I don't
care what term a vendor makes up I will
go back to the basics you know any cute
term any fun term right I said well what
are you actually doing oh okay this
deals with integrity
okay this deals with access control and
then the most basic security controls
minimize the impact of sophisticated
attacks security is difficult because
it's very detail oriented right there's
a lot to think about a lot to do but the
sophistication comes in also because
people are utilizing very simple ways to
get access to credentials that then help
create the more sophisticated attacks so
don't rely on defaults limit fate
sharing use cryptographically protected
protocols right and check your hashes
when you're actually downloading any
software right I know that I also
sometimes get lazy and I'm like oh yeah
no you know I trust it and then I'm like
oh no you know I really should check the
hash it will take me you know 30 extra
seconds maybe 60 right but we have to be
vigilant and then get alerted for
unauthorized changes and we have to
continue building trust in people right
we want to build a culture that builds
and maintains trust I think most people
are trustworthy as we saw in the keynote
yesterday you don't know
who's gonna have any kind of nefarious
agenda but same is true in the physical
world right a physical crime you're like
wow I never thought that person would do
that it's the same in the virtual world
you want to create values that center
around integrity and Trust develop
cultures of commitment you guys are all
committed you came here this morning
I was joking early I said you know
anybody that actually was at the social
last night and didn't come this morning
if they click on the video to see this
talk I want to drink it because I didn't
drink last night because I'm on stage
this morning so you want to challenge a
culture of blame the blame game has to
go away right the hype it's their fault
it's their fault they're dumb they're
stupid right we're all on this game
together
let's educate each other learn from
incidents and again educate each other
and Trust is always earned but you have
to verify right I might trust you today
I may not trust you tomorrow
so trust but verify and remember don't
have blind trust and standards
frameworks best practices reference
implementation certifications I do look
at them on occasion see whether or not
they have to be changed and then somehow
we have to measure effectiveness over
time and that's it for today
it's great thank you very much indeed
America we've probably got time for one
quick question because we are on short
coffee breaks today okay I hope you're
around today yeah I'll be around for a
couple hours
oh sorry somebody in a dark shirt in the
back of the auditorium yeah thank you
my name is Seenu from Indonesia how do
you think about cryptography in the
future because everyone it speed and etc
their data later cause according your
presentation cryptography has limitation
thank you yes thank you for that
question so I want to reiterate
cryptography is used for at least three
things
integrity non-repudiation and
confidentiality
I think cryptography is essential to
secure communication what I think we
have to think about is where we need to
have confidentiality because in my mind
integrity and non-repudiation and using
cryptography is essential for all
communications all pieces of data for
confidentiality you want to make a
policy decision because you want to see
whether or not you need to have
visibility to the data for other reasons
right thank you
one note we've spotted that there is a
rather hideous clash between the women
of first bath and the PC 2020 lunch and
since we don't want an all-male program
committee can you
no really really we don't want normal
program committee can you keep an eye on
the buff board downstairs because the
previously announced times may change
the last I have from Nora is we're on it
so if you're coming so thank you very
much very good
[Applause]