alright i know they told me to stay in
this little box but I want to walk among
you
how are you guys doing this morning are
you awake awake
alright I prove it stand up Huh up
everybody up not just the hack in the
Box crew who weirdly listen to me i
don't i don't understand why this
happens every year so okay I make you
get up because i have to be up and my
god I drank too much last night so if i
have to be up you have to be up for just
two minutes
so besides the jack-in-the-box crew have
seen me do this to the audience before
how many of you have been in the
security industry for some security
industry or computing industry for five
years or less ok so sit down those five
years or less it down ok 10 years or
less
sit down ok now we're seeing how old I
am still standing
15 years or less ok alright wait wait
where dwindling here so who is left
standing up
okay number one these are people you
need to buy drinks for because we've
been through a lot
ok yes you can all sit down at this
point so thank you so much for having me
again at jack in the box
you know the crew here we were talking
about it the other keynotes and I were
talking about how much this conference
you know takes care of you and the crew
takes care of you and today I'm actually
going to talk about essentially a
massive long-held social engineering
hack that probably started for me about
18 years ago my first Def Con was DEFCON
7 so yes you need to buy me all the
drinks because I'm very old and clearly
i need those drinks to live because you
know water isn't doing it for me but I
know for me I hacking has been a passion
for quite some time and you know my my
career started so long ago in this
industry that there weren't a lot of
ways to make money legitimately or
otherwise
actually because the early internet
didn't have the same dependence that the
current Internet has for us as a society
you know we didn't do any banking online
back when i was learning how to hack
right we didn't do a whole lot of things
that our society depended on
economically socially and politically
let's not even go there right now I'm so
depressed in the United States but the
point was if you knew how to hack a
computer back in the days that i learned
how to hack a computer there were things
that you could do with it that were
mostly curiosity bound and how many of
you saw errands talk yesterday morning a
chance
yeah so Aaron did this great see this is
who wakes up in the morning
this you guys are hardcore um but you
know uh in terms of hacking and what you
could do with it
Aaron did this great walkthrough you
know that was inspired by Hollywood and
essentially showing how life was
imitating art in terms of hacking but
way back there really wasn't that much
you could do commercially in order to
make money if you were a hacker
certainly the the movie wargames you
know which started the the Reagan
administration United States on this
path of criminalizing hacking because
they were afraid of our superpowers they
were afraid of what we could do
certainly that was was a big moment in
hacking history however it was a moment
in which our activities were
criminalized not celebrated not
understood and ways in which that we
might have been able to contribute to
the security of our society were
overlooked in in favor of fear and I see
this today in terms of legislation
original regulation that is being put in
place or is already in place in terms of
trying to deal with our superpowers what
they perceive the normal people in the
world perceived as magic of what we can
do so
one of the things that i noticed during
my first Def Con that they keep telling
me not to move across the space but
obviously I just I can't stand it i
really want to be with you so how many
of you had a computer when you were a
child right
ok so there's a generational issue here
too as well how many of you had an old
computer that could only do command line
when you were a child okay there we go
so the thing the thing about it is is a
if that's how you had to learn how to
use a computer and that's how you have
to learn how to use the internet there
were a lot of things that you had to do
manually that weren't set up for you and
so when we were learning how to do this
we essentially had to either learn very
quickly how these things worked or write
something ourselves that made the
computer do what we wanted to do in
order to get what we wanted a lot of us
got our start insecurity because we had
a younger brother or sister that we
simply wanted to keep out of our files
so that was our first you know attempt
at encryption others of us got into it
because we wanted to play a game that we
didn't have a license for and so
learning how to use a hex editor to
crack you know a game but eventually the
stakes became much higher for all of us
as our dependence as a society grew on
computing on the Internet itself and on
the ability of people like the folks in
this room to change the rules at any
given time of what was possible with a
computer with a network and at this
point in our in our technological growth
with anything at all that might have
code running on it and might be on the
internet they called the Internet of
Things I feel like that's going to be a
term that goes away very quickly because
that is going to just define the
internet just because every single thing
that you are that you could have that
you want to collect
data is going to be talking to every
other thing and when I look at all of
the inter connected devices our
dependence on it societally our
dependence on economically and the fact
of the matter is that our society even
if you want to opt out of this new
interconnected world
let's say you want to drive a car with
not a single micro chip in it for the
rest of your life
that's lovely but you will be sharing
the road with vehicles that have been
designed to drive themselves and so your
safety and and the safety of the people
that you care about will be somewhat
dependent on dear god the security of a
vehicle that may or may not have been
designed to be a computer as well and we
all know how fragile this ecosystem is
especially the old folks that you need
to buy drinks for we all very much yes
see he's he needs a drink right now you
just help them out but we understand the
fragility of this ecosystem and quite
frankly it frightens the heck out of me
that not only is our society dependent
on it now but there will be no aspect of
society where you can opt out anymore
and you cannot opt out of the internet
and you can opt out of security so the
the title of this talk is actually
hacking the Pentagon how many of you
heard about half the Pentagon ok
the crew and my friends in the front row
put your hands down and anyone left
ok all 12 to people who are not crew or
my friends in the front row have heard
back the Pentagon so just to give a
little bit of background I obviously i
was i was a tinker hacker for a very
long time in my life but at a certain
point in my career I decided that I
needed to do some hacking that was a
little bit higher level in terms of how
much i could affect the world I
certainly could find bugs and I
certainly could you know make my
penetration testing clients satisfied
because i was able to break into their
network or or do all that
stuff but i realized at a certain point
especially considering i was finding the
same types of bugs over and over again
that one it was getting boring too we
weren't getting better at security
necessarily and and three that i might
not be able to effect change and help
society as much as I wanted to
if I was essentially hacking one bag at
a time one client at a time so remember
I said that that my first Def Con was
DEFCON 7 now is in 1999 and we were all
kind of rolling up and waiting for the
y2k bug has anyone heard of the y2k ok
alright again besides the front row and
the crew who is left in the room
ok so we were concerned about this
glitch that was going to affect so many
computer systems worldwide and they have
a shortage of programmers who could
program you know in a lot of the the
languages cobol for example that that
we're running a lot of this vulnerable
code and we were worried that
essentially the grid as it were way back
then was just going to come crashing
down
you know we're worried airplanes are
gonna fall from the sky all kinds of
things
hardly any of that happened there were a
few little incidents that were related
to y2k but think about the computing and
interconnectivity that was around in
1999 vs where we are today in 2016 and
you begin to see this picture of that
was viewed as a potential disaster on
the horizon because of one bug
distributed across multiple systems
around the world you see the growth of
the internet and i would love to have
stats off the top of my head but let's
just say it's grown exponentially our
dependence on it has grown exponentially
today we have so many interconnected
devices with often no way to update them
it's not a matter of finding someone who
can write the code and correct the one
bug but you know I crew and front row
you're allowed to raise your hands for
this heartbleed anybody
yes you've heard of this ok so
heartbleed is such a great example of
where we are now in terms of our state
of overall vulnerability and inability
to deal with the
issues at hand shared library open
source bug in the code for more than two
years couple of people manage to
concurrently find that bug so proving
that you know if one person found it
probably somebody else did as well that
old theory or a bug collisions but think
about what the rollout looked like
you're dealing with that one
Varner ability coordination at best
between one hacker one finder and one
vendor is rough sometimes imagine
vulnerability coordination between
hackers vendors of an open source
library and then the fact that the
library itself has to be distributed
across the world that distribution and
that vulnerability coordination took
over a hundred different companies all
trying to keep a secret that ultimately
leaked about a week before the
designated date where everybody was
supposed to go live with it so thinking
about the problems with vulnerability
coordination even on a scale like that
where it's just trying to deploy fix for
one shared library and you look at the
world of internet of things and how many
of those things have full software
development houses in at their disposal
have full testing houses have automation
and testing have any kind of security
development lifecycle you pretty much
come down to almost no one and then of
those IOT vendors how many of the them
are using open-source libraries you come
up with most of them and it's a shortcut
way for a lot of these technology
organizations or these non technology
organizations who are suddenly adding
code to their to their devices and
systems to ramp up very quickly and
develop something that can suddenly talk
to the internet when they don't you even
know what they're doing and they have no
way to essentially service or patch all
of these devices so
let's get back to hacking the Pentagon
right so hacking the Pentagon 1 i'm
amazed that they kept that name hack the
Pentagon that was that was a surprise to
probably all of us who were working on
this project for the last couple years
we would call it that but what it was
was symbolically and effectively the
very first time that the United States
government one admitted that it needed
some help in terms of cybersecurity not
just saying no no we're secure
trust us it's fine all of your personal
data you know everyone who's ever
applied for a clearance it's fine where
we'll take care of it
one it was the first time they were
openly asking for help from the hacker
community to was the first time that
they wanted to do anything with the
hackers publicly except throw them in
jail and three
it was the first time that the United
States government was willing to pay
people like us for $MONEY in exchange
for vulnerabilities and you might think
that this was some kind of an impossible
task and it was for sure
definitely the people inside the
Pentagon who helped make this happen
who were the internal bureaucratic
hackers Lisa with wall
Charlie Chris Lynch all of those folks
and Secretary of Defense ash Carter
himself who made the decision ultimately
to go ahead and do this crazy thing and
prove the fact that not only could the
government work with hackers directly
but they could work with hackers and
invite them to hack the actual Pentagon
and survive and get better that program
lasted for about 21 days it was a pilot
program the Department of Defense's
publicly announced already they're going
to expand that program because what they
found was over 1,400 hackers tried to
pre-register for this program a lot of
people were thinking that this was not
going to work that that you know a lot
of my hacker friends actually are still
to this day very suspicious about the
whole thing thinking that they were
going to be registered in this giant
government
the base they were going to end up in
one time oh you know that essentially
all the paranoia was there and yet 1400
different hackers came forward and
wanted to participate in this historic
program and you know have all their
names written down in their social
security numbers known and all that
stuff but the fact of the matter was the
United States government wasn't just
looking for its bugs it was looking for
people who are willing to help people
who would actually answer the call when
they said we actually need your help
hackers we need your help so those 1400
within i believe it was 13 minutes after
the doors opened on hack the Pentagon
that the first vulnerability report was
received 1,400 people and already less
than 15 minutes into the program bug
started coming in so looking back at
what the Pentagon's goals were engage
the hacker community find out about
vulnerabilities in some of its websites
and figure out who is willing to come
forward and trust the fact that they
would actually come forward when called
to hack the Pentagon and they would
actually turn over the bugs they found
all of these things had to be met in
order for that program to be deemed a
success and deemed a way to move forward
in a new way with the hacker community
rather than putting them in jail for
threatening them but in fact embracing
them and I will not forget the fact that
at the end of the program Secretary of
Defense ash Carter invited a couple of
the hackers up to the Pentagon to stand
with him as he talked about the results
of the program one of them was a high
school kid and you know for those of us
who have been doing this for a very long
time can you imagine can you imagine as
we were children that the leader of one
of the most powerful or potentially the
most powerful military organization the
world has ever seen is thanking you for
pointing out his weaknesses
amazing this was incredible
so how did this even come to be the
first time I went to the Pentagon I was
still working at Microsoft
so for those of you who know how long
ago I worked at Microsoft i left in
$MONTH 2014 i started Microsoft's bug
bounties and 2013 that process itself
took me about three years to get
microsoft to agree to pay hackers money
but what had happened in order to lead
up to the Pentagon and this historic
moment where you know the leader of the
most powerful military in the world is
thanking a child for pointing out his
weaknesses began when I had actually
briefed some of the folks inside of a
small group at MIT and harvard on what I
had done to convince microsoft to allow
hackers to hack them and get paid for it
now does anybody remember it was this
back in like two thousand eight or so
does anyone remember what Microsoft
would say when they were asked about
whether or not they would pay a bug
bounty or pay hackers money in or
exchange for abilities anyone remember
ok no one remembers that's okay
microsoft was publicly saying that they
would never pay for vulnerabilities they
said that word they said never you know
most mega-corporations usually we'll
head around what they say and they don't
use absolute that they can't if they can
avoid it and Microsoft was using an
absolute saying never
and why was that in the microsoft
security response center
how many of you saw sweeties talk
yesterday didn't you be so sweetie
sweetie stop sweeties talk was i missed
it but I saw the slides the slides
looked great it's talking about all the
mitigation enhancements to the windows
10 platform and all the ways in which
exploitation techniques are becoming
harder to execute even if you do find a
critical vulnerability on the platform
but going back to $MONTH 2008 microsoft
executives were saying they were
swearing that they would never pay money
and what was going on what was causing
them to believe that they would never
have to do that when the microphone
Security Response Center they were
receiving over 200,000 non-spam email
messages per year of friendly hackers
who were volunteering for free to tell
microsoft about its weaknesses so with
that data they were thinking well you
know all these friendly hackers who want
to see the world being a safer place
these friendly hackers are willing to
come forward for free
rule number one always silence your own
phone when you're presenting okay there
we go
um actually the day I announce the
microsoft bug bounty programs I was
onstage in bangkok and I heard a phone
ring going off and it was going off and
I was thinking wow somebody really needs
to silence that thing and then I
realized it was a windows phone ringing
and I realized the only person who whose
phone it could possibly be was mine so i
had to go well okay there was maybe one
other person in the room whose phone it
could possibly be but I essentially my
own alarm was going off on stage the day
that I was announcing the microsoft bug
bounty programs and actually dylan and
Belinda were there with me was an
amazing day but so how do i get
microsoft from this position where they
were receiving so many bugs for free
where they were receiving tons of
critical and critical vulnerabilities
for free even when there was a you know
a an exploit a vulnerability market that
was alive and well we're all these bugs
were getting bought by other parties
whether they were defensive parties like
the zero day initiative how many of you
have heard of zdi okay great so zero day
initiative and other kinds of
vulnerability acquisition programs like
it are defense-oriented in that they
will buy the vulnerability in order to
get it fixed they will buy it they will
give it to the vendor to fix it they
will maybe build a product or an
alerting service or something around the
fact that they've acquired these unknown
Milner abilities but that's the defense
market for vulnerabilities the office
market for vulnerabilities is something
entirely different
the office market is buying
vulnerabilities and exploits in order to
keep them secret in order to use them
for attacks in order to keep them live
and and you know viable for as long as
possible so they're not just buying the
vulnerability they're actually buying
exclusivity how do you heard what
happened with hacking team any of you
heard of hacking team okay great so
hacking team was a great example of how
the office market really worked you saw
in the email dumps of hacking team that
vulnerability or exploit sellers were
offering a range of vulnerabilities and
they were offering a priceless price
plate breaks if you bought a bundle you
know bargain bargain bugs and they were
also offering exclusivity of the
vulnerability itself by tripling the
price they also had a payout schedule
that was very nicely documented saying
you know if you buy this bug give me
fifty percent of the money upfront and
then pay me out twenty-five percent
20-percent one month later and then the
last month later and you don't have to
pay if the bug essentially gets patched
or or something else happens to make it
less viable for attack
so you begin to see the the reason why
some of the the prices for
vulnerabilities seem so high in the
office market versus the defense market
is because again they're not paying just
for the vulnerability they're paying for
the hackers silence they're paying for
the ability to use this thing for office
for as long as possible so let's get
back to Microsoft right so Microsoft's
getting all of these bugs for free
sounds great sounds like a reason to
vows never to pay hackers money however
there was this pesky thing that I had
access to which was vulnerability
reporting data inside of Microsoft and
one of the things that was very
important to Microsoft was that it had
not just this pipeline of free bugs but
it had a pipeline of potential recruits
of hackers who it might be able to hire
to help make its products more secure
this direct interaction with hackers
potentially for recruiting was very
important
to the biggest software company in the
world famously let's see there was a
hacking group in Poland that some of the
early folks at microsoft security years
before i was over there went to go visit
because they had found some serious
vulnerabilities they want to go visit
them to recruit them some of those folks
still work at Microsoft to this day 15
years later trying to help make those
products more secure so the data that i
had was showing that not only yes the
bugs were still coming in but more and
more of the bugs the critical bugs in
critical software like internet explorer
we're coming in through zero day
initiative or other defense market
brokers so what did that actually do it
cut off access that microsoft had
directly to the hackers this is bad
it also did something that Microsoft
didn't like which was put a time limit
on effects and I hate that so they were
too kind of undesirable things were
happening even though they were getting
the bugs even though somebody else was
paying for them and even though you know
generally speaking at least a hundred
eighty days would pass before anybody
drop the ODA in this in this little
defensive ecosystem they realize that
they wanted to actually change those
trends to regain direct access to that
hacker community that's capable of
finding those bugs to be able to control
you know essentially the timeline
because of who might know about the
vulnerability and the one piece of data
that I showed the IE team that ended up
knocking over the last of the objections
of Microsoft was data so ye would go
through a public beta period where they
would release you know and a less than
stable version of the software in order
for the class of the the customers to go
ahead and test it in their environments
Microsoft engineers were fixing as many
bugs as they could
during this beta . so what was happening
with all these free you know free bugs
that the hackers were giving microsoft
how many of them do you think we're
coming in during the beta . one thing 40
50 now right actually very few so there
was usually very few vulnerabilities
coming in and then when they come in
there was a giant spike after the final
release of ie the release to
manufacturing so after rtm huge spike of
incoming vulnerabilities
what did that mean well the incentives
at that time for these hackers to come
forward with free bugs that microsoft is
offering was 10 . arial font and their
name in a bulletin so that was the only
incentive than a hacker had now if a bug
is fixed during the beta . chances are
unless it also affected downloadable
versions you weren't going to get your
name in the bulletin so hackers had
inadvertently been trained by Microsoft
to hold onto their bugs until the worst
possible time to tell Microsoft which is
after you're out of the beta . so i
showed the head of IE this big spike at
the worst possible time for engineering
for him and I said look all we need to
do is provide an incentive for these
hackers who are going to help us anyway
to come forward earlier in the beta .
and we can do this traffic shaping
exercise and we can move this spike
vulnerabilities and give you guys the
maximum amount of time to fix it
I didn't get through my little 12 slide
presentation to the head of IE i got to
slide to and he literally said to me
yes yes yes I'm gonna make it easy for
you how much was literally what he said
and I SAT there after a two-and-a-half
years about 12 and a half almost three
years I SAT there saying wait a minute
did that just happen did he just did he
just offered a back a truck of money up
to the microsoft security response and
pay for his bugs and in fact that is
what happened because just because he
wanted to align what the he knew the
hacker community was going to do anyway
which is look for bugs
he wanted to align what he knew the
friendly hackers were going to do anyway
which is turned them over to Microsoft
to get them fixed you wanted to align
all of these activities that were never
with his schedule and he was willing to
pay for it so that was that and that
finally ended Microsoft's long-standing
aversion to paying hackers money
directly for vulnerabilities finally
there was a reason to channel the
hackers eyes channel their energy and
point them at the product they wanted to
find out about which is the latest
product at the time they wanted to find
out about those bugs in the most
advantageous way for engineering and
then ultimately for the customer which
was the earliest part of the beta period
of that product so something else that I
was able to start at that time was not
just an individual bug bounty that was
time-based deliberately and and
orchestrated to move that big spike of
traffic
how many of you have heard of the
mitigation bypass bounty at Microsoft's
the $100,000 bounty that's been going
for the last three years
yeah so at the time you could go to poem
to own and that year you could get a
hundred thousand dollars was the top
prize opponent on that year for you know
coming up with an exploit that would
bypass all of the you know all of the
mitigations of any given platform target
you get a hundred thousand dollars if
you did the live exploits at that you
know at that moment during the contest
what i was able to convince microsoft to
do was not have a contest once a year
but essentially having an ongoing
six-figure bounty that wasn't
necessarily for a single exploit but it
was for something more valuable to
microsoft and that was for a mitigation
bypass technique
how many of you have heard a return
oriented programming ok how many heard
of jet spray right slightly fewer but
it's okay these are all representative
examples of mitigation bypass techniques
so whether you find a vulnerability and
whether you're able to exploit it are
two very different things right
especially as modern platforms have been
made more and more secure
so why would an organization like
Microsoft want to learn about mitigation
bypass techniques as early as possible
does anyone have a guess that's okay
well guess you know what will guess at
karaoke later it'll be more fun
uh-huh you know that's happening tonight
I'm just inviting you all at this moment
so the reason Microsoft needed to know
about it is early as possible is because
to create new mitigations to combat
those exploitation techniques takes not
just a patch tuesday it takes three
architects of the platform on some level
and that is something that usually takes
an operating system company several
iterations to change and it's not
because they're slow and they don't know
how to fix it is because all the
applications that run on top of the
platform all have to have time to adapt
to the new way that the operating system
works so it's essentially an issue of
future thinking engineering to make
exploitation harder because of what
you've learned about today of how
exploitation works on the platform today
these are much longer term fixes and
Microsoft essentially needed to know
about these new techniques as early as
possible to plan how they were going to
deal with it for the next version or
maybe even the version after that of the
operating system now remember I was
talking about those those different
markets and how you know they often will
pay for exclusivity and very high prices
how do you think that Microsoft was
competing directly on price with these
markets and we really think that great
so you don't think that or you've fallen
asleep
perhaps I need to run around you a few
more times ok but the fact of the matter
is they didn't need to compete directly
on price not for those IE
vulnerabilities that were critical
by the way how many of vulnerabilities
do you think were collected in that one
month bug bounty . at the beginning of
the ie11 beta release you want to guess
for a for ya
ok how much money do you think Microsoft
would have had to pay to get those four
maybe critical vulnerabilities
1 million dollars no I didn't hear that
out there
ok no actually what happened was even
though each of those vulnerabilities
there were 18 by the way vulnerabilities
that came in that were valid and what we
would call bulletin class they were
important or critical vulnerabilities 18
of them came in one month about 28,000
dollars total was spent to collect those
18 vulnerabilities
now why do you think you know it was
possible for Microsoft to get these for
such a low price
well think about those other markets
when the office market wants to buy a
bug they want to be able to use it for
attacks
why would they buy a bug during the beta
period of software why would they spend
six figures on an exploitable
vulnerabilities that may evaporate in
next week's you know test a new release
of the the beta software so they
wouldn't so essentially there's a gap in
the market they're now going back to the
hundred-thousand-dollar mitigation
bypass bounty
yes there was that same price for the
Pantone contest that year but remember
that was just offering a hundred
thousand dollars for working exploit it
could use one of those existing
exploitation techniques like return
oriented programming or just spray or
whatever it was didn't need to come up
with a brand-new technique in order to
claim that hundred thousand dollars in
that once a year contest so what was
microsoft thinking you know in terms of
will they have anybody who's willing to
come forward with this very very
valuable technique again think about who
the adversary is and what their goals
are the adversaries goals are to buy
these things that will work for as long
as possible but do they need it to
leverage of brand-new exploitation
technique in order for it to be
effective or worthwhile for them now
because the existing exploitation
techniques were working working just
fine so they didn't need to make that
additional investment in trying to find
these new exploitation techniques the
only party that was going to benefit
from acquiring these two new techniques
was going to be the operating system
manufacturer itself
hence
how i was able to convince microsoft and
not just by its own bugs in terms of ye
but by these new exploitation techniques
at what was until apples bug bounty the
highest ongoing vendor bug bounty or
vendor technique bounty essentially that
had been an unbroken record for the last
three years hundred thousand dollars on
going with no time limit and no end
anyone want to guess what the rate of
Microsoft's learning about new
exploitation was how often would they
would they come across a new
exploitation technique through other
means either disclosure you know from
research or you know from attacks in the
wild
anyone want to guess how often that
would happen before that bounty no one
wants to guess I'm gonna have to run
among you again
ok but actually it was about once every
three years and that corresponds with
the release of you know the operating
systems at that point right the new
mitigations come out some security
researchers and or some attackers would
research the ways that that Microsoft
tried too hard in the platform and make
exploitation harder and then you would
you would become aware of new
exploitation techniques once every three
years
does anyone want to guess at how many
times the hundred-thousand-dollar
mitigation bypass bounty has been paid
out in the last three years
well it's not once they paid out over
half-a-million dollars in this ongoing
County because the hackers who are
capable of thinking their way around the
latest mitigations often weren't doing
it for the money necessarily they might
be doing it for the recognition but they
were definitely doing it for what i call
the pursuit of intellectual happiness
and they were curious to see if they
could defeat these medications and
Microsoft was inviting them to go ahead
and do so and offering them six-figure a
man
aunt and all the publicity they could
possibly stand for being helpful in this
ecosystem so fast forward how did this
actually factor in to the Pentagon so I
had given a lecture about all of these
different mechanisms that I was
employing at Microsoft in order to
intentionally disrupt some of the
dynamics in the vulnerability to exploit
market and intentionally bring in some
of these bugs at certain times some of
these techniques at a faster rate and
all of these things and i had given this
lecture and somebody from the Pentagon
happened to be in the room that was the
first time i was invited to the Pentagon
so i gave the same lecture essentially
to a room full of people in the Pentagon
and one of the things that I noted was
you know as with any military
organization in the modern world there's
certainly where people who were in that
room who were interested in what I was
doing because they were annoyed because
it was going to make their offensive job
harder I don't know who they were i
couldn't identify them but the offensive
arm of you know the biggest military in
the world was in that room but the
defense arm was too and so the
conversations that were started at that
point became conversations I was having
over the next couple of years even as I
left microsoft even as I went to my
former startup company that does bug
bounties the conversations accelerated
this past fall and the reason they did
was because something called the digital
defense service was started inside the
pentagon now if you go into the Pentagon
and you find dds well or someone leads
you there they actually have a little
plaque under the door that says Rebel
Alliance star wars style right so you go
in and they basically say welcome to the
Rebel Alliance they've got you know
little bb-8 you know logos sides
it's an open seating environment and
they've got hackers and programmers from
some of the most interesting technology
companies who are doing rotations in
this place in the whole purpose is to
accelerate the Department of Defense's
acquisition and utilization of modern
technology and modern security
techniques so this brand new group that
had been created for the purpose of
accelerating uh you know dr accelerating
the Pentagon's adoption of Technology
much faster than the usual acquisition
acquisition time cycles of software that
was the group that ended up spearheading
on the inside the creation of hacked the
Pentagon because essentially they were
told do things better do things faster
and I believe in my purse is the card of
Lisa was well that literally says under
her title and this is an officially
issued card from the Pentagon get shit
done it says it on her card so how cool
is that they were they were given a
license to try and experiment with
technology and try an experiment with
some of these proven techniques that
were in the software security world for
acquiring vulnerability information and
interacting with the hacker community so
the time was right they were ready to
essentially launch you know their launch
their rebel their her rebel mission and
I remember getting the call from the
Pentagon saying good news we're going to
go forward with this and I thought this
is insane why is this happening am I
dreaming I'm asleep what time zone mi ni
have no idea how could this even be true
that after all this
they're finally ready to allow hackers
to have them and so how many of you
actually want you know kind of saw the
the unfolding of of the actual hack the
Pentagon challenge the 21 days and
everything couple of you yeah so what
that ended up being was it was a pilot
right to prove the concept to oil the
gears of the people receiving the
vulnerability reports and and needing to
fix the issues on the back end of the
Pentagon 21-day period and they not only
got all of these vulnerabilities i
believe was a hundred thirty-eight
vulnerabilities that they paid 70
thousand dollars for total but they also
got that precious access directly to the
hackers and ash Carter inviting that
child to come stand beside him at the
podium to shake his hand in the secret
coin passing ceremony of of how they
give you challenge coins you know in the
military is supposed to be silent in
person and with a handshake
so if you watch that video you can see
ash Carter kind of getting the coins and
shaking the hands of the people who are
on stage with him including this child
at the end of it
not only did secretary carter announced
how successful the program was but he
announced that it was going to continue
and expand this experiment that 35 years
ago when the movie wargames you know was
coming out and scaring President Reagan
into making hacking a federal crime
from that moment all the way until
secretary Carter is thanking hackers and
asking more of them to come forward and
help
seems like an impossible thing but given
the fact that a long time ago when I was
hacking computers that moment where I
decided that changing the world one bag
at a time wasn't going to be enough
figuring out how these systems worked
how how the objections of these large
organizations worked became my new
hacking mission and essentially that was
what ultimately caused not just
microsoft not just the Pentagon but
we're seeing more and more of this rebel
ocean where huge organizations and
governments are realizing not just the
need to work with hackers but that that
it's actually quite advantageous to them
to do so and that they can't possibly
meet the challenges of today or tomorrow
without us so they restarted my time
like five times what I'm going to do at
this moment is give you about I think
maybe two minutes to ask me some
questions if you're shy
we can take the questions out into the
the Fourier but really I mean what is
this about
I told you about how I was able to
reverse-engineer you know all of the
objections of these large organizations
and in fact exploit the mutual benefit
of being able to work with hackers
directly and in fact pay the money but
what does this have to do with you
how many of you are in organizations
that are considering a bug bounty
program
none you will not admit it ok how many
of you are in organizations that are
capable of receiving a bug report from
the outside
God so few so one thing was interesting
so I mean just for people who you know
will watch this later there were about
five hands that one up in this room that
does not surprise me one of the most
interesting pieces of data from my
former company was they looked at the
Forbes top two thousand companies these
are companies that make billions of
dollars in revenue they spend millions
of dollars on security they do all their
compliance stuff
ninety-four percent of the top two
thousand companies according to forbes
ninety-four percent had no published way
to receive a vulnerability report they
had no email address like secure at
Microsoft they had no web form they had
no page that on their website that even
said we want to hear from you hackers
tell us about our weaknesses ninety-four
percent only six percent had something
at all of the fortune 100 companies six
of them have bug bounty programs
so what does this all mean
this means that the world is not quite
ready for bug bounty programs because
the world is not quite ready to even
hear from you so what I would say to
that before i actually let you ask me
questions is think about all of the ways
in which an organization actually needs
to prepare to receive the bountiful
blessings from the hacker community
which are bugs and help them understand
that essentially there are only three
ways to learn about your vulnerabilities
you can hire pen testers or higher
really smart people to work for you and
find them yourself somebody friendly on
the outside like a partner or a customer
or a hacker can tell you about it or you
can be attacked now of those three
methods logically why would you ever
want to cut off one of them so with that
I would like to thank Dylan Belinda the
hack in the Box crew i would like to
thank all of you for waking up and
standing up and and entertaining me at
least for the last hour or so and i
would also like to open it up for
questions but at the end of the day I
mean we are the ones who have created
this technological world that we depend
on and we're the only ones who can
secure it so thank you so much
questions from the floor
don't be shy
I'm not singing yet ok that's not a
question you can ask but i will take
requests later
so what time is karaoke great question
what time is karaoke after whatever the
party is tonight there will be karaoke
no I mean in all seriousness I know you
may be shy and you might have but nobody
wanted to raise their hand when I asked
you know how many of your organization's
are thinking about but Manny's and then
how many of your organization's can even
receive bugs you probably have a lot of
shy questions you want to ask me in the
hallway and that's okay i'm pretty easy
to find on the internet but i want to
thank again the crew and all of you for
waking up and being with me and
indulging me this morning and now
remember who were those folks stand up
one more time the last group of people
who have been doing computers security
for the last 15 years or more
that last group of people stand up again
come on i know i'm i'm standing alright
these folks give them a hand because and
buy them drinks because my god we've had
so many reasons to drink ourselves to
death in the last 15 or so years
please buy them by the water as well
again thank you so much thank you very
much Katie Missouri's