all righty buddy it is two o'clock
mountain time four o'clock Eastern Time
I'm here with Bryson board and George
are Keeley's that is a lasting or chicas
I know you man it's all good
and I'd like to welcome both here
they're gonna give a talk on an
adversarial emulation with the CG matrix
thank you very much and take it away
well we ran a Twitter poll because in
the olden days of the haxing speakers
used to get Iced and so with that
Smirnoff original which is I'm sure just
as gross and just as tasteless as the
rest of them is what one so in honor of
the olden days just like a virtual
conference we are going to be drinking
one of these so cheers George you cheer
sir oh that tastes horrible oh my god
that's so gross
now
all right we ready this
oh and throw you off all right so
presenting all right so we are going to
be talking on adversarial emulation and
you can see our unicorn is sunny like
they were in San Diego so we are setting
the mindset that we were all in
California together the key to this talk
is we are going to be talking about how
to shift from a win centric mindset aka
ego driven to business driven or results
all too often red team's hackers pen
testers get carried away with trying to
win and the industry has started to
shift now where businesses are beginning
to look for results how do we work
together
of course the arrow is purple for a
reason what do you think that reason is
George
at a time well sorry so yeah purple is
uh how my daughter would say how you
make what happens when you combine red
and blue together and really being
efficient and business centric about the
purple team now the grukk we did two
years ago give a man in O'Day and all of
access for a day teach a man to fish and
he'll have access for life now I started
with this tweet for two reasons one
fishing business email compromise is the
majority access method that attackers
use in the real world and it works for
multiple reasons one statistics are in
my favor I can send you as many fishes
as I want
they cost difference to send one email
to 10 million emails is relatively
negligible and statistics are in my
favor because I just have to get
somebody to click - this is the theory
of this talk so we're going to be
talking a lot about conceptual framework
we're not going to deep dive into
PowerShell we're not going to deep dive
into any particular framework what we're
going to do is we're going to give you a
different way to look at the problem
we're going to give you a different way
to think through the problem and in
addition we're going to provide you a
number of technical resources that we
have built and shared that we will
continue to populate hopefully with some
of y'all's help after this talk to help
make you better in the long term that's
right
first of all Who am I I'm the unicorn
guy I'm also on the board of advisors to
the army cyber Institute I do some work
for sisa at DHS and I'm a senior fellow
of national security and cyber security
at our street
mostly I'm our industry silly unicorn
and I'm George or Gia's I have been in
offensive security for coming up on 10
years now at a large financial industry
contributions include the common
vulnerability scoring system a threat
let penetration testing framework that
we use globally for Red Team and
adversary emulation I teach for since I
have a red team course and other
community things like ISS a shout-out to
them and way back when I wrote a book on
an operating system you should not be
running which is Windows 7 speaking of
books I got some of these to give away
in this talk or whoever comes up with
the nice the best question over on the
channel so that is track 2 talks I'll be
monitoring while Bryson speaks yes so
please participate we love questions we
love comments the heckling probably
won't work so well because you're muted
but we do have several books to give
away on the definitive guide to Red Team
operations and development written by
Joe vest and James Tuberville alright so
obviously I've talked about who I am a
little bit but one thing I just kind of
want to create here is the idea that I
believe in the post access space which
is primarily what we're looking at red
teaming that the defender is not as weak
as we all like to think one of the
things that I've always found strange is
why in information security of all of
the disciplines and humankind's is it
the one place where it seems like
somebody else knows my stuff better than
I do
and that just continue to to sort of
rattle around in my head and I kept
thinking it can't possibly that can't be
true and the first place it's not true
is in communications when an attacker
gains access when they pop shell when
they land with a state zero when they
build that state zero up into a
multistage campaigns they start moving
to a place of interest and they need to
communicate one to be able to do that
because they have to have that command
and control to tell it what to do and
also it's kind of hard to steal anything
if you can't take anything out so for
those two reasons they need to
communicate and the way they do that is
over the communications that are already
organic to that enterprise I can't bring
my own wires to the table
and I can't bring my own communication
protocols to the table I have to use
what's already there because if I don't
I stick out and so one of the core
elements of the attacker is blending in
with what's already organic to that
environment how do they talk when do
they talk what ways do they talk and
being a part of that and then the second
part was well alright so that's that's
limited I can only talk so many ways
there's only so many communication
protocols in the world and companies
aren't gonna be using so many of those
what is an attacker do as a part of that
and the capabilities what they do what
they bring to the table that actually
allows them to accomplish their goal is
also bounded there's only so many things
an attacker can do now there might be a
number of ways to do those things but
their behaviors themselves are actually
finite as well and so I came up this
idea that called a bounded attack space
philosophy which is that while
exploitation whether that's technical
whether that's physical whether that's
social my means to get there is infinite
but what I do once I'm there is actually
a finite space of possibility and
furthermore what's the value of post
exploitation we start looking at post
exploitation we're now primarily dealing
with the largest surface area of every
organization and guess what it's not
technical it's people it's all the
different kinds of users and here we
have a representative example of some of
the different kinds of users from the
folks who don't know how to turn their
computer off and on who the engineers
who always want to be in charge of their
own station do the guy or gal who always
thinks you know what they're doing
Elon Musk whatever the hell he's doing
and then of course somebody else that's
coming in and doing what they want to do
so now we're gonna get into setting the
classic question of pen test versus
adversary emulation so we're all
speaking the same language
as well as we're gonna delve into some
concepts in this section talking about
some conflict of industry definitions
and terms and those are actually some of
the questions we got so shout out to
juice box and champ that's exactly what
we're gonna talk about here just to
level set we can't just get to adversary
emulation there's a maturity model in a
way to get there and what we found
speaking with a number of you that have
been doing this for a while number of
their organizations is that you start
with vulnerability scanning you scan a
bunch of systems you run your Nexus your
next close whatever born ability scanner
scan whatever if it's a web app and you
get a very long report that's step one
then you actually do vulnerability
assessment that involves a human looking
at those results doing some triaging
thinking saying alright this is internal
it's a lab box maybe it's a production
system on the internet and actually
doing some correct risk scoring with
cbss do a scoring system and really set
different boundaries as to should this
be fixed today tomorrow in 90 days or
never fixed from there we have
penetration testing and the main
difference there is that you're actually
going to exploit vulnerabilities and
this is really where a lot of us have
been for quite a bit but then regulators
came and kind of water down what a pen
test is and confined us to these very
limited scopes PCI is probably one of
the best examples that you can only ten
test a certain scope within their
environment once a year you only can hit
certain IDs and you can only attack
during certain times and you can't do
social engineering so because of that
time the term red teaming was started to
be used as a noscope entus or full scope
pen tests where you actually emulate and
do the same tactics techniques and
procedures as a malicious actors that
involves understanding the actor who is
likely to attack you each organizations
can have a different threat model and
then there you get to actually do these
tests
the difference between a red team and a
purple team is that a red team
assessment will be blind that means most
people in the target organization are
not going to know about this you
generally do this for a month to three
months some organizations are doing this
for longer and then you come back at the
end of that with your reports and all
that and you show how you did it and the
blue team gets some value there but
where we're going to is this purple team
concept now all the previous ones these
are still doing right you're not gonna
stop doing more ability scanning you're
not gonna stop doing your pen test or
your blind red team maybe once a year
but you can do some of these purple team
engagements to be more efficient and
purple team is just that combining red
and blue set them together and try these
TTP's see what should happen what should
be caught what should be detected what
should have an alert maybe at the sock
or instant response should be able to
see and that will make you much more
efficient in the short term to catch
some of these one-offs
in addition orienting you to a format
that were using in this presentation
you'll notice in the bottom right we
have a link that link goes to a much
more extended discussion on the maturity
model here in this case by George or
Jia's and throughout the presentation we
will have additional links for
documentation videos websites all
providing you additional information so
that you can build up your sources after
this talk or further detail so
penetration testing like we discussed is
primarily exploitation focused we're
looking at getting access popping shells
is rewarding there is nothing more fun
than to be sitting there banging away
get something and then just like
wargames the green glow of the terminal
lights you up as you finally get in and
you're on now this change here is that
about twenty or thirty years ago this
was all hacking was was a one-person
team focused on exploitation and getting
that shell and there are multiple things
that have changed in the environment
where we still as George discussed one
to look at penetration testing because
it's an important task
of system hardening I'm looking at my
surface area analysis how do I get in
what is my risk to somebody getting in
as I discussed previously though that's
the near infinite space and that's one
of the challenges that we have in
information security is trying to
measure something out of infinity is a
sliding scale furthermore defenses got
good
the software got good the software got
complex and good Microsoft Windows is
now a hard target
it used to be Swiss cheese and so that's
one of the reasons that we've now seen
the shift where while penetration
testing used to be the entire kill cycle
kill chain it's no longer anymore and
it's now just a part of an entire chain
furthermore there's a focus on crown
jewels or bus getting to add me getting
domain admin is good but only getting
domain admin is not so good because if I
get in I escalate and I just own domain
and walk out what does the business
learn furthermore that's not necessarily
what we see in the real world or what an
adversary is going to do so of course
topic here is adversarial emulation what
we're trying to do is getting out of
technically accomplishing something just
interesting that's technical and
understanding in the context of business
results which means we need to look at
what do we see in the real world because
that's the real threat model engagements
are typically shorter for penetration
testing because of course a lot of
things are compliance driven a lot of
folks in information security kind of
sneer at this concept of compliance
driven security because of course we all
know while compliance isn't security
compliance is the starting point for a
business to legally be able to function
if I have a requirement to go do a pen
test to get my check once a year that I
am legally valid as a business to
operate that's the starting point that a
business is going to begin to think of
so red team and penetration testing
internal red team's are going to be
conducting repeated engagement they're
going to be different philosophies
different techniques different
capabilities based on whether you're
internal external for lots of different
reasons internal is focused on repeated
engagements of remediation one of the
advantages can be that they have
privileged or insider knowledge because
they actually work inside that
organization a lot of organizations try
to almost push their red team to the
side for different reasons and that's
that's kind of that constant tension
between how do we create a black box
test versus a grey box versus a white
box test which will we'll define shortly
and then it the external red team is
useful because it offers a different
perspective they have industry
experience so here's a chance to
benchmark okay I'm a financial in what
do I look like compared to other
financials and I can hire a red team
who's had experience doing those kinds
of engagements against other financials
so I can get an industry benchmark the
challenge though of course is these are
incredibly limited by resource and money
so you're gonna get snapshots in time
one of the challenges with the red team
is I can only take do so much in so much
time and so I end up being forced to do
what I call more of a surgical strike I
have to try to focus on a few things get
in a few places do that quickly
demonstrate my value as fast as possible
because that's all the time I either
have with how much money the clients
willing to spend or how much time the
client is willing to spend and George
you are quite familiar with internal red
team yeah and some very good questions
about doing rotation between red and
blue and does you know do you get
diminishing returns because of the
internal red team and like I said I've
been there for will really have the red
team at this financial for about four to
five years and yes we do know the
environment way better that's why it's
often even though if you have an
internal red team sometimes it's good
maybe every two years or something like
that
get a real external red team to come and
and do an adversary emulation to see
what they find the good thing about the
internal red team is that they already
know a lot so they're going to focus
their testing on way more advanced type
of techniques and procedures that they
know will get through and that really
brings out the reasoning of why you
should fix those so I believe both of
them bring value you shouldn't replace
either of them even if you have an
internal red team you'll be able to do
more purple teaming for sure but also
contract an external team every once in
a while so that you get that real third
party no strings attached no prior
knowledge tested Reggie
one of the best insights I got on this
was actually at Wild West a confessed in
Deadwood South Dakota last year in
October and there were group of us
sitting around a table and we were
talking about conference attendees and
Wild West tech fest wild way West
hackfest is primarily a conference with
an offensive security focus and it was
interesting though is that means that
probably only about 20 25 percent of the
attendees are actually out of offensive
security red team penetration testing
seventy eighty percent our blue team or
IT and the other contrast that that was
it was interesting because if you go to
a blue team or an IT conference almost
nobody from offensive security attends
those which I think is a bad thing there
are certainly a lot of folks you don't
typically get started in red team you
usually grow from having learned how an
environment works in fact Jeff McJunkin
who was on this Court earlier today was
talking about how he learned PowerShell
as an exchange administrator before he
went over into offensive security and so
part of what I would like to offer cuz
I'm willing to bet that the hundred or
so attendees that are on right now that
most of you are not actually in the bed
team space that one that's okay
sorry I just got distracted cuz Jeff
just tagged me as I called him out that
cross training is absolutely applicable
we recommend a process and a framework
here that encourages red and blue to
work together at a doctrinal level but
at that same time at the personal level
we absolutely believe that the two sides
should be cross training and sharing
information because that's the best way
to have a business area focus from a
blue team side of why does the red team
engagement need to be something that is
binary they go away and they just come
back with results when I think about
purple teaming what I like to think
about is the fact that a red team is
going to be something that is done in
stages
hey let's validate application
whitelisting let's validate application
whitelisting
as many different places as we can
throughout this enterprise and then once
we do that let's whitelist the campaign
that will come together and say hey
here's what we learned
let's fix those things now let's
whitelist this campaign and go to the
next level we've now just emulated an
adversary by their ability to defeat
application whitelisting
I didn't have to do anything technically
complicated to do that I just had to
coordinate with the blue team that said
alright this executable this I
on script this DLL whatever that payload
is we're going to whitelist it and now
that's the equivalent of the Chinese
defeating our application whitelisting
control and the pic campaign is able to
progress and we're able to do that
collaboratively nobody on this planet is
going to spend the same amount of time
resource or money as a true adversary to
be able to emulate those things so
instead of actually trying to do it at
that level technically it's something
with a simple handshake we can
accomplish the same goal so on that note
this brings up the debate in our
industry about some terms emulation
versus simulation so I'm gonna start
with Tim Malcom Vetter who is the
enterprise red team lead at fortune one
and he notes the dictionary definition
of emulation as a reproduction
simulation as an imitation and then the
concept of a false flag which is a
covert operation designed to deceive by
creating the appearance of a particular
party or group the false flag operations
are where I might repurpose malware upon
the Russians I repurpose Chinese malware
and then I launch an attack on America
the immediate technical forensic
analysis is going to look like I'm the
Chinese because I reused Chinese code
and I've now given a false flag cover of
looking like something that I'm not and
he uses this as a call to the red team
because the red team in a false flag
operation is now boss flagging as an
adversary on the other hand we have
Caitie nickles who during my talk at
Derby Khan
quote emulation is sort of in the spirit
of but we can never match adversaries
exactly whereas simulation applies it's
an exact match so here we have contrary
indicating terms around emulation versus
emulation and to make things even more
complicated we have more simulation with
the breach and attack simulation space
where we now have different definitions
of what simulation is and so what I
would offer is the reason that we chose
the name emulation and adversarial
emulation is because I believe that
there's two levels that we're talking
about
one is where am i trying to replicate
the techniques tactics and procedures of
an adversary that I want to measure my
defensive controls against the other is
what exactly am i doing on a network or
a host computer so for example if I am
going to do ransomware I can't actually
do ransomware on a user's host computer
because no assessment should ever impact
operation so how do I effectively
simulate ransomware on a computer
without effectively ransomware in the
computer and the example that I give and
you can look at this up online where
I've demonstrated it is creating
arbitrary files using local encryption
to encrypt those files calling back to
by c2 server that I'm conducting the red
team operation from so I've host in
network activities tied to ransomware
but I haven't actually affected the
users computer so just kind of two
different levels between actual
operation of what happens on a computer
and then where I'm trying to replicate
the TTP's of an adversary that's a lot
of where we have this industry confusion
tied in to of course what force during
Gartner think that this is anything you
want to add there George yeah I'm
actually just reading through a lot of
people say you know a lot of these are
just buzzwords that I think in spirit
we're all agreeing that what we want to
do is understand how an adversary works
which is what we're gonna jump into
right now
emulate that or actually
that whether you want to call it
simulator me lake and improve at the end
of the day to improve the blue team
improve your detection then your
alerting your prevention and your people
and processes it's a comment on these
being buzzwords of marketing jargon
certainly you're going to find that
challenge throughout there are lots of
vendors lots of products all competing
to try to communicate their own goals
and their own agendas but I would argue
that in the practitioner community it's
really important that we try to come to
a common understanding of what we mean
and why that confusion is because at the
end of the day it's our responsibility
to protect our businesses that's what
we're hired for yeah and not and not let
it get watered down like we left
penetration test and get water down to
mean one IP address and just a little
bit of exploitation here they're the
proverbial missus scan report is a pen
test me exactly so what do we need to do
to be able to effectively do adversary
emulation so the key here is one
flexibility because I need to be able to
change what I'm doing at the host and
the network level to be able to
replicate and I keep using replicate
because I'm now avoiding the use of the
term it emulation to emulate that
particular adversary and it needs to be
repeatable and the reason it needs to be
repeatable is that this should not be a
one-off this becomes something that when
I've created that particular view of an
adversary I'm able to share that with
DevOps I'm able to share that with the
stock I'm able to share that with the
blue team so that's something that they
can take away and work around and I
build up my own baseline and library of
my organization's emulated campaigns to
be able to do that so we talked about
customization I need to be able to
change command and control I need to be
able to change what I'm doing
repeatable this helps me start to
establish metrics of performance because
the reality is that that organization is
always changing and with that change is
going to be the potential degradation of
controls one thing I always like to
point out to folks is how confident are
you that controls are uniform throughout
your enterprise which means that however
you feel you are protecting all of the
employees in that company particularly
an international multinational company
do you think that the controls are all
implemented equally across all of those
computers
kill chain incite so this is where I
talked about finding the defensive
contours where can I move down the kill
chain of determining what works and what
doesn't and then together moving past
that and then moving past that and then
automatable so one of the challenges of
course that we all have in our industry
is the fact that we want to be able to
make it easier or new folks or junior
folks to come up to speed and so part of
what I propose here is that you need to
have this balance in your organization
of the very knowledgeable experts who
can build out these capabilities who can
define them with whatever set of tools
that you're using and that those can be
pushed down so that more junior
operators can work within those limits
and operate them on the environment
so we talked briefly on white box versus
black box this is contentious compart of
the way we do things so white box is I
have full insider knowledge I am given
all of the details for me to be able to
begin like a well-established adversary
versus black box which means I just know
the company I'm looking at and I have to
begin reconnaissance and intelligence
collection to conduct my campaign part
of what I think confuses this is one
this is a little bit of a mix of surface
area analysis and penetration testing
but my personal opinion on it is that I
think all red teams should start from my
white box perspective because I'm
primarily looking at the business
potential risk
what is that contextual risk of what
happens once you get in there's no risk
to reconnaissance there's just a
question of what can you find and the
reality is going back to that nobody is
ever going to invest the same amount of
resources in time as a committed
adversary I'm not aware of any red team
that's ever been hired for a two to five
year red team to do a patient and
stealthy reconnaissance that also
includes interacting with human assets
for information so this is just my
personal view on why I think that red
team should start with a white box
perspective and there's absolutely
nothing lost by even beginning your red
team with set points within the
enterprise I know several large
companies that the bet team begins from
random hosts inside the enterprise and
they begin from there because they just
assume access defense validation of
question right about this of why should
we automate this and I think it's fairly
a great slide to answer that question
let you know that people are asking okay
do you want to take it this goes back to
the question someone just has to blow
what's the value of automating some of
these tests if there are TTP's and the
reason for that is that we want our red
teams to focus on and think and continue
to find new and new and interesting ways
of being able to do certain procedures
certain techniques the example I want to
give was that we
found a particular issue and it required
a lot of moving parts to get there so
for instance a certain log a certain
event ID had to get turned on then that
event ID have to be logged locally then
it have to be sent to a log aggregator
from there had to be sent to a sim do
some sort of security analytics and then
eventually actually show up further
level one analyst to see because it's a
TTP you can't prevent it's just
something we have to live with but we
have to detect it and one of the reasons
why we automated this and we created an
automated method of doing that
particular TTP we were able to give that
to the engineers they would run it see
if that correct log was running they did
that multiple times way better than
having a red team or drop a C to go
through and do or run an atomic red team
etc then once they get back to their
correct logging send it to the correct
place make sure that it's traversing the
network getting to where it needs to
then make sure that the analytics were
working they told me they ended up
running this over 30 times during that
time normally in tradition you'd have
your right team just redoing this
redoing this redoing this in this case
we can have them execute this particular
controlled you know kind of synthetic
type malware and be able to test it
themselves and while our red team got to
focus on another so it's not even
control validation at that point it's
really making sure it works then once
you do have the control you can automate
that control validation pieces make sure
nothing actually stops working right and
you can do this for various TTP's and
what we'll get to the threat Intel part
my turret acts early so back to you guys
yeah so to emphasize there one that
helps me build a library that the entire
organization can start to use because I
think that when we're looking at this
defense outlet validation the red team's
goal is to constantly be able to emulate
the latest and greatest threat to that
organization and I emphasize that to
that organization because not everything
is a threat everybody probably the best
example I can give of that is actually
so this morning I was having a
conversation with somebody and they were
talking about hey nobody has ever looked
at the threats to mining equipment
and my first comment was well what's the
threat bottle there I would say the
threat there is more likely that
somebody is going to be stealing
equipment versus that somebody is going
to try to manipulate this close access
industrial control equipment so just
because something can be done doesn't
mean it's something you have to worry
about we can't worry about all of the
things so we need to find ways to reduce
that burden for ourselves by automating
as much as possible and do that that
that part is the emulating the behavior
so in this example we talked about wanna
cry if I go and get a sample of one a
cry
I can validate myself against that exact
sample so first problem we have in this
ties into a challenge for threat
intelligence is that sample is going to
have a particular hash it's going to
behave a certain way it's going to go to
a particular IP or domain
well attackers already know that you're
going to catch this stuff which is why
they already build in the ability to
shift those things it's relatively easy
to create new signatures it's also not
that difficult to defeat signature ink
techniques that defenders use so I can
even be the same thing and look like a
different thing to you
and then it's not hard for me to
constantly have changing bounce nodes
and ip's and different things this is
part of one of the reasons why botnets
can also be particularly interesting
because they provide me my own basic tor
net for of consumer products for c2 and
so the goal here is being able to look
at ransomware behaviors versus just a
particular kind of ransomware is the
emulation that we want to do and then
the executive perspective on defense
validation is they're looking to
validate their investment in products
they've spent a certain amount of money
on tech on process and on people and
what they would like to know what works
and what doesn't
going back to the comment on marketing
jargon what am I actually getting versus
the snake-oil of what I've been sold I
cannot tell you how many places that
have spent seven digits on a particular
product we go and we do a particular
test and they come back and they go oh
my god
we're spending this amount of money and
it didn't even catch that bear on one
hand there's no worse feeling in the
world then realizing you spent a lot of
money for something that didn't deliver
on the other hand it's really good to
know the truth
so as hard as it is to call that the
emperor has no clothes this is the
executive interest in being able to do
this and then validating the investments
in people so a lot of things when we
look at this the goal across the
defensive matrix of what does a red team
do it's looking at protection it's look
at detection and then it's looking at
response so a part of that could be is
my sock awake are they able to see these
things what should they have seen and
when should they have been able to see
it or in the case of most businesses
because the majority of businesses don't
have their own internal sock what am I
getting for the money that I'm spending
with that managed service security
provider are they meeting their SLA are
they able to catch the obvious things
the threat intelligence today threat
intelligence today is primarily driven
by static identifiers and the reality is
those things are constantly changing so
it's disappointing so one of my points
on this is for us as an industry to be
able to adapt we should not have the
burden as practitioners in the red team
and purple team space to
and read a forty to sixty page analyst
report to try to pull out the
information for us to be able to emulate
an adversary so one piece of work that
came out at last year's attack on mitre
published an open-source toolkit called
tram tram does natural language
processing to go through those reports
and try to bubble that up for you I
think that's a good first step I would
argue that the threat intelligence
industry needs to adapt even further and
they need to be creating not lengthy
endless reports but machine readable for
emulation so instead of producing a 60
page report they produce some sort of
sticks or yarra like format that we're
able to ingest automatically and that's
something that we can put into all of
our tools so one of the things we're
going to talk about here quickly it
shortly is one of the tools that George
and I and several others created to help
catalog and identify all of the command
and control frameworks that are
available out there both open source as
well as proprietary and my point here is
that if the threat intelligence industry
creates a standard for all of us to
build - then all of those frameworks can
now look to ingest that to automatically
be able to replicate whatever they're
trying to do and of course you can't get
by without one reference through the
pyramid of painting by David Bianco the
challenge here of course is threat
intelligence at the bottom of hash IPs
and domains needs to grow up toward the
techniques tactics and procedures which
is really difficult to do given the
current state of affairs and then the
final piece is one of the riskiest ways
of doing this is neutered malware where
I go out take a sample of something
bring it in reverse engineer it make
sure that it's not harmful as well as
make sure that is something I control
and now I can throw that exact same code
out into my environment here is a great
example this is a call out to Katy Katy
no longer works at mitre actually Katy
now works at red canary though thumbs up
Katy but while she was at mitre she
created this idea of how to look at a
traditional threat intelligence report
pull it out and then automatically
correlate it using the mitre attack
matrix which is where we see
these different designations so now I
have the ability to start to look at
what are the metadata of a threat to be
able to emulate it which leads us right
into mitre attack probably just about
everything these days is centered around
mitre attack minor attack is one of the
major hot frameworks that everybody's
going with most of it that you've seen
is all enterprise attack which is
focused on delivery on through
they are fleshing out pre attack and in
addition they're also building out an
attack framework for ICS that was
published at the end of last year
so what mitre attack does for us and
this goes back to that save some of the
same challenges we have in industry one
example of simulation would be that I
run a box in here like account
manipulation so account manipulation in
persistence the then trying to do bypass
user account control and the point is
that I will I will run this and I will
get a score and then I will run bypass
user account and control and get a score
and then I will do something else
separately my argument is that's not
emulation because if you look at the way
an attacker works an attacker is going
to be state based my ability to do
access token manipulation in privilege
escalation is going to be dependent on
what information I've gathered from
being able to do one of these other
techniques my ability to do lateral
movement is going to be radically
different if I have privileges versus I
don't and so the way I like to think
about this is the mitre attack framework
should be looked at like a periodic
table of elements the individual
elements combined together create a
chemical equation which is my ability to
emulate an adversary them individually
are just inert objects so on top of that
they've also published sub techniques so
in addition to the high-level periodic
table there's now a lot more depth in
each one of those squares to go into the
sub techniques that that matched that so
just something to be aware of I like the
good thing about this is miter attack
gives us a common language now to
describe attacks and discuss what's
happening but the challenge is don't get
into a box focus
don't get into a rigid adherence to what
you think is in the framework and there
is no way to just blanket test across
all of mitre attack and don't get caught
up in you know we're green in this box
but yellow in this box it's it's it's
good as a way to describe what's
happening but do not do not over focus
on it and with that we're gonna go to
George with the c2 matrix w w SC 2
matrix comm this started originally
started when the folks over at Specter
off said that they weren't going to
support Empire anymore this was around
june july 2019 and i went and asked some
smart people like just McJunkin who's on
here and Tim and Ed and a few people I
say hey what other seaters do you use I
got a different answer for every person
then started just asking around more and
more and found them quite a bit of SI
toos without real really knowing which
ones worked all of them get hub code
that you have to read quite a bit into
and then talking with Bryson uh-uh
what was that I was Derby con Derby con
bird buggy of other other SI toos I
think you were playing with caldera at
that point or trying to play with
caldera at that point I think it was pre
version 2 and we just started
brainstorming of how cool it would be if
you had a list of all the SI toos with
all the different features because so
far we've talked about getting threat
Intel finding an adversary that's going
to likely to attack you getting out
those TTP's and then figuring out which
situ or what framework you can use that
would emulate most closely to whatever
adversary you want to do and that's
where this came out as you can see on
the screenshot here we have a number of
different factors I think we look at
over 30 different things in particular
focusing on the command and control
channel what protocols are used if you
read thread into and malware and we'll
cover this shortly you'll see a lot of
is over HTTP but you see a number of
them using others like HTTP to SMB ICMP
DNS over HTTP totally just bringing all
these together there's 35 of them right
now as you can see it it's all
completely full and every time we get
close to filling this matrix a new one
gets released generally on a Friday
afternoon so it's a fun little project
it's been taking out quite a bit you can
follow it at c2 matrix on twitter and if
you go to the next slide I want to talk
about a release we're gonna do right now
so one of the things I kept hearing when
we brought out the c2 matrix was how do
you actually get these installed how do
you make them run where the basics and
what we're releasing today is the how-to
so how to dot the C 2 matrix com it
started it's populated only for wild who
has hackfest so you're the first people
to see this and you can actually go
through and click on any of the C twos
and they'll tell you how to get it
installed how to run it and some of the
basics around a listener and agent how
to create that payload etc we also have
a couple other things coming out because
if you've ever tried to install any of
these you know they aren't as
straightforward as possible so as a sans
instructor working with sans we are
coming out with the slingshot C 2 matrix
Edition which will have the top 10 C
twos that we believe most people used
also been working with the folks over at
offensive security Kali Linux already
has PowerShell Empire 3.1 or actually
three one zero it is supported now by
team called BC security but by 2022 it
will have 11 C twos on there so uh this
is really allowing everyone to test
these out all these are open source
already most of them are and then really
the next phase is more strategic view on
how to use the C to matrix which
involves attack mapping an adversary
mapping so if we say a your your C so
comes and says you know January 5th
first day back from work or to work from
the holidays these Iranian threat actors
are high risk now because of the current
global affairs
what can a PT 33 and 34
you can look at the matrix and say
alright the C tubes are most likely
recover these TTP's are these go to the
how-to to end test them out and actually
have valid results for improving your
detective and preventive controls so all
that's available right now how to not
the c2 matrix to work in progress we do
appreciate everyone's feedback and
contributions we also have these c2
matrix stickers I wish I can give you
all but if you contribute I've heard
that you magically receive stickers at
your house I don't know how that works
but uh contributors have have been
saying that they're receiving themselves
pretty cool back to you guys
so emphasis here one this is a community
driven effort George and I and all the
others are not able to do this on our
own
there are new C to matrix excuse me
there are new C two frameworks
constantly coming out there are updates
to the ones that are currently in there
there are a lot of new ideas that we've
been debating for the last few months on
where we want to take this idea even
further we are looking for folks to get
involved in to help we want folks
testing we want folks writing how to's
we want folks crafting how to emulate
specific threats obviously we are going
to be releasing here and short bit some
new distributions which will make it
even easier because a lot of these will
already be installed for you so please
reach out work with us to help make this
better for everybody in the community
what are the ones that I called out here
is called Dara and since we're short on
time this fortunately I'm not going to
do a big demo but we provided some
videos and some documentation walking
through even more detail than what's
currently available on the c2 Matrix
website so the github for it all of the
docs so the good news is caldera is free
you'll notice they even say adversary
emulation in their github so we're on a
good site the bad news is this is the
object tree for caldera
it's his fairly complicated which is all
one of the reasons that this is a pretty
powerful tool I would summarize that
this is a great tool to practice in a
lab a lot of the things that are
required for installation so here are
some of the things you need for
execution make it difficult to use in a
production environment but it is a
fantastic tool for emulation in a lab
environment has a lot of capability and
you'll notice the links down at the
bottom though on the left side is a
thorough walkthrough written walkthrough
that we are sharing on us setting up
specific campaigns and how to do that
and then on the right is a link to the
video for that quickly going through do
you notice any trends here HTTP
obviously rules the day these are all
available for sale for almost nothing
these are still in operation years later
because they still work I talked about
network activities being a finite space
the emphasis I would put on here is the
one place that an adversary can never
fool you because they have to bend the
laws of physics is on the wire at the
network when I go down to become a 1 & 0
I become a 1 and 0 like everybody else
it's only by blending in with the
traffic that I can try to be clever
lateral movement of course is the most
common thing to look for almost no
adversary ends where they want to excuse
me starts where they want to they begin
wherever they begin they have to get
where they need to get which means they
have to pivot throughout and so there's
pivoting there's password spraying a lot
of folks don't look for that internally
use of vulnerabilities inside and then
of course just basic tricks looking at
the combination then from a defensive
perspective is understanding should
these things be talking
should these things be on the same
network segmentation is your friend post
activities we talked about this or the
purple team that we're gonna skip real
quick here to George doing a very fast
summary of an actual purple team
exercise actually got awesome questions
I want to thank everyone that's been
putting in questions because we've been
able to answer them subliminally about
while we're still doing the slide so
purple team exercises one of the things
that someone commented is you know in
your maturity module can you just jump -
purple team and not do red team or do
red team after and the answer is yes
it's just how some organizations matured
there are a number of them that it went
from pen testing to purple teaming and
then doing blind right team so by all
means whatever gets you there gets you
there the purple team exercise is the
way that we did it was blind test first
we're blue team hated the red team
because we were internal and we come in
and win and that was our thought process
back then right was about winning and
that's not the goal the goal is to make
blue better to make your detective and
preventive controls better to train and
improve your people process and
technology so we started doing these
purple team exercises in the first one
had to be in person just because of the
psychological and the history behind it
where it was very adversarial between
blue and red there's an entire talk here
on the bottom right that you can check
out and what's important about a purple
team exercise is to choose those tactics
techniques and procedures correctly you
don't want to choose TTP's that you know
aren't gonna get caught by anything you
actually want to see TPS that will be
detected but not necessarily prevented
and especially doing this early on so it
takes a lot of planning ahead of time
most red team exercises do as well a lot
of talks just focus on no initial access
and defense evasion but the actual prep
time or a purple team or a red team
exercise could be four weeks could be
eight weeks and there's where you want
to choose these TTP's and ensure that
you're bringing battle so start with
those TTP's that you know you detect but
requires a person to actually action and
then move on to
something more sophisticated or
something that should work something
that might not work really depending on
what you want to do so like I mentioned
there's a whole talk I did at the Sands
purple team summit slides are there for
running an in-person purple team II but
they're definitely high value and then
Sina will be doing a presentation on
thought card I've actually been giving
her a number of the lessons learned so
she's gonna have more examples there as
well but definitely bringing value is
the reason we do all of this is to
improve the defenses of our
organizations or your customers of your
third party it's not just about winning
which is exactly how Bryson's started
the conversation today and if you do
want a little more on this this is my
shameless plug I am a sentient
instructor and there's a two-day red
team exercise an adversary emulation
course where we do everything we just
talked about we use threat Intel by luck
of the draw I chose an Iranian threat
actor so well it was very timely in
these past three months to emulate apt
33 in the course we use Empire but you
learn all the basics and lovely
obviously we cover the c2 matrix so it's
a two-day course
5050 so all hands-on and you go into
from initial access all the way to
action on objectives and it's a lot of
fun so reach out if you want to do that
sans announced today that they will be
moving all there in person courses and
conferences between now June 1st to
virtual so we'll still be supporting the
community and anyone that signs up so
hopefully we see you there
Mattie Bryson we're done