what what exactly got you started on
this topic of doing after dumb early it
was I don't know it was a series of it
was one of those things that I get from
from new people like seriously questions
like hey we can I share my screen or my
yep we got your screen right now do you
want do you want like ugly like my face
here no no no they did for whatever
reason this room GoToWebinar does not
know why but the webcams are not working
in this room oh good okay
I'm not word pantastico camera's not
down there normally so the it was the
backstory on that was most you can ask
all the time by new people like I don't
know if I could do this job I'm not
ready for it and just talking through
just a bunch of just dead simple things
and I saw it's sort of an ironic thing
it's that I'll kind of talk about a
little bit more depth but some of the
more advanced people were missing some
simple things that the newer people were
getting and frankly myself included and
then taking that step back I was like
man this this is easier than it should
have been but I was just thinking too
high so it is kind of a fun talk and the
Derek and I did a version of this Derek
Derek Derek banks and at Buck Hills did
a version of this a couple of times we
had a lot of fun with it just just tons
of fun just talking through some really
simple stuff that has kind of a sort of
them unfortunately overlooked sometimes
that can have that you know significant
impact well and it's like I've told you
I'm looking back on the years where I
was doing a lot of testing it seemed
like a lot of the stuff that I did was
just like crap would fall out of the sky
and just work for me like oh I'll try
this password oh crap that works but no
you you have some amazing ones in your
previous presentation looking forward to
see the ones that you have here I think
probably one of the best examples I have
I'm gonna pick on jaw for a little bit
when Jafra started pen testing he jumped
right into a test with a very difficult
Bank and they put him on a workstation
he was trying all kinds of privilege
escalation techniques and all kinds of
crazy cool stuff and he was stuck for
about a week and then I'm like well
throughout that week I was like dude
have you checked different
files and file shares kind of before we
had a like share finder and tools like
that and he was like no no no I haven't
done that yeah I'm gonna try this
technique that I read about I'm gonna
try this technique and sure enough like
five minutes looking into a file chair
there was a share there was like
passwords and it had a bunch of
passwords to servers around the entire
environment it doesn't necessarily have
to be hard right well in that we if I
frankly that was one of the big pieces
where I had that epiphany we had a test
this we ran in financial institution and
they were locked down hard I mean it was
absolutely brutal it was one of those
first sort of apex defenders and we were
getting absolutely nowhere I mean
absolutely it was just it was painful it
wasn't fun and then we started looking
around the file shares and there was
users were setting up file shares all
over the place and sharing financial
information and this was a financial
institution where you had to have ten
million dollars to come knock on their
door so every single one of those bank
accounts had more zeros than I've ever
seen before and his bad guy you don't
need all of the data right you just need
the one and we sort of forget that
sometimes like we need that DEA we need
that database and frankly you don't it
doesn't take much to to live in a you
know some of these countries for the
rest of your life frankly for 10 million
dollars you can look at they've done
well in the US for the rest of your life
how's that all these other other
countries where you could you know
pretty darn near buy the entire thing
well I think it's time to shut down the
inside of the hackers studio Q&A session
and time to kick it over to you for your
presentation so everybody Jimmy Dean was
read siege hacking dumb burly not harder
rigid I have no idea it's funny that
that I have no idea how to pronounce
that I put it in there and I'm like I
don't is that
so I want to say read it'd be like
French but then I sound dumb but I want
to say Redux
but then I feel like I'm trying to
murder French so I'm glad I'm glad I
took that bullet for you yeah but that
was actually going to actively avoid
using that word so I'm glad you took it
for me so it was yeah thanks thanks for
everybody for effort for coming out
oddly enough I'm actually in San Diego I
can see the former con hotels from from
the window here well the rest of the
family is in San Diego I just want to
walk through some sort of examples here
of
it's the simple hacks that you'll see
kind of fun stories related to that as
well
I'm going to keep the questions and
comments I'd like to see if we can keep
this kind of interactive if you've got
some questions or comments along the way
happy to take some of those one of the
things that I've learned over my career
is it's important to be lazy and IT what
which sounds really weird I remember in
eighth grade we had mr. Kaylor and I'm
sure some of you out there are of that
same age remember the printers that had
the the track paper right you can make
the cool banners because it was all
together and it had that little stuff on
the side I would she make these monster
monster banners right and on this banner
he had this the same and forget exactly
what it was what it was but it was
something to the effect of the best
programmers are the laziest people and I
remember seeing that it's just being
shocked said him it always had been told
during my my classes you know don't be
lazy work hard and then he literally the
first day I explained it to us like what
why why is it important to be lazy Z
because the computer is really good at
doing the same thing twice don't do that
yourself right so you know try this some
of that that simple stuff person and
sort of an extra on that story I
remember my mom came in for tarrant
parent-teacher conference conferences
and she would she came home and she was
just livid like I can't believe Kaler is
a Tony who has to be lazy a bubble and I
tried to explain to her why that made
sense and it was lost on her cell with
week we just agreed to what to disagree
but when it comes to hacking it's
important to remember do some of the
simple stuff first right try dumb and
and this is what the real world
bad guys are doing here we always talk
about abt right apt is the one that has
breached every single organization
because frankly no one wants to admit
it's a 16 year old kid in mom's basement
which literally happened this was Apple
right we think Apple we think pretty
good security I know some of you
probably don't but whatever you know big
giant Apple they were breached by a 16
year old kid in Melbourne and when the
police came to the kids house they found
all of the Apple files in a directory on
his dad desktop in a directory called a
hacky hack hack in fact I was I was
wearing my heckie heckie shirt but you
can't see me right now but you don't
have to be this super advanced attacker
and frankly many of the breaches that we
see it's not some brand new O'Day that's
the way in it is not some sort of custom
payload that ended up getting them in
it's going to be some sort of
off-the-shelf some sort of vulnerability
that's been around for a while some sort
of technique that's been around for a
long time one of my favorite things to
do is I like listening to the darknet
Diaries super well done a professional
podcast they talk through a number of
times in their just various breeches
it's the same boring sort of stuff over
and over again and then we talked I talk
to clients all the time and they're
trying to set up those overly
complicated settings to it it said to
keep the bad guys out but then you ask
about some of the simple things well
yeah well that's that's not important
and and it's frankly miss focused
because the the simpler stuff I mean
that's how the bad guys are getting in
right and even if you talk about your
real apt your true nation-state apt
they're not going to bring down there's
you know their brand-new special hammer
until they absolutely have to
you don't lead with that because if you
use as an apt the off-the-shelf tools
good luck with attribution right because
if every single bad guy and the face of
the planet has this exact same tool and
you're the apt and you're using it there
is no way they can trace it back to you
know who actually launched this attack
apt is is kind of a lie many ways it's
mostly just the persistence threads and
frankly the persistence often times is
in a way itself a little bit of a lie
let's take a look at an example here
I'm still in this example from my
previous presentation
Equifax right and I'm not trying to beat
up on the people expecto facts but this
is an important case study so with
Equifax it let's walk through some with
into the timeline here March 2017 so
almost what three years ago today
earlier this week actually March tenth
is my brother and my brother-in-law's
birthday but the Apache stretch only
buddy was released right noticed assert
everybody gets the patched around that
day cool now this is a significant
vulnerability critical risk ideally or
get what organizations are doing is
patching this very quickly what we saw
in this but specific case was in with
Equifax we know the date here was March
12th this is when the breach happened
this is two months two months two months
after the the vulnerability is announced
now if you think this through we talked
about apt right the advanced persistent
threat this is an off-the-shelf pooled
off-the-shelf exploit that has been
around for months and this is the way in
right how advanced is it if they're
actually using just you know readily
available tools how persistent are they
actually if it took them two months to
do that now of course no organization
that gets breached is gonna come out and
say yeah we were we were breached by
just some thread actor right they want
to say the apt so it sounds worse but
realistically that's not often gonna be
the case right when of course they were
inside the network for a for a long time
since between detection and the initial
disclosure was a hundred and forty-one
days so about five months and nearly
three months between when the breach
happened and our detection a key here of
course is we've got to get up somewhere
patchy that's kind of another whole
discussion on developing patches and
identifying vulnerabilities why we
actually wrote a course where we talk
through some more of this and the
difficulties sometimes in identifying
these vulnerabilities
if you're not readily available on the
surface but the key here is the bad guys
didn't do anything necessarily special
it was off the shelf and it took him
months to what to do it right so
definitely not going to be advanced no
we're uh persistent so this is one of my
favorite wanna this one I got from uh
from Derrick banks this one absolutely
cracks me up so he was on a pen test
trying to use a net get downloaded Ned
cats and the AV just dinged him right
away no question just BAM it was gone
just glued the file and he was stuck so
so what Derrick did this it's so dumb
it's so brilliant I love it what he did
is he whips you and map now the end map
project they have a tool called n cat
and cat is like n map but it's got extra
features the beautiful thing is it's
part of a well-known projects right
every one of us knows and map and have
probably used n map at some point in
time and cat as part of that so he
downloaded n cat and it worked just
great
right there was there was no he had no
point in time did he have to try to
re-encode did he have to try to encrypt
his shellcode did he have to
reimplemented some sort of tool and
rewriting in c-sharp and then injected
him to memory or whatever it was just
using another tool from somebody else
and it worked just fine this is one of
those examples were trying this simple
stuff works and trying it first right
this this how much time we did it's
saved to try this versus doing your own
manual encoding if you've done that
spent time doing that that can be a
tremendous amount of time and you're
really just throwing a bunch of
spaghetti at the wall and hoping
something sticks beautiful beautifully
elegant I love this simple frankly a
little bit dirty a bit of work
absolutely fantastically well right the
other thing that we always see now what
I did is I guess today I was just wanted
to check on some more ideas so I wrote a
tweet and I've got a link to the tweet
at the very end because there
hundreds of responses for people that
responded with simple dumb hacks that
that happened and it was too many with
the bad passwords and this is one of
those situations where like talking to
clients where they're trying to fix all
these weird edge case security issues
meanwhile everybody in their
organization has these craptastic
passwords right I mean we get like
winner 2019 and of course the reason is
according to you know what forever ago
Moses came down from a mountain with a
third tablet on the third tab but he
said thou shalt change
nine passwords every 90 days of course
people can't remember their passwords
and they hate calling the helpdesk after
a while so they ended up just looking
outside and essentially - deriving their
password from nature right because it
outside the weather changes every 90
days I probably snowy where many of you
are and 90 days from now we'll probably
see some flowers and 90 days from now
and nice and hot and sunny and then 90
days later it'll be a the trees are
turning colors so they can literally
look outside and see their password and
of course there's a winter this year in
a winter next year we got capital W
lowercase enter and they need a number
and also they can't repeat the last
seven thousand eight hundred and forty
two passwords so they need another way
to differentiate some of those passwords
so they simply do of course bad the ear
and maybe they need a special character
that's gonna be the season then the year
then of course you're probably playing
along at home here the bang right top
left key on the keyboard and there were
so many tweets related to this where
people just used these types of
passwords to get in and if you work at
one an organisation I'm sure many of you
are on the blue team ideally you
implement a tool to ban these passwords
right if you end up telling users not to
use these passwords to be honest that's
that's not going to work you can see the
the tweet here from Anders I'm gonna
mess his name up leo
et or he says he depended a password
spray for an entire company and got 30%
so a password spray is you're gonna try
a few passwords for everybody in the
organization I was doing this a number
of years ago and at one organization
they had the it was like fall went into
winter try and fall or winter spring
like fall autumn or winter with the year
I think it was I don't know what it was
now but we had 16.3% of the people with
that set of that bat password that means
you go to somebody you take a die you'll
roll it you get a six they have that
season in year type of password and then
you see organizations focusing on all
these other much more complicated
security controls when they're missing a
simple one here and when it comes back
to the training right we tell users
don't pick this season in the air but if
you think about it from their
perspective they just want to get their
work done and they don't want to be in
this stupid security meeting just as
much as you don't want to be in the you
know whatever other training it'd be at
your organization that doesn't relate to
your day job so they're sitting there
tired in their seats and they hear this
season in the year and looking at what
this is a great idea I'm gonna do
exactly that and it could be anything
like that doesn't it to be the season in
year if you're gonna ban these passwords
which you should other things that
should be banned it should be your
company name you definitely want to make
sure that the user name and password
don't match those are gonna be some
significant things there but this one
works time and time again this is the
gift that keeps on giving
so defenders if even if you can't get
the blocks in place to ban these
passwords I would HIGHLY encourage you
get a process in place where you can
dump you the passwords crack them find
these provided it additional training to
these that these people and then force
them to to what to change their password
fun ones are default credentials related
to that obviously I was in one
organization and the password was simple
similar to you like orange one and of
course if user change the password what
has become Orange
sometimes default default passwords we
are now priming the pump it might not be
one of the normal quote unquote default
passwords or what passwords that leads
we see for example this season in year
but now you're priming the pump and we
saw that organization there was Orange -
orange three orange four we went up all
the way to 99 and we had I think it was
well over a quarter of the organization
with that type of a password so that's
part of your policy burn that thing with
fire alright another lovely one this one
cracked me up then coming back from some
of the tweets I had seen this I wasn't
quite sure how widespread this was
actually going to be but head number
people talk about test accounts my
favorite here out of Baldwin top right I
typed asdf asdf will demonstrate an
easier name enumeration in a login page
and it it worked it was a test user
created by the developer and that was
left in place I've seen things like that
I thought I was just a random lucky
thing
no there's another one bottom right here
a wiry bull Freddy Krueger and worked
just fine
I actually had a situation and this one
was actually kind of bad similar to
David here where I was doing a test and
I came across a domain admin account it
was actually for another pen test
company and no I won't share the name of
the pen test company and that account
was left left around from about the same
time I was there last year and led me to
believe that it was there you know
previous pen test the year before able
to log back log back in with that right
we wanted to make sure we clean that
stuff up that should be as part of a
process if you do a pen test have your
IR have someone in your team do they
clean up if it comes to those test
accounts make sure you clean those up
because invariably if it's a test
account it's going to have a craptastic
potential
but other lovely things that are just so
beautiful I almost feel dirty that
unfortunately or I mean of course from
an offensive person's perspective I
guess in a way
fortunately work all out - - well let's
see the number of times where you
attempts to log in and the pages like
you know what that password doesn't work
why don't you try this one the number
for examples where these credentials are
just floating around failed logins oh by
the way try this look in the page source
is it high-tech no does it work way too
often right we can see here like Zacks
what cracks me up a couple other words
similar ones as well where to make life
a little bit easier on us let's go to
the next page because this is all the
same is what admins will do is they sort
of assume that Active Directory is
invisible to end-users right Active
Directory stores all the account
information they assume that you you
can't do can't look at that unless
you're one of the IT admins so you see
this all over the place where the
password is stored as an attribute in
Active Directory most of the time in
clear text which means if you have some
sort of tool to look at that boom it's
going to rain those credentials down on
you and of course this is connect you
echoed by those those number of people
that I've seen online I don't wanna get
too much in the password we beat up
passwords but frankly I mean it just
happens time and time again and we're
focusing on all these heavy other
projects and if we could just get rid of
the password problem a lot of life sort
of goes away let me jump on the head
just a touch so you're probably thinking
like well of course if you've got crappy
passwords the answer that is MFA now one
of the quote on the guys are my team
Mike Saunders like he loves to bring MFA
to its knees it cracks me up he actually
in the last two or three pens s he was
doing it he was working on just broke
the MFA and it was frankly kind of a
dumb break
so what happened is hit the login page
enter the username entered the password
I had asked for the token and all he
simply did is then redirect to the rest
of the page force prowess to them to the
website never says like Oh
fair enough I think the website was
thinking oh if you got to this point the
only way you could get here is if you
authenticated so clearly you must be
okay so you know it was to call that the
the shopping cart problem right with the
shopping cart you put something in the
shopping cart you go to shipping you pay
the bill and there you go you finish the
order process the shopping cart issue is
you just skip the payment piece and the
only way of course that a normal user is
going to get to that complete my
checkout process is if they went through
the process so the server just assumes
they were good to go and we get stuff
for up for free all right so the mfa
it's awesome but make sure that you test
to make sure that's properly implemented
right let me go back a little bit so
we're talking about the passports there
right all right let's change gears a
little bit now this kind of goes back to
hey I was one of the I was kind of new
at one point right of course we all work
and I wanted to learn more about IOT
Hackett so I didn't know what to do so
what happened was I looked at a friend
of Mines blog post he had this lovely
blog post here this is 2012 on how he
found this issue in this trend that
camera right so let's walk through what
he did so what he grabbed his he grabbed
the firmware and then he use a tool
called bin walk now in 2012 bin walk it
was it didn't have all the features we
have today but what it did and frankly
does is it looks at some things like
firmware and it will identify different
section headers there's oftentimes our
firmware is just a bunch of files that
are kind of like duct-taped together in
a one file so what Ben walk does is it
looks for those various headers and the
newer versions will actually chop it up
for you now back in the olden days you
would do that chopping yourself you had
to get your Ginsu out chuck chop this
Rob so here's an example of where he
used didi to chop up the file in a
couple of pieces now I simply look at
the third fire the third file if you ran
the file command on it now what file
does is it checks for magic looks for
specific headers or footers in the file
to identify the file type and found that
it was just in Linux file system that
cool just unzipped it uncompressed it
and then mounted it and started looking
around the file system now in his case
he found a directory called server
inside server was directory called CGI
bin inside that was a directory called
inany take a guess what a Nani
stands for right a Nani his course is
going to be anonymous so it gave
anonymous access which means anybody
could ask access this webcam and do the
stream this is his page
pardon the the words at the bottom but
this is a straight screenshot from his
his blog simple access No pretty
straightforward so what I did I'm like
you know what I'm gonna do the same
thing so I bought a different camera off
of ebay I'm sorry Amazon walk through
the same sort of process where extracted
did DD it looked a little bit different
tracted the filesystem might use other
people's tools and techniques don't feel
like you have to reinvent the wheel
frankly maybe you even buy the same
product and walk through the exact same
process somebody else to grab this take
it home now if you grab a Linux file
system
cuz mine extracts it into a Linux file
system where's one of the first places
you're gonna look at like the first file
I am I'm assuming most of you are saying
Etsy password or maybe Etsy shadow
well with old Linux systems and the
password hashes were actually stored in
Etsy password right hence the name then
we learned hey you know it's not a great
idea to have aspirin hashes publicly
readable readable world readable by all
users so we can move that into Etsy
shadow now that's old Linux systems and
also brand new I
he devices so this device had you know
one Linux account
it was root so but everything's running
his route what's the point of having
etsy shadow and also the passwords were
stored using this really fancy
encryption called base64 right base64 of
course is not encryption so all we had
to do is just decode it I mean you could
type you can technically just decode it
by hand if you took a look at this
looked in the the web interface saw this
this user admin and then looked in Etsy
password and saw admin looked at my Etsy
password saw a viewer saw that the web
interface cool looked in Etsy password
found this factory test user it was not
in the web page so it says backdoor
account for for frankly test it had gave
us test access to be a camera and it was
a backdoor account that provided access
to the device and it was literally just
me I don't spin it I'm like necessarily
special here but I just followed
somebody else's back by numbers I mean I
felt a little bit dirty frankly no I
didn't feel so dirty when I did a bug
bounty and they gave me like four
thousand US dollars for it um but it
doesn't have to be oftentimes that
complicated
yep you were saying well it's getting
harder these days true but there's still
a lot of relatively simple stuff out
there try some of that simple stuff
first you don't have to reverse-engineer
the arm code you don't have to reverse
engineer or some random HTTP HTTP server
just look for some of the dumb and dead
simple stuff first another one of these
sort of uh situations
I had a iPad and I travel a lot because
I teach and I think we do consigned to
consulting I had my iPad I have an Apple
TV and what I wanted to do is I wanted
to watch my Amazon Prime on my Apple TV
but it was back in the days when Amazon
and Apple they had this huge pissing
match it was just this weird battle and
then the consumers were the ones taking
the brunt of it but I was watching
Amazon Prime on my iPad and I couldn't
watch it on my Apple TV I wanted to
watch it on a nice TV
but Amazon's like nope sorry can't do it
so I looked at the configuration here
every time I lost the app that would
pull a configuration down from from
Amazon inside the the configuration was
a line that said airplay enabled false I
was like you bunch of jerks the K the
capability here the feature is here but
you're turning off by my screen sharing
basically out of spite because I've paid
for the content that paid for my prime I
paid for the Apple TV I paid for the
iPad like mother this is staff in any
way shape or form they were just saying
sorry you can't do it this way because
we're pissed off each other so of course
I did like any reasonable hacker what is
I setup burp and when the connection
came down I changed that airplay enabled
from false to trip Dennis on air and it
said there was an application signing of
the configuration was improperly site
scroll down for the configure of the the
configuration at the very bottom was a
signature now this is a situation where
I typically ask the my class hey what
next and what I typically see this is
this is always it it's really
enlightening and it's this is one of the
pieces that kind of led me to this talk
is I'll see the more advanced people say
well let's reverse engineer how the
signing takes place and see if we have
overrides or is the key available or
something like that
meanwhile I'll see somebody neuter like
what what happens if you just delete the
signature okay like Oh
dead dumb simple simply just going into
the configuration with burp deleting
that signature it would come down to the
device the app would receive the
configuration attempt to verify the
signature and then say oh yeah well you
don't miss thing I'm sure it's in you on
and it worked just fine and I've seen
this more than once again how much time
wouldn't have taken to your reverse
engineering the entire signature process
and maybe we don't find a vulnerability
there dead simple just try the simple
thing here first right
talk about the MFA let's skip on to the
next one one of my other favorite bugs
was the Mac OS bug right so you can just
hit enter a few times with it with Mac
OS trying to get root root prawns you'd
be like yeah fair enough you tried you
did you did good enough I'm just gonna
give you root level access love that bug
is it high tech is it fancy is there any
sort of code reverse engineering now
some dude or do that just sad the
computer and mashed enter a couple of
times in frustration found this lovely
bug religious that is my favorite
vulnerability of all kind so we had that
mssql so my sequel this is a little bit
old now but still my favorite bug what
happens is you would authenticate to my
sequel and 1 out of 256 times it would
just say alright fair enough I call this
one the soccer trophy writing a soccer
trophy doesn't matter how terrible your
team is everyone gets the award that's
this it's like hey you know what good
job you tried hard enough I'm gonna let
you in anyway the story that I've heard
I don't know if it's true or not is
somebody wearing a bone scanner against
their my sequel and the bone scanner
reported a specific password as working
the security engineer went back attempts
to log in with that password and it
didn't work
tried it again and it didn't work and
then just got frustrated it put it in a
for loop and then all of a sudden like
200 tries later it works right
this bug just cracks me up I can't even
imagine the look on this engineers face
when they they figured this one out but
again just a little bit of dumb sort of
good force made that one not work quite
well so if you want to read some more
here's the original tweet there is a
whole giant list related to it a bunch
of simple dumb hacks there's a long
address down at the very bottom no one
wants to type that so I've got a short
link here let's each comm slash simple
dash app so one of the keys here of
course is you never know too much
never you never none of these attacks
are necessarily that we talk through
required super advanced knowledge and I
find myself I don't know about you but
sometimes I get stuck in my mind that
this next thing that this current thing
that I'm working on it's gonna be super
hard so I need to take this to 11 to
pull off the hack when realistically
this is like a 0.1 we're just trying the
simple stuff first related to that
here's an example so here's example
let's sort of walk through this together
a little bit
this actually won me a free trip to Las
Vegas and a black hat it's a little bit
modified here but I had something like
this so there was a app that worked on
your Android device at the time and the
goal was whoever scored enough points in
the app would get this free trip and I'm
like cool I've never been the black trip
but a black hat before I want to go so I
was like alright let's make this work so
what happened is when you registered
your device it would send a request kind
of similar to this this is just mostly
made-up but the format is largely the
same send this request to their service
and after this you would get 10 points
10 points for your first registering
okay good deal so if we take a look at
this we can see magic here at the
beginning and then data so I was like at
first like hey okay cool how can I get
more points this is the time where I'm
demonstrating this in a couple of
specifically in my mobile pen test
course that I used to teach I asked the
class like what next right how can I
score more points and immediately a
significant portion of the class is a
call that looks like base64 let's decode
that but think dumb early writes what is
the more simple approach and I hope
there's a couple of you at home saying
you know what screw decoding what
happened simply just send this over and
over and over again
exactly and that worked perfect so what
happened was we would just take the same
post send it in over and over and over
and over again and we
start coin points like crazy now this at
the time my friend of mine Tim tomes I
mean I'm not saying he's not friend of
mine he's still a friend of mine but we
both were competing for this so I'm
sending in my request I've got this
quick little I think it was just typing
a text file into netcat and then just
wrapping it in a for loop and then Tim
Tim don't lay - 53 he started doing the
exact same thing and he started passing
me on the scoreboard so then I ended up
using like two threads so he tried to
use in three threads and I'm trying like
four and his internet was was faster but
he's beaten and I ended up spool this up
on a bunch of different such like
digitalocean boxes and stuff so I could
blow past him and I remember it was
Mother's Day weekend we were going out
it was we were in Texas we were out to
breakfast with my mother-in-law and I
remember refreshing that scoreboard
don't like I should pass him in about
ten minutes about ten minutes comes past
and I'm getting text messages now from
Tom from Greg did Brett my
mother-in-law's Mother's Day breakfast
and I approached didn't mess them with
my phone but he starts texting he's like
hey man what's going on and I thought he
was just asking like how did I get to go
so much faster then we look back the
entire website is down
that's like comes back up a little while
later and they say sorry
no more replay attacks and they had
actually fixed the replay so we tried to
do this again we would get no additional
points so at this point Tim is ahead of
me by just a little bit like we'll wrap
now I'm stuck right I still want to go
Tim's ahead of me yeah I'm upset right
so at this point what's the next step of
course the answer at this point is then
what we have to do a little bit of
reverse engineering the short version is
we would take apart the apk file with
just a freely available tool looked
forward to the search for magic I mean
it was that simple just search for magic
found this function that essentially
what it did is it took the data portion
you can see that here it took the data
portion
base64-encoded again grab the last if I
remember correctly last eight characters
and then the seventh character or
something like that and that's how it
built the quote-unquote magic so now
we're able to do is take the data
regenerate the unique ID that was used
to uh count as a registration rebuild
our magic were like some friend of a
wizard at this point generating magic on
the fly right I think I'm a little eerie
Potter up in this stuff and then started
scoring again I had in that point Tim
and I get went back and forth to our
head-to-head and he started writing his
with with multi-threaded so again and
stuck with that situation I Tim got the
better internet connection Tim tomes I
guess there were both Tim's that could
be a little bit confusing he's got that
better internet connection I'm still
losing now an important thing to note
here is if you remember a little bit
about the specs and how HTTP works we
have what's called an HTTP keep alive
so what was happening with our scripts
is it was through syn syn ack ack send
the data and then tear down the
connection and then we would send it
again syn synack up send the data tear
down the connection so I was like you
know what what if we just connect left
the connection open so we don't have the
additional overhead of the syn syn ack
ack and the teardown we syn ack syn syn
ack ack and then just did it and it did
it data and just spam it as quickly as
possible that's exactly what ended up
doing again simple nothing fancy there
nothing like this is silly sort of the
proof force ultimately I ended up
getting it was funny I talked to Tim and
I told him what I was doing after I got
well ahead of him he's like oh that's
pretty cool I'm like dude can you just
let me win this he's like oh you wanted
to go oh yeah I wanted to go to go I'm
already going to blackhat so I got my my
free trip there but again there wasn't
anything necessarily fancy with us the
very simple piece the replay upfront
dead simple literally you can capture it
with Berger just click click and then
just get sort of a free pour
it's free money in a way if you will
another important thing especially as
senior people
I saw the quote forget the exact details
but confidence is not about being
confident and always being right it's
about being confident to say I don't
know it took me a while to figure that
out because I figured as an expert I'm
supposed to be the smartest person in
the room and I'm supposed to know
everything but there is a tremendous
amount of power to say you know what
I don't know also you're gonna have new
people on your team teams a different
perspectives and different experiences
and as the more senior type person it's
really easy for us to say you know a
better way to do that and we all work
with those types of people the the the
person who's the know-it-all who always
knows a better way to do something
that's great but if I'm always talking
about how I have the better ways to do
it at no point in time am i learning
which means I'm gonna absolutely plant
tell one of the most valuable things
I've learned is sit back shut up and
listen any one of these attacks that
we've talked about earlier this could've
ended some sort of new person on the
newb if you will but it come up and say
hey you know what why don't we just try
some this dead simple web right and if I
had squashed them enough times with
here's a better way to do it they're not
willing to speak up right get that
perspective there might be a better way
to do it but I wanna see it's empowering
I remember being the new person and I
worked in environment where that my
manager always knew a better way to do
it and it was soul-crushing he was a
smart guy but even when I was right I
was in a way wrong because he was the
smart person in the room don't squash
that and it's really it's really hard to
you see it all the time in IT where we
kind of want to show off with our
experience don't be that person get some
of that input use it there's going to be
a tremendous amount of value there and
frankly it's going to help you learn
some of that as well so take the simple
approach right all these are different
attacks that we saw try this simple
stuff first frankly from a defensive
perspective we talked about passwords if
you're implementing the latest and
greatest DLP cool you're missing some of
the mark here if you've got regularly
regularly end users are using some of
these terrible passwords that we talked
about before or you've got other gaping
holes that you kind of just don't want
to deal with but you've got budget
because I don't know some higher-up went
to RSA and bought this latest and
greatest tool here we need those simple
couple of pieces
last year anions event where we were
talking through vulnerability management
and and talking through the process and
and one of the people in the classroom
worth of the forum rather was saying
what he did is he just gave each baited
business unit three vulnerabilities to
work on each month that's it just three
the three that he thought were the
biggest risk and it was beautiful in its
simplicity because any group can be like
yeah I could fix three things cool I got
it but he could give him this giant list
they're just overwhelmed and they don't
know which one to do first or the list
is too long so they get none of it done
but if you break it down to these sort
of simple steps with the biggest risk
first instead of the fancy pantsy a sort
of behind you tool right another thing I
would encourage you to do - so I'm sort
of trying to pump up the new people a
little bit even if you're new you have a
perspective you have a different
perspective you end you have different
experiences than I do I want to hear
that time and time again I hear people
say well you know what I'm not ready to
give a talk I don't know the the things
to say I don't have the latest and
greatest new attack and I'm I'm
ironically trying to paraphrase John in
front of John which is making me wet my
pants a little bit
but he had some sort of story that maybe
John will jump here in at the end a it
complete this story but he told me he's
like Tim look you've got some
experiences you're pretty smart guy
which I was humbled by because I don't
try to do your talks that try to impress
the wizards I you've got people in the
room who are just starting out who are
maybe on the blue team or maybe an IT
and they need useful digestible
information if you come here and you're
trying to sort of in a way show off and
dazzle and everybody you might impress
the Wizards but is it going to be
accessible to everybody is LARP it
across the board and I see this cuz
we'll write blog posts that are more
advanced and frankly the more simple
ones are the ones that can get way more
hits on because frankly that's what
people need so if that's you if you've
never given a talk before go out there
and give it frankly go out there and
give a talk it doesn't have to be on a
tool that you wrote you could give a
talk at your local event or whatever it
might be on somebody else's tool but
give me your perspective on it tell me
why it's interesting to you because
that's what's interesting to me sitting
in the audience I want to see your
passion in your interest to come through
in these talks I want to see your
perspective on it why is it important to
you and again get out there and put
yourself out there there's plenty of
different ways to do this there's you
know local cons there's local meetups of
course there's some of the bigger ones
as well many different conferences above
us hacking fest included has help or
other new speakers out there do it
please do that the other sort of fear
point is people are always afraid of hey
you know what the the more advanced
people these quote-unquote wizards
they're gonna look down upon me at no
point in time has app have I ever seen
this and frankly if they do screw those
people is everybody else can use these
types of attacks so with that that is
going to let to wrap up my talk there's
a lovely QR code that gives you access
to the slides if you want those now get
people who are like not clicking your QR
code fine don't
but this be the worst way to hack you
ever between my name and two different
ways to as a concept so with that that's
gonna wrap up the talk questions do we
have any questions I can answer here so
looks like we do have some questions
who is the best noob you know that's a
Kevin Johnson question by the way huh so
look I think that you can look at that
as who is the best person at Penn
testing that you've seen that just kind
of
just got started you're like holy crap
they're really good well let's see
what's interesting I would see that as a
different perspective I like that idea
but I think a real power is if you were
experience pain faster and you can think
you can sort of go back and we had and
break things down into two simple and
then not to kiss but here but I think
liquid for example John when he breaks
things down to his analogies yeah it's
dead
thinking a simple Josh writes another
one where breaks things down to the
simple basic steps really oh yeah
why didn't I understand that sooner
right yeah the other one holy smokes I
don't know I'd have to think that
through there put me on that thanks
Kevin could you at least text to me so I
could about that one through of course
it's Kevin that asks that really really
hard question right look questions like
that Kevin's the guy if you ask me who
we can ask that question like Kevin yeah
I I'm trying to think of a guess I guess
okay I'll go with this I'll take a shot
buy you some time I remember and this
Kevin's were kind of primed it for me we
were doing a pen test with secure ideas
and phis years ago Kevin I don't know if
you remember this one and there were
like two amazing vulnerabilities that
came out of it one was the vulnerability
I think Kevin it was your team actually
I'm just gonna promote Kevin it'll just
be so much easier just to promote him
but I think it was the secure ideas team
that found out if you purchased a
negative one thing it credited your
account the cost of that no so I'm gonna
make him a panelists real real quick
I cannot revoke this once it's been
granted Kevin don't make me regret this
um so he should be coming on here in a
second that was I think that was Kevin's
team he purchased a negative it was like
a two-factor token thing but there's
then there that was the first pen test
of Ethan Ethan rubbish from Black Hills
information security and he found this
really ridiculously cool way of
executing a cross-site request forgery
attack this particular customer I
remember Kevin like these guys had money
they were very very good
and everything it was very very solid
and it was like one of your junior
testers and like my junior tester came
out with these two mind-blowing
vulnerabilities right out of the gate
yes yeah it's always amazing I think
Tim's point of paying attention to noobs
and not crushing them by always
correcting them or giving them your idea
is some of the best advice I've ever
heard well and I also think kind of
watching and making sure your team
doesn't crush itself going back to some
other interns years ago wonderful we you
know kind of start them out by going
through more ability assessment scanning
results we had one intern Kelsey at the
time she was just going through this
stuff meticulously she was treating it
like an accountant and going through
everything and researching everything
and grouping it by vulnerability and
plugin ID and I was in the room with the
two interns Kelsey and the other intern
and the other intern was just
downplaying everything that she said it
was just kind of putting her down
putting down her ideas and that was
stupid I don't know boy you're wasting
time on that and Kelsey was finding the
vulnerabilities the other intern was not
the other intern sounded like he was a
total badass hacker and one of those
interns now worked in has for a number
of years and Kelsey you know what I
can't remember his name but the way that
she approached things was absolutely the
right way meticulous and curiosity or
the two driving factors yes absolutely
the ability for a team pay attention I
will also say self-sabotage is bad
people have gotten so ingrained with the
idea that they don't know that you bring
them onto your team and they're just
doubting and doubting and doubting and
your job is to make them not doubt well
do you want to talk a little bit about
you when you joined in guardians at the
time they were in Tull guardians because
if I remember correctly you had imposter
syndrome real bad when you started I
don't know why you say that in past
tense because you're yeah good point all
right I don't want to talk about it
because it's it's Tim's presentation I
feel rude stepping in no no that's the
whole point I mean that I'm gonna let
the noob talk no no sir no by the way
your explanation of what my question was
is exactly correct and I want you to add
your own
that list of people who are able to
break things down in very simple
explanations yeah it's not that you
learn that I see other people do that
right and be able to do that is
tremendously useful but they had no
please I think your story's valuable
input here so please go for it well I
mean I joined in guardians I'm so
ingrained that were not allowed to call
him the other name so I joined in
guardians and it was some of the biggest
names in the industry that I knew of
and I then worked with them and I knew
nothing it didn't matter what and and
the idea of working with Tom Liston and
Mike poor and Matt Carpenter and like
it's just wow right I mean I learned
Linux by reading stuff from JBL and then
I had to be on calls with him and
explain to him what I was doing with a
Linux box you want talking about
pressure yeah it was just nuts and then
you start realizing that every single
person you look up to is looking up to
you or people like you or everybody else
right like we it's all the same it's
Devon part to do that transition if I if
I could add in there to like my first I
bought a college actually sort of second
I interned there left for a year went
back but it was these single worst job
experience I mean we were put in extra
hours I mean it literally I thought
about like jumping off of buildings and
that's not an exaggeration or order but
it was it was miserable and I kept
getting squashed and I remember going to
like the next job and and the boss man
was asking for input I was like what is
this like I didn't know I didn't know
what to do with it I think we hired you
on the team because we think you're good
at this
of course we want your input and that
was just I don't know mind-blowing ly
enabling and friendly maybe want to work
harder and made me a better person it
was it was so much more fulfilling right
I no matter what I think a lot of us go
back in our history and we had someone
that saw us in the early part of our
careers knew we were an idiot but still
saw kind of that spark that curiosity
still willing to put the time and
investment into it Mike before yeah Mike
poor I took a class from Mike and he
took
students to dinner and I got to sit next
to him and this was back in the days of
base right and Mike was talking to me
and Mike Mike just basically said what
do you want to be like when you grow up
what do you want to be and you don't
need like I haven't grown up still I'm
47 but um and it's not my birthday I
said to Mike I want to be you I wanted I
want to do what you're doing and he sat
with me we finished dinner we went back
to the hotel and sat mate I don't know
what time we finally went back to our
rooms and she just walked me through
stuff like well have you thought about
this have you done this and and then he
followed back up with me right like it
was hey what are you up to what are you
doing what are you doing next it was
amazing and and I hope that I get to be
able to do that for other people right
that's what we all should aspire to
Devon it's okay I still want to be Mike
poor everybody wants to be Mike or come
on and now he's working swords
okay you don't be him if you guys don't
know the voice Jonathan ham has joined
the panel and he also has a great intern
story as well I'll tell it I'll tell it
really quick nobody home week nobody
believes that now I'll tell it as quick
as I can
it was it was years years and years ago
when I was still at LMG and and got
called into massive project or one of
the biggest top three software companies
on the planet and one of the projects
was they had some people in the audience
probably heard this but they had sent
out a corporate wide memo to every
business unit on the planet that if
you're going to be spitting syslog spit
it at this IP address so they had
seventy's didn't know that like 27,000
sources of syslog spitting at a virtual
IP address load-balanced behind which
they had a massive array of our syslog
servers behind which they hadn't even
massive array of network at that storage
the likes of which I couldn't even
fathom and all they could do with it was
check the box saying aggregating logs
yes create plugs yes our drive light
they couldn't they couldn't do anything
with it and so the first chore that fell
to me was we need to be able to make
sense of this because we're going to
start shoving all that and the Splunk
but we need to be able to know what is
the thing of the 27,000 sources what is
the thing that's generating these syslog
logs I took one of my interns at LMG who
was just fresh out of the University of
Montana with his CS degree and a copious
knowledge of Python yeah this is Eric
right but no this wasn't Eric this is
Dave and Harrison
oh okay I hope it ends with David I
don't know how the story ends but well
the way it went was I figured all right
either I'm writing this in Perl and he's
gonna have to learn Perl to work to work
with me where I'm gonna have to learn
Python with him so I bent and and we did
it in Python but the only way that it
the only way that it could work out was
we had to do real machine learning and
and David was amazing he wrote machine
learning code in Perl that by the time
we trained this program because of you
know machine learning it doesn't that
you you you have to tell it how right by
the time we trained this machine
learning algorithm it could pick out it
could know the source of a syslog entry
by making model of the source off of a
single syslog entry with five nines of
accuracy and that's that's literally the
only way that you could parse through
that much data to try to make sense of
it right yeah well that was the only way
yeah but that's that was an intern right
fresh out of college with his CS degree
figured out how to do that I was near
support I was what I was training the
algorithm the hero I think as you're
used to Perl that right once we'd never
language
I haven't written a scrap of bro since
man