time travel and GPS that's fun I've
already kind of announced Larry and Mike
Larry is a co-host of security weekly
since the very beginning I have way too
many pictures on my computer of Larry
and various states of undress wearing a
Linksys wart
everyone has their hobbies but Larry is
one of the most brilliant wireless
security researchers we ever seen an
instructor with Sansa stood for a long
time he's been a agents with in
guardians for a long time as well
learned a tremendous amount from Larry
over the years almost anything weird
obscure and brilliant comes through
Larry has everyone just kind of shared
stuff with Larry Larry is probably the
nicest person in information scary and
then Mike pour as I mentioned is a big
brother to me
founding member of the consulting firm
Ingo pians and I keep saying this and
Guardians is the company that I hope VH
is can be we keep trying to aspire to
that level and they keep trying to
impress and amaze and succeeding at it
so with that I'm gonna hand it over to
Larry and Mike take it away folks thanks
John Jynx thanks thanks John it's a
pleasure to be here sorry we couldn't be
all doing in this in person but we will
raise our virtual glasses to all the
attendees and to all of the wildest I
can stuff Wild West hacking best staff
who are doing an amazing job and rolling
with the punches
so thank thank you very much you know I
know speaking for Mike that we
definitely appreciate the the
opportunity Mike what do you say how
about we dig right into it yeah it
sounds great I also just wanted to
extend my own personal thanks to John
and his amazing team you know we've all
been maintaining a lot of contact over
the last month or so over this just to
tell a little personal story in 2003 I
was working for Sam's and they sent me
to teach at the Sam Stars I mean sorry
Stan's Singapore conference during the
SARS epidemic they had canceled the Hong
Kong conference that was kind of the
outside of mainland China epicenter of
the stars epidemic then in Singapore
they decided to go ahead with it because
their Ministry of Health was basically
saying yeah we have 54 people but
they're all in quarantine and we're fine
everything's good I faced the prospect
at the time my wife and I we were
recently expecting at the time our you
know first on max I faced this daunting
idea of getting flown into an epidemic
with
real knowledge at a time we didn't
really know anything about SARS other
than it was spreading and it was deadly
that really impacted me tremendously
it impacted sands and a bunch of other
training organizations in lieu of that
you know sands grew most of their remote
training capabilities from that
particular event when when John and I
started talking about this and and the
phis staff you know looking at this this
was definitely one of those I don't know
if it's gonna work but we probably
really should go virtual for this so I
really appreciate everybody's
understanding in fact you know tons of
people that signed up for the particular
this particular event after it went
virtual because all of a sudden they
were able to attend so thank you to
everybody all gets and these are showing
up pH is especially gone and Felda Jason
and folks all deserve a huge huge air
hog and and round of applause you know
for pulling this off
so let's get let's get into this Larry
uh you know who the hell are we
absolutely so yeah I was having a little
issues those of them slides here but I
think we got it fixed so hey now you can
actually see stuff aside from the the
main screen there so yeah Mike who the F
are we I run in guardians with with my
business partners my main role comes in
the form of consigliere actually wartime
consigliere meaning when the shit hits
the fan that's usually when I engage the
most but after retiring from Sam's three
years ago I've taken a very active role
in managing the day-to-day operations of
the company my background is in
intrusion detection and data analysis we
I don't know about the expert there
Thank You Larry for the benefit of the
doubt
bassam someone writes your intro I like
it I like it I've spent a good deal of
my career as an educator and and the
public speaker over the past three years
I drove headfirst into the wonderful
world of blade smithing and sword
smithing you might see a little as seen
on forged in fire let me know in discord
if you caught that episode it was season
7 episode 19 the pyrrha episode lots of
fun this journey has really taken me to
a lot of places met wonderful people
some of them overlap we have Rob Decker
who was also at season one of Fortune
Fire
he's a InfoSec consultant at a Delaware
good friend of Larry's great InfoSec
practitioner and amazing bladesmith I'm
definitely a foodie and I love to cook
how about you Larry I'm the director of
research atom Guardians and the
technical operations manager helping the
guys keep the the wheels on the ground
and providing resources and stuff to the
folks as well as helping come up with
crazy ideas and start to potentially
find ways to implement crazy ideas very
much like the subject of today's talk I
happen to love the Internet of Things
all sorts of wireless protocols
software-defined radio and spend a lot
of time both professionally and as a
hobby doing those types of things I'm a
huge Star Wars fan haven't gotten my
stormtrooper outfit put together yet mr.
Kevin Johnson but soon and I also teach
the San 617 or the SANS Institute that
is the Wi-Fi class and I'm currently
lead author with a good friend James Lee
David all much like Mike I also do have
a bunch of other hobbies as well Mike
has been instrumental in getting me down
the knife making path and has been a
mentor in that I'm getting there
it takes some time we've had carpenters
in our family and engineers in our
family so I'd also say that I'm an
amateur sawdust maker in fact I'd like
to spend a little bit of time workshop
every morning making some sawdust of
some variety and if it's not sawdust
it's some sort of metal dust as well
very much to the wireless portion I'm
also a ham radio operator and I don't
nearly get as much time to devote to it
as I would like but now figuring I was
going to have to be on video to be doing
this talk I cleaned my office and my
office is actually like clean and I can
get to my ham radio and maybe I'll
actually turn that on every once in a
while too so thanks John thanks for for
having us and because now I have a clean
office I think we're gonna have lots of
fun today
and know some of those crazy ideas get
to be put in place for this one Mike
it's time to in for us to dive in on
some technical type of stuff which is
maybe a little unusual for a keynote so
clearly
based on the title of our talk time
travel travel and GPS fuckery we're very
much dealing with some satellite
navigation type of things and we want to
give everybody a little bit of technical
background as to how some of these types
of systems work at a high level we don't
want to make it too super technical it's
a key note after all but we want to
illustrate this to illustrate some of
the problems that we found and then sort
of bring that to some of our conclusions
so the fundamentals for satellite
navigation effectively we have a bunch
of satellites or each of the various
disparate systems in orbit at a known
position that are transmitting from
space down to earth
an RF signal that has data encoded in
that that RF signal it includes a
pseudo-random code that we can now use
to identify those transmissions it
includes the time of transmission from
the satellite otherwise known as the t o
T or the time of transmission and its
position orbiting the Earth at the time
of transmission so the satellite is
effectively all of the satellites are
effectively telling us where they are
and what time they were at so where they
were at what time we receive these
signals at our GPS receiver whether it
be our phone or some custom home built
thing or our sat-nav in our car
you name it once we receive that RF
energy we use that pseudo-random code to
align the packet to begin to tell us
where the start is and then decode the
rest of the information out of it such
as the time of transmission from the
satellite which then is compared to the
time of arrival from four satellites
this gives us the ability to tell how
far the distance has traveled based on
the speed of light we know the effective
distance it's told us where we are we
calculate how long it took to get here
gives us an effective distance from
those satellites with four satellites we
can now use that to gain some insight as
to where we are on those planets by some
effective triangulation so that turns
into the time of flight value how long
it took for that signal to get from the
satellite to our receiver and then we
compare
those with the time of tear transmission
times of arrival and use those would be
like to tell us where we are on the
planet so effectively we're using math
and all sorts of other fun stuff so we
need a bunch of satellites and we need
some equations to be able to determine
distance based on the speed of light and
the averages and the triangulation based
on those different values for time of
transition transmission to time of
arrival to create time of flight so lots
of lots of really interesting math and
yep math is absolutely heart and office
products also suck for math equations so
lots of sort of detail here but to make
this really easy the TLDR on our
satellite navigation space force math
and magic I actually included space
force as a joke when I was creating
these slides and turns out the US based
GPS satellite navigation system is
actually now managed by the United
States space force so not so much of a
joke after all satellites in space
sending RF that we use to calculate the
distance from that satellite to us or
triangulation to be able to determine
our location we have multiple systems
deployed with around the planet with
similar math it really was only able to
dig up the math for GPS but they are all
using similar types of things with
triangulation they may be using
different types of packet formatting and
pseudo random types of codes but we have
multiple systems and in various
locations so we have GPS here in the US
we have Galileo in Europe and a few
other locations as well there's also
GLONASS which is Russian implementation
of satellite navigation which is all
over the planet and then there's a few
smaller systems I do or China IRNSS
specifically for India and qz SS for
Japan and the Asia Oceania area to be
able to cover Australia and New Zealand
as well but the point being here is that
all of these systems use similar types
of math to similar types of
functionality for various places on the
planet and have multiple features
there's two abilities one force of
billion use so unencrypted signals and
then the ability to encrypt packets
based on a set of shared keys from
military applications where they can do
finer grained keishon analysis by more
accurately doing time of transmission
and and and so forth as well all of the
various systems have multiple add-ons to
do resolution enhancements so all sorts
of different types of abilities for us
to improve these systems over the years
and make certain of these resolution
enhancements available for either
civilian and/or military applications
because we also include the concept of
time with satellite navigation from the
time of transmission and so forth it's
also a very effective time source for
time synchronization and in many cases
where an atomic clock isn't used is used
for time synchronization for various NTP
servers so we may be starting to allude
as to where we can start doing some
potential time travel Mike you're up
satellite transmissions are weak yet but
that's a wonderful intro to the slide
the deal here is that satellite power
generation capabilities are relatively
low for what they are these systems were
designed originally more used by the
military after a job NEAs
engineer essentially reverse engineered
the signal this became available
essentially to the you know the civilian
use of GPS what we have today these
transmissions themselves are relatively
weak they have to happen often so on a
continuous basis these satellites are
solar-powered granted they have a little
bit better access and a little less a
cover then we do down here for solar
power because of that it really dictates
a window of opportunity or people on the
ground or people in low orbit to
essentially transmit a stronger signal
the other thing to think about here is
that in all of that math that Larry you
know so eloquently describes there was
no authentication of that signal
reception on the civilian side of things
right so you know you fire up your phone
you fire up a GPS handset for example I
fire up the the the chartplotter on my
sailboat for example and it's gonna
start receiving the signals doing the
math calculating our position and
because of that the fact
it's unauthenticated it's coming from a
signal transmission that is relatively
weak and from far away
these can be interfered with right now I
want to point out over here technically
illegal right license transmissions
Vance meaning that by law which of
course only affects law-abiding
individuals but by law were not allowed
to manipulate or spoof or transmit on
these particular bans unless you have a
license to do so and because there's no
method for this mutual authentication
and the signals are weak and there's
motivation to manipulate these signals
you talk it into the you know in a bit
what ends up happening is that as long
as you can move that signal that radio
frequency signal to the the general
location of where you are it is
relatively trivial to start manipulating
the time as well as manipulating
location data based on that right now
there are some mitigation technologies
that do exist they're very expensive to
implement there they're certainly not
for the the casual user you know for
example if you had a you know
multi-billion dollar enterprise that
relied on you know GPS time signals for
example then it would make sense to
implement something you know to one
mitigate the problem two to try to
detect any manipulations that are
currently taking place one thing you
know I'd like to point out kind of as a
driver for for for us to start me
looking at this one uh there really
weren't any civilian and certainly no
open-source projects that would allow
you to actually detect the manipulation
of these GPS signals so that would that
was a definite good motivation the other
thing is that those of you that have
seen you know the the the wonderful
movie The Hunt for Red October I live
right next on my sailboat right next to
the Hood Canal which is essentially our
version of polyarny right so if the
kemper peninsula here in the northwest
were to secede from the United States
not suggesting it they would be the
third largest nuclear power on the
planet so that's where we keep our
boomers over here on the Pacific
side and so regularly when we're sailing
we run across
nuclear submarines so that are above
water of being escorted by Navy and
Coast Guard and so you know based on
some of the things that we'll discuss in
a little bit
I started thinking you know are they
spoofing GPS are they spoofing AIS which
we'll talk about as well are they in
addition to all of this you know and
being up here next to the straight up on
to Foucault which is one of the largest
shipping channels in the United States
the side thing to that is that the US
Navy out of Naval Air Station Whidbey
operates a large fleet of growlers that
are outfitted with electronic warfare
capability and they've made part of the
Olympics out here on electronic warfare
range so that was kind of a secondary
motivation for me to really want to
develop a system that would detect any
kind of manipulation of these signals
it's definitely been an interesting
project so far and I really can't wait
to see where it goes all right thanks
Mike yeah we we talked about you know
that potentially these these signals are
spoonful and and absolutely it actually
it's fairly easy for us as civilians to
spoof GPS with some readily available
commodity hardware would be hacker F and
some other software-defined radios and
some free open-source software with GPS
SDR sim available for free and can spoof
GPS over a short distance using the
power of the heck RF now of course we
could potentially make this larger with
some amplifiers and so forth again
technically illegal to do so if you're
doing any experimentation make sure
you're being smart about this consider
Faraday cages consider direct connection
from your devices via cable and then
still doing those in a Faraday cage
again be very careful with testing type
of these types of stuff now with the
hacker F and and some free open-source
software we can spoof both location or
time so if a civilian can do that very
inexpensively why do we trust it and
then who really cares who's gonna mess
with it I mean maybe you just want to
mess with it so that you can go get
Pokemon and and those types of things
but maybe there's some more larger
applications
or something outside of the civilian
market and maybe into the military
sector and certainly a motivation and or
those with significantly more funds or
motivation say nation-states have the
ability to have more advanced
capabilities and maybe highly motivated
to perform GPS puckery so what happens
when we start messing with GPS Mike you
tell me well you know and we're speaking
about GPS here but but what we're really
talking about is any one of these global
navigation satellite systems you know
have these inherent problems so you know
apologies for using the term
interchangeably yes when we first got
into this you know Larry and I are
clearly still having problems with that
in that us we think of GPS and GPS only
outside of here a lot of the experts in
this field always refer to this as you
know GNSS the things that we use to
trust these things huge financial
systems dock trading for example where
does it get its time you might ask well
actually from signal that's based off of
this many years ago I did a project
looking specifically at NTP and she
started looking at taxi systems and all
these other systems that use NTP to
synchronize their time based
transactions and then you start looking
at things like the Bureau of Prisons or
you start looking at large companies
that rely on navigation and tracking so
for example your huge logistics and
shipping organizations that you have
obviously state and military things that
are directly pulling stuff off of this
you've got you know for example we'll
cover some of the things going on around
the world in Russia and China and other
places and also in the United States you
have trucking companies that are
tracking their truck drivers in their
trucks across country with with GPS for
example many other organizations and
uses for using GPS other than just
simple navigation I say simple
navigation as if it's a given right it's
definitely something that is relatively
easy to do on a simple level the more
complex kind of fuckery that you want to
you know get into with GPS for example
or any of the GNSS systems obviously you
know your hardware and your power
requirements go way up but we'll look at
a couple of those types of situations
right but when you look at what happens
when time changes well obviously
anything that is using time based
transactions from your financial
transaction stock trading and so forth
to airport luggage passenger and flight
tracking and many other things right
we've got issues with ICS SCADA and
general in the infrastructure Internet
of Things uses you know time based
signals for a lot of their stuff
including seating of session credentials
and and other things as well already
mentioned financial systems rely on that
precise timing and most of these systems
you know just to realize are reliant on
this even though there's no
authentication of signal right which was
one of those things that really blew my
mind when we started looking at this
like well hold on a second all of these
disparate industries if you will are
relying on a signal that has just
inherent open trust built into it as a
standard for example the systems that
are connected to ntp or via WWV be so
radio transmission of these GPS time
signals for example so pretty much all
of your radio clocks across the United
States are all essentially deriving
their time out of a rake radio frequency
server that is based in Colorado and
sending that data out so here we have a
nice little quote from NIST a
hypothetical disruption to GPS could
result in a thirty to forty five billion
dollars in economic losses over a 30-day
period so a tremendous amount of
business requires a GPS you know I know
from my side on the water for example
that all of our shipping is almost
entirely reliant on GPS or other global
satellite navigation systems right the
but primarily GPS
so when Chinese ships are coming into US
waters there are auto pilots for these
cargo ships that are cruising along at
25 to 40 knots they are basing their
signal off of these satellites so if for
example that signal is skewed bad things
are gonna happen some people haven't
have hypothesized now this is a
conspiracy theory or hypothesis sizing
exercise here but we had two very
specific events that happened in the
Pacific in the realm of the South China
Sea and between the South China Sea and
the Sea of Japan where large US Navy
boats went off course one of them ran
aground the other well ran into another
ship show and immediately following that
the u.s. Navy reactivated their
celestial navigation courses as a
requirement for anybody that's going to
be driving one of those things now it's
kind of telling to me when the United
States Navy decides that they want to go
back to a sextant town and a bunch of
tables to determine where the location
was on the planet so one of the first
kind of places where we started to see
widespread global navigation satellite
system spoofing and fuckery was out of
the Russian Federation so there's been
an ongoing project that are between a
group of engineers that are studying
this problem and but this originally
came out of fishing boats on the Black
Sea for example they had a number of
their boats go off course they were
noticing that their GLONASS receivers
for example were bearing white widely
you know showing them on land and
deviating from course and they started
to bring this data up to to the news and
the news media would would publish it
and so forth but what they uncovered was
currently as far as we know the most
sophisticated levels of the satellite
navigation system spoofing out there so
the Russians have been heavily involved
for a number of different reasons one to
protect their VIPs right they're very
important Putin's right you've got a
situation where they've seen this in
Moscow
they've seen this around important
events like the Sochi Olympics for
example they've seen this around
sensitive facilities the military
facilities and the like and including
one facility where it was originally
built as essentially a palace for the
Russian leadership kind of a a a Camp
David retreat on the OSHA are on the see
this reporting by these fishing captains
is actually forced the public attention
on what was going on it had been going
on in Moscow kind of for about a year
and a half or two before it was noticed
by the fishing captains and it is
currently an extremely active area you
can see from the slide that during these
exercises hundreds of shifts both
civilian military you know fishing
vessels so some kind of working vessels
all affected with false locations
hopefully they were using their eyes and
ears and nose as their primary senses of
navigation a magnetic compass and so
forth but I can tell you from a civilian
standpoint there are very few vessels
out there that are constantly doing dead
reckoning and and doing course plotting
on paper even though it is still
required in many locations so you know
that this allowed you know the Russians
to one develop extensive capabilities in
this arena another active area that we
see is Syria Syria is a huge place for
global navigation fuckery because you
know they're trying to protect their
assets they're trying to get our systems
to go off course for example so you know
if you wanted to protect a specific
location you would essentially skew the
the global navigation position for that
location so that if bombs like RJ dams
for example which enable essentially
dumb munitions to act as smart munitions
they're using a constant tracking of a
global navigation satellite system to
hit its intended target so if you change
the position of target a to location B
for example that JDAM once it leaves the
aircraft's news glowing
to find its target at location B as
opposed to location a the and in
addition to that provide essentially a
bubble where they can essentially move
positions change positions report false
positions to a wide area both on the
grounds and to low level orbit depending
on the power requirements here a little
bit on the technical side for some of
the ways that they're rumored to be
doing this they're performing some RF
jamming based attacks from both mobile
and fixed locations effectively creating
excess RF noise on the channels for the
l2 and the l5 signal coming from those
those satellites effectively forcing the
receivers to fall back to that the
primary and use the primary of l1 which
is quite easy to provide a spoof signal
for you have all these signals that you
can use and now all of them go away
except for one and its unauthenticated
potentially unauthenticated and now
you're just reliant on this one which is
now which is now spoofed yeah absolutely
the actual technology that they're using
you know for example or alleged to be
using in Russia and on their operations
is very sophisticated but the the base
parameters is a relatively simple right
so it's a question of acquiring hardware
and operating in a space that is
currently illegal in the United States
to operate other next layer we've been
shanghaied so uh the same group that has
been studying the global navigation
satellite spoofing activity noticed that
there was spoofing at the port of
Shanghai now they were doing a number of
things they they were spoofing GPS
signals they were spoofing Baidu signals
which is their particular satellite
navigation system also there was alleged
AI asked
signal spoofing so AIS is the using of
the VHF band to transmit location data
and additional data about the vessels
that are around you so for example I'll
take my sailboat out and fire up the the
chart plotter that is connected to a is
transmitter and receiver and that way my
course location and speed is transmitted
over VHF to those two
vessels in the local area the vessels in
the local area will see that on their
chart water and notify them if there's
going to be an imminent collision for
example and a bunch of other kind of
parameters that are surrounding that
from a is a s gets its data from GPS
that's that that's how it knows kind of
where it is on the planet owns it uses
calculation based on that data to figure
out course signal and speed so that when
transmits the heading information and
the speed information to the surrounding
vessels over VHF so we're looking at you
know what is it dive like 10 miles or
you know a rough line of sight to the
horizon it's 16 kilometers so that that
should be about 10 miles a you know in
in freedom units with regard to what we
see here is we see we see them
especially around the port of Shanghai
doing this now there are many reasons
why that could be happening right it's
certainly a unknown motivation right but
let's just say that you were trying to
track a specific shipping container
within the port of Shanghai well this
would make it very difficult to do there
are many governments around the world
that that ship things and put them
essentially on hold in different ports
for when they need them this could be a
way to essentially elude the precise
location of those within within that
area and the port for example it might
be as eluded here of potential to a sort
smuggling or illegal mining on the river
it could be something to deter piracy
right so that pirates couldn't rely on
the GPS signal but the problem is with
some of those theories for example is
that well if the Pirates can't rely on
the GPS signal neither can the shipping
captain's I've only seen video footage
of your chart plotters as you come into
let's say the port of Shanghai or the
port of Singapore for example and even
with all of that assisted navigation it
would be an absolute nightmare it's an
that to navigate I couldn't even imagine
without it and or if that data was wrong
or incorrect just as a side note that's
one of the things that we're really
concerned about here in the Pacific
Northwest with our shipping is having an
electronic warfare range that is jamming
signals moving signals and other things
so close to one of our most important
shipping channels and it's shared
between the US and Canada
same thing for the port of Shanghai it
definitely points to something unusual
going on we don't know what it is we've
also been able to confirm the GPS
confirm the GPS spoofing through things
like Strava for example you can see
essentially areas of kind of bloom of
data outside of the general clusters you
know which shows you that there's been
deviation in that direct area Odile we
can make a little animated gif going
going on there all right all right so
yeah it you know you know thinking back
to how easy it is for some civilians to
do this a couple commands here using GPS
SD our sim with a hack RF you need to
effectively calculate your time and/or
position based on a friend me I can't
pronounce it so we're gonna ephemerides
there we go
effectively did the knowledge of where
the satellites are to generate the
signal coming from l1 to be able to
either manipulate time and/or location
it generates a transmission which then
you play back with hacker of transfer
it's quite simple for us as millions to
be able to do some GPS spoofing over
short distances so we can do the same
things that nation-states can do over
much smaller distances and it's now
something within the realm of things
that that we can do Mike and I were
talking about some of this type of stuff
and the question came up of well clearly
they have these folks with loss of
motivation that the cads project the
University of Texas and various other
nation-state capability or detecting
when GPS is being messed with the
problem is is there's no method for
civilians to be able to detect GPS
occurring so how do we do that there's
been a couple of projects out there to
deal with the GPS health one of them is
gal Mon which monitors the signals from
the satellites themselves to interpret
how they're reporting their health so
it's not the same sort of data and in
speaking with the gal Mountain folks
that there has been some of this data
available but it's been largely in a
khadeem
and of those projects for University of
Texas and cads which I'm just not privy
to
and just as a little side note
definitely go check out the Galman
project it was started literally two
weeks before we announced our project
which is awesome or at least they they
went public with their data it was put
together by a friend of mine Bert Hubert
in Holland it's brilliant guy used to
work with the Fox IT over there in the
Netherlands as Larry said it's really
focused on the health of the GNSS
satellites and their signal so if they
start to identify drifts for example or
a natural change in in gain for example
from those satellites they can confer
with the folks that are managing these
satellites to see you know if one the
signal is degrading if that satellite
has to be retired and or replaced what
we're more interested in is well is
there GPS fuckery going on or even time
signal fuckery going on and how can we
detect it how can you uri detect it
opposed to you know waiting for you know
some massively large funded projects you
know from you know a government agency
for example to detect it and or tell us
about it exactly well we started getting
into this we're like okay well let's
build one how hard could this be Larry
well it actually wasn't too bad but we
had lots of help so as part of this
keynote Mike I'm just gonna say you know
we we're calling this project whale in
and this is after a character in a
wonderful James Bond movie and we're
we're GPS fuckery was was definitely
introduced to the public when I called
Larry up and I said hey we should do
this so it would be a 1 an interesting
research project we have a couple
locations around where we could
potentially pick up some of this kind of
manipulation of that a signal and one
other thing about the signal
manipulation that we didn't mention is I
mentioned about the track companies
trying to monitor their trucks over GPS
and everything else well in the United
States that literally is the most common
use or manipulating GPS signal is done
by the truckers so if you live next to a
highway definitely put together a whale
in sensor and start start detecting when
those trucks are going by and spoofing
your
location signals definitely interesting
so Larry once you take it away
absolutely Mike and I talked about this
and research to what it would take to do
some detection and we put this together
with some help Mike and I were
definitely some idea guys and put some
skin in in the game technically but we
couldn't have done the Whelan project
without the help of our full-time
security analyst and developer faith
hadn't Guardians a huge thanks to faith
who was up until about 4:00 a.m. this
morning putting together the final
release for Whelan and knocking down
some of the last little little bits
she's on Pacific time so she will be up
soon and will be finishing the final
upload as part of the Wild West hack and
fest release for Whelan including a full
Raspberry Pi image for you to just burn
to Mike or SD and have a full running
system and not having to do any of the
manual install methods what we wanted to
do with Whalen is to provide an
inexpensive expandable open source
platform for citizens to be able to
approach and monitor for GPS fuckery
using and comparing the ability for us
to receive from multiple GNSS platforms
whether specifically here in the US we
can get Galileo GLONASS and GPS so our
initial development platforms feature
three different GPS receivers only
receiving signals from those satellites
in which we can compare and contrast the
location on those in case only one of
them is being confined the project on
github in the Whelan repository there's
also an Amazon wish lists with all the
parts including the extra stuff that
we'll be implementing in the future
currently using a Raspberry Pi 4 with
two rtos DRS for the future ad SB and
AIS reception so that we can compare and
contrast those to what is being received
from GPS we can also include more of
those for doing other time sources for
comparing time such as wwvv
and we're currently using three
satellite navigation receivers that you
block CMS with serial to TTL converters
and our current setup here for the u.s.
is GPS GLONASS and Galileo but if you're
in someplace else on the planet you can
configure those GPS receivers to use
other
systems and will give us the ability to
have multiple inputs from that data
currently we're taking all of that data
as gathered by the GPS units and
ingesting them once a daily into a local
influx may be instance which we then
post process once daily with graph on ax
which generates some nice visualizations
that we see here on the slide and then
if there's anything sort of outside of
two standard deviations for what we'd
expect or distance at a fixed locations
it currently sends some alerts to your
own configurable discord server and
channel but it's extensible so we can
create additional methods later whether
it be IVA email SMS text all sorts of
these other things and and on the right
is a picture of actually the station
that is behind me stuck up against my
window this one happens to be when we
had it deployed in Seattle for some
initial testing it expensive to build
fairly small and all sorts of other fun
stuff but Mike tell us about where we
want to take it on the future absolutely
one of the things that was so cool about
just the simple platform that Larry came
up with there is that it is expandable
or even kind of make it smaller we're
just giving you an example of kind of
what we did right now our next stages
are gonna be to put together a site for
our whale in so that other people can
essentially create accounts and upload
their own data so we can have kind of a
global view of where these sensors are
and what they're what's it detecting if
they're detecting an event and have it
have some capability to be able to push
out alerts when we're noticing these
particular events I made a little joke
here for Johannes Ulrich D field here
but for GPS the D field was essentially
the original gatherer of intrusion
detection data that became the storm
center we also want to add some
additional support as Larry mentioned or
a DSP in a is just to see for example
when we detect a GPS deviation do we see
it on either a is so that'll be surface
of the water essentially or a DSB which
is coming directly from aircraft so if
we see a B is
isn't changing but a is that is changing
but we can get a general idea of kind of
the power of the transmission and the
scale of the fuckery and some other
things too for some additional receipt
of time-based stuff we can use all of
the various RF based time sources WWV
here in the US and a bunch of others
across the planet for over-the-horizon
time synchronization such as those RF
enabled time clocks and so forth we also
want to do some a little bit better
alerting methods either locally or
through the quote global reporting
engine so that we can support additional
platforms Dischord happen to be quite
easy for us to get set up as a sample to
show how we're doing it or it can be
done and then we're currently using
batch processing for the alerting so
we'd like to be able to make that so
it's more real-time so that as soon as
it happens you can potentially get a
text message as opposed to getting a
text message at midnight to say that it
happened at some point over the last 24
hours
so Mike how can I help the biggest thing
would be to go out and get yourself a
copy of the code or the distro and set
up a sensor and also help out you know
with ideas or code to help build out the
essentially the reporting engine that's
the the big Next heavy-lift we've got
something that you can monitor your own
but we want to definitely improve the
sharing and effectively crowdsourcing
the detection of GPS fuckery what this
is a keynote so we talked about some
technical things and we really want to
sort of get everybody together at the
end of this and realize that this
problem is so much larger than just GPS
and to sort of provide a call to action
we thought about this from the
perspective of GPS what happens when
someone messes with this on
authenticated signal that can affect
time and/or location the problem is is
that in our daily lives and in our
enterprises we're reliant on so many
other sources of unauthenticated RF
transmissions and what happens when
people start screwing with those other
signals that we blindly trust whether
that be GSM or television or FM radio
with data transmission with RDS
on 433 4 and 33 megahertz I'm seeing in
discord vor and ILS for flight control
there are so many things that we've
become reliant on as a society for magic
RF that we have no ability to detect we
become reliant on its unauthenticated so
where's the next fuckery going to happen
from an RF perspective think about what
those other transmissions that were
relying on for our organizations and
they may be transmissions we don't even
know about right now but they're still
there and think about how manipulation
of those would impact your organization
and then think about how we can go build
detection mechanism because this problem
is larger than GPS we really need to
step up our detection game for all of
these signals as a society so that we
can protect ourselves for things that
we've become reliant on so that's sort
of our challenge to you as the listener
is to take this to the next step
think about all these other systems and
might could you sort of have any final
words on this one as well yeah you know
you might be thinking to yourselves okay
I'm not on a sailboat or I'm not in an
urban situation I'm I'm out in farm
country somewhere well just remember
what do you think those large combines
set their borders - oh right GPS signal
and GPS posts in the ground that ought
to make you sleep well at night but
definitely you know go out there and
think of these things figure out a way
that we can bring the detection of that
manipulation to the civilian population
absolutely and and and to that you know
we've talked about in other venues about
creating FM radio signals with some
other projects and it's very difficult
for organizations to detect that there
are F environment has changed because
there isn't a lot of detection
mechanisms now and would become reliant
on them that we now need to become
reliant on detection systems or when
they change so we've got one minute left
apparently my slides have gone away
thank you everybody for hanging out with
us that's what I was gonna say if you
guys have any questions please join the
discord
Mike and Larry will be in there and just
address your questions directly to them
in the discord channel that would be
fantastic
and I think