mr. Kevin Johnson oh man
it's funny Jonathan Kevin and myself we
all kind of started at SANS Institute as
instructors at the exact same time and
kind of came up together and really look
at these guys as kind of brothers in
arms' and that kind of weird cauldron of
strangeness because it is weird and talk
to and be like hey this really strange
thing happened to me with international
flights is that the way it works for you
guys yeah that's the way a word huh
Yemen is hands down one of the smartest
people I've ever met but that wouldn't
might be the reason why I bring him on
here one of the biggest reasons why I
have Kevin on while was hacking this
year is because there are very few
people in this industry that have a
firmer dedication to sharing knowledge
with as many people as possible
Kevin's sole existence you can tell from
the time he wakes up in the morning to
the time he goes to bed is how can he
share and get as many people up to speed
in computer security as possible he's a
he's an amazing presenter a brilliant
technical mind and if you've had the
opportunity to take a class from women
consider yourself very lucky and if you
haven't and watches classes whenever
they come up at secure ideas calm but
today's labors of Hercules
so Kevin please take it away I don't
know if I can live up to that that level
of expectation that you've you've thrown
out there and I'm very disappointed it
won't turn on my webcam I have my Sam
Cooper on a mannequin behind me it's
awesome but you all are missing it I'm
gonna try to live up to that I I will
say that I am honored to be part of the
speakers here at Weill was acting best
Joanna has put together an amazing thing
I'm just upset that we've stopped the
Old Home Week banter because this talk
isn't gonna be as much fun
so I gonna talk about the labors of
Hercules and John didn't mention this
but what I always try to do is come up
with a talk that makes me laugh and has
a reason why I think it should be and I
picked the Disney Hercules movie because
it's my oldest daughters one of her
favorite movies and I love her she's
awesome
I love all my kids all three of them it
has been pointed out to me that I
misspelled Labor's I did not
that way on purpose because it's the
European spelling and since we're
talking about Hercules I felt like it
was important I have to say that all
graphics are copyright somebody other
than being I'm just using gives me
things which means we'll get a
cease-and-desist or something a little
bit about me before I get really started
I am the CEO of securities that's the
fancy way of saying head nerd I'm an
audience faculty member I am a course
author and instructor and John is right
about I don't know if I'm as dedicated
as he said I am but I do believe that
our purpose in life is to grow the next
group of people to do what we want to do
and if we're not sharing our knowledge
we're dying and I don't want to die you
can follow me on Twitter I do a bunch of
things I open-source fanatic I'm the
crew one of the creators of samurai WTF
Q apt 101 which is a six day WebP
investing course that's completely open
source and free it's out on github I am
also a dad I've got three kids two
daughters and a son that's me in the
Vader costume and the clone trooper I am
a member of the 501st that is actually
the thing outside of my family that I am
probably the proudest of for the people
who don't know the 501st is a costuming
group that raises money for charity
there's actually a number of security
people that are members of it which is
kind of fun we build screen accurate
Star Wars costumes and then go visit
kids and hospitals or raise money for
charity
I believe that figure for 2019 was like
seventeen million dollars worldwide
raised but I don't know so that's what
we do my wife says it's the nerdiest
thing ever I pointed out that she met me
when I was 26 she doesn't know what was
the nerdiest thing ever a couple other
things one I am full of tangents I'm
full of lots of things and my eyes are
brown and too
I have a sense of humor now many of you
you may have misunderstood that and
thought that I said that I had a good
sense of humor I did not I said I have a
sense of humor to give you an idea Mike
current favorite joke and it's been my
current favorite joke for a while now is
why was Walmart not hacked and the
reason is they're not a target so I
actually got the introduce like the CSO
of Walmart or something I don't remember
what their position was and I told that
joke and they wouldn't shake my hand so
let's talk about why we're doing this
one of the main reasons is there is a
gap in a cost for learning and I'm not I
want to be very clear we see all these
headlines right now cyber security
talent gap and all that kind of crud I
don't know how much I agree then there
is a gap in hiring I know it's hard to
find people to hire I know that it's
hard to find people that fill the
positions we have but but I think that
that's probably because we're looking in
the wrong place and we'll talk about
that in a second but the other problem
is and this is something that I have
really harped about quite a bit and that
is the cost to become trained and I'm
not picking on any particular company
here as a matter of fact the costs that
I have on the screen were pulled from
public websites and they've gone up in
all cases from the time that I show
these screenshots and they're all
different companies like this is not a I
can poke fun at that company whatever
that company happens to be this is
really a problem with our industry if
you're starting out that I can remember
when I decided to stop being just an IT
nerd and become a security nerd
um I started an IT in 1991 mainly by
accident I was a nerdy kid a guy I knew
was starting a company and he needed a
guy who knew how to develop and run a
network and was cheap well I fit all
those and so they hired me and I got my
first job right out of high school so I
always giggle when people say well when
I got out of college I don't know when
they were in college I got a job and
then I stuck with it so I kind of fell
into this position of being the 19 nerve
and I decided that security was
interesting to me and I wanted to get
into it and even then it was
expensive but we're talking 20 years ago
right I was I had to convince Denise to
let me spend money in training and the
let me go figure stuff out and we made
it work
luckily for us right but I look at it
now and now as a business owner you know
I've got 19 employees and they come to
me and say hey I want a class and I say
well how much is the class and they say
well how it's $6,000 or $7,000 and I'm
like what I can't afford that
III and they can't when we look at the
training costs and I'm not I want to be
very clear if people want to spend that
much great good for them if you want to
charge that much if they think it's
worth it
good for them I'm a greedy capitalist
I'm perfectly willing to let people
charge whatever they want to charge for
whatever they want to offer and if
people want to pay it good for them but
I think that we have a problem and I
think that the problem is that we aren't
teaching enough people we aren't
reaching out to enough people have these
skills and get them to understand what
they need to do and then we also have a
problem of what do we teach I think that
the biggest problem there is that people
don't know the path the end yes that is
an operating system pun but I like it so
we talked to people and and as somebody
you know John mentioned it earlier I
present all over the place I teach all
over the place I'm constantly going out
to customers locations and I'm I'm I'm
in the face of the company which is
really a bad choice because I'm funny
looking but we we go out and I am
constantly being asked by people I've
got schools that say to me how do we
teach our kids and and they're like well
I want to be you I want to do what you
do how do I get there and I think that a
lot of people think that there's just
this I can wake up in the morning I
finished high school or at finish
college and I'm now a penetration tester
but they don't really know what they're
doing and they don't know how to get
there and how to improve and where to
focus we see where it often like where
do I practice I want to learn this
but I don't know what to do or the
number of times I've seen people say
like on Twitter hey just go join a bug
bounty program and practice there I
cringe and that's not even a problem
with bug bounties like I we can talk
about bug bounties offline or somewhere
else if you want but that's not even up
I don't like bug bounties it's a if you
were a company offering a bug bounty did
you really want to get the people who
don't know what they're doing and are
practicing no that should not be our
advice we should be giving people who
are learning practice areas and in
places to go to learn more and end
whatever right on top of that if you're
the person learning or the person
teaching how do you know you're getting
the correct information one of my
favorite videos and and and I'm gonna be
really boring so you might as well gonna
watch it now but but go out to youtube
and do a search for next-gen hacker 101
this kid and I say kid I don't know who
this person is and I and I and I want to
be very clear I'm not making fun of them
but this video is where they walk you
through and show you how to see the IP
addresses of everybody else that's a
visiting a website right now
and you watch this video and the kid
goes through this explanation of how to
use and I'm gonna pronounce it the way
he pronounced it tracer T which many
people on this webcast probably caught
that it's traceroute and this kid is
doing a traceroute from from me it
sounds like a him his machine to
google.com and every single one of the
hops it takes he claims is an IP address
of somebody else is visiting google.com
right this second and he starts
describing and he goes into this detail
and let's be very clear it could be the
ultimate troll I don't know
but this kid has put a lot of thought
and explanation into what he sees on the
screen
and he talks about how the timing right
the the 15 milliseconds whatever that
that is telling you how fast the
person's speed that they very internet
connection is and it he talks about how
you know that that's their user name and
that knows the coast like it's just
every bit of information in this video
is wrong right and I'm a Star Wars fan
so you know it's it's it's like Lucas
says right everything you just said is
wrong but he was so positive and so sure
of himself and and want to be clear I
admire that but I'm not I'm following
Tim's advice right
I'm not blasting this kid I'm just point
now that we failed him
because we didn't get them the correct
information
and he doesn't know that unless it's
just an elaborate role but I know people
who have watched his video and thought
it was real
thought that was the right information
how do we verify this and I'm not gonna
get into Facebook and Russian trolls and
fake news and all that kind of stuff
right but if we can't even get the right
information about politics how do we
expect to get the right information on
technology out to people
and are we teaching ethics and I know
that's a touchy subject subject for a
lot of people but are we teaching ethics
are we teaching the right ethics are we
teaching people when they should and
shouldn't do what we do because let's be
one what I do for a living day in and
day out is against the law except for
the fact that have contract except for
the fact that I have permission and what
does that mean right how do we how do we
know what we're allowed to do I just
have a conversation with a really really
good friend of mine one of my best
friends yesterday what a guy I think is
one of my best friends and he asked me
about a company that is just scanning
the internet and it talks about with
this problem in that and and Giovanni
was like hey well how does how did they
get permission for this and and he was
double-checking this in his opinion
correctly so they didn't have permission
so what they were doing was an ethical
and I happen to agree with that idea so
that's what I said no like yeah no
that's that's wrong but here's a company
who's offering a service of we scan
random other sites and tell you about
their vulnerabilities hey and I'm not
gonna throw them under the bus right you
know I'd like to so how do we teach all
this
so in my mind what we have to build what
we need to focus
we have to stop thinking about
information security as magic we have to
stop thinking about information security
as this really high education if you
don't understand you don't have a
doctorate in computer science reverse
encryption quantum flux capacitors
whatever what we really need to start
thinking about this is that we're really
just a trade and I'm not trying to
demean anything I'm proud of being a
tradesman I'm proud of being somebody
who is an internet plumber right and I
think that we need to start thinking
about things on a path just like a
trades person does and and you know the
the traditional historic apprentice
journeyman mentor and and please note
that mentor is the last class and
there's two reasons I know many of you
probably know the term master I don't
want to use that and then there's two
reasons I don't want to use it and one I
think it's pretty obvious there are
negative connotations whether you agree
with them or not or you understand why
people find them negative they are there
and we have to recognize that and in my
opinion just as importantly now maybe
not just as important but importantly we
also have to make sure that the person
who has made it to that level understand
that their job is to mentor everybody
else and honestly all three levels
should be mentor right if you started
out your entry level you're an
apprentice and there is a set of things
that you should learn and know how to do
and and so when I look at and as we'll
talk about in the next couple slides
we're going to talk about building
mentor programs and how to build this up
and create these programs but when I
want a mentor program I look at the
people who are just coming in as
apprentices they're their entry-level
they may know tons of stuff and we may
find out within a week of having them in
the mentor program or a day of hour a
minute of having them into the mentor
program
but really they should be a mentor
themselves or they should be a
journeyman or whatever right but but the
reality is when they start we think of
them as apprentice and the reason we
think of them as an apprentice is
because we want to hold them up to a set
of skills a knowledge base a knowledge
level that they should have the start
and and I really like pulling people
into these programs from a variety of
backgrounds I like pulling people from
help desks or pulling people from QA
teams or even project management teams
and non-technical teams to bring them in
to these mentor programs even if their
goal is not to become a super badass pen
tester but so that they can understand
and so that they can grasp because we
want everybody to understand security
because security is everybody's
responsibility right so we bring them in
as apprentice but we start showing them
stuff be sure working with them and this
is bi-directional we want to take stuff
from them too we want to learn from them
because let's be very clear being a
mentor is not the end it really is just
the beginning so we start to talk and we
start to discuss things we start to
teach them and show them and guide them
and that last part I believe is critical
to understand our job is to guide not
direct
we don't force them down of house we
guide them where their need to go
I'd them where they can get the best
knowledge and understand them and then
as they're doing this for a while as
they learn as they explore as we support
them they become a journeyman at this
point they're really confident maybe
they're excellent at some things but
they at least have a level of competency
and what I like to think of is using my
company as the example right what we do
is we consider somebody who's a
journeyman somebody who is ready to lead
a project they're not just a tester but
they actually are the ones that are
interacting with the customer and and
kicking the project off and scoping
projects and selling project right there
they're capable of we know that they are
good at what they do and they understand
more than just somebody who's like oh
yeah I know how to pin tests they know
how to be a consultant now that's a
secure ideas tournament
in your organization because you should
be building these programs in your own
organization in your own groups in your
own whatever that that level of
competency may mean a different
description and that's why I say it as
vaguely as I can on the slide but
there's somebody who's competent at the
job we're bringing them into and then as
they continue to grow because mentoring
doesn't stop I think that and you have
these random thoughts right I think back
to Richard Stallman's writer if you
bring him in to speak and let's be very
clear based on his rider I've never met
Richard Stallman but based on his rider
he is a nutjob
and I mean that as nicely as possible
but you know one of the things he wants
if you bring him in to speak is parrot
that he'd like to stay at somebody's
house and he hopes they have a parrot
what do you keep says to them don't go
out and get a parrot
because parrots can live like 70 years
or something right there they live very
long periods of time and like if I
bought a parrot at my age and the parrot
was young because while it's not my
birthday
today it was my birthday a few weeks ago
and I turned 47 if a parent can live 60
years it is unlikely that I am going to
outlive that parrot a parrot is a big
responsibility being a mentor is a big
responsibility you're constantly working
with them so as they get to a point
where they're a journeyman as they've
grown into a competent worker right
you're a job now is to continue to guide
them to continue to provide that support
and knowledge and understanding so that
they can grow into being a mentor of
their own because that is our goal as I
said the very beginning as John used to
describe me which I still don't
understand the accolades but okay I'll
accept them today but our job is is to
get to that mentor capability is to get
to the ability to pass on the skills we
have just recently okay a week before my
birthday I decided that I needed a hobby
that didn't involve computers
because I'm a nerd I've been a nerd for
so long that the guy who used to steal
my lunch money
still takes it on a regular basis and me
makes a good Subway sandwich
but I decided I needed a hobby that
didn't involve computers and I've been
fascinated by wood lathe you know where
they turn the wood and they use the
gouge to to carve it into a shape make
cups or bowls or pens or tops or random
shapes that fly all over the garage not
that I know speaking from experience and
I've on a lathe but before I bought the
lathe that was my birthday gift
I bought the lathe I started watching
YouTube videos
I started watching people who were
sharing a craft the art of wood turning
just like we should be sharing the art
of penetration testing or information
security or IP or project management or
whatever we do and I was just struck by
how much so many of these people in
these videos just wanted to share what
they're doing one comes to mind
immediately Steve Ramsey was his name
and he's the woodworker for mere mortal
woodworking for mere mortals is his
channel and I'm not pimping his channel
and I mean I am he's awesome and and he
just wants to show you how to do
woodwork and there's other people that
do the same thing right like here's how
you do this Turk wave and I was just so
impressed by their passion of sharing
and I hope that that people recognize my
passion for sharing and that you should
have the same passion so let's talk
about some of the rules you know Phil is
the trainer in Hercules see there is a
relevance to the Hercules reference when
Hercules needed to become Hercules at
least in the Disney movie in either the
trainer and he got Phil I'm not gonna
try to pronounce Phil's real name
Pullman and he has a set of rules and
let's be clear in the movie he has like
a hundred rules or something
I've only pulled some of them as
relevant to what we're talking about
because most of the rules were jokes for
the movie and then I put some of these
relevance here right and then I
highlighted some of them and then I
think are important I think they're all
important we need to learn from our
mistakes but I think rule number one is
probably very critical for us to
understand and that is is that everybody
needs a hero
or a mentor is in my mind the hero is
the mentor that's what you become you
get to the point of you're a hero and
then you become the mentor everybody
needs one we all stand on the shoulders
of giants
I am only where I am today because of
the people who lifted me up and I hope
and pray and worry that I'm not lifting
up enough people that I want to be the
shoulders somebody else is standing but
we all need that hero every single one
of us we also need to remember that we
shouldn't get cocky and I think that
that number 13 on here is the same thing
right
don't stop for applause we don't do this
or we shouldn't do this a recognition of
being smart for being the best for being
number one III I worry so often when I
see people talk about things like oh man
I want to be an information security
rockstar you know what I don't want to
be an info SEC rockstar I remember when
I first started teaching her sans when I
first released
5:42 it was a four-day class and Mike
poor used to joke and tell me that I
wasn't a rock star I was a pop star
because I only had a four day class we
shouldn't be doing this for the applause
I've done some really really neat thing
and I don't mean that as in look at this
cool stuff I've done I've done things
that I look at no man that was fun that
was awesome that was impressive to be
but I didn't do them because they were
impressive I did them because I needed
to do them I did them because I wanted
to show somebody else I present on a
regular basis I I think I have five
different presentations I'm giving in
the next two weeks
I am absolutely petrified of public
speaking
I don't vomit anymore before I do it but
I am petrified of public speaking I hate
it I was nervous and upset all day with
the idea that at 4:30 Eastern today
I had to join a green room to check my
screen and my monitor and all that kind
of stuff to make sure it was working and
then a half an hour after that I was
gonna be presenting to all of you I've
been nauseous all day I didn't sleep
last night because it still scares me
and that's why I say I don't do it so
people can come up to me later today and
you did awesome or you socked it did it
because I think it's important for us to
share now a couple other things to point
out one play by the rules if we don't
follow the rules then when no better
than the people we're trying to stop
well no better than the people we're
trying to protect it gifts to play by
them one of the things I like here is
that greater your agility the greater
your ability and I like that because way
too often we get people who want to
focus on one thing I'm gonna learn this
one thing and I'm gonna be amazing at
but if you don't know all the things
that support it everything that is part
of it then you're not gonna be as good
as you need to be and as you're trying
to guide other people you're gonna have
problems and then finally we need to aim
this is a hard one I'm not a list person
I'm not a person who says this is what I
need to do and here's all the steps that
I'm gonna follow if you followed Tim's
Twitter thread yesterday threw in an
example of a story and I sadly didn't
make all of Tim's stalks I don't know if
he mentioned it of when Matt Carpenter
and I were doing a pen test and Matt
follows a process Matt Eames amazingly
well Matt Carpenter is a person that I
am blessed to know privileged to call
friend and he follows a process and you
know what I don't I should
we did a pinch s together and I got root
access to the system ten minutes into
the test and it was funny because Matt
complained dead our boss that he didn't
think it was fair I didn't follow the
process he was following the methodology
and I got root and and I'm I'm
paraphrasing and making it sound way
more blah than it really was
the reality is that I got root in ten
minutes but Matt did a better job
Matt produced better results Matt
produced a better test than I did and
it's the same thing when we try to teach
other people if I just stand up and say
I'm gonna teach you information security
you're gonna fail to learn it and I'm
gonna fail to teach it because we
haven't aimed correctly we haven't
realized what we need to get to
now having said that you have to be a
little careful because when I started
that journey to become a security person
I actually built a list i sat down and I
wrote ten I think it was ten thing that
I needed to learn and like I said in the
previous presentation when I hijacked it
I wanted to be Mike poor I wanted to be
like Mike that's probably trademarked or
something right and so I sat down I
wrote down ten things that I believed I
needed learned to be Mike and I focused
on the first one and I learned it and I
crossed it off the list and I realized
that I had a list of 23 things I needed
to learn
because when I was learning that one
thing
I learned a bunch of other things I
didn't know that I needed to know but I
still needed to know it so I learned the
next one and I had a list of 75 things I
needed more and then a hundred and then
the thousand and a million and now at
the point where I have a list of 473
Brillion items that I need to learn it's
actually why I believe that I will never
solve the imposter syndrome idea and
that's because I know how much I don't
know but I'm still aiming as we build
out mentorship programs we have to aim
so how do we build them because the
reality is we need to build them to help
everybody else and grow dreams of people
we need to secure us
and let's be very blunt I don't mean all
the people we need to hire to be
security people if we don't teach as
many people as possible what security
means and I don't mean user awareness I
mean actually understanding security
actually understanding why security is
important actually understanding what
security means if we don't teach every
single person we come into contact with
we're never gonna solve this problem and
I know we're probably not gonna solve
the problem it's just gonna keep
changing but we can make it better and
to make it better we have to mentor
other people now I'll be very clear I
don't like doing sales pitches okay the
only sales pitch I do in my talks and I
haven't done it yet is that if you're a
veteran or an active-duty military
person or a first responder much of my
training that I offer is free some of
its not if it's not it's hugely
discounted as much as possible
there's my sales pitch so if you are a
veteran or meet that qualification drop
us an email and we'll send you the
coupon code that's my sales pitch I have
two examples of mentoring programs that
secure ideas has built I want to be very
clear both of these programs are
services secure ideas cells I am NOT
pimping them I guess I am right I'm a
greedy capitalist here's to mentor
program you can sign up for and pay me
for but what I want to show you is the
implementation plan and we're gonna walk
through it right now of house here ideas
build these two programs so that you can
build the same programs yourself I want
to give you enough information that you
don't have to pay me cuz I've talked
about this many times I joke and say
that my goal is a business owner is to
be protested by the Occupy movement I'd
like to be so stinking rich but there
are pup tents in my cul-de-sac
complaining about my lack of paying
taxes or something like that right but
the reality is that my business goal is
to go out of business my business goal
is to show people how to do it
themselves so they don't have to hire me
they don't have to pay me now the people
who hold my mortgage are happy to know
that that's probably not gonna happen
anytime soon
and I'm gonna continue to pay my
mortgage please hope so right but how do
you build a mentor program yourself okay
there's a couple things you need to
remember one you gotta follow a series
of guidelines
first one is make the program formal
now I don't mean that we all wear tuxes
what I mean is that we actually have to
formalize what the program means what
its goals are and what is part of the
program well what we plan on offering
how we plan on communicating it and we
need to communicate the plan right so it
has to be formal I've seen only too
often when I worked at Blue Cross of
Florida we've tried to do mentoring and
lunch and learns and stuff like that and
and I'm not bashing Blue Cross we either
people trying to do it or who've failed
and the reason we failed was it was kind
of this I will just do that when we can
right how about we meet during lunch
when I don't know when are you available
maybe that's week what do you think
about Tuesday ooh Tuesday is good
oh no Tuesday's not good formalize it
build out that process that plan that
communication and then let everybody
know what it is here's what we're gonna
do like for example with salsa what we
do is we tell people every two weeks
there is going to be a live webcast that
you can join there you go here's how you
join it here's how this works
this is the schedule and here are the
topics it's gonna cover you do the same
thing build out that entire process
before you start don't don't go into it
with the idea of well I'll see if people
want to do it and if they want to do it
we'll figure out what no don't do that
be flexible right if you come up with a
plan and you say okay every two weeks on
Tuesday we're gonna do this and then the
people you're mentoring come back and
say ah Oh Tuesday doesn't work and
here's why is there any way no no I
formalized this it's - no don't do that
be prepared to flex but have the plan D
flex fum okay because if you don't have
the plan you're gonna fit all fart
around for a while and that's what
happened with us when we're trying to do
the mentoring at Blue Cross is we fiddle
farted around and then we realized it
wasn't really working and because it
wasn't working nobody had the interest
to try to fix it
but that that was the issue it's a make
it formal
then
identify mentors now this I say
aggressively I don't mean go beat people
up right pull a gun and run around
shooting at people until they become a
mentor what I mean is don't just put out
it let's say you're doing this inside
your company inside your organization
let's say you wanted to mentor people in
the sets right don't just write a people
and say hey anybody interested in
helping us teach other people how to
prepare for this program we actually see
this a lot with development teams but
security people realize that developers
need to know more about security and we
wanna build up security in our
development lifecycle and what have you
and so what what you'll see is a
security team will reach out to the
development managers or they'll send out
an email to all the developers or groups
developers and they'll say hey anybody
interested in becoming a security
champion I always love that term
security champions I got a shield and a
sword and a horse No
and it sends these emails out hey
everyone do this anybody anybody Bueller
Bueller
and they don't get anybody or they get a
couple people worse they get people who
there's no way that person is ready to
be a Venter notice I didn't say they
couldn't be a mentor then they're not
ready to be a mentor
go out aggressively and identify the
people that you think and be mentors and
drag them into this program obviously
you can't kidnap them right you can it's
illegal in most states go out and
identify who you are gonna have be the
mentors to help out with this stuff
bring them in and work with them on the
plan work on them on the formalization
of the program now you should have the
plan started at least mostly done by the
time you bring the mentors into it
because if you bring them into it and
you say look I don't know what we're
gonna do but we're gonna do this they're
gone but bring them in and start working
with them on adjusting the planet for
the way the program works now the next
part is pretty complicated for a lot of
people but it's critical
have to provide multiple paths for
learning and there's a lot of reasons
for this Jason Gilliam one of the owners
here at security as hit dude is genius
he talks about as we were building our
mentorship programs how people learn
differently I don't know about you but I
like to read I read a lot I read every
single day I try to take in as much
information as possible
I don't learn well by watching a video I
just don't now having said that I just
released a whole bunch of videos this
morning but I don't learn that way
other people do I was just talking to
somebody I don't number who it was and
they were like oh man this is awesome
i watch these videos and it's so oval
one of my consults and he was watching
the professional evil fundamental videos
that we released today and he was like
man this is great this is a great way to
learn I I understand things so much
better when I watch it in a video and
now I'm happy to say he didn't learn
anything from the fundamental videos I
released today because he's above that
he's one of our senior consultants he's
one of our mentors but he's like I
learned from videos other people my
oldest daughter she likes to listen to
audio books and audio podcasts and
things like that listen because that's
how she can focus there's nothing
distracting she just sits there and
listens whereas my younger daughter
Sarah
she likes the videos she likes to see
things she also likes to do hands-on
doing the lathe we've also been pouring
resin to do these different our nerding
out at home with crafts right but we
have more glitter than anybody else
should have she watches a video on how
to pour resin but then she has to go to
it and until she does it until she
actually sits down with the total boat
and combines the hardener with the the
resin and stirs it up with the powdered
coloring and then pour it into the mold
and wait for its whole time and I'm
probably using terms that don't matter
in this context but you know the resin
that we're using has a pot time and then
a cure time and Dara read it in the
directions and she's 13 right so she's
read the directions then she watched a
video
Evon in Caitlyn it's the video series
that she and I like to watch together
and they were talking about it and
they're pouring it and Sarah kind of
understood it but it wasn't until we sat
down with the actual resin and poured it
and stirred it and watched it start to
harden as we were stirring it that she
started to understand pot time like how
long until you can't pour it into a mold
anymore and then the residue are using
as a slow hardening resin and so it
takes two days to completely cure and so
about three hours later it's
able to be removed from the mold if you
want to this particular resin don't
don't take this an advice on how to do
resin and we pulled it out of the mold
we were impatient right hahaha but you
could still tell that it wasn't
completely cured and it wasn't until she
held in her hand and did it that she
really understood the difference between
pot time and cure time and what that
meant in doing this process and I find
that quite often with people learning
how to pen test until you dump a
database do you really understand sequel
injection so yeah
change the price on a website they
really understand logical art so there's
multiple paths that you have to take
into account in your mentoring and then
you also want to think about different
communication paths that's part of that
paths to learning right and what we like
to do is you know you've got some books
or written material slides
you've got recordings of audio and video
teaching you how to cut and do stuff and
then you have I say chat room that's
right but like we run slack workspaces
where you can sit in the slack workspace
and talk to other students and mentoring
and peas I guess is there I were and
like for us we actually have our
consultants idling in those slack
workspaces so that they can be there at
any time to answer questions right and
when we actually have a an SLA that you
know within half an hour you'll get a
response during business hours to a
question in the sastra channel and and I
point that out that you should be doing
the same thing you should give people
this is part of making it formal jumping
back you give them an SLA an expectation
of how fast they'll get a response how
fast they will be able to talk to
somebody and and you also need to have
them understand that the people being
mentored have a level of expectation
because there's nothing more frustrating
than reaching out to somebody and asking
a question because they're your mentor
and and and let's be clear it's positive
busy right they have jobs they have
lives their families whatever their
hobbies but you ask a question and it
doesn't matter how unimportant that
question may seem to somebody else
to you it's critical to your mentee or
whatever that word is right it's
critical they have to have something so
having an expectation of response is
important in your program and
communicating that expectation so that
people know and I'll pick on sass the
right I don't let you but I have no
work-life balance
it's a whole it is very often that it do
in the morning I'm sitting on my
computer working and it's the reason I
need the wood lathe and somebody will
throw a question into the sausage
channels and I'll answer it because I'm
sitting there but we try to make it very
clear that if they get that answer at
2:00 in the morning
that's a one-off we're trying to help
because we're there but but the
expectation is that there will be there
during business hours we'll be working
with them at that time and then finally
as you build out this program you have
to ensure that people are engaged that's
a typo it should say engage them reach
out to the people that are in the
program all of the people in the program
the people attending the people
mentoring the people and this should be
a group thing but make sure that you
reach out to people and are you
understanding are you following are you
doing this are you like we we give
assignments like if you go through our
sis mentorship program you get an
assignment every single week of stuff
you're supposed to read and quizzes
you're supposed to take and practice
exams that you should be following up on
and we reach out to students and
attendees and mentees whatever you want
to call them hey are you reading it are
you getting this are you following this
is this making sense that we try to
engage them and there's a number of
reasons for that one it's important
because people will feel like I don't
want to bother them know it bother us
let me manage my own time people also
they get stuck and a lot of times I
don't know about you but I've done it
right where I've gotten stuck on
something and the next thing I realize
is it's been three days and I haven't
solved my problem and it's because I was
stuck but if my mentor had reached out
in that three day periods of Kevin how
you do I would have immediately said
having problem with this the other thing
that you need to make sure that when you
reach out to them is that you are
accepting feedback and paying attention
to the subtle unspoken feedback of how
well you are meant to ring
because if you reach out to one of your
mentors one of the people you're
mentoring to me and they comment that
they haven't heard from you in a couple
weeks they're not trying to be mean it's
just that great here for me I
interviewed a couple weeks you're
failing you've messed up in your program
you need to make sure that you're paying
attention and if they ask you a question
one of the things I hear
I'll explain something and mentoring
students whatever you hear this you'll
say hey okay this ask you a question
you'll explain the question and how
often do you hear an instructor say make
sense
you got it does that work yeah yeah you
you with me and the only right answer
there's yes of course I got it now
that's not true that's not the only
right answer but as the person mentoring
that's the instructor what you need to
listen for is first and going yeah yeah
it's okay I got it
no you probably don't let's talk a
little bit more you don't want to bother
in it you feel dumb we all feel dumb
I can tell them to tell you the number
of times I've had somebody teaching me
something and I've just not gotten it
and I felt stupid asking them to repeat
it again and again and again
the mentor if you engage people if you
reach out to them you'll know they're
having that problem that's our goal and
like I said security is we've
implemented two programs of mentorship
that we believe are very successful the
feedback we've gotten from people are
very successful we're building more and
I'm not saying that like oh hey look at
these great programs by them
please look at these great programs by
them that's the way I make payroll but
you can build them yourself
our entire responsibility is to be like
Phil now I mean the rough-in a drunk
I mean mentoring the next series of
Heroes being the shoulders people can
stand on thank you and now I'll open it
up to questions I am NOT in I just
realized I'm not in the discord Channel
so I'm going to let whoever is the
person in the discord channel repeat
questions to me oh that would be not
problem is we get all of these different
things that pop up got a question for
you this is from I'm gonna just call
them swag nur cuz that sounds cooler
spent the better part that's two years
establishing Club my college that
provides a live environment to learn
blue and red team options any tips or
resources for building an introductory
mentorship program most of the time we
have new members come in and tend to get
overwhelmed the concepts are more
seasoned members are engaging so I think
it's like that wave thing where the
people that are at the earlier part they
get in and they start doing amazing
stuff and then people that come in get a
little bit intimidated yeah so there's
two things I'd recommend doing it one
and we just started it this morning
we've released our professional evil
fundamentals and it's a YouTube playlist
as dumb as that is and they are two to
four minute videos that are just
definition and we're we're we've got
like 21 of them recorded now and they're
being published two at a time three at a
time over the next few weeks but but the
goal there is and you can do the same
thing is start documenting and recording
whether it's a video or just writing it
down that introductory stuff so that as
somebody comes in they've got a place
they can go to get it that's that's the
first recommendation the way John
described that's right yeah you have
these waves of people come in and and
they come in and then two weeks later
there's
new group but the old group is still
pushing forward the second
recommendation and I'm gonna pick on my
sis mentorship program because it's how
we do that if you were to sign up and
and check on sales pitching and I'm not
if you were to sign up for the
assessment for program
it's a nine-week program it has a
definite calendar it has a start and a
stop and you pay for it came for it that
one time you then get to take the
mentorship program as many times as you
want because our goal with all mentoring
is not just to prep somebody for that
test but to prep people for
understanding of the knowledge right and
in learning and so what we do and we've
actually seen it it's been beautiful in
the Syst program is that what you have
is we have a nine week program people
take it they learn they engage they talk
they build relationships and they finish
the mentor program and then we take
about a month we do it a month because
we're billable consultants and then we
launch another mentor program and
everybody who is in the other one can
sign up for the new one and then we have
new students come in and what we find is
that one the experienced mentees I don't
know if that's really the word but they
start exploring more we start getting
more complicated discussions going and
deeper dives into the theoretical and
this and that which is awesome right and
fun and also probably overwhelming to
the new people but the new people are
being presented the stuff in that same
calendar moving forward that is that
program that everything else and but
they're also getting exposed to the the
more advanced stuff but what I'm seeing
and this is the beautiful part in my
mind we're seeing the people who have
taken the mentor program before becoming
mentors themselves they're helping
people they're answering the questions
they're guiding people through things
it's gorgeous
and and so that to me is the way to do
it is to have a time frame per program
but too often I see these these hey
here's a lab environment you can play in
and everybody gets
it's freeform and there is no this is
the star here's the end and that's leads
to that oh man people are so far ahead
of me that I'll never catch up I might
as well stop is that I hope that makes
sense yeah I think that answered it also
another question I came in I thought was
interesting was I'm a college student a
cyber security program in school do I
need a mentor I don't have a clue about
cyber security I'm accomplished student
and I have worked with computers all my
life I'll take a crack yes but you don't
necessarily have to go and find someone
and say will you be my mentor because
there's lots of people like Kevin ibh is
we do webcasts all the time there's a
tremendous number of people that are
constantly giving back to the community
that you can basically be hooked into
their program and start seeing the
webcasts going through their training
packet Vox all of these different things
that that would be my recommendation
Kevin I agree with your recommendation
the only addition I would do is I do
actually recommend getting a local
mentor as well and the reason is and in
my opinion it shouldn't be one person
what you should do is try to engage in
local groups
everybody needs Mentors you're gonna
need mentors your entire life no matter
what you do there's gonna be something
else you need to learn and there's gonna
be somebody who knows it better than you
I will tell you that Black Hills is an
organization I I am in Slee admire the
John said at the beginning of how my
passion is to share so this is John
Wright and they are constantly putting
stuff out there get engaged follow
people on Twitter join the conversations
getting slack channels and ignore the
noise uh I've seen way too many people
who jump into these things and they'll
they'll still out a question as somebody
who is quote-unquote awesome at this
stuff
and they'll get a rude answer back what
I have found is everybody who gives an
asshole answer to something is probably
not that good at what they say they can
do people I know there's actually good
at stuff want to share it well and I
also think the the noise there's there's
places like that are fine Prannoy it's
like Twitter is there for politics noise
and social just Argyle argue out things
but don't for a second think that
Twitter is what the information secure
security community is and that's all
that it is you can go to LinkedIn where
it's professional it's a little bit
almost a little bit stifling from time
to time but don't think that that's what
it is you almost got a hit in multiple
places and spread out and take the good
and ignore the death unless I will
actually say find those live somebody I
was gonna say if somebody on Twitter
basically says you shouldn't wash your
hands for whatever reason you're still
safe to ignore those people oh and Nazis
and more Nazis I did agree I don't think
we should ignore Nazis I think we should
punch them in the throat oh crap that's
right remember our parents always said
violence is never okay unless Nazis I
mean even my mom I would play
Wolfenstein and she's like I'm like mom
it's not just like okay it's go kill him
one final question before you go I'm not
gonna say who this is from but who's
your favorite employee favorite employer
let's be very clear my wife is an
employee of the company that is the only
right answer