hello be weird today cuz normally I
teach and other people talk back and
there is no talking back except in the
discourse channel and I can't see that
so hello
if you can hear me let me know in the
discord channel just real quick that I'm
pretty sure it could because you heard
my music awesome thank you alright let's
get started and you can see the discord
channel you can actually see yourself in
the discord channel saying yes you can
hear me in the disc or Channel
so today we're gonna cover how to grade
how to's and I got my slides up here and
we're going to go through it this way I
have to keep them this size
it's been a long week so for most of you
John's gonna chime in here he might
talked about showing up let me see if
he's in here and I need to promote him
ah nope so most of you if you haven't
heard already I was on a cruise last
week in the Caribbean turban ribbon and
I was on the cruise and while I was on
the cruise John did a unscheduled
webcast so we hadn't prepped for it who
works with me had the to put all that
together they did the webcast on
Thursday so I I was able to get some
in-room internet and I sent her a note
afterwards and I was like Deb how was
the webcast and she said it was great
it went really well John just told us to
that Baba's had confessed is going
virtual at that point I realized that my
vacation was kind of over and even
though I was in the one a cruise ship
also on that cruise ship anytime anyone
coughed on the cruise ship or like
allergies allergies but I'm not so sure
anymore because it's been five days and
it's exactly so well we'll see how that
goes so for those are you getting here
thanks so much for coming to my workshop
it has been quite a week we were able to
put this virtual conference together in
just a few days for the most part a lot
of this was put together of the weekend
where we start putting like actual
structural things in place with Derrick
and some of the other team the first
thing I asked Deb to do was make sure
that everyone that was going to present
this week trainers and speakers had good
microphones and cameras and so she went
through and did tests with every speaker
every person here because you all will
be forgiving to slides you will be
forgiving forgiving to cameras you will
not be forgiving to bad audio and so the
most important thing for us was to make
sure that we had good microphones and
good audio and and so we checked all
that anyone that didn't have good audio
we airdrop them essentially from Amazon
microphones so that way they can present
today and not sound bad anyone that you
did hear that you're like huh audio is
kind of bad I don't think they showed up
for the test
so you're here I'm here and we're going
to talk about how to create help twos
essentially this is just how to get the
knowledge that's in your brain outs of
people so that they can learn from you
because I have learned so much from
others I believe you've learned a lot
from others I was a teacher for nine
years I got a chance to stand up in
front of classrooms and teach all the
things I had learned to others and I was
able to watch them take that information
and start doing something with it and
then they started teaching other people
as they graduated got out into the
industry I taught filmmaking at Full
Sail University from 2003 to 2012 so
about nine years I taught content
creation so producing at the time we
called it low-budget producing because
it wasn't millions of dollars it wasn't
hundreds of thousands of dollars it was
what could you produce for ten bucks
four hundred dollars or a couple grand
and so at the time we called it
independent producer Hilo bunch of
producing looking back on an Al's off
all we were doing is creating what
people are now making content wise and
YouTube wise and everything like that I
will check the questions window but for
the most parts if you have a question
asked in the questions window which is
in the control panel and I will check
that from time to time I don't have any
helpers here today it's just me that's
okay I'd like to thank the 48 of you
that showed up here
it's a open workshop and I really hope
you get something out of it in the next
two hours so with all that preamble and
let's get started so this is the how to
create how to sharing your knowledge who
am i I am Jason Blanchard I work for
Black Hills InfoSec you can follow me on
twitter at badger crash-land I am Jason
at Black Hills InfoSec comm she needs
some me an email and I used to if anyone
ever met me when I worked at my previous
employer which is the SANS Institute if
you ever met me there I generally would
introduce myself to a giant room full of
network players and I would say hi
everyone hi I'm Jason I work in
marketing and people be like no we suck
right we do for the most part I mean we
don't but I mean every email you get
you're like yeah I really want to get
that email when I came to Black Hills
I asked Jon I was like can I change my
title from marketing to content
community because that's really what we
do we create content and we help build a
community and so yeah that's what we did
we changed my title from marketing
director to content and community
director and the reason why is because
marketing feels like I'm trying to get
you just doesn't feel right like I just
don't like marketing I don't I like
creating content that's as useful and
beneficial to you and humanity and
things like that and I like creating a
community and if those people choose to
give us money at some point that's
awesome and say don't that's fine but I
believed in community
I owned a comic book store for a bunch
of years and I'm bouncing around here
like you own a comic book store you were
teacher yeah I was doing it all at the
same time it's kind of crazy but I owned
this comic book store and the reason why
our comic store became successful and we
did become very very
successful is because we built a
community and we would throw a party and
like 300 people would show up and for a
comic book store I delaford crazy we
would invite nerdcore rappers to come
and perform in a parking lot like
everything we could do to build
community it even led to a point where
we built a bar inside the comic book
store that we called the geeky Z and the
reason why we called it EK z because it
was kind of like a speakeasy that you
would have to go through the comic book
store to find a secret door that led you
to a bar like this awesome
geek bar and it still exists today if
you do a google search for the geeky Z
in Orlando and a comic shop in Orlando
that's still totally exist so that's a
little bit about me why I don't like the
word marketing anymore
I am a storyteller I believe I was born
to tell stories and I believe we were
all told bored to tell stories and so
what I would highly recommend is if you
go to and this could be the first link
that I give you to go to youtube and if
you haven't seen this yet go to jason
blanchard Derby con
and you will see a talk that I gave a
presentation or presentations because
presenting I gave here so what this is
and that the commercial but what this
talk is it's a 30-minute talk is
essentially a talk on how to give talks
and it breaks down how human beings like
to hear information because I was a
teacher for nine years and the greatest
thing our university ever did was give
every single student a laptop and at the
time you know before the laptops because
I can remember what life of like before
the students have laptops and what life
was like after the students had laptops
before the students have laptops you
would always hear chatter there was
constant chatter going on in the
classroom so your teaching you have 40
50 under students and hear a little bit
of chatter a little bit chatter
everywhere and normally they were
talking about like you say something and
it invokes an idea and then I turned to
the person next to him and they start
talking about it just like right now as
I'm talking to you it invokes an idea
you start thinking about college you
start thinking about if you had a laptop
in college like as I speak it starts
invoking and triggering ideas in your
own head
and so what happened was prior to the
laptops there was chatter
after the laptops chatter stopped and it
took a little while for me to understand
that maybe like a week or two into his
laptops I would say something and I
would hear a student like a few seconds
later go I was like why are you laughing
he's like well what you said was it was
okay but what he said about what you
said was really hilarious nothing what
do you mean what he said what I said
he's like I just chatted with him was
like you guys are all talking about me
but your laptops though that was a like
the thing that caught me off guard so
you're also talking the the greatest
thing about giving a roomful of students
laptops was all of a sudden I had to
become better than the world essentially
like if you had the ability to watch
youtube videos or watch you know
anything that you wanted to instead of
me you're paying to be in a classroom
but you're paying just like all of you
right now at any time you can choose to
click on another tab you can go watch
anything that you want you can tune me
out and so I have to be better more
interesting and all of that and so the
greatest thing about giving all the
students laptops was that I had to
become a better entertainer I had to be
a better speaker and I had to really
dive into why people like to hear
information the way they do and so what
I do is I recommend you go to this talk
that's currently on your screen and I
hope you can see my screen I think you
can at presentation or presentations
because presenting and the reason why
the title is that is for SEO to do a
Google search for derbycon presentations
I'm one the first thing that pops up
because I do like what I do because I
like messing with people all right and
when I say messing with you I like this
I liked
hack all right so let's get back to the
presentation so I am a marketer I'm
sorry I'm a comedian so I like to
practice during stand-up comedy
I'm funny if you got a chance to see me
at Derby con I was the present I did
Derby con two years but the last year I
got to be the I called myself the
keynote speaker because I was the first
person to speak at the last ferry con
but I got to do comedy at Derby come my
backgrounds and comic books and
filmmaking like I've said before I was a
teacher and so I come from the world of
comic books and filmmaking it was really
nice that ed SCOTUS because if you know
it's Curtis he took a chance on hiring
me at sans I didn't have any idea how to
do cybersecurity my wife is a hacker
she's a hacker in the family but at the
time I didn't know anything really about
cybersecurity and AD scared of soul my
background in comic books and filmmaking
and he's like yeah I think that makes
so thank you Eddie for giving me that
opportunity
I'm going to start here and I'm gonna
ask you so you got you got the questions
window
please for the next minute tell me what
some of your favorite podcasts or blogs
or twitch channels or any of that is and
I just want take a look in the questions
window and take a look at those
telling us a try guys
on Angel education and let me expand the
second see financial education channel
on YouTube Jocko podcasts all Jocko
I've never heard try guys keep them
coming
if you're in there keep them coming
Diaries
really good show Adam Savage nice
darknet diaries another one
for darknet Diaries I've started
encouraging people who play back doors
and breaches and they don't know how to
come up with a scenario is to go listen
to a bunch of darknet Diaries and that
would give you a good opportunity to
learn about storytelling and
cybersecurity and coming up with the
breeches or the possible scenarios which
is great
satisfactory streamed in okay
hardcore history that sounds interesting
Jason Blanchard reminisces nice thank
you baby so thanks for that and the
reason why I ask is because all of us
consume this stuff we are consumers of
other people's content and so what I
want to start shifting is you going from
a consumer to a producer you know
someone that you know you take a look at
what darknet Diaries is doing you take a
look at what Adam Savage is doing you
take a look at the choco podcast you
take a look at what other people are
doing that are successful and you say
that's awesome and I like what they're
doing how can I adapt some of what
they're doing into what I want to do or
what I want to do to share my knowledge
and so as you keep posting these their
comedy youtubers yeah okay try guys is
come to youtubers so the reason I ask
you is just because we all consume we
all do but I want you to start switching
over to the thought process of I'm a
consumer but now I would be a producer
and I used to tell my students this you
know you teach film school and every
person that comes to film school
really wants to make the next big TV
show the next big movie the next you
know the next thing they want to be the
next Steven spielberger to the next up
that guy from clerks Kevin Smith they
that's what they aspire to do and so I
remember how in film students said you
are the people who follow your dreams
you know there's a dream that you have
and you're following them and what you
do as filmmakers is you produce content
and this is going to sound far
you produce content for the people who
don't and it's the people who stay at
home they watch TV and I'm not saying
you're not following your dreams tonight
I was saying everyone that's not sitting
at home are following their dreams but
really that's what a lot of us do we
produce content for the people who are
afraid to produce content and now I'm
not saying everyone needs to be a
Content producer and all that stuff
police and twist my words but there's a
thing that I shifting from a consumer to
a producer is a different mindset and I
want you to be that kind of person that
if you have a dream inside of you right
now to have your voice heard or to
create something or to share your
knowledge hopefully in this talk in this
workshop I can help you switch that
raise your hand if you're shy and I know
I won't be able to see it but and I know
you're gonna feel we're doing it at home
but raise your hand if you're shy and
I'm gonna raise my hand too I'm a shy
person I know that 10 minutes people did
it in the let's go they did it in the
GoToWebinar panel
I am shy if you've ever met me you're
like really you're shy I'm like
absolutely I'm shy ten minutes before
this webcast this workshop started a
harvest are in a race and I was like I
don't know if anyone's actually going to
show up and this is going to be
interesting are they gonna pay attention
all that stuff so I started getting shy
there's a difference between going up on
stage you know if you've already got a
chance to see me up on stage it seems
like I just look confident and I look
like I'm you don't know what I'm doing
and then as soon as I get off stage it's
like he has it gone and it's nice
um there's you know there's a difference
in that because I'm shy so if you are
shy if you're at home if you're thinking
about how shy you are getting over that
shyness is really the first part of
creating content it is that first part
of internally you think who is going to
care about anything that I have to say
I'm not smart enough or I'm gonna make
something of people are gonna laugh at
it or I'm gonna make something it's not
going to be good and and yes that is
true there's gonna be people that don't
like the things that you make but you're
not making it for them the
think I can if I can teach you today
you're not making something for
everybody you're making something for
the people who want the thing that
you're making hopefully that makes sense
is that if there's a hundred people in
the room and right now there's fifty
eight of you in this room you all showed
up here because you wanted to learn this
and so that's a different audience I'm
hoping that the fifty-eight of you take
there's something away today and you
learn something from it but if I was
doing this workshop right now for the
entire while was hacking fest virtual
there's about 400 or so people you're
the only fifty of people that showed up
so if I was doing it for all 400 people
I'm only caring about the 58 of you that
showed up that cared about what I had to
say and so that's something I want you
to start thinking about is that you're
not making something for everyone you're
making something for the people who are
gonna care about what you make that
should take some of the shine this stuff
is it's not about another person who
looked I mean whether the worst comedy
shows I ever did was that besides Las
Vegas and if you were there last year
you probably saw it and what happened
was we did stand-up comedy in the big
room it was in the big room you got like
a thousand people in that room and they
asked us to do stand-up comedy up there
and I got up on stage and I'm doing my
show and I know my show was funny
because I've done it before in other
places and I know my show is funny and
as I was doing my show it was it was as
if no one cared as if no one cared and I
was telling a joke and I got to the
punchline and I heard there like a
person in the third row like over
another thank you thank you so much
because I realized that there was a few
people in the room that cared and that's
what we're doing there's this whole
world out there and most of them do not
care about what you're about to make but
for that one person who loves for that
one person that says thank you for
creating this because I didn't know it
until you made it that's who we're
making this for
all right next your own voice seriously
the sound of my voice is the worst thing
in the world to me I don't know if any
we've recorded like your outgoing
voicemail or if you've ever been on a
show if you've ever been on a podcast
you've ever been anywhere and all of a
sudden like it's time to hear the
recording and you hear it and like is
that what I sound like is it odd isn't
it Oh God so for those of you at home
right now the first homework I have for
you and I'm gonna have little homeworks
here and there and is for you to at some
point record the sound of your voice
when your computer is somewhere and
getting a better mic is gonna help but
it's only gonna help you hear the sound
of your voice better like it it just
does like no must one just want the
worst microphone possible so that way
you can blame it on the microphone what
I want you to do is record the sound of
your voice and just hear it over and
over and over and over and over and over
again until it becomes less terrible
because that is all of us all
fifty-eight of you that are currently on
this if I was to like hey I want you to
hear the sound of your voice
I also learned long time ago being a
photographer is if you ever take a group
photo of anyone and you hand that group
photo but somebody was in the photo they
don't look at anyone else besides
themselves
settle in for a second do you hand a
group photo to somebody and they're in
it they won't look at anyone else but
themselves and they're looking for flaws
and they're looking for things that they
wish they could improve and it's just
something that we do you know my
daughter came home the other day and
she's like I don't like the way I look
Oh sweetheart I don't think you should I
mean I can understand why you say that
but I don't feel like you should judge
the way you look right now while you're
like in puberty because you're not gonna
look like this so you know you from now
just like whatever no no you're so cute
but when we look and when we hear
ourselves and we watch our videos were
so critical about what we what we do and
so that's one of the things that you
have to get over is that self-critical
miss and it doesn't go away if I go to
hear the recording of this or if I hear
the recording of my own talks from
derbycon or anywhere else there's so
much like oh I see that oh there's so
much cringy moments but in the flipside
I'll have hundreds of people reach out
and say thank you so much for doing that
thank you so much for saying that sync
thank you so much for teaching me that
you're welcome you just have to accept
that impostor syndrome we've already
talked about that a little bit but the
sound of your own voice just amplifies
the fact that you shouldn't be talking
and since flix darn it to the imposter
syndrome kicks in am i qualified to tuck
to teach this at Kellan I think you're
here telling you gave your talk
yesterday about you know you're new to
this but you still have something to
teach you can still mentor somebody when
I work with some of the Black Hills
testers you know you have some junior
testers and they have the imposter
syndrome - because we're Black Hills
information security we've ranked blogs
we do these webcast and all these people
show up and when I'm like it when I talk
to a junior tester not like what you
like to give a webcast like how many
people are on it so that's like a
thousand like well think about oh you're
fine like what am I going to teach
somebody and as like - you're a webapp
pen tester in like yeah and I was like
so what did you learn about seven months
ago that you now know but you didn't
know seven months ago you know like well
this this and this I was like that would
make a great webcast because there is up
most likely a ton of people out there
that also don't know those things now
but if you taught it to them right now
they would know those things have mantra
now so don't just think that because
you're at this point your career you
have nothing to teach or if you're at
this point in your career like there's
so much for you to share with others and
this is not just about InfoSec this is
about your hobbies this is about the way
that you live your life there are so
many things that you can share with
others I'm thinking about doing a twitch
show right down on adulting because I'm
41 and I have a 14 year old daughter and
I've been married for 21 years it's like
is there anything there that I can share
with other people who are just learning
so there is an opportunity for you to
teach somebody something and I want to
share this with you is that never deny
sharing your knowledge for someone else
you know there there are so many people
out there that
like I just keep saying would benefit
from what is currently in your brain and
so if I can encourage you to do anything
today it's to start submitting CFPs to
talks for other conferences it's to
start your own twitch channel where you
go through how to do web at 10:00
testing it is to do your own your own
short how-to videos on how you use a
tool it's to create your own tools it's
do something like that please never
denies someone else learning what's
currently in your brain because there's
so much knowledge you can share but why
why do any of this
well I do any of this why share your
knowledge like create why raise your
hand why face the the criticism why
overcome your own fears your shyness fly
do any of this and there are three main
reasons there's a B and C the first one
is to give back you know if your whole
intention if your whole purpose is to
just say look I learned coming up to the
point of my career I've learned over the
years how to do these things and I just
want to teach the next generation I just
want to teach somebody else I just want
to share what I have that other people
shared with me up to others and if that
is your main intention it's gonna shine
it's gonna shine them through and all
the things that you create it's going to
shine through in the way that you teach
it's going to shine through it
absolutely is and people are gonna
resonate with that because people like
generous other like they will follow
generous people it just will
they'll see someone that's giving away
knowledge and they're like thank you let
me learn more from you and so by giving
back you're gonna help others but you're
also gonna start creating community
around the knowledge that you're shared
and then those people will start sharing
knowledge I get to see it every single
day of Black Hills is that we share our
knowledge with so many people and we
created a discord channel this week for
Black Hills and when we did that we
invited 50 people from Twitter we
invited another 100 Twitter and we just
said there you go we're just learning
how to use this and they started sharing
knowledge with each other it was a
little bit of you know here's what I've
learned from Black Hills hey I have this
question and B started sharing with each
other and that is exactly what we're
looking for is that we we are the focal
points that got the conversation started
but then once the community gets goings
in that community it's just out there
and helping others and so that you can
be the beginning of that conversation at
the beginning of that community or what
you want to do if your intention is to
make money you will you absolutely can
make money by sharing your knowledge you
can make it through training you can
make it through uh advertising on your
blogs you can make it through sponsors
so I work in marketing I work in
marketing and if I see somebody out
there that has an audience so darknet
Diaries about a year ago I saw darknet
Diaries and that they were growing and
not only were they also you know because
darknet Diaries is fantastic if you
haven't heard them go check them out
jack is an amazing storyteller and has a
way of relating information to others I
can also hear my dogs in the background
just barking and somebody let them out
and I'm sure that's fine there's whoever
let him out it's gonna bring him back in
so actually I really don't know who let
the dogs out so if you want to make
money so when I saw darknet Diaries as a
marketer I looked at the fact that he
was building an audience and I reached
out to Jack and I said do you take
sponsorship and so he has a person that
reached out to me and said we absolutely
do and we started looking at you know
would Black Hills sponsored Dark Knight
Diaries and so if you have a show if you
build an audience and people are
starting to show up people like me will
show up to and say how much money can I
give you and we do this like there's
gonna be some sponsors that are
currently in there to listen to the
workshop right now I know that you're a
sponsor and I know that you're here and
you do this too when you see somebody
out there that's that's building an
audience and sharing their knowledge you
start looking at them going how can I be
a part of what you're doing to get our
message out to your audience and so if
you're building an audience people like
me will show up and ask can I give you
money so that is the thing that you can
do build your career this is an
interesting thing by sharing your
knowledge by being a teacher by being a
subject matter expert but not calling
yourself a salt leader just not leader
when whenever so people ask John come
speak at something and so it's me and
John on a call and they will say John
you're such a thought leader like I can
feel both of us just cringing you know
it's just because neither one of us want
to call Jonathan either I don't want to
be a thought leader I just want to be
someone that's sharing my knowledge but
as you become what other people perceive
as a thought leader it will help you
build your career think about this let's
say you're doing a blog one Splunk
all the ins and outs this blog and how
the spunk works and how this works and
how all that stuff works and then all of
a sudden you lose your current job but
there's hundreds and thousands of people
who read your splint blog they watch
your how to videos all that stuff you
have a mailing list that you've created
of people who want to see your content
in the future and you somehow lose the
job that you have due to whatever
happened no it's layoffs so the company
folded or they got bought out by someone
else they didn't want you whatever it is
that caused you to lose your job and you
have this audience this community these
people who respect you and look at you
to learn from
and all of a sudden you write a tweet
saying hey everyone I'm currently
looking for a position right now this is
my background this is my history it's
like a thousand people who look at you
who are constantly oh yeah come work for
us this can really help you build your
career by giving back by sharing your
knowledge by creating content and by
being brave even though you're shy oh I
love this quote - bravery oh I wanna see
it right saving a baby that fell into a
pool is not really brave it's just the
right thing to do
he's you know baby Falls employee jump
in the same
not really breathe
now a baby falling into a pool full of
sharks and then you jump in to save it
that's bravery and so what I mean by
that is if you're afraid if you're
scared if you're shy and you still do it
anyway that's being brave but if you're
like wow this is really I don't know if
that's bravery and if you're sitting
here like
Jason that feels controversial let me
talk about in this Court channel because
I like to start conversations okay so if
your goal is to give back and that is
where you start from that is your
intention and that is when you're
creating anything that is where you're
you're the center of the of your why if
your reason is to make money then that's
the center of your why and so that's
going to change the way that you create
your content and how you reach out to
sponsors if your goal is to build a
career and that's the core of why you're
doing it it's going to change the
content is create and why you're keep
braiding it but I will tell you this if
your sole intention is to get back you
will make money and you will build your
career
I get just it will happen if you start
from the generosity of giving back those
other two things will happen
it just does
all right so some of the types of things
that we're going to talk about today so
we're gonna jump in and talk about these
different types of things that you can
create and then I'm gonna get real
practical in how to's I got an hour and
a half still so just stay with me and
then hopefully we'll get into a Q&A
section at some point so we're gonna
cover webcast and streaming we're gonna
cover how to videos great on blogs and
light presentations and podcast audience
in turnovers public so I added this
slide after I talked to someone at
derbycon
so I got done doing this whole talk yeah
for the most part I did this talk at
Derby calm but it's more expanded for
you all I gave this talk at Derby con
and right afterwards a guy came up and
said Jason I loved everything you said
you know it was good I see the the
beneficial giving back I see this I see
all that but I work for an organization
where I can't talk about any of the
things that I do yeah that is a thing in
security well I had not thought of that
and so I added this slide for you that
person who's in a position where you
can't give a live presentation you can't
do a webcast on the things that you know
you can't write a blog because of the
nature of the work that you do and so I
just well as I was talking to her I
realized there's a difference between an
internal audience and a public audience
and so for those of you that are in that
inside that world where you can't share
outside of that world what I'd like for
you to start doing is think about how
you can be that internal creator of
content and so what I mean by that is if
you work in an organization where you
can't really share things out outside
what if you created the internal
security blog or your company or in a
how-to video inside your company or you
initiated the conversation with the
executives on security and you gave them
a rundown and here's how phishing works
for executives here's how this works for
executives and you started taking the
knowledge that you had and break it down
for people who are not in your section I
remember I talked to Derek Brooke one
time and Derek gave his presentation
this morning I don't know if he's here
but he did an internal CTF I think was a
physical pentesting CTF at his
organization so it was picking the locks
of your internal doors or
and I may have this wrong but I think I
had it right but it was a internal
physical pentesting CTF inside your org
and so what he thought he taught some
lock-picking he's taught this and he's
like you know came up with the CTF
inside his organ and that's awesome
that's like engaging that's getting
people interested but then you become
the subject matter expert for security
and so think about can I apply any of
the things that I'm about to talk about
to of that internal audience or can I
apply to a public audience now the
public audience if you work in security
and you can't share any of the things
that you have there then the public
audience might be one of your hobbies
there aren't like my core is this hobby
this amazing hobby of making knives and
making steel cutting instruments I think
that's a sword I got yeah but he created
an Instagram for that and he started
getting out there and he got invited to
be on this TV show because of the work
that he does it's incredible and so
there's a if you have this hobby or if
you have this thing that you'd like to
do maybe that's the public mounting that
you create and then if you take your
security that's the internal work that
you do now I have this other note here
laser focused and so when I talked film
school students would come in and they
would pitch projects and like I had this
idea for a move you had this idea for TV
show I have this idea for you know web
series and the first question we'd
always ask us who is your audience you
know like what's everyone that is the
worst answer because it is not for
everybody and so what we would do is we
start diving down who that audience is
and what we would normally do is say who
the audience isn't and so you would have
to get into demographics and so
demographics is normally big chunks of
people and I would say are these the
kind of people like their own cruises
and there is a kind of person that goes
on the cruise I became that person last
week there's also the kind of person
that goes on the cruise in the middle of
the corona virus that's a different
demographic but you have these people
that do they wear Wranglers
in clerks I was like yeah that's a kind
of person I mean there's a there's a
demography out there of people who wear
Wranglers and so you start diving
through Timah graphics and as we would
use different types of demographics you
would start narrowing down your audience
and so it'd be like is it the kind of
person that uses Linux like yes Wells
are the kind of person I'd use Windows
yeah so as you start thinking about all
the people who it is not you would be
left with the person who is that it is
for and the reason why this is important
because it gets back to that there's a
thousand people in the room but only
four people are listening trying to do
comedy in a room full of a thousand
people
that wasn't my target audience the
target audience was the four people
imagine if I had taken those four people
into a cyber room and did the show for
them it would've been a completely
different experience and so that you
started looking at this laser focused
audience group because you're not making
it for everyone you're making it for the
people who care and so if you do come up
with an idea you do like I'm gonna write
a blog about this I'm gonna do this the
first thing I want you to do is write on
your sheet of paper who is my audience
and start thinking about all the people
that it's not and then you'll be left
the people who it is and then you can
figure out how to reach those people and
we'll talk about that in a little bit
content chunking yeah I love this so
much being a person who creates content
is that your goal is to make a big thing
that can be broken into smaller things
but it's a big thing I can be broken in
smaller things so you're always thinking
what is the big thing I can make that
can be broken into smaller things what I
mean by that is can I give an hour-long
webcast that has
full breaks in it so every five minutes
I'm talking about this subject and I'm
talking about this subject or this
subject but this is up
then can I break that webcast down into
five minute section I then make those
five minute sections available on
Twitter or someplace else like how can I
make the big thing that I put on
youtubes and I could break it into
smaller things or how can I make a at
sans I made a lot of posters and so if
you have like the blueprint pentesting
poster that was something that I made
with our graphic designer if you have
the pivots and payloads you know the
game poster you can download all these
PDFs if you want the first poster that
we started with was the whiteboard
poster and let me go ahead and bring
that up
and she what we did with it so if you go
to white board poster sans pen testing
okay also I've been staring at the white
ring around my camera for a while and so
then I got this cute
hopefully you can see this what this is
it's
things that would help you with bash our
shell Python some commanded exe these
are all little hints and notes that
would just help you be a better pen
tester and so you can take a look at
that and go download it so the idea was
you are the kind of person you know when
you find something that's good you write
it down you're like keep it and so what
if you were in your cubicle or if you
were at your home or somewhere and you
started hosting shows up around you
and so that was the initial concept it
was like okay so it's like a whiteboard
you know you got all your notes on
whiteboard well what if we just created
the whiteboard and then we sent it to
people and so it's already got all the
notes on it so that's where we did we
designed this to look like a whiteboard
and if it's hanging up in an office it
looks like someone's actual whiteboard
if it's actually a big poster and it
looks like you're just really diligent
about finding things that will help you
do your job and so we created this
poster and then here's the part that I
really liked is that each one of these I
don't know if you can see my mouse each
one of these became a piece of content
that wasn't shared on social social
media and so each one of these cards on
you know so there's five Python cards
there's like six PowerShell cards just
like nineteen bash cars and there's this
each one of those wasn't broken down
into its individual piece and then that
was shared out and what we did is that
we said if you like this then click this
link to go get a full poster or to ask
for us to mail it to you and so all this
was broken down into individual chunks
and so if you look at the giant poster
PDF here
this all broke down and it was
promotional because you can't make
anything without being able to sell it
- do we get this here all broken down
the individual pieces that's what I mean
you create a giant chunk of content how
can I do it how can I make something
that's big and then break it down into
its individual pieces if you've ever
played back doors and breaches that is
what this is we said how can we make
something that's incredibly useful to
people something that's gonna help them
with doing instant response like the
sole purpose the intent was how do we
get back absolutely the very core of
this was how do we get back how do we
create something that benefits people
now it is beneficial to us because each
one of these has like a blog on it that
leads back to us but the sole purpose in
the very beginning the genesis of this
was how can we create but if you take a
look at the concept of content chunking
this is a deck of cards all of this is
one big piece of content big it's
content that teaches people something
and it leads back to learn more but then
each card is a piece of content so this
is one big piece of content the whole
deck and then each one of these is its
own piece of content that leads to other
pieces of content because there's links
on here and there's other things like
that so if you go to and I wanted to
post an example today for you if you go
to the
be Black Hills
I did this today as an example so this
is one card of 52 and here's the two
blogs that lead back to it and if you
take a look at some of the stats 12
click throughs or link click throughs
lead back to the website and so people
learned more about fishing today because
of that link
so content chucking the concept again
just to run through it as you great
you're like how can I make something big
and then break it into smaller
individual pieces
evergreens
so whatever green means is that you make
something that lasts
or forever essentially you write a blog
that can be useful to anyone for the
next 5-10 years you do a webcast that's
gonna be useful for the next five to ten
years you create a tool that's gonna be
useful for the next five to ten years
you're always thinking about is this
something that's gonna be evergreen and
not everything that you make will be
evergreen I remember we put out a blog
last year and Kari wrote it to is a it
was a how to bypass Windows Defender or
something like that it was something
that was like no this is this is really
good useful great put out to an audience
and was in a day that blog was dead -
someone at Microsoft was like oh no and
they fix it they fix the bug like almost
instantly and so that blog was pretty
much dead within a week and so we're
like no that's that sucks but the
techniques that were used in it we're so
useful and so in a little bit you'll get
a chance to see our content library and
when I go through the content library
you're gonna see tons of blogs that are
just read out what that means is that
they're no longer useful because the
techniques or the the tool that was used
no longer useful and
and pentesting our offensive security
but you're gonna see a ton of them that
are still useful so a blog written in
2017 and still be useful to somebody in
2020 because the techniques use the
tools use are so useful and that's what
I mean by evergreen is that you've wrote
it in 2017 but you can still keep using
it all the way up until today and so
when you're looking at creating your own
content you know that's something to
keep in mind is this something that's
going to be evergreen every single piece
of content needs to be evergreen but
just really good if it is
content library make it once use it over
and over and over over and over and over
again so content library I'm gonna show
you what ours looks like
so every time you create a piece of
content
well that's the name of it this is when
it was published we give all of our
contents an ID and that's Mick Douglas
and he wrote this and we can take a look
at come how many people clicked on it we
could take a look at where the link is
you know I stuff and then we also have a
content library that goes along with it
so this is the same title same ID yeah
Mick Douglas and then we have a
pre-written tweet and a pre-written
LinkedIn post are you ready to go and
this was built so that way we could hire
interns to be able to do our social
media scheduling for us and so we can
schedule out and say on this date that
this time post Z reserves of one if you
never noticed this before on all of our
graphics on our post on these see do you
look it up in that top corner you got
zero zero four three six that is the
graphic that goes with that post and so
we created this so that way if an intern
and I'm not saying interns aren't smart
I'm just saying interns you need to get
the speed quickly and you need to turn
them over and if you're managing them
all the time then why even have an
intern so we created this uh you know
content library so that way if you
create something back in 2015 and it's
still useful well then you can still
post it now I know it's made 2015 but
like I said if it's still useful and so
as you go through here and as you can
see all the red those are no longer we
asked all the pen testers and all the
blogger authors to go through and say is
this blog so relevant is this blog so
good art is and every ones that are read
it was no
but you see all the ones that are still
not read and we can post those
and why are we posting them because
they're helpful because we're giving
back to the community it does lead
people back to our website and if they
want to hire us they can but the sole
purpose of it is that this is useful
information we're getting out to an
audience and those people have been
sharing with others and learning from it
and the blog written in 2017 you may
think like I already know that you may
think you already know that like it was
written in 2017 I've been in industry
for five or six years I know that why
are you still posting it and it's really
because of that new student who just got
into college who's starting to learn
cybersecurity that decided to follow our
Twitter feed and now they're like oh
what is that and now they're learning
something so it's once again it's not
just about you it's about the whole
community and so the thing that you
create that you created a few years ago
could still be useful to that person
who's just getting started
all right so this is what a content
library looks like and this is how you
manage it super simple how do you create
graphics you can do it on Fiverr you can
find someone on Fiverr so if you get a
fiber fi berr yes
a great place to find graphic artists is
to go to Fiverr and you can hire them
and once you create the template once
you creates a template then it's just a
matter of sending here's a new title
here's this here's the number please add
it and change it so we have a graphic
designer that works with us and her job
is to make these she makes a lot of
other things but one of her jobs is to
create these for us to share
there's
all right and then one last like tip
before we start diving into some of the
more how to's is interviews
so let's say you are a you want to start
a podcast that talks about Hollywood
Stuntz and I'm just starting it was like
a brain of thing that seriously just
popped into my head
and you want to do a podcast on
Hollywood stunt people
because you want to be a Hollywood stunt
person or you just loves Hollywood
stunts
what you can do is reach out to
Hollywood stunt people
and one of the ways to do that is to go
to IMDB if you didn't know I am DD
Breaux I don't have a pro account so I
can't show you right now but if you go
to IMDB Pro back when I worked in the
film industry all the time IMDB Pro is
my best friend but with IMDB Pro you can
essentially find any agent or contact
information for anyone in the film
industry so two years ago I ran
something called free comic book day so
if you've ever been to a comic book
store for a few years I was the person
who brand free comic book day for the
creek for a comic industry and one of
the things I would do for a free combat
days I would reach out to celebrities
I'd reach out to people in the industry
and I would ask them if they would make
videos or something to help promote free
callable day and I am going to show you
my favorite person that I ever got to do
a free comic book day
this it's levar burton it was like the
best day of you adult Jason's life when
I got a chance to reach out to levar
burton through his agent through IMDB
Pro and so I got into contact and I said
this is who we are that we're free comic
today we're all about you know comic
books and we were looking to see if
lebar levar would do this and they said
sure and so I got a chance to call and
talk to levar burton walk him through
what we're looking for
he asked me you know like why are we
doing this and you know not why we're
doing this but like try to get the wise
that way he could say what he wanted to
say properly and he did it and so the
reason why I bring this up is because I
have very limited Osen skills super
limited Osen skills
and you don't some of you that are
currently listening to this workshop
have amazing hosting skills and you can
track down anybody anywhere and so I
want you to start thinking about that
that with IMDB Pro or your other
websites that you know that you can
track people down I mean back in like
2004 or five when Facebook was starts
just starting you could message anybody
I was before they set you to the other
category you can message anybody and
back then I would reach out to Hollywood
producers and directors and writers and
I would just send them messages like hey
I'm Jason um this and they would get
back home with me not all of them
because not everyone always gets back
with you but one of the people that I
reached out to back in my space days to
myspace is I'm not going to myspace I'm
gonna go to this guy here Jason Aaron
but my name is Jason my business partner
names at the time was named Aaron and so
this guy who had just written one book
at the time it's called the the other
side named Jason Aaron and we've read it
it was fantastic and we're like let's be
friends with that guy so on myspace I
reached out to Jason Aaron and I said
hey we are comic book store owners and
we'd love to become friends with you and
we did we became good friends with Jason
Aaron and four years Jason Aaron would
come to Jason and Aaron's joint birthday
party and it's like Jason Aaron presents
Jason there is anyway it was fun but
this guy went on to become like an
amazing superstar in the comic book
industry so he writes tons of other
great books and it really started with a
myspace message where we got to meet him
got to know him and we've been friends
since like 2006 and I'm I'm not a my
name dropping I hope I'm not name
dropping what I'm hope I'm doing is
showing you how you can use your Osen
skills to get in touch with people
because here's here's the step I want
you to take next if you have a show or a
webcast or a blog or this and you want
to interview somebody that's
don't go a list famous because you don't
have an a-list audience to get a list
famous people yet I mean if you want to
feel free to go and try that but if
you're looking at the B level or sea
level or D level or the crew level you
know these people who are part of this
industry over here a part of this
industry are part of that industry
you're a part of your hobby or something
like that
you can reach out to these people you
can contact them and you can say I have
a podcast I have this show I have this
blog I have this interview channel I
have this twitch I have this thing I
have this thing that I'm creating would
you come on and allow me to interview
you now as a part of my job one of the
things I do is I go out and I look for
podcasts I look or shows and I say we
have these testers would you like them
to be a part of your show and a lot of
these your podcasts and like your
podcast you're gonna you're gonna need
someone to interview and so marketers
like me are always reaching out and it's
not going to be a sales pitch it's no
vendor pitch and now you highly
recommend that you don't do vendor
pitches and sales pitches because that
just turns off your audience is that you
reach out to the person you want to
interview and say I have this show would
you like to be on it
now if they say yes and you're doing the
show together what are you doing while
you're interviewing person
you're starting a relationship you're
creating a relationship this person that
you're interviewing and that
relationship may turn into a business
relationship may turn into a personal
relationship may never go anywhere else
but that interview interview is your
first step to building a new contact a
new connection and your networking it's
an opportunity for you to make friends
and I call it the Trojan horse because
there are some people who if your sole
purpose is to make money or build your
career with your content you're creating
they do this on purpose what they'll do
is they'll take a look at their top 50
prospects or the top 50 leads or the top
50 companies that they want to work for
and they will reach out to those top 50
companies and say would you like to be
on my show that is their first step in
the door now working with that company
this is something people really do and
so if that is a goal or the intent of
yours if you're a business that does
pentesting and you want to do it for
these companies you can reach out to
these companies you can say hey we'd
like to bring you on the show and we
want to talk about security and so maybe
you're talking to the sister or talking
to this person I'm talking to them about
things that they can talk about because
once again the work that we do would be
pretty
Begg when we do discuss it and so as
you're talking with these people you're
also building an injury relationship
with them now if your sole purpose is to
make money or build your career then
what you do is about three or four days
later you send them the link or the
podcast or the show or the Twitter or
whatever it is that you're creating you
send them a link and you say hey thanks
so much for being on my show really
appreciated it hopefully I can reach out
again and talk to you in the future if
they respond back then it's like a what
we eat and marketing call a drip
campaign is that you start with this hey
let me introduce you and then over time
let's build this relationship and then
over time I would like to tell you about
a product that I have or a service that
I offer so this is something that you
can do and it this turns you off if if
as I'm telling you this right now and
you're like oh big cool good and you're
gonna start with that the sole purpose
for doing this is to get back ok what
I'm saying is that whatever your intent
is there's an opportunity here so if
your intent is to get back and maybe
it's just building relationships with
people who taught you something and you
want to bring them on because that
person taught you something and you want
to give them an opportunity to share
with the audience that you've been
creating
interviews our Trojan horse and you have
amazing Osen skills there is nobody
that's outside your grasp of reaching
out to and asking if they can be a part
of your show
I'm going to
give us a 10-minute break
should I give it some more break
most of the questions if you needed
seminar break I don't
just make sure if I see one yes I would
do it son number
Ali said yes so I would be back in ten
minutes but I'm not going anywhere but
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna take a
break from doing the content and I'm
just gonna answer some questions so I'm
going to go to the discord and I'm going
to answer some questions
so shoot em on
hey Oscar
alright are you calling me your mom if
you have any questions feel free
question is it possible to get a
template of your content library yes it
is I will get that out to you I will
figure out a way to prospect I will put
it in our active countermeasures calm
slash presentations and I will put it in
while I was hacking fest virtual folder
and you can get grab it there
[Music]
I get the Ryan Reynolds thing often
I I feel like I'm the more the better
looking version of Ryan Reynolds you're
watching something else other than
discord during your talk that explains
it
so we're going to start up again at 105
for content in the meantime take a break
and I will answer question
is giving back to the industry
the best sort of guidance
know that that's not my guidance my
guidance is know why you're doing it
so it's it really does boil down to
those three things is it to make money
build your career or give back and so
you just need to know why you're doing
it because if your goal is to make money
then that a year later is your key
performance indicator like you've made
$10,000 like okay so that is your key
performance indicator if it is to build
your career than a year later do you
have a different do you have the job
that you want that you didn't currently
have if you're if the reason why is to
get back and maybe it's the community
that's being built and the amount of
people that are showing up to your
webcast and it's it's about the numbers
of humans and it's not necessarily the
number with the connections that are
being made a lot of times we have over a
thousand people in our webcast and you
see the same faces over and over and
over again those people are becoming
like family and so what's cool is that
you see the same people coming back and
it's not just becoming a sea of faceless
people is becoming our friends and it's
becoming like family
what do you do when you were asked to
teach talk about something you're either
don't know or aren't familiar whisk ah
so one of the greatest ways to learn
something is that to give a presentation
on it like it really is is so that is my
number one recommendation if someone
asks you to presenting something you
currently don't know and it gives you an
opportunity to learn it
same thing with content creation if
there is something that you do want to
learn plan to do a webcast on it six
months from now and you're gonna give
yourself a reason to learn it
I will talk about this in a little bit
but just during the break is that I and
many of the people I know when they
submit a CFP they have no idea how
they're gonna do the research or how
they're gonna build the slides or how
they're gonna put anything together
they just submit a CFP for this thing
that they want to do or this idea that
they have this research that they want
to do and then if they get accepted I
know I have a deadline learn this thing
so I would say
so what do you do when you're asked to
teach something not familiar was quickly
learn it or asked not to present
the only time now I don't say only time
the time that I look really
uncomfortable presenting is on the one
slide that I don't know as well like all
the other slides I'm like I'm good I'm
good I'm good and then I get to the one
slide where I don't feel real confident
about it I like internally I'm like
don't die like the anxiety shoots up my
heart starts racing more like yeah the
room starts getting like so I would just
say that if you are presenting on
something you don't know very well it's
gonna show in the way that you're
confident
unless it's whose lot whose slide is it
anyway and then that's just fun we are
going to try to figure out a way maybe
not for this event but to be able to do
a virtual who's slide is it any way
through discord and presenting
all right how do you adapt your
presentations a very young audiences
like kids who don't swear I don't think
I've sworn before heard this hello if I
if I've sworn let me know when I
generally teach when it especially when
I talk college I just swore all the time
is that I really felt like it got the
students more engaged either they hated
it and they paid attention because they
hated it or they liked it and so they
paid attention because I was being
brutally honest like garyvee so how do
you adapt to kids so change your
anecdotes to things that they would
understand what I mean by that is when I
teach I think about my audience all the
time so right now I am adapting
everything that I'm talking about for
the most part to InfoSec but I could do
the same exact talk or somebody that
worked in an automotive I could do the
same exact talk for someone that worked
in marketing I could do the same exact
talk for people that worked in other
industries and I would just start
adjusting my stories my anecdotes my
reasons is something that that audience
would understand but when working with
little kids you start thinking about you
know what is their world like
and and
and I don't fit that how much time is
too much time into creating content
that's up to you and your schedule
we'll get two into this in a little bit
but one of the things is is
don't publish anything until you've made
a couple of those things and I'll give
you an exact number here in a little
while but don't publish anything until
you've made a bunch and the reason why
is because that first one you make might
have taken you two weeks to create and
then at the end of it you realize you
don't have two weeks to make that thing
and so all of a sudden you know you
decide not to make stuff anymore
what's the best way to reach out to
people that you want the Siri content
that's people aren't specifically
looking for my youtube channel
cybersecurity wareness channel I know a
lot of people may not be interest but I
want to increase awareness for the
average person reaching these people
seem to be difficult
yeah
so I would so in that situation finding
people like that is you start looking
for influential people in other
industries so if you want to bring
security awareness student but you call
the average person then you would find
someone that's already has an audience
either through twitch or through
Instagram or through other places and
it's called influencer marketing and so
what you do is you would reach out to
them and say would it be possible for
you to mention this to your audience
because it's really beneficial to them
and it can really help you and help your
audience learn about cybersecurity stuff
so if you didn't catch that what I'm
looking what you're looking for is other
people in other industries that have
influence and then you reach out to them
and say would you be willing to share
your influence with your audience to
help this get out to that Ani
you know of opportunities for learning
or getting a mentorship for creating
content like brainstorming content ideas
turning those into draft content
co-presenting son
um telling
let me think about that no it's not
weird just let me think about the best
way to get that
all right so we lost a few and that's
fine we lost a few people during the
break
to get ready to start back up here and
Sue back to the imposter syndrome and
back to the shyness is that I just like
you if you're giving a talk in a live
presentation and somebody gets up and
leaves it hurts
for some reason at first and what
happens is they get up and they may hey
but who lived Juma treason they gotta
use the bathroom they got to go
somewhere else they want to go to
another talk they get up and leave and
you're like this is something I said
I've been better could have done
something different and so you know we
just lost a few people during the 10
minute break and I was even thinking
about that do I have this 10 minute
break because I might lose some people
but once again the people you lose are
the people who
you're not reaching or they wanted to go
to another talk and so I have to
understand
heart
and we're back
webcast live are recorded so this is
lead-in to what I just said about the
people staying in the people going and
all that stuff
webcast so what is the webcast webcast
normally a 60 minute or 30 minute where
you're gonna cover a single topic so one
of the things that you're going to need
is a webcast platform at Black Hills we
use GoToWebinar you could use
GoToMeeting if you have a up to like
depending on your accounts I think you
can have between 50 to 250 people so if
you don't think it's gonna be a lot of
people showing up in the beginning you
could just create a good a meeting
account you can post a link out in your
social media or wherever and say I'm
going to cover this topic for a little
while if you want to show up again it's
going to be engaging I want answer your
questions
yes stuff like that but if you start
getting into larger audiences to this
year at Black Hills we started averaging
more than a thousand people per webcast
and like I kind of exploded like last
year the average was about 500 to 600
and then it kept growing and then now
we're we're averaging one webcast was
like 1500 people and stuff and the
reason why I bring that up is because
there is multiple tiers like you're not
just a webcast for the people you but as
you increase the amount of people you're
talking to you also have to increase
like an infrastructure answering
questions and things like that so for
those of you who are just getting
started if you're doing webcast you can
start with any platform while we were
looking at we had like 6,000 people sign
up for a free training class that we
were doing we didn't know how to
facilitate if all six thousand people
showed up so we found a it was webinar
jam alright so for those of you don't
want to take a look at this figure
there's a ton of platforms out there we
liked webinar jam the only issue with
webinar jam is that they have a
vulnerability inside their platform and
so until they fix that vulnerability
we're not going to use it but webinar
Jam is here you do it for like if you're
doing a smaller we're doing an
information security webcast and so to
have a vulnerability in a platform was
not good for us but if you're doing a
webcast on your hobby or something else
that you like to do then maybe a webinar
jam it's like $90 a month they can give
you up to 5,000 people you probably
start with a smaller tier
but there's a lot of different services
out there we just use GoToWebinar
because of stable and it's secure even
we got hit by let's just call them
Rooskies who were hitting us with a bot
and they were filling up ours like our
list of they were just they were
registering everybody and so we reset
the GoToWebinar and we said hey we're
having this problem and so they created
it they were in the middle of creating a
CAPTCHA shut that stuff down and we
became a bae beta user for that so what
is the difference between live and
recorded and I would tell you this it's
the retention rate it's people's
attention the retention rate for a live
webcast is about 90 percent
retention rate for a live webcast is
about 90% the retention rate or eight a
recorded webcast is 10% or less
think about the the retention rate for a
live webcast is 90 the retention rate
for a recorded is 10 you know those are
people who go all the way through from
beginning to end and why is that
because you are a human being and I'm a
human being and I'm currently speaking
to you and you're hearing me and there's
a chance that you can engage with me
write a question we can go back and
forth but what's it recorded that's not
I'm just a video just like all the other
videos on the internet and if it's not
interesting to me after 30 seconds I'll
just kill it but there's something about
human to humans like if we see another
human being we will give them our
attention and it's the reason why in a
live presentation if I'm up on stage
generally people won't leave and the
same thing for you if you're up on stage
and giving a live presentation generally
people won't leave it's because there is
something about us humans are like you
know I'm just gonna stay I think it
would be rude for me to get up and leave
but it doesn't mean they're paying
attention the fact that you're still
here doesn't mean that you're actually
watching me right now are looking at my
slides it just means that you're here
and so I know that you could be looking
at other things you're doing work right
now you're checking your email as your
own this discord channel I still don't
have your full attention but it's more
than if I was recorded and so if I was
going to encourage you to do anything I
would say I would encourage you to do
live webcast and live webcast can help
you start building her mailing list and
them as you build your mailing list or
your discord channel especially if
you're doing twitch or some other
live-streaming like YouTube live or
something if you're doing live your
sessions live streaming and those people
are engaging with you and then you can
say hey follow me on my discord channel
or go enjoy my mailing list then those
are the same people that when you go
live again and you send out the email
and say hey we're gonna live at this
date at this time he'll show back up for
the next one because you've given them
something that they've beneficial to
them it now journalized it they liked it
it's good they pass it on to others and
so you start building that community
right there to live now doesn't mean you
don't take your recording and put it up
but that recording should point people
to your next live offering so you would
want that recording to constantly be
pushing people to the live version
because live is where the engaging part
takes place so it'll get an account you
can do use go to meeting you can go to
do others and then what are you gonna do
your webcast on
whatever you really want to so telling
you brought up a good point
who do you brainstorm with and at Black
Hills they have me they do and at some
organizations I'm gonna put your name
it's later later I know you're asking
Guardians and so they have you and so
one of the things I do is I reach out to
staff and I say hey we need a webcast
for this date what would you like to do
it on and they're like I don't know I
was like alright so what are you
currently working on I like what I'm
doing this how's it so what was
something interesting in the last pen
test report you know like well this was
an interesting finding well how'd you
find it like this way is that a tool
that you're currently using mm-hmm is
that a tool that other if you would want
to know about like I think so okay cool
so we're gonna do a webcast on this tool
using this technique that you use on a
recent pen test night okay and so it is
beneficial to have someone to bounce
ideas off of because if I'm sitting here
right now and it's just me yeah
posture syndromes gonna kick in super
hard and I'm like well what about this I
could do a show about that it all sounds
like no one wants to hear you say that
nobody would want to see that no yeah
okay well it does help have somebody to
bounce ideas off of and I will talk
about this in a little bit but for your
how-to videos it's always good to have
someone else around
Oh kelan and the rest of you if there's
someone that you trust or their opinion
and I would recommend that you reach out
to them and say here's like the five
ideas that I would like to do which one
of those do you think is best or you ask
them this question what's something that
you wish you knew a year ago that you
currently know now
and that's a good question to get people
started with I wish I would have known
it's about Metasploit I wish I would
have known this about going hiking as my
wife and I like to go hiking and one of
the things that we do is that we learn
about hiking through other blogs or
through other people's websites and one
of the things that we really like is
there's a website an app called gut
hooks or all trails and it's the reviews
that people leave and so that's content
you know if someone goes to a to a cabin
and they're like this is the information
about it cool thank you so much for
sharing your knowledge with us before we
get to that place and so I'm not just
talking about InfoSec I'm talking about
you have a so much that you know and
other people could benefit from it live
streaming this is new I took a class on
lives training about four weeks ago and
I know about live-streaming I know about
Twitter know about YouTube and I know
about gamers and I know about all these
people but I am 41 I realized that I'm
five years too old to be really good at
this really
but object like 43 and I do it it's like
I know but I missed it just like my
brother is seven years older than me and
he missed the internet completely he was
seven years older and by the time the
internet came out he was already in his
career so there's things that we miss
it's just our age we don't catch it like
discord there's some of you are using
discord for the very first time and you
are progressing Lee using it because
you're a slack user and so I was talking
to someone yesterday and it's like no I
like swag and that's fine it's just that
you know we've missed things we have to
be taught by other people so I took a
class a couple weeks ago and black boots
was really cool and I said I want to
take some training they're like what on
and I was like streaming click okay it
proved it I flew a former student of
mine so it's a guy that I taught 12
years ago at film school I'd gone in the
streaming direction so he's now
streaming in that industry and I saw
what he was doing I saw the work that he
was creating and I said could you come
teach me and so I recommend this for you
all to if you see someone out there
that's doing something interesting you
can bring him on as a consultant no
please teach me what you know and so he
came in and did this class on live
streaming and I learned a lot
one of the things I learned was twitch
has a section if you twitch that TV
right now I am blind from looking at the
light there are all these different
sections whoa there's it all kinds of
twitch is Jenna okay dog
so just chatting it's a place that you
would want to be so just chatting is
where you can talk about anything that
you want to cover and the reason I was
just because I know that there's gonna
be a recording here and I don't know
what's there and I didn't want to look
at it too long so which is fine I can't
imagine what the discord saying right
now so live streaming you would be in
the just chatting section so this court
I mean twitch in the beginning was all
that gamers it was a gamers doing gaming
stuff and people watching other people
play games and that could be the
contents you create but they did start a
section called just chatting and just
chatting as any topic whatsoever there's
a guy who's a mechanic and he does a
livestream of his being a mechanic all
day and the cars come in the cars leave
but when the cars come in he does a
diagnostic check he walks up to the
camera he talks through what it is and
he has a thing where if you pay to be a
subscriber you can ask him any question
and so for people who are learning about
being a mechanic or learning about
automotive work they pay some money to
be a subscriber and they ask his
question and then he answers their
questions and so that's just something
that he does so if there's a topic or a
hobby or InfoSec even and you want it to
be a live twitch streamer or a youtube
streamer then you can do that so what
was the big thing that I took away from
that class you didn't ask me that but
I'm gonna tell you anyway is by the well
the big things was this camera that
you're currently seeing we use that
this microphone we already have so if
you're like what do you use and you
sound really great now thank you so much
so we use this camera if you want to get
that and we use this microphone fiver is
a great place to get the graphics made
for your streaming Channel
and then it's that I spent if it wasn't
for that class a couple weeks ago we
would not have been ready for this
virtual conference this week it totally
wouldn't didn't know a lot of things
that we were currently using and the
discord channel which feels like it's
pulling this whole con together in one
place was something that I learned a
couple weeks ago and once again I'm 41 I
didn't know about this cord he taught it
to me I saw the capabilities I saw them
the ability to pull it together and so
we built this discord on like Monday
evening and sent out the invites just
because of that class so what was the
biggest takeaway from I think the
biggest takeaway from that was how easy
it was to stream
looking for software to do it did a
stream labs for those of you that have a
PC or you're going to use OBS if you
have a Mac is that I
thought streaming would be difficult
because the last time I tried the stream
or do work like this was about six or
seven years ago and the computers just
could not do the things that I wanted to
do my head like I wanted so look like
listen I won't do that
and so my I was basically my knowledge
on the things that I saw years ago and
so what happened was this consultant guy
sat down and he started showing me and
he showed me stream labs he showed me
OBS and he showed me how you can pull
these different streams in and how you
can do this and I was like it's it's all
in real time isn't it he's like yeah
it's just real time you just drag this
over here he hit stream you can just
drag it while it's real time on your
laptop
oh my god this is so easy and it really
was that the biggest takeaway from the
entire class was how easy it was to
stream and so
just something to give you as a takeaway
tell easy dream labs
oh screen deck so we just bought this at
Black Hills and we haven't used it yet
stream deck
this right here inside stream labs and
inside OBS you can build these think
caught scenes and then you can map these
scenes and cameras and everything to the
actual buttons on here and so while
you're streaming you can just hit the
buttons on your stream lab and it will
take you from camera one number two or
take you from the camera and your slides
to just a shot of you or it would take
you to a camera above showing your
keyboard it will take you to you know
something if you're doing hardware
hacking it would take you to whatever or
if you have this really cold transition
at each you and that you get made on
fibre that takes you from like and like
your production value just goes up so
stream duct is what we'll be using in
the next couple weeks we would ease the
sooner but I went on a cruise and then
we had this virtual
right
saying that's a bad thing that's what
happened all right how to videos
all right how to videos are different
these are the three to nine minutes
single topic on how to do something when
I first came to Black Hills I was like
hey John we need to make these how-to
videos and there was a bit of a culture
shift from what we were doing because if
you're used to doing these long-form
pieces of content doing something short
just feels weird but if you start doing
something short than doing something
long would probably feel weird
so we got these seven minutes single
topics
and it's real basic it's getting started
with basic google searches it's got some
information here brought to you by this
is 7 minutes and 32 seconds and if you
take a look I'll show you the numbers
here the numbers for our long forms 800
there also
the numbers for our short film content
is pretty good too the difference is the
long-form content the 60-minute stuff
has that 10 percent retention rate the
short form content has 50 to 60 percent
tension rate retention rate and so there
are people who just start it and go this
isn't for me
and so that kills us right there but for
the majority of the people they're going
all the way through to the end and so
somebody will give you you if you think
it's gonna be good for you will give
someone at least four minutes on the
internet bill four minutes is an
eternity you know why I know four
minutes is an eternity on the Internet
there's a five-second commercial before
a YouTube video feels like the longest
thing in the world and so four minutes
is an eternity and so if you're making a
four minute how-to video just remember
that the majority of people will get
through it because they think you're
gonna teach them something but some
people won't so if you're making a 60
minute thing but and you make a 60
minute thing and then break it into
smaller five to ten minute things that
content chunking coming to the smaller
pieces
alright so shorter form content is the
how-to videos you're the Internet's full
with them be and then whenever you
create the title
there's there's some back-and-forth
between using the actual word how to how
to or getting started with that's all
back to the SEO what are people
searching for so if someone searching
for how to use Metasploit that might be
you call it how they use Metasploit or
how to use this tool inside Metasploit
how they uses exploits inside medically
how to use this inside cobalt strike how
to use this like what is the thing that
you can show people how to use and does
that become the title of your how-to
video
now you can amass a massive audience
with how-to videos because I see it all
the time on YouTube there are like I get
a little YouTube jealous when I see that
this one channel of them on Metasploit
how to use has like 1.2 million
subscribers and we have like 10,000 but
I'm like that's good Jason you don't
have to compare yourself to them all the
time it's okay but these how-to videos
will build a larger subscriber base
I believe faster than long-form content
the long-form content is really good at
building that relationship so if people
watch all over to the end they start
becoming like family and it's become
like family but there's how two people
you know they have a larger audience for
that next video blogs a blogs the Black
Hills
a lot of blogs we currently have like
400 and some but every journey starts
with a single step so if you go all the
way back to the very first blog and all
eternity written I
Douglas and so your very first blog will
be zero zero zero one if you haven't
written one before and you will create a
Twitter out Twitter post and they
LinkedIn post why is it different
yeah because the format's a little
difference and you don't want to just
copy and paste it from one to the other
so yeah
so your journey to a hundred blogs or so
will start with a single one what are
you gonna write on
I don't know that's your first step the
one thing about blog writing though is
everyone who writes a blog writes a blog
on how to write a blog now I'm not gonna
tell you how to write a blog but if you
go and watch that talk that I gave at
derbycon a few years ago I think it's
here yeah a presentation or presenting
presentations because presenting if you
go back and watch that it will give you
a really good structure for how to do a
hook a beginning a middle a climax and
an end to your blog and how you follow
that format of asking a question of your
audience and how you answer that
question at the end of how you give a
takeaway now you hopefully inspire them
to want to learn something new like
here's a follow that format that's in
that webcast tonight good place to get
you started
okay so back to the what do you call
your blog do you want to call it how to
do something when I first came to Black
Hills and I apologize to all the testers
is I started making them change the
names of their blogs
because what we learned is that anything
that started with the words how to
became very successful anything that
started with like creating the next
generation of interns like how to create
the next generation of interns would be
way better than creating the next
generation of insurance you see the
difference is that people don't search
for a lot of these things but if it did
say how to do something and we could
shoot show data-driven decision making
that anything that started with held to
was getting a lot more organic search
results to Google and so that's
something to keep in mind is that you
you and I me we have these cool titles
we want to give something but that not
might not necessarily be the thing that
draws people in and gets them to find
your plug and if your sole purpose is to
get back and you want more people to be
able to read it if usual purpose is to
make money then you definitely want more
people to read it and if your sole
purpose to build your career and once
again you want more people to read it so
if you can just adjust the title of your
blog and some of the the wording inside
the blog itself and that just creates
more people to come back or you and
that's cool I'm going to show you this
LM and and arm like I had no idea what
this meant when I first got here
but I do now and the reason why is
because it is the first blog right you
have the Wikipedia and then you have
black holes this is the single most
traffic blog on the black holes website
every single week and every single month
regardless of what we do this gets more
traffic than anything else on the
website and it's just when someone does
this and it's how to disable MMR and why
you would want to but anyone that
doesn't search for Ella MNR it will find
her blog and it leads to a massive
amount of traffic for us
all right et tu tu tutitu
Podcast
yeah if you haven't listened to darknet
diaries definitely go listen to dr.
cards
they do podcast really well but that is
not the type of podcast you're gonna do
the goal is not the to do someone else's
podcast the goal is to create your own
and it's gonna take a little while for
you to get over the sound of your own
voice so once you get over the sound of
your own voice then you can actually
start settling into what your topics are
gonna be and what's gonna be about and I
said a little earlier don't publish
anything don't tell anyone that you're
starting a blog don't wait up
don't wait up Twitter for your podcast
don't go out and start marketing this
thing that you haven't made yet and what
I mean by that is I would like you to
create 20 of something before you start
sharing it
so create 20 podcast 220 fully edited
finished podcast and if you like Jason
but that seems like a lot of work
without any reward yeah it is
I mean if you want to go be a live
twitch streamer you can start in the
beginning you won't have an audience so
it's probably gonna take the 20th time
of you doing that live twitch train
before anyone actually shows up but do
20 of something do 20 blogs I mean you
can invite people to your webcast but if
they don't show up you still give it and
the reason why is because you're going
to leave this workshop and I've seen it
I jeff McJunkin if you're in here you've
seen it too when you get done teaching
people something they're really excited
about when I taught filmmaking I talked
content creation and Tut yeah all that
stuff
I wouldn't like the students was like
sketchy dance class go mix them and a
lot of them did like they would leave
the class they start making something
but I'm telling you right now that the
motivation and the desire I'm currently
expressing to you and that you're
feeling inside it's not gonna last long
by Monday it will be gone it really will
I'm trying to instill in you that if you
this is something you want to do then go
make twenty or something before you
release it because if not you're gonna
have a blog that has one block and the
blog is going to say I'm getting ready
to start my blog or your podcast that
you start on iTunes is going to be like
your first podcast that you actually get
up you're gonna have the account for it
but you don't actually have the podcast
for it as you as you realize as I'm
making this podcast I'm watching other
podcasts I'm listening to other podcasts
on how to make podcasts as I'm doing
this but I don't have the time for it
you don't you don't have the time to do
the OSINT you don't have time to do the
interviews you don't have time to do
this and so I want you to make twenty of
something before you start publishing
and start telling people about it
because it's gonna take 20 for you to
get it down it's gonna take 20 blogs for
you to get it to where you start finding
your voice and and how you want
structure what you want to do so it's
gonna take a little while you are going
to be motivated leaving this it you know
there's forty eight of you that are
stuck around so I'm guessing the forty
eight of you are pretty motivated and
you're thinking about the stuff and
you're journalizing all right now and
you're trying to figure out how to apply
it to yourself and that's going to run
out real soon
one of the coolest things that happened
after a talk like this at Derby con is a
guy reached out and won Twitter and he
said I've written my third blog Jason
17 more to go
about ten and he's like alright um oh
and Seth like this is not easy I
understand I'm excited for you to hit
that twenty I will let you know that
he's never written me to let me know
that he hit his twenty and I'm not
saying you don't release those seven you
don't release those twelve because it
would be something that's really helpful
with other people and it could be
absolutely release them if you get to
seven and he can't go any further just
put him out there so if people learn
from them but if this is something that
you want to do consistently and as a
career as a way of giving back and it
has to become scheduled and it has to
become something that she create
regardless how difficult it is now
hopefully I haven't killed your desire
to want to do this but I've given you a
perspective on how to move forward
you if you got a chance and I hope you
saw Derek or Jeff's this morning I hope
you were tuning into the ones this
afternoon
you know yesterday or is that yeah I am
hopefully there's 48 of you that are
currently listening to this I hope you
decide to submit a CFP for a future talk
especially awhile this hacking fest we'd
love to have you good presentation that
you give a presentation that you submit
to do that and it's gonna do a lot of
things like we already talked about is
that it's gonna force you to do the
research it's gonna force you to learn
something but it's also gonna force you
to get out of your comfort zone because
when I did that raise your hand if
you're shot if you actually raise your
hands that yeah you know there is that I
gotta be brave there's a talk coming up
I gotta get up on stage I have to show
this information and that's gonna give
you an opportunity to grow and stretch
yourself as a person but how do you give
a live presentation you'll watch the
video on how to give a live presentation
it's 30 minutes long and it will break
it down for you from the hook beginning
middle climax and end how to structure
your your talk and even how to take a
blank sheet of paper because I hate
blank sheets of paper because blank
sheets of paper laughing at me and
they're like you don't have an idea so
the way I've gotten around that is I
just write the word hook beginning
middle I max and end on a blank sheet of
paper and I start filling in those
sections and then as I start filling in
those sections the hook is here's my
question to the audience the beginning
is here's a journey that I went on to
learn and to know more about this topic
here's the the middle here's the
pitfalls and the highs and the lows of
doing that research and figuring out
this new thing climax is how it applies
to the audience because if you give a
talk and you don't tell the audience how
this applies to you
that's just a terrible talk because the
people just sat out there and just watch
you just ramble on about something you
thought was cool but it doesn't apply to
them and so that climax is how does it
apply to the audience and then the end
is the you know tried to inspire try to
give someone to take away and try to to
wrap up everything that was most
important in your talk so Ellis story if
you don't know how to give a talk and
this you know the whole world just shut
down right now because of a pandemic but
if you're watching this recording and
things have gotten better then I want
you to join a local Toastmasters club so
Toastmasters is a place where you can go
and speak it's a pretty safe space for
you go and speak there are very casual
Toastmasters groups there's more strict
with like sergeants of arms to type
Toastmasters group so try a couple out
and you're it in a community but what I
want you to do is is join a toast if you
want to become a better speaker if you
want to get off on stage if you want to
give presentations internally or to the
public if you want to do a Twitter
stream anything that you want to do that
you want to use your voice and talk to
an audience and I highly recommend
joining a Toastmasters and this will be
a place where you can practice you can
come up with talks they have a pathway I
think it's even called path yeah it's
pathways pathways is your first talk is
the icebreaker talk the second talk is
an informative talk the third talk is a
persuasive talk the fourth talk is this
type of talk the fifth talk is you give
the talk you get feedback then you give
the talk again
it's an organization that can help you
become a better speaker and presenter I
really like Toastmasters I became a
better speaker and presenter just by
doing it every single time in the
classroom and by the students having
laptops and just trying to figure out
how can i hack their brains to get them
to care more about me researching and
learning about how the human brain how
human beings interpret information as
you're as you're teaching it to him so I
wanted to become a better presenter and
speaker right that was my goal and that
was my job in my profession so if this
isn't your job and profession that I was
just joined to look with Toastmasters
and that would be a way that you can
start learning and be a better presenter
and speaker
if P submissions once again now that you
have an idea for a talk or you see
places that you want to give talks him
right now there is no place to go to
talk unless it's virtually is everyone
this postponed I am dude I'm a sponsor
of all these events and I'm just getting
the emails right now like and we're
postponed and we're canceling right now
it might be few and far between for the
the CFP submissions but when it is time
to present or if you sort of want to do
a virtual con and more virtual concert
popping up because we are doing a
webcast this upcoming Monday on how to
run a virtual con and it's just gonna be
a brain dump of all the things that we
learned over the last seven or eight
days if you submit your CFP submit it
like this
and the O's thing the only place I ever
get rejected to speak is that marketing
events the only place I really did
speaks at marketing events and really
it's because I'm not paying as presented
marketers unless you're kind of in the
club and I know you what you're thinking
you got to be in the InfoSec Club which
is why b-sides is so important to the
InfoSec industry is giving new voices
and new speakers a chance to get up and
present so when you submit your CFP
follow those five rules to hook
beginning middle climax and end so it's
the there's here's the the question to
the audience here's the journey I went
on here's what I learned or what I will
learn by doing the research here's how
it applies to the audience and here's
and then you sum it all up all the CFPs
I've ever submitted in the InfoSec
industry had been accepted I think it's
because if I was a pretty simple like
the person who's reading it think about
the person reading it that's the
audience that this person's getting like
a thousand CFP use another which one do
I take
and it's the one that's just broken down
and the easiest way for them to
interpret and read if you send a stack
of papers oh my god so it's a five
breakdown
my time today I won't be able to get to
do this so I'm gonna jump over to
marketing and if you're wondering what
slides I just went through in my live
version of this I run through someone's
idea and then we actually run through
all the ways to create that idea you
know do we do live versus capture do we
build a studio do we do screen capture
actually exit I will do this and I'll
just run through mallow faster tip if
you make a video or you make a how-to
video don't remake it so if you make it
don't remake
that 20 that you're creating and
everything why you don't remake it is
because just make the next one it just
makes the next one after that just make
them and they will get better as time
goes on but if you're trying to make the
best video alright like let me record
that let me get different lighting when
we get this let me get that let me get
this and just keep making the same video
over and over again then you will have
one video to make 20 videos that
increasingly get better instead of
making one that you're trying to make
perfect so don't redo I had a
photographer friend of mine that we
would go out and do these photo shoots
and I keep touching my face even though
I have
so we had this photographer that I would
work with and whenever we'd get done
with the shoot you know we do the photo
shoot we have the models we have the the
client we have the product we have
whatever it is that we're shooting when
we would get done with the shoot he
would always reach out and say like hey
can we shoot that again no we can't
shoot it again and the reason why it
still on the drive home he kept thinking
about why I would have moved the light
here I would have done this differently
on this I would it had this different
angle and he can't you can't go back and
redo it you can just make improvements
for the next one if you're doing
post-production the tip here is to
outsource if you're doing your own
podcast don't be the editor of your
podcast give that over to someone else
and let them edit it and if it cost you
$50 and that's the cost of doing the
work that you're doing now you might
make that backup I see my sponsors you
might make that work back by doing a
patron patreon Eitri on this sounds cool
so you might make that money back by
doing it you know raising funds through
subscribers on twitch there's all kinds
of ways to make money through doing
streaming and doing content creation and
when I took that class a couple weeks
ago I was dumbfounded by the economics
of live streaming and EMPA true patreon
and things like that so that's something
for you to keep in mind is that if
people are giving you money then take
that money and outsource the editing of
the content that you're creating to
others and really the reason is because
the the sound of your voice it's the
sound of your voice when you're trying
to edit yourself you're constantly
critiquing yourself and so you can't
really get the Edit that you need
because you hear you but if you give it
over someone else like someone said I
sound like Ryan Reynolds I don't think I
sound like Ryan Reynolds except when I
watch a Ryan Reynolds movie I'm like no
I see it but when you hand that over to
someone else they don't have that same
bias that you have same thing like you
should never edit your own photos you
shouldn't edit you know things like that
because you will find all your flaws and
it won't be perfect outsource
distribution this is that tip from
earlier xx finish before you go there's
so many places for you to distribute
your content I'm pretty sure you can
find a blog a blog on how to distribute
blogs a webcast and how to distribute
webcast a podcast and how to distribute
podcast so
if this is something that interests you
there are so many people have created
content about distribution but what I
wanted here was iTunes it's about
reviews about having a concentrated
amount of reviews in a short period of
time so if at some point if you're doing
webcast and you decided to take those
webcast you know the big piece of
content and then break it into podcast
but maybe you ask your discord audience
if this is something that you really
like I'm now putting it on iTunes for
you to download as a podcast could you
please go and review it so that way we
can show up higher on the rankings and
by showing up higher in the rankings
more people find it more people listen
to it tip for promotion join forces
email the social media it's one of the
easiest in turn to find these days is a
social media intern and it really is
because anyone in college feels like
their social media expert in free a lot
of times they are they're really good
because they've grown up with it and
it's just now when they apply it to
business and can they apply it to making
money and things like that but when it
comes to social media most of you are
experts already you've been doing social
media for a long time but I if I have
time I'll show you some tips the email
list is important and if you're like
email Jason email email Jason yeah
create a MailChimp account or a Jim
Constant Contact
so as you're getting started create a
MailChimp account ready Constant Contact
count and start building up your email
list because when it's time to go live
you will announce it in your discord
you'll send an email out to your email
list and then people show up and then it
keeps built in that community and the
thing about emails that's really easy to
share you know if they're we generally
get four hundred new people to our Black
Hills webcast almost every single time
there's an average of four hundred new
people every single webcast that we do
and those were not people we emailed
they may have seen on social media or
something like that but for the most
part it was someone that has been to a
webcast before they liked our webcast
and then they forward it to a colleague
and say you need to come to this it was
cool is that my wife works for an
organization that is in information
security and when we send out the Black
Hills email on Mondays she will get that
email not for me
but from a colleague of work that says
hey this looks like a really good topic
we should all check it out and then
she'll come up and she like got another
email from another colleague says you
got a webcast coming up mm-hmm
ah it's funny join forces so if you find
somebody that's currently doing what you
do or they're in the same sphere as you
and they have a better audience or
balance it better they have a more
robust or bigger audience so maybe you
can join forces with em and as your
audience grows they can get some of the
audience over there if you didn't know a
couple years ago they started YouTube
studios the YouTube studios was a place
in California and Los Angeles is so
exists it's pretty cool and YouTube
studios what YouTube did was they found
these youtubers that had hundred
thousand two hundred thousand million
subscribers who would who were in their
house like right now like me and all of
a sudden I have like a hundred thousand
subscribers and YouTube would reach out
to me and say like would you like to
move to California and do this at
YouTube studios so a lot of youtubers
moved from all over the country to
California to Los Angeles and they
recreated their bedroom at YouTube
studios so it became a set so it's the
same thing that you would see you know
six months ago but they would recreate
it at YouTube studios but now they had
professional cameras at professional
lights at professional production
equipment and post-production equipment
and they were helping them crank out
their videos and YouTube would keep half
the revenue and so what was cool about
that is AMA you let's say I'm a youtuber
that has a million subscribers and ten
feet next to me is another youtuber in a
different you know edit suite or
different this I would get the chance to
meet them and then we would start doing
cross promotional videos where I'm now
hanging out that youtuber and where our
subscribers are now we're crossing each
other so that's all of a say if we we
Black Hills have been looking for
presenters at while was hacking fest
that have given presentations that we
think would be good for the Black Hills
audience or for the Wild West hacking
fest webcast audience that we're gonna
have here in the next couple months and
so we're gonna reach out to some people
and if we don't reach out to you I'm I'm
sorry it's just we didn't think that
that talk would resonate with that the
audience yet
or that type of talk or you may need to
improve your speaking skills a little
bit or your gear so if you're like what
about me so it's just you may not be
ready yet
because it is thousands of people and we
want to make sure that you're good to go
for thousands of people and so we're
gonna look for other people that want to
work with us and we want to work with
them to cross-promote that way 14
minutes to go
marketing
three I've been living by
Blanchard for like the last 20 years
have been living by these three steps
from marketing
and the first one is to get people to
know you exist there's no reason to care
animes them once you once they do and it
just comes down to if people don't know
you exist and they can't even make a
decision about you so I will
there's 47 of you right now listen to
this and there's gonna be a recording
later and people listening to the
recording you listening to this right
now
there's a certain amount of people that
know you exist that's your circle
and you can reach out and get to know
more people
right now there's a ton of people that
don't know you exist that's fine but
once they know you exist then they can
make a decision if they like you or not
so if they want to hire if they want to
listen to your content they want to you
know some so until they know you exist
you have to introduce yourself and so
that might be stuff on social media you
show up to a con you give a presentation
you come to the discord channel and you
introduce yourself there's an
opportunity for you to introduce
yourself to people now they may not care
I tried to do a comedy in a roomful of a
thousand people most of them did not
care but you have to give them a reason
to care and so there was a couple people
who were close to the audience that
heard what I said thought it was funny
and they started to care now once they
started like had they were having the
conversation with Oh Nelson I actually
this is kind of interesting and then I
got a chance to do some more trips and
by the end of my set there was a good 40
to 50 people in the front that were
laughing and they were engaged they
didn't know I existed until I got up on
that stage
they didn't care until I started making
them laugh and they didn't really laugh
like I wanted them to
until I got him over that part where I
amazed them because people have an
expectation of you and when you can
exceed that expectation is when you can
amaze somebody not saying to lower it
was expectation so they amaze them
no don't do that gay people know you
exist you're the reason to care and
amaze them once they do all right
audience engagement way better than view
thank you
my pair
engagement is way better than views what
I mean by that is if you have a hundred
people that follow you on twitter but
only one person ever likes your your
tweets well then really you only have
one person the other 99 or most likely
bots or just people that don't care
about the content that you're putting
out and that's fine once again it's the
subset of the larger audience the people
that care but once you find those few
but I care then you hope that they
engage and so you're creating stuff I
heard a you know couple couple years ago
in marketing you know I'm 41 there's
people coming out there's people younger
than me is that millennial marketers
will post something in social media if
no one clicks on it in the first 30
seconds they delete it and then they
rewrite it
it changed the image they adjust it they
put it back out again data like that oh
cool
that is how much Millennials are tuned
in to engagement because they want like
if I put this out there no one responds
to it then why am i you putting it out
there okay what you're looking for is
engagement but let's say you have a
thousand people who like chair over time
about what you're doing but only ten of
them show up when you do a live webcast
and really what you have is ten people
and so it's not about caring about the
overall number it's about the engagement
number and that would grow as time goes
on hopefully
eat the other nights audience questions
are gold yes I'm glad I got to this tip
so I'm doing a webcast right now and I'm
gonna scroll right now through the other
questions and there's a discord channel
and things like that people have been
sending me questions throughout if you
want to know what to do your next
webcast on it's the audience questions
from your last webcast
so use the audience to help you start
crowdsourcing the content to make next
so if you do a webcast and all the
sudden four or five people ask you a
similar question but maybe you write a
blog post on that and at the end of your
blog post you leave that back to the
overall webcast you break that webcast
into five different chunks you can now
link those different chunks each of one
of those can be its own blog where you
take the transcript from the the webcast
and you put it actually in the blog
itself you can pay people to write
transcripts for you or we recently
learned that if you bring up Google Docs
Google Docs and you take a headphone or
so and you stick it next to the
microphone on your computer and you turn
Google like talk to text to talk to text
on it will give you a transcript of your
video it's not a hundred percent you got
to go in and make some adjustments but
it's pretty damn good and so that can
give you a transcript of the talk that
you gave and then that can revert it
into text and then that text will be SEO
capable and two more people come to your
website and then that will lead them to
your upcoming live webcast so so your
audience questions are the fodder or the
thing that you can do next I wanted to
do a tip before I finished today I want
you all to start liking LinkedIn a lot
more if I if you can take anything away
from today it's to like LinkedIn if you
want to be a content creator if you are
a usual Twitter user then most likely
you're like LinkedIn really so here's
what happened Twitter became a dumpster
fire so all the people who are like I
don't like dumpster fires I don't like
all this they went to LinkedIn you
really did they went to LinkedIn and
that's where they want to get content so
much so I'm gonna show you so Black
Hills had a LinkedIn account for a long
time
and you can see the comings and goings I
want to show you this range look if you
found me
all right so in March of last year we
averaged about 266 people out our
LinkedIn but we started putting out
content from the content library so
remember the content library we took all
the old content stuff that was so
relevant we built out a Content schedule
we had someone help us post that stuff
to social media over say you know use
this number on this day here's the image
here's the text here's all these things
and all of a sudden the engagement just
went through the roof or adding like
3,000 people or so a month
and if you go down here you can take a
look at your engagement rate versus
others
and I'm not saying that I look at this
often just because I'm competitive but
you can see your company versus other
companies and your new followers versus
their some how many updates you have and
what your engagement rate is versus them
and its really nice that active
countermeasures and Black Hills that a
number so by posting content like all
the sudden our numbers start shooting up
and guess what those people who were now
following the Black Hills website
started coming to our live webcast and
then those people started sharing it
with their friends and then those people
started showing up hey kitty those
people started showing up so LinkedIn is
awesome
one of the really cool features on
LinkedIn that I want to show you is and
I didn't know this existed so Gary be
put out it like a PowerPoint to us like
290 pages recently and I read all of
them it was great
but there's this feature inside LinkedIn
and I want to show two or all of you
that have been presenting this week
and our speakers if you go here to
shared document so you got this writ of
post you can make a picture you can do a
video where you can do in a document so
I'm going to choose this from my desktop
over here
Thank You compromised so if this is your
talk
that you gave and so Jeff is here and
some of the other speakers are here
you can upload your talk think here and
I'm not gonna upload this one I'm just
going to show you
if it turns your talk into 28 piece of
the content
and so now people can go through and
take a look at your talk and then what
you can do is in the way so up here you
can link to where it is on YouTube so if
there's a link for it on YouTube you can
post it here you can see here's to talk
here it is if you want to download the
slides you can go to my website and on
my website you can download the slides
if you want the PowerPoint version but
you can start using this the engagement
rates for these right here are
ridiculous
if my normal post has an engagement rate
I was like five percent these have an
engagement rate of like 46 to 56 percent
and what happens is in LinkedIn's world
the algorithm sees all the people
looking through the slides and converts
that to like well your engagement rates
massively high so let's show this to a
large audience and so it keeps showing
it to a larger audience and so some of
the ways that we built up our LinkedIn
or the last couple months because by
sharing the slides or the presentations
all right in conclusion we're at the in
conclusion slide
in conclusion thank you thank you for
being here you know you do a workshop
and you ask people to show up and you
say this is what it's about
and you showed up and I appreciate that
and so in conclusion I've tried to live
by this never deny teaching someone the
knowledge that I have in my head I love
being a teacher that's one of the things
I love most with being a teacher for 19
years but I realized that I wasn't
growing as a person anymore because I
was teaching the same topic so I was
covering the same materials and so what
I decided to do was quit my job and sell
my comic book store because I wasn't
growing and just do something different
and I've learned a ton of stuff over the
last nine years that I've been doing
things different so I'm looking at
teaching again but now it's with 18
years of knowledge and so I am excited
about teaching again I am excited that I
got a chance to teach you here today so
thank you for listening I hope that the
one thing that you take away from this
is that you have knowledge in your brain
and then you have the opportunity to
share with others and it may be virtual
because the world that we're living in
right now might be a little the word
isolated little distancing and so we're
gonna need each other more than than
ever and connect in ways and share our
knowledge and ways and it might be
virtual and streaming the recap develop
your voice it's gonna take some time to
develop your voice but as you develop
your voice you also have to get used to
hearing your voice and so as you develop
your voice it's gonna take time it's
gonna take a little while to get over
that imposter syndrome and over the
sound your own voice to make something
content chunking and I make something
big and break it down into the
individual pieces so that way I don't
have to make a thing and just keep
making more things and keep making more
things can I take a big piece of thing
turn it into smaller pieces that way I
don't have to keep doing research I can
do this research once and turn it into
all these and then go research something
else
career advancement if you do any of the
things I talked about today your career
will be advanced because you would be
start becoming a subject matter expert
on topics you would be able to start
doing this people start looking to you
as a leader even though you don't
consider yourself one and it will be a
way for you to start advancing your
career networking I always I will
encourage you right now get up on stage
it is immediate permission for everyone
in the audience to come talk to you like
if you don't know who to talk to at a
con you can always go talk to a
presenter or speaker because you heard
them talk and now you have something to
start talking about so by presenting its
instantaneous networking and get back
and with that
find me in discord for your questions
thank you so much for your time I'm
going to kill the presentation I will
see you in discord