hi welcome to our talk on enabling
autonomous teams through policy
enforcement
before we get started a quick
introduction about ourselves
my name is james alsoth and i'm a
security engineer at ubico currently
focused on cloud infrastructure security
presenting with me is john reese who is
a software engineer at yubico with a lot
of experience in go and kubernetes
before we get started let's go over what
we're going to be discussing today
first we're going to start with a brief
history of kubernetes at yubico
how we got started on our kubernetes
journey and some of the previous gaps in
our kubernetes tech stack
we're then going to discuss how policy
helps to address those gaps and enable
more autonomous teams
we're definitely going to talk about the
awesome open source tooling that enables
us to enforce these policies
and we're going to wrap up with
discussing our journey thus far
sort of where we are now and where we
see ourselves in the future
and of course there will be some time
with them for questions
so let's chat about how ubico got
started on its kubernetes adoption
journey
for us that started about two years ago
with an initiative led by our
infrastructure team to standardize the
platform that our services run on
uh previous to this we were mostly
running on virtual machines
and we didn't have too many
containerized workloads yet
like many organizations we used to
manage kubernetes service to get up and
running as fast as possible
and to help avoid some of the pain
points of cluster setup and cluster
management
for us though probably the first
question that pops into our head is how
can we ensure that the kubernetes
workloads are configured securely
and what that's really asking is how do
we control changes that are made to the
cluster
well we started where i think most
organizations do leaning on three things
authentication authorization as well as
consistent peer review
diving into the first of those we were
able to take advantage of the managed
kubernetes offering
than that it allowed us to tie into our
existing identity provider very easily
so we got up and running with
authentication pretty quick
additionally it probably comes to no
surprise to those of you who are
familiar with yubico
but we also require strong multi-factor
authentication with web on
web authent and yubikeys additionally we
regularly expire the sessions for those
with access to infrastructure
requiring re-authentication with
multi-factor authentication frequently
moving on to
the role-based authorization thankfully
kubernetes has role-based access control
built in
and it has for quite a few versions now
this allows us to tie
users groups and service accounts to any
any role these roles can either be
scoped to
a namespace or they can be applied
cluster-wide
these roles allow for extremely
fine-grained permissions
allowing you to specify the exact verbs
an actor can use
such as create update or delete what
types of resources they can act on
such as a deployment resource and it can
even go as far as
allow restricting it only to
specifically named resources
again our managed kubernetes offering
made this easier by tying groups into
from our idp into this system
and the final tool in our toolbelt was
peer review
for us we enforce this using github
branch protection rules ensuring that
all changes happened through pull
requests
and on each of these pull requests we
required at least one other person to
review
for us most of this peer review work
landed
on our infrastructure team because they
had the most experience of kubernetes
and had spent the most time to
learn about all of the best practices
security or otherwise
about peer review though it definitely
has some drawbacks when it's the only
way that you're restricting changes to
your clusters
for one it needs to be consistent in
order to be effective
and when you have consistent review
that's a significant time investment for
the reviewers
because of this it often bottlenecks on
the team or individual that has the most
experience with the technology
which of course in this case is
kubernetes and all of this adds up to
slowing down the release cycle
and this is important because when he
teams hit too much friction
they often start to work around your
processes whether you know it or not
this is of course bad for security
because you no longer have control over
these configurations
but they're also bad for just general
cluster consistency and maintainability
none of this was really a surprise to us
we kind of
saw this coming from a mile away but
that didn't make the problem any less
real when we had to deal
with it so what we did is we spent some
time researching what other
organizations were doing and what the
kubernetes community was doing
and for us the answer became abundantly
clear policy was the way forward
when people think of policy it's usually
a negative reaction as they
imagine having more hoops to jump
through in order to get their work done
however in our case since all of these
changes
to kubernetes happen through the api
server working with structured json data
we can automate the enforcement of these
policies entirely
but what do we mean when we say that in
this context well
it allows us to enforce what we actually
care about for example we don't really
care that a services team is deploying a
new version of their service
that's a part of their core job function
however we do care that when they do
that
the resources are configured securely
for example we probably want to ensure
that the workloads aren't running as
root
and that they don't have any extra linux
capabilities attached to them
these policies can also easily extend
past security related settings though
for example we can require each resource
in a
namespace to have a certain label set
that identifies the owner of that
resource
that makes it easy so when you're
working on troubleshooting an issue
or you just need to know who's who owns
that resource it's right there in the
metadata of the resource
with that i'd like to turn it over to
john to discuss the tooling we've
selected to enforce these policies
thanks james so as james mentioned we
knew we wanted to use policy to solve a
lot of the problems we were having at
yubico
we looked at a lot of the tools out
there that solved this problem
but opa was the clear winner in this
space we saw a lot of adoption with
other tools
that we knew we wanted to leverage and
it came with its own
policy language but before getting into
opa itself
it's really important to understand what
a policy is
what it looks like and rego itself so
rego is the policy language that opa
knows
that understands and on my screen here
you can see a policy
for a kubernetes manifest that says that
it must have
a owner label on it specifically
namespaces
must have an owner label so when a when
a request comes in
in the cluster for a namespace creation
this policy will first check to see
this input that's coming in this input
document is it of type namespace
and if it doesn't have an owner's label
on it return a message that says
namespaces must have an owner so the
user the uh the individual trying to
deploy this namespace knows how to fix
it
and so the important takeaway here
is the input keyword the input keyword
denotes a input document for rego and
the input document is just the
structured data in our case it's a yaml
file
so anything beyond the input dot should
look really familiar we see kind we
see metadata but the the input dot
and anything after that is just
dependent upon the data
that you give it it could be terraform
it could be a docker file
any sort of of structured data so
again very generic language um
immensely immensely powerful and so now
that we have this
this rego file we need a way to actually
determine
if the document that we give it would be
would be in violation and there's a few
ways to do this right we could
we could be the input document the the
rego
to james and he can verify on a
case-by-case basis whether or not the
document
is uh is violated or not but we're we're
all about automation so
as briefly talked about before we
decided to go with uh with the open
policy agent and just like
just look at the logo of of course we
did um there's
there's just there's no reason not to
choose opa it's a work
of art but no really we um
the community is great again there's
there's so much adoption around
opa it was um it was it's been it's been
a real joy to leverage
opa um working in their their slack
channel
everyone's super friendly there's always
someone there to help you out
it was it was a really good a really
really good choice for us
and so how this how this works how opa
works as a service
you uh you deploy it somewhere be it
kubernetes
be it a web server wherever you want to
put it as long as you can get a web
request to it
um and then you also include your your
regular files with that with that
deployment so opa can know which
policies
you want it to enforce and so you you
submit an input document again be it a
kubernetes manifest
be it a docker file anything you want
give it to the opa service
it will validate the the document run
through run it through the policies and
tell you
does this document violate any of the
policies you have
loaded into it and there's also the the
really
nice piece of the fact that it can also
take external
data so you can see here in the the
bottom right the
the data document that's external data
and that can come from
any number of sources so if we build on
the previous example of
the policy where that teams must have a
namespace label all name spaces must
have a label of owner on it
we could also add a policy that says
that owners
teams can only own a single namespace
and so
in order to do that we would need some
form of external data in this case a
count of how many namespaces that
they've already
created and so when we create namespaces
when we delete namespaces we can keep
track of that number give it to opa and
then opa can use that when it's
when it's evaluating all of its policies
and so while that was an example of
using op as a service
you can actually use opa as a library
which makes it
so much easier to to enforce policy
there's a lot of tools out there
that will actually take the opa engine
um
import it as a dependency and then run
the the same checks
that uh that opa itself would
and so we really wanted to leverage this
um this type of functionality
in order to shift our policy enforcement
to the left because we quickly realized
that
when we deployed opa while we were able
to
have this policy enforcement this policy
validation
our engineers didn't really know whether
or not the
code they were writing the policies and
uh manifest they were writing
would be in violation until they
actually deployed it
so we really wanted a solution that we
could give them
put on their local machine and they
could just run it without having to
worry about any of that and that silly
networking stuff
and so we found a tool called called
comptest
and comtess more or less lets you
run opa on on on your local machine like
opa
you can but contest just makes the
experience
so much better so like when i said
before
you can give any input document to opa
it doesn't really care
it's like it's half true it still
doesn't care but
as long as it's yaml or json so
com tests can actually take a lot of
different file formats you can see here
ini tomal hcl and it can convert those
file formats
into into json and then shepard into opa
so you can actually use
any format with with opa there's also
some nicety about
being able to take in files from from
different folders
anywhere on your on your machine and
then print the result again in a user
friendly way so com test is for
local policy validation it's for
pipeline validation in all of your your
manifest
and then anything beyond that would be
like opa deployed as a service for
continue enforcement
and so you can see here this is a
another example of a policy file on the
left this time we're looking at
deployments to make sure they're not
running as root and that
the container has app label for pawn
selectors
and on the right we have our input
document our deploy.yaml
itself and so if we actually run this
through com test using the test command
all you have to do is pass in the
policy.rego as well as the deploy.yaml
and then it will take that deploy.yml
and see
does that input document violate any of
the policies that we have set forth
in this case there are there are two
policies that were that were violated
and we can take this policy and we can
apply it to
the op as a service and get the exact
same behavior so we're checking
both the the local environment as well
as the
um as well as the production environment
and then again this it can be run
local machines pipelines and you can get
that immediate feedback
there's also the benefit with comtess to
be able to
share policies across the organization
because
it's a fair use case a valid use case
that your policies are managed and
written by a completely
separate team a security team much like
they are done at yubico
we'll have a lot of different
repositories we want to make sure that
the our policies are being enforced and
there's really no way to get those
policies without
trying them out in the cluster but with
comptest you can actually
push policies policy bundles to a oci
compliant registry
and then pull them down for for later
use so you can see here in the example
where
we're pulling down a bundle of cluster
policies
and then we're actually running the
comptest test command locally
on that bundle that we just pulled on
that same deployed.yaml and then the
result is the same
so this is a way to be able to push
policies out there and then pull them
down
for for cross-team usage this is really
huge as well in um
in pipelines or other kind of approaches
where you need to
bundle together a lot of different
policies
and so artifact hub is
an attempt to be able to
expose a lot of different policy bundles
because
more or less like the policies that we
really care about things like
containers having resource constraints
containers not
running as root those types of policies
should more or less be
the same but we're kind of in a state
now where teams companies organizations
are all writing the same policies we
don't have a good distribution mechanism
and artifact hub is again the the the
solution
for that um it's currently it's a
sandbox project there are a whole lot of
policy bundles out there i think there's
like one or two
but i would definitely keep an eye on
this contribute where you can
if you do have a public bundle that you
want to to contribute i
recommend pushing it up there and let's
try to make this successful though so we
can actually start sharing policies with
one another not having to uh
to rewrite them over and over and over
again for every team who wants to be
able to use policy
and so a lot of the talks of we've a lot
of the conversation we've had
is all about policy enforcement on the
local environments
but we also need to make sure that the
policies are enforced in
in production and so once you get beyond
the local environment we decided to go
with a
tool called called gatekeeper and
gatekeeper lets us enforce these
policies continuously inside inside of a
kubernetes
cluster it's a mission controller
so when you deploy a resource to
kubernetes
it'll go through the admission
controller look at all the policy that
you have
loaded and if any of the the resources
that you
are attempting to add to the cluster it
will reject
or or let the policy go through it also
has an and some audit functionality
saying it'll continually audit your
cluster
are there any resources that that are
violating policy if
in the case that you're just starting to
adopt gatekeeper
and you want to see if i were to
actually enforce this policy how many
resources
are kind of out of band or just in the
case that gatekeeper went down for a
little bit you know want to
make sure that there wasn't a a resource
that got in like during that that small
window
and again the huge one here is it's
using the same policies so
we're if you're checking on your local
versus in production
we can always continuously use the same
policy that doesn't change from
environment to environment
but with that said um it's
almost the same policies so uh we go
back to
the input document um when you're
working with yaml the input document is
going to be
a yaml file so we would expect
input.kind
input.metadata just like we saw before
but when we're in the context of
admission control it's going to be a
little different i bolded here
input.review.object because this is what
a
admission review is going to look like
to to gatekeeper
this is the the document that is going
to be received
from opa so again it's not
quite the same you would actually have
to write a policy
that had input.review.object in it but
that would only work for gatekeeper
and if you did just input.kind that
wouldn't work for gatekeeper
so what we ended up doing was really
adopting this idea of rego being the
source of truth your policies because
it really it really is rego is
generic it's it doesn't matter the uh
the context that you're in
it's really all about does this input
document that you're giving me
violate this policy that you have
defined and so in every
everything that's that you do that's
based off of your rego
should should adjust the changes of your
regula and not the other way around
and so to solve this problem we actually
wrote a tool called constraint
and constraint brings to the table three
really important
factors first and foremost it it
actually does provide a library
where you can write policies that work
with both comptest and gatekeeper
it's really just a a wrapper that
normalizes
a a polyfill that that will say
if you're in the context of gatekeeper
then
spit out your policies for
input.review.object if you're in the
context of conf test
it's just input dot and that handles all
of that for you
so your policies can be completely
unchanged
no matter what environment that you're
running in the other benefit is the
template and constraint creation and
management
so when you saw on the previous
constraint uh previous screen
the the rego there was actually embedded
into the constraint template the yaml
and that's because that's how gatekeeper
is able to um
to uh to load in your policies it's just
done through a yaml file
and so you're gonna have a rego file on
disk
and if you were to change that rego file
you would also have to
copy and paste your changes into that
yaml which
isn't the most ideal situation and so
what constraint will actually do is
it will look at all of your radio files
and then it will actually
generate the template and constraint for
you so
you never have to touch yaml you're only
focused purely on
on your rego file and then lastly it
actually will generate documentation
for your policies we really wanted to
give our engineers the ability to see
what policies were being enforced as
well as
how they can how they can resolve them
if they ever run into a policy violation
and so when it comes to the policies
themselves
it'll look relatively familiar that the
biggest difference here is definitely
the the comment header
we added some some metadata to to the
policy in form of a
header comment where we say title
is the the title of of the the policy
here we're saying images must not use
the latest tag
and then why this policy exists or
really any other flavor
that you want to give it to give this
policy be the description or anything
else
the the enforcement type here is saying
deny
the alternative is dry run in case you
want to
test out this policy in your cluster and
not actually do any sort of
enforcement and then which kinds which
kubernetes resources that this policy
will be enforced on be it just ingresses
be it just namespaces workloads etc
so we define here a list of resources
that this policy
isn't forced on and then we use this
metadata to generate all the other yamls
that we were previously
talking about and in the violation
itself you see here we're importing two
libraries which is the constraint
library
the the important note here is that
pods.container
our pods library will actually look at
containers from
any possible source because pods can
come from cron jobs they can come from
deployment staple sets daemon sets
there's a large list of those and
they're all embedded in kubernetes
resources differently
so pods handles that for you and then we
can take
the the resulting container that comes
out of that does that container have an
image of latest and if it does
give a note to the the user saying that
images must not use the
the latest tag and again we have two
commands for that one to generate the
the templates and the constraints and
then one for for the markdown
describing describing our our policies
and then this is an example of what the
documentation
looks like you can see here the the id
p1001 we also embedded something into
into the tool that you can actually
assign an id
to a policy so you can refer back to it
instead of just using a title
the the severity is coming from the the
severity of the rule because in rego you
can have
warning you can have deny you can have
violation and based on that rule
different things will happen so we pull
the severity out of the rego and put
that in the document for you
same with the resources that it impacts
the
the description that dictates what this
policy does or why we have it
and then this is the the rego itself if
you want that information
again completely completely configurable
if you change your rego
again all the documentation is
regenerated
none of this is hand typed and then you
also
are given a link to to the source and
that source can either be a relative url
if the policy lives in the same location
of the source the same repository
or if it's a remote repository the
source can also be
a uh be a url so we um
we found a lot of usage out of this tool
we use it for um like almost every day
it's really ingrained into
into our workflows when it comes to
gatekeeper and policy so
if you're interested if it sounds
something like you'd want to use
always open to uh to talk about it
contributions always welcome and uh
that's really all i have for for the
tooling piece of it
uh james is going to kind of go into
into deeper detail
of how we actually have leveraged these
tools in our policies
and in our pipelines and processes
thanks john now that we have an
understanding of how the tooling works
together
let's dive into ubiko's policy journey
in the beginning since we didn't have
too many workloads on kubernetes yet
and we were sure that we had consistent
peer review happening
we started with a simple plan because we
didn't anticipate too many resources
would violate these policies
we would start with writing the policies
and their tests after which we would
engage with our services teams to add
these checks to their ci flows using
conf test
simultaneous to that we would be working
on deploying gatekeeper to our clusters
in audit only mode
and then finally after we had worked
with the teams to remediate all of the
identified issues
we would flip the switch and move
gatekeeper into enforcement mode
as you might have expected from how i
framed the previous slide this plan ran
into some issues
we made it as far as writing and testing
the policies but when we moved to engage
with
some select teams to add conf tests to
their ci flows
the issues became pretty readily
apparent
well for one there were more violations
than anticipated
which meant that there was a potentially
a very long window between when we
identified these resources and when we
would actually be able to
apply remediation across all of our
clusters
this was compounded by the fact that we
were all
not only migrating existing workloads to
kubernetes
but we were in a growth period hiring
and starting up some new services on
kubernetes as well
additionally since the policies were
always essentially production
there was no way to safely test new
policies or changes to existing policies
this meant that in a ci flow with conf
test the ci flow would fail immediately
if
a violation was found and similarly
gatekeeper would just reject changes to
the cluster if it didn't meet policy
additionally adding conf test to rci
flows wasn't as easy as it could have
been
for one it kind of required our services
teams to know the comp test flags and
sort of how it worked
and additionally these it took multiple
steps to actually get
policies from a remote source into the
repo and then run the test
but most importantly the contest results
weren't surface to the teams working on
the resources
this meant that unless there was an
actual violation
no one would even know what tests were
run or anything like that
this was especially important to us
because we do have some policies that we
have labeled as just warnings
which aren't blockers for deployment but
they are a way that we want to
communicate to our teams
that the way that they have the
resources configured might not be best
practices
practice finally
policy admins such as myself had no
visibility into the test results
so we didn't really have any way to
track which
repositories or which teams had started
using the policies or any of the results
uh for which policies were making
the test runs fail or which ones were
just emitting warnings
with these pain points identified we
determined that there was essentially
two things that we needed to do
we needed to build a policy pipeline and
that pipeline would ensure that the
policies are safe to enforce throughout
our clusters
and we had to make the policy adoption
as easy as possible
if either of these weren't true it was a
pretty good chance that they
our policies wouldn't be adopted or it
would just be a long uphill battle
trying to get our teams to adopt them
so first let's focus on what we did to
make that policy adoption as easy as
possible
and to do that we created two github
actions
the first is a wrapper around conf test
itself and it addresses some of the pain
points
from the previous slides it
automatically pulls the latest policies
from a remote source
it surfaces the policy violation
warnings and
violations and warnings into the pull
request comments so that the teams
working on the resources
can see the test results
and it submits the results to a remote
server so policy admins can
monitor the deployments
the second addresses an issue that we
learned about later
was that some of our teams had started
to adopt flux cd for continuous delivery
and we're using its helm operator and
this home operator has a custom resource
that lets you specify the helm chart
source
and then what values you want to apply
to that chart and then it will
go and fetch everything needed and just
make those changes in your cluster for
you
however since helm templates are just
that they're templates they aren't
kubernetes resources
we couldn't use config on them directly
and this is because the data structure
in the yaml was different
and even if it was the same with
templates you wouldn't actually have
everything you needed until after
execution
so what this action does is it parses
the
the helm release resource
it pulls the chart info the version all
of those things
it automatically sets up a helm
repository so that it can pull those
templates from the remote repository
and then executes the templates so with
this we can easily
template out these resources before we
run conf test
so that it's nice and easy and it's a
solid flow
this makes it easy for our developers
because they don't have to remember all
of the flags for the helm template
command or with the argument order
or anything like that one thing to note
here is that this currently only
supports public helm repositories
but we're working on adding support for
private repositories too
so with the ease of adoption addressed
let's move on to the policy pipeline
itself
early on in the design of the policy
pipeline we have this one rule
is that we must not ever break
production
and for us that also includes any of the
pipelines leading up to production
this meant that for our teams that have
an automated deployment from development
to staging to production
using custom metrics that breaking their
access to the development cluster is the
same as breaking their production
pipeline
in order to accomplish this we used two
main methodologies
the first was data-driven policy
promotion and the second was a git ops
deployment flow
so diving into our policy promotion
strategy
we wanted to tackle one policy at a time
which again is just
reducing the window that new resources
are introduced
that violate the policy while you're
working about on remediating the ones
that you already know about
another key component is we use
gatekeepers enforcement action property
to enforce to introduce the policies in
dry run mode
where they are not enforced however when
they are in this mode we can still use
gatekeepers audit functionality
to audit our resources in our clusters
and see which of them
violate the policies
we've made the decision to only switch
to enforcement mode
after we've identified that all of the
offending resources have been remediated
and as a side effect of this we have
avoided setting hard deadlines for our
teams to
update their resources and make sure
that they're remediated
so one thing that we've done to work
around that is in the case where a team
says they just really can't
get this fixed in the next couple weeks
we can add temporary
exceptions to the policy for those
specific resources in specific name
spaces
but only when necessary that way we
still have good coverage of you know 99
of the resources in our clusters that
are here adhering to the policy
and finally we only promote policies to
production when they're linked to a
change management ticket which allows
them to be scheduled
this of course ensures that all the
potentially impacted parties are aware
of this upcoming change
and it lets us schedule around times
that we may be adding a feature release
a product launch or something like that
moving on to our get ops deployment flow
approach it's a pretty standard approach
where we use pull requests to move
policies throughout the pipeline
we use branch protection rules to ensure
that peer review occurs and that all of
our unit tests pass
a couple of things that we're doing
there is we require each policy have
a unique policy identifier and we
require that each policy have at least
two unit tests
one is for the positive path where
gatekeeper blocks something that we
expect it to
and the second is the negative path
where we
a gatekeeper allow something through
that we expect it to not lock
we also take advantage of the github
code owner's features
which ensures that the peer reviews come
from policy admins
and that's because the policy admins are
the ones who are the most familiar with
the regular language
and also some of the more intricate
details of kubernetes
and what's probably the most important
point is that we use automation to
create
the gatekeeper and conf test resources
this means that reviewers can focus on
the policy
and not the gatekeeper resources you
know those giant emo files
and it also makes it really obvious if
someone is attempting to go around the
tooling in place
because no human should ever be trying
to modify the gatekeeper or conf test
resources directly
with that let's go through the life of a
policy in this policy pipeline
so here we have a higher level view of
how the policy flows
we start by introducing a policy into
the dev branch
through a pull request and we want to
make sure that the policy always has the
enforcement action set to dry run
after it's merged flux will
automatically pick it up and start
syncing it to the development clusters
next we then promote this to staging and
production branches
still in dry run mode and this is to
ensure that we have full visibility
across all of our clusters
because try as we might to keep all of
these clusters configured identically
through
development staging and prod there's
almost inevitably some variation in how
they're configured
so one thing to note is when we merge
into the production branch is when we
actually generate the conf test
resources
and one thing that we do there since
conf test doesn't have the concept of
an enforcement action is that we
parse that enforcement action from the
comment header and we
in line rewrite any violation or deny
rules to warnings
so that when they're used in the ci
flows
the warnings are still surfaced to the
teams working on those resources
but it doesn't fail the ci flows yet
so once we have all of these set up and
running we then use the gatekeeper audit
data as the source of truth
to identify our existing resources that
violate the policy
and then we open tickets to work with
our teams to remediate
the issues that we've identified or to
add exceptions where necessary
after we've ensured that those are all
remediated and the audit data shows this
we switch the development clusters and
the development branch to
actually enforcement this is done by
changing the enforcement action in the
header from
dry run to deny and once again
after we make this change and merge to
dev we are continuously monitoring the
gatekeeper audit data to make sure that
there isn't anything that we didn't
expect finally once we do that we
follow the same flow to promote to
staging and then production
it's worth noting again that when we
make this change to production
is when the conf test policies will
actually
be changed back to either a violation or
a deny
so at this point is when the ci flows
will start failing
if they have resources that violate the
policy
the comptest metrics here is useful for
us to
see what's going on across our
organization to have a more full picture
especially of newer repositories and
newer projects that
haven't actually made it into a cluster
yet but they are not the
source of truth for when we promote
policies
so where is ubico now on its policy
journey
well we have gatekeeper deployed to all
of our clusters and we're tracking the
resources that violate our policies
additionally we're making our way
through each policy and moving
each to enforcement as we go we've
noticed that in
a lot of scenarios these policy
violations are actually introduced
upstream
whether that be internal or external
project and whenever we run into that we
try and make our
upstream our changes as well looking
into the future though there's a few
ways that we can work on making this
better
the first is to enable our teams to
write their own policies for enforcing
their own specific best practices
this can be anything from a custom label
to requiring that every deployment have
a
horizontal pod auto scaler attached
additionally we're looking into syncing
data from outside the cluster into
gatekeeper to be used for
more informed policy decisions for
example we might want to sync our
on-call rotation schedule into
gatekeeper so that only the person who's
on call for a given team
can make changes to production in the
event that a production issue or outage
is occurring
looking even further we are considering
adding mutation controllers as well
and those are a different type of
controller that the api server can work
with
which rather than just rejecting a
resource if it doesn't meet policy
it can inline change the defaults as
needed
one thing to note there is gatekeeper
currently has an open
design for their implementation of that
they haven't
started on it yet so if you want to add
your thoughts about how that should be
shaped or anything like that
go ahead and just search on the opa
slack for
mutation design and it'll come right up
and that about wraps it up thank you
everyone for attending and we are going
to open it for questions