okay uh so welcome everyone to our
lightning talk hardware backed security
for multi-tenancy at the edge uh with
spiffy and parsec
let's quickly introduce ourselves uh my
name's paul howard
i'm here representing the parsec project
i'm a solutions architect with arm
and i lead the team that's contributing
to parsec inside of arm
so andres over to you thank you paul
and i am andres vega i am product
manager for the
spiffy inspire projects representing
b projects and i happen to also work at
vmware as a product line manager
okay cool thanks um so what we're going
to see today is a first glimpse and the
first demonstration really of how parsec
can work
in combination with spiffy and spire and
how we can use the security and key
management abstractions of parsec
in combination with the production
identity framework of spiffy
to provide us with a multi-tenant
security abstraction
where multiple workloads can use
hardware-backed security
to protect the private keys based on
their own
attested and proven identity it's the
first time we've shown all three of
these cncf projects working together
to provide an integrated solution
so let's just quickly summarize what
these projects are
parsec is the new kid on the block
parsec joined cncf sandbox just earlier
this year
and it's the platform abstraction for
security parsec aims to create a uniform
software interface to the hardware
security of any platform
making secure services like key storage
and cryptography
available to cloud native applications
in a platform agnostic and language
agnostic way
so application developers know they're
getting the best available secure
features of their platform like hardware
protection for private keys
but they get that without having to
understand and code against all of the
specs and apis
that are needed to store keys in say an
hsm
or a tpm parsec handles all of those
details and then allows applications
to just code against parsec and not only
that but they can code against parsec
using their preferred programming
language
and using an interface that is
simplified fluent and sensitive to
common use cases
in key storage and security and let me
hand back to andres
to summarize spiffy inspire for us
thank you paul that is very interesting
so spiffy inspired spiffy
really defines a set of interfaces
the apis and the documents for proving
validating and obtaining service
identities
spire is the software that implements
the spiffy interfaces
for establishing trust between different
systems
now when we talk about trust that goes
from securing the microservice
communication
automatically through application
proxies
x509 certificates or json web tokens
it can help authenticate to common
third-party services without relying on
any api keys or embedded secrets
and it can also help build bridge
and extend service meshes across
organizations without
sharing any private keys
back to you paul
i think you're going to talk to this one
as well andres
i do intend to talk to this one as well
so bringing the
projects together in an integration
parsec is establishing the keystore
partitioning logic
you see here at the bottom of the
picture now
from a developer percep perspective
it is a platform agnostic experience
nothing changes in their workflow
and from an application perspective
these being multi-tenant applications
neither application can see each other's
keys they're
hard partitioned all that is required
is a reliable source of identity to tell
one apart from the other
okay great thanks and that's where spire
and spiffy come in of course
um so for multi-tenancy to be a feature
of parsec
there has to be this reliable and
verifiable source of identity
um that source could be anything in fact
and parsec doesn't prescribe a single
solution to that
um but if our workloads are running in a
spiffy trust domain
then it absolutely makes sense for
spiffy ids to be what parsec uses
to separate the clients and isolates
their key storage
and all that's needed is the appropriate
three-way integration between the
application
and spire and parsec now all parsec
client applications talk to parsec
through a client library that is linked
in process
so if we give that client library the
capability
to consume a spiffy identity in the form
of a spiffy verifiable identity document
or an s-vid
from the spire agent on the local
machine then the client can pass that
s-vid to parsec in the form of a job
token
which is added as an auth header onto
the api request as it goes from the
client's library
into the parsec service and then the
triangle is completed
by a new authenticator module that we
add to the front end of parsec
which is going to see that incoming
s-vid and verify it using the trust
bundle
from spire
so let's get to the demo and before i
run through the demo here i just want to
make a couple of shout outs to some
great people in the cncf community
who've helped to make this possible
so firstly to my colleague at arm
development who actually made the demo
we're about to see
um also joe ellis who was the founding
contributor of the cli
parsec tool uh that you're going to see
us using um and lastly to savory
blackmon
who created the rust client library for
spiffy that we're going to use here
now what you're about to see we split
the screen into these four quadrants
and each one is showing a shell command
session they're all running on the same
machine
so on the right hand side we have our
services
parsec lower right and the spire service
and the spy
agent running upper right we've created
a very simple minimal deployment here
where both the service and the agent are
running together
on the same machine and the services are
run during the entire demo
we've got logging enabled so that you
can observe what's going on
in the services as we go through the
demo
and then on the left we have the two
client windows
and in these we're going to use the
parsec tool which is just a simple
command line scripting interface for
parsec and we're just going to go
through some simple key management
operations
nothing more complicated just creating
listing and deleting
some keys but the important thing we're
going to show
is that each one of those clients has
its own key store
the key stores are isolated from each
other because each client has a
different spiffy id
parsec is going to verify those ids and
partition the keystore views
so that neither of our clients is able
to see
the keys of the other
okay so let's start by spinning up the
parsec service
and then from one of the client
applications we'll just run a quick
ping using the parsec tool just to make
sure that parsec has been spun up
and is healthy and agreeing to talk back
to us so there we go
and now upper right will spin up the
spire service
and then we'll generate a join token
from the spyder service which we need to
start the agent
and so now we're going to use that join
token
to join the agent to the system
okay and there we go so we have the
agent running there as well
so now we're going to register two
spiffy workload ids
for our two clients um we're going to do
this based on the unix
user id of each client so we're running
each client as a different unix user
we're using the uids a thousand and two
and a thousand and three
um so in this really simple system the
only selector
is going to be the uid but of course we
could have any number of selectors
to map the workloads to their ids
okay so both of our workloads now
registered with their two different
spiffy ids
so let's now go ahead start interacting
with parsec
from those two client windows and we're
just going to use the parsex cli tool
here
to run some simple key management
operations
so first of all we'll list the keys
and we get an empty list back to show
that we're starting from a clean state
we haven't created any keys yet
so you can see the bottom right just
there also
we'll highlight it just there um but
parsec has
seen and validated the job token that
was passed to it
and mapped it to its correct
corresponding spiffy id
which becomes a name space for the key
store
okay let's create a key now with the
parsec tool from that first client don't
worry about the details of the key
um except that its name is toto that's
generate key toto
okay so it's telling us that the parsec
key toto was generated you
see some chatter there from the parsec
service as well
but now let's switch clients and the
lower clients begin to repeat that list
keys operation
and you'll notice again that the key
store is empty
the key we just created isn't listed now
the reason this isn't listed here is
because this is a different client
a different spiffy id and also it's a
different name
space and so it's a different key store
this one is still empty
and just to label that point you'll also
see that we can't delete that key either
um if we try to delete it here let's run
a delete command
it's actually a destroy command let's
run a destroy command for toto
okay if parsec is now reporting that
we're trying to delete a key that
doesn't exist so it is now ensuring
that the second client cannot see or try
to work with or do any operations on the
keys of the first client
so let's go back to where we can see it
let's go back to the first client top
left
and now destroy the key we'll list it
first
show that it's still there and then
we'll destroy it
and lastly one final list keys to show
the store is empty again so there we go
it deleted successfully
um and we're done uh so you've seen two
distinct parsec clients using spiffy
inspire
for the identity management parsec for
the key store management
using those spiffy ids to ensure that
the key stores are kept separate
and that's it that's the demo it's very
simple we're just creating and
destroying some keys otherwise not doing
anything interesting with them
but it very visibly demonstrates this
principle of isolation
uh using the spiffy ids as the name
space
um and with that let me hand over to
andres to wrap up the talk for us
thanks paul you've said simple but it is
illuminating
to see how we can do hardware-backed
security
for multi-tenancy at the edge in a very
simple but secure way leveraging
parsec spiffy inspire if you would like
to learn more
about the projects how they come
together
as well as the intricacies that there
are to
each of the projects respectively we'd
like to invite you to
check the resources available you see on
the screen you will find the
code repositories on github for both
parsec as well as
spiffy inspire the respective slack
channels
if you have any questions if you would
like to
share work that you're doing and would
you like
feedback or the perspective of others
that's a great place to come join
exchange ideas learn from others and
collaborate with the community and last
here are some links to the project
websites for each of the projects where
you'll find
documentation available i hope that you
find
our talk informational and hopefully
it's something you can get to try for
yourself pretty soon thank you
thanks very much