[Music]
[Applause]
marhaban welcome Bienvenue wishing you a
warm welcome here from the Policy Forum
I can 65 in Marrakech Morocco
I'm gisla Gruber and with me today I
have two of the leaders of the African
regional at large organization also
known as a Frollo fatima Tasya sila
wishing your warm welcome and muhammad
al-baqir welcome my first question goes
to fatimata a foreigner regularly drafts
statements regarding I can policy and
issues relevant to end-users in the
African region during the ICANN 65
Policy Forum our frolla has finalized a
statement on the evolving I can
multi-stakeholder governance model as
nephrology de how do you see a frollo's
unique role in the process evolving
Thank You zerah
Afflalo has been but continuously
participating in the multi stakeholder
model process through a lakh meetings
through working groups through icon
international meetings bringing
different stakeholders from the regions
whenever I can meetings are organized
within Africa and most importantly is
that within we've started this since I
think 2010 for every ICANN meeting a
Frollo will think about you know the
most important issue at the moment and
make statements based on the challenges
we have within the region based on the
opportunities we have within the regions
and to formulate recommendations for the
board this time for I can 65 the Africa
community worked very hard on the
multi-stakeholder models showing what
the opportunities are showing the
challenges we have and making key
recommendations and you know what is
important is this in this is that this
is our unique way of participating in
the policy development of icon on icon
issues mainly on the multi-stakeholder
model and this is also an example for
the other regions because what we are
singling out what we were showing is
also true for many other regions even
though it these are acute for Africa
these can serve as in inspiring models
for the other for the other arrows and I
think Africa Africa but it's not only
within the the afrinic community but
this is open up to all I can community
within Africa we work together we draft
together we submit together we comment
together and we follow up together until
the recommendation make get an answer
from the board thank you thank you so
much fatimata
my second ghost question goes to you
Mohammed
so as the outgoing a Frollo chair can
you comment on the after all a hot
topics and other accomplishments and how
you envisage the future of a frolic
owing forward thank you very much
deserve a further have a unique position
because it's the organization that
brings the African users perspective to
I can also development process and in
order to facilitate this dialogue this
bottom-up dialogue with the community we
have established a working group that to
work on agreeing on a selective policy
topics that we see are important for the
region and the working group has came up
with about eight or nine hot topics
issues that focus to their to the
Internet users and in African community
and the DNS system and I can mission is
critical to the operation of the
Internet and to us as end-users how we
access the Internet so our community
have selected topics like the security
and privacy of the domain name system
and specifically the DNS SEC
implementation in Africa as one of the
hot topics our community as well
selected Internet Governance as one of
the hot topics issues and there's lots
of issues about access it might not be
directly relevant to I can but it's
relevant to the African community the
issue of diversity and participation
within I can as well as one of the the
hot topics that has been debated a lot
in our region so the idea is to bring
those topics to I can arena do capacity
building an outreach to our members in
Africa to educate them about those
issues
thank you so much Mohammed that was been
very interesting having both of you here
I'd like to thank you very much for your
time during this very busy meeting and
wishing you a successful I can sixty
five and I hope you get to enjoy
Marrakesh thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]