[Music]
hi I'm Rachel Macfadyen and I'm at I can
65 in Marrakech Morocco with Rafiq democ
the G NSO vice chair and head of the PDP
3.0 team and we're here to talk about
that and about the evolving the
multi-stakeholder model welcome so let's
talk first about the PDP 3.0 model or
the PDP 3.0 effort so how is that going
so far what what is your impression of
how it's good okay so I think we are
making progress so we started in Kobe
meeting by forming the team composed by
volunteers from the genus or Council and
we set up our work plan and we set a
target to deliver our work in terms of
implementation to the genus or council
by the meeting in Moorea so that now
give us a roughly four month to finish
our work and give us a little background
about what the state of the project is
and how you know where you're at with
what it looks like at this point okay so
yeah background it's important to
understand where we started in the
beginning so it was in last year we had
our TNS on council meeting in LA January
last year and so we had that kind of
really frank and candid discussion
between councilor about all the issues
and the concerns they see in term of the
policy development process and working
groups and we get as an input staff
paper kind of highlighting some issues
from their perspective and using that we
had that discussion and dialogue and
thought how how we can do better what
kind of improvement we need to do and I
think
the really key words on this is how we
make the PDP more effective and
efficient and understanding all the
constraints we have in terms of the
budget human resource and to do better
planning so we finish on time and so on
so we had that discussion and we spent
like last year working on the
recommendation and they will approve it
in Barcelona meeting but after them the
recommendation what matters is the
implementation and the discussion and
the general council level was is what's
the best approach to do so and it's
important I think for the council to
take ownership and something get started
and we have the small TF composite of
councilor representing the different
stakeholder group in the enso
and I said we started in Kobe and we are
making progress in our work to get
things delivered by Mori heart because
we are talking about to be effective and
efficient and we have to live up to
those expectations ourselves so this is
a really ambitious project this is
talking about looking at root and branch
of the way that I can makes policy so
this gets at the multi-stakeholder model
of governance so this gets into you
evolving the multi-stakeholder model of
governance how do these two efforts work
together so our kind of initiative or
project pre proceed or predates this
whole discussion about the mentee
stakeholder model evilish evolution and
also in terms of focus we are really
just about the PDT because we need to
remind that the General Council is the
policy manager and so it was important
for us to see what we can do better as a
manager of the process but also what we
need to do to help the working group so
the idea how we can support the working
group leadership
what the role of the liaison from the
council and then how they can help in
the working group and also what we need
to provide in term of resourcing and how
we can do a better planning but also if
you see it as a term of project
management we improve the reporting and
so on so it was the focus well for the
genesis was really about the genesis of
PDP and I see that it's important to
have this PDP 3 that all to succeed as
it's kind of a continuous improvement we
see and I understand that many parties
within Jeana so they want to participate
and give their their input so it's kind
of I think it will set for the future
and we will continue and probably maybe
we need to to see how we can include
more input and so on compared to what's
going on with this multi stakeholder
evolving model I get there is overlap
and this is maybe what can concern many
parties it's just we we should avoid the
overlap or different duplication of
efforts and this is this is what we are
doing is more bottom-up we need really
we need it really to to succeed and at
the end we probably we need to continue
the improvement because there is no way
we'll fix all of all the problem we are
trying to adjust and we are learning
from the experience and of what we will
apply in the future and hopefully things
will change so give us a an idea of what
you're focusing on in the next say three
to six months in fact even less than
that four months I mean we have several
category of recommendation that we are
working on the implementation but this
is basically really like how we can get
the consensus because all our
recommendations are consensus basis so
saying we need day they are consensus
made it's not in our office we need more
guidelines we need to support
working group leadership and kind of how
to get that and also in terms of
procedure do we need to improve them do
we need to add more I'll say guidance so
it will help all parties to understand
the procedure on the other hand is for
example to improve their reporting it's
not just to add more workload to the
team but it's to help the General
Counsel's policy manager to monitor
what's going on and so also to add that
that accountability so we said we have
those categories and we know that they
are not enough in fact they're from what
we discussed last year we have some
recommendation that they were not
approved yet and we know that they need
more discussion and also during the work
of the PDP 3 that all team we kind of
find out there are many maybe some area
for improvement but since we're just
focusing on the implementation we are
thinking just we can propose that the
General Council for further work in the
future so yeah we have forma we need to
get things done as said before because
we have to live up of what we are asking
the work working groups and gns so to do
and it's also a good experience for us
to see if what is visible and not and
I'd say using some of those
recommendations in practice and see if
we need some so much has been what is
your best case scenario in the in the
you know in the mediate future in the
you know I uh I won't be optimistic
enough to say at the you know at the end
game but like in the immediate future
what's your best case scenario I think
it's kind of to some extent is going
it's happening is really to succeed in
implementing this recommendation as soon
as possible I mean it's fine to spend
the time to think about recommendation
or to work out implementation but what
Matt is really that it's implementing
and to practice it and so to see that in
in a real cases so yeah the best cases
we get those implemented or I mean based
in the plan we are working on as soon as
possible hopefully like by next year in
a new working group or even in existing
working group trying to kind of improve
them and to help them there in their
work so that's really what I hope and
what we want to achieve great I wanted
to go back to one of the the issues that
you meant mentioned before about the
some of the issues that the community
raised about a lovely issues list and
you know the some of the issues with the
policy development process how do you
feel you know the progress has been made
in addressing some of those so I cannot
really speak about the issues this but
because that's in an ongoing process but
reading some of the comment I think
there is some overlap of what we are
trying to do or achieve but I understand
there is a lot of work still to be done
and I really believe that process as
what we have that can be tweaked and
adjusted can respond to this so we need
to know there is a frustration and the
different part is part of the community
about the PDP in terms of effectiveness
efficiency being done in timely manner
and so on but also we need to balance
that about all kind of the principle we
have like diversity representation and
so on and that's also at work in our
thinking when we start discussing the
PDP 3.0 so it's how you can improve and
keeping those principles and so like
that's what we are now doing to the
implementation is to think do we need
some guidelines do we need some
checklist for decision-making and so and
to improve that process I know that
usually and I can we are quite a
procedural process oriented but at the
end it's kind of
a needed factor to ensure the trusted in
all parts with different interesting I
can they can work together so that's why
we're spending time in the process it's
not because it's it's our hobby but it's
one of way that you can get everyone to
work together that's excellent
thank you very much thank you thank you
Rafik tamaak from the PDP 3.0 team and
the GMS o counsel thank you very much
thank you
[Music]