hello it is a pleasure to be part of
this year's virtual besides Earth and
event obviously due to the covert 19
situation it is not possible to be
together in person this year but it is
great to see the event still going ahead
in virtual format and I hope that you
can all still enjoy it online firstly I
would like to wish you your family and
your colleagues all the very best and
that you stay safe during this global
crisis what I would like to reflect on
in this talk is the changing
cybersecurity landscape that we've seen
over the last few years and specifically
from the lens of the defensive
perspective of how you will go about
defending a large modern distributed
enterprise hi I'm Kevin Jones I am the
group chief information security officer
at Arras and I am responsible for the
cyber protection of Airbus globally and
across divisions so we have a huge task
to do what do I mean though by a cyber
security in the modern distributed
enterprise well let me take a bus as the
example and you've all heard of Airbus
as one of the world's largest commercial
aircraft manufacturing but what you may
not know is that Airbus is also Europe's
largest helicopter manufacturer and we
also have the defense and space division
that makes military aircraft is Europe's
largest satellites designer launch build
and operator and we have a plethora of
security products including a cyber
security business that provides
high-grade cyber security to a lot of
Europe's military we are truly a global
enterprise we have about a hundred and
thirty four thousand workforce globally
which translates by the way into roughly
300,000 endpoints that we have to
protect
we operate in 35 countries and a hundred
and eighty sites worldwide
in addition to that we have
approximately 12,000 suppliers the form
part of our critical supply chain that
we have to make sure keep their parts or
their components or whatever their
manufacturing and supplying to us
flowing like most organizations of our
size Airbus is also undergoing a
significant digital transformation at
the moment so as well as protecting all
of our different sites different
locations all of our user group we're
also making a significant transformation
towards the adoption of cloud
technologies much more as well in terms
of our manufacturing plants and how we
make them integrated with factory of the
future and bring IOT devices into that
particular environment in addition we're
also looking at how we better use things
like machine learning and artificial
intelligence on our data and make it
much more effective for the business so
not only do we have a huge and
significant landscape we're also going
through an evolving and agile digital
transformation all of which we have to
protect from cyber threats so how do we
do that how is cyber security organized
The Devil's well firstly cyber security
nervous is not just about IT we operate
distinctly in four pillars IT being
obviously a very large and significant
pillar with the IT landscape that we
operate globally but it's also important
that we consider the fact that Airbus is
one of Europe's largest manufacturing
companies we make aircraft satellites
helicopters so protection of our
manufacturing plants and our industrial
environments also forms a key part of
our cyber security program thirdly we
operate around the cyber protection of
the products themselves how do we
protect them from cyber threats and
finally the fourth part of our pillar or
fourth pillar is people
how do we go about protecting the people
that operate in our environment and make
sure that they are a key part of our
cyber defenses to do this we operate a
federated cybersecurity organization
which we think is relatively unique so
it's worth touching on as the group sees
oh I have accountability across and
visibility across all of the divisions
but each division has its own Caesar or
divisional digital security officer as
we call them because of the four pillar
nature that we operate in now
each division is legally accountable and
runs their operations locally we will
also then have local teams in
engineering for example for our cyber
protection of product we all have local
teams in manufacturing for the cyber
protection of the production lines but
we have to have a way of coordinating
that so we centralized the reporting we
centralized the coordination and we
centralize the strategy if you like for
how we're going to implement all across
levels and that's what we termed the
federated model now not many
organizations today operate in that way
before how a particular environment it's
so far proving exceptionally effective
we also have a corporate level
key capabilities so we have things like
risk management we have enterprise
security architects that look all across
the estate and we'll do our urban ISM as
you like so they're the city planners of
our infrastructure and make sure that we
keep the standards everywhere that we
will expect we also have a detection and
response capability at corporate level
working with our I am colleagues to form
effectively the cert and the Sauk so
once we detect something unusual in the
infrastructure the certain the Sauk will
go about their escalation business and
will then try and remediating mitigate
or put controls in place and I'll come
to some of that later on in the talk we
also have a corporate level our own red
team our evaluate
testing so these are our pen testers our
deep dive specialists that can reverse
engineer and do code verification
validation for us and they will do the
red teaming activities they're the
people that attack us for us to make
sure that we have preempted the attack
path and can already start working on
our mitigations and our detection x' in
architecture and response and finally we
have an innovation and scouting team
that is very much forward looking into
the future and is developing
capabilities that an organization like
Airbus needs to protect itself sometimes
that can be unique customizations of
technologies that already exist
sometimes it can be completely new
technology that is bespoke to Airbus and
other times it can be just making sure
we have the right knowledge that is
relevant to our business we adopt a
compliance regulation and a risk-based
approach so some parts of our business
are highly regulated their safety
critical parts and therefore we have to
follow the highest standards and make
sure we're implementing security that is
pervasive in everything we do
we are obviously required to be
compliant to IT regulations like gdpr
and other standards that we adopt to
make sure that we are consistent in our
cybersecurity approach and that we're
able to consider ourselves adopting the
best-in-class that the cyber security
has to offer some security community has
to offer on the risk-based side
obviously everything we want to do has
to adopt a risk-based model what are we
doing to reduce that cyber risk for ours
finally something I think that is
important to note is that we adopt the
cybersecurity ethos in Airbus is all
about people process and technology
preferably in that order
so we don't just adopt the latest
state-of-the-art technologies we also
want to make sure that our processes are
right and
that we're adopting a people centric
approach to everything that we do some
of that is fairly unique and is related
to the scale in which we operate and
some of it is just adopting
best-in-class design for what we do I
should say at this point the defender
will always has to be going through a
cybersecurity transformation as well but
I want to switch my mindset slightly for
a moment and when we're looking at how I
would defend the network we should first
look at how an attacker would come about
attacking an organization like us and
it's always useful to adopt the
methodologies that are already out there
and I use the Cal chain example for that
so I think it's worth going through that
Cal chain for those of you who are not
aware of it obviously at the beginning
of an attack the adversary will do
reconnaissance both prominently external
to your infrastructure so that we
started doing social media mining
building capabilities around your your
business learning how you work before
they even touch your infrastructure then
the reconnaissance moves towards shall I
say external scanning of the networks
and of the infrastructures so that's the
point at which the adversary is trying
to see what you have what your digital
footprint is on the estate once that
reconnaissance phase is actually adopted
is completed you will see the
weaponization phase so this is when the
adversary is picking what type of attack
tools they want to use and they could be
advanced tools that you can procure or
they could be customized tools that the
attacker is making for this specific
type of mission then you go through the
delivery phase and that's obviously
where you want to get The Dropper or the
malware or you want to be able to try
and move laterally through the network
to put your tools in the right place and
you can also live off the land if you
like so a lot of apt adversaries will
use traditional network admin type tools
in their modus operandi
then we want to do the exploitation
phase so the exploitation is whatever
type of privilege you can get depending
on where you land in the infrastructure
so you want to have a look to see what's
on the internal estate you want to try
and put your tools in gain privileges
move laterally and really try and do the
installation phase of your attack then
you're doing either something like
command and control to make sure you can
keep that at that particular connection
to the infrastructure all your executing
whatever type of attack that you think
it's going to be or you want it to be to
have the impact um
the actions and objectives then once
they're complete whether that's data
exfiltration whether that's to cause
damage or whatever that might be is
notionally the last phase of the kill
check if I'm being very honest with you
an advanced diverse route will have an
extra stage to the kill chain which is
not traditionally spoken of and that
advanced stage is what I would call the
cleanup phase for the attacker how do
you cover your tracks once you've
completed all how do you move in such a
way around the infrastructure that you
want to be undetected however we've
we've done a lot as a community to
understand this particular attack path
in this particular way that adversary's
work and we also therefore have a
significant number of tools in our
defenders toolkit and generally speaking
we divide them into architecture or
monitoring type of tools specifically
all the process type of activities that
we're going to go ahead and do so on the
architecture side obviously when an
adversary's lands on a box or in a web
portal or something like that and we
want to make it as difficult as possible
for that adversary to a live on that box
and be to try and move anywhere else in
the infrastructure whether that's an
endpoint whether that's
whether that's a web server in a DMZ we
want to make sure that we are always
protected by architecture and there's a
couple of new things that are coming in
when we talk about architecture that are
really useful multi-factor
authentication has been around for a
while now quite some time and is
actually really effective at making an
adversary when they've stolen
credentials from trying to be
authenticated from a second device it's
not foolproof
you can still spoof a user into giving
you the passcode or the key or clicking
on the token that appears on their smart
phone but it really helps with stolen
credentials and if MFA's in place you
can detect when you have failures in mfa
as well and start reacting and
responding to them there are however a
much more modern and up-and-coming
technique which is generally termed zero
trust networking with zero trust
architecture and that is when you
encapsulate around your network around
your applications and around your data a
real authentic ation check because you
don't trust your network anymore
and the idea of zero trust is obviously
every time a user accesses a resource on
your network you real authentic eight
the user the problem with that is if you
had to enter your username password all
do an mfa challenge every time you
access something you would soon give up
it's not very user friendly so this is
where zero trust uses and leverages
machine learning techniques to learn
about the user as that lot as that login
happens it learns behavior for a user
over a prolonged period of time and you
can set parameters in your
infrastructure for things that user can
do depending on the given trust level of
that axis and I'll give you some
concrete examples if a user logs in from
a different country within moments of
having logged in in your LAN on your
network then there's probably something
not trustworthy about that second
and we might want to at that point flag
a second challenge and MFA challenge to
the user or if your policy states just
block that access and won it in addition
you can also do things like if a user is
accessing resources they don't normally
access there might be a valid business
reason for that but you might just want
to do a second MFA check just to make
sure but what about the endpoints itself
what about where the attacker first
lands well there's some good techniques
here as well we've seen the adoption of
things like micron virtualization so
effectively putting a mini VM around
each application there's some challenges
to use a adoption for that but actually
if the attacker has to break out of an
application a VM even if they use
something like a buffer overflow attack
I think can install into the application
it's very difficult to break out
somewhere else into the box and
similarly EDR techniques and tools are
becoming very widely adopted the monitor
all of the behavior on that box to see
what is going on and can block certain
actions certain behaviors and report
everything back to your sock or your
skin operations to be able to respond
accordingly
we've also seen a prevalence of things
like data loss prevention DLP tools that
specifically look at the data that's
held on that box or the data access that
comes from that box or that user and
again similarly any unusual behaviors
can be blocked or a policy can state
that you can't access this resource this
data type or that area and specifically
you can also do things like USB blocking
or CD blocking or email blocking around
data a deal piece is very very useful
for syntactic and semantic matching of
data types and you can really automate
the data that is on the box and the data
that user can have access to and that's
really good for both insider type
attacks and also if the user has clicked
on a phishing link downloaded something
to their box it prevents a an external
adversary than doing malicious things as
well
cloud security is a big thing we're
seeing the emergence of things like
cloud data focus we're seeing the
emergence of clarity encryption
techniques and the cloud operators
themselves of really providing this as a
service predominantly but it's up to any
organization adopting the clouds that
make sure firstly their cloud
environments are secured properly and
configured properly so there are
automated tools to help you with that
that prevent the risk of cyber attack on
your cloud and even then encrypting all
your data when it's on the cloud is
absolutely key but one of the most
interesting areas I think that we've
seen developing is the notion of
deceptive wear so tools that will put
fake credentials throughout your network
throwing your endpoints through
infrastructure to try and a slow down an
attacker because they don't know if this
credential is valid or not and B to
operate effectively like a honey trap so
that if one of these credentials is
trying to be used somewhere else in your
network you immediately know that
something's not quite right and then
finally looking ahead on the network
side we're seeing things like
software-defined networking that has
real potential to allow localized
policies a much more fine-grained
control over your network
infrastructures on the security
monitoring side this is obviously where
we have things like security operators
security orchestration and automation cm
tools have been used with orchestration
automation to make the first line much
more automated to deal with the deluge
of alerts that's coming in and obviously
the more security tools that you put in
place the more data you're getting into
your security operation centers to
detect the anomalies we're also seeing
the emergence of a machine learning
being applied to try and filter out the
noise and the dualities and therefore
you can concentrate much more on the
collective view of your systems and of
what's going on and you can respond much
much more quickly if you're automating
the process in your security operation
centers there are still challenges when
it comes to things like for example
industrial environments and how you
integrate sock into
dusty environment an abbess has already
gone down that path deploying certain
technologies and and improving our
forensic readiness even in industrial
environments that are not traditional IT
environments as well so very much an
important area I should say by the way
therefore all the tools things like for
example prop Mon and syslog are still
valuable data types for this is for the
sock but then you have to manage the
large data volumes that comes with that
so even if an attacker does land on an
end point the modern enterprise will
have tools and techniques to try and
prevent that movement and the relevant
monitoring techniques to detect unusual
behaviors in the infrastructure to try
and move quickly however we still want
to think like an attacker and this is
where we have our own red team coming
and our red team will do for example
deep dive evaluations to find
vulnerabilities in the products that we
buy and the products that we make as
well before lashing to make sure we have
the highest standards of security the
pentest team will perform pen tests
across our entire state preferably as
early as possible in the development
lifecycle with pre deployment testing as
we want to go from that element and
really thinking like an attacker having
a dedicated red team and pen test makes
a company much more secure because we're
finding things before our systems go
live and we're able to very quickly
verify and work with the blue team's the
defending teams to be able to work on
hypotheses when we see alerts that might
come in and finally just to conclude -
that it's not just a technical view of
the world we have to take and adopt a
human centric cybersecurity approach and
everything that we do and Evers has one
of Europe's first dedicated research and
innovation teams to human centric
cybersecurity so we look to make sure we
have best-in-class awareness but also
take techniques that are natural and
normal to the aviation industry like
black box thinking
if an event occurs and we launch a
investigation for example are we doing
the right things we need to look back at
every reason why we got to that stage of
the investigation and take a real human
view at it it's not a blame culture it's
really looking at things through
different lens and making sure we
haven't missed anything
so human-centric is really key and
really important we do however still
have challenges as an industry as a
whole now looking outside of evers
firstly on the red team or pentest site
I've been very specific that you have to
think like an attacker
we do a lot of work pen testing Web Apps
but what does that mean how does that
deliver value for the business and how
does that translate into shall I say the
impact it could have further down the
line when you chain these things
everything you do as a red team or pen
test has to be done legally and it has
to be done ethically engage the
businesses that want to engage with you
look for things like vulnerability
disclosure policies but don't just go
and pen test infrastructure without
permissions so work with people or be
part of an in-house team or a team is
contracted by a company to do that and
really think about the system itself
think holistically
not just about the software stack in
front of you think about what it's
running on where it's going to be most
importantly be part of the community
second issue I think you have as a whole
can be a whole community is security
metrics and risk management generally
speaking we're not very good at
presenting risk metrics that make sense
to a company and especially escalating
that to the board so we need to really
think carefully about how we present our
work whether that is a results of a pen
test and an audit or whether that is a
the current operational state or risk
state of a business the biggest killer
to all of us is complex systems of
systems so how do we work with
complexity how to manage that complexity
as we integrate more and more through
our environments think of the global
scale at which airbus operates
it's hugely complex and how do we manage
that how do we control that and to a
certain extent how do we automate our
security as much as possible on the
dates of classification site you can't
protect what you don't know so really we
need a lot of work on dates a
classification to make sure we know
where the data is and what type of theta
it is finally the other area I think is
probably most important to look at is
playbooks and incident response plans
make sure that you have a playbook and
an incident response plan that is
appropriate make sure by the way a
playbook is not a prescriptive this is
exactly what you do it's these are the
right people you call and you bring them
in so generally speaking is that
community need to share or play books
look like what they are and upskill
other organizations in how large players
do it what I also want to look at is
slightly beyond the perimeter so key
message is we used to have this model of
the security perimeter of an aspect be
under no illusions in the modern
distributed enterprise the perimeter is
gone the perimeter is dead we're now
dealing with multiple suppliers data out
counting suppliers networks
interconnectivity between suppliers and
our own portals we have cloud
technologies we are really running more
and more services so we need to think
differently about how we protect our
infrastructure and how we provide cyber
security firstly application development
as it's been done either by suppliers
the applications we're buying and also
the applications we're doing in-house
that may live either in or outside of
our perimeter we have to adopt
best-in-class things like dev sec ops to
be able to do that think about your
cloud infrastructure in your cloud
estate for most organizations how do we
protect that and we've seen a lot of the
highly advertised data breaches that
have occurred over the last four or five
years have been because of cloud
technologies not being secured by the
supply chain is also a hugely important
area for what we want to protect if you
have data in your suppliers or data in
to conspire
interconnected with you you still have
to protect that as part of your
infrastructure and there is ways it
means you could do that also physical
security and extended enterprise so
those that connect to you how do you
protect your key assets physically when
they're on your site without that you
don't have good security and I will
remind you that you need to do that
across all four pillars that we spoke
about earlier so IT industrial and even
if you're not a manufacturing company
you will inevitably have things like
logistics or heating and ventilation
systems that are inter connected to your
network now so consider those for those
of you make something whether it's a
product that is physical or whether it's
a software product you need to think
about that as well and people so finally
I want to leave you quickly with some of
my key takeaways things to remember when
you're doing defense security firstly
put cyber security at risk at the board
level if possible you have to escalate
security of your organization as high as
possible to make sure that the board is
discussing it on a regular basis to get
the support that you need in Airbus I do
not sit in IT actually I sit under the
chief security officer and I have a
counterpart who is the head of I am IT
cybersecurity and we work very closely
together and together we present to the
board always follow your data
the modern district Enterprise your data
is everywhere and you must follow the
data wherever it goes
consider IOT and infrastructure in your
cybersecurity program it's a must for
all organizations especially where you
have new smart technology smart
buildings heating and ventilation
systems or even if you're using IOT
sensors for various things around your
operations that is part of your
cybersecurity program and that includes
things that are not necessarily managed
by IT in your estate monitor your supply
chain and extended enterprise absolutely
key if you're going to have an incident
and it can come from your supply chain
or incident on your supply chain can
have major impact on your business
find security matrix that makes sense
and they're not necessarily IT security
metrics but they might be depending on
the type of organization you are think
like an attacker in everything you do as
a defender because that way you will end
up being mature and make sure you're
operating with state-of-the-art
techniques and finally plan for a cyber
incident and test that plan you've got
to test it the first time you're testing
that plan is not in a real incident so
you must be prepared and mature for your
cyber defense so that's the view that I
would like to give you from the
defenders perspective I appreciate your
time thank you very much for listening
to me I would once again like to wish
you all the best and stay safe during
this time