for our first track talk of today i'm
super excited to have abigail from
salesforce
we were very excited to have her talk
because she's going to be focusing on
the partnership side of managing risk
you cannot effectively manage human risk
if you're working all by yourself in
isolation you've already seen some
tidbits of this how it's recommended you
partner perhaps for example with your
digital forensics or incident response
team but you should also be partnering
with human resources
audit communications marketing
you to really effectively manage human
risk you have to have really good
partnerships with other organizations i
sometimes joke if you don't like working
with and helping other people
you're probably in the wrong career
awareness and you're going to struggle
because the key part of this job is
liking and working with others and the
other real win when we saw abigail's
mission is this
she's with salesforce salesforce
continually has one of the most mature
security awareness programs i've seen at
a global level now they have tremendous
resources also so bonus to them all
right abigail thank you so much for
joining us you are now on thanks
lance um hi everyone i am abby dealer
and i am currently a security awareness
manager at salesforce and i just want to
thank you so much for joining this
session on how we at salesforce built
partnerships to mature our security
awareness program
now i want to kick things off by asking
you to imagine a scenario
i want you to imagine a scenario in work
in which you've been working really
really hard for months to build and roll
out an omni channel security awareness
campaign
ahead of national security awareness
month
you know you ensure that all of your
templates and messaging are cohesive and
you roll out your campaign leveraging
all of the communicate communications
channels that are available to you
you're really thrilled because you know
you just executed on your plan perfectly
well not really
soon after implementation you hear from
your corporate communications team
that you've used the wrong template you
know the one that you're only it's only
supposed to go out to customers and um
let's just say they're not pleased
and you think to yourself wow if only i
had partnered with that team throughout
this process
okay so you know a partnership with the
corporate communications team would have
obviously helped to avoid the scenario
that i just described
um that scenario is a pretty
sort of simplified illustration of how
critical strong partnerships can be for
successful execution of campaigns
but hopefully it did get your attention
and it brings me to the conversation
that i want to have today around
partnerships
in this talk i'll really be focusing on
not just from the perspective of their
importance in helping you to deliver
targeted and on brand um
security education across various
audiences
but really how to build successful
partnerships in order to mature a
security awareness program and achieve
overall security awareness programmatic
goals
so as we all know and i think alex just
reinforced in his talk um the vast
majority i think it's 85
of cyber security breaches are a result
of human error
employees are often the primary attack
vector for cyber criminals and so
building a security awareness program is
really essential to help manage human
risk and create that strong culture of
security that i think we're all striving
for
salesforce security awareness
programmatic goals align to compliance
requirements
incident related issues and behaviors
particularly self-inflicted incidents
related to user negligence
salesforce's overall security strategy
and the effort to drive behavior change
across our organization
now particularly in this virtual
environment i you know this robust set
of goals can prove really challenging to
accomplish with one small team you know
maybe some of you only have one person
um so we at salesforce leverage
partnerships across our entire
organization to help us achieve our
programmatic goals
just a quick overview of the areas that
i'd like to touch on today
first and foremost the sans awareness
maturity model i'm sure most of you are
familiar with this given that you are at
a sans conference
and how our security awareness team at
salesforce uses it
then i'll talk a little bit about our
team's programmatic goals
the key partners that we identified to
help us achieve these goals
um some of the steps that we took to
solidify those partnerships
um and then of course the outcomes and
the impact from these partnerships on
our program and then you know i'll give
you a chance to
ask any questions that you all might
have
so with that let's dive in
um okay so as i mentioned earlier i'm
sure most of you are familiar with the
sans security awareness maternity model
but in case you're not or in case you
need a refresher
the sand security awareness model is
really an inch industry benchmarking
tool that provides guidance on the
maturity level of a company's security
awareness program
and at salesforce we're really striving
to reach and maintain kind of those
sustained culture change and metrics
framework benchmarks for our program
and i will say that you know before we
identified and solidified some of the
partnerships that i'm about to outline i
would say salesforce was hovering
somewhere around you know that promoting
awareness and behavior change benchmark
now aside from
achieving that sustained culture change
and metrics framework uh those positions
on the model we also have several
additional programmatic goals
first and foremost we must fulfill
compliance requirements um we have
several related to standards such as
uh pci fedramp and socks i'm sure some
of you are familiar with those and also
have to comply with those um
but yes compliance is really paramount
for us
um and next i would say we focus on
tackling instant related issues
particularly those related to
self-inflicted incidents caused by user
negligence
these types of incidents typically
involve a set of key security behaviors
that are both engineering and
non-engineering related
our third goal is to support the
strategy of our security organization
pretty self-explanatory
um and then last but not least our last
goal is to drive behavior change within
the company
so i won't get into the specific
breakdown of what each of these goals
entails but i will say you know overall
accomplishing all of these feels like a
pretty big scope for us even though we
do have a pretty robust um team and
program um but you know it felt daunting
for us as a team to tackle alone so we
came up with the idea of trying to
address and achieve these established
goals through partnering with other
teams across our organization
and we had a lot of conversations around
which teams made most sense to try to
partner with um and after a great deal
of discussion a few teams both within
the security organization and outside of
the security organization came to mind
so now i will talk about kind of the key
partners that we identified
the first set of partners we identified
were the sales force incident response
and threat intelligence team and we call
our instant response team c-cert so
you'll probably hear me reference that
throughout this talk
um and both of those lie within security
and we wanted to partner with both teams
to understand kind of the incident
related issues that salesforce was
currently experiencing as well as that
external threat landscape
um we figured that data from the csr
team should really inform our awareness
efforts and help us drive down the
number of self-inflicted incidents
related to user negligence
we also thought that the data from
threat intel could help us get ahead of
any emerging threats and avoid any new
incidents that might be on the horizon
remember one of our team's primary goals
is to tackle those incident related
issues
so the second team we thought would be
beneficial to partner with was our
employee communications team
so remember the scenario that i
described in the beginning of my talk
yes well we wanted to avoid that from
actually happening to us
and we thought that employee
communications could help us understand
the proper channels available to us for
our campaigns and to really help us
share our data-driven messaging
the third team that we wanted to partner
with was employee success strategy and
analytics
now keep in mind that two of the
security awareness team's main
programmatic goals are around
establishing a metrics framework and
driving behavior change
and display employee success and
strategy and analytics team was really
interesting for us to talk to because
they specialize in understanding
employee behaviors through data among
other things
and so we really wanted to talk to them
then lastly we thought you know it would
be beneficial to connect with the
information management and strategy team
they sit within the security
organization like cser and threat intel
and they are really focused on data
governance
we wanted more intelligence and metrics
around our employees security behaviors
and we needed to ensure that the data
that we could potentially be looking at
or storing was properly classified
um so now that i talked about the
different teams and organizations that
we wanted to partner with and why i kind
of like to shift to the how we went
about solidifying those partnerships
um we first identified individuals in
each of these organizations that we
thought would be appropriate to meet
with
we reached out to those folks and asked
if we could set up meet and greets with
them you know pretty simple
um
and during those meet and greets we
asked a lot of questions in order to
really understand what the needs of
their teams were
and we we learned some great insight for
instance you know when we spoke with
members of our incident response team we
learned that they were very swamped uh
with triaging self-inflicted incidents
related to user negligence and they
desperately wanted to
reduce those numbers
when we spoke with employee
communications they emphasized their
need to focus on building trust in the
sales force brand and reinforcing
messaging around trust which is
salesforce's number one value
when we talk to employee success
strategy and analytics they profess
their need for more insight intelligence
and data around different types of
employee behaviors
when we met with the information
management and strategy team
they mentioned needing to improve sales
force's data management maturity
so as security awareness professionals
you're probably already starting to see
some of the commonalities here between a
security awareness team's needs and
those of the other teams that we met
with
once we identified needs we work to
really align on common goals
so for example
similar to the c-cert team the security
awareness team has a goal of driving
down the number of self-inflicted
incidents related to user negligence
and similar to the employee
communications team
the security awareness team has the goal
of reinforcing key security behaviors
related to trust as security is a key
component of trust
and you know we believe that it's
everyone's responsibility at salesforce
to preserve the trust of our customers
and the value of our products
so moving on to the commonalities with
employee success strategy and analytics
just like them
the security awareness team wanted data
around different types of employee
behaviors
of course our team's focus is really
around you know key security behaviors
and their associated risk to sales force
um but that data did fold into what the
es strategy was looking for
um and our team the security awareness
team also had a goal of creating an
automated dashboard to showcase that
data and the risk around it
and the employee success strategy team
had the expertise and resourcing to
support that build which was great
and then lastly if we were going to
create a dashboard that contained such
data about employees we need help with
the classification of it from the
information management and strategy team
and it was a huge bonus that they you
know wanted to beef up their program's
maturity
so once we kind of aligned on these
common goals and narratives each team
went to their respective executive to
achieve buy-in
and as i think you know most of us know
executives tend to hold the power of the
purse and are typically the decision
makers so achieving buy-in for any
project is very critical
given that our teams had aligned on
mutual goals they were all able to
achieve buy-in from their executives
relatively easily and obtain resourcing
for the efforts
and i just wanted to showcase um
our security awareness dashboard project
given that i would say
it required the most effort and buy-in
and resourcing from other teams
and this project ties directly into the
security programmatic goals and kind of
stemmed from the desire for
both our security awareness team and our
security leadership as a whole
to have more insight into security
behavior and human risks across our
organization
and we thought it would be able to you
know provide us with better metrics to
um provide more targeted education to
employee population groups and
really uh indicate the success of our
overall program
so for this project we basically looked
at a variety of different uh data inputs
that we thought were key indicators of
human risk across salesforce
and you can see some key examples here
you know we have compliance and training
completion stats
phishing metrics
key engineering behaviors um
employees onboarded by security incident
reporting
incidents related to user negligence
which i know i mentioned are very key
for us
last passage option metrics and employee
patching stats
and then we worked to kind of funnel
those into a tableau dashboard and for
those of you who aren't familiar with
tableau
it's a data visualization tool and it
was actually recently acquired by
salesforce so it was great that we could
really leverage that
um and while our dashboard build out is
still in progress i thought you know it
would be great to kind of showcase its
prototype at a really high level
um as you can see we've assigned weight
to various behaviors
and inputs and compiled them into a
dashboard that you know displays risk
levels across different organizations
within our company
and then this allows us to provide
targeted education and awareness to
particular population groups based on
risk and need
and i do just want to say that um you
know all the stats and the information
listed here are meant to be
purely illustrative and you know are not
based on any real sales force data so
just wanted to flag that
um and then next i just wanted to share
a couple of highlights
from a few of the conversations we had
with our key partners about the mutual
benefits of our partnership particularly
um with the dashboard build up that i
just highlighted you know that project
was a big endeavor so
um first we hear from chakri who leads
our data engineering on the employee
success strategy analytics team and he
shared that their team
actively developed synergistic prod
projects with teams outside of es to
expand the human-centered philosophy of
running and managing organizations
the security awareness dashboard fits
the bill perfectly and is at the
cross-section of behavior and security
now keep in mind this is coming from a
team that's outside of security
and then we heard from michael who is
actually the data architect for the
dashboard and he shared that the
information management and strategy
team's involvement with the security
awareness program will help us improve
salesforce's data management maturity
so here you know you can really get a
window into kind of the conversations
that we had and see how
both teams partnered with us and really
benefited from helping to bring our
security awareness dashboard project to
life
and i do want to call out i know that um
i've made it seem like everything
throughout this process of solidifying
these partnerships was super easy um and
i just wanted to share that it wasn't
all rosie you know we definitely did
experience some challenges
um you know i would say that no matter
how good your case is
justifying resourcing for a project
outside of your team scope is never
an easy task and we certainly had to do
some convincing especially you know for
the dashboard project which as i said is
a pretty big endeavor
and i would also say you know with
employee communications too we had some
challenges um you know
they can be protective about messaging
that goes out to employees and
we definitely did have to explain to
them on multiple occasions why security
really is a key component of trust and
you know why it's so important that
employees do care about it so these
partnerships definitely helped us
achieve their goals but it did not come
without a set of challenges and i just
you know wanted to highlight that
anyway uh now that i shared kind of
how we built and solidified partnerships
outside and inside of the security
organization and with and without
challenges
um i kind of i want to talk about the
outcomes from those
so the incident response and threat
intel teams were able to provide us with
user negligence related uh data and
threat landscape data
and we then use that data to help inform
our proposed security awareness
campaigns
our employee communications team was
able to provide us with channels to
support our omnichannel security
awareness campaign and provided us with
metrics um you know success metrics
we're then able to take those metrics
and funnel them into a larger automated
security awareness dashboard developed
by our employee success and information
management strategy team
and there you have it the security
awareness team now has a metrics-based
approach that measures the success of
our program
this approach involves establishing
benchmarks and goals tied to key instant
related issues
and the continued build-out of a
dashboard to display key metrics for
leadership consumption
we're able to review those metrics for
continuous improvement of our program
and we're able to better prioritize
resourcing and develop more innovative
programs through established
commonalities across organizations
within the company
so now i'd like you to imagine another
scenario
imagine having access to a variety of
unique metrics you know beyond the
classic fishing and training numbers
related to your organization's key
security behaviors without having to ask
security leadership for any additional
headcount funding or resources
now this is not to say that i feel like
we've completely advanced to the metrics
framework position on the sans maturity
model
um i do think that there's a lot of work
to still be done in terms of continuing
to really refine our metrics and achieve
that desired state
however i do think that we're well in
our way
and as salesforce continues to grow and
evolve
the security awareness team hopes to
leverage new and existing partnerships
to meet the changing needs of the
company
and as evidenced through the
partnerships we've made and the impact
that i described today
the security awareness team at
salesforce really does play an integral
part in assisting the company to meet
its overall mission and goals