all right i'm super excited to have
crane join us today we reached out to
him specifically because of his
expertise and business email compromise
what is it and what should we teach
bec is the silent killer of the internet
we're all hearing about ransom because
it's always in the news because if you
get hacked by ransom where you're going
to be in the news but it's estimated
organizations only lost about 500
million in ransomware last year it may
be 500 million 700 million in ransomware
this year as crane is about to show you
when it comes to bec attacks and fraud
we don't deal in millions we deal in
billions and this is purely 100
human-based attack and primarily one of
the only ways you can stop this
is through the human so i felt it was
very important for you to better
understand this risk so you can better
manage this risk
crane
you're on
all right thanks lance um with that out
of the way um so again my name is crain
household i'm the director of threat
intelligence at abnormal security really
excited to talk about
um
uh you know what we've seen in the bec
threat landscape over the past couple of
years and really as science mentioned
how bec has really
transformed into the primary threat that
most businesses all around the world are
are focused on this year
now i've got a lot of stuff to talk
about here but first i really want to
level set on the problem of business
email compromise and not just look at
the scope and how big it has become but
also understand why it's actually
happened why it has become such a big
issue
now before we you know get into
that problem let's let's
throw down some definitions so we can
all be on the same page about what we're
actually talking about when we talk
about bec because it's one of those
terms that really has fallen into this
very nebulous definition and a lot of
people mean a lot of different things
when they're talking about bec now the
definition that i primarily use when i'm
talking about business email compromise
is it's going to be a targeted spear
phishing attack
that involves the impersonation of a
trusted individual or someone that a
target knows in order to trick that
person into making a making a financial
transaction or sending sensitive
materials
generally speaking that's what we're
talking about when we're talking about
business email compromise and there are
two primary ways that this can actually
happen one is through
spoofing either the display name you
know looking looking at who it's coming
from or the email address usually those
are done in conjunction with one another
or it could be done through the actual
compromise of an email account which has
become more
prominent more recently which we'll talk
about here in a bit
but using a compromised account to
actually send the messages
one of the things that's really
important to keep in mind and i'll
probably i'll mention this a couple of
times as we go through this presentation
is when we're talking about business
email compromise we're generally talking
about a simple response based attack
that doesn't include a phishing link
that does not include a malicious
payload it's simply a text-based attack
that's trying to get a person to respond
to it
now
you know lance that's uh you know
attributed to this a little earlier but
let's look at the the numbers of the
actual losses that are attributed to bec
and all of these numbers are coming from
primarily from the fbi's internet crime
complaint center or or ic3
and one of the one of the best alerts
that the that ic3 put out was in late
2019 and in that um in that alert ic3
said that between june of 2016 and
october of 2019 more than 26 billion
dollars had been lost to
the bec attacks globally and when you
put that on a per month basis that's
about 708 million dollars that's being
lost every single month and that was at
this point about a year and a half two
years ago and we know that bec losses
have only grown since then
the amount that's lost per bec attack is
about 96 000 and that does vary
depending on the type of attack which
we'll talk about here in a few minutes
and then what's also really fascinating
is when you look at the most recent ic3
report that came out earlier this year
and you look at the comparisons of all
of the different types of cyber crime
that businesses are seeing on a on a
daily basis
bec
actually adds up to about 41
of all cyber crime losses that
organizations are seeing
and when you compare that to other types
of cyber crime activity ransomware is a
great example of that
it's not even close that bec is the
biggest financial
uh
the biggest cause of financial loss out
there
so why has bec become such a big problem
well my my opinion there are three
primary reasons that bec has become such
a the the issue that it is today
the first is that traditional email
defenses that have now been around for
decades have primarily focused on
technically sophisticated threats
they're been focused on things like
ransomware or other types of malware or
even credential phishing
and the cyber criminals have actually
identified this and they've noticed this
and what they've done is they've pivoted
their tactics and moved to less
technically sophisticated techniques
moving to more pure social engineering
instead of using malicious payloads or
malicious links
and so they're they they've sort of
adapted to the improved defenses that as
a community we have we've gotten to
the second reason is if you think of
cyber crime from the the perspective of
a business
um and in most cyber crime is a business
because it's financially motivated
from a from for bec it has a much higher
return on investment than other types of
cyber attacks you know one of the things
that you know i've been saying for a
number of years was you know at some
point the eastern european and the
russian cyber criminals that have you
know historically been known for more
technically sophisticated cyber attacks
are gonna start thinking to themselves
you know
why am i spending all of this time and
resources and money you know setting up
infrastructure for my malware or hiring
developers for my malware when i can
just send someone an email
ask them to send me money and they'll do
it
the overhead there is so much lower and
the amount of profit that they can make
from a bec attack is so much higher
that i think
we started seeing more sophisticated
actors moving into the bec space in
recent years and i think it's going to
continue that's going to continue moving
increasing moving forward
and then the final reason bec has become
such a problem is
at the end of the day
social engineering is extremely
effective as long as human beings have
been on this planet and we've been
interacting with one another we've been
social engineering each other the only
difference is today we're doing it
through email through a computer instead
of doing it face to face or over the
phone or through the mail
the same concepts that have been used
literally for thousands of years to con
each other are still being used today in
bec attacks and other types of scams
and so that's you know a very brief
overview of you know why you know how
big of a problem bc has become
over the past five to six years and why
it's become such a big problem so next i
want to sort of pivot into looking at
the the various flavors of bec and what
types of bec attacks that we're seeing
on a regular basis
now the first one is uh it are our wire
transfer attacks now these wire transfer
attacks this is really where bec
you know uh uh uh started with back in
about 2014 2015
basic ceo impersonation scam someone
trying to you know impersonating the
executive at a company
and is saying you know can you please
send a a wire transfer to this vendor
that there's there's a there's a payment
that's overdue
this is where bc has come from still
about 20 or so of all the bec attacks we
see on a regular basis are requesting
wire transfers to a fictitious vendor
now the upsides to these from the cyber
criminals perspective is the payouts are
generally significantly higher you know
the average amount for these wire
transfer requests is between usually
between 50 and 60 000 as you'll see here
on a couple of slides that could
depending on that type of wire transfer
request that could be significantly
higher but on average it's about 50 to
60 000
and then also what we'll see and we'll
see this more on the next slide is when
we talk about these types of requests
the threat actors can actually develop
some pretty sophisticated pretexts and
reasons why um these payments need to be
made
now the downside of this if you look at
this from the cyber criminals
perspective you know the payouts while
they may be higher they're actually they
take a lot more time to actually go
through in order to get the money from
point a which is the target organization
to point b which is the scammer it needs
to go through multiple different
channels it needs to get wired to a bank
account from that bank from that mule
account it actually needs to go to
generally through a number of different
hops that where you're also going to be
losing money along the way before it
eventually gets back to the scammer and
it also requires those money mules
it requires a generally a third person
that is going to be receiving and
passing on the money uh that other types
of bez attacks don't require and you'll
see here in just a second what those
types of attacks are
now this is one of the more
sophisticated pretexts that we've uh
that we've seen more recently and what
we've seen is some of these
sophisticated actors that are places
like eastern europe or russia or even
israel where israel is one of the places
where we're seeing a really emerging
hotspot for bec actors
we see
these more sophisticated pretexts in
this case it's a it's an actor that is
first impersonating the ceo of a company
and saying that there is a really
important uh confidential payment that
needs to be done and
what they what this actor does is they
use one persona and then pass the target
employee off to a secondary persona
that's actually uh impersonating a
legitimate uh attorney in places like
western europe and that that second
persona is the one that's actually going
to be
working on the the actual payments
and so this is an example of some of
these sophisticated pretexts that we've
started seeing over the past couple of
years that the
that bec actors are able to do with wire
transfer requests
another type of bec attack that's really
undergone some really significant
transformations over the past year and a
half to two years is payroll diversion
and in these attacks it's essentially a
bc actor that's going to be
impersonating an employee at a company
usually going to be a c-level executive
who's uh who's going to be contacting
someone on the human resources team to
say you know i've just changed my uh my
bank account i need to update my direct
deposit information can i just give you
the information can i give you the
account details and see if you can make
the account the change on my end
and so that's sort of the concept behind
these attacks over the past year and a
half
this has gone through a significant
decline to the point of in july of last
year
only about three percent of all of the
btc attacks that we were seeing on a on
a monthly basis
during that month were actually
requesting payroll payroll uh diversions
whereas now since the middle of last
year we've seen an almost consistent
month-over-month increase um as actors
have actually moved to the types of
accounts that are being used to receive
these funds
and a month over month now about 25 of
all of the bec attacks we see on a
monthly basis are now requesting uh
payroll changes
and you know one of the some of the
upsides to these are
the detection of for these attacks is
actually usually delayed if you think
about it you're usually getting paid
once every two weeks
and so that is if i'm not receiving my
my paycheck right away i might not
realize that and so there may be a
little bit of a lag time between the
time that the the the money is actually
sent into a mule account in the time
it's actually identified by the employee
who's missing the money and that delayed
detection uh increases the success rate
that the money will be able to get
passed on to the scammer without being
retrieved by by a financial institution
and then the other upside to it is a lot
of the the payroll diversion activity
that we see today is driven by prepaid
cards these are cards that you can pick
up at many big box stores like a walmart
and these are cards that are ex that are
generally going to be marketed to
receiving direct deposits or other types
of unempl of uh government benefits
and these cards because they're easier
to set up um and in some cases they can
be set up online only without actually
having to purchase the actual card um it
becomes it because it gets a little bit
more attractive
for scammers
now the downsides to these obviously in
most cases there's an unknown amount
they don't know how much the employees
are actually making so don't know how
much they're actually supposed to be
getting in
generally speaking though as i mentioned
they're going to be targeting executives
so the thought process there is that
there's going to be a a larger dollar
amount than than
trying to impersonate some other
employee at a company
and the targets are are very limited
obviously the p the number of employees
at a company that i can actually change
and have control over someone's direct
deposit account is very limited and so
those are really the only employees that
would be the the targets for these types
of attacks
so the third type of bc attack which is
you know has become significant has
increased significantly over the past
couple of years are
bec attacks that are requesting gift
cards as a form of payment and you can
see an example of one of these on the
right-hand side of the screen um
generally these are going to be
attacks that are going to be
impersonating either the ceo or
executive at a company or even an
employee's supervisor
saying that you know i'm looking to get
uh some to get some gift cards for
either rewards for employees or gifts
for potential customers can you go out
and buy a thousand to fifteen hundred
dollars of these of certain types of
gift cards and and you take pictures of
them and send them to me right
and what's really interesting here the
reason these have become so popular is
one they're usually not reversible once
they've been sent to the scammer they
are laundered extremely fast you know
with we've seen you know i've done some
research where looking at the time when
these
even like two thousand dollars of you
know 100 apple itunes gift cards are
sent to a scammer and those are
individually laundered uh they're
generally going to be posted for sale on
online peer-to-peer cryptocurrency
exchanges and they go from the time they
receive the first ones received by the
scammer to the time that that those
cards are laundered and hit the scammers
bank account can be as little as about
two hours and so that is a very very
fast process um it also doesn't doesn't
require a middleman
or a money mule in order to facilitate
these transactions the the pictures of
the gift cards are sent directly to the
scammers the scammers post them up on on
some place like paxful and then they're
immediately laundered from there
but really i think one of the real
reasons that gift card uh attacks have
become so popular is the population of
potential employees that can be targeted
by these attacks is significantly higher
you know essentially any any employee at
a company can be the target of one of
these attacks you know i've seen gift
card bec campaigns targeting a single
organization where 50 or 60 employees
were targeted at any given time
and this isn't a you know the success
rate needs to be really high for these
attacks
if i'm just making if my success rate is
maybe one percent
i'm having a good pay day at the end of
the day
and so i think that's one of the really
big reasons that uh that these types of
attacks become so popular
the downsides to these are the payouts
are much much smaller the average
request we see for gift card btc attacks
is about uh a thousand to fifteen
hundred dollars and the employees are
much less convincing you know i sort of
ran through what one of these things
might look like and while the initial
premise of one of these attacks that you
know i need rewards for
for employees or gifts for customers may
make a little bit more sense as you go
along with this and you try to get the
employee to go purchase these individual
cards take pictures of them uh each one
of them individually send them all
separately scratch off the backs of them
you know they have to be emailed and not
sent in person
it sort of allows a lot of time for red
flags to sort of pop up here but i think
obviously because we've continued to see
such a big rise of these types of
attacks about 50 of all the bec attacks
we see on a monthly basis are requesting
gift cards and it's been steady over the
past couple of years because they're so
popular that must mean that the return
on investment the roi for these attacks
must still be there or else the actors
wouldn't continue to do them
but really the biggest bec threat today
that i think is really important for
everyone to understand and as we go
through with this this is really where
security awareness really comes in
is what we call vendor email compromise
and vendor email compromise is
essentially a hybrid between credential
phishing attacks and identity deception
attacks where a threat actor may
use a phishing a a credential phishing
campaign
to
compromise mailboxes of a number of
different employees
the actor will then go into those
mailboxes and identify high-value
targets that are um that are involved in
things like payments or invoices or
customer contact
and once those high-value targets have
been identified
they will then sit on those mailboxes
and collect intelligence to better
understand you know when payments are
due who the customers are what normal
communication patterns look like they'll
steal copies of invoices
and they'll sit on these mailboxes for
weeks if not months until they
eventually inject themselves into a
legitimate payment that's actually
supposed to be due and they know what's
actually due because they're getting all
the information from these mailboxes
and then they target one of those vendor
suppliers customers with an email that
looks extremely realistic
because
they're using all this information
they've collected
and so the ultimate target here is going
to be that vendor or suppliers
customers
that are going to be the ones sending
out the payment
and vendor email compromise is really
interesting because i think when you
when you talk to most people about
phishing attacks today
most people will probably give you the
answer of know who would actually fall
for these types of attacks and what's
interesting about vendor email
compromise when you look at these emails
the
the question goes from you know who
would actually fall for this to who
wouldn't fall for this because
everything looks really really really
real realistic when you're looking at
these types of attacks
you know one category of of bec attacks
that we've seen become more frequent
over the really of the past six months
or so
are uh bec attacks that are requesting
aging reports and this is what i
consider to be you know a vendor email
compromise attack really without the
initial compromise
and so for those of you who don't know
what an aging report is an agent report
is a report that's handled by vendors
and suppliers
that contains all of the outstanding
payments that are due by customers and
also includes all of the additional
contact information for those customers
for whoever we're getting for whoever
the accounts payable person is at those
customers and what we've seen more
recently is instead of compromising
accounts we've seen actors impersonating
uh you know
some executive at a company
contacting an accounts receivable
specialist and saying hey can you send
me the most up-to-date aging report um
for for my for my for my understanding
for my knowledge i can do some research
and the employee may send that that
report which looks very similar to what
you see on the screen here and the the
actors will then use that information to
craft an email that's going to be
targeting
uh that vendor or suppliers customers
very much in the exact same way that we
see with classical vendor email
compromise attacks except there isn't
there is no actual mailbox compromise on
the front end
and so why are vendor email compromise
attacks such a threat so one is the
amount that's lost in these types of
attacks is usually significantly higher
to other types of bec attacks and as i
mentioned earlier um you know on average
wire tran you know general ceo
impersonation executive impersonation
wire transfer bec attacks the average
requests there are between 50 and 60
thousand dollars usually um there was
some great research that was done by the
better business bureau about a year ago
that shows that for vendor email
compromise attacks
the amount that's requested or lost in
those attacks is about a hundred and ten
thousand dollars so we're talking about
generally twice
twice the amount of money that's being
lost from vendor email compromise
attacks to other types of wire transfer
vec attacks
also the actors are using trusted
identities individuals that the employee
is actually communicating with on a
regular basis because they're part of
these financial transactions and so
because that trust has been built up and
the employee recognizes those normal
communication patterns that the actor
actually knows they're able to sort of
leverage that trust to their advantage
again as i mentioned there these emails
are crafted using real intelligence that
are collected from these mailboxes which
results in extremely realistic looking
uh emails that are being sent to the
vendor and suppliers uh customers and
then the final reason that they're such
a threat is you know as i mentioned the
ultimate
organizations that are sending the money
are the customers that being said the
ones that are actually compromised are
the vendors and so the cut the the the
customers that don't actually have have
actually no
uh no control
over the initial compromise so it that
that compromise occurs outside their uh
their area of control and because that
happens they're not able to very well
monitor for any potential ato activity
also the generally speaking the vendors
and suppliers that we see being
compromised by vendor email compromise
attacks
are generally much smaller than other
types of organizations that may not have
the resources that can be dedicated to
things like security awareness training
or other types of email defenses
and so you know i've seen i've seen uh
or you know companies as small as five
people be the initial uh uh target of a
vendor email compromise attack on the
phishing side of things and that small
vendors customers were then targeted
with follow-up phishing attacks
so there's a little bit of an overview
and we've so far we've looked at the
problem of bec we've looked at the
different types of bec attacks that you
might see on a day-to-day basis but i'll
close out here with looking at you know
security awareness training and how that
can be used to better prepare our
employees our users to defend against
these types of attacks
so the first thing to keep in mind here
and i mentioned this very at the very
beginning of my presentation you know
phishing is not just about links and
attachments as we've seen with bec
attacks most of these emails are only
going to contain text so if i'm training
my users to only look out for bad links
and bad attachments
it is it will not prepare them for these
response-based attacks
and that sort of goes into you know
security awareness training as it has
emerged as this
as this industry
it was originally built around
preventing malware attacks preventing
people from clicking on malicious
payloads it was not built around
identifying you know basic social
engineering attacks
also it's really important to keep in
mind that that one size doesn't fit all
you know from from a bec perspective
especially when we're talking about
vendor email compromise attacks because
those actors these cyber criminals are
using intelligence based on real-world
interactions if you're doing bec
security awareness training effectively
you should also be putting the time in
there to
to include that intelligence that a that
that that uh that a cyber criminal might
be might be using um to to socially
engineer your your users
and so it's much harder to automate
these more real-world bec attacks than
it is to automate something like a
credential phishing uh campaign or a or
a malware campaign it's much harder to
automate those types of attacks so you
actually have to put a little bit more
work to make that type of training more
effective and better for your users
and then finally i think this is really
important is you know
when we think about what we're trying to
accomplish with security awareness
training you know this is it has
traditionally been a metric driven
industry where i'm trying to get you
know what is my click rate what is my
success rate for for uh for a phishing
simulation
and what is what do you think about
what's more important is that data more
important or
is the fact that i'm trying to prepare
my users for more real world attacks is
that more important to think about when
you are running these security awareness
campaigns and b it's actually it's and i
say that because it's very hard to
measure
the effectiveness and the success rate
of response based attacks because you
know with most phishing simulations
being able to click on click a link or
open a payload is relatively easy to
detect but with bec attacks i have to
actually look out for whether someone is
responding to an email and that requires
additional infrastructure being set up
it requires additional monitoring that
most security awareness
training platforms don't have the
ability to do and so you know
while we want to be able to to measure
the the get some metrics behind our
security awareness uh uh simulations you
know that's not always possible and you
know when we're talking about you know
is it better to you know leave that data
behind and just make sure our users and
employees are prepared you know that's
that's sort of a trade-off that you have
to think about
and so that's all that's all i have for
today um i'd be welcome to answer any
questions um any any contact information
you see some contact uh information here
on this slide feel free to reach out if
anyone else has any questions
all right so lots of questions crain
that was fast and furious
so folks um just one or two quick points
and then we're going to ask craig bec
stands for business email compromise
also commonly known as ceo fraud as
we've been saying throughout this uh
event and crain pointed out people a lot
of times have different definitions
and the other thing oprah i'm going to
ask um one question i've been seeing
asked in slack and then i'm going to go
to the q a in soon
is these seem seem so basic you know
gift cards asking it for a wire transfer
why are people falling for these what
are the bad guys doing that makes this
so effective and people happily transfer
money happily buy gift cards
that's a great question i think this
goes back to something i mentioned a
little bit earlier is you know at its
core social engineering is extremely
effective the same themes you see
over and over and over again in bc
attacks as well as other types of
fishing campaigns you know these actors
have learned to harness the same
principles that uh that that that you
know con artists have been able to use
for for a number of years fear anxiety
doubt reward these are the themes that
you see over and over and over again
in these uh in these phishing attacks
and those are the that's essentially you
know it's very hard to override our
ingrained human nature to trust what we
see in front of us and so that's that's
prime that's one of the primary reasons
that um
that these are being so successful it's
also you know when you look at the the
weaknesses of email just generally
speaking the the fact that i'm able to
very easily change the display name to
make it look like it's coming from a ceo
or some other executive you know adds
that level you know for most people who
aren't technically sophisticated i'm
gonna trust that that email is coming
from my ceo without giving any other
without uh having any other information
to make me think that it's not
so i was reading those examples you
shared crane which are awesome and what
i noticed is one
almost no spelling errors no grammar
errors in this case since they were
english based the english was very good
but also like you said it seemed like
the bad guys had done their research
they were pretending to be an executive
they pretended like they knew the
individual they pretended like they were
part of the company
that seems like part of what makes this
so successful
absolutely so we we see that more and
more it's more common you know while we
certainly see a heavy volume of the bec
attacks that have the traditional
spelling grammatical errors and most
people would be like what is what is
this i would never fall for this type of
thing you know you have some of the more
sophisticated actors that are moving
into the bec space that really take
their time crafting these messages even
outside of the vendor email compromise
realm you know just in the basic you
know ceo impersonation attacks
you see a lot of these actors that are
now
requesting more
more and more uh higher and higher
amounts of money
and taking the time to craft very
sophisticated um lures that are being
sent to these uh to employees to the
point where there are some groups that
we know i
really feel that there's you know in the
on these underground you know
underground forums that there is a um
they're actually hiring people to
translate certain uh certain emails for
them that are in perfect either native
english or native french or native
whatever language um to make them more
effective
and then where are these threat actors
getting this information on people
so that's a great question you know
what's really interesting when we when
we on when we look at you know how
targets are identified through bec
attacks what's really interesting is
that the same legitimate commercial
services that sales and marketing teams
all over the world use to identify
sales prospects these are the exact same
services that bec actors are are using
to identify targets and so they'll go in
for either a um or either a a short-term
trial or even use a compromised credit
card to pay for one of these services
and they can do a number they can search
on a number of different variables and
receive a very finely nicely organized
and curated list of potential targets
meeting those criteria that then then
use to supplement with additional open
source uh information to identify things
like who the ceo or executive i'm going
to be impersonating is and use that as
their base of targeting information to
then send out the the btc campaigns
so crane brings up a fantastic point we
think the bad guys are getting this
information because they're hacking our
data they're finding an insider threat
they're going to the dark web and
dealing with other cyber criminals and
cranes like no if i want to hack a
company and if i want to learn about
executives i'll just go to any sales
database and buy the marketing data
because the data rate's already out
there yeah
exactly
that's exactly what they're doing i
think what's what's also really
important to keep in mind is that there
is a very robust
underground communication network
between these actors where they're
always sharing tactics and techniques
with each other to help each other out
to to make their attacks more successful
so and this is this is always going to
be a cat and mouse game where we're
going to be you know evolving our
defenses and making them better and
they're going to pivot in a direction
and we all this that's why threat
intelligence is so important because
then we need to know where they're
moving to what the next iteration of
these attacks uh is going to be in the
future
all right fantastic crane really really
appreciate it and folks that's what
makes be so dangerous in many ways it's
a spear phishing attack wailing attack
but no links
no attachments the bad guys have done
the research and people are falling for
it to the tune of billions of dollars a
year crane thank you so much folks if
you have questions for crane please meet
them in the slack channel thank you
crane
thank you