all right heads everyone ok so our first
talk is Brent Kennedy with Sir and then
Jason Frank with the very go after
yourself ten penthouse tactics of
looting
good morning everybody
that was less enthusiastic
thanks for coming thanks to everybody at
these sites of Pittsburgh on the
conference really appreciated me my name
is Jason Frank again I'm with their
scripts adapted threat division we're a
small DC based security consulting
company
I run a team called the indented threads
division group of about 20 head testers
so if anybody is looking to jump
for senior and junior I also teach the
adaptive penetration testing class at
blackhat coming up here my specialty has
been focused on building and executing
penetration testing programs for both
the federal government as well as large
providers will serese--
and I've read penny here Harry
I work across the city insert Carnegie
Mellon's campus as part of software in
software engineering Institute I am one
of the wheat pen testers there we
partner of Jesus company and some
government clients to do a lot of
testing for federal state local
governments as well as a lot of critical
infrastructure so if you haven't work in
any of those domains you know come
near the after we can do
some really cold work after you guys a
very good price that you pay and we'll
Schrader I think I'll try to love this
presentation we project you've been
being here follow him on Twitter and
start enjoying he does a lot of cool
stuff he's one of the lead researchers
at bears group he's one of the
co-authors on the Bell framework
compared to every thought it's a Navy
bypassed by pest hole he's the sole
author of the power tools which when we
get into a lot today so a big trigger
for there between the three minutes we
have about fogers experience two leading
cuts less engagement so we go from a
neighbor
like I said to you know private
customers so we kind of get to see the
broad spectrum of everything
so why are we here so you know it said
we do always defend this and we you know
kind of start seeing a theme you know
usually if the defenders out there you
know usually out briefing on the last
day you're talking the customer to
telling what you found
we started to see this trend where you
know we get you know system ins not guys
soft guys they started coming up to us
and they just start asking your
questions you know how do I get involved
with this you know how do i you know any
self investing online and little books
can i read what tools are using and
especially we start doing findings you
know we say you know here's our tack
back we got in through this this web app
and they were like I've been here a year
and I've never seen of my life how did
you find that in two days so you know we
started thinking to ourselves you know
what we were using all these specialty
tools and they learned ability reducing
the same exact things is it could be for
a couple reasons you know obviously it's
two different sides of the fence you
know they may not have the offensive
training you know skills this life hack
classes are expensive and you're really
just thinking offensive these always a
different mindset you know you know even
though the attacker the offender they're
playing the same space which is a
different way of thinking
and also sometimes the actor coals so to
speak you can I get the bad connotation
of people start thinking of Africa which
is to break my Network everything's
gonna go down where in actuality as
you'll see here a lot of this stuff is
really just you know mapping information
gathering things like that it's not you
know your remote code execution in those
things quick poll how many people here
operate on the blue team
it's all sweet and
it's kind of strange you know we'll be
who executes one to two week engagements
and in the course of those five to ten
days we'll know more about people's
network than some people
blues I know and so that's kind of
daunting right you go to the out
briefing you're like that they're like
well I don't even know those Network
Rangers in those web apps exist like and
so so we're trying to get these some
tools and tactics to kind of get the lay
of the land and it really valued your
network
a bit more
so it's under your blue teamers up there
I will seriously buy you a beer later
because your job is so much harder than
our job be a part of that like you said
we find stuff because you know that's
our job over there too but you are so
you know you so many things you have to
worry about the biggest thing is you are
just trying to find everything on your
network if you work for a big
corporation things like that there could
be stuff everywhere you know especially
if you're working University type
studies we do those where you have
students researchers they have the
freedom to come for a stuff on the
network and then it becomes your problem
and you have to worry about patching and
updating instructions and West level
patches it's all the little software
people are installing custom apps their
party stuff and you're just trying to be
consistent you're trying to you know you
might have like a standard base image or
something that everyone uses but then
you're gonna get the special questioning
at the CEO and whatever saying I want
this I want this music online whatever
you think you take a different policy
like that yeah you're in it not to
mention costs you know where everyone is
required notice we're always up against
you're probably not even here how does
the unlimited budget to do wherever you
want with so kind of have to pick and
choose what polls that give you the best
value
it finally you know kind of goes into
the whole political thing you know
security is always easy to trade off you
always you know I think it's getting a
bit better and I think that's just
because CNN is saying we're cracked
every day but you know you have to get
everyone to buy off on you know getting
a security card because some of them
isn't cheap and until something happens
people don't think it's important until
you get breached and something like that
so we know that's we're trying to put
about aim here that we can kind of maybe
give you some of these goals in these
tactics that and give you that leverage
down the line to have some political
capital or yes
so on the flipside and you know as an
attacker you know we'll talk about from
a high level you know what's an attacker
looking for they're looking for the same
thing they're trying to find what hosts
are on your network they're trying to
find what's out there your domain
structure you know are you a big ad shop
what groups are you or the abuses that
the fault is a custom this sorts of
things also a software patch you because
they're going to officer out they want
to know what patches you guys they can
exploit or what version of ie are you
running what version of Java are you
running those sort of things and it's
all to find this attack vectors those
exploitable conditions they can you know
find the way in your network and find a
way give it around and certainly you
know the attackers are there for a
reason they're after your consoles there
after to make money or to embarrass you
or to do something but it's not so much
it's just finding what your consoles are
that may be obvious depending on what
business you're in but it's also how to
get there an attackers always take that
path of least resistance you know they
might not be trying to break into your
database directly to see all the
information they're gonna for the router
network
and steal the DA's credentials and just
login so there's always this different
paths that if sometimes you're harder to
think about that that attack
and as you can see from kind of the list
on the last slide to the list I'm here
attackers and offenders are kind of
looking for the same informational of
time the whole inventory thing patch
cycles those sorts of things so that's
the other reason why we started doing
this presentation was to you know if
we're using the same tools to find this
stuff you know maybe defenders can use
the same ones as well
so some you know pros to hacking tools
this isn't inclusive to everything that
every happen tool out there obviously
some are little worse than others but if
everything we're talking about here you
know they're just going to be smaller
scripts you know it's not the big cops
product installation has to go on
everything this is just stuff you can
run with a Python or PowerShell are
things like that some even run it member
they don't even touched it is free is
awesome I think everything we talk about
is on github which is great it's that
straightforward easy to use you just
read the flies you kind of play with it
and kind of most importantly as I said
you know that hacker clothes kind of get
that bad connotation sometimes a lot of
the stuff we're doing here especially
the PowerShell stuff you know it's using
the valid system calls it's it's talking
to the main just as a user what are just
how you interact through your computer
it may be doing it in Vulcans in a lot
of the time but it's you know valid
calls its valid traffic which is good if
you maybe have to get some sign-off to
run some when your network usually this
will be a little bit easier because it's
all this stuff the bad side of it is the
package using it that's valid stuff so
you know your IDs is things like that
might not catch it
it's kind of a no web sort there yeah
and I have conversations with quitting
for the Chamber's a lot they say well
you know we don't have the budget we
don't have the political
and so these are our quick wins it's a
list of quicklinks
that are going to allow you to kind of
build some momentum within your
organization you'll find the information
you actually make changes to your
security posture hopefully enough that
if you have to invest money down the
line you're gonna have the you
won't be able to say I need this for
this right so you're gonna see kind of a
trend here for a lot of the lists we
operate as pen testers primarily in the
Windows environment and a lot of you are
saying okay well you know the crown
jewels are on mix boxes they're on the
databases that type of thing chances are
though most common way into an
organization this foot is spearfishing
and send an email a lot of people click
on emails people fix stuff all the time
they're not supposed to and so what's
gonna happen is when people click on
those emails chances are you're gonna
land on the windows box that windows box
is probably going to be the user land
space which is connected to a domain
environment which is a pen tester or an
attacker we can leverage to move around
your network get the access we need the
Linux the BB admins they're gonna have
Windows boxes that we can leverage to
just look directly in to those crowns or
Target boxes so that's kind of our
attack path that's that's what we use an
allotment because we are using valid
credentials are using valid calls and
things like that the blue teamers can
tend to be blind to our activity
that's why we're trying to educate you
on how we're doing it so
anybody's power show on their day to day
operations yeah so if you haven't jumped
at the power show yet I always saw a few
hands for Windows this has been a huge
step forward from the admitting side and
I always talk to people I say pen
testing is just admitting with a
different intent right everybody was
afraid when Windows 7 Windows 2008 came
out doing how all these memory
protections all the traditional buffer
overflows they're not going to work
because you know aslr and death and all
that Wow okay but then people started
hooking in the power show and seeing the
real power behind it and what you can do
with it and we've actually put together
on our team of library offensive tools
that we can use to carve through Network
pretty quickly there's a note here
cover real quick microsoft intended to
put up an execution policy in so that by
default
you can't just import your own scripts
and modules and things like that and
extend PowerShell functionality if you
just put that little flag there just
bypasses it off
so let's take a look at our arsenal some
of the stuff you might know and that's
been around forever
a lot of the tools here stuff we try
internally a lot of my guys right house
weight with the exception of PowerPoint
that's written by a different group of
people
Christian global of Mac braver
but nmap used for you know kind of
mapping out your network eyewitness
we'll talk about it's a screenshotting
service for your website's power sploit
offensive power so if power up is heavy
because we use that privilege escalation
heavily
Power View we use pretty extensively
kind of querying
talk about a lot of the features there
and then in res assess to kind of test
your memory
detection for data that lead
now we'll get into the fun stuff so
we're gonna go over kind of ten tactics
and they kind of follow a thief so you
know each one kind of has three things
there quick quick to run be generating a
lot of data for you and they're free as
we said most bees don't get up so our
Buller is kind of you know when you
combine those three things for each of
these that it's going to give you kind
of an immediate value you know we like
to say it's stuff that after this you
might be able to pull that together and
a script you might go to run this you
know if you have these your system in or
something you have overrun the soft
drinking your coffee daily weekly those
sorts of things and see some changes
there solid Jason start off here with
the acid
the biggest thing what's in your network
a lot of people are like I don't know
he actually they said we're going to use
your pen tests as our inventory
exercises
all right so kind of free cheap right
use nmap to conduct a network discovery
in your network you know how do you know
your range
hopefully you don't ask and there's put
a cron job out there every 25 hours do
hit and stay on your network what this
will do is over the course of a month it
will detect throughout the day changes
within your network there's going to be
some network on plates that you should
see a lot of change it's going to be
these Orlan trays people put their
computer asleep wake it up and all that
but there should be things that don't
change like your server on claims your
database on
if you do see Delta's there you can
script that bolero quick
as needed what we do once we find the
endpoints as we do a service detection
and we find out okay what TCP services
are available anything that comes back
that's come into web 84 for 380 those
types of things or what and that tells
us as a website we throw into a tool
called eyewitness written by Chris
Spencer bye guys and what it does is it
reaches out and it creates an inventory
of all those websites and it's in the
HTML document for each team
document and you can just quickly see
all the web applications within your
network these slides are going to be
posted so here's some syntax that you
can use both for endpoint identification
as well as service identification and
then we form a eyewitness there and
here's a screenshot real quick by
witness what it does is it summarizes it
to talk about its finding it does
attempt categorization between printers
and network appliances and potentially
highly vulnerable web servers and then
it also gives you a running inventory
here of a screen shot as well as the
little bit information about the request
okay so as Jason said earlier you talked
about spearfishing it was kind of the
most common attack better today it's
cheap wood all hate it but it kind of is
what it is so you imagine if you get
spear fish you know hundred people it's
different they're gonna lay in 104
places within your network you know
maybe we'll get a system it or something
like that probability losses know
they're gonna you know it's going to be
in the HR department it's going to be
and we're good whatever first thing that
the Tigers going to do is we're really
going to look at that base image and try
to find out what it is what's on there
and introspective or the patches and
things like that and they're gonna try
to escalate they're going to try to take
the basic user who clicked on that
phishing email whoever that may be
they're gonna try to you know get bigger
privileges it's just all so back to the
kind of consistency thing you may have a
consistent you know Windows baseline or
something that rolls health every suit
user this is you know how you want to
check that and you know a lot of people
say you know about every you know every
time you touch it that's great you need
to do that but that's just thing here
the windows stuff you're going back to
the third party touching it's the custom
apps you know things that are specific
to your business you might have develop
stuff the in-house that maybe just be
kind of running in at higher levels
things like that
do you have it is there's a one of the
power tools is called power pop-up mean
escalate
and what it does is it goes through all
of these baseline checks and it's really
looking and the phone call checks
function will check everything looking
at kind of screenshot you can see really
what it's doing it's good a new rating
every single service that's running on
there and it's gonna start checking
things like what does that service
running ads what are the permissions to
to run the service start and stop and
things like that where path is the
service in so you know this runs almost
instantly on a team a sign we suggest
that if you have maybe multiple
baselines you can make sure you're
running it on each but you know for
example the one that's highlighted here
you can see that this is 10 6 service is
horrible horrible service there too but
what that means is the path you know
that's a service of training at higher
level privileges and the normal users
shouldn't be able to mess with that
service but they can write to that path
so what you would do is you would take
make your own 10 6 malicious executable
replace that and a lot of these happens
services things like that they start on
the boot whatever eerie goods a machine
in limited sticky-fingered stickykeys
attack that's what this is reboots
machine that'll run your malicious
executable at that higher level
privileges and that usually gives you a
shell back at a different level stuff
one example from a desolation but this
tool just kind of goes through your
checks checks all of those if you're if
you're wondering first of all this is
not an intrusive it's just checking
stuff number two the
subjects are pretty well-documented
we're going to give you some resources
on what exactly checks work a lot of
this is just publicly available
information pen testers have been
talking about these these escalation
tactics for some time now we just made
it pretty quick and easy for you know
one powerful service
so the next kind of it is a favor one so
I want to show hands but somebody do you
know your whether your work you're like
somewhere you talk about Windows
Explorer and like you see like the
network button then you kind of click it
it you found a week to see everything
populate down anything like Joe's
computer you're like take a look at that
you know start like through people's
five minutes yeah the whole time yeah
but Tigers of investors do it too
because you find a lot of stuff in there
you know especially if you're a big
corporate environment you have file
shares everywhere because they're needed
you know people are doing projects
they're sharing stuff to the departments
I think Sogeti misconfigured I know one
of my favorite stories is we're on an
engagement and we got into this guy's
computer and it is drive to get an excel
file and honest to god it was like 350
lines long which is column a username
color B that's where column see what it
is and it's just like 10 credit cards my
3 bank accounts my retirement my domain
password you know just everything like
three of my eesti in it like everything
was on there you know bigger tips yeah
password book but you know that's his
personal stuff and obviously that can be
bad but you also think about if your
company's you know harboring any
sensitive is your made sensitive
information some proprietary stuff
things like that and so the next story
will show you it kind of looks for all
these file shares it is Power View which
is very powerful tool this specific
function is called invoke sheriff
sheriff finder and what it's doing is
when you run in this a partial script it
don't just query the domain in the
domain will be able to return and this
is a normal user do you know anything
elevated over user the domain will
return every single file share that it
has
computer additionally you can add the
check share access line and that's going
to check the current user you're running
against it's going to check to see what
user that has access to so we will
always run that and I'll show you with
the screenshot here and as you can see
it's kind of giving an illicit thing so
those are the things that the user is
running as the vouchers that he has
access to so this is also the demo
environment you know we highlighted
there's a secret over there that's
actually hidden so we'll all that hidden
folders as well but you know we've also
see a lot of things like you see a pin
dollar sign there your eyes that light
up because that means that you can that
user can absolutely remote to that
system and actually gain access to the
photo stone this is what I like to tell
you know gluten gluten offenders because
like I said there's so many shares out
there it's so hard to keep track and a
lot of people have access to different
things and you know it might not either
be it might just be you know the new
ones where we see a lot of floors where
they are configured nicely you know it's
only this user this is your this user
but then someone check everyone at the
bottom so just against everything that
they're trying to do and you know we
find ways like that and this is a big
way that attackers are using to fit
around the network for things
yeah the dollar sign yeah you're gonna
notice - this really comes down
within a subgroup within Active
Directory appeared you guys with
motherhood too
you're adding
to this year this tends to happen we
actually went into a pancreas
and we were able to see as a normal user
so somebody anybody may have any effect
on the email we could see although them
personal files of every employee because
what they did was they added all users
to the to the parent floor and so we
just jump up to the president of the
banks share and he had a just an excel
sheet of socials
tiii in all kinds of craziness it's like
yeah we need to verify our accounts that
are held by actual people for
regulations and it's like
and this is another one where you know
back to the check share access like if
your assistant you have this ability you
know make it user in each each different
group whatever groups you have within
your company and then run this to see
because it might not just be looking for
why the professor's you might also want
to check for to make sure that users in
this group don't get to see certain
things you know everyone a company
shouldn't be privileged to everything
they know where you are
so it's good to know who your admins are
especially if you have a complex Active
Directory setup you know depending on
the size of your organization right if
your organization has made acquisitions
right if they've bought companies and
just kind of merged Active Directory
infrastructure together and it's
Frankenstein setup sometimes it's really
hard to derive it through the look the
admins are right so it's good to know
that and again we talked about the
concept of nested groups power Channel
and the situational awareness tool
allows you to get the admin groups
it allows you to reverse these groups to
figure out who exactly is in these
groups that has access to what here's a
quick screenshot of that
but more importantly where are your
admins operating in your network
does anybody have a policy that says
okay if I'm an admin in the network I
need to have a regular user account
I'm privileged that I haven't supposed
to operate in yeah perfect so how many
admins actually adhere to that
oh good good presentations
chances are they don't right and so they
said well you know I I'm an admin I know
what I'm doing so I'm you know don't
worry about me but if as an attacker I
get access or I get one of those guys to
click on something my job becomes a lot
easier because I don't have to escalate
I already have added proofs on your
never
again how are you what we do is we do
this we perform this technique called
these are hunting highly documented by
little straighter but the purpose of
this is again however you reaches out to
your Active Directory infrastructure and
queries it says we're on my hosts
give me over the back and then it
reaches out those hosts and inquiries
and says who's logged on to this house
and then what you can do is you can say
okay if this person is in this specific
group and typically we're looking for
privileged terms like domain
or that or that's not bad that is that
type of thing if you're in a certain
group return from me the box standpoint
that this person's will have internally
and the name of the user so I know who
to target right as a blue team if you
want to know where these admins are are
kind of residing within your network
because if you get access to one of
these boxes you can use that access and
move throughout the network so you want
to make sure that these things are on
played up so you'll see things like file
servers
DC's that type of thing you want to make
sure that these are kind of protected so
it's a little bit harder for the
attacker to get there
so this is the equipment I'm not gonna
bore everyone in the room with password
policy overall most security people will
right here you know you have to probably
yell it your significant other your
mother your grandmother changer past
regimes most often but it can be hard in
a big environment to make sure you use
it or change their password sure that's
your policy sure you can for some things
and that's great you know but there is
also you know other things offer there
many systems that are under the radar
there may be things you people that are
excluded you know your your sea level
your board of directors you don't want
to deal with all your crap so you know
but they still change their passwords so
this is just a quick quick check to be
able to check for a you know last time
passwords were changed so nothing too
crazy here is you see the goodnight user
command which is part of Power View but
that's really just your standard net
user commands which enumerates
everything then it kind of gets piped
through a lot comes through there that's
really checking for it this this one you
can see the negative 12 meeting a year
12 months
checking for those accounts so when you
run it when it does that it gives you
kind of a nice listing of your entire
domain of usernames that have another
password changed within a year like I
said you know for the most part probably
take their calls to this is a nice way
to just check to make sure that nothing
is flying under the radar plus you see a
lot of like service accounts that were
pulled from this demo that's probably
true you're never because they're not
probably a policy adhering to your
policies your setup or they're not in
that and you know some of these may or
may not have to be changed but you know
service accounts can be just as juicy is
where
on some occasions who would be serviced
but I mean appliance the service it is
so and those are things that service
accounts can have going back to the
service checker to power up you know if
they may be running under specific
service account you know for whatever
some separate you know custom software
and they might have elevated privileges
so the Gantt point making tomato see
usually
now if some admins putting in like some
sort of like
Porter the enemy curve I just share some
global admin account which is great
so talking about domain trust there's I
think we can give a whole talk on the
main trust but again think back to the
concept of acquisitions right if
somebody and the company buys another
company and they're cooking there in
Active Directory infrastructures
together a lot of times to make work
right away but we would as attackers
will tend to see is still just global
trust each other and so what that means
is that an admin in domain a can then
become an admin and domain B and so if a
subsidiary is getting acquired and maybe
they didn't have as much money in it and
have as from a busted security posture
and the mothership is sitting there and
hook together and you can just ride into
the city and get out to the mothership
and they get the crowds to the
mothership and so that's that's how we
tend to operate again however you can do
this for you it has a function called
map domain trust and yeah these are all
just system calls to your Active
Directory infrastructure and you can
export a CSV but just in water
another one of my guys did is he figured
out a way to visually represent these
domain trusts using Socrates Hawaiian
it is great yeah
so what will 10 that happen is we'll
jump into like the core network you know
Spearfish in need to catch a Nina jumps
up to the mothership and then we might
jump it over to contracts and then just
ride trust down into another company
jump into the crown jewels eventually
right it takes a lot of kind of figuring
out where you are in the network and
typically and this is a little bit of a
longer term engagement but it can be
done and something like this is very
good to kind of present to your
management structure to figure out okay
you know what's what's talking with each
other
it's easy
the other thing is your domain
controllers in Active Directory tend to
be highly critical boxes within your
network also you know other high value
servers but who has local admin access
on your domain controllers sometimes you
know obviously your domain admins are
the enterprise Entenmann's in the domain
are going to have access to the
different domain controllers for the
house servers and things like that
but both will see on occasions will see
other people other you know Adam in soon
we find that some admins 10 available
easier than others they might just add
themselves to the local admin group on
the domain controller so instead of me
running around your domain
infrastructure if I know that I landed
via Spearfish on this specific admin I
might just try deploying into the DC
director
excuse me directly so it's good to know
all the different ways into your domain
controllers into your high value servers
again as an attacker I'm gonna take the
path of least resistance
just we you can also do this in power
view figure out your domain controllers
and you can figure out you can look at
the logo admin group here here's just a
quick screenshot of what you might see
so you might might be with my heart to
tell but you'll see you know domain
users versus local users here
so they started a job you're gonna
computer your desktop computer your
laptop you know obviously you log in you
log into that thing and all sorts of
things you know there's things on your
desktop you might already have a printer
set up they might be some option or set
up for you all that stuff that's being
set up with group policy preferences but
really what that suing is you know you
need your computer's gonna query the
domain the publicist fought for it's
going to look for these XML files those
containing all the actions needed to you
know whatever let's just say setting up
a printer you know it doesn't but some
of these okay need look like managed so
in that XML file over to see password
file containing an encrypted password I
think it's encrypted yes and then it's
they 64 thing and you computer brings
that down and it has a built-in
Microsoft think Krupke and if the
encrypted password and it runs the
administrative process did not even
upgrade anyone know the problem with
Alice
yes thank you
yes not just that but Microsoft
published that he to like tell like the
internet missed him yeah so attackers
lit up with that one and this is one R
using Mac rivers full power sploit
really what that's doing is doing
exactly what you computer just it's
gonna you know clear the domain look at
that stuff so for its going to pull all
the XML files is gonna look for anything
that says CPAP sir it's going to use the
key that is just built into the tool and
it's gonna start decrypting them and
here you can see where those T's live
you know it's some some passive
administrative options because those
needed to do the function because it's
an administrative function yes this has
been patched I think it was 14 and 25 M
s 40 no 25 exits so you know most people
are probably good with this now but once
again you know in Pentos we see
everything these plus the XP machine you
see mm so this is just a nice quick way
this kid Pete Bochy to be password to be
able to make sure that you know you're
rid of this denier entire demand
kinda Windows 2000 Fox in the pen sense
and the guy was like oh yeah we usually
unplug that whenever the auditors and
testers
what are you guys using for CD burning
great all right last ones a little bit
of it's a biggie especially with a lot
of their breeches that are happening
we've actually gotten a lot of interest
within the healthcare space most
recently about this but what you can do
but this kind of requires a little bit
of an infrastructure setup you can use
an Amazon free instance but you can use
a total coffee presses cents again
written by one of my guys then
essentially what it does is that's an
attacker once I get to the point in that
work where I know that I have access to
your crown jewels whether that's you
know patient data or if it's like
financial bank data or you know anything
that choose your poison what I want to
do is I want to test your egress
capabilities so I'm in your network I
want to see if you can do text instead
of data leaving your network and you
know I might try to be you know kind of
quiet at the beginning I'll wrap it in
these you know SSL and you know send
if you don't see that and I'll say okay
well I'll get an HTTP clear-text dude an
FTP oh you're still not seeing it more
negative the problem but we use this
tool for is to generate a bunch of data
fake data either credit cards socialist
you can generate as of last we generate
four identities fake identities random
user name first name last name address
social that type of thing and so what
you do is you set up an account of
border box maybe like I said in Amazon
and you set up the server piece and the
typeof a.load you want to drop it into
it so in this case it's going to be a
web server excuse me and then on the
client you know felt like you've been
doing it all along with the windows
powerful stuff is you can import the
PowerShell modules for egress success
and then specify the mode specify where
you're going to send the data to and
then the data
and hopefully when she sees this is a
screen china it's hard to see this is a
screen shot of snore B which is a
front-end restored you'll see an alert
pop and you'll see the data right so
this checks for two things right it says
okay what am I actually getting the
alert that I'm supposed to know okay
stop you know to yourself or if you are
getting the alert you have the process
in place to actually act upon this if
you actively see hex so happening within
your network are you in a position to
rapidly stop it and then eradicate
whatever is on that box that's causing
the in stone if no then we we have to
have
conclude here you know what did you
learn and don't say nothing at least off
my face we hope you take anything away
from this is that you know maybe you
know if you guys people out there there
are oh the Blues have a pension won't be
as scared as hyper tools or Mabel to
start looking into the hacker community
and start trying to pull down things at
MIT they make your life a lot easier you
know everything with the tactics I think
you know like I said before or trying to
make sure that they were quick they give
you a lot of data and they're free so as
you saw here a lot of these are easily
repeatable you may not want all the over
deal with them but you may be able to
take a couple with me they'll strip them
together even more like I said run it
running in the morning we're kind of
your morning coffee and a lot of these
is Jason I think kind of mentioned
before you know we're really exploiting
anything this wasn't you know safe it
was just you know domain weavers things
like that things on the network so what
they're really trying to do is just find
those misconfigurations because nowadays
you know the
external is getting smaller things like
that people are getting better with
patching you know still out there you
still have this you know splittable
conditions or you need that new new
grades remote kind of exploitation
whatever one of the times that attackers
are getting into the spear fishing
they're moving around their network
they're trying to find that one missed
configuration it's going to give them
that there's at the main item in it and
then we're just gonna walk in your
database or whatever it may be so our
goal here was to hope that these types
of will help kind of you know rid those
of your network and help find those
misconfigurations you want to get to the
point where we're not in our outbreaks
and as pen testers were asking the blue
team
well I didn't know that
simple point like a lot of this stuff is
such a situation anywhere it is and
gaining a deeper understanding of what
and finally like a lot of the operatives
to you know we have you know wall will
see a great IT crew but they may be like
three people deep into maybe this major
organization and they're just like we
just don't have time because I get
steady your job is hard and you have to
cover so much ground so we're hoping
that with this being freed and
repeatable that it maybe give you that
some of that leverage that you can maybe
take up the chain you can show your
bosses this you know look up you know
look at the holes we governor Network
and it's not a matter of just all I can
go fix them right now its we need
resources we need appliances detect you
know egress stuff things like that so so
I mean it let's take away from this is
you gather information to make immediate
impact you gain your political capital
do what you need to do
profit alright so again my name is Jason
Frank on Twitter is Jason J Frank we
have a whole bunch of stuff on our blog
Barriss group adaptive threat division
right there a lot of the write-ups and
things for how to really I we quickly
went over a bunch of these tactics but
for how to really jump into these
schools and extend the functionality
it's already not a bunch of use cases
are up there as well and then you can
actually get the tools most of our on
our site because a lot of our guys are
writing these things but then some of
the third-party ones as well questions
we're also someone
sure so the question was you're saying
that we need to isolate our high value
servers however a lot of these are
writing over SMB in Active Directory
calls which need to talk to the
endpoints anyway there's a couple
different ways to do that things that
I've seen our authentication firewalls
where you know in order to actually yeah
you can query the VC but actually in
order to log into the DC only certain
accounts are allowed to do that
the other thing that I've seen is
Microsoft and we can talk a little bit
offline about this but Microsoft has put
out this concept of a red forest and
essentially what this is is a it's a
domain set up that employees some
read-only type setups in that type of
I can't really jump into the specifics
but there's there's definitely ways to
kind of enclave off and not allow for
direct login access there
any other questions yep how is
configuration management like puppet and
chef helping prevent people from needing
to log on at all and have those
privileges on those boxes
if I I just probably like a little bit
and I think you know we talked to some
people that do that if I'm wrong you
know it's just certainly good if you can
get if it's fear involved and if you
have full control over things because
you're right if you can use puppet you
can you know everything's going through
that you know for a fact that every
machine can be configured the way you
want to configure it but I think a lot
of people they struggle at getting to
the point where either they have full
control over that they can make those
decisions or you know those sorts of
things where you know other people just
still need this they still need that
they can get everyone in the
organization to buy in the puppet or
those sorts of things so though is to be
multi policy of you something wrong with
your public configuration then you're in
trouble because then it's an Elena Falls
guy yeah what would stick to is you know
what make recommendations and we'll say
okay well if there aren't things that
you can do but what ends up happening
for a lot of the environments that
- is there not or not I'm healing setup
yes and then exist yes there are other
controls out there that you can put on
it's a function of time budget that type
of thing but
yeah I mean cupboard assembly instead
for
you know what
thanks for the time