hi how's everyone has the conference
good awesome today Rob and I will be
talking about social engineering we'll
be doing kind of a share we talking
about the psychological aspect of social
engineering why we're so terrible at
defending against it and some of the
techniques that we can use rubb we'll be
talking about yeah I want to talk about
some experiences that we had during
social engineering engagements that
really were inspired this talk because
it got the the notion that quite a few
organizations were just giving up they
didn't really want to do social
engineering engagements because they're
like well we know that someone can get
in we're going to focus all our
resources elsewhere and just kind of
ignore the fact that we know someone an
organization could be coerced into
running a malicious payload or could be
tricked into giving their password to
someone but before we get into that
actually wanted to ask when you're here
is performed social engineering
assessments before okay a few people um
who's been a victim of social
engineering are you sure ah who has a
concern that their organization may be
or may have already been a victim of
social engineering attacks okay almost
everyone yeah so the the inspiration for
this came from kind of some of those
experiences but also while I was in the
shower listening to the foo fighters
like heard this lyric and I thought
about the pretender which made me think
of social engineers and also the never
surrender that that's really where the
inspiration for this game because so
many organizations really were kind of
giving us that that feedback that they
had given up and didn't want to didn't
really know what to do to protect
themselves against social engineering
and the other aspect of this was not the
pleasure an opportunity to work with one
of the best social engineering talents
in the industry which is Christina
so I kind of wanted to team up with her
and and put this together so just some
short introductions I'm Kristina I'm
actually from Australia i moved to San
Francisco a month ago upon entering
Pittsburgh I saw my first white-tailed
deer and my first lightning bugs all
yesterday which has been a new
experience for me I've participated in
the DEF CON social engineering CTF three
years in a row and I've won high scoring
recent report for two of those I wanted
to mention that she's basically going
for as many rings as the Steelers but
with DEFCON CTF challenges will tell you
later um sorry what was I gonna say next
I work as a pen tester and social
engineering has been an interest of mine
for many years admission Fox yeah we we
both work at an organization called
Bishop Fox that helps organizations
secure their applications networks and
data and my name is Rob I am a
pittsburgher I was born and raised here
I live in Atlanta now but I really
started into my hobby and then
eventually my profession with security
right here at PA 2600 meetings over at
the pit Student Union about 12 years ago
and actually there's some familiar faces
here and I don't know if it's from other
conferences or if it's from Pittsburgh
security stuff or just like my curse of
a photographic memory but um come ask me
my IRC handle unlike the PLP I 2600 and
pound some work on channels maybe we
know each other cool so let's get into
it let's get our hands dirty as always
I'll start with a definition of social
engineering for anyone that doesn't know
this definition is taken from social
engineer org and is defined as the act
of manipulating people into performing
actions or divulging confidential
information and I like to think of
social engineering as a blend of science
psychology and art it taps into basic
human emotions and it looks at why we
react
the way that we do when I talk about
social engineers I like to explain them
as people that study people truly
committed social engineers will study a
lot about body language voice control
vocal indicators and group dynamics it's
also a study of introverted individual
personality types that come out through
body language and vocal cues a more
simple definition of social engineering
would be an exploitation of trust it's
someone who can leverage a trust of
their victim to gain access to sensitive
information or resources or to elicit
information about those resources the
use of social engineering is successful
because it preys not on technology but
on the inherit weakness of the human
component and this is done by
manipulating the human victim with
messages that can exploit your trust
pick your interests and desires and
evoke a strong range of human emotions
such as fear anxiety trust human
interest and reward but to make this
very very simple we are professional
liars social engineers are people that
can lie and get something that yeah
specially gonna say that like being
charming is another way that you can put
it and that's not really a compliment if
someone calls you charming if the true
definition of that is actually very like
sly and sneaky not like you rub when
people are vulnerable people are lazy
people want to be helpful and people
want to be nerdist making this field and
especially enticing target or making
people especially enticing target as a
really simple example of this we can
spend hours weeks or months to train a
brute force our way to a password when
crafting the right pretext or sorry when
a phone call with the right pretext and
the right questions can get you the same
information or more in a matter of
minutes
and that's exactly it social engineering
is the path of least resistance it's the
low-hanging fruit so utilizing
techniques such as planning the right
pretext sorry pretext is like creating
and using a contrived scenario
exploiting someone's trust and appealing
to sounds emotions often results in
obtaining the same piece of information
it it's almost unbelievable or you can
achieve by simply posing looking we're
looking like someone else this is
something that we're both very
passionate about I think that as an
organization how many people in here are
information security professionals okay
that's what I thought just wanted to
make sure I was recently on a panel at
interop out in Las Vegas and the first
person that kind of kicked off the
conversation said users are our biggest
problem if we could just get rid of the
users that we'd have no more problems
and I just leaned it and I was like I
disagree i think that that's really
deferring the blame and we as security
professionals it's it's our job to help
I don't even like calling them users
their people that's like kind of even
demeaning calling them users ah it's
adrian and porter felt she's the head of
security for chrome user security for
chrome and so she has to deal with a lot
of folks that don't really care what ssl
is they don't they have no idea no
inclination no motivation to understand
ssl warnings or even what that acronym
means so it's our job as security
professionals to help the firefighters
and the blog babysitters and the
grandmothers of the world know that they
can use the internet and still be safe
and striking that balance between
usability and security is I think one of
the biggest challenges but I would like
to stop having the notion that users are
our biggest problem and
just start coming up with some technical
controls and some changes to our
policies and our processes and how we
interact with people to address the the
issue and I'm continuing on from rubs
point controlling humans is difficult
because it's beyond technological
control and absolutely subject to human
nature and because we can't put controls
on the way each individual thanks making
this a very very challenging aspect of
security to handle again to keep this
simple people are the root of all evil
and we are the reason for all security
issues and this is because there is no
patch for human stupidity how long do i
wait for everyone to read the coming
most people probably seen this before in
your head this is where I go take a
drink when you combine people with
technology you will encounter problems
humans are unreliable technical systems
when we think about technical systems
they're reviewed their scanned their
penetration their pen tested sorry I
don't like seeing penetration tested but
how about people how do we measure
vulnerabilities in people and the answer
is we don't at least we don't do it
effectively we like to make people feel
shameful we like to pass blame we like
to ignore the problem while not doing
anything to help to really help the
situation and an on this note I actually
had a client tell me well a couple
clients tell me once that they did not
want to do a social engineering test
simply because they knew that they would
be vulnerable and then this is
absolutely not the right attitude to
have
and when I thought about why the client
reacted this way I thought well we don't
like to do this testing because it makes
us feel vulnerable and we don't like to
feel vulnerable and when you combine
people with technology you get this big
blob of mess and the fact that people
are really unreliable means that we need
to come up with just a whole new
approach and I think there's a lot of
technical controls that are
underutilized there's a lot of the whole
going back to the shaming and blaming
approach I've heard so many clients that
that's their that's their mindset going
into solving this problem and it it
doesn't work I've seen it seen it tried
over and over again so it becomes our
job to try to convince them to take it
to take another route and to really
assess what their goals are and then
really ask themselves is is shaming and
blaming your employees or your your
co-workers going to help the situation
so what Rob saying is people are
unreliable and we can't rely on just the
human aspect to fix this problem and
this is because again people fall victim
to basic psychological and physical
needs and people can be easily
manipulated and persuaded I like to give
the example of the sea aldini six which
are six useful frames when it comes to
social engineering and this affect your
persuasion and those can be broken down
into authority so we tend to be
influenced by authority positions liking
we're influenced by those that we like
social proof we look to others to
determine good behavior scarcity our
value is tied to our availability
reciprocation so we feel like we have an
obligation to return what other people
provide so just like favors
commitment and sorry i miss Cassidy
Cassidy did I say I did say scarcity
social proof is the one I missed differ
all right sorry I'll just go to the last
one and commitment and consistency so we
are pressured to remain consistent with
prior engagements I did okay I can't
count she also stayed up all night
working on these slides and didn't sleep
so Shh I I spent all week working on
these I did not leave it to the last
minute him so let me tell you a story
this is one of my favorite stories at my
previous job on an engagement I had I
had posed as an internal employee for a
law enforcement agency and I did some
recon dances recon insists on this
person or the person I chose as my
target and after doing some research I
found that she was on holidays at Hawaii
and I found this on her Facebook and
from this information i crafted a
pretext on the information that I knew
and that is that she came back early
from her holiday buildings a pretext
sorry she tell them what a pretext to a
pretext I think I mentioned it before
but a pretext is like crafting a
scenario that you were going to follow
when you do a social engineer engagement
so in this sense a pretext sorry the
pretext that I created for this scenario
was that I came back early from her
white her holiday to Hawaii and that I
needed to urgently finish a report from
my manager and that was the story that I
created for this scenario and from this
story I had created a sense of urgency
and when you create that sense of
urgency they were naturally inclined to
help and from there while I was on the
phone impersonating this person I had
managed to get ahold of the IT
department using the same sense of
urgency and praising them for being so
helpful I said to the person on the
phone let's call him Rob hey Rob I
really really need to finish this report
but I know I've forgotten both my domain
and my email passwords because I've been
on holidays
I'm so so sorry can you please help me
out and what was most surprising is that
I got exactly what I wanted which were
both passwords read over to me read to
me over the phone with absolutely no
cross-checking that I was who I actually
said that I was apart from me being the
same gender as her and what was the most
amusing is the guy said I'm not supposed
to do this but and gave me both
passwords he had also asked me what I
wanted to set it to you and I said or
Mike I'm sorry it's a rub I've been on
holidays and i'm still in holiday modes
can you please set it to something
simple and he said okay sure i'll set it
to password one but I pull a dollar sign
in front just to make it a little bit
more secure thank you rob but the point
of this story is that this works because
most people trust others by default and
respond to social rewards well many
people especially customer service
agents help desk receptionists and
business assistance or even secretaries
who were trained to assist people and
not to question the valid a look the
validity of each request tend to trust
others and I'm naturally helpful that's
worth two factor right oh yeah sorry I'm
sorry forgot to mention that before i
got my passwords read to me over the
phone he asked for my TF a token i put
the phone down and i went into the
background i made lots of noise as if i
was looking through my knowledge for
about two minutes i came back to the
phone and said Rob I've looked
everywhere I've turned my luggage inside
out and I cannot find my two-factor
authentication 2fa token so they did
have the right technical controls in
place by bypassing this through
psychological means avoided all of that
and following on from that I'd also like
to mention that this is this inherit
trust that we put into social media it
was because she posted that she was on
holidays on social and media in the
first place that I knew how to craft
this pretext did you have a question yes
so this was back in Australia when I
worked in Australia and she was
Australian and I am Australian yeah oh
sorry still me so let me show you how
this worked or a very simple attack
model of this story I just told so we
really just need to can you even see
that not really gather the right
information develop a relationship with
whoever your target is be it through
small talk or a common interest
exploiting that trust and executing your
attack now I can hand it over to rob
enough about the fluffy stuff barb is
going to talk about what we're doing
wrong yeah and that scenario arm it was
nice that there was two factor
authentication but the fact that there
was no process to authenticate the
person over the phone and it was merely
a christina was able to create this
sense of urgency to coerce the gentleman
on the other line to give not only a new
password tour but also a new 2fa token'
value and then allow VPN access into a
law enforcement agency so let's go into
what we're doing wrong it really is
almost everything we have users watch
training videos they do elearning
modules on they tick boxes and there's
posters hanging up in the office but I
think that helps folks feel good about
themselves from a security awareness
training perspective
but what we're seeing as consultants
that are hired to repeatedly perform
these types of assessments is that that
these techniques are not working at all
but organizations are still repeating ly
putting more and more resources into
these types of security awareness
campaigns and i think that the big
takeaway that we hope they have after
some of the things we'd like to show you
next is that there are other things that
we can spend our time and resources on
besides more computer-based training and
and posters around the office saying
don't don't trust christina when she
calls you so some of the things that
I've noticed from or different
organizations that we perform social
engineering on is that they tend to fail
with how they track their social
engineering assessments the frequency
that they're doing security awareness
training is also a concern and the
conditioning of their the members of the
organization so let's get in a little
bit more details tracking stop tracking
clicks the number of clicks that occur
in a social engineering campaign I
haven't really seen be as useful as as
folks would hope tracking by Department
is something that we've been asked to do
as well because as if there's some type
of statistical correlation between the
number of people in the sales department
that click versus the number of people
in the Executive Board group or the
people in marketing or recruiting
division I don't know why a graph that
shows that is helpful because
statistically the sample size was
probably not big enough to make any type
of valuable correlation out of that and
we can say that we've done this enough
times that it doesn't matter we get
senior network system administrators to
click on fishing scenarios we get every
type of employee it doesn't matter
and all we need is one in most cases to
compromise an internal network in a lot
of old social engineering engagements
I've had in the past I had a lot of
clients come up to me and ask for the
people's names after an engagement so
they wanted if I had a pool of 20 people
also and six of them fell for the social
engineering engagement that come up to
me and say Christina can you give me the
names of departments of the people that
fell fell for the social engineering
engagement and this is not the right
attitude to have you do not want to
victimize anyone you do not want to
create a paranoid culture and I always
refused on the phone I said no sorry I
will not hand over the names for the
social engineering engagement because
you have to understand that this problem
is on a company level not an individual
basis you cannot pass blame onto people
for this for these sort of engagements
all the time that's a good question sir
have you been social engineered into
giving those results I like we have
given those results to some clients that
really it was a part of their motivation
to address it on the personal level but
that again was an exercise where they
spent time and resources on coaching an
individual when I guarantee you we can
just pick 20 more people to target and
we'll get half of them to click as well
and then what do you do you just go to
talk to every single person and train
them one by one and try to make them
terrified of of everything that they do
with computer resources and on their job
what I would suggest instead and I've
not I'm not just suggesting this because
I think it's a good idea I've seen it
work there's some organizations that are
more mature i would say on how they're
handling these issues and we've had the
fortunate perspective to see what works
and what doesn't work and tracking the
successes has been tremendous for a
couple of organizations that we work
really closely with what i mean by that
is rather than tracking the clicks or
how many people were were compromised
track the number of people that reported
an incident
because our best hope in defending
against these types of attacks is going
to be our incident response plan that is
specific to social engineering attacks
and at that point whenever you take the
charts and graphs to the executives that
are sponsoring the security budget your
charts going to be going up ideally
rather than going down rather than
trying to get the number of people that
clicked to go down which is going to
fluctuate what for example one
organization that we worked with a we're
using like a service like fish me that
does teachable moments you send up big
pool of emails they click and then it
says hey you this was actually fishing
here's some training on why you
shouldn't have done what you just did
which is all fine and well and they were
doing it every quarter for three years
and with varying a number of emails that
they sent because with that bit with the
fish meat business model you have to pay
per email that sent and they started out
with a few hundred started ramped it up
to a few thousand they eventually on the
last one that I reviewed with them send
an email to every member of the
organization through this fishing
campaign eight thousand people at this
organization how many do you think still
clicked after three years of quarterly
training on this any guesses a thousand
one-eighth still clicked so there's a
lot of time and resources sure no
Oh
they their internal security team made a
really nice Prezi presentation that they
would deliver to the different business
units that they thought needed more
attention that would help raise
awareness of all of the types of attacks
that they are commonly targeted with
isolated a media organization and they
do a lot they have a lot of politically
motivated threats that are targeting
their employees they have a lot of
celebrities that work at their
organization and they are explicitly
targeted for their personal information
and having 8,000 employees in an
organization like that and a finite
budget for their security team and very
very motivated attackers became a you
know that fortunately they actually did
even they have a finite budget it's
still pretty large compared to most
organizations and so they it it just
that was part of their package was like
let's fish me everyone every quarter
just because we can afford that but I
compare that with another organization
that's also very large and I saw them
tracking the number of incident response
submissions and basically so creating a
culture in an environment where rather
than try to go give more training to the
people that are clicking more they were
rewarding the groups that were reporting
more incidents you know so ideally that
awareness training that's being
performed should feed into this strong
incident response plan that is
specifically geared for social
engineering how many people in here have
a detailed incident response plan that
the exercise regularly at the
organization good on how many have one
that's very specific for social
engineering for like a fishing campaign
or for a phone based social engineering
physical some folks some are some
organizations one of our clients that
they're another media organization
actually they have to worry about bomb
threats and people bringing guns and
knives in and they have like kids on
field trips in their organization every
day and they worry about very serious
physical threats but they don't worry
about the geek like me that walks in and
plugs in something into the network well
Jack in the hallway that is in the
elevator lobby that's on a VoIP phone
that still connects into the internal
network that's behind that locked door
but well this is kind of quintessential
to some of our recommendations and
takeaways from this presentation is
having a plan specifically for social
engineering can put a organization in a
much better position to react whenever
these types of attacks do occur i also
have an issue with the frequency that
some organizations do awareness training
again I think it's a time and resources
matter and maybe your organization has a
lot of resources to put into awareness
training but I think there's actually
there I found quite a few there's
actually Harvard Business School
research paper on the amount of
diversity training your organization
does starts to have diminishing returns
and actually the opposite effect on
people's mindsets the more you kind of
shove diversity training down their
throat I think the same thing happens
with security awareness training and I
want to tell a story about an
organization that asked us to do very
frequent training and it really tried to
convince them otherwise but the other
thing was the conditioning aspect the
negative reinforcement and and rather
than rubbing the people in the
organization's nose in this problem like
they're a dog and like demeaning and
degrading them for clicking on a fishing
link which very well anyone could make a
very very convincing email or very very
convincing web application and some
people are very tricky and can talk you
into doing almost anything over the
phone I think using positive
reinforcement to if the person the
organization reported that incident
track that reward them and make them a
good example for others to follow and I
think if we're asking how can we get
organization on the defensive against
social engineering it's making reporting
these incidents easy making it the
default behavior and making it rewarding
so another story was specifically around
a
an organization that came to us and
wanted us to develop their social
engineering defenses for the customer
support representatives they had 4,000
approx customer support representatives
around the world some of them local to
the US some of them in India some other
offshore areas and some are just entire
external third parties that they don't
have a lot of control over what goes on
inside those those organizations other
than what their legal team can get into
a contract so arm currently they were
kind of training and simulating se
scenarios when they came to us on an ad
hoc basis and they were had some
incidents they had attackers calling in
and coercing customer service
representatives into giving them access
to personally identifiable information
access to customer accounts and on top
of that they were regularly receiving
emails that were actually a phishing
scam so that was like risk number one as
they're describing to me all their
problems I didn't have a risk number
ones you're already having these
incidents you're already getting these
regulatory phishing scam emails and
these emails would prompt them to reset
their passwords on regular occurrence
and then kind of trick these
representatives into giving up their
passwords the second risk identified
from the problems they were describing
was that they were occasionally getting
malware infections on the customer the
CSRs terminals just for not they
probably weren't even sure how that was
happening they just would they're
incident response was just to image it
not really get to a root cause analysis
of why that was happening and the there
was kind of a lot of different problems
that they were describing and they
wanted us to do monthly security
awareness training it's basically
sending phishing emails and sending and
doing phone calls on a monthly basis and
then their plan was to fire repeat
offenders and I they had a new see so
join recently and I know that she was
actually firing heads of departments
because in the security unit because
they didn't have a good relationship
with the other business units and she
felt that they couldn't
anything effectively done because they
had the reputation of will steamroll you
or will go around you or will you'll get
fired if you don't do what security says
and that was creating all kinds of
office politics that I think we had
identified as consultants that I've been
working with them for a while so we're
basically tried to recommend a
multi-phased approach that involved
doing some social engineering and
security awareness training but perhaps
monthly was overkill until they had some
other plans in place to review those
terminals that the customer service
representatives were using like asking
policy questions like why do they have
internet access do they really need
access to everything can we just give
them an iPad to surf the internet on if
they're bored at work in between
customer support calls can we whitelist
every application and software that runs
on those systems as well and detect any
anomalies and abnormal behavior to
prevent that risk of the malware
infections that were occurring on a
regular basis can we redesign the
security questions that they use as the
authentication process whenever
customers call in and say that they need
to change their address or change their
phone number or change the billing
update the billing information on their
account are they really doing a good job
of or do they know that there's websites
out there that you can pay 99 cents and
get anyone's social security number with
just their name and their maybe one
address that they've had in their life
so kind of bringing that some of those
to lighten and asking them to take this
approach where we use social engineering
as the tip of a spear integrate that
with penetration testing of some of
their internal applications and the
applications that the customer support
representives rely on a regular basis
reviewing their incident response plan
and how they're going to handle us
incidents that were already happening on
a regular basis there what there was no
specific incident response plan for it
and really analyzing what their plan was
for the their people their processes and
their policies are related to social
engineering flowing that into what
enterprise security technical controls
can we implement and we have actually
like a list of 12 of them that I want to
want to get into would you talking a
little bit more about some of the
technical controls and defenses around
like well I pull this up sorry about
like what you see
it's your decks
I'm just going to wait for you to pull
these up I can tell Don story dude all
right I'll tell another story in the
meantime I wanted to in this
presentation talk a little bit about the
trust that we put in social media and at
the Def Con and social engineering CTF
one of the challenges was we got a
fortune 100 company and sat a dinosaur
my company was was bowing and the goal
of this CTF was there was a list of 35
questions that you had to answer and
they ranged from whose the garbage
disposal company to getting someone
internally to click on a link that you
sent them and the way that I did this
was I created a very fictitious
character called naomi wolf and naomi
wolf was completely fabricated she did
not exist in real life but fur Naomi I
created her a fake facebook fate
linkedin fake Twitter and over a few
weeks I built up these profiles i added
people from boeing who worked their
managers co-workers everyone that i
could get ahold of just through social
media and and after a few weeks i found
that the job was doing itself i started
getting friend requests linkedin
requests from people that worked for the
company i actually got a manager that
worked for boeing messaging me on
facebook and say hey Naomi how's your
internship sorry so I was posing as an
intern an aeronautical engineer intern
and he messaged me saying Naomi how are
you enjoying your internship thus far I
would love to meet up with you and get
to know you and get some feedback on our
internship program and I thought that
was absolutely frightening that this
this person that I created completely
from like this person I completely made
up in just a few weeks she was
considered to be a real person a real
employee that worked for Boeing and
using those connections I was able to
get people to click links that I had
crafted I was able to get payroll
information i was able to get a lot of
internal information about the company
just because people thought I worked
there
yeah I've more stories yeah question
so I also had another slide on genders
and I get this question all the time
every time I do a social engineering
presentation I I get a question so it's
because you're female isn't it and the
answer is no so both genders have their
their benefits and some syrup to to give
some examples I did some studying and i
found that females were terrible at
posing in authority of positions in
higher positions like managers ceos and
technical positions so any time I tried
to pose as someone that knew what she
was talking about technically or someone
that was trying to give authorities
sorry that I was in authority position
and tell other people what to do that
did not work out well so so males have
the advantage in this case and also on
physical social engineering engagements
females couldn't dress up as like
engineers or auditors or people that
came in to fix something or take the
garbage disposal away males have the
advantage here as well so it's utilizing
your gender and the benefits that come
along with those both genders have their
yeah positives and negatives I would
agree with that I just with a change in
the tone of my voice can affect the way
that people are listening and it's it's
very effective over the phone whenever
you are pretending to be a manager from
the IT department you're asking someone
to help get their system up to date and
install a patch on it and they're their
systems the only one that's that's not
up to date in their department and
getting them to go to a website that
looks like it belongs the organization
that has fake green progress bar saying
has this patch has this patch has this
patch and then a red one that says oh
you're missing this one just click
download and put that on there and then
we'll get you a compliant I've even had
members of the organization say well is
this legit
and basically using some of their a they
would then go on to tell me that they
recently went through security awareness
training and I kind of use that against
the organization even instead well yeah
we were following up with not only
making sure you did the security where
nurse training but also that your
computer has all the patches installed
we can't get the automated deployment to
deploy but I'm feeling kind of ill today
I didn't have to come by your desk and
now and get you sick as well so if you
could just do this over the over the the
web app that we set up for it would be
save a lot of time and then they just
want to be helpful so I wanted to show
you what i have found to be yeah so I'm
sorry for the text blob some of the
these like that kind of top 12 things
that I found that work well and would
really put a hampering on what we do
when we're performing these social
engineering assessments and I'll walk
through these and explain what we mean
an alias for reporting incidents this is
goes back to making it easy to four
members of the organization having like
stranger danger at example.com so that
whenever someone thinks they got a
phishing email they can just forward it
to stranger danger and there's someone
on the other end in the security team
that's ready to review and respond to
them and say maybe even automated
message like we are currently looking at
this and we were planning on letting you
know as soon as possible what the next
steps are implementing since 2006
there's there's been some things that
prevent email spoofing right now from
our research ninety-nine point nine
percent of the lexa top 1 million allow
email spoofing and that means we can
send likely an email from the CEO of
your organization to any member of your
organization and it would appear in
their inbox just as that person and
asking them to do whatever we want and
there are things like SPF that a lot of
organizations have in place and the
stands for sender policy framework but
it actually is it doesn't work unless
you also have D command D mark and that
we found that a lot of organizations
don't know that they think that they've
set up the sender policy framework which
is a white list of IP addresses or
domains that are allowed to send an
email from your organization but it
doesn't work without some of the signing
and crypto components that are in D
command D mark that almost no one has
implemented and therefore it still is
possible to spoof email from most
organizations this one's probably a
little bit overkill for most
organizations but maybe you're a
military organization or a
law-enforcement organization and
removing the HTML from your email
automatically takes away a lot of tricks
an attacker can use up their sleeve that
involve spoofing links hiding links
hiding information in an email or making
it look like it's got the letterhead of
your organization and it really
eliminates a lot of tricks that we use
in our email spoofing I'll stay in
boxing the the browser or the email
client can also help sandboxie is one
that actually every person that uses a
Windows machine at our organization also
utilizes that basically forces all
changes that are made to the system from
anything that's running on the sandbox
to be done on a copy of that on the file
system or any like registry changes that
something may make that may be
downloaded in your browser or any file
system changes that actually made to a
copy of that file that you can clean up
and throw away if it was something
malicious or something that caused
damage browser plug-ins one of the
organization's we not want I've multiple
that we've targeted have been using
things that actually harm mature enough
that they have all their customer
service representatives on mac mini's
running chrome with no script and other
other security extensions that are
really making it more difficult for us
to compromise a member of their their
csr team with social engineering tactics
having an organization wide web proxy
that tracks every URL that was visited
is instrumental in instant
response we're going to weave a
financial institution that we had
repeatedly year after year compromise
with social engineering got a little bit
wise to actually being able to implement
in their incident response plan to go
into websites and look at once they had
the incident reported we maybe we
registered a fake website or flight
domain and then once that was reported
they were to go see every user name and
work station ID that visited that URL
and then treat that as now part of the
incident response and they called us up
and they said was uh was this email with
this don't link to this domain you guys
yep did you in fact Jessica so-and-so's
computer only yep all right okay we feel
we feel better this year we found it and
it was because they had that
organization wide web proxy although
users were going through and they could
track down the every user that click the
link and then go and reimage their
machine and force them to change their
password even they also started setting
up things where they would alert on
domain names that contain their
organization's name in the domain and
they actually thought that it was us
registering some but it was actually
another part of the organization that
they weren't aware of registering some
new domains and Rob fuller moob Ock's
actually talks about like these attacker
ghost stories and one that he he shared
was not only taking the list of all the
domains that you know that may be
variations or typos of your domain or
replacing the letter o with 0 and things
along those lines taking that list and
even don't even necessarily have to
alert on or register all those domains
although if you have the resources you
might as well but you can put them in
internal dns entries and then have your
internal users go to a site that says
hey this was probably a phishing attack
or you made a typo because we don't have
a zero in our domain name please report
this incident if you received an email
that coerced you into going to this link
customization of authentication
processes this is something maybe your
bank does where they make you pick a
picture to recognize when you're logging
in can help prevent social engineering
as well or fishing basically if the
attacker has does not have a piece of
information it's almost in that sense a
element of two factor authentication
it's something that they don't know but
you do you pick the picture of the race
car when you're logging into your bank
and if you don't see that there then
it's not really your bank's website
application whitelisting would be having
a list of all the approved apps that a
customer service representatives machine
needs to run and if you see anything
else pop up that's bad news bears and
some of the basic defense in depth
techniques that we're talking about
earlier today encrypting data in transit
and at rest to mitigate the risk of an
already compromised machine or a
compromised application from pilfering
other sensitive data one of the
financial organizations we work with a
and force that whenever their users take
their laptop home they can't connect to
the internet without going through the
corporate VPN and then they can still do
the things like monitor the web traffic
through a web since the proxy and make
sure that they are kind of overseeing
what what websites that go to on a
corporate issued laptop and basically
performing regular social engineering
assessments for the purpose of training
the incident response team more so than
training the users I always ask whenever
we start out on scoping for a social
engineer engagement is your motivation
to for this to get a better idea of
security awareness levels at your
organization or is it to get an idea of
how well you'd send responses for social
engineering and often they say both but
I think a trend towards spending more
time training the incident response team
than trying to Train everyone in the
sales marketing or recruiting
departments who can caneel a lot better
return on investment
time
yeah sorry I didn't mean to knock
posters too much I just I do think
there's value in security awareness
training I think gamification and I
think you may have some comments on this
is a great way to make it rewarding and
make it somewhat competitive even maybe
between co-workers to be the best at
reporting social engineering incidents
and I think that depending on that it's
really got any custom the
recommendations but depending on your
organization if you're an organization
has a very small security team and very
limited finite budget you may want to
only do the minimum amount of training
that's required for compliance she may
have a different opinion all right great
this talk was not meant to sound like
you should forget about the human aspect
absolutely you should still consider
training humans but there's also
technological controls that you need to
consider you cannot rely on a human
because like I said three lated we fall
victim to psychological attacks and
again gamifying security awareness
training try to make it fun don't make
it a paranoid culture don't make people
bored of like reading your e-learning
module with this clip art and tick boxes
you need to make it fun you need to make
it engaging you need to make the end
user want to do this training or at
least not hate doing the training yeah
it's going to say as pen testers we're
often required to still do the the
training before we're allowed to use
that internal domain account and oh man
have seen some really bad ones ones that
I can just keep cooking the multiple
choice until lets me through or just
like disassemble the flash and go to the
end link that says yep you completed it
here's your certificate but it my
training so we can do better than that
if you are going to be training at least
make sure that you're measuring the
effectiveness of it a lot of
organizations I've asked them was like
what how are you measuring the
effectiveness of your training and like
huh we just do it I just remembered
something very interesting that someone
said to me last time I presented on this
topic and that is when you get a
phishing email or went all sorry when
you get an email or a phone call that
makes you want to react in some sort of
psychological way like something that is
creating a sense of urgency something
that is a
to your desires just stop and think for
a second saying why does this person
need this information from you right now
what emotions is appealing to me so if
it seems fishy at all think about what
the email is asking or what the person
over the phone is asking from you in a
psychological sense so I hope that makes
sense yep we didn't sleep last night
sleep dinner was good
we have a hundred percent success rate
of at least getting one person to fall
victim to our campaigns and one is all
we need and it's really kind of it's
rough to be on the other side of that be
on the defensive side and say like I
have this Hydra of attacks like coming
at my organization and I like can cut
off one head but that the six other ones
still got me but I really would like to
see it treated as a finite resource
problem say okay I have X amount of
people I have X amount of dollars in my
budget here's what I'm going to do with
it here's my priorities and here's i'm
going to mature my organization security
so i can sleep better at night as a
defender and say that I got my
organization this this year to implement
spfd Kim and demark properly so now at
least attackers can't spoof email from
our organization and that's their
progress and then they can show that to
their management and say we did good
we're making progress
we did
sure um and and it really is it's kind
of funny because we work with a lot of
different industries we work with a lot
of different sizes of organizations from
fortune 100 to startups and really have
to be cognizant of this above you're
gonna be able to do here and now and
here's what we should we should hire you
know for these these guys did you forget
we have one more celeb
yeah I think
we're seeing a lot of organizations
actually want to outsource their there I
are there is a response even to us and
lungs like we at a decline because we
all have the expertise in-house to take
I think I trend we're seeing is just a
outsourcing get some of its an expert in
into their response and
out of the organization I one more
really cool side of the show that
question I could
yeah I
someone earlier reading this book on how
to lie with statistics it's a very old
book like from the written my twenties
or thirties
maybe it's a product of it actually is
the attitude the organization is really
helping me for the better amazed pitched
in the presentations to management but
the organizations that I see that are
tracking their Incident Response
successes they feel much better please
they're still getting compromised
remediation they're able to do a lot
better analytics on what should we
change what technical controls may help
what policies may help what processes
are broken what are our people's
attitudes when it comes to we had an
incident to sit down to talk about it
and kind of generally treating that as a
team effort that we're going to help
solve down and change some things to
prevent that
and keep getting more people in the
sales department this quarter that are
clicking efficiently that's not really
knowing them much other than sales
people I don't see your question before
about having listened to the hiring
process
to have but the reality is or what I've
seen a lot
is when when a new person comes on board
the corporation's they have a huge
onboarding process they have heaps of
security modules they have heaps of
training
about how to write reports or powder
comes this huge confronting list
of the stuff that mean
to do and serious
I guess that they're not engage unless
they don't
that security training so it's difficult
balance
strike
training the use of people they into the
organization and
also very very fluid
yeah the attitudes of fire people just
need you to have to train the new people
all over again from the start so
we have like a really cool it's very
penguins you know getting a cold
because your imagination
any requests ? oh yeah
big numbers
how often you get people to go hey you
don't work
not often enough
all
they say hey your number is up around
or hey we don't have an AR people
working at our organization so it does
happen and that's
because we like to report on
yeah that's happened
that's one over here
sure in the back
why
Oh
gamification
game
they're like
yeah know your audience and
it's really important for writing any
whether you're pitching to the Executive
Board on your social learning results or
you're pitching to the technical folks
or just the general culture the
organizations and yeah it's just tailing
you training too
the people like that
you