thanks everybody for letting me speak
today this is my first time here I'm
going to change things up a little bit
my talk will be a little more conceptual
and hopefully more entertaining so we'll
see how that goes a little bit about
myself I have infosec career experience
spanning 20 years I've worked for
fortune 50 companies I've worked for
companies that had 10 employees and I've
been in large IT organizations as an
internal team member I've also been an
external consultant and I have a multi
security discipline skills across the
areas of technical infrastructure design
implementation assessment governance
risk and compliance so my goals for this
session I want to share some information
that might be of interest to you
hopefully you'll learn something new and
maybe we'll have some fun along the way
as well so smack what is it is this it I
might feel like that but smack is
something else now show hands who who
here is heard of smack in relation to
cloud before anybody got one over here
one over there okay Gardner calls this
the nexus of forces what the hell does
that mean nexus of forces doesn't mean
anything to me but smack is social
mobile analytics and cloud that means
something so how big is smack well it's
pretty damn big it's four galaxies in a
universe big how important is it well
about a year ago the CEO of Microsoft
decided he needed to change their
go-to-market strategy the previous CEO
was calling their new look and feel
devices and services anybody remember
that and now he said no that's not good
enough it needs to be cloud first and
mobile first cloud and mobile two parts
of smack not sure how you get both of
those to be first but I get the idea
so let's break it down a little bit
these are my definitions of these four
areas social media it's represented by
any number of public internet sites that
facilitate personal interaction with a
potentially unlimited audience so who
hears heard of litterin that's right I
haven't heard of it either because it
doesn't exist it could exist because
it's the mash-up of Facebook LinkedIn
and Twitter and just like this guy you
know you can do a whole bunch of things
at one time on flitter in all in one
place and really when you come down to
it the social part of smack is all about
the Me's you know you got like me and I
have to read this here it's a little
small listen to me army watch me find me
so all the B's all the Me's are part of
the social part of smack every one of
yous of me every one of you has
different personas so it covers a lot of
bases mobile anytime anywhere any device
digital endpoint interactions on a
potentially unlimited scale so here's
something that keeps people up at night
we got the people walking up to the BYOD
vending machine and then they go to IET
and say hook me up and so there's a
tendency to try and lock it down but
that really doesn't work analytics also
referred to as big data alludes to the
mashup of data from a variety of sources
that enables extended data mining that
would produce comprehensive information
not otherwise possible think about Big
Data it's pretty scary you don't really
know what you're going to get when you
start mashing up data what once was a
data that does not is not attributed to
anybody or any person all of a sudden
becomes pH I or PII and again it's very
stick it can be very scary stuff not
only that if you take a tool like a doob
which is
or the poster child for analytics it
takes unique skills it's expensive and
the expectations for the outcomes are
maybe a little too i but guess what
we're going there cloud this is a
reference for the classic internet-based
third party resources that are generally
engaging arm's length with a
self-service model and just as absurd as
this may seem cloud is the answer to
everything that is the perception in
many cases that it's the answer for
every problem that exists so regardless
of how ridiculous that is you better
embrace it because this could be you
okay so here's a quick overview of the
smack forces working together how they
relate to each other so down in the
bottom right we have the cloud which
provides capacity to the mobile users
and to the analytics backends the mobile
devices provide social activity to the
social network and in turn the social
network provides social marketing back
to the mobile user and analytics is the
backend back in engine for all of this
it provides feedback for the voice of
the customer and the mobile activity is
also another source of information into
the analytics engine as well so what is
smack matter well business is changing
to a more collaborative customer centric
environment align with progressive
business strategies so that means that
smack forces will play a strategic role
in meeting that change and new and
emerging initiatives will likely be will
likely leverage SMAP to get there but
most importantly customers and consumers
will demand it to be there so I would
change the information tech landscape
well new and unforced unforeseen
security trends will emerge
due to the contemporary variables at
develop because of the new facets of
those four things interacting with each
other because of that traditional
security controls will fail to keep pace
and impacts to budget to IT security
product selection and budgeting will be
significant in order to keep up so this
wheel moving around from northeast to
southwest is basically representing the
notion that as you move around the wheel
your governance control diminishes as
you go from analytics where you can
possibly have a lot of control through
things like classification of data and
data tagging and dlp and drm when you
move to cloud you move a little bit
further away from control you can
certify your vendors through procurement
processes as you move to social it
starts to get a little more dicey as
Telugu who does what when and how and as
you get out to mobile now you're talking
about any device somebody's at home with
their xbox and they need to do something
at work and you know all bets are off on
the platform so again in the square in
the middle we talked about for social
you can work on increasing your
assurance levels for mobile you there
are ways of addressing device and
application management and you can do
things like binding your mobile devices
to your social identities to try and
retain a little more visibility and
control so what to do and in most cases
as in life it becomes a question of
balance anybody recognize this image
here this happens to be it's an album
cover it happens to be the movie blues
from the early 70s I just happen to like
the philosophy of a question of balance
but it's definitely applicable here and
you know the thing about security is I
take a different approach I think to
most people I think of security first as
an enabler so you know really the
mission here is to enable business on a
secure and resilient foundation rather
than security being the moat or you know
the protection I want to look at it as
something that you can use to launch
further beyond where you are today so
what are some examples of proactive
activities that can reduce smack risk so
in the social realm it comes down to
mostly identity i believe and so
identity assurance levels become a truss
point for utilizing this element and
some examples out there in the world
today are mystic which is a government
private sector avocent advocacy group
consortium that was formed in 2011 to
trust framework for Federation and an
ecosystem for IDs phyto is another
example fast identity online it's a 2013
industry consortium with a specification
for a full range of multi tech factor
authentication and I just read this week
that mystic joined the phyto alliance so
I thought that was a fairly significant
event in that particular realm in the
mobile realm as i mentioned device and
application management or effective
methods for increasing the value in
reducing the risk of mobile devices also
binding the mobile device to an assured
persona ID aka device pinning can take
trust to a higher level that's what i
was referring to in the previous slide
analytics again we talked about data
centric technologies and controls to
provide tools to minimize exposure and
uncertainty and damage examples are data
classification leaked data DLP drm all
tied to a relevant access controls and
in the cloud space ox supplier
certification making sure
at the cloud vendors have a good program
in place and cloud government cloud
governance platform that's a name that I
coined myself remember that we'll be
talking about that in a minute or two
the cgp can provide the visibility and
data control over cloud service that the
vendor may not be able to provide
otherwise so let's do a quick shallow
dive into what cloud computing is
there's five essential characteristics
the first one is on demand service
second one is broad network access and
again anytime anywhere anyplace any
device resource pulling so resources are
not dedicated to any one particular task
they're used on demand as needed there's
rapid elects elasticity so 5 10 servers
and I have a big event I can ramp up to
100 servers very quickly by just pushing
a few configuration buttons and be on my
way and finally it's a measured service
so that i only pay what i use pay for
what i use so this is the nist model of
cloud computing and on the top layer
those are the five characteristics that
i just covered in the middle we have the
service delivery models so software as a
service platform as a service
infrastructure as a service and then at
the bottom we have deployment models
we've got public-private hybrid and
community so just for the sake of
argument what are the examples of
service delivery models Wells salesforce
com is the poster child for software as
a service amazon AWS is the platform as
a service that everybody knows about
verizon terremark is the infrastructure
as a service and then if we look at the
deployment models we got public that
would be AWS again as an example private
will be an enterprise cloud hyper would
be the combination of the AWS and the
enterprise cloud and a community would
be customized public cloud subset okay
so this is a graph that to me is sort of
a spectrum as you go left to right here
and you know that the yellow represents
the subscribing 10 identity or the
enterprise and the blue is the vendor
the cloud service provider so on the
right hand side we see software as a
service and we see that the vendor has
complete control over everything and the
organization has very little control in
most cases so as you move across to the
left platform as a service you start to
share a little bit of responsibility and
visibility and control infrastructure
you give up a little you gag you gain a
little bit more when you get over to the
far right now you have you have complete
control because you're within the
enterprise environment the point here is
that the boundaries matter and where you
make the compromise to give up control
and visibility will matter in the end
and as my previous speaker as the
previous speaker mentioned in his talk
the cloud vendors usually will not take
responsibility for your data so when
you're over on the far right-hand side
it's up to you to take action that
they're not going to so just for
industry trends the drumbeat of cloud
computing just keeps getting stronger
and here's a graph that's a little bit
dated but it's still trending true IT
spending on cloud is going to triple
between 2011 and 2017 so it's really an
unstoppable force so cloud governance /
platform I talked about this a little
bit earlier I'm going to deep dive into
it a little further now a cloud
governments platform is a tool that you
can leverage from a third party vendor
that would sit in between your
application in the cloud and your users
it could either be on premise or in the
cloud itself and it gives you control
analysis and discovery over the usual
suspects suspects which are the items
over in the right hand cloud there with
box and office 365 and Salesforce and so
on so whether your users are at home in
your enterprise mo
whatever this platform is going to give
you visibility that you didn't have
otherwise mobile users even if they
don't come through your enterprise still
can have you can still have visibility
and control over their activities and
again Gardner has another term for this
they call it a cloud access security
book a little too wordy for me but there
you go so the part about the mobile user
that's pretty significant because
otherwise your mobile users running
box.com app on their on their smartphone
you lose complete visibility without a
cloud governments platform whether you
have tools in your enterprise it's it's
pretty much gone out the door so let's
talk about two use cases for cloud data
control and visibility strategic
initiatives cloud governance platform
for box calm and cloud governance
platform for salesforce com so in in an
enterprise setting for box typically
what happens is you may invoke sam'l
assertion a single sign-on to box from
your enterprise and you basically tell
your users okay there it is go ahead and
use box and for me the real value add in
boxes collaboration the fact that you
can just drop files in in the Box cloud
is okay but the fact that you can
collaborate those files with other
people especially third parties outside
of your organization is really where the
value is well without a cloud governance
platform you really don't know much
about what's going on out there in the
Box cloud but with a cloud governance
platform here's an example of 12 file
vents that you will have real-time
monitoring and logging of all these
activities that occur and what's really
most important here for me are these two
in the right hand column share and
invite collaborator so now you have more
visibility about what's actually going
on so you can tell your users okay we're
going to allow you to share regulated
data with third parties but owning with
the parties that we have quality-assured
through our own
kind of governance function to make sure
that they're HIPAA compliant or PCI
compliant or whatever if you don't do
that we're going to know about it we're
going to get alerts we're going to take
action on those things so this
particular kind of platform can actually
either be in line or it can be offline
meaning that it's it's off to the side
and through an API it's looking at the
box file activities without even being
in line with the user to give you back
that control and visibility and feedback
so what additional features can i
leverage with those 12 functions I can
do policy-based pre cloud storage
encryption if I like so that I don't
have to trust box calm to handle my data
any particular way because I'm
encrypting it myself I can invoke DLP
independent of the cloud service and I
can optionally integrate it with my own
existing enterprise DLP policy engines I
can retain enterprise based granule or
access controls completely independent
of what the cloud vendor provides and
again a big win here is the mobile
device coverage for BYOD and extra
enterprise source devices as well so
somebody fires up the browser on their
xbox then they go to box they have
credentials to get in you're still be it
you're still being able to monitor what
they're doing through that kind of a
session even though they're not on your
enterprises they're not even on a
sanctioned piece of equipment so what
features can we leverage in order to
support sharing of pH I and PII
regulated data with third parties we can
have live audit log and event access
monitoring we can in real time out DLP
anomaly detection and instant
notification again we can have coverage
for native mobile in order to end or
desktop clients and we can also do
something interesting like a scheduled
scan for discovering interesting content
so even if you put up a policy
it says yours here's the rules of
engagement here's the things you're
allowed to do even if you're not looking
for specific things in those policies
you can define regex queries and other
kinds of unstructured data in inquiries
into the data in the entire store to
understand what other kinds of
activities are going on within that
environment so here's an example of a
log file from the DLP engine that
occurred in box and in the third column
from the right we see the anomaly value
so we have a couple credit cards some
social security numbers a HIPAA member
ID and we we will immediately see the
user that was involved in that
particular event some other attributes
time and date stamp that occurred this
is our actionable information if there's
there's a policy violation for example
okay moving on to Salesforce claw
governance platform here's the model for
Salesforce think that's key to this
particular architecture is the fact that
it is specifically in line so we're
doing a little DNS manipulation here
we're doing CRM ABC com on the
right-hand side on the left hand side
we're actually going to ABC dot cells
for comm the real URL but more to the
point of the the encryption that is
being invoked within the cloud vendor
the keys the session Keys the store for
those keys is handling is being handled
on the enterprise over there on the on
the right hand side the vault key server
is on-premise it could be any particular
kind of key server doesn't have to come
from the cloud governance platform
vendor through the km IP protocol key
management interoperability protocol the
premise key agent can query the key
server for session Keys push them out to
the cloud and even the cloud vendor is
not really going to have a knowledge of
those keys and how they're derived so
now you still maintain control of that
data and all the data to get that gets
stored in Salesforce is still under your
domain and control so in this particular
case we have a transparent in line proxy
with an API interface to salesforce com
providing field level encryption and dlp
scanning according to your enterprise
policies this slide here is actually a
little bit overlapping with the previous
discussion the graph on the on the upper
half if you go across the horizontal
axis you're looking at preserving
functionality in your encryption
selection type if you go across the
vertical axis you're talking about the
encryption strength so we got seven
different kinds of encryption techniques
here to be able to protect your data in
order to strike a balance between
preserving functionality that data such
as searching and indexing those kinds of
things and the encryption strength that
you would be able to affect and then the
bottom half are basically some academic
papers probably from the same realm as
the previous speaker and the heavy matha
cos into those those theories that go
into those papers but the product of
that research are these seven different
encryption types so this particular
slide here is a screen grab from a tool
that you might use to configure the
encryption types for your salesforce.com
application it's a little fuzzy but you
know the first column represents the
name of the field the second column is
the API name so every time that that
particular field is in a particular
application or record you're identifying
it by the API name rather than just the
field name the third column represents
the occurrences of that API within the
application and then the fourth column
represents the type of encryption
of those seven types that you want to
apply to that particular piece of data
in order to strike that balance again
between functionality and encryption
strengths so final word cloud computing
is just going to keep exploding it's
something that you really can't push off
to the side it's going to be there it's
going to come at you from every which
way and that's all I have any questions
i blinded them with science