good-sized Jewish lives all right we're
going recording is going all right how's
everyone doing good how many people are
still working on the red hat last raise
your hands though I know I know you want
to see you guys that's fine you can keep
doing that we are laptops are not
required for this it will be you can
probably do some things in your laptop
that's really going to be a more
interactive workshop I'll give you a
little background why that is so I
apologize in advance is it some of the
stuff that you weren't expecting I'll go
through with what this will eat and what
this won't be so everyone's beware
beforehand
so you don't sit here for two hours
waiting for the labs or though anything
like that so a little bit about me I'm
information secure officer and local
government also a managing partner with
a software development company called Co
Greg essentially also play a weapons
instructor and unicorn salting security
frequent talker go word all the things
you might have heard me speak before and
xeni OneNote that is in the corner all
right so this is gonna be a little more
interactive I'll go through from the
agenda here I'm gonna do a lecture and
discussion I really want the lecture and
some of the things I'm talking about to
be kind of a two-way thing how this came
to be a workshop I did submit just a
one-hour talk here and then they
contacted me about a month before the
cons that they can you do a workshop so
this is what I put together
so I apologize you guys be my guinea
pigs here we were also supposed to have
I was I'm gonna give Benny a lot of crap
for this but we were supposed to have a
whole instance of the automation
orchestration as well as the centralized
logging
in this CTF environment we're gonna
actually be able to give access into
that and actually be able to build out
some of these enrichment engines as well
as a lot of automation that's what we
can do in the CTF environment so as
people were attacking a CTF environment
we even see events come in and we're
going to have some kind of pre build
events go through and do some triage and
kind of automate some alerting and see
it all all the context and everything
get it from there obviously some of the
threat intelligence stuff wouldn't work
because of all internal IPs on the
network and things like that but we're
gonna we're gonna try and set that up so
we don't have that but we will talk
about that will talk about the concepts
we'll talk about the concepts of
automating security operations where to
focus that as well as go through tool
time on a budget again this is on a
budget so there are a lot of enterprise
tools that can do these things for
enterprise orchestration and automation
engines a lot of things out there and
some of the tools that we'll talk about
there's probably six different dozen
tools that we will that we'll be able to
do what we're going to do we have a few
that I use so we're going to be going
through some of those but I mention
other ones and if anyone's had any other
ones we can talk about those as well and
then we'll have an exercise time kind of
more of the workshop it's gonna be a
modified tabletop time people have done
a tabletop exercise this is going to be
a modified version of 15-minute tabletop
15-minute tabletops kind of the term I
have for them are just very very low
level or high level tabletops one
scenario you a few injects you're just
could this discussion base and just kind
of fill out an after-action report this
is a little modified to focus at
learning what what part of your instant
response or security operations or even
IT operations can be focused on being
automated for time to remediation so
we'll go over that as well
so as I said a workshop what it is and
what it's not that's not a hands-on
workshop sorry
you guys don't don't beat me up over
that we're not going to building any
automation infrastructure we only have a
few hours here even the environment that
we're going to do here you have to build
build automation and I'm not talking
about just having ansible do things and
having you know Shepherd puppet I mean
this is going to be security operations
and it's a response a lot of automation
as well as a lot of things that go into
that that are kind of you can have you
know 10 different servers running where
these dm's running and stuff like that
so we're not going to solve all your
problems you know we don't I don't have
unicorns and keyboard elves working and
we're not the you know I can talk bunny
cyber community AI Skynet systems huh
those behind that that's that's about
three more hours it completely covers by
that the unicorn that yeah what this is
again as I said as an overview
automation help it's in the security
operations and kind of what he needs for
that you get them pretty I would say
mature but definitely foundational
security environment just started doing
it any thought of me anything because
your automation is only as good as first
of all your skill set your staff as well
as the data and the items and process
that you have built in that right just
like any piece of software or any even
process it's only be as good as what you
put into it right so if you don't have
those built then you're not gonna have
good a lot good automation at all right
and we're going to review some
frameworks tools resources technical
frameworks to build a lot of automation
on a budget I will go over those I wish
we'd go more into the tools and you have
a couple demo instances that I have
access to but again without setting up a
full environment and having full
caseloads kind of loaded
we just don't have that one give you the
full what kind of aspect we can
definitely talk about it so the goals
understanding the basic components and
role of automation there are things that
you really want to focus on and make
sure those things that you don't want to
focus on automation at first I mean
obviously the goal is automate as much
as possible in any type of IT
environment but you definitely want to
play this if you don't have a lot of the
foundational items in certain places of
your security operations or LT
operations then you might be able to
automate something there may be
something that you know is accurate and
has the data that you need to do the
automations and workflows that you have
available again identifying areas of
automation even if you can't do some of
this automation or your other
capabilities of it you can definitely
the tabletops are good especially the
small tabletops are very useful and just
identifying areas of basically just
improvement I just need to have to be
automations it could be process
improvement and that's really the goal
of any tabletop exercises identified
gasps and had the workforce at the end
that show from the people that said that
they have done tabletops before are
those official like one day to day full
tabletops or were those like at date
tabletops and just shut shout out for
food it full bit full day yeah so nice
thing about was what I've done with some
of those 15 actually it's a whole group
work group of people have built a 15
minute table tops you can take you know
an IT team and maybe even some upper
management you can just have like an
hour hour and a half meeting you can do
a full tabletop again it's not going to
be as intensive you're not gonna have
multiple inject scenarios you're not
gonna have all your policies and
procedures out there to you know but
you'll definitely go through a scenario
and identify large gaps so a lot of
people that are building automation off
budget probably don't have the resources
to do you know hold a multi-day
tabletops and stuff like that so let's
get a lot of people here have I assume
those some of those too
probably government employees maybe you
know what we'll get into that I ain't
gonna have people basically introduce
themselves if you don't want to
introduce yourself what you do tell you
that I want to get a fit of the audience
feel free not too costly yeah right here
discussion time so if you don't feel
comfortable I just want to get a kind of
label and to the audience and stuff so
we can kind of have again two-way street
here who has been involved with security
offer automation or automating and it's
a response and things like that
okay well this is probably really boring
for you guys sorry so what's a what
level maturity of that you mind me
asking maturity worth our you are you
enriching data for analysts to have a
better time we major are you in full
automation where there are actions being
kicked off and a off of certain type of
datasets wouldn't know me anyway I
mentioned so I know I'm not talking
about from like the maturity matrix or
anything like that just just general one
maturity you know we're not going to get
too much into the frameworks or
technical staff discussion guys awake
how many vendors we haven't there any
MSG's
cool sim security working on new
progress in progress stealing my
information not really
so okay alright do we have how many
government do we have local governments
take over my federal government y'all
say what Aeetes here I think okay do we
have healthcare sector in here okay do
we have what level what size the health
care by my asking insurance insurance
that's interesting
how about education Marshall University
represented no university marshal all
right let's see any other industry
sector I know I can go through all all
of them but just like financial use
financial any other financial banks pull
stuff art students those students okay
imagine anything huh utility utility
okay well a public utility or private
utility is it related Federal's or any
state local government here are you guys
part of like them acai sac all right
cool just I've also co-chair on the
disaster recovery business or the
business resiliency workgroup so a lot
of these 50 min table tops are covered
inside of our monthly calls are also
available if anyone wants they are not
they are open source essentially all the
table tops the table tops we'll be doing
today are kind of modified table tops I
make them a little more technical the
ones covered usually or more high-level
alright chatty crowd okay automation
does anyone anyone have a background
automation
in the theory of any computer scientists
in the room alright any program theory
classes any nothing yeah okay all right
good all right so anyone want to be able
to guess what type of automation will be
mostly talking about here today machine
turning machine yeah it's a big one I
wish yeah we'll be focused on
combinational logic again basically
taking something if something does this
do this there are a lot of machine
learning algorithms that will be fuzzy
logic and things like that again it's
combinational logic when you start get
into the larger portion of automation
you're talking just something that the
secreting setting is just getting into
maybe if you have some of the IBM Watson
stuff doing some type of or dart trace
or something like that you're getting
kind of in there but you're still not at
still a high level of automation when I
say that I mean automation or logic
where a lot of stuff is still just use
with fuzzy machine learning there's very
few things using any type anything over
that again
scary automation from the combinational
logic we'll be focusing on it again and
taking all of your foundational
sections of security and models within
so if you have more mobility management
you have your secure operations of
centralized logging obviously you have
your sin and your alerts and you have
your intelligence data and just marrying
all those together to be able to make
essentially logical choices automated
logical choices on that to enrich the
data and as well as the event data to be
able to make better decisions quicker or
completely automated
but again those automated systems are
called it very very simple for instance
this comes in block to this IP at us
that's great automation as simple that
is that is monumental to for a security
department to get to again I know that
there might be the firewalls not
automatic but I'm talking about things
have gotten through all right am I
talking about just you blocking or
blocking cuz it's on it now or a list or
something like this I'm something's
gotten through and all of a sudden
automatically block in it or at least
making it very easy to block so one of
the largest our lives and we'll get into
this more and more detail is safe
phishing emails right phishing emails
come in are they reported by our users
Fushimi males are blocked I probably
don't really care look at them as more
stuff that's coming through but how many
how many people have an organization
where you can report the phishing email
not simply just forwarding to a mailbox
but an actual button that actually takes
the headers for all headers and things
like that right it's pretty basic now
anyone else know has a report to just
button I have a phone company yeah so
okay so again there's ways to implement
those things there's a lot of open
source utilities to do that but you know
getting those things once you get them
in and train your users use that you're
getting all kinds of the emails report
you and probably 80% of those are
probably marketing emails they have on a
subscriber list I mean you really need
to go and look at those but how do you
know maybe it's a spoofed subscribe you
know vendor or some type of notification
right how do you know that if you're
also given hundreds of emails reported
you only have two sockets all right
how many people have more than five
people on the spirit of our
many people are the only ones in their
secured apartment - okay I'm going - all
right that's it right yeah so I mean if
you have and I assume how many people
have over a thousand users in their
foundation how about 5,000 users okay so
again we started getting it up to that
and you start getting the I hope if you
have more than 5,000 users you have more
than to be warriors Department but you
might not but when you start getting you
know say 0.5 percent one percent of your
user population daily you know reporting
phishing emails you can get up to the
hundreds pretty easily
what's the average do you think a stock
analyst to spend on a phishing email
triage I'm not talking about is
something that's clear text or something
like that they're just if there's a link
and there's it goes 30 minutes right
maybe right I mean you have to switch
over it might take you five minutes to
do it but you're doing other things
things are coming at you might be thirty
minutes maybe an hour on something
that's a little wacky right but I mean
if you got hundreds of those are you
gonna look at each one right I mean you
got right now when they come in you know
that that person is a high-level VIP or
you know executive or as access the
classics are sensitive data right away
or you have to look at the directory
then you have to kinda look at a job
title maybe the jobs held right after
directory and answer time how's that
how's that work pretty other list people
you know important just like I was there
was certainly not certain
does anybody have an actual
classification of risk per employee you
want tactics a little explained matter
yes high profile c-level executives fall
into a certain category and basically
any anything they touch or have access
to it's a great on scale of one to ten
in our name and where is that is that
stored in a classification system or is
that even an accurate record you have in
them in a specific oh you and they're
just always there yes so partially
Active Directory then we actually have a
custom in-house database these stores as
much of the mystical data
yeah so yeah so when you get into a lot
of this stuff and you're saying hey I
need to like this data enrichment this
also you start throwing up access
databases and you start you start kind
of doing your in-house stuff again if
you want to pay for something you know
you could pay for like a something like
a a Verona solution or something or any
type of other user behavioral analytics
system right so you could start putting
that metadata and taking it from Active
Directory knowing what permissions they
have access to what folder structures
have access to and things like that
those those cost a lot of money and it's
really not if you have skilled people
it's not that difficult again to get
that type of information in there so
that is kind of a kind of going right to
the incident response to triage here is
that again you're trying to limit as you
can see that you have that that dwell
time the containment time visited back
I'm not talking about full instant
response kind of process but it's just
generally speaking they're you know how
long you said maybe 30 minutes right you
know that's even before the vault times
they're right one users report you know
an email I've already clicked on it they
kind of click
report it right and then when you're
talking about regular just events and
things like that
I mean how well are you sins really
tuned how much data they really do you
know they getting a lot of day trees
having thousands and thousands of alerts
or del alerts or not even sure if it's
really working and you're like oh maybe
I would I be able to detect if someone
also got access to a sensitive security
that wasn't supposed to I mean with
would you would it would anyone be able
to detect that in this room say an
administrative assistant got access to a
legitimate access to a a folder that
required a sense of security group as
define - does Microsoft active record
pretty much live workers with that would
that kick off an alert how would you
know if that was a ticket that actually
that person is supposed to have
especially discussion time
previously I was like I said whether
that work I had auditing turned on users
privileges for some reason were changed
there was a change with the object table
type of change and how would you know
wasn't it a ticket it wasn't legitimate
did the end and that's good thinking
system right that is correct
so at least from a default for those
accounts yeah those are all learned
immediately correct yeah yeah okay but
then as we move through and identify
critical critical data a file share
those words are also being identified
and alert you know how do i how do I
associate that to an access to get well
you can actually access things for
tickets to but larger organization right
so some some we use a third-party
software that would track access okay
yeah so like someplace in my bucket I
aim our eidm system that kind of has a
functionality or if your security
operations is inside that ticket
workflow most likely you would know
that's not a legitimate off the table
here maybe it does in richer and change
your similar game and also and you know
that first has legitimate access to this
this folder I mean I would say hope if a
someone like an executive assistant or
janitorial staff also got like account
operators or print operator I hope that
every one would be alerted but I mean
have you tested that right not saying go
test that but I mean hey or do you make
sure there's an alert that would
functionally kick off and who'd that
kick off to so like when you see a word
DG so part access management team three
more channels when that happens though
we do get alerts for instance like that
questionable there's more of a manual
process that's why I'm not saying people
have these things I mean yeah good
discussion yeah okay that me I would
hopefully have some type of me know
progress I mean every single thing is
mean let's find a lot of places operate
like that I'm not saying that not having
automation you guys are in the Stone Age
but it's really something to think about
a lot of people don't really go through
and see the workflows of how something
gets actually reported to remediated
for instance and our environment our
security operations does not have the
ability to remediate some things like
that because we are not domain
administrators that's the engineering
team a specific team within that that
has that type of access so we have
interoperate with those people how many
people security department also the
domain
yes traitors I have that capability all
right thank you okay now how many people
that don't have those are your domain
administrators essentially on-call
working 24/7 that would respond to a
security incident I mean do they have an
on-call list yeah but I mean are they
gonna wake up if all of a sudden you
know how long would it take for that
person to wake up and then use something
right
so again identify those gaps if that's
what you have you have so just again
identifying those gasps going through
whereas automation makes sense of words
it not make sense
good discussion anything else there
anyone want to add I I never really
started by me we tend to automate things
that when the wartime automating a small
piece of the puzzle
mm-hmm but still continue to do the
heavy lifting manually so it's as if
there was no benefit to doing the small
auditionees we spent three hours to save
ten minutes okay that's but that's 10
minutes over or potentially entire year
right every time that happens right so
if you take something like this and
identify that essentially or that that
10 minute or that one hour task you know
you can focus what should you automate
right at the other day again you want to
limit it a lot of time you also want to
make it make sure your day is accurate
Network well how many people have gotten
a ticket and then the information on
that user anything has been completely
stale or an axe all right that happens
is that anything you love do about that
probably not right there in that
instance or even your team might not
have the ability but how can I be
automated how can essentially an
employee transfer be automated if you
don't again cloud environments don't
have identity management or
orchestration kind of doing a lot that
workflow
well formally I came from fortune 500
that had
and then a small little government
didn't have any that we actually used a
pretty basic our HR system mm-hmm
exports a user name job title phone
number work location cetera and it can
spin into every eighty area so they know
that as long as they've registered that
work change or job change or location
change with HR it's exactly what I was
looking for someone kind of the same
because that's a lot of places for some
reason just don't do that and they have
that capability because the HR system
might just be this thing that's in the
that said that you know maybe they
charty people have access to your look
but people don't in the small areas
don't do things like that things get
stale all the time especially and again
I'm talking about small small meeting
business as well as local conference
things like that because they just
changed so much over time it just gets
stale and it's never really a problem
until you know security looks at it or
there's scale records for something
that's a lot takes this payroll might
still be going climb HR source or record
it again Active Directory to someone
really care that you're not a senior in
their title or your phone number change
real quick because the phone system
really push down the ad and stuff like
that can you really call you really know
where those users are located do you
have cute numbers things like that those
can help have the accurate data and make
the data integrity a lot more viable to
the again do automation not saying that
99 percent 100 percent goal environment
has to be accurate do automation but
know we did review before you start oh I
know we had we had larger than any
management system send a lot of
orchestration and auto provisioning and
de-provisioning with the click of a
button just because it was this there
right I don't know how you would even
track if somebody moves from HR with
access to critical you know employee
data to finance and suddenly gets
financed now they've got both you're not
tracking that they left they're not
right I mean a lot of places when they
do in a full active directory review or
you sit down a pen tester or a risk
assessment comes in run something like
bloodhounds how many people are familiar
with bloodhound runs bloodhound you know
and there's a stuff everywhere
there delegation issues there's they
even know half the things had delegation
all the way up to you know media server
admin or something like that because
someone need to access some fiscal
department need access to RDP into a
server that had a pack line on it and
also gets yes server admin for all
servers right I mean there's things like
that can happen especially in your low
budget environment low resources and a
large amount of staff which happens a
lot one of the things that we had before
we got our new HR system was we kind of
a leap request built in chairman and so
it was looking at the directory and if
your information was incorrect then you
couldn't send it to your manager unless
your manager was correct because then it
would go to someone else and they would
say you don't work for me didn't get
your leave so it was you know he came
down to the employees saying I want to
take my leave get my information correct
that makes it more personal right yeah
then certainly you want the system right
not saying that you should just do that
for people but yeah that's one that'll
make it a little more personal from an
MSP MSSP what happens when you guys go
into an environment and you get hired by
a and and you know they buy your blinky
boxes and they're the core tools and you
go to a company or entity and they just
don't have any type of date
tegrity for your blinker box in the
unicorn system somewhere awful what what
would be interesting
no one knows who you guys are an
audience they don't know what a mosquito
but it's just curious informing them
what lack of is a little house now do
you usually because you know if you do a
proof of concept you might know that
ahead of time but you know if they think
it's gonna solve the world what do you
guys also offer like what do you ideally
you tell them beforehand yeah if you try
to give them a point for what it wants
to as anyone that's had MSP services
before or have they have they come in
claim things which is finally probably
does do what they say it does in some
aspect but then realize that it's
dependent on a lot of data structures
that you just don't have anyone know you
guys good things again alright so as we
discussed kind of going right into again
key things with for automation your hand
just generally like foundational secure
practice need to exist in inventory need
CMDB need asset classification a lot of
you guys a professionalism there's a lot
of your an incident response automation
even experience this is kind of new to
you but again as a classification to be
able to develop those workflows and the
data classification do you guys have for
asset classification do you guys just
put that right in your cm TV do you have
a separate system what do you guys well
you guys you guys doing
combination of combination of both
anyone else I'm gonna start calling
other people around yeah we got our own
star people here okay the CMDB or some
form is attached to it how many people's
help desk system or taken system
connects directly with their security
operations or Sam right got that for
enrichment data No
then this espied of course there's how
many people do a CSV dump of the CMDB
from your ticketing system and at least
just have it queryable by your security
systems or injected in there anyone know
kind of little certain is it it's a
similar thing to the HR database thing
right for employee data going into ad
why wouldn't you think it would be very
similar to do it into some here you know
events and and event enrichment things
like that let's say the whole databases
and put your sent but when you get an
alert from system maybe here TCP scope
and reverse lookups work or maybe but
then do you know exactly who that person
is attached to who owns that asset from
your sin description here we're going to
take here soon so you have a large I
have gotten since then we're still
coping huh
I don't know actually we're actually
pretty fresh with ok we're linking in
wherever we can I had a cookie I'd given
up so yeah that's that's there so exact
what I'm leaning towards right but a lot
of people don't have a set of Sakura
stration and management systems because
to buy something like that equivalently
the pair expensive and something that
you'd have to additionally budget for
and I assume that everyone in the past
five years has already just got budgeted
for their their Splunk instance or their
logging instance or the vulnerability
management instance or their staff penis
that's right how do you go back and say
hey now I need this holder pieces to
connect everything like how do you make
that that's that whole kind of story to
the executives that get on board with
that right how do you do that how you
tell us all right anyone else do
anything like that
he said kinda yeah I don't so the other
guy on our team mainly handles he can't
be system administration he handles more
of the data one here and there my handle
and you also have an IT tech name system
I'm gonna start with some days of
questions here even people is it
speaking into your security some you
guys know so if you got an alert from
something and you had to know the owner
everything how long would that take you
guys to know exactly what even that
asset is before you can try them 20
minutes 20 minutes right and that sounds
like all 20 messes in a bad time but
imagine you get in like 30 alerts right
mama at least and again I saw that
instinct right that 20 minutes really
gets
you know very frustrating and very fast
because again all you're doing is
logging into another system and
essentially clearing another database
that is also just a text files anyway
but I summer school one right it's just
you know again all that they just won't
easily be mapped into your other systems
all right so I beat Matt down again open
source we can support it a lot of things
I'm going to be talking about here open
source one one a gentleman already
mentioned the hive again how many do you
have an eye Pam working on one eye Pam
just paid for one paid for one
SolarWinds no oh yeah we have one
analyst in the middle it has a rotating
thing is now surrounds videos everywhere
scrum board of your assets just got to
now I was like oh wow okay nice so
here's what did you read - bed just know
I didn't really got a cookie now you're
just I don't know if there's wholly me
or work there just
we're gonna be best friends
so again heaven I cam if you have
Microsoft backed record how many is that
attached to some type of an enterprise
da and some form I would hope so if
you're a business I mean even it's the
lowest enterprise agreement you know
Microsoft has an eye panthan right you
have to set it up but it's it is in
there again through you know doing DHCP
you do I Pam we can do a lot of things
so if you don't really realize that and
it can do things other than Microsoft
that sets I mean how many people know
that they can import and also manage
Linux systems in a subset pretty much
from Microsoft like secm and and Mike
surviving yeah how many people did not
know that and were kinda surprised about
that that's killing me here suppose my
mom already that really might work but
again it's about reviewing what you
systems have and what their actual
capabilities are again a lot of these
systems you can get for free from
something again I'm not suggesting to go
and replace your entire environment open
source or just take anything off the
github I definitely review leave
especially but so a lot of these things
could be put in there but again review
them we've gotten to a stack of open
source products where where I work at
but it has taken a time we've had a lot
of battles there a lot of war stories
and things like that
we've rebuilt things multiple times you
know things like PHP ipam are something
to look at there are other ones out
there too as well that people use just
as well
I can't name off and there's a one of
the people just less I was gonna ever
share some but there are a lot of things
out there again
looking at and how do people actually do
for that have small environments and map
their environment do you like mantis I
actually do dips of the end Maps waist
hands yes I see nods these will use load
up the end if and you review it every I
just started getting started using that
okay lots of color lots or so I think
you'll have our ability got some type of
scanning engine what happens when it
scans and there's something new on your
network what happens
so I using API hmm and then it turns it
into a custom tracker and it compares a
few tweets and the new scans if it's not
there anymore to disclose and where does
that run from it runs on a server that
runs will make your machines like your
guests okay yeah that's cool that's why
I know that's that's again yeah it's
very creative design right and that's
what a lot of people are finding out
that they're going through and some of
your your products again peanuts a
professional it makes sense to but guys
like I know some of these products like
yeah it'll give you an end it will give
you a dip but like what do you do from
that you know I'm really gonna like dig
in to see you guys respond in here and
then sharing some stuff we feel
comfortable in
just a touch on your heart probably yeah
the emails and a malicious and one thing
in the button so one thing we did we
wrote the cost of macro that we deployed
in our environment to send those headers
to a monitored mailbox mm-hmm and then
we wrote an app that goes through this
you know and pulls out links does he
have smoke ups on it once it has the IPS
everything it then feeds them to rural
state browser API Cisco umbrella and a
couple other it get services that we
made work to kind of generate a report
is that all custom you talk the high
pass that's good though it's very
convoluted have you know and that's and
that's what 3500 plus the fire in person
environment so it's it working progress
but it's working no definitely so again
workflow in frustration against you kind
of scripts work all engines platforms
all kinds of things like that we're
going to be again it comes down as some
you guys answer itself you're skilled
staffing with passion again spilt a few
with passion is worth more than product
out there and it's the best thing that I
think security operations environment
the department can have again you need
that skilled staffing not everyone has
to be a developer but I'm Tonya you have
people with I won't even say development
skills but curiosity skills with
intelligence go a long way if you start
really developing a lot of code base
we even implemented our own git
repository internally that can do code
versioning and a lot of things to all
our engineers already been doing large
PowerShell scripting and things like
that where you can start sharing
information and even get code reviews we
haven't gotten even if you have
developers on staff they might be able
to help at least review the code is I'm
the engineering scripts and things that
a lot of secure doctors are starting to
build because a lot of developments
starting to happen customization we
custom API is in a lot of the other
places of the environment and operations
and business don't really operate like
security does at least at this time
obviously development does right there
going towards the DevOps models and
things like that
the how many infrastructure guys you
know they might be run the scripts and
stuff but playing with API and stuff my
experience is that security is he is
kind of the people that are looking into
make sure all the api's are connect
what's the ability of this product we
got this product that we paid X amount
for it has all this capabilities all
these API is we have to develop them you
have to connect them and have to set the
alerts up so I did have slated a break
right here but I think I'm just gonna
keep going unless anyone wants to walk
out I think we're all adults here right
children all right cool cool time on a
budget here when you get into some of
the tools a little more in-depth again I
wish is a little hands-on with the shop
maybe next year I think we talked about
developing a lot of stuff the hive and
running even entire hive and instance
inside we see gif I'm doing a lot in
your instrument a lot of observables and
things like that again I'm gonna start
I'm not expecting to read some of this
stuff here but again if you have the
even a smallest environment can do these
things
one-man IT shop can go online get some n
math stuff and match your friend I can
write it and map end it and you have
these batch didn't even have run and in
a large environment start start with a
specific subnet hopefully you have some
type of subnetting structure and start
with something so yeah so hopefully you
have its target small if you have you
know your HR team or your your law
department or your some type of critical
team is very sensitive start running
this on that specific those assets or
that that asset a web that is on the
network and making sure nothing else is
popping up all these slides will be that
I just like people take yes all these
will be distributed I'll have buff slide
notes as well so there's a lot of
supporting so you don't have to like
that's a that's a picture right I like
it real code and stuff like that again
I'll have a lot of links for training
OVA training VMs and things like that
that you can get for all the products
and stuff that we talk about here I was
you can kind of play with your own
environment I hope the next time I have
this workshop to have all again those
training environments up and running and
a bunch of tested counselor people can
actually start logging in looking at
some inventory classification systems
tying in to logging and look-up tables
and then enriching the data through like
a superior operations and management
system that's really where you start to
get a lot of it seems like a lot of work
at first but you once you get it you
really can't live without it so next one
here is again scanning SMB shares how
many people know that's md how many
people are familiar with the versions of
SMU what was your favorite version of
SMB yeah how many people are have SMB
anyone that they are trying to
decommission it's habit it's there I
know it's there
are you tracking it what just to explain
some New York if you can I know there's
a little sensitive stuff without my
security right doesn't work
imagine how good you're doing like even
though that everyone has problems and
we're all talking about your company
name ya know so uh our company around
for quite a while and several points of
its existence enable all the West when
it came to purchasing hardware or
software and regulatory card the overall
company would basically find some more
companies and buy them and say here for
us now we put our name in their office
and then walk away and go talk to them
for years basically so now we're kind of
try to bring everybody enter under the
umbrella again right like some some
rogue row by teen going on there right
like rogues the only it broke two things
in our environment was a security that
was running open source here that ms
peas in the room was the other thing
printers they were both working one was
the security here one may once have any
war stories with us would be one copiers
and those are those are quite the the
beasts MSP you guys do you guys monitor
press and eveyone some customers don't
care what you can pan tilt that over
[Laughter]
okay yeah so again a lot of things again
these are two examples for nmap there's
a lot of nmap scripts I'm sure that how
many people are very familiar with that
map now I'll make you look really messed
around with the end scripts and things
like that as these scripts and things
like that
I'm sorry yeah successful goes yeah I
can copy and paste them and I can I can
tell if I get if I get like valuable
information usually I get mobile by the
infrastructure guys that my nmap scans
are shutting off VMs we're shut down
infrastructure yeah that's because it
was insecure yeah exactly
who's getting the phone the server any
other war stories and map so yeah so
definitely I recommend that the scripts
are a little interesting but again
understanding some of this stuff getting
maybe partnering with somebody if you
have someone in the infrastructure or
keen that does like bash or anything
auch or a 1000 Python development if you
have those people your capability one
have a once we learn what
have connect with them take just
literally in that class find it in my
class taking there's a lot of
capabilities you have you can do when
you customize things a lot of the code
you'll find on a map it's usable but
then again it has to be configurable for
your environment I need to know kind of
what it's doing you don't want to show
off network infrastructure it probably
will happen go against a test
environment but definitely even small
shop can run and map do some dips at
least even just a basic scan and a diff
and you can get a lot of useful
information you'll be surprised when you
find your network but that's anything
from you know IOT cameras that people
set up in there you know offices or
screenings to all kinds of crazy things
relying on that and that stuff that you
really want to get off your network some
people when I realize it's on the
network like themselves a psycho I plug
it in to start working until I started
using it so I could use my less at work
exactly
again I'm going to beat it down for
things
after the basics again inventory
classification processes again
considered centralized login how people
have centralized logging specialize
logging okay
what does that mean to you guys to you
now I'm not saying again yeah well our
logs are in one place that's fine it's
all of them that's all that matters okay
as it is does that go to I'm just going
to play devil's advocate here do you
have a more like a specific NTP server
is everything on the specific ntp server
for you GCS all those are things you
seen but any type of things may be ours
we leverage your cloud solution for all
our logging I said up in the cloud yeah
just go to the cloud storage a cheap
okay so I guess cloud time yes
I answered done okay well centralized
doggy how's that how's that working out
huh it's there it's a rate but the
volume of data is really the building
remembers what she not this video okay
so we have centralized logging but for
the years and years of things are just
founded properly um we learned that it
hasn't so we're going now and I guess
because okay so I'm right I'm helping
the process definitely what else
centralized logging not really kind of
using the high for that too which is
just a lot of data we try to go back
against it are using a long source
solution for essentialize logging
okay I was wondering okay good you
didn't see last time
that's very good we skip that slide I
guess so so yeah store is a huge thing
if you have a centralized logging in any
of those satellites logging components
open source notes that okay so school
yeah so there you're anything specific I
would say build of the elf stack like
something likes like or it's just full
straight help
there's no combinations without stack
out there and they're gonna have things
built on top of that ingest data we have
our so we still use the bar but I also
have a constant front that I've been
working on mm-hmm okay
is that also then essentially has your
sin to or yeah I guess have a separate
sin that that things are going to or we
view so what period have a separate tool
that can be used of the simple it's not
really used okay kind of it's anyone
have an open source in here they never
heard of a bar called sin monster we
looked at that it's interesting boys I
know where I'm gonna go over that but
I'm just trying to throw people off
there but it is another product yet
though as we're talking through it again
dated Richmond event Richmond again
ackers accuracy completed data is
essential to not even just automation
but instant response especially since it
really happens and you don't want to go
to when your executive your CTO your CIO
or something's like yeah you know what
if we just didn't know what this asset
was because I think guarantee you they
had certainly know what machines are ads
and what they're doing who they signed
to did you know I've been in places
where people get leave the company and
also in that department just hordes
their machines you really know how long
it takes I need to get a machine out
there on they're just sitting there and
they're just used and then they're
they're given and then I feel like oh we
never ever request for a laptop oh yeah
we already have what you know that could
be like four or five months down the
road right to kind of give some funny
business
I'm sorry let's hear it I'm on a
workshop for working here I'm all about
sit down at the company with recent
policies in hospital years of our
company young sea level particularly sad
it's very interesting
oh yeah oh yeah now they have to be
white but there's a whole process so but
Ava sea level is good to keep their
laptops oh yeah of course you to push
back I mean it's a huge mess so I don't
think it could get worse so hiya what I
have implemented to basically make it
acceptable is um ever every laptop that
we've had a lot so Elohim they're
completely okay with the being weight
and everything's all of my said very
well if you're a paper to be white then
you're OK to replace the hard drive give
you a brand new machine basically
because I would feel more comfortable
knowing that you just given machine and
then repurposing that internally they
eat the laptop we replace the hard drive
okay but an insert certain so that
depending at what sea level because
we've had sounds like a fun environment
we've certainly directors that are under
them sometimes we've had directors
actually get to keep their laptops and
you know my boss because without all the
business annotated this is against the
policy is we have that's what we you
know we have
you slow jacker like absolutely software
anything to track about the W climb so
yeah continue well just this is more
getting back to the automation soon talk
about because we have the same thing
something throws a lot pop drawer pulls
it up to us later I come back here we go
we actually have we brought automation
again sorry D you know hasn't logged in
in two months
mmm-hmm it's kicked out of the domain
that's out yeah a lot of user hasn't
logged in in three months their users is
disabled you might have field workers or
users that never log it again you're the
same how do you have exceptions that Wow
I mean service yeah so but we don't have
acceptance in the organizational we
actually have higher indices on
consultants yeah okay and yeah so again
if you guys how many people
automatically terminate a a user account
ad that has not been used or logged in
automatically and that's a pretty neat
Terminator to say disabled right it's a
basic process right it might be maybe
not automating the Batchelor you have
someone run it so weekly how many people
do that for the actual machine op that's
right as you mentioned to give the
presentation no no this is what I want I
wanted that some attacks were you know
Portugal areas and they wouldn't be able
to snap online for 16 plus 8 sometimes
so finally when they get back online
they don't money you gotta call us and
like we'd have to walk through a process
and white and there's always push back
to try to bend the rules like well we
need to create exceptions for this time
like first off your initially you're in
an area where if you're about to get so
on it's not gonna be a good then and
so yeah it's yeah it's definitely lot
more storage with machine object
disabling machine objects I know we have
a lot of emergency operations that are
used in certain instances that might
only be used once a year annually
certain things you do really make sure
that you know your organization's
procedures and policies and how if you
have redundant or TR equipment things
like that that you just you do you are
aware those things and things like that
and as well as your if you do have a
desktop Support Team things like that
that they're also aware of those
procedures product and processes once
you put it in place and that's just the
worst part we had was doing the same
thing way back one that's they were they
were sitting laptop staging them and
then just sitting them there when people
would go what would leave the company
and also they would go try to reimage
them or put them back on the network and
they would be disabled and it was just a
process where they'd have the rights and
things like that to the joint back or or
renew the Machine account things like
that and just created a operational
inefficiency right there that was over
comfortable but again you talk about all
this and you got an influx of 30
employees I got hired and you need to
add these machines back on that you can
get into a kind of a cluster they're
good stuff when I go through some of
these tools again this looks familiar to
some of the people how many people look
at PHP my ipam or an Afghan the one
person okay so I'm not going to go into
the I Pam this is just one it's there's
a lot of things like that I pan again
this is some of the things as an example
of what it inventories and you can have
more you could have a lot of extensions
on and I do a lot of customization on it
again it is open source again you have
something like you have a number of
subnets this isn't just an extinct our
example of our can our network again
over 1200 you know you got the VLANs
there
ipv4 addresses and those are only things
that are actually specifically scanned
you can choose a scan and not scan
things we're not skating at pv6 how many
people track ipv6 inside their network
internal how do you guys would you
disable it on just on the switches
workstations to disable don't yeah so if
you do disabling ipv6 on your your
network stack you might still have it in
your network
ipv6 also does something really fun for
security people
anyone know what ipv6 does interestingly
in the network world it's a public
address what does that mean robin bowl
with so it ignores a lot of
configuration and exists if you have an
ipv6 address it is probable it's
obtainable right it will ignore certain
minimal restrictions and security
policies inside of melody gear because
all you probably only have a separate
menu 6 or I did before so it's very
something very interesting to scan for
when you arguing to mere passive
scanning or analysis if you're hitting
head but windows event logs or any type
of system of that logs really understand
ipv6 traffic another kind of war story
share that you'll notice that even if
you do have it disabled your network
layer your workstations might still be
communicating directly to other devices
that have it turned on so you said you
disabled two workstations you disable it
all the printers right so that's
something to be conscious of as a
disabled printers and the interesting
thing about printers is that unless you
have some some vendors some large
vendors don't have
prick management like you can't just
push out unless you have a separate tool
set setting set of printers I don't know
if anyone has things that they can share
about how to manage or print
infrastructure some of the best things
I've seen is this - SNMP but that is
also you know manually set up unless you
have some senders that have print
management operations built into all
that printers just just blows my mind if
I'm incorrect with someone has some type
of large vendor that has print
management
unless it's one specific one I know of
I'd be very surprised if somebody ello
we have feet on the ground figure around
yep logically up now dreamless sleep
there was a lot of issues with Microsoft
operating systems when you move a v6
search the knowledge base there's issues
for the the IPAM people in the room are
you guys reporting on printers and I
can't I mean people's printers have
static or reserved IPS or they all just
use so there's you could just literally
load it and type in how many people know
that they just they change the default
passwords on the print management cuz
every printer has won by default turned
on our scanners potential site so it
tries to log in office now fun stuff you
can put SSO on into just for fun thing
of printers there's a lot of
functionality when you get enough
however we need a connector pay
yep all right yeah so again going down
the ipv6 number of kind of going through
locations again you get a lot of
locations in there you can have racks
how many people have Rack diagram
somewhere like of their data closets or
their right are those just in Visio or
in Excel Visio yeah all right
wouldn't that be nice to be able to see
in an iPad or an inventory management
system we're doing to know exactly where
did a closet where it was located at
things are the locations at least in the
CMDB maybe oh cool
all right so I'm going to go through a
little more of the patreon I pan this an
example some of this is custom to us you
can add custom fields pretty easy too
and this is just an example so again you
have IP address which is usually
obtained by DHCP some form rights as
long as the it's as the the items paying
a Bolton it will also show you this is
just an example of one IP address there
are entire subnets you can do and things
like that and you guys pin if you
literally Google PHP I Pam at the wid is
call obviously built on PHP but the name
of it is PHP I am the again you can put
devices locations those are all
dropdowns put notes tags some of the
things that we put in is vendor name
hardware a lot of those are custom
fields POS that we track for PCI our POS
systems things like that DNS an extra
DNS names some some things that are more
you know large a lot more DNS things and
just wanted it's a large environment or
a a a specific like Vienna in to
structure things like that we try to
just denote those things what's running
on them and things like that and those
are all like com comma delimited fields
and things like that we also have
firewall there's more on this by this is
what I want the screenshot
again we have device type and things
like that so you can easily see all the
cameras on your network and things like
that without actually having to scan the
network for cameras a lot of on
durability management systems or
scanners will do this for you as well
like obviously device types and things
like that again everything costs a
license right
so again if something is like a camera
printer some type of non workstation
device it most likely has a static
observe typing right or at least eight
reserved subnet of things as a CB scope
right I'm so at least you would know
that all these things on this subnet are
most likely X device or something the
same buddy has something somewhere on a
said you had a PhD hi Pam this is kind
of starting in system the automation
stuff we got to have build up automate
some things because we do have spenders
those kinds of things
the hardest part we have is getting the
the stuff that I can do automated who
really owns it where you know where's it
located those are all the other football
things are get into those messes so I'll
give you a use case and automation here
so we're just like talking about random
tools and secure operations but okay
imagine you have that map right yeah
then mapped if it runs say nightly all
right it can PHP I Pam for example has
the ability to import its vs CSV and all
these are just headers in the CSV and
literally just think work large mile and
if you overwrite all of these use the
week field as this IP address and you
can change those you need feel so that's
what it's hanging against when you
import something to do it overwrite the
fields that you want to overwrite or my
default it just does it by IP address
so if you have an ENDIF come in you can
export the csv file make sure that the
headers match and then you can actually
import or know that when data if if you
can actually do logic where okay this is
a new device on network I know it's a
new device was it implemented in PHP i
Pam with like say it was vendor name or
agency user or agency owner are those
things still in all or not and you can
kind of start getting reports like that
and just knowing that so you can
actually make sure that people are
actually putting things in or you know
what is the criticality level not there
you can run reports directly into in PHP
I Pam as well as hominy as I still have
a criticality left little things like
that and there's a lot of to overcome
when you first do this because nothing
has that right or maybe you have another
tool you can pour it in right but if you
don't have that after that you start
doing that it becomes very easy to
automate and that's not ought to be the
full process but again it's kind of
cleaning the task list there you know
what we do make sure that you have your
accurate and useful data there that
makes sense that find that yeah and then
it actually ties back to your role as
logging idea it doesn't logging
everything well if all your data is
coming back to I Pam and you're either
preparing it manually
yeah report or you have automating that
prepare and saying here's where you're
missing so once you have stuff like this
in place there are API is first for all
usually all I Pam's including page graph
and you can actually put into your
centralized logging music open source
solution and we can actually create
look-up tables so when an IP address
comes in to the centralized logging we
can actually enrich all of this data and
tied it to it so then our centralized
login has all of this data accessible
just because it knows the IP address and
it can pull that right so then you know
that okay this is the subnet is this you
know owned by this agency it's this
machine all that kind of stuff
especially if you might be an
environment
is maybe the more unique to us where we
don't have we don't have control over
some of the sub agencies under us they
might have it on my three departments
but we'll see what the HTTP scope it's
all the stuff it won't have so it's very
interesting once you get to a say
multi-tenant or environment maybe we're
company has a lot of subsidiaries or you
still mom or some of their assets we
only have access to certain amount of
data okay now I'm going to get into and
I don't expect people to read this
specifically but just to get the idea of
how things work we use a open source
solution called great log for our
centralized log in people familiar with
great log it's there's a learning curve
to get it set up and how large your
environment is but this is our just
general architecture of that and just to
kind of go if you go through this it's
actually built off the last
elasticsearch so these are the elastic
search databases here with multiple
shards each and then you have the great
log essentially interfaces and then we
have something that's called h8 proxies
in front of it and then these are all
these specific log instances are coming
in right here and it's going through
some normalization process right here so
these all things right here are things
like cisco firewalls here but then cisco
routers and switches have a different
one essentially each ingest probably
contains to a different parser to parse
that right so you're normalizing all
your data as it comes through here so
are using AG a proxy double balance
yeah so we get so many events to certain
types of systems that we actually use a
proxy to make sure that the intricacies
of the product does not burn so I use
making constant constant
stole advance more is a reporting
mechanism and health not not so much
that more of a failover yeah I mean that
would be for redundant ID yes yeah yeah
yeah so I mean I guess it's probably
we're typing column stay the same they
say the same thing right so but because
sometimes we found out in the
environment that we have because we're
getting like probably thousands of
messages per second we numerous up to
20,000 messages per second and that's
per second that we get in so we found
that sometimes it just times times out
because it's just how it works and we're
honestly still through again our
operational enhancements and learning
curves and things like that if the first
instance we did not have a a proxy was
how do we add to the scale there's white
papers out there and stuff about a
specific grade log how to make it more I
would say enterprise and failover
capable that's one of the suggestions
there and it's not custom I would say
it's customized whether there are our
instructions and installations on how to
do that for hi available so yeah and
then some of these are different
adjusters so one of these are the left
server how many people are familiar with
wet and wet in Windows when is that
forwarding and collection but if you
will have Windows Event 4d and clutching
working in their environment to a
centralized web server I don't I didn't
set up okay how many of you are familiar
with it so you guys have a set up no
reason we need will go to sweevil as a
collection agent not when there's
sending we go up okay yeah so for
everyone just be aware of the overall
architecture and capabilities of Windows
is that and there's a great one
Microsoft ignite I think maybe two years
ago
be far maybe three years ago by somebody
to name of Jessica pain and she actually
demoed it set up an entire Windows event
collection instance and was about
fourteen literally within like 15 20
minutes onstage and before that kind of
explained it not it's very obviously in
the dumpling bar very easy to setup
again you're enabling Windows Event 14
you have a Windows collection server or
you're pointing to a you have GPO to
push out and you're getting the mess
right and you have to have the Windows
Event Collection server has to have
certain types of subscriptions and
things like that to be able to get them
and there's a whole set up and I
recommend researching that and seeing
that because again that's a lot of data
that is better than that you could get
and you can analyze better than you
might have an agent right now right on
your machine or you might just not be
able to get in getting Windows Event log
so you can do a lot of things within us
that logs even if it's just your domain
controllers at first so you can at least
get log ons and all kinds of other types
of domain controller activity from that
it's very useful so we have that we
collect everything under the Sun so
that's every Windows Event firewall
we have a whole subscription we're gonna
events that we get and we monitor those
and have learned even things I set up
like that and there's a lot of cool
stuff that you can set up with that
there's also I'll have it in my notes
afterwards it's a great talk that was at
Derby con that was did statistical
analysis and essentially triaging of of
the most common attack vectors and
capabilities pentester hughes and just
essentially doing logic between I think
twelve different windows event IDs and
being able to tech everything under the
Sun including you know basically me cats
basic credential staffed remote desktop
anomalies and things like that now if
you start being obfuscation and things
like that obviously it might
is as useful but again a lot of basic
stuff from this 12 wonders of an idea
I'm sure the MS ESPYs know that because
they like city logic between like 15
different atoms when is that gonna go
now am I wrong am i right I mean right
similar it correct me if I'm this color
is someone accurate someone after yeah
right so we have our web server that
then towards to our sometimes longer
actually I'm your son yes you can so it
depends on your products so you found my
according to a sim so the pannier sim
some Jew recommends that you actually
Ford from the left server directly and I
know we're trying to get to the point
where we're forwarding on and everything
is actually coming from our centralized
login to whatever similar team because
our centralized login to do lot or
learning but it's not going to do
correlation we might be able to build it
in there but again acts with our sims
doing we don't want to take it away it's
not replacing our symbols even our send
better information and it's giving our
sim normalized data to be able to do the
things it does better right but it's a
lot a lot of a lot of places do you
recommend that they get me data directly
from the left servers themselves just
because of how the data is formatted so
you actually do have it's not depicted
on this but you'll have a collector
agent or some type of you have to
normalize the Windows Event format to
whatever you're filling it in a lot of
send vendors that you would pay for have
that correlation or that's that now that
I would say parsing built into their
products and you've made it has been
developed and it's very extensive others
you have to least have some type of
Trane's transporter for that we use
something called NX law and it actually
sends it into great log defect format so
it actually can translate when is it at
4-4 format to the great log extended
format and things like that and that's
when you get into the really neat Gritty
of the development and architecture of
that something like HP arcsight or
something or Splunk they all have their
way to be able to just read the windows
of that data because they're they
develop those parsers and engines like
that anyone have any more stories around
that okay how does that work out we
trust in the gray level different times
and every time we just keep the
resources that it serves like yeah it's
not repurposed maybe like it like in a
VM bonus or something along those lines
I can to try and proof of concept it's
where we could get it working but it's
always it seems like the resources are
never enough for what somewhat how much
resources have you uh how many men how
many events per second are you trying to
get messages per second literally the
first we've got is we've got stood up
and and losing a thousand once you start
getting into the thousands you it's not
gonna take it you're gonna have to have
a a multi-tiered architecture to take
that it's gonna have the same we have
same similar issues and and that's gonna
be honestly true with any type of
centralized logging system but like if
you have a Splunk or anything similar
something like that it is in take
resources now obviously things like
Splunk
they might not be as many architectural
layers like this but it might actually
be like that just you might not be aware
of these that's gonna be a appliance box
or in the cloud or something
again there's definitely learning curve
in the architectural and I recommend if
you run into the thousands again to look
at the ancient proxy installation and
documentation stuff through click rate
law you know a lot better experience but
it is a learning curve and stuff to go
through we went through about three or
four different environments before we
got one that was usable start using a
company-wide also the caveat with I
don't know if it's been changed but I
know a lot like registering more than
thirty years old memory had it where it
first had issues I went I went to an
elastic search object training and one
of the developers was telling us but
basically he walks around to incident if
you figure to give it that much memory
you need to senses and that's why we've
learned some more things like I can't
speak on this specifics to my
specific staffing on that but I know
that that was an issue in some forms of
was memory it was something else and
that's why we actually set up those six
servers or an account right there and
they're not like all running 32 gigs are
all running only 16 gigs they're not
actually that powerful but just having
separate instances went very far as the
stability of the environment and that's
just a learning curve of the entire you
know alas using of something like
elastic search and we have our you know
you get to a point where you know you
might have some of the DBA developers to
ask you how you're using elastic search
because you might be the first you know
people using that more than the rest of
the whole development team or the IT
team stuff like that you know I'm not
the private side of some of the stuff I
do so we find I hate that
you know you can quickly search a lot of
stuff yes
all right I'm gonna go in some of our
specific dashboards and great log just
to show you some of the things I wish
this was a little light like because
it's a lot clearer online anything
anyway sorry about that so you can
actually read some that stuff but I'll
go through it again this is our AP
overview this is a this is a a there are
a lot of templates that great log has
for dashboarding we took one modified it
again it's very easy to create
dashboards the backend of these
dashboards are just they're just tiles
and that even really - sportsman they're
operational metrics really and it's just
a query format that constantly will show
you a query and some type of
visualization it can do just basic pie
graphs and other types of just
visualization it's not gonna do anything
like students it's not give you anything
like the mana it's not gonna do anything
like an actual full dad dashboard
visualization tools I'm gonna be power
bi or anything like that it's you we
we've got a little very far and having a
log name that centralized logging
environment other than our sim for our
engineering and infrastructure to have
access to be able to see a lot of this
data without having to give them some
type of delegated access to a sim and
then trying to teach them how to use the
sim and parse through it and do all
these things a lot more
at least in our aspect that's worked
well for us so if you look at some of
this stuff it's tracking RDP usage
computers created accounts created clear
text log ons Pro Microsoft's things
Windows Firewall days out there we can
see the app Locker data events are down
there that is being tracked failed
logins all across the board
PowerShell use again and the batch
service log on to count deletions anti
forensics things like this I'm not gonna
go through each one of these these are
there's like an actual date range this
looks
mostly there seven days some I think all
of them are seven days so it might be
one day but mostly they're all seven
days and this is something that you can
see and visualize very quickly to see
the RDP users it's nice to be able to
see if there's an influx of crazy RDP
usage and then slowly I know some of the
projects that I've been working on is
it's restricting and going through and
setting everything to already be
gateways and really eliminating the use
of RDP and things like that that's
something we would work on stretching
the tracking that throughout the
environment some of these people see
like these dashboards helpful they would
have dashboards like this or that useful
with the products they add or anything
as yeah something somewhere yeah if you
have Splunk you're like yeah you guys
you guys got the my tribe unison yeah I
think people have Splunk in here okay
yeah so if you want to save like 600,000
billion now you could spend the the
agony to switch over to something like a
log there are things that spunk does
amazingly but there's a lot of things
that something like great log is
essentially a lightweight version of us
funky boys great long does have an
Enterprise version gives you a lot more
support and ease of use and simplicity's
that spunk has again it's not gonna do
everything Splunk does a lot of things
that we talked about we mentioned the
high we'll get into that there's a lot
of components and licensing modules that
this pumped that Splunk does that does
the same things but again you paint a
lot of money for this and if you have
that and you can do that that's great I
would I would have been today without
wood I would go through a Splunk
instance if I could have the resources
it's definitely beautiful to them say
well sure it does yeah
anyone have any other well you go to the
dashboard here again was hoping to be
able to actually play with these things
and give access tool but this is a
specific security one this again
track-and-field logons retail logon
reasons and top 5 keys and usage and
things like that these seem like large
numbers but they're not really large
data but we did but how many people do
not have an account lockout policy
everyone has walk out policy how many
people have protective security groups
and able to people know what that that
is how many people have that enable
haven't even tried to enable that so we
have that enable and that was why that
number is that large again it's dangling
the stings out there trying to log on
scripts and things like that that we've
locked down and it's not it doesn't
actually have any operational impact
it's just dangling things out there that
people clean up that are attempting to
authenticate the protective security
groups are something that you can it is
possible to enable we have been able dit
and we've used things like tracking like
tracking the items like this to really
see where the issues are before we did
that as we migrated user sent to that
any of the hurdles are on type of
security groups like to share
it was a fight malaria BC management yes
it's still ongoing but I have Windows is
definitely doing some things right now
Microsoft and Tigers here here is
definitely a very interesting thing to
look into if you don't look into that I
recommend looking ups on the
documentation on that the restrictions
and the default framers it puts around a
account it's very interesting and
there's things that are probably in that
back over there somewhere
you will not read and you will not see
you're not understand exactly what it
happens it will things will happen we do
that just test it and understand it it's
fun stuff you got the first step done
which was separating their normal long
if you want to do Prudential
partitioning here maybe no credential
partition it really means
I feel no credentials are there we go I
got there now we'll meet in the middle
so critical partitioning I'm sure that
luckily you are aware that but it's when
you have separate essentially separate
accounts separate potentials first or
activities and then forcing that fire so
usually your domain admins he's the
kingdom of some type of account that
only has that access those those
accounts cannot log on to end-user
stations it can only log on to main
controllers you only log on domain
controllers you've not log on the
servers you don't log on to your PC
don't log on to a end-users PC with
domain admin credentials because what
happens when you do that what happens
what happens it captured what has
forever
cassia's the credentials right mr.
elevated economists are consignee
elevated we have that privilege here's
our RSA tokens in order to know on top
of that that's good esa if you factor a
multi-factor some type of other factor
authentication yeah um if you were using
a Microsoft in my face last week no MFA
Monday ok yeah so that's that's very
interesting we we do have experimented
or we have on the tool that experiments
things like uni keys and things like
that
right now we have specific VDI machines
that they can only log into the domain
admin account for that VDI machine up
their actual computer so it's gotten
those credentials off those the actual
end user machine that you you email a
lot of stuff with credential
partitioning can go even further to the
server environment as well as the end
user environment and then also the end
user the display to local admin and
things like that if needed in very
special use cases that is called how
many people are familiar with the
Microsoft tiered model security to your
model I recommends if you don't look
that up it'll be I'll put that in some
my notes to it's not really so your
operations automation but it is also
linked you was just feeling there's a
jackass in here so so look that up they
have a tiered model going from tier to
tier 1 to tier 0 look that up again that
will help enrich and and and and focus
your automation capabilities so right
now instead of having to log all the
machines that Dumanis could have access
to we only have to log certain machine
or or put alerts around certain machine
it's literally enforceable only on those
it helps your automation we need to use
some of these segmented accounts and
clear credential partitioning and also
helps you want you to do that there's a
partitioning it's actually put people in
the protective users group you guys man
again it's only domain admin a con
anyway put that if you try to put a
regular user and protective users group
that is going to be very interesting
because again a regular user does things
that that will also enforce and make it
the common use of whole potentially I'm
sure there's probably a way to do it and
I'm sure Microsoft will tell you but
it's definitely usable higher tier
levels okay now I'm going to go on to
SNMP minor how many people are familiar
with libra NMS anyone heard of this
anyone do have like a slower ones
equivalent or some type of network
monitoring system that mon-sol slow-mo
sub-goals us what's what's up gold okay
what's up cool okay cool you know that a
lot of those network wiring tools like
what's up gold as well as the solar ones
have an ipod ipad built-in i don't know
about the gold specifically has an extra
license on I know that for once you
usually I could put clear on this as I
Pam license if you have Florence you can
use an eye Pam just like you could PHP I
Pam just to let you know that while your
tools might have some these capabilities
and you take advantage away this is
something that we use it actually
connects it has a native integration
with PHP I Pam that would be great if
they have the same order huh that would
be great as you know are the same owners
but they have native integration they're
not why I'm saying missus I've got a one
group of solar lands and another group
that manages the Iban that they don't
want oh wow we really have a very unique
similar environment that's why we
created the I Pam we actually in our
environment very interesting do you have
a separation of your wide area network
team and you're like same local area
networking yes
that's what it is that's what we have to
build a lot of buildings and facilities
we have it's set up like that and
they're separate teams interesting so
again this is I want to get to the point
of this again it's Network modern tool
it's getting SNMP information so you can
actually get how many people are what
the information you have is well there's
a config change on a router switch does
would your sim know that something was
modified to a critical component and
alert you of that all changes go right
to your sim and you just review those
like every I just irritants so all
changes go okay notable action look up
how many other people would notice a
route change on one of their hundreds of
riders and with that would you know that
anyone do any automation around that of
approvals of network changes like that
perfect changes the network team has
they use Europe to track all their
changes requests really these giraffes
interesting because we had the kirkenes
10 different ticketing systems ticketing
three months like your console that
being the ticket like I'm not getting
anything you know but yeah yes oh Jesus
our track but yeah I feel that we have a
lot of group big water changes and I'll
see a ticket come in with like 30
different things and then I'm like wow
that was the same time hmm okay yeah
definitely definitely a problem and we
actually have we do have sword wounds we
have a separate lead random-ass system
so we can track configs and changes
separately and holistically I
even though that somewhat of a
redundancy but again it's happy API you
know whole bar systems that play at
Richmond data things like that I'm gonna
skip to slides I think to right here
I'll go back to that but this is an
example of Lieber animus and showing a a
civic Cisco device amount of utilization
it had Paris name its mother for people
in the camera Paris we have horses in
here we have all kinds of things so yeah
so this is this does the sinks in that
and it can fix and the changes and you
can go in and put specific words on that
you can do that with for once you do
that word for what's up gold and things
like that but again if you're doing it
are you doing a way that's then pushing
back to something that you can actually
see that event data quickly without
going to different systems I'm gonna go
through the over here back to the last
slide I must have must a slides up but
this is like a basic environment that we
have right here again we have the PHP
type am we also utilize things with just
we're we have multiple things to do
multiple things but they are focused
areas so we might have a specifics in
that think are going to we do use
awesome insert areas because we give
better data and we want to look at those
those things with just different
configurations and we don't want to we
don't have the licensing budget to pay
for those so we just cut some configure
OSEM on a small network our environment
and again all the data feeds back up and
we also have again the hive is going to
be a huge piece and it's orchestration
again a lot of the things are built on
elastic and great logs kind of the focus
of that with the vet collector as well
as annex love and then we kind of have
Libra and a message
Smt and we have which is not the open
source further this but we could have
rocket seven we don't have we only have
an expose as pravara building management
again you see that we have open boss up
there too so reps I was only doing our
critical assets and things like that I
do it some passive scanning so this is
just an example of an environment that
we had there's a lot more in here this
is just some of the components that
we're talking about here for
orchestration do you was Pro though we
have tested bro on our network and doing
some things we had a we were clean bro
on raspberry pi's on sort of subnets and
trying to track lateral movement things
like that or certain that we might not
have as much visibility and we had some
good it was good but we just got the
data three other other means and the
other thing that we had we had up
instead we had the monitor honeypot
network the kittens things like that you
can actually it's a police through
stretch scream it's also free just some
interesting things not as much as the
obviously grow but you can run some
funny class up on bro we also had a
problem with forty bro logs and making
sense of them in other systems it was
nice to analyze on the system we also
tried secure e onion places and the
other thing that was very interesting
that we use and I would like to use
again was if you ever heard of selfs has
anyone I'm gonna grow cells they
wouldn't heard of Cercado so sir so
celtuce who are kind of built in the out
stack it's one package it's my company
believe they're open and either French
Germany and it's it's good it's really
nice I recommend trying it out I know
that I want to try
one and a half before we got a lot of
good information from it but it's a
learning curve because we had to support
a full-out staff and that's one of the
reasons we want a great log to the
assist yet we got the available early
the the quickness of the searching and
responsiveness of the search database
with the simplicity of not having to go
through a full help staff support so you
think great log hard to put try to put
an elk stack in there and forward things
to it that's quite the no alien holds
does it uses cercana alienvault has a
Cercado as well as snore and all kinds
of queries I have is essentially like a
security onion where's a lot of things
are in there hmm
yeah circa is nice we used her credit
for some of our some of our IPS systems
at our perimeter and I'll bomb egress
but it's not built on the elastic belt
stack or anything like that she's
basically Cercado
the lock people know some of the
differences of Cercado the snork just
for the general audience how long the
processing yes yes yes so Cercado works
a lot more multi-threaded I can do a lot
of things parse it also has different uh
different rule set script there's a lot
of different things that's one of the
primary differences of snore at least or
might not have a multi processor one now
I'm unaware but I know that for a long
time those were ending factors and and
that was some of the things why we could
run
circuit and a lot larger environment was
the lower resources okay again okay now
we're getting tend to do anyone want
take a break real quick five minutes are
you guys good I'm gonna break
I don't know
[Music]
yeah
oh yeah yeah did you
[Music]
really start
which is like second and I kind of go
through all the records also failures
where people can automate stuff then
just never document it or anything so
yeah
it is a well his name is Eric he's my
business partner and I just wanna wrote
this in his face that was important that
was started back okay you talked about
some automated fishing especially off
fishing poles that like kind of that you
had a user would be like have a button
then we give the report back not just
obviously forwarded email did something
that has so Microsoft actually are you
365 so Microsoft actually have it'll
build it now you can get the add-on
they've always had a report fish like
I'm building there but they actually
have a enter an enterprise customization
add-on into 365 now it's relatively new
so I'm something more than message
drizzle oh yeah yeah you can actually do
it in the 335 admin console you actually
it's an add-on and you can put on
everyone have a report to button another
thing separate of that that I recommend
is no before no before is kevin Mitnick
secured weirdest platform fishing so
they have a lot of free tools one of
them is a fish button all so what only
called you customize it you can clearly
give it an address to go to and put it
you can upload it or install it and
execute a bowl on every one so it will
show up in there now the client before
you can install as an XML add-on within
the 365 Council so every user will have
it inside of either OWA or on the 365
client
inside the message you won't get metrics
from that you will just get it forwarded
if you don't know before splat form of
kevin mitnick's actual full platform
it'll give you all the metrics so that
you can do fish and simulations that you
do a nice congratulations and things
like that
number four has also a slew of free
tools like branson that will simulate
ransomware on
machine in a way of knowing if there's
three shares and stuff like that and
connect to there's like they'd like 24
different random tool is doing they
could do they can if you connect into
your active driver you digging your skin
will see like the top 1000 passwords and
all kinds of like you know all kinds of
just general tools like that so no
before I thought slew of free tools that
you can use so yeah so there are a few
other vendors out there that have been
offering for you fish buttons and things
like that so I'm sure there's father are
loving that can I compare them all I
started using fish buttons when they
were like with no through no before when
they first start implementing like three
years ago so before that my previous and
employer
we actually custom put in a fish button
in the lowest note and that was the blue
description awesome our user request and
I teaching systems in there - it's still
next today we're starting back up
everyone ready fueled up yeah we cut cut
all the other people that don't want to
hear anything we have meat we have all
the cream cream the cream that's well
MSP always hadn't covered them so let's
see if I can tell Adrienne the time is
or ten note that my so I could tell all
right so this is a an example of
security operation management platform
specific call the hi there are links the
hive is on github
you can look at that they also have is
called the high project if you want to
Google that and goes the high project
net and you can go through there a lot
of good information there there's also
something specific to look at the github
there you can look up for the high
project training VM and you can download
that and you can upload that into a
virtual box and you can have the full
high platform will actually go through
that and I'll show you it I don't say I
will show you the platform as a straight
instance I don't have a lot of stuff in
there which I did have a full workshop
but this is the basic components of the
high there are other engines in there
the hive is basically made up of a few
different components they kind of call
it the three-in-one security platform it
has the security operations as a
security orchestration piece which is
called the cortex engine everywhere you
see like a little brain there that is
the cortex engine it's essentially
working as the management of different
types of integrations and customizations
and scripts that we get loaded through
the cortex and then the hive itself is
essentially a case management system in
ticketing system that will be able to
visualize and track whatever alerts and
instances come up and then match that
data with other enrichment data so it
will go through specific examples of
that also the other component that is
very integrated and compatible with a
hive is something called Miss other than
the other high persons everyone know
what anyone else know what miss is yeah
this okay good our information sharing
platform all right so the Miss is just
like has a lot of open threat fees how
many other people are familiar with like
otx alienvault OGX right very some what
I want to say it's similar but I even
get LTX feeds again you can get a lot of
feeds into the
nice thing about the Miss and I'm sure
other tools have this tube that you can
actually create I'll say a si firewall
rule things like that off of an
observable or IOC or other types of
things how many people don't have a Palo
Alto same when I pull out those really
if you have might melt integrated in
that you just have everything got an
innocent guy might know you got how
anymore as well but and then they'd be
covered tomorrow as well oh yeah so mind
meld is a lot of good I get your pain
you know for a product or things like
that but also has mine melt
I recommend looking mind build-up and
how it works and a lot of orchestrations
and things you can get at the other day
if you have something come in there's an
observable a testable attach this a lot
of your Richmond data also you know okay
I have to implement actual and it might
not just be block IP address block
domain it might be a port certain types
of network traffic and to be able to
create those rules on the fly it again
takes more time if it takes 20 minutes
to you to to find your I see I have this
asset inventory to know what it is and
then other twenty minutes to understand
what to do with that and for even if you
have all the information and then
another 20 or 30 minutes to create a
rule that you know it's gonna work if
it's a little complex a lot of engines
now can right-click kind of create and
put that IOC in observable in psycho
rule format so you can actually put it
into your firewall so it's not just a
basic like a lot of them might have your
rules they might have some more rules to
to detect but then how do you prevent
that in an a essay you know Cisco
product or Alto you know for Scott
whatever you have right and a lot of
items when I'm over straighten that and
making that user again going through
through this again you have the case
templates your cases going back to the
basics and foundations is if you do you
the people that had a lot of the
automations you have instant
classification like so you have you you
have a
of instances that come in as opposed
your sim it kind of escalates into an
actual incident on the so those are
things that you can recreate and map
into something like this make sure that
you're all talking the same language as
well as classifying and what they
classify in the sensitivity of the data
to because again the malware sharing
information platform if you're in a
trusted workgroup or like we're local
government we might want to share some
of our indicators with other local
governments you actually choose to share
what we want for classifying all of our
data and I know seized off of that so
and if we want to share something to the
general community we can classify that
as well just the overall whole case so
if some of you guys are familiar with
something like the TLPs traffic like
protocols of being white amber or green
things like that because labeling
classifying data how sensitive and how
much you want to share that for data
sharing things like that so you every
case that blows your cases you get your
alerts or missed events in there so
you're constantly getting alerts misses
something that would also tie into like
your centralized blog infrastructure
that see are you getting indicators or
getting IPs and things like that from
things of knowing malicious activity or
once you put something into the case if
it's a phishing email or if it's if
you're even manually putting something
in there an incident it will
automatically go through and analyze if
there's reported missing a doe or other
types of malware feeds and things like
that and then once you go into the
analyzers in observables it has things
like the iPad built in api's and
analysis and most known I would say
analysts use tools so when you get an IP
address what do you do with that IP
address let's go through this there's
none of that what do you guys do you get
IP address something that's bad or
domain what do you do what what's the
first thing you guys do there's no right
and wrong answer here check this
reputation so what do you when people
could use check reputation
Petey Petey Petey Michael okay anyone
else do something else right something
like that no combination huh abuse IP
good okay involves towels right the main
tool who is right just basically showed
in you no good right anything else right
or any type of URL scanner right out
there right or maybe your products
built-in right if you have Cisco it
might be going through again towels that
we said Palo Alto might be checking my
metal or just your products blocking
right so again those those analyzes all
connecting those systems imagined you
all go out there manually check those
things usually I mean know you guys got
that or straight through spunk maybe or
something right so a lot of sins
automatically check against things like
bill TX and to maybe other types of
feeds
maybe they pay for feeds right so again
getting those things and tying them into
did anybody have like a malware sandbox
that they use charlie anyone malware
sandboxing nobody malware sandboxing
will services sandbox will you
he's their sandbox or okay so you can so
you when you're analyzing something it's
in like a sandbox like I explorers out
there or whatever your PDF or something
you're opening a sandbox okay with fire
okay but the end if you're a member of
the InfraGard yeah so Bob huh guarding
at our best scarier kind of tips so if
you're in local government you have
access to something similar than for
guards through
the m SI saket it's a generally just a I
think it's too strong threat stream
right also if you use like anomaly or
something other thing that you use the
sandbox if you ever anywhere I've heard
a cup Co sandbox being right it's an
internal sandbox again a lot of those
things if you know that someone's got as
much as PDF and things like that and
they reported the email through this
system instead of just having it and be
able to do all that analysis and we'll
walk through this ad hoc you can
actually tie into some of the api's
virustotal
or you can actually get an api a lot of
your systems lot systems already have
that you can connect in there I don't
know InfraGard probably doesn't have an
API with it but I know that other
platforms like the ones that we have for
local government you have an API key
that we can just put in and
automatically do it and send the report
back and you also be able to see the
report in the system itself so those are
some of the things that you want to do
when you get and then the announced
report will already be there so all
those things can happen right when the
users are reporting something and or
alert is kicked off so you have all that
data already enriched and you have all
that data already there for you to
analyze and you can already understand
if you know what if I get a domain that
came through as a phishing email and the
domain went through but I know that
learned what my web filter or proxy is
already blocking that I'm probably going
to put that on a lower priority list to
look at then something that isn't being
blocked by the web filter or any type of
other a firewall or defense-in-depth
machine or system makes sense fun stuff
all right so just also mention just a
few other operation management and
orchestration tools that are out there
to look up and again don't be in the
notes that when I release this what I'll
probably do is just so you guys know
I'll probably contact the organizers and
have them send out to everyone that's
registered and probably will probably
just be on their website or something
like that all that information that I
have here
but the other things to look up or
something CrowdStrike
has the falcon the orchestrator there's
anyone and had any experience with that
it's an open-source project actually
open source that I would say it's
somewhat let's say somewhat limited
obviously they want to do these they're
full tool anyone heard of that use that
that's interesting to look at if you're
in an orchestration specifically
security orchestration Homeland Security
actually the tool called walk off
remember that interesting illustration
is cool
so I recommend if you haven't I think
it's not even the information assurance
division anymore but it's literally the
NSA's github hub if you look through the
NSA's github not their github of
everything but argument okay hub they
have a lot of PowerShell tools a lot of
how many people are familiar with stakes
stakes right so I mean if you get the
stage you're getting that from a DoD of
some form right NSA has a very large
repository and their github of security
policies Windows GPOs all kinds of
things that are right for the picking to
be able to use as well as orchestration
things and tools and stuff like that
definitely something to look at um so
death to email works right this is
additional integrations again this is
something called
sensor you guys using the worst to hide
that right 500 oh yeah I got a bunch of
calls I was like you didn't get all
right so are you guys using these
synapse to Lola that's newer and the
newer hive instance within the past I
think three or four months it's a one
point one right now they actually fully
connect into exchange to have an
exchange connector now so they can read
a lot
emailed a lot better and before it was a
Python parser which works I
but now it's and I still believe it's
built in Python but again and in the
hive is built a Python module so
anything is extensible with a Python
they have actually everything cause it's
literally called the hive or PI so they
have an entire documentation on that for
the hive connector so everything is
going through essentially a like
service-oriented architecture and a name
system so you can you're able to extend
the functionality tremendously because
using one one one centralized connector
there so so it's interesting it's it's
it connects outside of the cortex right
into so the cortex has a lot of is
essentially the analysis engine and then
the height also has like a extension
that's called for the the four pi part
of it and it all goes back into the hive
and the cortex but it's kind of like
they built off the extension module
something a little separate so you can
build in separate cortex engines but you
can also then build in fees through the
actual hive so everything goes it's row
thrown in through the cortex engine it's
just the input from it so again they
have built in against like when you go
back to here this is more in the
specifics of this area right here so
then once everything goes in it's still
coming down through here through the
cortex engines before there were cortex
engines directly there are also cortex
engines to analyze and parse the email
now what is happening though it's
happening on this side so it's actually
getting it normalizing the data so I can
do more with it so synapses yeah it's
essentially a
I'm not an architectural software
engineer but it's like a middleware
parser we'll go through it I'll actually
go through the email analyzers and more
detail so and then the hive recently
also has a built in native integration
with IBM QAR again that's native you can
build everything in custom as well so I
think they already have one for Splunk
let's talk about there so I think that
was their first one so we have browsing
time so I'm going to try to do this
since I am limited here and actually
browse through some stuff so I'm gonna
get out outside of this it's going to be
interesting how I'm gonna do this I get
it right here hold it okay
there's my boom okay so I want to go
through some of the stuff that to talk
about again this is the hive box
it's the documentation within the I
project and so going through here I'm
just going to kind of go through some of
this training material they have an OVA
for the training module you can download
this and go through again that includes
on the top of the high of the cortex
engine again the the API kind of
connector engine which is the hive for
PI the cortex for PI which again is a
different connector for that and any
available cortex and analyzer there so
that is what you get there are also more
to go through so I can get all this this
is kind of the architecture here of the
hive specifically so it is also built on
elasticsearch which is nice the front
front end there has a bunch of rest api
is a quartet cortex engine is there
where it goes through the different
types of analyzers and responders
responders or the things that just come
back essentially with information
externally so that is the why I went
through the workflow architecture
already that is what the hive does look
like we'll go more in-depth into that
and yeah so just want to kind of talk
about how the court's attention and
place with that and everything so we're
gonna go through go back the training
again you can get it you go through and
download this there's previous versions
beta versions
but you know how to category we use it
there's a lot of documentation here
that's all I'm gonna go throw on that
the thing that I want to go through
though is this synapse use case so this
is a synapse using case here it's a demo
I'm not going to go through and read
this work forward but essentially
someone has clicked or someone has
gotten an email and actually forward it
on to the cert team however that is
again if that's through again and here
saying that she attached it as an MSG
file how many people try to explain
users and the training that attach
attach emails to send it to the how how
fun is that or an announcement right
Microsoft changing outlook how you do it
every question always is walking on the
school yeah and that's why buttons are
amazing
take one thing that's not even superior
illustration really related other than
the source find an email reporting
button it changes the life of like
training and awareness and you will get
a lot of people clicking that button we
have people that will click that button
on every spam email and I say spam email
I mean more like like marketing email I
get junk email will get every morning
will get thirty four the same person at
the end of the day we can call them up
and say hey report this as a business
at least they're reporting it to us
right we get we get people don't forward
look at an indication that hey just say
though we just put this into a span
because it's spam probably not you don't
forward that but they think that emails
and the little thing else painful turn
actually female because we got to the
point where when certain Department sent
out communications and they don't say
put a signature or they just it's just
weird we'll get a whole thing we have to
watch out our orchestration piece so you
automatically start blocking internal
communication that's just a carful thing
that we have it's kind of interesting so
you get the email forwards to the cert
team look at that it says dear cert team
isn't that beautiful
it might not be nothing just in case
again there's a so now that and this is
interesting because we didn't do this at
first with orchestration of I've been
learning this through the synapse I
didn't really think about this because
we just had automatically go to the hive
and just get the email inboxes just like
a just a transport mechanism really this
is kind of interesting them so what what
the hive is is suggesting this use case
is setting up custom categories in the
shared outlet box for your searching on
for every one of your users or your your
your security sock analysts once it
categories as that it will automatically
create the case it will say that that
person that's essentially setting that
that person is working on it and so then
and what they do is they actually have a
manual intervention that they drop the
folder into a specific folder name
called the hive so the highest
constantly looking at the folder name
some people as this is using this
certainly we actually have a spam at our
domain dot just add our domain so that's
what this fans going it doesn't go to
our thirteen other stuff those are to
some people everything goes to their
search team so depends on a hug so
that's why ours the transport mechanism
they're all it's all spam filling it the
only thing is going there is directed
spam through that system nothing else
but this prevents potentially if you
have one IP security
at or if you had IR at you just had
every user security at you could
actually control so not everything that
people will send you is going to the
hive are going to your frustration
platform put a folder and you put lies
around that so again they're drag and
drop it into the hive as you can see
there and see the right high folder okay
it goes down so now there's a get
request going to synapse and it goes in
and it goes through the API and again
the the specific URL that that system
was coming from as you saw was from
stargazer or so synapse actually does
the FT QT the fqdn and sends it toward
let's see I'm kind of follow this we are
not using snaps yet I'm actually looking
forward to it it seems like it had a lot
more flow engine and the basic email
parser that's in the four pie so again
Electric creates a task at a science' to
EE which was the person that actually
categorized it it gets created as
strange email from and that person again
it's all built in however you want this
the workflow or go through some of these
things are built into the hive directly
like as I said of TLPs
you want everything coming from a
specific income of having a student EOP
and then you can lower or higher that as
you go through manually in the process
you'll see the case created again inside
the hive you actually create tasks for
each case so again the synapse created
the name communication and so it will
actually connect the the full the full
email body to the thirteen their
attachment handling their
attachment there these are what we're
called talking about the observables
there so that's an order form the PDF if
you drag anything into a hive case it'll
automatically create it and put the file
name there and if you have observables
or you have systems connecting the
virustotal
automatically run that through wax poles
camp and get you the summary of the
results and let's see if that comes
through here again that's going through
it's the summary of the email message
here automatically has the headers in
there so when you reply back and it also
sees the team so when you're adding any
information inside the hive this isn't
showing a lot of the information so I've
sorry I kind of I knew this just came
out of those good users for this class
but so inside the hive when the person
put in communication the task
communication it actually will
automatically email that person
something using a chain connector so
like we have inside of the cert inside
of our cert thing or inside of our strip
email we had it set up where I meant to
notify the user that we'll work out the
case that's just a cultural thing how
many people have that set up an auto
reply or something like that what you
can do is you can essentially get
auto-replies as you put and work in the
case information to update the user if
you want to do that
open this good since I'm gonna have to
just go into the hives correctly this is
going through configuration ok that's
not showing what I want to show what I
wanted to show is it takes the PDF it
runs through BIOS folder comes back it
creates the rules within this I'll see
if I can get
all right all right so we'll go through
and just go through some of these things
and a little bit to one of the exercises
that have built up so all the way to top
here you could see the summary of all
the analyzers can everyone read this I
was hoping that that use cases and
synapse things notes itself don't use
walkthrough documentation that you don't
know it really says so you're a lot of
the pre analyzer that's built into the
high that you can attach through the
cortex engine again a lot of people have
mentioned abuse abuse finder Utku
sandbox if you have a KU sandbox running
obviously you have to have some of these
systems running D shield email parser
again that was what will take in and
actually parse through the email for IP
addresses and observable and other types
of domains and information will Safe
Browsing information I'm not going to go
through every one of these we missed
this morning lists OGX query can query
your otx api you go through threat crowd
your else can do which is actually very
interesting if you guys don't use that
before one of my engineers saw that like
i think maybe a year ago it's very
interesting to me to use the repor gives
you a screenshot a lot of their other
one that do it to it does it very well
to give you a screen shot of the website
and things like that
you can kind of like crowdsource what
other people are reporting things like
that again analyze you're requesting
special access that means that you need
some type of account or specific maybe
small paid API access things uh always
do they have IBM x-force upon you that
there's showed an is essentially the one
I wanted connect their every I believe
Black Friday Christmas time and holiday
show dan has a a a deal where you can
get like a five dollar lifetime deal API
the showdown I recommend getting that
many people have a showdown accounts
like an actual account have you got it
during the five dollar window of course
well of course right so if you don't
know that they have a I'm sure that
Sealy just runs year-round but it's
always randomly watch of Twitter it'll
be a five dollar deal I don't even know
what it is normally it's 50 bucks okay
yeah it's always on Black Friday is
always on like various holidays and
things or like I decide to so recommend
doing that and connecting that up just
general general thing is that how many
of you shooting on a regular basis when
you're doing that what do you actually
put it in to look up that's kind of a
good question but usually the IP address
are going Ange you put anything else in
there mmm-hmm you can actually on
vacation summer vacation you can put
your a SMS as well if you guys didn't
know that versus your whole essentially
IP block potentially it see everything
in that so to put in IP range where you
can monitor screen a it's a lot easier
to do they also just recently put docker
instances of their scanning up there so
that was just reset I think there's like
first day or something like that I don't
know how recent it was it might be a
month old I want to read Twitter every
couple whole times a year but that's
something where they had up there again
subscription-based if you have domain
tool subscriptions other types of things
emerging threats and subscriptions nessa
subscriptions so yeah and buyers hole we
can actually the subscription to it as
well you get the kind of special wires
hole feeds that they have record
features also on there does anyone use
something stuff like record future and
go threat intelligence systems but you
know people said they miss you guys use
any other type of threat Intel
emphasized the ice axe okay the useful
friends still or no Walter you still use
a little edge okay yeah so again those
are the analyze specific we're not gonna
go to much students again is not really
like a full working workshop here
other things that I want to go over I
have up okay this is I'm logged me out
so very connector now this is again this
is the training version of it can
literally just be uploading the OVA up
passwords are the hives and the high of
one two three four change those when you
get in there this is essentially what
you're going to see I I tried when I had
this up phone in there I didn't want to
fully set up and start putting
observables you actually do have to
connect the cortex analyzer as an API
didn't suffer to start working so this
is this an example of like a domain
photoscape th things like that and you
can start going through the way you
caste alerts this is kind of like the
nice thing that it creates and and if
you have a full sub platform it does
this you know does all the open cases
case
status tags resolutions we have the
security department do more things in
the dorsum we fulfill what usage reports
we fulfill forensic reports we fulfill
vulnerability analysis and remediation
just random investigations that come
rogue things and the network all those
things things aren't in our operations
management and we don't want to put
those in our IT ticketing system because
the IC ticketing system isn't built to
have all those things and to upload
malicious PDFs and start analyzing them
and hold them because previously we used
to just do that and just have those
malicious PDFs I'm like a hard drive on
one of our analyst machines and that's
not much better so how did other people
here do you guys have one kind of use
your IT ticketing system for all stuff
security operations use your own use a
combination of all your tool and their
own take main system right that's it
were kind of in right now is that some
of our investigations can't be in the
ticket system you if we had it built in
because it's a can't right and this is
kind of one of the tools that we can
build in and even if you don't have a
cortex engine or analyze or observer
attached to everything it's still a
central place to put it in and start
tracking the case management we we
haven't done this we haven't even really
researched this but it's kind of an IV
idea of our IT team they want to have
centralized metrics so we're talking
about create an API just to created
there was a case you know and the case
ideas of this and maybe put certain
metadata around it but not nothing more
than that
so ease the metrics can be and the IT
team service desk team and stuff could
be happy that we have our metrics there
and we're doing something and we're not
in our own black box doing row ticketing
so we looked at interoperating like that
anyone else look at that life is your
because your Splunk has like a ticking
system kind of built into it right is
that inter operated with your IP
thinking system awful is that not really
taking the system as well as fun really
I'm an MSP they have an app for it it
doesn't do anything how about the the
hive user in the back here what have you
guys been building this out you this
looks familiar I assume so your arm what
cortex analyzers are really using or you
kind of just play with it oh we use DNS
to use DHCP we use virustotal
we use email but not the synapse through
the do the analysis on it there again
we're still in the fans ability right so
as you can see this is the case but then
there's the cortex engine here we can
have job histories and like how things
are being pushed off and you can
manually analyze things you can put
certain types of rules around automatic
analysis tie to certain cases and things
like that you could essentially build a
whole workflow engine in here I'm not
gonna go through building an entire one
or anything attacks are probably because
this Ram training OVA probably won't be
able to talk outbound or do anything but
that is essentially what you're playing
up is a lot it's very simple once you
put your mind to it and you kind of
focus on it
and it helps a lot better than the one
place so that is some of those basic
demo stuff I want to be able to show you
guys let's go back to little some of the
slides here
no done surface so again that was the we
just looked at that's kind of it built
out a little more screen shot you can
see that there's like a lot of stuff
from the misfit in there again that's
like open source intelligence things
coming in you guys someone mentioned
here for guard right would you get this
flat how many other people are increment
you get flats messages pins or whatever
what when you when they have IP or of
IRC or they're both what do you deal
with those it is like hop casing from
that PDF file on just throw them into
like the thing right you guys do
anything one of them I always just don't
do nothing whatever to the panel get but
come with the rest of the flyer so a lot
of you can actually go in and do a lot
of parsing stuff so you can just upload
those parse it out and it found and I
could go through and enrich that data
and that doesn't seem like it's a big
thing that's a it is a big thing where
you can just drag and drop and go
through and see as long as the parser
engine works right you can see if
there's any hits
you don't really worry about it right
it's really nice especially if you get
we get intelligence from what was in CSV
format of like militias IP with stuff
from certain ice axe and things like
that and it just gets become a lot of
data even if it's easy to do just copy
and paste data all day into a into your
centralized log to be two or three F
teens just start doing that right sorry
ignore that we took a break later so but
it's a way heavy heat down some blackhat
there so
so exercise time my guys ready to
exercise tabletop time are you guys done
for the day
anything on the table to exercise on the
table all right if you've done exercise
before this is just general this is for
the 15-minute table tops I just start
with this again this is uh just
generally then the format and framework
of a quick tabletop exercise it's
against air on the meeting we're
learning parts points
don't make this narrow too large
essentially we needed out loves to the
whole groove will do that but that's you
know in a meeting setting and then use
the discussion page it's like a separate
discussion page which is kind of like an
index page that's really just like what
to discuss or around those or things you
want to focus on because you know
there's gonna be issues potentially and
then always take notes and any potential
gaps and identify any areas of
automation that could help in the
security operations again there's do's
and don'ts that's pretty straightforward
when go rain system area alright ready
for scenario time all right so while
reviewing access logs an alert was
raised to the employee attempting to
gain access to a network share file so
folder contain sensitive data which
requires a specific security group
membership under upon further inspection
you realize other folders that count has
been accessing that contains sensitive
data do not have any restricted
permissions but domain users web
filtering logs also show large uploads
to unknown cloud storage environment
that wasn't used by the enterprise again
I'm going to go right into essentially
the results of it and that's how these
the quicker table tiles kind of work is
that I ended up being email phishing cam
campaign
yes that's I need to work on that that
was Miss resulting in credential
compromise other credentials also used
for a DFS and SSO to VPN result in a
remote compromise the users machine
valid credentials then result in data
exfiltration how many people think as a
realistic possibility to happen in an
environment all right agreeable to crazy
of attack chain right how many people
are know the entire folder permissions
in their entire environment and monitor
that all right how many people know and
scan exactly how many folder my folders
can be accessed in NTFS permissions just
domain users right it's it's something
limited it's right so this could
definitely happen how many people when
you're monitoring what you're monitoring
monitor when someone's trying to act be
accessing or try to add a group over and
over over again even if it's
unsuccessful you and monitor that being
able was unsuccessful all right anyone
else in this in an unsuccessful attempt
not just successful yeah external would
you know that that group that folder
actually had sensitive data in it or not
that's the second favorite and that's
what's like HR right right exactly and
that's that's against do you have
folders that you know have sensitive
data or at least supposed to us the data
other people can put things and I guess
you know whole deal key modern stuff I'm
just saying like you have poverty that
you know that all these folders are
specifically set for sensitive data and
you have probably say hard-coded static
monitoring on those that in financial
little internal auditing
right because it's a lot of data they on
we use a tool called aromas I think for
our shares money two minutes health care
man that's we brought us a very good
talent yeah we used that to manage any
group bags and I'm structured down yep
that's exactly what so you would see
them throw it would easily see something
like that yeah you ever looked up bronze
is a very interesting tool it's very
expensive that bricks is another kind of
IDI
purchase tools like that the other thing
that you can use when is event that's
what those systems are using since using
record is using very well you got a put
the gloves on back away
automated so again the thing to take
here when you're looking at automation
and what to automate is looking at the
things in the bottom here I'm looking at
seeks my laptops kind of right here is
the time to fully investigate how long
will take you to fully investigate this
I kind of have general numbers in here
for a small business that has one or two
security guy hasn't maybe an IP
apartment of a few dozen or something
but what do you think throw numbers out
do you think don't sell yourself short
so yes this is like left he just saying
okay I don't want to learn I'll look
into this oh no I didn't know that lurks
think about your alert fatigue to over
this right yeah that's why it's an eight
hours of the three businesses right
you'll get probably six like my spam
emails in between getting that work like
this and hot stuff how long anyone like
you know the first one to know no one no
idea how long you get it officially for
you to realize in your environment
no 30 minutes our six thirty minutes for
fishing them now that we talked about
that right
potentially you know what the proneness
guys are they're like what happened to
just blocked it
we didn't those milliseconds there this
is just you in your current environment
with your skill set so again think about
that not only are you looking at the the
group membership we're also looking at
the web proxy logs or that we're about
also the compromising the VPN logins
that were probably anomaly anomalous and
then the phishing email that came in
that actually compromising because again
it was using valid credentials no we're
also trying to determine what was taken
no this is just fully investigate to to
what this is that you know what that
happened let alone whatever those files
would write and then how many people
would have to be involved so I have a
kind of number here like in your
environment you know if we have
segmented access or certain things how
many people you have to contact or
firewall team this isn't that how many
people are actually involved who do you
tell your manager does your manager tell
your manager is there you know how far
up does this go you know 15 people and
then when did it actually happen right
this is essentially manual analysis
right so I'm just putting this in there
as two months but it's just again
arbitrary numbers these are the numbers
and you think about you're looking at
scenarios like this let's see how would
you detect this and your environment
that's something to think about
yeah I think you definitely look at like
the activity level all right so I mean a
user if we look at this as a fish
successful fishing you know financial
harvest then I mean even I think even
your sophisticated tools if an indicator
of a user they got that that this
credential signs in during normal
business I return today I mean every
guy's credit on our proportion
have it and one user got the popular
pound ten minutes trying to login I mean
it depends on I guess when we initially
picked it up great so I'll go right into
the discussion points so every every 15
minutes a pop exercise that we do
actually goes back to the Miss functions
and you can probably put them all on
there in some portion but I've put a few
examples what we're always trying to put
in this function on there and then we
also have the discussion points here so
again how was it detected initially you
know manual analysis or the the spam
again you were talking about what key
items identified the RCA write files
being accessed long activity will have
activity again this is now our
credentials so it's not a felt nothing
would be now maybe there was an
anomalous RDP traffic right or maybe
there's an anomalous login to the VPN
maybe it was maybe you know that that
user only VPNs in like why did you
Canyon mill a day they are also logged
in right did you have anything that
checks and your products that checks
that a user is logged in internally and
you can at the same time just something
to think about it yeah that gets it that
extensive but even just that do you have
something that just checks again against
even if you have a baseline of one day
check they log in but just if someone
also logged into from an internal
machine and VPN des in from the outside
same time from the inside right yeah
right you could hear pin back in but
yeah so it's just like you have
something to detect that assuming that
it was interesting things for the MSSP
right you know you have an alert how
looks at correlation maybe maybe you
have the right campers
and you think of that completely you
have Melissa okay all right
is that would be something that you guys
probably might not would think about I'm
just discussion I don't have any of this
right now I'm just off top of my head
well in through some of these right you
know what else could you automate again
want to even look at you slow get into
the learning alerting and correlation
then what could you automate how did you
know you would go through and see who
was involved in the overall
investigation it was notified so for
instance once something maybe escalates
to a point where you know it's an
incident and the hive or whatever you're
in do you put okay now the work has to
go out to upper management right does
NEMA hood upper management says hey we
have an issue this might it's not a
critical issue yet but something we're
investigating oh like you know we might
need to get more staffing or golf maybe
additional Forensic Services where would
you or what point would you work into
getting in contact with the account but
we were saying hey and that meant all
into that sometimes we immediately jump
to conclusion that there's nefarious
activity and then we went to the account
holder and there's a use case that we
didn't write maybe they left their you
know their VPN session open at home set
to machines and you know then maybe how
they needed to access a sensitive
document because the ticketing system
wasn't working in a ticketing what their
ticket wasn't getting completed and they
were trying to act as his crew and they
couldn't and then all of a sudden you
know they had access to a different
group that had to fully domain user
access and then also they were just
copied stuff up maybe they have to work
from home because or work from different
locations they were traveling to
different location they were using some
cloud storage so it was shadow IQ right
it could be a use case right so when you
want you call to user queue it was go
back down to your policies procedures of
do you have policy around when you do
make sure
to contact when you have security event
information you guys have any guidelines
around that anyone response policy
regularly just shut it down there you
going so it's very interesting again and
can you work floaters so once you get an
instant like this into like something
like the hybrid orchestration there's an
automatic email or contact the user or
put a test in for the sake analyst and
manually called the users and put in the
notes what they expect right with all
those kind of automations that can help
you essentially go through your run
books like you have a run book or a play
book around how you do your instant
response processes or any other
procedural things you have and you can
just recreate those run books even if
the tasks are automated at least the
tasks are there created and then you put
in the data manually and that's still
getting into the foundational models of
some what security automation
orchestration and essentially walking
and analysts through if they put in a
phishing campaign now these are all the
things that either the system is going
to do automatically for you and rich
that data and this is what you should do
and one you should do it this is when
you call the users it's not when you
call user this is one you call me good
users manager and things like that what
do you think would cut down the total
time and it's something like this go
back to the original scenario but we the
most time extensive thing here in your
acid environment other than for honest
people most ability to protect our wine
right away it would have cut down if the
user would have notified somebody hey
this could potentially damages mhm
exactly the report to the one thing you
get from this get a report button
or if they would have maybe for the
email correctly an attachment all right
anything else does your security team
know the folder permissions and how
those should be assigned throughout your
entire environment or that's something
the engineering infrastructure well we
just admin under the desk
no yes
automation ideally ahead of time regular
scanners alert that says hey anywhere to
recognize brightness or not so those are
those are things that able to solve and
the activity that you can figure out
that is something that is a typical
monitor on that does anyone here have
something that analyzes exfil of data
exfil of data you're like a web proxy or
something or a proxy moderator so so if
you okay I upload 50 gigs to a random
Dropbox oh yeah I'm in total window we
can happen
alert the net flow data or something the
firewalls endpoint top-20 okay can't
Gatsby
yeah Gatsby would be a crying no that's
what I would do is I what we have
capable of a cache new solution that
would well I didn't say the task as B
solutions product has a shadow IT
okay anything else no one else detect
that he dresses supple at all
footwork games I mean we we detect
encrypted up was actually detected we
also hire to block all possible all
passwords as its categorized by a
product yes yes so new file storage or
somebody someone has like own cloud set
up on their home right I know those are
the things to think about
just as the devil's advocate right not
that you have to have an answer for
every scenario but and that's why I kind
of said unknown cloud storage meaning
that it's not something I've categorized
by the web filter that you could be
weightless you're blacklisted
unless you're potentially blacklisting
on categorized how many people blah blah
Uncategorized network activity better
they're whatever they yeah firewall we
do yeah if it's not categorized we don't
win it out did you get a lot of
categorization requests yeah but they're
required to go with the process we have
they're required to get vice-president
or their managers sign off before it hit
security so we don't have to worry about
what yeah so you know if we don't get
the tough ones it's yeah and then have
to bump it up to the VP right it goes
the other way yeah see we were a local
government we do a lot of small
businesses right very small businesses
legitimately so everyone down to the
local barber that goes to the jails and
cuts people's hair mm-hmm they have a
website that's somewhere and they need
to get to it for vendor information all
that stuff it's very interesting to see
how much things aren't categorized
because it's not a large on the top you
know 1 million lists or something like
that that's reversible there's a way
that we've tried to automate
categorization right so the helpdesk
go through and categorize something
waitlisted first and categorize you
later after else things like that so in
this type of investigation how many
people would you only deal with the
security team would you have to deal
with like two or three RIT teams maybe
escalate to a manager obviously
supervisor maybe even higher
we actually this has been probably the
best thing that we've done we hire we
have a person that sits on the in
destructure team that is an FTE out of
the security budget and all they do is
security requests so anything we need to
do that we don't have access to or
separation of duties that FTE is capable
to do so there are a point person for
anything else for currently that's good
that's good we've we've done something
similar where we've actually give a
standard screening to somebody just
denoted that person as the security hat
they get training it's up like that so
they kind of see a car I have the kids
things like that were just having
somewhat similar but the thing is at the
end of the day is that if you have a
cert team or you have your instant
response plan there's someone that was
involved in this that wasn't in the cert
team that should have been or maybe
should not have been right and and one
should have they have been you kind of
refined some your policies again because
your orchestration and your automation
it's going to work off of your possible
procedures you don't want to start
automating orchestrating things that
don't have any documentation or policies
wrong right because that's assume you
Lackey then they're like why are they
this workflow
alright there's no actual so again it's
only to be back to the foundational
things your your automation and
orchestration only be as good as your
policies your procedures your your data
integrity of your assets as well as any
type of other enrichment data that you
have
so again we're gonna go through here and
go through the measurement improvement
ROI so how many people in their
environment measure ROI specifically in
the model the analyst time spent on
something even if it's something focused
right so here's some just quick
interesting math around again number of
phishing emails per day is forty right
that's not a large amount to get
reported right I'm even assuming eight
point five percent on a thousand
personal organization to say forty is a
a melted number there III did me know
review would be one hour but we as we
discussed early it could be thirty
minutes so you can cut out all my
statistics in half it's still
significant a lot of money again average
how relate an analyst I think the
average on like last or than $39 pledges
to put thirty five government so less
than that but you know whatever that
history guys we have that statistics
needs to get right you know it's what
you make yourself at least you can use
that or go high or lower based off of
whoever its job it is to look at these
things as we said most people don't have
more than five people so it's usually
you guys in the room anyway so you go
through the overall cost estimation it's
very interesting there's only phishing
email and it's very simple math that's
over 1400 hours a day can handle those
phishing emails that's assuming you have
a five sock analyst to handle forty
right or stage two and a half because
you can do it in half the time in thirty
minutes right and then so say you don't
even have that amount of people what
type of risk are you absorb you right
what type of like if you had only to
sock off analysts you might go down to
sixty percent of the female to be
backlogged every day right or thirty
percent if you're you know
doing in 30 minutes right and what
amount of risk is that is actually
pertaining your environment based off of
some type of Industry report statistics
that you can use and back up in an
executive meeting
well they twenty percent of users
generally respond or click on phishing
emails right that's going to change
based on your security whereas your type
of user industry all that stuff right
but you know basic survey and research
kind of shows that give or take so that
then you can kind of that's like twelve
percent of those emails that are a
feedback law could be compromised in
your network right so where does
security orchestration more automation
work for you to make sure that that one
hour goes down the sub five minutes
right sub five minutes in this analysis
I'll be you know you could have that
much staff savings and do everything
under 3 to the 1/2 hours triage time or
even less than that a few if we're doing
30 that's right half that time anyone
ever really look at that and it's not
mind going math there but it paints a
picture that executives and fiscal
officers kind of might understand more
than hey I get all these phishing emails
and I don't know staffing and we do all
these things and you know if you just
say like takes me three minutes dudes X
cats we get this amount of tasks in
place this is how much it costs you to
staff these people and this is how much
it's costing you a year and if I invest
and I buy this $150,000 orchestration
system or spend this another staff
person to do build the system I could
cut down you know 360 or you know under
$40,000 earned $30,000 staff right that
makes sense or that seemed pretty easy
did you guys do something like that
so I'm strategy that it was just so it
was pretty services really good
absolutely
using that
anyone else aw I mean really I mean
either your your CISOs or CIOs I mean
you can talk with them about this stuff
your managers or maybe you're the person
previously I had to show how to purchase
something that was a major purchase
where was our breakeven and that make
sense to another of the high I mean how
did you guys beat the high again just
just kind of got in it's open source so
you free you put it in there you
contestant fill it out or maybe you guys
can go through an ROI obviously knew you
needed right something right so was
there any general just interesting I
mean it was one that I had a big but it
was a finding actually from on my table
play okay look at that so time was spent
evaluating the high was not the only
kind of security incident response and
tracking even in the open sore from yeah
went through all of them reviewed them
and he chose the higher based on things
having analyzers and a little sex but
you know obviously there was there there
is it's not that there's no cost went up
server you back it up yeah yep do all
those types of things VMware licensing
it was inexpensive enough that it didn't
require a lot of cop specification but
justification around a lot of other
products are obviously return on
investment but some of them are not just
don't always come down to a dollar or or
you know for email kind of analysis a
lot right exactly else oh yeah you know
how much risk reduction do I get with
this month yeah so that that also get
actors into that and there's made the
risk analysis was the biggest one that I
am if we do a risk assessment
iris issue that only work directed aside
wall we're just going to accept the risk
anyone else on that you guys looking at
that so hopefully hopefully you're
looking at that and generally making out
between the specifics with something but
other than taking consideration when you
look at like your average of fishing for
today
sporty this is that case of this but
then what happens is something like this
happens right so all of a sudden you
have you know that's here that's your
normal theta there your normalize data
and all of a sudden you start seeing a
phishing campaign against you right and
yeah luckily the blocks are you know
going up along with the the total total
and the core teams are going up but you
know what's getting through right and
who's it getting through to right again
once you start getting saturated with
logs like this and then attack how are
you analyzing that you know things that
aren't getting through obviously your
blankey boxes and things like that
arguing a lot of the front working that
but you know what there's probably
percentages very well just I'm just
getting through and unfortunately as you
all know it only takes one time right so
how you orchestrating to make sure that
you're covering all your bases when all
of a sudden your intake of potentially
even just one event being emails spam
emails increase by two hundred three
hundred percent right you don't have it
all sent or if you're gonna send people
work before you right can't call in the
Calvary or anything like that so that's
that's something just to think about
right and something also there's an
additional ROI calculations we can do
for that to normalize and all kinds of
like more into statistics and stuff like
that to make sure that you're covering
all of those but it's definitely
something to review and
go upper-management it's pretty simple
and it talks it talks to that usually so
that makes sense everybody okay I got a
quick examples time permitting so I
wasn't sure the time on this I know
we're going people are walking out here
because we're kind of reaching them they
have been going to six I don't think I'm
going to go to six so I'm going to go
through these examples pretty quickly
they're not large examples at all
they're just two slides and those two
examples here and we've already kind of
talked about right so when you're
looking at your spear operation is a
host firewall analysis again are you
looking at your how many people are
actually looking at all the ports
internally they're being used I'm talk
about four stations right when you start
going and getting that data even if you
were getting that data what are you
gonna do with that data there's no way
unless you're going through like a
already an instance that is analyzing
that for you to put context around that
to be able to make sense of that data
here this is an example of a large
amount of traffic that it's being
permitted and it's a large port there I
believe that is Lorde's think like
nineteen forty-seven or something so
large that we do you think that poured
that or ended up game no it was huge we
didn't allow port only important yeah
anyway
well this is just a server so this is
just a workstation again this is more
lateral
what's the most evil things in IT realm
printers printer right um there's a
rogue printers right people who use
their own printers up they happen
directly what anything stop someone from
putting a printer and mapping it
directly when you guys are you guys do a
port security on every everything I jack
port security every contract with mac
address whitelisting to make us how it
works huh okay why was if it's an on
demand machine pose you guys any dark
race in here no offense dark face very
probably before it huh I've heard some
interesting things about not involved in
any of that so anyway so those are
things to look at when you import
analysis right is is there a whether the
top ports even if it's not ports across
it what top ports per machine that are
over saying like 30 percent right those
are the things you have to look at when
again it's almost getting into like
somewhat correlation and you're logging
and infrastructure and use them but
again it's not something that's going to
replace your sim you're just making
sense that's more data analysis right
and then off of that you can make your
orchestration or some type of automation
here's another thing here this is a you
know we apparently were blocking ipv6
until we start looking at the giant
amount of ipv6 traffic internally and
that's interesting what was it again a
printer right
do you disable printers and if people
bring them in do they just connect them
and also ipv6 Murad right so very
interesting stuff ah hi you guys do MAC
address filtering for ipv6 with a
separate adapter the same same way or
getting me tested it yeah so the thing
is and most likely magnet or some
actress but those are the things you
might want to test this make sure you
know especially I'm sure since device is
doing all that kind of stuff but
sometimes you know we're ganna ipv6 is
an interesting so just be cautious of
that those are two things again I always
leave with this I get I get a lot of
people from either when I'm in my
private sector or in the public sector
role saying like you know what this is
all cool stuff that's not happy that's
how many people have heard that well
it's not happening to us they don't have
this right one thing I just I just
recommend it has nothing to do with
security or automation or anything like
that it's fine all of the businesses in
the area of their high level one of a
level or in your industry sector in like
your general vicinity if that's the
statewide citywide or maybe tri-state
area or something relatively close to
home that people know if you're a
financial services industry or if you're
an education industry and then just make
a slide like this this is what I got
right so we got websites hacked with
Isis messages would have ransomware
shutting down public sector we have
anonymous attacking cities and taking
them down we got it's us employees
hitting with scams of dubbing twos this
is all just an aria really make it make
it something flash like that as well but
at the end you know just wanted getting
taken away is conducted tabletop
exercises full-day tabletop exercises
are great but they take a lot of people
it's hard to schedule hard to get all
those people did you stop being like one
of those 15-minute once the special
points maybe a little more in-depth I'll
include
tabletop exercises just in some of my
notes things like that that you can use
there's also good things to follow on
Twitter that have instant response
tabletop exercise of the scenarios that
are like tweeted out I don't know if
they're daily but they might be weekly
or some type of frequent amounts again
reviewer inventory system but also how
you access and how quickly you can find
something in there and see if you can
just get dumps of that and it towards us
and then put it somewhere it can rip
some your data might be very easy today
right and then again just start setting
up bi-weekly lunch meetings discussed
automation place things that you can do
scripts that you can get working
how you managing those scripts we were
kind of talking about scripts earlier
and the thing that's be very cautious of
when you're doing automation especially
stuff with a hive and other things like
that is that when you start running out
and doing all these automated tasks and
widening the firewall level make sure
your scripts aren't also gonna be your
the end of the end of your days as well
because those things are hijacking
easily and the worst thing security
people and the best thing security
people can do is develop things and
hands a hum it's the kind of a
double-edged sword and be very careful
with that look at how probably that's
just signing your code PowerShell sign
if you guys have a some kind of PKI or
your stupidest or look at signing it and
look at code version controlling that
stuff even if you're not you guys aren't
developing full application who you're
developing scripts that change over time
look at version control and there are
open source utility it out there
whenever uses frogs GOG asks you can
push up internally it puts like a GUI on
top of internal gate Lavazza torie it's
a very manageable easy Oh included notes
to use it have almost like engineering
and infrastructure share PowerShell code
we've found it being very useful because
we had a disconnect with our engineering
team for this power so you code for you
know ad stuff and 365 stuff when we
started collaborating and sharing law on
they're also putting documentation
with the code or probably code comments
there's probably like a little you know
in front of your eg script or wherever
you got you might have like a whole
little comment section of litt does but
you really have documentation around
that why is it built what's it doing
we've been using are when you look at
windows vent collection when it's about
40 and you're building that out and
you're turning on off subscriptions and
events we've been using that but
apposite ory has more than the local a
full documentation around lives about
forty we've been using that instead it's
been it's been pretty helpful each and
every time the code gets updated we have
to push it up there and then the
engineering team actually copies the
code from there and puts it into the
production so it's kind of like just a
very simple process you can put in place
again once you start talking through
those things to somebody once you buy
weekly lunch meetings monthly lunch
meetings about it maybe once you learn
some stuff like that and as I discussed
earlier is uh you know load up the hive
training VM play with it other other
ones I don't know and we were talking
about looking at the hive and other
things we there's also other things like
fur out there it's called fast instant
response it's also another operation
managed mantle if it doesn't do the core
tech stuff but that was something that
we looked at first those through a sans
I think that sans or French government
or something kind of like back bits
we're looking at other us thirteen we're
looking at other cert teams in general
like nation cert teams country cert
teams and just see what they used to
manage all their cases and in census so
I recommend doing as much research as
possible with that and again also just
talk about when is the right time to
bring in automation if you don't have
the things you don't have to automate
things but again if you drill the
processes then maybe you could
eventually automate all right so that's
that's kind of all I have I'll leave you
guys with that about thirty minutes
early I'll take additional questions and
leave you with a kind of a quote that I
I find fun this if you go from 30 36
percent on fire 27% fire you're still
still alive
take it from you I got to name something
else so I took the question party for
you any questions
nothing was that was that better and it
wasn't a hands-on workshop that's why
you apologize to that you can blame the
organisers for not having a high degree
law of environment but I got through
that it was somewhat interacted the
discussion base I'll be here at the con
you want to talk to anymore about you
the hive or specifics on automation
orchestration let me know that I hope it
was somewhat useful you learned
something take away something at the end
of the day take away one thing what can
it be pushing the button fishing buddies
vision button alright good
just step one of automation alright
thank you guys
[Applause]
by the way and seen between 350 degrees
consumers and we took a break where we
go I'll let it roll you a roll