all right good afternoon
well hey today I'm gonna talk about
security awareness I bet called this
guaranteed failure awareness the
greatest cyber insanity and I'm not
talking about how we're gonna act later
tonight after we've had a little bit too
much to drink but anyway so real quick
poll who thinks that we're doing a good
job in InfoSec anyone if I didn't think
you were sarcastic I'd pick any of the
rest of the time but anyway so cyber and
sanity basically if you look at
everything we're spending or actually
our breach detection times have risen I
think by some like twelve thirteen days
over the last year so now there are over
90 days we have more breaches any of the
security controls that we currently have
can be bypassed ransomware incidents are
increasing and basically boils down to a
good hacker just simply can't be stopped
now on the other side of things
cyber spending is at a record high in
fact it's increasing by almost 10
percent every year and it's expected to
top globally one trillion dollars
between 2017 and 2021 basically you know
we're spending a lot more but we're
tuning worse as an industry and in no
world is backwards progress or backwards
movement progress and some of the
reasons I think that we're seeing this
our number one compliance is still
thought of as the destination instead of
the starting line compliance is is a
great thing but it's a starting point
it's the bare minimum set of standards
not the finish line not the end-all
be-all if you will our budget it's still
being driven by compliance or risk
management frameworks instead of actual
risk and in our industry
just about everything tends to be very
reactive instead of proactive quick
example of that is our encryption anyone
know what what problems quantum
computing might cause with our current
encryption
exactly and does anyone have any
solutions for for this problem you know
it's funny the the NSA and all major
governments really around the world
they're collecting every bit of data
they can get their hands on or web
traffic that they can get their hands on
why because they know in just a few
years maybe less we're gonna be able to
decrypt any bit of that data so you know
from an offensive point of view we
understand that these things are highly
vulnerable but on the defensive side of
things what's the answer about this
well quantum computing will create a
solution for the the encryption problem
well we need a solution now not a few
years from now and we're not really
future proofing our technology and then
the next thing is most of our our
technology is designed around treating
symptoms of the problem instead of the
actual root cause of the problem well
what's that what's the biggest problem
in cybersecurity yes guess somebody here
that's awake anyway so people are the
biggest problem in fact according to
latest Verizon data breach investigation
report they said 96% of breaches start
with a fish so people are clearly our
biggest problem so what do we do to
solve this problem well we assume that
the we can't do anything about the
people and so we we just they're gonna
click on something so we'll all of our
technologies are after the fact we have
antivirus for after they click on
something we have our firewall for after
they click on something we have our our
anti-malware technology all designed
around after somebody clicks on someone
uh
luzon ah well I'm just there we are ok
but basically most of our technologies
they treat the symptoms of the problem
instead of the actual root cause if I
get a cold and I go to the doctor I
don't want them I mean well maybe I do
want some cough syrup some of that
stuff's pretty good but
when I go to the doctor I'm going there
for antibiotics something to actually
treat the problem and and then next is
we have these dangerous misconceptions
in cybersecurity as anyone ever heard
the phrase you can't patch stupid anyone
ever said that phrase oh come on I know
we're all guilty but it's this dangerous
misconception and if we accept that you
can't patch stupid well we've given up
before we even tried and and basically
this all boils down to the fact that all
of cyber security or almost all of cyber
security is a human problem not a
technology problem and if we continue to
try and solve the problem with nothing
but technology we're gonna continue to
get the exact same results we have been
which is failure so you know in
cybersecurity there's one thing that
exists at every layer and in security in
general it's it's composed of layers
it's the onion theory if you will and
the only thing that exists at every
single layer is humans and when we make
mistakes then that breaks down and it
can cause horrible things so we all know
that people clicking on fishes is the
easiest way into any network and a
guaranteed way for hackers to get into
the network but the site of things that
I think a lot of people don't think
about is what happens after they get
into the network
well the IT admins are making enough
mistakes that it's guaranteed that the
bad guys can get full access to anything
they want no joke I saw one time this
was a sort of hilarious but but it's
scary and stupid at the same time had a
pen test where the IT director who knew
the pen test was going to start five
days later
decides well I want to test out a self
password reset tool and so he puts
manage engine on the perimeter and
actually connects it you know gives an
external IP address but on top of that
doesn't bother to change default
credentials and these are self
populating default credentials at that
and it's connected to their Active
Directory so within minutes of starting
the pen test we find this
engine and I didn't even have to look up
what the default credentials were
because well they're self populating I
just had to click login and as soon as I
log in it says would you like to sync
your credentials or your credential
database or with an external database or
whatever is said and I said yes I would
and we had full access to all of their
credentials and domain admin and whatnot
you know within minutes and so this is a
big problem domain admins in fact I was
on a pen test last week where I found a
spreadsheet with three different domain
admin passwords in it this is something
that we all know about but our IT ops
are still making big mistakes and then
on top of that then we have our our
defenders and nothing against blue
teamers there's some great blue teamers
out there but there's a lot of blue
teamers who haven't even ever read or
maybe don't even know about the mitre
attack framework and the types of you
know things that the bad guys are
actually doing and so then you've got
this element where now the defenders the
cyber security professionals are going
to guarantee that it takes that much
longer for them to do detect you once
you're in the network and so it's a
series of human failures that create
this perfect storm and it's the reason
that we continue to fail so how do we
fix the problem well I think we should
stop focusing so much on education
because frankly computers are a little
bit like people or I guess people are a
little bit like computers they're
difficult to train but pretty easy to
program so we need to do more with
conditioning and and sort of kid
programming if you will our users and so
I've got here the for ease of security
awareness and each these are incredibly
important the number one thing on here
is entertaining as anyone ever enjoyed
security awareness training know anyone
done the DoD training before it was that
miserable
exactly and so most training is just
miserable it's boring it's not
entertaining and so 90% if not more of
what we're teaching our users gets lost
on deaf ears because they just don't
care why would you care I've been
through that training of many years in a
row the exact same boring thing and it
was just it was horrible and I'm in
security you'd think I would care but no
this this training just made me not care
about security so we need to do better
about making stuff entertaining the next
thing is it needs to be encompassing so
when we think of security awareness
typically we're thinking about nothing
but the basic security awareness well
what's the difference between HTTP and
HTTPS think before you click cover
before you click cover over the link and
you know we go to all of this stuff but
we're missing other elements of security
awareness training like educating our IT
ops about common mistakes that are made
which make it very easy for anyone to
take control of the you know the entire
of network what about our our executives
who are c-suite who don't understand
cybersecurity and so they're not leading
and because of it it's difficult to get
budget and the proper support that you
need maybe they need a little bit more
education around cybersecurity so that
they can better understand what's
happening what risks it poses to the
organization and there's a million other
areas of cyber security training that we
should be adding in above and beyond the
basic security awareness next it needs
to be engaging users have to care if
we're not making users care then we're
not doing good enough in our training
and ultimately we're gonna fail but most
importantly and the reason I have it at
the center is it needs to be effective
how do you measure anyone got any ideas
how you might measure effectiveness of a
security awareness program no one
I believe there's only one mesh metric
that matters here and that is does it
lower our incidence does it reduce
incidence if it's not reducing incidence
then it's not effective we can look at
other metrics like I don't know fish
cliques all day long and that that's a
valid metric but at the end of the day
if it's not driving down the number of
incidents we have it's worthless with
what we're doing isn't really helping us
so from here I'm gonna jump into what I
the the top ten what I call epic
security awareness fails and I think the
the biggest one here is that we tend to
have under qualified and overworked
staff running our programs now it's not
that security staff are our you know
under qualified insecurity it's that
they're not educators they don't
understand psychology they don't and I
keep knocking this thing out but anyway
they don't understand security they not
security they don't understand education
and so as a result of that is that going
to come back on oh oh hold on that close
to the program huh since when does
unplugging the HDMI cable go close the
the program hold on bear with me here
all right so they don't understand
psychology and and then the next thing
is that we we take people that already
have dashboard overload anyone in here
on a blue team do you have plenty of
time in the day to do everything that
you need and maybe extra bandwidth where
you could add in a few more chores no no
do you have plenty of staff and your
team no see that's the thing and so what
we do is then we we take and we hand our
defenders a tool it doesn't matter how
great the tool is if they don't have
time to manage the tool they're gone
it's not going to be utilized and so the
best tool in the world is worthless if
it's not being used I know because I've
quite a few tools in my garage that have
never even been you know opened out of
the box I like to think that I'm a handy
handy man sort of guy and until I
actually get around to it and then I
realize no I'm the guy that hires or
calls the handyman and ask him to come
out and fix something but the best tool
in the world is still worthless if we're
not effectively using it and this is not
moving forward Wow
technical issues here huh let's try this
again
okay so here's a quick story about a
client and bear with me apparently we're
today is the day of technical issues but
I recently did a penetration test and we
we had this client they had 2,500
employees they were designated us
critical infrastructure and some of the
stuff that they were doing was was a
little bit scary how easy it was for us
to take control of course therefore the
2,500 employee organization they had a
total of three cybersecurity staff one
of which was the C so not discounting
CISOs here at all but at the same time
most CISOs aren't hands on than the
day-to-day operations which means for
date actual operators working day to day
they only had two people in this company
so they're already dealing with that
dashboard overload and the CTO just this
I'd say we're gonna purchase know before
without even asking the security staff
their opinion or anything throws it at
them and at the end of the year they
sent a total of two fishes with that
tool so I don't care how how affordable
it was two fishes is not very you know
effective use of the tool in fact
there's open-source tools you probably
use that would have been cheaper if
you're only gonna sent two and of course
we were not only able to break in but we
were able to take full control
of everything and this particular one
well was the the level of access that we
got in the things that we could have
done were very scary we could have
caused massive loss of life we could
have caused major natural disasters or
not natural disasters but disasters of
iron mental disasters and so it was a
little bit scary and I bring that up
because if we're not fishing our users
enough which I'm gonna get into later
we're not going to our users won't be
prepared and of course they're gonna be
very vulnerable now the next thing is
that we tend to have poor you Jim use
our engagement do do you think your
users care about cybersecurity yeah 9 2
most of the time users don't care about
cybersecurity unfortunately but there's
also this false sense of security did
you know that some users actually think
that the network is so secure that
nothing they could possibly do would get
them infected in fact I read a recent
study that I thought was a little bit
hilarious and scary at the same time
where they surveyed a bunch of users and
they found that these users it was very
common where they would find have some
sort of suspicious shady link that they
didn't trust clicking on at home and so
they would go to work to click on that
because they wanted to and they thought
that their work network and computer
systems were so secure that they could
open anything up over there and so they
take this fish they forward it to the
work email and now they're opening it
there makes sense right so users have
this false sense of security the next
thing is does anyone penalize their
users for causing let's say a ransomware
outbreak no what about rewarding your
users for secure behavior anyone reward
your users maybe an extra bonus at the
end of the year if they've been
reporting fishes they haven't clicked on
anything so that's another one of the
big problems see employees are motivated
by what money so if they have no
or for good behavior and no consequences
for bad behavior where is their
motivation to be secure and to keep the
organization's gear
they don't have it the next thing is
there's rarely good top-down support so
one of the things when we start a
security awareness program I when we go
through the kickoff and we say hey
listen here's an email sort of sample
email but what we need you to do is send
out an email all your staff from the CEO
saying that this is a very important top
priority for the company
guess who sends that email 99% of the
time the seaso and it's nothing to gets
to see so because i'd love CISOs but at
the same time do you think the employees
give a crap about the sea so as much as
they care about the CEO so and that's
the thing and in fact it's it's sort of
hilarious when I do pen tests
it's very frequent that the IT director
will cheat if you will so as soon as I
get that they tell me hey we want you to
run the fish by us before you send it
out I know what that means that means
they're gonna forward that fish that I
send them to the entire company and say
don't click on this the thing is I'm not
worried about it do you know why I'm not
worried about it because they're gonna
click in fact when I get in their email
it's not uncommon that I see that
message mass email sent out to the
entire organization saying don't click
on this and that's not been read but my
fish was read and it was clicked on so
to that regard if you have a trending
threat of a fish what do you think's a
better approach to warning your users
emulating that threat and creating a
fish and fishing all of your users with
that threat that you're worried about or
sending me an email saying don't click
on this we need to be emulating those
threats in fact I saw study that said
something like users were I forget the
exact number was around 70% less likely
to click on a fish if they had seen it
before so if they're seeing it from us
the good guys for
first they're much less likely to fall
for it if they see it in the wild and
then the next thing is we have a lack of
emotional tie into what we're doing and
the next thing excuse me is that we tend
to be and not have that user performance
feedback anyone and does anyone work at
an organization where they fish you know
one okay anyone get regular progress
updates as to how secure they are as a
user do you think that might help you be
more secure if you knew where you stood
how well you were doing so we're missing
that performance feedback and then the
next thing is that we really we're not
collecting a lot of data around human
security now we're finally starting to
get a little bit better with you know
behavioral biometrics but a lot of
that's you know we're we're we're
getting good data it's looking at things
like you know what time am i logging in
and from where in the world am i logging
in and and what type of activities do I
have while I'm in the networks and in
the systems things such as what what
files am i accessing but when it comes
to social engineering and security
awareness and and phishing which is our
biggest threat what data do we typically
have did they click yes or no if yes
which fish did they click on that's
about the extent of our data when it
comes to people and so there's a lot
more that we could be asking like who's
who's participating who needs to improve
on what I got one that's fun how long
before our users relapse after we've
educated them that's a fun one and the
thing is really if we can think it we
should be measuring it because you can
collect all the data in the world in
fact storage is cheap so it's not a big
deal to collect data even if you don't
have a clue how you're going to use it
or even if it's valuable because I can't
go back in time and collect data after
the fact but I can collect data right
now and try and figure out what I'm
gonna do with it long down the road and
so if you can think it measure it and
the next thing is we don't have a lot of
insight into our risk and so one of the
things when with all of our security
investments especially around security
awareness
we're not defining our KPIs before we go
in well how do I measure success how do
I know if what I'm doing is actually
working the next thing is which
employees present the most risk to my
organization how about what departments
present the most risk to my organization
and do I have some locations that might
present more risk than others in fact we
found quite a few organizations that had
location specific locations where they
had twice or three times the fish Khanna
or click count of any other organ within
the organization so if we're not
measuring these things we won't know
maybe we have a cultural issue over
there
or maybe it's just my entire sales team
in that office and that's the reason
they're clicking on three times more
fish but you know we need to be looking
at those things and then you know who's
improving and who isn't improving do I
have somebody that's just this
perpetually clicking on everything other
than the educational emails maybe they'd
if it's a fish they'll click on it all
day long in fact we had one user last
year that clicked on 11 fishes in one
year but we kept fishing them and
fishing them and fishing them and after
their 11th click they have at this point
not clicked on a single thing now in
five months and that's because we
increased the amount of fish is this
user was getting to the point that I
think we sent them 36 fishes over the
course of a year the more they clicked
on the more we sent them until they
finally quit clicking but and then
there's other things everyone has heard
most people would assume sales is the
most most likely to click on a fish
right so and they are by the way in fact
they're way more likely to click on a
fish than any other department within
the organization number two though that
we found is developers developers are
very likely to click on fish now the
reason I bring this up is because sales
and developers they don't click on the
same type of fishes so
understanding who is clicking on what
and what departments are susceptible to
what types of fish can help you increase
the effectiveness of your programs so
sales people they will click on anything
social media themed whereas you get to
developers and yes they love to click
but they will click on anything business
communications themed or security themed
and so it's very different risk that
they pose an understanding that can help
us do better with our users with our
education initiatives and most
importantly we do in reducing risk and
another thing that we have been tracking
is who has access that we call them
sensitive information users it could be
HR with access to all of your your
payroll and your you know employee
information or it could be somebody with
in finance or well maybe your domain
admins that have the keys to the kingdom
and so what we found is that more often
than not when we start measuring how
much of the the user base has a high
level of access versus how much risk
they actually posed the organization we
found that more often than not there
they pose a significantly higher risk to
the organization than anyone else in
fact we had one company it was around
15% of their users were deemed sensitive
information users and that 15%
represented 32% of their fish clicks
that's scary isn't it when I when our
people that we give the keys to the
kingdom to are the ones that are
clicking on everything so we actually we
had a question a little while back and I
said you know I want to know what
percentage of users present how much
risk is the organization because I
figured there's probably a little bit of
an 8020 rule here and in fact it's far
beyond the 8020 rule because we found
that one point one nine percent of users
actually represented eighty nine point
eight two percent of phishing risk now
this is a guy with the data that I have
but I've talked to a lot of SEOs and
their numbers are backing this up
they're seeing the exact same thing and
so this is a trend just
very very small portion of our users
represent most of our risk within our
organizations now that's you know that
that's both good and bad the good news
is that it's a small group of people we
have to fix to have a massive impact on
our overall security and and to reduce
our risk bad news is that's a very very
difficult group to actually get to stop
clicking and so that brings me to the
next point which is low frequency
training how many people do ongoing
security awareness training at their
organizations
awesome how frequent once a year ok so
that's that's typically what we're
seeing is you know this once a year and
then maybe we supplement it and what the
most common thing that I see is adding a
security awareness statement to the
company newsletter does anyone read the
company newsletter anyone at all
I've never read it but I know that when
I when I talk to people I say well what
do you do for ongoing awareness
education they said what we put
something in the newsletter but I guess
my problem there is no one reads it you
know maybe instead of putting it in the
newsletter we should put it on pay stubs
who reads their pay stub anyone know ok
well if I still think it might be
slightly more effective we can put
security awareness messages on desktop
backgrounds there's so many places where
we could incorporate what we're doing to
have more frequent training but on top
of that there's there's this lack of
repetition in security awareness
training so in advertising everyone
knows you have to would constantly
barrage somebody with the message before
they're gonna remember it unless it's
something like you know one of these
big-budget Superbowl ads then it might
be clever enough and humorous enough or
or have that emotional tie-in where
you'll remember it but you know it's
security awareness is very similar to
advertising or marketing in the fact
that we need repetition if we want our
people to remember what we're what we're
teaching them and so we're not keeping
security front of mind by touched on
this earlier that we're not taking
advantage of all touch points
anyone has cybersecurity awareness like
posters up in their break rooms so what
about on the internet so there's a lot
more places that we can put this message
to keep people or to keep security front
of mind and the reality is is our
threats they're evolving daily it's not
an annual or quarterly thing and so
we're only educating our users once a
year then we're failing to address the
the changing and evolving threats and
the next thing is that if I'm only
educating you once a year it tends to
cause me to get into the weeds as an
educator so now I've got 10 million
topics that I have to cover in this
annual training and so now my my
training tends to get overly complex and
this subject that already intimidated
the users now we're just proving to them
yes it is way too complex there's no way
you're ever going to understand it
because we're getting into the weeds and
and so then the next one and I think
it's number five you can't see the
numbers on there but number five in the
top 10 countdown is boring content it's
you know I don't have to say much here
we've all been through it you know our
most content is way too lengthy even if
you you take like sands it's still three
and a half or four minutes of you know
education that's very dry it's not
entertaining people and that's an
example of the good side of this whereas
there's other security awareness
training that's you know an hour long of
boring boring boring and no one's paying
attention to anything and then we've got
overly complex messaging has anyone ever
seen one of those those phishing landing
pages that's something like the 15 ways
to avoid clicking on a fish you ever
seen that so here's the problem I have
with that do we really need to educate
users on 15 ways to avoid clicking on a
fish or is think before you click
maybe all the bad messaging that we need
maybe we can simplify things a lot more
to have better results and
it doesn't entertain and it tends to
intimidate people but beyond that it's
painful to watch so I'm gonna play a
quick video here and hope well we'll see
if we have audio and hopefully you'll
enjoy it but the idea here is to show
you this was a sample video that I
created just specifically for this talk
to show that it's easy to create
entertaining content that users will
actually enjoy so here it is no we don't
have audio let's see oh oh well I guess
we're not gonna do this
catch me later I can send you a link but
it was meant to be I was totally at
audio but I don't know what's going on
anyway so then the next thing is one
size fits all and do later I can show
you the video but in our educational
programs what we're doing is we're
applying the exact same training to
every single person in the company so
what happens our users who are less
secure that creates a lot of risk for
the organization they don't get as much
education as they need now our users
that don't pose a lot of risk of the
organization that are very secure they
get way more education than they need
it's not efficient and it's this middle
ground that causes everything we do to
fail and so the our programs need to
adapt to the individual users needs or
risks the next thing is that our fishing
exercises should adapt as well and and
our different people actually pose
different levels of risk to the
organization if I am a domain admin and
I'm clicking on fishes is that a big
deal do you think I should be a domain
admin if I'm clicking on fishes maybe
not so you know different users do
present different risk and beyond that
different users need different education
if I'm handling wire transfers every day
that's a good bit of risk I need to be
educated on you know best practices on
common scams that might try and target
me so that I'm not likely to click on it
but somebody they're not click on it but
not likely to fall for it
somebody that doesn't have that access
they may not need the same level of
training as me and then the next thing
is that not everyone learns the same way
there's visual learners there's auditory
learners there's a lot of different
learning styles and so by treating
everyone the exact same we're not
adapting to the individual and the next
thing is one size is simply inefficient
what's the holy grail of business doing
more with less in education we actually
have an opportunity to do more with less
all we have to do is start customizing
to the individual because that that
number that I showed you earlier one
point one nine percent of our users are
causing a majority of our risk which
means we can get really invasive with
one percent and do a little bit less
with everyone else and we've actually
not only increased our the efficiency of
our program but we've also increased the
effectiveness all while being doing less
as a whole and so it's less employee
disruption which is what people want and
yeah different different people have
different needs and so to that I ask you
know are we setting ourselves up for
failure as an industry especially when
it comes to security awareness we're
basically doing the exact same thing
most organizations are doing the exact
same thing now that they were doing in
the 90s and they're wondering why it's
not working well times have changed we
have to adapt accordingly and then the
next thing is that we're missing our
just-in-time engagement anyone when they
fish their users as part of their
educational programs does anyone put it
that send them to a landing page to see
if they'll you know enter a password or
open an attachment so I argue that
unless we're doing a Red Team assessment
we should not be doing that the reason
is is because at the moment a mistake
has realized that user is uniquely
susceptible to learning so if we just
exploit them we're not taking advantage
of that opportunity to educate them and
so beyond just not taking advantage of
that opportunity to educate them right
now does it really matter if they type
in their password
did they not already click
could there be a browser zero-day behind
it or maybe just you didn't update flash
and then the browser I mean it doesn't
really matter
once they've clicked it we may as well
just assume it's game over and so at
that point we should be sending them to
some sort of landing page to capitalize
on that and so it's these when they
realize their mistake it actually helps
to anchor that lesson in in memory now
the next thing is when people click on
fishes more often than not they don't
get a follow up email to their inbox
telling them that it just clicked on a
fish and telling them what the red flags
were in that fish and how they could
have avoided it
but and one of the problems I have with
that is that now if they're not getting
any feedback here now for as far as that
user knows they're maybe they don't even
realize they clicked on a fish but even
if they do you know we're not
encouraging them to sort of report
anything where they're not getting that
that feedback we're not giving them any
feedback so it could have been a bad guy
could have been a good guy and so we're
not we're not providing that level of
insight we exploit instead of condition
and and then the next thing is we're not
most often we're not just picking up the
phone and calling somebody what I found
is one of the most effective things we
can do for these what I call chronic
clickers just pick up the phone and call
them and it's not a matter of telling
them hey you've been clicking on
everything you're a horrible user you
know that maybe you'll have to escalate
to that at some point but doing nothing
more than saying hey you know I noticed
you've been struggling on some of these
fishing programs just so you know the
information security teams here for you
if you ever have any questions can I
answer anything for you you don't
actually have to criticize them as soon
as there's that human connection they
are more motivated now to be secure and
to do things right and so just a simple
phone call without even lecturing them
can increase your effectiveness and then
the next thing is that we have these
overly complex landing pages like I said
15 ways to avoid clicking on a fish and
so here's an example of a you know
follow-up email that we could do and
here's what I think it makes a really
effective landing page
oh I forgot we don't have audio there's
a siren plane right now but we actually
we use this as a landing page for these
users that are clicking on everything
and I promise this is a more effective
landing page than telling them 15 ways
to avoid clicking on it and what's the
messaging here is there anything no
because we don't need it they already
know they made a mistake and so letting
them sort of educate themselves and sort
of helping them to is actually more
effective and so again are we setting
ourselves up for failure now the next
thing is that we're missing emotional
anchoring there is in education in
general there is a dangerous lack of
psychology that says it's being employed
in education we definitely need to use
it but especially in security awareness
we're not following basic psychology
principles in order to make things more
effective so emotional anchoring it
increases retention it actually helps to
build that impact has anyone ever
watched the Super Bowl in large part for
the ads or anyone enjoy them yeah and
why why do you enjoy those ads do they
make you laugh budweis there's a great
example they will either make you laugh
or make you cry but they understand a
pro basic principle of getting their
message across and that is emotional
anchoring so they use emotion in their
advertising and you remember their ads
anyone what what's the first Budweiser
ad that comes to mind anyone that for me
I'm thinking the frogs butt or that
what's up one from way back in the day
but you know the whole point is is that
we remember these things because they're
using that emotion they're using
psychology to help get better messaging
or to help get better retention and
we're not doing this and it helps to
push better engagement and base you know
it's just it's it's proven and so then
that brings me to the number one biggest
mistake that we make in cyber security
awareness and that is lousy human virus
definitions I love this meme what if I
told you your brain is the best
antivirus
that is it's so true has anyone ever got
a fish in their inbox and they didn't
even have to open it they didn't even
have to look at it immediately they knew
was a fish but you couldn't articulate
why without looking at it before you
look I bring that up because I've seen
it happen even with me yeah if I started
looking in I can find reasons that
that's a fish
but before I've identified those
immediately I get a red flag in my head
that says up something's off about this
and that is my subconscious clicking it
and so the bandwidth I forget the exact
numbers but the the difference between
the conscious and the subconscious in
terms of how fast that it's processing
data is significant so no no
exaggeration if the conscious brain is
working at let's say one mile an hour
the subconscious brain is working at 500
miles an hour and and so what we want to
do is we want to get the our users
subconscious triggering and telling them
don't click on this there's something
fishy about that no pun intended well
maybe a little bit but but we need to be
educating or planning those human virus
definitions and so how do we plant human
virus definitions and our users we fish
them more phishing equals more virus
definitions if we can prepare our users
for every type of threat if they see it
from us first then they are
significantly less likely to fall for it
when they see it in the wild that it's
it's the most important thing that we
can do in security awareness so I want
to pull the audience how many people
fish their users at least once a year
anyone fish their users once a month so
I actually with the users that I educate
I fish everyone a minimum of once I'm
sorry twice per month a minimum those
are my good users I actually have
high-risk users the people that click on
everything that I will fish as many as
eight times in a single month why
because that's how I get them to
clicking you know if we look at the
United States military we've got you
know we're we're a world superpower why
are we app has superpowers it because
our military is really great at
educating or is it maybe because we're
really great at conditioning so it's not
that we don't do good at education in
the military but it's the conditioning
that makes it so that our soldiers are
prepared when for lack of a better term
hits the fan and that's exactly
what we need to be doing with our users
and so we need to condition our users to
watch for red flags and we need to be
simulating any of these attacks and then
the next thing is the only fix for
spearfishing is spearfishing your users
I've seen where you know we would start
off at an engagement and when we send
that first spear fish we're seeing 35%
of users clicking on fishes within just
a few months of regular ngon like
regular high frequency fishing we're
seeing those numbers drop to fractions
of a percent we had recently I put out
this challenge I teach social
engineering classes and so I was in
Hawaii teaching an advanced social
engineering class and I put out a
challenge to my audience I got one of my
clients I said listen will you love me
fish you as you know or will you love my
students fish you as part of the class
and they said sure and so I tell the
class I said I want you know we're gonna
spend this entire time I'm going to
teach you how to do all of your Oh sent
your research how to come up with a
pretext and at the end of this I'm gonna
have you actually put this in use and
put everything you've learned action and
create a fish and what I want to see is
if you can get anyone at this
organization to click this particular
organization we have drove fish clicks
so low that it's below 0.1% and so it's
very very difficult to fish them with
any success and so they the class they
go on and they find a job listing that
is done through their Human Resources
software they were using this company
called bamboo HR and so we think ma this
this could be an interesting
pretext for a fish and so they they go
and they buy bamboo HR calm Co which the
actual websites just bamboo HR calm and
then they come up with a fish and they
send it from the CEO saying hey we've
had a data breach and your Human
Resources information was included in it
click here for your free credit
monitoring anyone think that that would
be an effective fish not one single
click and nearly 70% of their users
actually reported the this fish and I
bring that up because we can do better
if that company can see results like
that any company can see results like
that can we stop 100% of fish clicks no
but if we can stop 99.9% of fish clicks
that will have a significant improvement
or effect on our bottom line it will
reduce our malware significantly our
number of incidents significantly and so
we got to do better and and so that
brings me to sort of the recap or the
top 10 so number 10 is that we we have
under qualified and overworked staff
running our our security awareness
initiatives we're not educators
I'm sorry cyber security people should
not be handling anything education they
get in the weeds they make it too
complex and just in general it causes
our programs to be less effective
because they're not educators we poor
user engagement we have poor missing
data collection we have very little risk
inside and when it comes to our people
in fact does anyone actually rank their
people high medium and low risk based on
their actions do you think that might be
effective what kind of fun things could
we do if we had a red list of all of our
high risk users and I don't mean the the
users with a lot of access but all of
our users they like to click on things a
lot and open the company to risk what
might we be able to do with that we
might be able to segment all of these
users off onto their own separate VLAN
to help minimize our risk if we have a
domain admin maybe pop in there we
remove their credentials until they
become more secure and so having this
better insight can help us significantly
we're using boring content
we have one-size-fits-all training
number three is missing just-in-time or
JIT engagement and number two is missing
emotional anchoring and the number one
biggest mistake we're making is lousy
human virus definitions phishing once a
year not enough fishing once a quarter
not enough I I would argue we should be
fishing our users though even weekly
because the bad guys aren't worried
about some schedule the bad guys are
constantly in our users inboxes and so
to me the only question is do we want
the bad guys to be the only ones in our
users and boxes or do we want to be
there too because we can try and block
everything but it only takes one getting
through and it's very difficult to block
a Spearfish because there's no
definitions for them I mean you know all
the all they have to do is go set up a
Google business account and that can
bypass 99.9% of spam filters so you know
we get we got to do better and so before
I open it up to questions I do have some
sort of closing thoughts here does
anyone have children I have some
children and they've recently learned to
drive that was very nerve-racking and
scary still is but you know what got me
to thinking I what what kind of crazy
parent would let their 13-year old climb
in a car and drive across town with no
understanding or no practice or driving
training whatsoever would anyone do that
no and why wouldn't we do that because
they might kill themselves but then on
the other side of things with our people
our employees we tend to let them access
our computer systems and our networks
without any training they're essentially
that thirteen year old that doesn't know
how to drive that we just said hey yeah
go go on a cross-country road trip no
big deal have some fun and so what
happens is that our employees might end
up killing our business as a result of
that it is very similar and so I asked
once again are we setting ourselves up
for failure in security awareness any
questions no way you've been such a
quiet audience today
I know it's four o'clock
yeah and we can see okay let's do it no
worries that's on the internal hold on
this Court is so thick that it doesn't
there's not really enough room to to
plug it in and have the laptop up here
alright let's try this again ready
[Music]
[Laughter]
all right so that that's just sort of an
example of how we can do a lot more in
fact when it comes to education there's
this thing called the fair use act it
basically means that you can take any
content and reuse it for education and
you know like anything on YouTube you
can start incorporating these videos in
and you can do it completely legally
because of the fair use Act and because
it's education it's not an issue to go
on and sort of do those things so just
FYI it makes it incredibly easy there's
so much content out there so you know
let's let's get creative find some fun
and entertaining ways to educate our
users any questions well thank you so
much
[Applause]