do you have good audio for the young do
a preview for the audio and make sure
all right cool all right so first of all
I have a question for everybody how many
people have seen me present before yeah
I don't do a whole lot with slides like
you're not going to have anything that
you can write down for my slides and be
like wow that's really important I I
don't read anything I stand up here and
I tell you a story I'm a storyteller so
my purpose is to introduce you hopefully
to something new
CTF and to actually pique your interest
so that you'll out actually go out to
the resources that I'll provide that are
all basically on one slide at the end so
applying the principles of dodgeball
right the true underdog story to CTF
I wrote this presentation almost four
weeks ago and that was actually way too
restrictive so I went ahead and my own
little I've defeated myself I rejected
my own talk right and the reason is I
was too restrictive how many people have
seen dodgeball story yeah so there was
like three roles right right four but
really three because one of them
repeated itself so I said you know what
I'm gonna go ahead and go with what I
know and I'm a child of the 80s so
you're not gonna get just dodgeball the
dodgeball story and keys to success from
that but from all the movies that
inspired me from the 1980s how many
people do I have in here that are that
are born in the 70s are younger all
right what about the 80s born in the 90s
yes so I was actually I I teach classes
every once in a while at Marshall
University for for Bill and last time I
was there was a couple of years ago and
one of the students came up to me
afterwards and said hey great
presentation I didn't understand any of
your movie references you need to update
movie references that's I was like I'm
not gonna update my references because
this is how I learned
what I need to do is a little bit
awareness and training and get all this
younger generation to appreciate the
movies that came out in 1980 or the 80s
so this is kind of the format of my
slides I'm always going to have I think
there's two slides I don't have a
picture on so I'm going to have a
picture from a movie method title of the
movie when it was created or released
and then an inspirational quote or kind
of an idea of why I picked that and why
it motivated me so how many people have
seen Red Dawn I'm not talking about the
crappy remake in 2012 Chris Hemsworth
great guy but come on 1980s is where it
was so I'll set the scene for you
there's a colonel named Andy Tanner and
he's he's shot down over occupied
America he makes his way to sis group of
freedom fighters called the Wolverines
right and he wants to bring in this
tactical influence and he wants to teach
them how to do ambushes and things of
that nature she's got this big mock-up
of this ambush they're gonna do and he
simply says you know we're all right for
plains Cuban bunker Russian bunker
munitions dump Terp tents and he goes
through all these different movements
right things that anybody that spent any
time in the military would understand
and he says anybody got any questions
and the first guy says yeah what's a
flank the second guy says what's grazing
fire and then he just says you know I
need a drink
so so this really motivated me to plan
everything in life if you set goals and
you plan other people may not understand
your plan but least you will you have
something to judge yourself by so Who am
I
first and foremost I'm a Christian I
believe in God family and country in
that order spent 20 years in the
military but if you've not watched his
to the world part one it has one of the
best dialogues ever between Commodus and
Jesus so I encourage you to go out and
at least watch that scene it's the Last
Supper scene it's hilarious I actually
spent some time at seminary but that's a
different
different presentation Empire Strikes
Back not Star Wars Episode five I don't
give a crap about what they renamed it
right Star Wars alright I'm sorry the
empire strikes back on the original
building it wasn't a third one it was
just that so the point of this slide is
I am a father I have four kids now we
keep collecting kids adopting them and I
would like to point out that you have to
pay attention to detail whenever you're
doing CTF the phrase is not Luke I am
your father it's no I am your father
so that's one of the most misquoted
movie references there is on the
Internet
alright next I started in information
security before they called it
information security 1991 I became a
navy cryptologist I did everything from
pulling wire putting up fences for
physical security alarm systems
telecommunications engineering security
architecture infrastructure architect
I've done everything one of my favorite
stints was actually doing training and
awareness and that's why I put this up
there Tron
you know Tron fights for the users I
like to think that I fight for the users
Ari and then the last one like I said I
was a child of the 80s I don't know if
they still use this phrase anymore
latchkey kids so whenever I got off the
bus every day at school my parents
neither one of them got off work for
like three more hours so I basically sat
in front of the TV from you know
kindergarten all the way up to my senior
year and watch TV
so movies and especially a show mash
became major influence on my life all
right so to get into the subject matter
what is a CTF light stand by me where
they're going to search for a body in
CTF you're actually searching for flags
there's different types of CTF so
basically both of them are are there's
two two main types both of them are
considered games our simulations one of
them is called
style and that's where you are po or you
have questions posed to or scenarios you
go look for the answer and you report
the answer back and you get you get
points the second one is attack and
defense scenarios those are usually on a
larger scale they're not always public
and the reason is is the amount of
resources it takes for those is just
astronomical one of the biggest public
ones is actually at the CTF at DEFCON so
if you ever go to DEFCON and you go into
the room those guys they don't sleep for
72 hours or if they do it's four minutes
at a time maybe an hour at a time so
it's pretty cool to watch but another
common one is CCDC so some of those most
of them are defense related some of them
you you get some attack scenarios where
you can attack someone else's Network
they always involve involve some type of
analysis and then some of them you have
to actually run exploits so that you can
get the flag and then once again they're
educational in nature the the purpose is
to to help you learn skills that would
be beneficial to you as an infra sec
practitioner this is one of my two
slides I think that doesn't have a
picture where are they held most most of
these are going to be held in person
almost every conference I've been to in
the last say five years has had some
type of CTF even if it's just a like a
crypto challenge an actual CTF like we
have here and then they can vary between
different types some of them I have
participated in one at besides Knoxville
where it was half social media
challenges where you didn't even need a
computer to figure those out I used my
phone and then the other half were
really like crypto challenges exploit
executions things that nature and then
there's this growing list of online
capture the flags and I actually have a
pretty comprehensive list at the end
that's been published by someone else
but it those are really nice right now
there's one going on called Kringle con
let's put on by the people that do the
SANS Institute and I've been playing
around on that for the last couple of
weeks and it's it's pretty interesting
so Santa Claus there's they always have
like a scenario like Santa Claus you
know somebody hijacks a sleigh or the
elves revolt there it's always a pretty
intense story that goes along with it
what is a flag so flags basically they
are the result of performing some type
of action here's an example of a flag so
I don't know if you know much about
github the repository but basically in
order to do this challenge you you
basically remote added a package to
github and then you would you would push
it to master and then it would respond
with the flag so some of them we would
call that a zero level or an
introductory level so it's not really
hard
you could probably google it and get the
answer I've actually seen one where on
it was a social media challenge and they
had basically a flag buried in their
their Twitter page so it really can be
just about anything
you're usually given some instructions
but not a lot of instructions and then
it's kind of a free-for-all another flag
this is kind of hard to see but
basically you're given a subnet or a
range of IP addresses and that's it so
what this person did in this instance is
they just did a ARP scan they determined
there were three IP addresses that were
active and then they just ran in map
against one of them the 1:02 which was
the
I usually pick the first one but you
know they picked the last one that ended
up showing that it had TCP so port 21 so
they actually just opened up a browser
typed in our sorry FTP I don't know when
I said TCP FTP opened up our browser
went to that website using FTP logged in
anonymously and the flag was there
there's actually a text file called flag
txt I've seen somewhere you have to
actually take your computer up to the
people and say hey I found this flag and
then they give you credit for it this
particular one you would actually after
you opened up that flag txt file there
was a link you would go back on to their
intranet and submit the flags so every
flag that they had you could submit via
a submit button so they could be
everything in between I've seen CTF that
were just physical I've seen some that
at this year's Def Con that was actually
a fox hunt so they had emitters all over
Def Con and actually people were moving
the emitters around and you had to build
you have like 24 hours to build a device
to capture the wireless and then you
would roam around and find these
emitters and every emitter you found you
got a series of points based on how
little RF transmission there was so if
like it was a very weak signal that
would be worth more points you got to
see some really cool hounds for that a
lot of some of them would have like
actual
old-school sonar scopes so anytime it
would it would pick up on a signal
whenever it was broadcasting I'd put a
little ping and you would walk towards
it and that ping would get closer and
then let's see so always have a game
plan has anybody this is one of my
favorite movies is anybody ever seen the
movie zero boys no I didn't think so so
this is a classic paintball it started
getting big in the early 80s in 1986 the
zero boys came out and this is a story
of three paintball champions they go out
into the woods and they actually start
fighting for their own lives because
they realize quickly it's not a game
right and the tagline was the game is no
longer a game right so it is what you
make it basically but I highly recommend
this movie and one of the reasons is
their budget was like $200,000 and they
used the scene from Friday the 13th one
through three
so yeah kay Lake Crystal all the cabins
everything the same exact scenes but the
purpose of a game plan is you want to
make sure you have your outcomes you
determine what your outcomes are if
you're just starting your outcome maybe
I want to meet people your outcome maybe
I want to get really good at this one
tool in my labs just not doing it for me
have a process if you have a written
process it's easier to understand where
you made your mistakes or where you did
well and then we'll talk a little bit
about tools I'm not going to teach you
about tools because there's some really
good classes next door let it teach you
about tools what we'll highlight a
couple of them that you absolutely have
to have so two of my biggest outcomes
number one I just want to learn
something new every time I do a CTF as
I'm prepping for it I'll learn a new
tool and then my hope is I used to be a
pen tester back in the military I we
used to say we're pen testers without
the test portion
but I've lost a lot of that whenever I
came out of the military all the tools
we used were proprietary and I didn't
want to do that job anymore I felt that
I was weak in governance risk and
compliance so I wanted to learn that and
then I I learned eight years later that
once your skills atrophy it's hard to
get back on the other side of the fence
but this is I mean come on
gunnery sergeant Hartman yeah I remember
this guy from Full Metal Jacket intense
I love that dude he taught me a lot well
the second thing is I always want to
meet people so I use CTF as an excuse to
talk to people I don't have a hard time
talking to people
I'll talk to just about anybody but once
again it's just one more excuse for me
and then the waste sometime whenever you
go to a conference you guys are gonna be
here possibly for three days right
sometimes you don't want to sit in this
room for another minute
so go out do Lobby con or go into the
CTF room talk to somebody say look I
don't have my computer can you just show
me what you're doing right here a lot of
times I'll say no get away sometimes
I'll say yeah sure sit down and then
before you know it
I've had people actually slide their
computer over and say now you run the
scan so that's pretty cool
shiny all work and no play makes Jack a
dull boy yeah so that was that was me
wasting some time sitting in the frozen
maze rape one once again I always have a
process in the military we used to
always say no plan survives first
contact with the enemy but if you go
into contact without a plan you're
surely gonna die so at least have a plan
or process have it written say here's
how I want to traverse through this
network and then you get the rules and
that may just that may go out the door
right but some of those things you'll be
able to least evaluate your plan later
and grow from it
write it down and then as I always say
write it down if you're beginning as you
start to understand your tools and you
get familiar with them
you can start freestyling or some people
call pivoting that's really the word I
call it freestyling because I'm a child
of the 80s right I was a skateboarder
for about a week
whenever you grow up in the country and
didn't have any asphalt or cement around
it was kind of hard to skateboard on
dirt so I gave that up so freestyle when
you go from riding it down to
freestyling I still always tell people
write their stuff down because one of
the learning processes for me is I write
about what I did during the CTF and if I
can teach someone else then I really
know my stuff and I can I can emulate
that next time anybody seen gotcha
came on 1984 I don't know yeah this is
one of my favorite absolute favorite
movies right
the my base my my favorite scene of the
whole movie there's there's some
classics there is this guy Jonathan
sitting in a French restaurant and he's
looking at the menu he can't read French
he can't speak French he's got his
little book open he's trying to
translate and the waiter comes over and
he says parlez-vous English and he says
a little and he says I want the per node
and the guy was like per node and he
points and says oh paronella and he's
like yeah I won't or not and then that
thing comes back and says modern crayon
s grand at Mon crayon s1 and the guy
says your pencil is big and yellow and
he says absolutely get my part I love
that scene all right after that it meets
the sexy spy that helps to sew tools
we'll talk a little bit about tools and
the most important thing you can get
from this presentation is going to be
this sign no shirt no shoes no dice from
Fast Times at Ridgemont High the sign is
important but really what comes after
that is Brad the guy that works in the
restaurant were all these guys basically
disrobed and he wouldn't serve them he
pointed it to the sign and he made him
read it and they said no shirt no shoes
no dice
right and Brad says right learn it know
it live it so whatever it comes to your
tools
learn them know them live with those
tools because I don't know if you're you
know if you're like me if I don't use
something after a period of time I lose
it right it's just gone so simple things
like what are the switches on an in map
scan
I don't remember all of them right I
used to be in map beasts but I can't
remember half of them now at least half
the ones I used which weren't even all
the switches so make sure you pick a
tool you learn the tool and then you
apply the toilet or CTF man with two
brains one of the biggest tools you can
have is your brain but it's always
better to have two brains whenever I do
cts by myself I know what my weaknesses
are and I know that there are flags that
I could only get by using a tool that
I'm not familiar with so if you have a
partner or somebody you can bounce ideas
off of
or maybe you're better at this tool set
and they're better at that tool set you
can work together you'll I guarantee
you'll do a lot better than if you were
doing a CTF by yourself
teams are even better um a man with two
brains any fans this was kind of one of
those weird ones wasn't it yeah it was
just the the only thing I really liked
about this movie is this is one of the
few movies growing up where I actually
heard my brother cackle so that's I mean
I still hate the movie I can't watch it
to this day
but you do get some gold and some golden
one-liners from from this movie well
yeah I mean I'd be normal Ferris
Bueller's Day Off the second tool that
you'll need is some type of computing
device right so Ferris Bueller if you've
ever watched this other than the famous
quote Bueller Bueller Bueller my
boyfriend's cousins ex-girlfriends
sister-in-law's boyfriend said that she
saw him at the mall and he was throwing
up I think he's going to die right is
this I asked for a car I got a computer
how's that for being born under a bad
sign some poor
to you it's very I won't say it's
impossible because I did
CTF at besides Knoxville I use my
samsung so my note 8 I actually came in
second place so I'm kind of proud of
that I did have to route it and add some
things had some tools but yeah sometimes
I go way overboard but doesn't matter
the OS sometimes it does based off of
what tools you want to use but whether
it's Windows Linux Mac OS it doesn't
really matter I will tell you that
things like if you want to run an ARP
scan a simple arts can use Linux because
it's built in the command line there
there's no special tools you need right
most people don't do ARP scans they just
fire up in map and and they'll they'll
use that I like iris cam because it's
pretty clean and simple and I don't have
to fire up any tools for it or like I
said even a phone with a browser once
again if you're doing the team approach
you know got to go to the bathroom
you're gonna be indisposed for 30
minutes jump on your phone see if you
can get some of those social flags nuts
not like social like talking your
neighbor but social like social media
sam bit how many people have Samsung's
do you use the Samsung internet app huh
it is so on the note series it actually
if you just swipe up do search Internet
it's going to come up with a big blue
circle right supposed to look like the
earth but it doesn't what I like about
that is number one it's very light
Chrome especially on laptops but more
are somewhat on on phones it's a beast
and it will hog your resources so if you
are going to use a mobile phone for for
some of those things do you have it on
your blue disc just type in an Internet
but the cool thing about it is you get a
lot of those annoying pop-ups from
chrome that say you know you can't go to
the site it's insecure Samsung Internet
does
have a crap about that it's like you
want to go you're bad
you do what you want to do I'm just here
to get you know render pages other
things you need I never recommend even
at little places like this using your
personal laptop to do CTF unless you
have some type of virtual machine
I don't like adding tools any tools Kali
back box anything like that to my
personal laptop where I've got you know
credit card data anything college work
it doesn't matter I don't like doing it
both of these are free you have Oracle
VirtualBox that's what I use mostly and
then VM they just change it VM
workstation player is what they change
it to they have a free version and then
the pro version what you have to pay for
and then if you have a Mac you can do
what is it parallels yeah I used to be a
big parallels fan not so much anymore oh
by the way whenever it comes to laptops
I usually have two on me one of them is
this so it's Adele 1570 kind of an
unusual number there but uh I love it
because it's got an i7 solid-state drive
it can crunch anything I throw at it but
to be honest with you my favorite I took
it upon myself
my wife's mat 2010 MacBook Pro the
battery swelled up and busted out the
bottom screws so I replaced the battery
for like 30 bucks
put a solid-state one terabyte
solid-state drive in it and upgraded the
RAM to a big ol whopping eight gig and
this thing is a beast
it has handled more sometimes if I have
like five six vm's open on this it kind
of starts hiccuping a little bit this
MacBook Pros never giving me an issue
it's like feed me more feed me more so
2010 I love that thing but ya get one of
these tools run it in
not mode not bridge mode if you run it
in bridge mode it shares resources with
your host system as NAT device it won't
share all those resources to share the
hardware but you can't transfer files
well actually you can if you click a box
but you can't get from the host system
to the VM very easily and once again
depending on the environment this has
nothing on it that's personal
I think preference I don't really have a
preference I like both VMware and
VirtualBox and the beauty of using these
is you can actually download vm's from
the internet like exploitable or it's
like really damn vulnerable or something
like that so you can have your lab up
and running in like an hour and have 20
30 devices that you can start attacking
as practice so that's pretty pretty nice
ghostbusters never cross the streams
why because you could that would be bad
right I always say this because that's
probably one of the most powerful tools
I've ever seen in my life right I mean
these things they can just absolutely
wreak havoc on ghosts and Cally's the
same way Kali has over 600 tools
currently on it there's no way you can
learn all of those tools but the reason
why I like Kali is because you have over
600 tools so there's been times where I
have been in a CT of a Xiuquan there is
a CTF in shmoocon where one of the flags
you actually had to use a
software-defined radio to actually
capture that like a mini radio tower
that was broadcasting throughout the
conference he actually had to I don't
know any other pen testing tool that has
an SDR native to it a lot of them you
can load them but it had one so I was
able to fire that up as soon as I you
know somebody spoke too loud and I
realized I was looking in the wrong
place borrowed
tena from someone learned how to do SDR
on-the-fly
I didn't get the flag cuz I suck at that
too but you know whatever so callie
callie's the big boy highly recommend if
you're going to use Kali and have a good
system if you have like a system with i
three processor you're gonna get some
sputters especially for use and things
like a Wireshark or something like that
you're ingesting huge amounts of traffic
so that you can go back and do analysis
and automated sometimes while you're
capturing your ex you're writing the
file out and then reading the file at
the same time it will it just choke on
it so I do recommend back box so back
box
it's another Linux based packaged pen
testing tool and doesn't have it's
pretty light it's kind of like the
difference between say a boon to and
mint if you're a Linux person right so
mint I mean you can run mint on probably
two gig hard drive
I mean whereas you know Ubuntu is going
to take a lot more than that but yeah
it's got a lot of the same baseline
tools like in map and Wireshark and
things of that nature I don't think it
has an SDR once again you can load those
packages if if you are using a Kali I
highly recommend you go out to their
page the beauty thing of a beautiful
thing about calories is large community
that supports it so they have their own
people that support it maybe they come
out with like pen testing with Kali all
these different kind of books they have
online resources one of the best
resources I've ever seen Waldo's hacking
fest actually sat through Johnny Long's
class on Kali dojo so they actually
teach you and you can get this from
their resources online how to build your
own Kali system with whatever tools you
want on it so you can completely
configure Kali and you can have it
replicated across machines you can
all kinds of things happen or this so
it's great so you'd like build one gold
image that you want let's put it on all
your team's machines pretty cool any
questions so far all right going a lot
faster than I thought I would
my original presentation where I had
actual instead of just quotes from the
movies at video snippets from the movies
whenever I ran through it last Friday
was an hour and 45 minutes long and like
an hour of that was video and my
brother-in-law as a lawyer is like you
know I think you've kind of kind of gone
past the fair use doctrine here so as
your legal counsel I recommend that you
not give this presentation especially if
it's being recorded so how many people
are either participating in the CTF or
plan on doing something tomorrow all
right so the first thing I'll tell you
is this this CTF there's no physical
security flags so you will need some
type of computing device make sure that
whenever you go in there you ask about
the rules this one seems a little both
fun and can be very annoying
because one of the things they're
allowing you to do is as you get flags
they're converting that the money like
their own little Bitcoin on their
internet right and once you get a
certain amount I think it's like three
thousand credits yeah you can SWAT
people so if you can figure out the
other teams information you can pay to
have them swatted so they get dust or
arrested so they have to get off the
network for a period of time that's kind
of a cool concept but if you're starting
tomorrow there might be some people that
might just SWAT you guys because they've
been building up flags it is their Oh
oh yeah coz so all the zero flags are
the first level flags are new but and I
think the level one flags are new ok ok
yeah but they said they're gonna start
adding more flags because people can't
get past the first level so
unfortunately I think some of the things
they've introduced are the ones from
last year and two years ago so yeah ok
ok so one of the first things I'll have
you do is just go to their website and
you'll register a team name every CTF
I've ever been to is run the same way
they'll have a team or they'll have a
tracking page that shows you the points
and it's usually in real time or near
real time you'll have a lot of the
reason why I say near real time is you
have a lot of people that are doing CTF
and they're either new at it and they
think that that box is actually one of
the boxes that's in play because I don't
understand networking or you know
sometimes heck I've been there freaking
10 o'clock at night exhausted from just
staring at a screen all day and I jump
oh I stopped you know doing like a slash
24 and all of a sudden you know scanning
slash 20 I don't even know where that is
right and I'm like oh crap
you know like well I get any 2000 boxes
there should be 5 boxes on the network
and then you're just like oh cider
notation moron
so you'll you'll always register a team
name and then if they have them read the
rules so I've been to some where your
very first flag you get nothing
except a network and your very first
flag is a text file that's the rules for
the game and if you violate the rules
before you read the text flag you
actually get negative on your flags so
you could be like negative 400 before
you capture your second flag so those
are kind of interesting never
underestimate your ability of social
engineer there's gonna be a lot of
people in that room and maybe not this
one but I've been somewhere there's
in eighty ninety hundred people in the
room and there's people walking through
constantly and I'll just get frustrated
I'll hear that maybe somebody's working
on the same flag as me I'll go take a
break have somebody watch my computer
but take a break and then swing by that
team's desk just listen in for a while
hey I've never done that before what's
that toy you're using
oh well IP address for you on oh wow
that rocks and then you've got a fleck
and they do all the work and unless
that's unless social engineering is
specifically prohibited by the rules
it's fair game like I said this is to
help you build your skills so that maybe
you could get that dream job you want at
some point unless your dream drives GRC
and then We Need to Talk
because I can tell you for a fact as
much as I love policy I'm sick of policy
so here are the two takeaways other than
all my movie quotes and all those those
lists of movies that you're all going to
go out and watch right especially if you
were born in the 90s that's that's
almost embarrassing have you guys you
guys look pretty young y'all seen any of
those movies
okay I'd start with I definitely start
with gotcha I mean that that's just it's
a classic spy game and only he doesn't
know he's a spy he's he's yeah it's very
well yeah one of my favorites probably
watch that movie a couple hundred times
anyway so CTF filled guide this is
really cool because they actually it is
a book that they've published at this
website and it will talk about some of
the same things that I've talked about
they'll actually they have some teaching
resources where they'll teach got to use
different tools and then the second one
Jordan I don't know how to say his last
name wines or Wiens I like his website
cap TF comm and the reason is is
whenever he does an online capture the
flag or whenever he does a capture the
flag at a conference he will actually
write very detailed scripts on how he
did it not only that
but he actually has a list of websites
that you can go out to and he'll rank
them like if you're a beginner start
with these websites if you're advanced
start with these websites if you've
never used this tool before go to this
website and do this one right use
Metasploit able Adrian do you know have
you ever used the I think it's called
the really damn exploitable website or
something like that
it's another virtual machine that's a
web server yeah damn vulnerable web app
that's it yeah my one and only for a
using burp suite was against that and I
can't stand that tool but anyway it's
it's corporate it's huge and I can't
afford it so there you go so like I said
my whole point for this was to tell you
a story hopefully you enjoyed it really
everything that you could ever want is
going to be on one of these two websites
and if you follow Jordan wines he tweets
about his CTF experience all the time I
don't think the guy actually has a job
because he's constantly tweeting about
it um so are there any question oh by
the way no no no no I forgot about this
movie so gotcha is gonna be the second
movie you watch the first movie is real
genius have you seen real genius it is
absolutely other than maybe the Saint it
is probably the best movie that Val
Kilmer has ever been in I'm a big fan of
the Saint but you know Top Gun hey you
know he rocked it out of the park there
but his character in this show is the
guy I grew up wanting to be except I
wasn't smart enough to be so yeah at
some whenever you watch the movie at
some point you're gonna realize why I
just said what I said because he's just
you know you've got those people that
are so smart
they just don't care and they can be
chilled because they can have a job you
know a job at the drop of the Hat
but yeah so he's like a PhD student at
age 19 or something like that and they
get a 17 year old that comes in and
beats them and all these different
things and yeah he retaliates the best
way you notice how which is practical
jokes so yeah one of my favorite quotes
from here Mitch which is the young kids
17 year old high school student comes in
helps with their PS ph.d program
actually a weapons program he says what
are you doing and Chris Knight Val
Kilmer says Self Realization I was
thinking the immortal words of Socrates
who said I drink what right and I mean
that's probably that's not even one of
the best lines in there but one of my
favorite lines and you know you guys
you'll see this so if you watch the
movie I'm glad that it really worked but
I hope it doesn't explode so keep that
in mind
all right questions comments cool thanks
a lot guys I do have one more thing I am
teaching my other actual passion handgun
safety course the NRA sponsored on on
nra certified instructor I teach three
four four courses this one I'm teaching
for free here and if you are from C
Pennsylvania you don't need it if you're
from Virginia West Virginia and you want
reciprocity because you don't have to do
in West Virginia you don't have to take
a class now you don't even need a
license to open carry or concealed carry
if you're over the age of 21 but if you
want reciprocity in other states you
need one and unless it's not oh hi oh I
think Georgia and somebody asked me
about Alabama earlier it counts for
Alabama oh yeah yeah yeah
but yeah so free training takes one hour
and then I'll give you guys a notarized
form that says you took NRA class from a
certified instructor I'll put my number
on there and it's free so all right cool
now thanks
it's seven o'clock