it's on yeah take two so this is a
presentation about attribution drink
divert attribution yes however it is
simple attribution we're going to cover
a lot of the broader topic to make sure
that people understand there's more than
just cookie tracking and handle tracking
but the majority of what we're here to
talk about is how to track people down
this was prompted by so you have a frame
of understanding why I'm talking about
it by a client who was being harassed
online and when people come to me and
ask me how they can make money and how
they can get into the business and do
things with this skillset that we seem
to acquire this is one of the ways you
can do that so use your powers for good
do not use this information and
knowledge to harass people not that
there's a whole lot in here that's very
in-depth because this is a more of an
introduction to the topic but the
information in here is also not complete
[Applause]
so this is about eight hours worth of
material shoved into a one-hour
presentation there's plenty of more work
to do you know how to find me online all
the information you need is online
everything is available online and this
topic has been covered in numerous other
places before although not exactly like
this so it's fun to figure out who
posted stuff and it's good practice it's
something that you can do for free to
hone your skills you can track people
down but don't do it maliciously or with
bad intent because that's called
stalking
and if you thought we were gonna teach
you how to find your ex girlfriend
boyfriend whoever that may be on
Facebook this is not that presentation
most importantly this is me this is me
daxing me so you don't have to bother
everything that is in this presentation
comes from me and old profiles and old
me things because I can't use real
people they might get upset I can for I
use Adrienne but what would be the point
we all know all of the stuff out there
so you needed something new that you
hadn't seen so this is me I am the
example so the problem that we're facing
is anonymous posts when people say
something that you don't like when
people say something especially about
your client that is bad for them like
your business sucks and you sell
poisonous food you should never eat here
that affects their business there's
actual damages that can be assigned so
if you can track that person down you
can sue them and we get some of that
money back but in a lot of cases it's
just not worth it it's not enough damage
to bother with but in some cases it is
in this case it was a extended amount of
damage over a long period of time which
included intentional destruction of an
animal not in distress other words they
killed her dog so we were very
interested in finding this person but
anonymous posts and so on you don't know
who they're handle is tracking this
stuff down is not pressed oh I know who
this is you have to go through the
motions and if you're gonna use it in
court it has to be provable in court the
average person doesn't have the ability
to do some of the things that we do from
the legal perspective because we have
the legal system behind us
if you can't issue subpoenas or you
can't ask for subpoenas
you're gonna limit yourself to a whole
bunch of narrower perspectives that may
not produce what you want on the other
hand if you are working outside of the
law for example and govern
you have access to a whole bunch of
other techniques and options that we'll
touch on a little bit that that are much
more productive and faster but there
really isn't much the normal person can
do because unless they're dumb enough to
you know this is my facebook profile and
this is actually me and make it really
easy for you to identify who they are
like if they slam you on a Google review
but they use their actual Google account
to do it that's not gonna take you long
to track them down but real perps real
people with intent real stalkers real
bad guys cover their tracks pretty well
typical tools that they use VPNs
impersonating using other people's names
impersonation is one of my favorites
because it creates noise it creates a
lot of noise depending on how you do it
for example if I go by the handle John
Stewart and I've been posting in
political forums there's gonna be a lot
of mixed confusion there because it's
the same stuff in the same forums but
the biggest problem that we face in
attribution with this stuff is the
second main point here that is they they
fail to get in touch with professionals
in a timely manner because aside from
medical data legal data things and
regulated industries
nobody has to retain their logs no
there's no reason that Facebook has to
retain any logs other than the fact that
the CIA and the NSA want them to but
they have that isolated in a different
place in Utah but nobody else has to
maintain logs so if you have a sketchy
website and you want their audit trails
to figure out who user 2 1 7 is you have
to get to them in a timely fashion if
you want any chance at all of getting
those audit trails because they will
either delete them intentionally they
will roll them there's all sorts of
reasons why they just aren't there they
weren't configured right to begin with
because there's no reason for those
people to do anything like that so they
don't
however if you can reach out and touch
them with a subpoena or an audit or a
legal order you can then force them to
start logging and if you don't trip up
your target you can then get those logs
back but again it has to be done in a
timely manner because you may lose the
target the subject of interest so time
for a lot of these off our operations is
quite literally important Twitter it
keeps everything forever Facebook does
but they don't tell you you don't have
access to it in general there's the way
back time machine we're gonna talk about
that but time when you're trying to
track people down for things they do on
the Internet just like the real world is
very important camera images from
security cameras they don't stick around
forever but we have multiple methods of
identifying perpetrators depending on
how we're going about it and what they
did if it's a physical issue you can be
using physical identifiers but we're
talking about social media stuff so
we're just gonna kind of skip over
fingerprinting and hair and stuff like
that and talk about linguistics it will
details exotic identifiers and of course
the penis they can all be automated to
some level the nice thing about
computers is that they make these
processes faster for us so you can go
out and use tools to make this stuff go
really fast especially if you're working
for a government I can't sorry brain but
when you're doing this stuff
professionally and you're not a
government and you're not doing it
because you're stalking somebody you
have to take the client sit them down
and have a talk and ask them are you
sure you want to do this this is gonna
cost you ten to twenty thousand dollars
it's not cheap to have somebody spend
this kind of time on technical matters
and run this stuff to the ground
especially when it's dead end after dead
end if you get lucky you can click a
button in multi go and presto there's
your answer but you're still gonna have
to put together an evidence package it's
still gonna take time none of this stuff
is free so they have to be damaged
enough to make it worth their while
if it's personal reputation and it's an
individual chances are they may just
want the knowledge they may not need the
extra baggage of legal protection but
it's always going to cost something the
other problem that we run into is every
now and then it's a one-off you get
somebody who goes home drunk one night
after eating at a restaurant and doesn't
like the food and logs on to somebody's
account and post a bad review and
they're gone they sober up they forget
all about it it never happens again
there's no way to track that down it's
it's gone and it was only a one-time
deal so no big deal time is always the
enemy but it's not hopeless there's a
variety of ways that we can track people
who do leave extended trails which is
the people that we really want to track
down because that's where the effort is
they put in the most effort of being
jerks which makes our job easier to
track them down
linguistics analysis is always fun some
of us have certain speech patterns
certain ways that we write certain
things that we say adrian has certain
characteristic phrases that uses quite
frequently I have characteristic phrases
that I use quite frequently like time is
money
then there's OSN which is kind of what
we're here to talk about in around about
fashion there's social engineering traps
which is another favorite of mine if you
can't get the logs if you can't get the
evidence from the existing materials you
can construct a trap this is fairly easy
if you know your subject which brings us
back to figuring out who they are
through the OS and pathway we may not be
able to get attribution but if we can
figure out enough about the target then
we can construct a Nessie trap and get
them that way always work through a
lawyer things like that can border on
legal problems can create legal
situations that you may not be equipped
to handle including things that we need
warrants so work with your lawyer and
potentially law enforcement when doing
things like that unless you're just
trying to trap your friends and then
it's cool fire up set and have fun bait
traps is another one
you may have seen or heard of people who
have warrants out being trapped by
winning prizes that's a great one you
have won an Xbox and an all-expense-paid
trip to Vegas to see the new computer
system displayed and then they show up
to collect and you arrest them bait
traps as a physical thing but it's there
if you need it
private investigators are necessary in
some states for all of this stuff so
know your laws if you're doing this in a
business format you may not be allowed
to do some of this stuff without a
license and then there's more exotic
traps pretty much it's open to your
imagination how to get people to give
you the information that you need to set
them up which go back for just a second
things like exotic traps cross readily
into this is how criminals make money
social engineering your uncle from
Nigeria who died with all that money
that's just a Nessy trap that's criminal
in nature linguistic tracking you've got
to have enough content to make it useful
this is more useful in a political forum
than it is on a restaurant review board
as you can see there's gonna be a lot
more text especially if they're very
erudite and vocal they talk a lot or
write a lot spelling mistakes are an
easy catch but this is not the normal
sort of stuff that we use for OSN
tracking this is more on the
intelligence side because
but it's legal when you're when you're
playing with friends or doing this stuff
for personal use you may not be trying
to figure out who the gesture is but you
can technical tracking now we're getting
into the fun stuff data everybody knows
about the extra invisible image files
that show up when you're browsing the
net and the different types of cookies
and tracking and all of that stuff the
neat thing about those is that they can
work in the reverse direction so what's
used to track you can also be used to
track back particular identifiers will
indicate a specific individual and this
is where it starts to get more
interesting down the list here you'll
see exif data which isn't as big as it
was but chip ids for intel if you can
get their chip ids from their processor
that's a pretty solid match it's not
guaranteed will it hold up in criminal
court and probably not will it hold up
in civil court probably you have to do
some tricks to get that to work for you
though like get them to run a program
memes images anything that anybody posts
on the Internet in any form and any
content especially if it's a consistent
use over time like Facebook Twitter
imager I mean every app that's on your
phone all of that stuff can be used to
track people back we're gonna talk about
a little bit of it in detail then
there's the exotic stuff which falls
more into government work getting audio
recordings of people figuring out who
they are from that watching through
cameras to see if somebody is the same
person when they're in disguise are not
facial recognition GPS history signal
noise signal noise is one of my
favorites but it requires you to have
access to the thing that's generating
the signal noise when we're talking
about this the historical
version I can't remember whose
murder-mystery it was but there was a
murder mystery and the letters were
typed and there was an error in the
typewriter and they tracked it back to
the typewriter in the ribbon and they
found the purpose yay well that works
for just about anything that produces
any sort of signal if there's an error
in it it can be detected and if you can
detect that error and track it back to
something at their location then you can
pin the tail on the donkey so to speak
so this is an example of signal noise
from a monitor that was taken from a
screen shot if you serve a warrant on
that person and collect all of their
computer stuff and find the monitor that
generates the same problem piece of
noise you've got a match potentially
that's exotic though we're not going to
be doing that so the tools that we're
using for OSN match up in common use
everybody here knows about multi go who
doesn't know about multi go no okay
multi go is a really handy tool I'll
show you a little couple pieces of it
here but it lets you put in things like
a user handle or a user name or a phone
number or an email address or a physical
address and then press a button and go
check the web for everything else that
matches so it goes from I've got a
handle to a map of a thousand different
options in in like the blink of an eye
and then you have to go through and
filter and go no no no no no yes no no
no yes and then you can recursively go
through this data to generate huge maps
about people and their habits and the
one that I put together for the case for
the lady with the dog was about 4,000
pieces of data from the perp and related
people who were involved and turned into
a conspiracy and terroristic threats and
all sorts of fun stuff and I'm sure the
DEA had a blast with it after I got rid
of it but the diagram that matched up
everything they were doing online with
all their Facebook and Twitter and
imager and everything else was Hugh
and yeah multigo just makes it really
easy to do you can download a copy you
can play with it you can learn to use it
without paying for it you can buy a
licensed copy I think it's like 300
bucks it's not expensive talk a little
bit more about that when we get to the
demo part not a live demo never do live
demos no idea process so the process for
tracking somebody down and pinning this
information on them it all depends on
what you're starting with typically in
an online harassment type stuff you've
got a handle if you're lucky you've got
an email address if they never use the
handle anywhere else ever again probably
gonna have difficulty tracking them down
and you're gonna have to use some tricks
to get them to interact with you like
responding to their post if they only
used it once they may not be monitoring
though so it could just die on the vine
and go nowhere but if you have a handle
that's been used in multiple places that
gets you to different parts of the web
different things that they do tells you
more about the subject gives you more
leverage and then each time you flip
over a rock and find something new
that's associated with the perp it gives
you a new place to look it's usually a
mixture of manual and automated and
searching what we do everybody who does
this for a living
has scripts that they run lobbying
multi-dose basically just one giant
script engine that you don't have to
mess with but even that can be enhanced
and I still use my own Google scripts
and Bing scripts Google foo for tracking
stuff that way because it's faster and
easier and it gets me the data that I
need to put into multi go to make it
more useful so there's a cyclical mix
that you go through to get this
information to churn until you find your
solution
you can't rely on any of it one of the
problems with attribution is it until
you're entirely positive until you have
proof beyond any reasonable doubt that
it is that person for example we picked
up their laptop and my gosh yes that's
them if you don't have physical evidence
matching them to the crime you can't
really pin stuff on somebody it's
justice through their virtual presence
you can make it look really bad but it's
gonna be a problem you can use it for
whatever purposes you want and making
them stop but if it's gonna be a legal
thing you're probably gonna want some
sort of physical tie-in like their phone
they use their phone that's a physical
tie-in but it comes down to needles in
haystacks if you pick somebody else's
handle if you pick a non-unique handle
it's a pain in the behind to track you
down if you plug John Smith into multigo
and tell it to go you're gonna be doing
a lot of filtering for a long time
because that's a common name but if you
plug in something distinctive like I see
bkr you're gonna find a very small
solution set and it's gonna be easy to
track one of the funny things about
people who like to harass people online
is to tend to have egos the size of the
planet and eventually even if they use
something anonymous to begin with you're
gonna find a unique distinctive handle
the pres 88 to 7 that's gonna lead you
directly to the one person that you're
interested in common identifiers so it
if you're a bad guy obviously do exactly
the opposite of what we're saying here
pick common names use Smith and good
OPSEC OPSEC makes our job terribly
difficult
luckily almost nobody is any good at it
even the professionals OPSEC is life and
it will make the job impossible within a
limited scope so the first technical
thing that I want to talk about is
browser fingerprinting because it's
really easy we all use browsers what
every browser shows can track you down
very readily and it's not hard to do
anybody can write this you can
throw up a website and start tracking
people yourself every time you visit a
site they're tracking we all know we're
being tracked on the web these days this
is not news to us anymore what may be
news is how closely identifiable you are
based on your browser signatures the
people who make money off of selling us
are very keen on this and they can
identify us very well this site and my
unique org is great for showing you just
how bad you are feel free to go there
right now
go right ahead you are being tracked
machine fingerprinting goes right along
with that if you can't get them from the
browser you can get off the machine
the cpuid is like I said one of my
favorites but in order to fingerprint
the machine
generally speaking you need system
access you can't get system access
without a payload without hacking which
is why we're talking about this at a
hacker conference but you have to have a
legal justification for infecting
malware on someone inflicting malware on
somebody's machine but again it works
Google after all has an actual patented
process for how to identify you from
your surfing characteristics they are
keenly interested in keeping track of
everything we do as is Facebook people
selling things track you all of them
amazon everybody they've all got it
we've all seen it
experienced it you're talking on your
phone to somebody and you mention a
product and then you go use Facebook on
an entirely different computer and lo
and behold there's an advertisement for
that product you like what is this well
that's because you're the product but we
can use these same things that they're
using to track us to track perps so
understanding how they work and knowing
your target if we're looking at for just
to simplify the example if we're looking
at cookies from America and our purpose
not an American and they're not in the
cotton
United States American cookies from
websites serving American people are not
going to help us we need to know who our
subject is to figure out how we want to
track them but you can use their tools
to track back you can for instance by if
say the interaction with the purpose
occurring in a Facebook group you can
purchase advertisements on Facebook for
next to nothing and if you set your
keywords up to match what it is they're
posting and where they're posting you
can be pretty sure that you're gonna
pick them up as part of the group and
it's cheap but handles Nick's synonyms
these are all the things that we
normally see and they're the first thing
they like to put into multigo they show
up in all kinds of places that do not
want you to track stuff so you have to
know your way around the web and how to
get in there and see things that you're
not supposed to see but it's there
multigo the 800-pound gorilla we talked
about this a bit it requires a lot of
patience when it pops out a thousand
results for something you just have to
take your time and go through it it's
it's just the way it works multigo is
available from Patara com I'm not
endorsing them as the only solution here
but they are slick as hell so they have
it it's also not expensive this is what
it looks like when you use it this is
the not live demo so you got our me
you've got our handle you've got Twitter
you've got email this is almost no
filtering because I see bkr is a very
distinctive handle there are some
garbage now because it's 2018 and
everything that is unique on the network
is now not unique thanks to spam and
different things but it will kick out
Yahoo I can't read that one RCN
Twitter some phone numbers a couple
other handles lots of stuff for you to
take off with so the stuff works no
denying that everybody wake up
secret hidden entrepreneur tip time is
money
anything you do that saves money can
make you money that saves time can make
you money whenever you're doing stuff as
a professional or as a hobbyist or
whatever if you figure out a way to save
time whether you write a script or you
write a program or an app or anything
like that that's a way to make money so
monetize what it is you do or make money
off of the secret that you're keeping
either one there's a couple companies
who are very very good at stuff anyway
heard a great key Greg he makes a device
for breaking into phones Apple was very
upset about this and they made their new
OS so that Greg he couldn't get in and
that lasted about five minutes because
Greg it was a whole bunch of secrets and
they don't tell Apple so if you know
stuff that is worthy of being paid for
by all means get paid for it
never do something for free if you have
bills to pay and all of this stuff is
like that IP addresses is another one
this used to be in the dark early days
of the Internet if you had an IP address
you could assign it to somebody and that
was really cool because you could blame
people
well I gots to eat over at NASA he's a
pain I don't like him he makes bad
comments in my political form and you
knew it was them because you had the IP
address well that's all garbage now but
it's still something to work with right
if you have an IP address you have a
starting point it may not be the
destination but it's a place to start
and eventually you can track through the
net and find where they are posting from
even if it's a Panera Bread that's a
particularly broad end point to work
with but it's still a Panera Bread right
you now know where they are
they're not using a repeater from the
inside of a Panera Bread that's for sure
well I mean you know somebody could be
but no not these guys
so variable values dynamics part of the
problem with IP assignments though and
people who are serious about this like
people who are paid to harass other
companies yes that's an actual thing
people are paid to harass companies or
people who are engaged industrial
espionage any of the criminal aspects of
IT that we deal with the rule of hacking
what is the first rule of hacking
anybody nobody
first rule of hacking always cross a
border preferably a language border
preferably a political border so if
you're going to hack you're going to do
it from a Russian address but that's
only one layer removed and probably not
a good idea because the Russians are no
more friend and friendly than the CIA so
if you're going to do it you're going to
cross multiple borders and multiple
language barriers that's the best way to
stay hidden even if they can trace it
back chances are they can't get the
audit trail so they can't get the access
they can't get the records it's gonna be
a dead end
that's what the big boys do attribution
is hard the best one I heard a year ago
a year and a half ago was there was a
hack and somebody came out and blamed
China and then somebody pointed out that
the code was Russian and then somebody
pointed out that it was actually the
Israelis way to go guys MAC addresses
again limited availability we can change
MAC addresses now this used to be carved
in stone now not so much but it's still
a piece of data if they're using a MAC
address and they don't change it and
it's valid and you have the hardware
then you're good to go
MAC addresses show up in log files or
systems routers things like that but
again they're limited by time so if
you're doing some sort of attribution
that involves this material time is of
the essence or you're going to have to
lay a trap
images and characteristics for a while
their exif data does everybody know what
exif data is it's the stuff the cameras
and phones embed the knowledge that they
embed inside the pictures that you take
you then upload to the web that we can
then look at and track you back like the
GPS location of where you took the
picture now Facebook and Twitter and a
bunch of other people Google things and
they have started stripping out all of
the exif data because stalkers were
using is to find people and people are
getting upset about it but it's still
out there in some places and if you're
dealing with pictures that were uploaded
to a BBS or something low-key not a
facebook something more mild or
something on the darknet then the exit
data is still there and that can be a
direct link things other characteristics
in the images are the background
different pieces of repeated use
different I tend to reuse a certain set
of memes anybody here uses memes for
communication you know what I'm talking
about there's a certain subset that you
keep handy because you're going to reuse
them again and again and again so if
those keep popping out in different
comment threads with different handles
maybe I've got a characteristic there
that I can work with and then
backgrounds and pictures if I'm taking
selfies and I have a Guy Fawkes mask on
and the background is identifiable as
something then I can pin location on you
I can I can tie that picture to you
using what's in the background you see
that used a lot in CP cases with kids
which is terrible and sad but I'm glad
they figured out a way to use the data
to get the bad guys so exif data did
they take it that somebody else take it
is there any data but again this is
becoming more limited so sort of skip on
that image characteristics themselves is
fun it's mostly a manual operation there
are people who write scripts because
they do this all the time fun things to
look for pixels that drop out certain
color features in the camera
if you can identify what specific brand
of camera they are using there are
certain image characteristics that will
be produced by that camera in every
picture and you can then go back to
image search using those characteristics
and find other pictures that they have
taken or likely have taken you'll be
writing custom code for that though
pixel maps colors locations they can
Photoshop you onto a picture of Yosemite
but it's still a picture of Yosemite I'm
sure a lot of us have used Google Image
reverse search to go back and take
something and find something else that
like the original picture footprints
domain Amazon ID different things that
they're using deleted posts from way
back there's all these different little
dark places that you can find you have
to dig into this stuff old web sites
that they may have generated and if we
started with wellhere's I wanted to pull
this let's see
okay escape maybe not good alright one
second this is a nice blog by Michael
basil give some credit out to somebody
who helped me find some stuff he talked
about digging through old reddit posts
here and attribution for the Texas
Ballmer
Austin llama just trying to another way
to find attribution reddit all of these
sites are useful to you depending on how
prolific your guy and you're trying to
track down this back to our regular
scheduled presentation anybody needs the
links for this they're all in the the
slides online or catch me afterwards
yeah man is technologies got so much
better okay so we started out with IC
bkr and the chain is lengthening one of
the pieces that came out in our search
there with multigo was dsl reports
there's an entry on a dsl reports
website dsl reports as a provider
documentation and testing website so
what we get from this is the location of
the last place that he was when he ran
the speed test which gives us a location
a huge huge advantage in finding people
is knowing where they are we've got time
frames for when they were when I joined
when he joined when I joined the last
time that it was seen he know that it's
still active they're still using it
there's all kinds of valuable
information just in this one hit the
second piece that popped out was this
old web entry from the cobweb RCN comm
/ic bkr
there might be some source code there we
can look at maybe there's some comments
in there that will lead us down into
other paths maybe they'll be language
indicators but the fact that this alias
was now used in multiple places tells us
that it's a consistent alias if we can
tie it back to me we know that this is
the same thing over and over again and
we've got a wonderful time frame here
2005 to now that's a lot of material
that we're gonna be able to get assuming
I was prolific and we've got IP
addresses over time which tells you if I
moved around if I came to where
Allentown PA recently maybe I was
testing someplace else before then that
information would then allow you to tie
back to a personal history report which
you can get without any of this
additional electronic stuff right you
all know that you can just log onto a
site pay them ten bucks and run
basically a history of somebody and get
their addresses and their phone numbers
any criminal filings all kinds of nasty
stuff so that combined with this will
give you a pretty solid reference crumbs
that come out when you're looking at the
DSL report site other things that are
useful potentially but maybe a little
minor different types of OS and browser
possibly some se targets that come out
of the multi go circle search we have
locations to put crafted malware we now
know that it's United States its eastern
us we can do things like send an email
to me that says the Eagles are not going
to win the Super Bowl this year they
suck it and if I'm an Eagles fan I might
open that email up and click on the link
and reply or something like that not an
Eagles fan by the way
guy so location and then the joint at
3:00 a.m. that's weird is that on the
previous one why did I say that
oh yeah
yes adjoined at 3:00 a.m. who works at
3:00 a.m. but it tells you that there's
a clock if there's a person doing stuff
at odd hours so the other piece that
popped out on multigo that I couldn't
read is Jenks there's an entry down here
on the bottom when we pop in Jenks which
is a t-shirt site of let's go with that
it's a t-shirts I had to make cool
teachers but something popped out based
on that information from multigo that
takes us to meme generator net so now
we've got a link to another site we've
got more information tied to icy bkr
tells us more about the perp gives us
something to work with chances are so I
probably play games I have an Amazon
account because I bought a fire
controller so now you've got more places
to look for more information and I like
memes and I can well enough to actually
make one so you've got more content
there if you go and dig around you can
probably find more things that I've done
maybe a bunch more maybe not I don't
know but there's some it's something to
work with so you've got different
characters that I've created actual OC
as we say in me morale post like you can
look at comments on my posts and see if
there are responses to those comments
because if I thought enough to reply to
a comment it's probably going to contain
some information that may be useful and
if nothing else you can reply to those
comments and get my attention especially
if it's a recent contribution that shows
that I'm still active I'm still paying
attention to that account
one of the other memes that pops out
leads you into a whole nother area
anybody know who crypt yeah is yeah 50
is a spook like a real spook like an
intelligence guy really smart cat he
uses this stuff for tracking government
actors and he is way better at it than I
am but I've got a response on one of his
posts so now you know that I know a
little bit about the intelligence world
and some of the people who are within it
at least enough to have conversations
and not look like an idiot talking to
this guy which means I have some level
of skill that's another piece of
knowledge for you to exploit also you
know that I am at least familiar with
him possibly friendly you may be able to
impersonate him and get me to respond to
something that way it's more material
for you use and if you're trying things
if you're trying to interact with the
perp and failing you have to just keep
trying right one of these is gonna work
but you also don't want to tip them off
if I get a hundred friend requests from
Owen or different people on a hundred
different websites in the same day
chances are man knows something's up and
again this gets us down to Twitter down
here another confirmation that this is
the same cat from Twitter if we go to
any URL Icebreaker using our Google food
we pop out a website a blog
it contains copious amounts of
information that detailed personal
habits political leanings opinions
professional habits this is like a
jackpot if we can prove that this is the
IC bkr that we have been looking for
this gives us scads of information to
use the only problem is that it's from
2006 but people don't change that much
over time so while this might be a
cobweb it's still gonna be full packed
full of things that we can use
and there's a chance since it's still
out there and hasn't been
doing a bust huh hoping okay did I had
that did I add that no okay yeah there's
a few things out there so many I don't
remember yeah so the cobweb gives us
more information we're talking about
spam blocking software attorneys
different kinds of handles that you can
use to get a hold of the subject give
you different clues of places to look
another alias unfortunately the profile
is private you can't get in from there
however if you can get around that you
can use it to your advantage but all
sorts of fun stuff and there's another
Association down at the bottom somebody
called brain doc our looks like Brian
it's not it's brain doc are there's a
completely different dude but he's
another handle and access into the world
of icy bkr that you may be able to
exploit you notice that they're both
associated with Concord law so now
you've got a school association that you
can go back to and mine you can maybe
call them up and request academic
records they might be dumb enough to
give them to you
schools are fairly low security bars to
cross but they don't get you Facebook
and more importantly even if you get
facebook if you don't have access or if
it's not a public profile it's not going
to get you anywhere because Facebook
does take their security seriously does
anybody know why Facebook takes their
security seriously wrong that's not why
they take their security seriously it's
not because they care about you it's not
because they care about the law your
privacy or anything like that it's
because you are the product and you are
their source of income and if that data
gets compromised they can't make money
anymore
just like hospitals and HIPAA they don't
want to comply with HIPAA not because
it's the right thing to do but if they
don't they can't do business so that's
why they're worried about security so if
you have access into a profile and this
is one of the things that if you do this
professionally or or as a habit for a
lot of things who's got more than one
Facebook profile is it is it is it a
legal contract if both parties don't
agree because I didn't agree to what
they're doing with my data so why should
I honor a contract that they claim is
enforced let's do that anyways I have
like 27 different Facebook profiles and
they all have different characteristics
and associations
chances are one of those profiles I can
get access to your information unless
you are extremely guarded on Facebook
with what you do and who you associate
with
and remember in facebook it's not just
what you do it's what your friends do so
unless your friends are just as paranoid
as you and it's good enough OPSEC to
keep people out who know what they're
doing your stuffs accessible but
Facebook even better I can just give
them money and get whatever I want so I
can send them money and say show me
everything without I see bkr in it and
they'll just give it to me because
that's how they work no subpoenas just
money subpoenas take time to execute
they're boring my job is very boring a
copy hard drives for a living
is essentially what I do dcfldd in file
I'll file
but it pays the bills and then I get to
do fun stuff like this once in a while
but it gets boring fast too because it
comes back to looking for information
and hunting down lawyers to do things
for you you've got to have subpoenas I
know you've got to have subpoenas for
this stuff it's the only way to make it
work and it may alert a canary some of
us have legal Canaries out there that go
off when we are given subpoenas I have
them on my website and if I am
subpoenaed for any reason about client
information then those Canaries go off
there's nothing that they can do about
it thankfully there's legal costs that
go along with it which so it's business
there's a good article on e F F dot org
the URLs at the bottom which you
probably can't read but it will be in
the presentation slides online or you
can just google secret files Anatomy
bogus subpoena and it tells you about
bogus subpoenas and how they can be used
to pry information out of people and of
course there's humanitarian concerns too
all of this don't be bad you can not
only use this stuff for direct harm
finding individuals tracking them down
and exposing them daxing people you can
also make their lives a living hell and
that's where it gets horribly wrong say
adrienne is looking for a job i can make
his life much more difficult by
purchasing google adwords and putting a
horrible article about him right at the
top of the Google search so they really
can I borrow some money
yeah so say he's trying to get a job in
academia I can write a blog article
about him or claiming to be him to make
it even worse that is directly
confrontational with academia and they
will be very reluctant to hire him yeah
we don't have to do that though cos so
you can use these abilities in both
directions for good or bad questions
before we get to questions thank you for
sitting through the entire presentation
I appreciate that I hope it was useful
and here is your bonus slide one of you
at least one of you should go take this
material and run with it it's a way of
thinking about how to do exploits that I
have not seen previously I just thought
of it yesterday if you want to find bugs
to exploit and ways to exploit systems
this has nothing to do with Oh assent or
social engineering this is red team
hacker stuff so here's Oh see if you
want to find the Buffalo go to where
they're wrong everybody's sanitizing
input these days well this should be but
there's still a bunch of low-hanging
fruit out there that I have not seen
given the attention it deserves
so if somebody here with a technical
bent that's bored would like to go and
look at places where there are no
sanitized input possible that seems to
me to be a very productive line of
inquiry and if you give it some thought
you'll be able to figure out where in
the world of technology we have lots of
data input with no sanitization of
inputs because there's a ton of it and
it's just not being looked at very hard
so goldmine for is zero days okay that
was fun back to the talk questions
comments criticism I have prizes No
okay well we'll just give them out then
because only the caramel who wants a
t-shirt cool t-shirt it's got a hacker
on it
it's just Excel Oh didn't quite make it
anybody want jerky you gotta go to share
they've already had it so they know it's
good your hands should have shot up you
should have taken that jerky and then I
have a golf shirt extra large all right
yeah no balls
yeah the t-shirt yeah by all means
little code I heard of those guys
they're dangerous