I'm gonna be shifting back and forth so
it's kind of easier for me this way so
okay all right so welcome everyone to
the last talk for for today I'm gonna be
talking about a cyber security
simulation portal so a little bit about
me I am a research associate faculty in
the CSE department at West Virginia
University my research areas are fire
for security and I'm also a huge fan and
advocate for open source software a bit
of a late bloomer at least in the
faculty world I didn't get my MSS se
until 2016 in my previous life though I
spent about 20 years as a Linux or UNIX
system and grew up in central PA
Harrisburg that area if any of you are
familiar with that but most of my adult
life I have lived in Morgantown West
Virginia but I did have one year stints
one was in the raleigh-durham area
during the whole comm boom of 2000 and
the crash that came after it and then a
one-year stint in the San Francisco Bay
Area
I was getting my masters in software
engineering so introduction as we're all
I think pretty much aware at this point
the the need for cybersecurity
professionals is very well documented
there is a huge shortage gap you know
every company I talked to is like how do
we create more people we want to hire
all your students you know the
unemployment rate is zero or negative
depending on how you look at it so I
think you know we're all pretty aware of
the need so we need to create more
cybersecurity professionals but training
them is gonna bring in you know
challenges you know my opinion
cybersecurity is a doing thing and so
unless you're putting students in like
real world experiences you know it's not
really gonna be that effective you can
talk about like ports being open closed
and filtered but I think until someone
runs the scan in real time they don't
really get that so in trying to teach
cybersecurity one method is called
challenge space
learning and so you know basically you
give them a challenge they solve the
challenge they get a they change a flag
from you know red to green and they get
a reward
the problem with CBL in cybersecurity is
it requires a lot of infrastructure to
give a hands-on experience and so the
configuration and maintenance of these
environments in my opinion presents a
barrier to effectively teaching
cybersecurity you know me being
assistant min I was capable of setting
these environments up but it was
becoming a real pain setting up these
test environments for competitions you
know it only be up for like a day or two
then you tear the whole thing down and
set it up again and so that was getting
really old really fast so some of my
motivations for this project was CCDC or
the collegiate cyber defense competition
and that's an inherit and defend
competition where students like teams of
eight are given a set of boxes that will
simulate like a corporate network or a
hospital and they are given an
administrative access and then their
goal is to inherit these systems and
defend them against attacks as well as
complete injects like maybe you'll have
to add a hundred email accounts to your
exchange server or things like that so I
needed a way to cheaply and quickly give
students exposure to real-world training
simulations to teach these concepts and
I also needed a way to quickly set up
and tear down these training simulations
that wasn't taking me days to provision
and get ready before an actual
competition that started so the solution
to everything these days is we use the
cloud write the clouds gonna save us
from everything it's going to end world
hunger you know world peace is gonna
happen through the cloud so you know
obviously we use the cloud but all jokes
aside you know some of the benefits of
the cloud it's a demand pay-as-you-go
model so there's not a lot of upfront
cost if you're gonna run your own
simulations on your own hardware you
know you're buying racks you're buying
lots of computers probably hiring
someone to set up and all that maintain
that so with the cloud let's just get an
account and pay-as-you-go
also in the cloud there's many different
pre-loaded operating systems so you can
quickly get up a Kali Linux box or in a
bun to system or Windows you know 2012
server and it's all available to you all
the licensing is taken care of on the
Amazon side of things so that also makes
it really nice you also have the tools
to build complex network topology
environments so most of your on or above
to say pretty much all of your on-site
premises like setups could be moved to
the cloud and so they have constructs
for you know virtual private clouds
routers gateways subnets internet car
Ethernet cards you know anything that
you would put into a data center you can
replicate that in in a cloud and also
very important with the cloud at least
with AWS the others have this as well is
you have programmatic api's so I'm not
manually going through and clicking
things you can do that but using the API
as you can quickly write code to set up
instances teardown instances set up
subnets gateways etc etc etc so the
cybersecurity simulation portal CSSP and
so when I started this project was in
the summer of 2016 and I've since
learned that cybersecurity really
shouldn't be spaced out like that
cybersecurity is preferred to be one
word so at some point I'll probably
rename this but if you've done any
programming you know sometimes just
changing the name of something can be a
lot of effort so for now I'm still
running with it and and just not using
the correct spelling of cybersecurity so
what does it do it provides a web portal
for effectively controlling and
delegating access to cloud resources to
Gmail email addresses so kind of like an
entitlement granting engine I can create
an instance and say this gmail address
can have access to it
it's written in Ruby on Rails and then
Amazon Web Services has a Ruby API so
I'm able to talk to AWS that way being
using Ruby and for authentication I used
OAuth 2 and this was awesome for me
because WVU
uses Gmail for all their student
accounts and so by supporting Gmail
authentication I didn't have to like
work with anyone in my university to do
authentication I can easily give stuff
to WVU students via their their mix
addresses is what we call it and then a
so we're going on password database I
mean if you've ever set up a server and
you've got to maintain your own database
of users now you've got to deal with
password resets and lots of other
problems so for me that's all offloaded
to Google someone can't log in
that's a Google problem you know they
have to fix that with Google so the base
functionality at Raizel right now
there's basically two roles there is a
Blue Team role and if you're familiar
with like CCDC and various competitions
Blue team is typically the defenders and
so in the CSSP application the blue team
people can log in and then get
connection information about the
instances that have been assigned to
them the in mineral can create and
delete instances and then it can
associate or disassociate instances to
specific email addresses or users and
here's a simple picture of what the
environment it's pretty flat razzle
right now I have one VPC I have one blue
subnet the blue instances then live in
the blue subnet there's a blue route
table I do have one global security
group so in Amazon speak security group
think of it as like a firewall you can
basically allow certain ports to certain
like internet addresses or you Sitter
notation so I have a global sort of
security group for the entire
environment and then if you're going to
talk to the internet you need an
Internet gateway and then the Internet
is outside of that box so conceptually
that's the environment very simple right
now hopefully over the years it will
evolve we'll talk about that later
so for identity and authentication
management I'm using devise and that's a
ruby gem which is really good for
identity and authentication and then
they have a module or plugin interface
so there is a plug-in for devise that
lets you
interface with oauth2 and Google and so
as I said this allows Blue Team users to
log in to my application with their
Gmail credentials the beauty of that is
I never see the login like I can't like
sniff out the passwords that are being
sent to me and you'll see later in the
demo kind of how it redirects you to
Google and then back to my application
and then as I said it allows the a
minute in senses to their email
addresses so a little bit under the hood
of OAuth 2 if you're not familiar with
it it's getting a little used a lot more
you know you're seeing more sites where
you login and then you can use Facebook
or Twitter or Google as your back-end
for authentication so with OAuth 2 you
have the identity provider such as
Google you have the relaying party
typically that's you the developer and
so typically the way this works is you
register a developer level account with
whoever your identity provider is so I
registered a developer account with
Google's API console and you need to
register with with them and then you
have to give them just a name that's
anything you want and you have to give
them the application URL and then what's
called a callback URL so basically when
they come to your app they go to login
they're sent to Google Google processes
it and then sends back a callback URL
which comes back to my application and
at that point Google sends me the email
address and I think we have one more
identifier that we capture there's a
couple attributes that you can capture
on the user that Google would send back
to you but in no way could it be the
password or or anything like that for me
I just want the email so I basically get
the email address and I load that into a
local user database and use that for the
system so when you register with the IDP
they give you secret keys to basically
authenticate to Google so they Google
knows you're not just some random person
trying to authenticate against them
and then you take those secret keys you
sort of drop them into your application
and then there's a there's like four
different grant flows for oauth2 the one
I'm using is the client credentials
grant flow and so this is basically the
client gives credentials and I get sent
back a mail email address and I move you
look maybe an identifier of some sort so
and that's kind of what I said next in
the in the next bullet point though so
Amazon has what's called a Mis these are
just machine images you know like an OVA
would be a similar construct to what an
ami is so in CSS P actually launched
from an ami an image that I've already
constructed and unfortunately currently
this is not integrated into the
application itself so I have to go into
Amazon directly and create the ami
however once it's created if you're
familiar with tagging in AWS I can
create a tag and my application knows to
look at all the ami is that it'll only
bring the ones that have the CSS P tag
into the actual like operating system
that I can are my CSS P application that
I can use so access control you know one
thing you don't want to do is put this
like server out on the cloud and then
open it up to the world not really a
good idea especially if you're doing
security testing and maybe you want to
put up vulnerable things so I needed a
way to make sure that only the people I
want it to were able to access the
instances that were assigned to them so
as I mentioned the instances that are
created by CSS P they're all signed the
default CSS P security group now when I
associate that instance so that a
certain user can use it it creates
additional security group it just names
the group after their email address and
when they logged into the web
application the web application can
record the IP address of where they're
coming from and so when I associate the
instance a new security group is created
and the only thing it's populated with
is the IP of the person that I want to
give it
so they login it gets their IP creates a
security group attaches that security
group to the instance that they have and
then enables full tcp/udp open so that
they have full connectivity to the
instance but you know anyone on the
internet wouldn't the neat thing with
this is like let's say they start
working on something at school and then
they go home well then they go home and
they log in again it'll just update
where they're coming from so it allows
the user the end-user to be mobile or
even doing remote competitions
you know we've used this where you use
slack to talk and then set up a bunch of
instances and have people connect to
them from you know over Christmas break
or something like that so these may be a
little out of date Amazon keeps updating
their prices pretty frequently but the
costs are pretty compelling the reason
that Windows Server instances are more
expensive is because typically for a
better experience I have to use more
powerful machines Windows doesn't really
run well on a t2 micro but Linux will
run just fine you know but even there a
scenario with ten Linux servers and ten
Windows servers for two hours we're
talking you know pretty pretty cheap if
I do my math right so like I said it's
probably cheaper today with with Amazon
now there are some problems Amazon has
an acceptable use policy so some of the
cyber security training activities that
you may want to do you couldn't really
do in this environment so this isn't the
environment to set up a distributed
denial of service attack that wouldn't
make Amazon very happy so unfortunately
there are some limitations to what this
can do but you can work with Amazon and
they have a forum where you could say
hey during this time I'm gonna do this
and they will they will grant you
permission or say change things around
but you can work with them to get maybe
more slightly complex stuff than if
you're just using the the general
instances without permission so they
have a link to their this is a security
penetration testing thing where you file
a request you describe what you're doing
and they'll come back and say yeah
that's cool
or now we have issues with you doing
this or this or this all right so enough
build-up we're gonna go ahead and kind
of try to launch the application and
demo it here live if all goes well so
live demos are always scary but we're
gonna give it a shot so before we get
started I built a ami that already has
my application built in a docker
container and so all I have to do to
launch it is pick my ami and I have a
CSS P host ami and then this is just
boring Amazon stuff but you have to go
through and configure your instance add
your storage can add a tag so you know
what it is
now I already also created an existing
security group so I'm gonna apply that
and it's complaining because I have four
3,000 open to the world
nothing's running there yet and it's
only gonna be up for an hour so
hopefully I'll be alright and then this
is all just Amazon stuff I'm not early
here to teach you about Amazon but this
is how you set up an instance and you
see - okay and so now the instance is
firing up one thing I do have to check
is to make sure that I can access this
instance so earlier I was coming from a
different IP probably than I am now so I
just want to double-check that really
quick
and so she'll be able to my IP and save
alright so now I should have SSH access
to my application host ok and another
thing I want to work on this now one of
the things with Google is they will not
let you point to an IP it has to be a
domain so every time I'm starting up at
instance it's getting a different IP and
so I want to go ahead and assign this IP
in route 53 route 53 is just the name
for Amazon's sort of DNS service so I
need to get the IP of my current
instance and then just go into route 53
and this is my entry for CSS PLC SC
cloud net and then just replace that and
then in about five minutes that will
update so that CSS PLC SC cloud dotnet
resolves to the IP where I just launched
my application
okay so the idea here is this is
supposed to be really simple something
you can just pull down from github set a
couple environment variables and you're
up and running so these are only things
you need to set before you run the
application you have to have an AWS
access key and then the secret part of
that and then a Google client ID and a
secret for that another thing we add is
an in mini mail and so whatever email
you put in here when you log into the
application that will be granted the
administration do want to use whether
it's Ohio Virginia California whatever
so basically to configure this all I
have to do I've already created a file
with my environment variables I'm not
going to show you the contents of that
environment file because it does have
Google keys and all that good stuff but
all I have to do is SCP the file to the
environment source it and then start the
container actually make this a little
bigger for you sorry flash is a simple
SCP command now I can actually connect
to the machine and yes these
sh if you actually want to console all
right so now I'm into the system my
environment file is there so I will
source it so now my all this environment
variables that I set you know told you
about they're all set now so now I can
jump into my application and this is
deployed as a docker container so I
already ran the build container script
so that's done so at this point all I
need to do is run my container and now
the application isn't running yet but
I'm sitting at a docker container in a
root prompt so one thing if you're going
to run the application you need a V PC
it's a virtual private cloud where your
instances are gonna gonna live now
before we started I created one so what
I'm gonna do is delete the old one and
then show you how I actually create the
whole V PC
okay so we're in Ohio so here you see
this is the CSS B default this is the V
PC that I'll use and we identify that
again by tagging so you can tag a V PC
and so basically my application just
looks at that looks for the V PC that
has the CSS BT CSS P tag and uses that
so I'm gonna go ahead and delete it so
it's going to delete its warning you
this way I'm gonna leave everything
that's associated with it
that's exactly what I want to have
happen so we're good so I delete it and
we're good okay so now in the
application I have some AWS scripts so
I'll run my initial
setup script and so this is
authenticating again because the
environment variables pass through and
so that's how all the keys work and it
doesn't look like you're typing any
passwords or anything like that so this
is just some ruby code we wrote using
the Amazon API and as you can see it's
setting up the VPC it's setting up all
the security groups I need the blue
subnet gateway etc etc etc so just some
Ruby if you want to take a quick look at
what what coding what the API looks like
that's just a quick sort of snippet so
fun stuff so now when I come back here
and refresh there it is it's back so
very easy to destroy it create so
deployment is supposed to be that simple
just get the ami set some of our
variables run a script to create the V
PC then I've got two more small scripts
I've got a run that configure my app and
start it up so two more scripts that I
have so this is a simple setup script if
you've ever had the pleasure of working
with Ruby on Rails it's a lot of fun
little tongue-in-cheek where else is
great when it works sometimes you have
an abstraction that you don't understand
and it's expanding something and that's
when I hate Rails but and then I'm using
Puma and I got fired up so we're good so
I'm just running screen there so
obviously that in a background screen
session okay so now before I connect I
want to make sure that my IP is updated
so just want to do a quick sanity check
well I guess we'll just find out if it
works so I'll do that okay
and it's up because I've already logged
in I ought to just let me in so that's
not very much fun to see so I will show
you in a in incognito mode in chrome
kind of what it would look like so
you're given a login screen you then
sign in with Google OAuth 2 that then
takes you to Google and then from there
you would log in as you log into Google
if I could type and then we have a
multi-factor authentication so I'll need
an app second
well this is cool so if your
organization has MFA and stuff then like
if you're using this for authentication
that's going to go with it log
so it's giving me the callback URL
sending me back to my app and letting me
in all right okay
so now for the demo I'm gonna log in as
the administrator an instance and
associate the instance to an email
address so one thing I'll show you under
blue team controls right now there is
nothing assigned to my actual email
address so in manage instances try make
this a little bigger so basically it's
any AMI it finds it's gonna put a nice
pull down for you I only have one so
that's all I set up for this and then
you can change like the type if you want
t to micro is fine for this demo so I go
ahead and create the instance so now I
called the API it launched an ec2
instance it's telling me the type the
the image ID and the status is pending
and so also from the app from the app I
can stop and start instances or
terminate them so now I go to the
instance mapping and then when I
associate this instance with my email
address so right now only have one of
each that's pretty easy but if you have
multiple users logged in you'd get a
pulldown actually he did login for me so
so I got it go ahead and create this map
and now when I go to blue team controls
it's there and so also when I went to
blue team controls it created a security
group it applied it to that instance and
then a populate it with the IP where I'm
coming from
[Applause]
so you can see or maybe you can't
because it's too small but I try and get
down there down in this area see there
was a second security group that was at
it and I could go ahead and click on
that and look it inbound and so
basically it's just open all TCP and UDP
to the IP of where I'm coming from so so
now as the blue team person I can show
the instance and so that's just going to
give me some information I give both the
public and private because sometimes if
you're talking internally you've got to
use the private IP of the internal
interface for the for the AMR if not the
ami the instance but you've got to use
the public IP to get to it in the first
place so this is set up to be a very
like simple basic challenge where I
enable a route log into a box and the
challenge would be simply to disable
route logins and create another account
that's administrative you know kind of a
basic cybersecurity exercise but you
know you could build out a Mis as
complex as you want and then just launch
them you know as many as you need on
demand for people all right so I'll take
my connect string and I have a
for secure password of Tor right now and
now I'm into a fully functioning system
so at this point the the blue team ER or
the learner would be then going through
and completing some tasks or whatever
you've asked them to do so yeah
basically these are the injects if
you're used to CCDC that's just speak
for a task that you have to complete so
the injects for this would be change
default password or disabled probably
better and disable the route from being
able to log into the system and then
change password for the abun to user
it's kind of funny because Amazon makes
the remedy is pretty secure so I had to
like launch one of their bun two images
and make it less secure so that I could
have an effective challenge cuz Amazon
by default they really want you logging
in with SSH keys and initially that was
the way I did it and if you've ever
tried to teach someone cyber security
and they don't know too much when
they're starting and the first thing you
throw at them is SSH keys you're gonna
have a difficult time so I think for the
simpler challenges just simple username
passwords to get them on board is the
way to go so that's kind of what it does
today it is an active development so
some future work that I would like to do
for this is make it so I can manipulate
and view security group information from
the application itself you know
basically I want to stop going to Amazon
for anything and I want to be able to
manipulate my a.m. eyes from within CSSP
itself so I should be able to like take
a running image and say create a name
ami from this I'd also like to get the
the SSH key pair generation in place and
so I could give users the ability to get
SSH keys for things another big problem
is there's no automatic shutdown of the
images so I have to manually make sure
that I terminate things when when things
are done so that's kind of annoying and
more than once I've let some things run
a little longer than I and I want to and
I'm on demand pay-as-you-go model that's
not what you want to be doing you know
this only does single machines right now
and that's cool for a lot of things
but you know for training you'd want
more of a network with like a mail
server and a database and a web server
so I've thought about like interfacing
with CloudFormation or something that
would let me deploy sets of machines to
users as opposed to just one so maybe in
CloudFormation I could make different
templates and then quickly deploy them
as you saw the deployments still not
quite as nice as I want it to be there's
still some manual steps so anything I
can do to simplify the deployment and
then you know my dream is to get this to
the point where I would release it as an
open source project you know I really
target this for like if you want to
teach cybersecurity and you don't have
an infrastructure you know you can't
build that out hopefully something like
this could be trap a program you know
you don't need barely any money all you
need is an Amazon account and this code
you need some money to pay for your you
know Amazon usage but you know all the
stuff that you'd have to do to do this
on-site you don't have to worry about it
so you know I'm hoping that this could
spread and help you know educate and
fill this obviously knowledge gap not
knowledge gap but employee gap you know
we need trained professionals in this
field and that's it so any questions and
if you're too shy to ask now that is my
email address that you can send to me so
any questions all right then we'll wrap
up a quick and thank you all for your
time
[Applause]