audio coming through okay okay all right
I guess we'll get started
so apologies this is a little bit
marketing use this presentation some
other places so just bear with me on
that but basically we're going to look
at redheads identity management today
and how that can simplify using Active
Directory identities on Linux machines
so I'm Roy Williams Red Hat certified
engineer a boom with Red Hat almost
three years now
been doing Red Hat products and identity
management for several years now and
helping develop some solutions for IDM
around smartcard and things like that
just different solutions that we can go
out and deliver to customers and then
this is my friend Chris Malthus who
usually does this presentation with me
unfortunately he wasn't able to come in
but that's him you can see us on YouTube
doing something similar to this so today
I want to go over just the different
components of IDM different trust
methods that we have available and that
would be your Active Directory trust so
trusting for identities and
authentication how we manage users in
groups the architectural design and some
discussion on how the authentication
works and then we're going to briefly
touch on some generic some generalized
field studies objectives out of this
they're going to be understanding the
fundamentals of the different
integration methods so the different
ways we can integrate with Active
Directory and identifying which method
is best based on your situation so what
is IDM IDM were free IPA as you may see
it in the community free IPA is the
upstream of what we mark it as rel IDM
is a centralized way to manage
authentication authorization and policy
so thank your
Active Directory domain controller this
is analogous to that on a Linux iden so
as it says here without IDM of course
you typically all your systems are
managed individually unless you're using
LDAP or something of that nature to
manage your users but even if you're
doing that a lot of times you're still
managing all your pseudo policies on a
server by server basis and your hosts
based access control is all in a SSH
config on each server this really allows
us to simplify that in a single location
yes so the advanced features would be
the host based access control suitors
and we can also do like file shares for
home directories so you can automate
your home directories you can define all
that in a single location much like
Active Directory the other big benefit
here is it's all native tooling and we
can still integrate with Active
Directory so there's no third party
products they're going to break every
time you run a em update it's all native
stuff that's already there so the
benefits the your IT administrators will
be able to maintain identities in one
place so you're not having to go to
every single server to update a password
or lock a user that left we're able to
apply policies multiple machines at one
time so we we find that we have an issue
with a sudo rule we can go out and
immediately modify that sudo rule across
the board instead of doing it in every
single system that that user or that
group is associated with we can set
different access levels so one of my
favorite examples for that scenario is
you have a group for your admins and you
give them access to everything with sudo
and then you have your developers you
give them access to only to development
servers and you don't give them sudo or
maybe you give them pseudo to run one or
two commands that's very easy to define
in IBM again the centrally managed
privilege a privilege X privilege
escalation that would be our pseudo
policies
and in the easily integrating with
Windows Active Directory that's done
with a trust basically just like setting
up a new Active Directory domain and
trusting it to an existing one the user
interface for it is a web UI there's
also a command-line interface and an API
so there's multiple ways that you can
interact with the service and the UI is
very nice rich UI that's pretty simple
it's not something super complicated you
can basically sit down and find things
as you're working through a problem it
allows for increased worker productivity
just because you're not having to go all
over the place to manage several
different things you're able to do
everything in one place and of course
decreases cost because you're freeing up
your resources so the components we have
for IDM we have our servers and we have
our clients pretty simple so for servers
sometimes you have see references to
master and replicas but realistically
everything is a multi master replication
so the way that boils down is you have
the initial one that you built and then
you make replicas off of it but at any
time any of those others can take over
as the master if you need them to they
the server's also act as the central
repository for all your users unless
you're pulling all your users from
Active Directory and it's also the
central repository for all your
policy-based control with so your host
based access control studio etc our
clients obviously are just in the Linux
machine this isn't just a rel thing or a
CentOS or Fedora
there's also SS SD packages which is the
client-side software for Ubuntu and
other Debian based distros and then
beyond that unix-based operating systems
can benefit from this as well by just
integrating with LDAP and Kerberos there
may be some limited functionality there
but you'll still be able to make use of
the identities and and some of the
single sign-on capabilities
so our IDM server has several pieces to
it
we've got dog tag CA it's a small CA
it's not a full-blown CA like Red Hat
certificate system we've got Kerberos
KDC which takes care of our single
sign-on
we're running bond to take care of our
DNS much like Active Directory does when
you join a new computer to it
and we also can do NTP from here so if
you have a stratum 1 you can point the
IBM service at your stratum 1 device and
then they'll pre populate all of your
NTP settings and then we manage that
again through web UI and command-line
tools and there's also the API that's
available but this is really nice
because if you need to make a quick
change web UI super clean and easy to
use if you have a bunch of changes you
need to make you can easily script it
out with the command line utilities
other clients there's there's no
dedicated software like there's no
third-party software you got to go out
and get everything is in the base rail
repo or if we're talking Cintas it's in
the base OS repo same for fedora I think
that may even be the case for Ubuntu but
don't quote me on that
and basically the package that we use is
SSS D that's the actual client software
there's another package IP a client
which is basically a package group that
puts SS SD and other things on there and
that IP a client installer that gets
installed with that will set up SS SD
for you
the only real requirements we have to
set up a client is good DNS good time
and that's really it
DNS and Tom synchronization are
crucially important for Kerberos if it
can't resolve the hostname correctly or
it can't there are the times skewed then
the Kerberos tickets won't line up and
authentication won't occur so the
client-server relationship
again this is pretty simple we still
have our IDM server over here and then
for our client we have the SSS D client
that talks to our IDM servers for LDAP
and Kerberos and then we also have cert
monger that will come over and that's
what that's going to do is it's going to
pull in our CA search so that your
search for your browser if you need to
go to the administrative UI or something
are all valid and then we can also
assign out other certificates to the
systems if we need to and manage those
with cert longer so different
integration methods we have first of all
why do we want to use Active Directory
why do we want to integrate a lot of our
customers come to us they've you know
for a long time had a big Windows
footprint because they use Windows
workstations it happens it's pretty much
everywhere and everybody wants to use
those IDs that they're already familiar
with these same usernames passwords etc
and there's been lots of ways that we've
been able to do this in the past some of
them are good some of them have been
kind of not so good and we feel that
this is well what we're going to go over
is probably two of the best methods to
do this and really the way to choose
between the two is strictly based on the
size of your environment and how much
you expect it to grow so integrating
with Active Directory allows us to again
focus on managing one set of identities
instead of managing users for both
Windows and Linux the cost savings we
talked about you know that's just
because we're freeing up our time and
resources there's less passwords to
remember which means less password
resets for everybody that does helpdesk
and easier auditing because we got one
place to go see who logged in where when
and it allows us to use those users that
we already have so our two methods of
integration are direct and indirect a
direct integration means that we're
directly connecting our Linux system to
Active Directory so for anything that
has SSST so talking rail we're talking
CentOS Fedora Ubuntu we can directly
connect that
to Active Directory by using SSSs D for
rel variants we have this thing called
realm D it's a wrapper that basically
assists with the setup and configuration
of SSS D so that it really streamlines
the process of connecting to Active
Directory the indirect integration is
where we start talking about using
Identity Management or IBM as a
middleman between our Linux clients and
Active Directory so why one or the other
the direct integration is a lot simpler
if you just have a couple systems
you just go out set up some config files
you're done but it's hard to scale if
you got a large environment it's kind of
painful to go out and deploy a config
file everywhere and hope that there's no
variants and things and it's just it
becomes a nightmare to manage there
there's certainly some tools that help
with that but we're setting things up
this way you're more or less doing a
trust between each individual system and
Active Directory and performance there's
performance hits and just trying to
manage it doesn't really work out well
at large scale so that's where while we
want to go with indirect if we have a
large environment or even if you just
want to have some extra tools like
managing your Sudhir always all in one
place so for this for more complex
setups or large environments that's why
we want to use indirect you know if
managing pseudo policies and host based
access control rules are important then
we probably wanna go with indirect even
if we have a small environment so s SSD
integration again this directly connects
us to Active Directory each individual
system all the users live in Active
Directory which is to be expected at
this point and we can do some host based
access control with group policy it it's
not great but it it's there
it takes some customization to make it
happen but it can be done
there's no additional hardware software
to maintain so you're not building any
additional infrastructure when you're
doing this so that's why it's a little
bit simpler and again it's a simple
solution for small offices all you need
is your users to be available to log
into those systems this is probably the
easiest thing to do and for anybody
who's interested in smart card
authentication you can support smart
cards on this with rel 7-3 or newer and
the best part about all of it it's all
free open source software so it's stuff
that's already there with the OS stuff
that's upstream downstream everywhere
you don't have to even buy Red Hat
Enterprise Linux you can use Cintas
fedora or whatever it's there the
requirements you have to have knowledge
of the Active Directory environment
obviously if you're going to connect to
it you have to know how to connect to it
you have to know what server to point to
you have to have domain administrator
privilege that way you can join to the
direct Active Directory domain and one
big caveat if if you're using ntlm then
this isn't going to work ntlm is you
know been dead for a while but some
places it still is in use if that is a
requirement there are other ways like
win bind that will work for that but SSD
does not support ntlm so realm D or from
D join again this is a wrapper that we
use to set up s SSD it will also set up
win bond so in those edge cases where we
have to work around ntlm and yes so this
allows this is the wrapper script that
allows us to easily set up the direct
integration using either of those
clients and what it does is it helps
discover the identity domains and helps
configure the the client software
instead of you having to go out and
manually edit the configuration files
yourself alright so into the indirect or
cross for
so the trust is all based on Kerberos
Kerberos allows us to have that single
sign-on and basically when we
authenticate we get a Kerberos ticket
that says hey this person is who they
say they are and they have access to
things and then that ticket what we're
doing is trusting where that ticket
originated from so that it will also be
valid and accepted on our systems and
this is not restricted to trusting a
single ad Forest and we'll talk about
transitive trust here in just a minute
there's two main components to doing
this trust we have what's called a trust
agent and a trust controller an eidm
server any IDM server can be a trust
controller or word trust agent and we
have to have at least one trust
controller to talk to Active Directory
and the reason for this is the trust
controller is able to resolve the users
and groups it's able to enroll clients
but also it's able to manage the trust
so it's able to set up that initial
agreement and keep that agreement valid
whereas the trust agent while it can do
the user to see the users and groups and
can register systems it doesn't actually
have the ability to manage the trust so
in a small deployment you don't have to
have any trust agents because the trust
controller is a trust agent but in a
large environment you don't have to have
every single system that every single
eidm system be a trust controller you
can have a bunch of trust agents in just
a couple controllers managing your trust
so the requirements for setting up a
cross force trust we have two one a very
important thing is because we're staying
up a new domain we have to have a
completely separate domain so for
example we'll say we already have an
existing ad dot example com what we
would want to do on the Linux side is
set up something like IPA example.com or
Linux dot example comm the reason for
this is because we have those DNS
records for Kerberos that are not
necessarily like a records but they're
records that just blatantly go out and
look for what Kerberos servers will have
what LDAP servers who have and their
records that
are probably already populated well will
be already populated on your network if
you're using Active Directory because
they have to be there for Active
Directory to work so if you were on the
same network and your Linux system is
trying to reach out and find a Kerberos
KDC or a LDAP server it's going to get
confused because it doesn't know which
system to go to so we split it out on a
separate domain that's no longer a
problem we have to get firewall ports
open so if there's a firewall segmenting
these networks you know we have to take
care of that we also have to take care
of the host-based firewalls making sure
that things are able to get in and out
ok we have to have a good NTP source so
ideally we won't have a stratum 1 source
but you know any any source you know
nist or any other ntp source will work
and everything has to have different
NetBIOS names so it's pretty simple we
have a central one-way trust which means
we're going to trust the domain a will
will assume domain B is our IDM server
domain a is our Active Directory server
we're going to set up a trust where we
trust domain a which allows users from
domain a to be able to authenticate on
systems in domain B in our a DM
environment similarly a transitive trust
allows us to say if we're over here
domain C is our i DM environment and
we've set up a trust with domain B well
users in domain a or B will be able to
authenticate on domain C by transitive
property of you know having a trust
between a and B already in place now
there is some filtering there that we
can set up if we don't want to have
access or don't want users from domain a
to have access we can do filtering but
if those trusts exist we'll be able to
see those users and make use of them if
we choose to
so the different designs we have here a
basic server topology you know this is
very simple to what we just talked about
with domain a domain a and domain
be where the 80 users can authenticate
on IBM because of this trust and then
also if we have users to find in IBM of
course those users can be used on our
Linux resources just another drawing
kind of expanding this out a little bit
more we got our Windows users typically
coming in from a Windows desktop or
laptop so they're authenticating here
they get their Kerberos ticket and then
they use whatever SSH client of their
choice that supports Kerberos and then
they're able to single sign-on to the
IDM systems over here and that's all
done because of the trust that's exists
between our IDM servers and Active
Directory say hey we trust your Kerberos
tickets and we allow access to you also
whenever the Kerberos ticket comes in it
will read from the IDM servers whatever
hosts based access control rules are in
place so while the user may be valid and
have a valid Kerberos ticket we may have
a policy in place that says this user
doesn't have access to this system and
we're able to kick them out at that
point
all right so again we want to make sure
everything's unique primary domains we
need to make sure that the necessary DNS
records are added so if we're using some
third-party DNS instead of the internal
DNS we have to make sure we have some
specific rules in play or specific
records in place we have to run the ad
trust set up on the first IBM server
just make sure that the trust is
established and after that we can just
set up trust agents from there forward
and we need to there's some stuff we
need to do on the ad side that will
requires to be 80 admin in order to
complete the trust so now we get into
groups with groups from IDM were able to
see the groups that are in Active
Directory but we can't do anything with
them because there are things that are
read-only we can't do any make any
changes to them so we have to do is we
have to create a group that we want to
be able to manage an IDM and then
reference that Active Directory group so
you're basically map
it mapping something that you can see
and you can see what the members are of
it to something that you can actually
modify and control and this is useful
because like I said for our host based
access control and our pseudo policies
we have to have groups that we can
assign policy to to say that you know
group a can get to server group B but
not server group D so we have the
external ideas are the ones that were
able to see from Active Directory but we
can't really do much with and then we
have our internal POSIX groups so these
are the groups that we create in IDM and
then we build the references from those
POSIX groups to the Active Directory
groups so a quick walkthrough will go
over the architecture here real quick
again the separate domains
I can't harp on this enough if you try
and do this install and it's on the same
domain you will have problems and
possibly break what you already have in
place we utilize the microsoft
privileged access privilege accounting
certificate this contains the CID or the
security identifiers and sss d and ID
and we're involved to help associate
users and groups and permissions for the
policies and getting all those mapped
groups taken care of
alright so do the authentication
walkthrough now
so we have our user that's come in from
their Windows laptop they already have a
valid caruso ticket they log into the
IDM client and that sends out a request
to the trust agent which goes over to
the trust or the domain 80 domain
controller
where we verify the ticket the Kerberos
ticket comes back down through checks
for host based access control rules to
do policies whatever they're trying to
do make sure everything's valid and then
the authentication is successful it's
pretty simple looking at it from this
level can definitely get a lot more in
the weeds whenever you're actually
on the keyboard working with Kerberos
and trying to diagnose why something did
or didn't work so some different
deployment scenarios well we'll go over
some planning first again our
considerations are going to be our size
of the deployment how much we expect it
to grow any kind of any kind of
compliance policies we have so FIPS is a
big one especially for federal customers
and IDM does support FIPS mode we just
have to make sure we do that upfront
because if we want to enable it later we
have to rebuild cost is another big one
you know there's a lot of technologies
out there to help bridge this gap but
they cost a lot of money these solutions
cost nothing if you have rail or you
have CentOS already in your shop you've
got what you need the number of staff an
organizational structure plays a big
factor in this if you got a lot of
people sitting around doing nothing well
maybe doing everything individual
systems is okay but if you don't have a
lot of people you need to streamline
things make it really efficient so for
some of our general case studies here
client number one their information is
that they have a large ad environment
like we've talked about you know they
pray have a lot of Linux or a lot of
Windows desktops laptops and they've got
a small rail footprint that they're
expecting to grow so they've just
started dabbling in Linux they haven't
really you know jumped all in but they
expect to have a lot more growth over
the next few years you got a small team
of Linux administrators in a small
budget and they require a solution as
soon as possible so what do you think
the best solution is here what what we
think would be the best solution here
because of the size of the environment
and the time that they need it and the
level of expertise in-house we would use
direct integration because we're able to
just take the small amount of systems
they have and direct directly connect
them to Active Directory instead of
having to bring any new tools in the
environment that are ad
is that our already probably overworked
don't have time to learn client to has a
large ad footprint again they already
have a lot of rail machines they're
planning to or they only have the one
domain some recommendations for them we
do the cross force trust but we have to
create a new domain for IBM and there's
some other things we can do here where
we can migrate some of the systems over
time as they start doing some rip and
rebuild of putting newer systems in we
can migrate those over to the new domain
to get all of the features but you know
do the size of the environment and the
fact that they're still growing an IBM
solution with the trust would be more
appropriate here so things that consider
after we do the installation there's
some configurator or some customizations
we can do at the client level such as
the default domain suffix out of the box
whenever you set up this trust you won't
be able to just type in your username
and password you have to type in your
username with an app and then the domain
of the domain you're trying to log into
so your username at your Windows domain
but if you're only using users from
Active Directory we can simplify that we
set this default domain suffix and then
it assumes that if you just give a short
username that it's from that domain we
also have offline credential expiration
so if you have systems are always
connected and you want them if they go
offline because somebody has stolen it
from the building or something if you
want to make sure that they can't log
into it with any cached credentials
you'd want to set this to where
everything is always expired now for a
laptop or something somebody may take
home you may want to cache their
credentials so they can log in when they
get home when they're off the network
can also over at the home directory I
mentioned earlier we can do auto mount
rules so here we can set the home
directory to an alternate location
instead of the default location so that
we can have it set up to an auto mount
some of the post setup verification that
we can do we can do a IPA trust show
what this is going to do is just list
out a bunch of information about the
trust the status of it when it was
configured etc we can test the Kerberos
authentication so with this what we
would do is just do a que in it and then
space the username at the domain this
will generate a Kerberos ticket if it's
successful and you can look at that
by doing a que list and you'll see
something similar to this this is your
ticket granting ticket that you get
whenever you'll whenever you do the K in
it if you don't get this then that means
there's something not right with
Kerberos but if it is successful what
you'll see when you do the K in it
you'll get prompted for a password and
you immediately drop back to the prompt
if it's unsuccessful then it complains
and says you have issues you can then
test login to a client so SSH from one
system to another make sure everything
works but keep in mind when you're doing
this we have to also consider our host
based access control rules and make sure
the toes are set up correctly and then
obviously if we already have a Kerberos
ticket because we did a K in it we can
then test
SSO or single sign-on by SSA Qing to the
next system note to do this though you
have to use the fully qualified domain
of the system you're planning to go to
otherwise it doesn't resolve the the
hostname correctly for the Kerberos
authentication so troubleshooting where
do we go when things break is inevitably
it happens we have logs on client 4's
SSD also we logged some of these errors
in var log secure so if you have failed
authentications var log secure is a good
place to look we can increase the
logging level for SSD by modifying the
debug underscore level in s SSD kampf
SCS SSD SSD kampf
we can
attempt using using debug or a trace for
the k8 command and this what this will
do is it'll give trace level at the
command line so directly and your
standard out and there's also Kerberos
logs in VAR log K RB v KD C dot log on
the server side we can enable debug with
debug equal true in SCIP a default comp
of course this is going to really kick
up your log level on a lot of things so
I wouldn't recommend leaving that on
very long and we have our directory
server logs at var log derserve slap D
the name of the realm and then the
errors log so some common issues that
we've ran into dns resolution dns
resolution is huge is hugely critical
for this to work you know if we don't
have dns then your client system is not
going to be able to communicate with our
domain controller so you're not gonna be
able to see the users you're not gonna
be able to get any kind of Kerberos
ticket if it's even a record that you
have records for the ITM servers so we
can go out and see the users but you
don't have Eckerd in there for the
client then Kerberos isn't going to work
because it can't grant a ticket because
it doesn't know who the client is so we
want to ensure that all systems have
properly configured host files and
resolved comm files our host files of
course are going to you know be mainly
just so we have localhost references not
really so that we use that in place of
dns and it resolved companies to point
to one or multiple of our IDM servers
just to make sure that we have some
resilience there if we have one to go
down for maintenance or or an issue we
want to test the resolution at CLI if we
have issues using tools like in a dig or
nslookup or even the host command you
know any of these tools that are
designed to query DNS and make sure our
rules are in place or our records are in
place
another common issue is time sink time
being skewed only by a few minutes will
break Kerberos because it wants things
to be all in the same place at the same
time and if time is skewed then it
assumes that there's something not right
in the world and refuses to authenticate
you
so Tom sink is very critical that's why
we include NTP as part of IDM so we
typically setup NTP with ntpd or on real
7 variants fedora
we have Khurana we can verify the time
is in sync with the date command fairly
simple just run date on two different
systems if there's a variance of more
than a few seconds and you probably have
a problem you need to go out and make
sure karani or ntpd is running another
common issue is who's based access
access control rules or h-back it's not
that the hvac itself is a problem but
sometimes we don't get the rules right
so what we can do there is a test
utility that works both from the UI and
from the command line in IBM that allows
us to go in and define our host based
access control rules and then we can go
to this utility select a user select
what system they're trying to login to
what they're trying to do so if they're
trying to use sudo or trying to do if
we're just trying to log into the via
SSH or they're trying to log in via
gnome we can select what we want to do
there and then we select the policy or
we can select all active policies and
hit test and it will give us a pass/fail
and that lets you know if your rule is
defined correctly because you can see if
if the rule passed so you know the if
you were intended to give someone access
to something you can make sure that it
successfully did that or if you're
trying to remove access from somebody
somewhere then you can make sure it has
done that correctly and if that test
passes then you know you have an issue
maybe more with Kerberos or something on
the client level and not at the server
level so these can get a little tricky
to set up but we have a utility there to
help define those rules
finally some smart card integration not
sure help me people in here really are
too interested about this we're just
going to breeze over it real quick smart
card integration we can do it with
direct integration with 7/3 and newer so
rel 7/3 are newer Cintas 7/3 and newer
I'm not sure about version specifically
of fedora that would hit but yeah so in
direct integration which is where we're
using idea more free IPA and in the
middle and setting up the trust our
clients can be rel six eight or newer or
seven to inure and this is just because
with IBM being in the middle it kind of
changes the way we do things a little
bit we're able to do things a little bit
different way so we can support some
older clients with rel 74 and newer
we're able to do certificate mapping
which if anybody in here has done
anything with smart cards and Active
Directory this is how you typically do
smart card on Windows workstations or
Windows Active Directory you're not
actually putting the certificate in
Active Directory you're matching a email
address or some identifier on the cert
and you verify that whenever the card is
inserted in a client we can do the same
thing with rail starting in 7 4 and
newer the one thing to note here is that
so this keeps us from having to upload
the certs but this only works whenever
we're doing GUI based authentication ssh
itself doesn't support x.509
certificates so we have to do things a
little bit different for ssh but if
you're using wind or if you're using
linux desktops or workstations laptops
whatever if you're using gnome you can
make use of this certificate mapping to
avoid having to upload a cert for every
single user back to the SSH access SSH
daemon does not support x.509
certificates this is something that's
been requested
to the ssh community several times but
they are very apprehensive to implement
it because it obviously opens them up to
a lot more threat by integrating SSL
Certificates into their authentication
so what we do here instead is we utilize
Kerberos SSO with gssapi so we're using
that SSO that Kerberos provides to get
from one system to the next so on our
windows workstations if we're talking if
we're talking smart card with an
indirect integration what we typically
see is user comes in they log in to
their windows computer they get a
Kerberos ticket when they log in then we
use an ssh client that allows gssapi and
you're able to use that Kerberos ticket
to then get into whatever Linux resource
you need so for that secondary access
you have used the same credentials that
you the same credential that you use to
log in to the Windows workstation and
thus everything has been controlled by
the smart card we can also if we don't
have the ability to do Kerberos system
so we can actually dump the entire
certificate into IDM but that's very
painful to manage but it is possible if
we have to do it that way so some
resources and information we have a
windows integration guide it's part of
the rail Doc's we also have a blog
specifically aimed at Rehan apprise
Linux one of our well we have several
people that contribute to the IDM stuff
but we can use you can use the tag IDM
and that will bring up most of the
articles that are related specifically
to add any management or Active
Directory integrations and then of
course if you need some help with any of
this you can have somebody like myself
come out and help you with Red Hat
consulting services and with that I
thank you and enjoy lunch
[Applause]
see what