okay i'm going to show you how to create
a ticket on the diana initiative server
if you can see all the attendees
channels click on submit a ticket
and pick the type of ticket you need to
submit
go ahead and click it
and then you can type your information
in here
uh let's see
let's miss that
here we go
general support
uh this
is a test in this case you probably want
to give them information about uh what
it is you're having problems with if you
do a roll request if you're looking for
a speaker role or something
or if it's code of conduct violation say
who and what channel
and maybe include a screenshot if
possible hopefully that helps thanks