hi everyone this is nicole and i am
doing a little video about how
we at diana initiative are going to do
our hybrid or apologies our virtual
speakers
this year
so we'll give you a stream yard link
which when you click it it'll say
processing and then it will ask you for
what your display name is make sure you
put in what you want the audience to see
this doesn't need to be your legal name
or whatever it could be your handle
whatever you're known as and you want
the audience to be able to see
you can see that it shows up here
you can see right here that it says my
mic is working
and we can see me here you could mute
but because you enter into a queue
that is not necessary
so what's going to happen is first
you're going to join a green room just
so you can test out your mic
sharing and everything else like that
then 10 minutes uh before your talk
you're gonna join where the prior
speaker is finishing again you enter
into a queue so that's not a big deal
so make sure this is all working
and you should have verified your
settings uh using the green room so now
i joined the link for the actual
live stream and i'm going to say enter
studio
now that i've entered studio it tells me
that i'm backstage
so the prior speaker just finished
and they are going to
go away because they don't have q and
a's
they've got the advertisements up there
those would be for all of the sponsors
at this point i need to get ready so i'm
going to share
i can do it two ways i can share my
slides
or
i can share my screen
in either case
i recommend making sure that you can see
the private chat
and this is so that you can comments are
public so you don't want to comment in
comments that goes out to the youtube
channel you want to comment in private
chat to say that you're ready
to
start your talk whenever they are you
can see i've got my speaker notes up
here so i'm ready to go
it's important to if you can have two
screens so that you're able to see your
speaker notes your private chat
everything because i'm down here this is
the cue
so when i'm in the queue
no one can see or hear me even though
i'm talking and my mic is working so
don't worry about muting your mic or
your video because i'm in the queue i'm
not live yet
so i've got everything ready so i'm just
going to say i am ready
and the mc should come on to introduce
me
thanks
there we go i've got my slides so this
one is the shared slide deck
which means that here at the bottom i
can progress the slides
by clicking these
um
and so that makes it pretty easy but
again can't see the speaker notes in
here so i've got my speaker and it's off
here on the other half of my screen i
happen to have
a big screen
so i could go through give my
presentation i might see
questions come through in private chat
or i might see my speaker wrangler
saying hey you've only got five minutes
left
um you know that kind of communication
so try and keep an eye on it
and then when i'm done oh no 10 minutes
left quick go faster so go faster
uh
now
jamie can you switch me to the screen
share
out of the other one so i can show how
that
progresses there we go so with this one
it's sharing my entire screen which is
what i told it to do so i go make sure
this is full screen mode
and it appears here on my screen so your
keynote or whatever you can just get it
to progress
and again you can see that i've got my
speaker slides going over here
so this one may be easier for you
if you're not having two presenters
share one slide deck
um just because these things will keep
in sync and progress
together
uh so okay i got 10 minutes left i got
to the end i've worked out ahead of time
with my speaker wrangler that they're
going to pass me on any questions so at
this point i'll say
hey
do i have any questions from the
audience and the speaker wrangler should
catch any of those questions i have a
lot of slides sorry
we'll get to the end uh so i get my
first question
and i'm like okay
the question is we recommend you repeat
the question out loud for the sake of
the recording
as well as for anyone who maybe is not
in the discord who might just be
watching the live stream so the question
is you know what is sas well sas stands
for static application security testing
and you use it for x blah blah blah you
know whatever whatever it is you need to
say
uh and then
you may stop getting questions there may
be more questions for you but you may
stop getting them because your time is
up so when your time is up
um your you can either just close this
tab in stream yards all you need to do
you don't need to like exit log out
anything you just close the tab boom
you're gone no problem
uh or
you
can get removed from stream if you're
going over
you might just get taken away
so
hopefully this is helpful please let us
know if you have any questions and see
everyone soon