welcome back everyone you've made it all
the way through the day and we're on our
last talk
so while the villages are winding down
you can still stop by the networking
channel and drop in your linkedin and
twitter to keep in touch with folks
and also pet pics is still full of
adorable pet pics so definitely stop by
there
we also want to remind you to stay tuned
after this talk in about 30 minutes uh
we'll be kicking off the closing
ceremony so make sure to stick around
for that as well
um and with that i'm gonna
introduce elaine harrison newkirk uh she
works for scythe her talk is titled
kicking imposter syndrome to the curb
which i'm sure a lot of us can relate to
um so this talk is pre-recorded but lane
is actually in discord and will be
answering questions so hop into the qa
channel and drop your comments and
questions there thanks so much and
thanks again to all of our sponsors as
well
my name is elaine harrison newkirk and
i'm here today to talk to you about
kicking imposter syndrome to the curb
this talk is about my experience how i
discovered i had imposter syndrome and
the steps i've taken to kick it to the
curb
so first a little about me
i lead the customer support program at
an amazing stump startup company known
as scythe i'm also a technical writer
for scythe
i'm the mom of three awesome young women
and a bearded dragon named taco
he's also my office mate he's pretty
chill he comes to company meetings the
only thing we don't really like is when
he decides to eat his life or lunch on
my desk
i started out as a hotel manager and
then i pivoted into it as a pc
technician
i've worked my way up through my career
and i've been in cyber security for over
10 years now
i'm also volunteer director of education
for cyber security nonprofit
i'd like to thank the diana initiative
for having me here today and also i'd
like to thank ellen fair enough for
mentoring me and helping me with my
proposal for this talk he was super
awesome and helped me a lot
so i have a couple of things for you to
think about
do you know what imposter syndrome is
and what does imposter syndrome mean to
you if you do know what it is
merriam-webster's definition of imposter
syndrome is a psychological condition
that is characterized by persistent
doubt concerning one's abilities or
accomplishments accompanied by the fear
of being exposed as a fraud despite
evidence of one's ongoing success
so for me i don't particularly like this
definition i feel like a fraud is
someone who's purposely trying to
deceive other people or be deceptive and
i don't think anyone who suffers from
imposter syndrome is doing that we're
not out there intentionally deceiving
people
um i for me imposter syndrome is just
constant self-doubt
lack of self-confidence
anxiety and worrying about how other
people see me
i found this meme in a blog about
imposter syndrome and the link is in the
slides
and um i thought this was a great one
for me because i do beat myself up for
all of these things
i
constantly stay up at night worrying
and getting really anxious about stuff
that's out of my control stuff everyone
else has literally forgotten about like
maybe a conversation i had with somebody
and i lay in bed wondering
did i offend them do they not like me
did i say something wrong did they get
mad afterwards but honestly it was
probably a four-minute conversation
about what we were going to have for
lunch and they are not even thinking
about that now they're sound asleep
and then stuff that nobody else has even
noticed
so as i said in my uh perception of
imposter syndrome i feel like self-doubt
plays a huge part
um
i'm sure if you do suffer you have sat
in team meetings and had these thoughts
you know um you may not want to speak up
during the meeting because you feel like
you don't know as much as your teammates
do or you don't want them to think
you're incompetent you don't want to say
the wrong thing and say it sounds stupid
um also you may just feel like
constantly like no matter how hard you
work you're not going to be able to
prove that you're as good as everyone
else that you work with
so think about this what self-doubt
doubt thoughts do you have during
meetings in your personal life
during activities with other groups
maybe groups of parents or um
people in some community in your
community or a community you volunteer
with
how do you um
you know beat yourself up with these
self-doubt thoughts
and how do we keep it from happening
that's something else that you should
think about how do you keep those
self-doubt thoughts at bay
so asanas block turn imposter syndrome
into confidence between tips for
managers and individuals
lists
uh
characteristics of imposter syndrome
sorry i have to move my head out of the
way
and um
so these are this is just a short list
there's actually
i'm sure a lot of other characteristics
and i'm sure if you put pen to paper or
finger to keyboard you could come up
with a list yourself
but i've thought that these
particular characteristics definitely
applied to me and my imposter syndrome
um i used to always feel that my skills
or confidence were lacking i always felt
like um
i wasn't going to do something right
because i didn't have
this
the stellar skills to do it
um if i
worked on a project and completed it and
i got kudos for that i would kind of
just shrug it up and be like oh yeah
thanks you know
um it was just luck and googling
um just constantly worrying that you're
not good enough or
if you work remote particularly you may
find yourself isolating yourself from
team members
i still do that at times where i just
kind of pull back and don't communicate
with anyone
um
perfectionism a lot of us who suffer
from
impostor syndrome definitely work toward
perfectionism which is really just a
waste of time in in my opinion i've come
to realize for example
i um when i record talks i record them
10 or 15 times trying to get them
perfect
and now i realize no matter how many
times i record them
i'm gonna make mistakes if i was doing a
live talk i would make mistakes
um overwork and burnout that's something
that we also suffer from right we're
trying to prove ourselves so we're
working
probably more hours than we need to
we're putting in extra time
and that's going to cause you to burn
out and you know what most people are
not going to notice that you work 60
hours in a week on a particular project
or tasks it's just going to be you who
notices and then you're going to be
really tired and the next week is not
going to be great because you're just
burnt and done with it
setting impossibly high standards for
yourself
i don't know if it comes with age or the
fact that i i'm working toward getting
rid of imposter syndrome but i have
definitely lowered the bar for standards
for myself i do not try to be perfect i
don't try to get perfect scores on tests
anymore
you know i'm just happy if i pass them
now
low self-esteem intense fear failure and
decreased self-confidence these are
definitely all characteristics that
ruled my life for a really long time
so what other characteristics would you
add to the list something else that you
should think about
there are actions by other people
that feed your imposter syndrome um so
these are actions by other people that
have come into my life and have fed my
impostor syndrome
being blown off
uh
giving input during meetings and people
just ignore me or they constantly
interrupt me when i speak and step on my
words or move on to other topics and
they don't hear me
authority figures teammates family
members teachers all people who may put
you down either intentionally or
unintentionally
that certainly feeds imposter syndrome
and then also these same people um
comparing you to someone who's better
maybe you're getting you're in high
school and you're being compared to
better students who get better grades
um not better but you know students who
get better grades than you but you might
be really skilled in other areas it may
not be your thing for example i was not
great in algebra
and it
it still isn't my thing i think
i just have a terrible fear of algebra
but being compared to students who are
amazing in algebra didn't help with my
impostor syndrome
what feeds your imposter syndrome what
actions do other people take that feeds
your imposter syndrome and makes it
harder for you to work towards moving
away from it
i did some research and i tried to find
studies on impostor syndrome
um there's really not a lot out there i
think
there probably will be more as
you know time progresses and more people
know about imposter syndrome
i was able to find a few studies most of
them targeted women
i will say that men certainly suffer
from imposter syndrome as as well but
maybe it's not as out there in the open
or maybe they're just aren't as many who
do
so in my research i found that women of
color are highest rate kenan studies
followed by trans women and women who
work in male dominated industries such
as manufacturing health care and
information technology or information
security
the kpmg study which is linked in this
slide
noted that 75 of women executives have
experienced impastor syndrome at some
point in their careers
um 85 percent have not talked about it
because they don't want to be seen as
weak
and less than five percent of employers
have actually addressed impostor
syndrome with their staff
so now i want to talk about how i
learned about imposter syndrome and what
it was i actually did not know what this
term was until two years ago
a little over two years ago when the
pandemic started i was in lockdown
i decided i was gonna turn a bad thing
into something good and i started
signing up for different webinars and um
tried to really bump up my virtual
networking
so i watched an imposter syndrome
perspective excuse me i watched a
webinar on imposter syndrome
perspectives for black women in tech and
this was sponsored by women in cyber
security
it's a really awesome webinar and that
is also linked in this slide
for you to watch
um
so as i watch this i was like
holy moly i have imposter syndrome now i
know what it is now i have a name for my
intense self-doubt and lack of
self-confidence like i felt like a door
had opened
and i like
knew
how i had been feeling all these years
was actually
something legit
my experience with imposter syndrome
syndrome started as a child it followed
me into high school and then into my
professional life in i.t and cyber
security
mine started out as a child i had a
family member who constantly told me i
wasn't good enough
um this person would either
actually say the words or you know play
a lot of mind games to make me feel like
i was less than i was or less worthy
than i was
i would do the dishes and that person
would make me do them over again until i
did them exactly how he wanted them
just a lot of
coming down on me that did not help me
as a child feel confident in what i
could do or what i knew
um in high school i was a pretty decent
student but i was horrible in gym class
i was not an athlete i was the kid that
hung up the second knot up the rope and
was like hey i can't do this
i just simply wasn't physically strong
enough to climb a rope
but our gym teachers were not looking at
that they they were looking at the fact
that i could not climb the rope and they
made me feel really bad about myself
because i couldn't
um honestly i've never had to climb a
rope in my life
and i think
i'm sure there's a lot of other people
that i was in gym class with who also
have not had to
i did join a couple of sports teams i
joined soccer and i joined basketball
i ended up benched because i was not
athletic and i wasn't good at it i
really didn't know what i was doing and
the coaches didn't want to waste the
time on me when they had star athletes
that they could focus on
so that definitely did not help with my
self-worth or my
self-confidence
i basically spent my last two years in
high school sitting in the computer room
typing away on my little commodore 64
because that's where i was most
comfortable and i knew i was really good
at it
as i moved into i-team
um my
life of being dismissed by male managers
and male executives began
i had so many examples of times when
these people
who
have been in working in corporate for a
really long time
just
walked right by me ignored what i had to
say they i had one person walk by me and
tell my female manager that he needed me
to do something rather than just coming
to me and telling me
that really upset me and obviously it
has stuck with me
um i have had multiple times where i was
interrupted in meetings or had my words
stepped on by other male managers
recommendations were ignored until my
male counterparts agreed with my
recommendations and then they would get
picked up
i have spoken to managers in the past
and told them how i felt about how they
were treating me and they promised to
improve but they didn't
i had someone actually tell me i was
constantly seeking recognition and i was
jealous of my co-workers which was
absolutely not true i was just trying to
um get some of the issues i had worked
out with this person
and um have him not treat me the way he
had been treating me
i've also had female managers who didn't
stand up for me which really did not
help at all and only fed my impostor
syndrome
now if you want to take a minute and
think about times that maybe you've had
interactions like this and
did that also feed your impostor
syndrome i would assume that it did
because it certainly isn't none of these
were positive interactions
so can we uh recover from impostor
syndrome is this something that we
recover from or will imposter syndrome
always lurk in the background is that
always going to be that little ugly
troll sitting in the woods waiting to
jump up on your shoulder
and whisper in your ear and bring you
down
i don't know i'm trying to recover from
it i'm definitely not fully recovered i
still have days where that troll is
clutching to my shoulder and whispering
in my ear
but these are the steps that i've been
taking over the past year and a half
so to start with i left a toxic work
environment i
finally had kind of had enough of not
being listened to or
um
feeling like i just didn't know what i
was doing
so i found this job at site
and it's been really amazing all of our
management and executives support us
they encourage us to get out there and
do things that we normally wouldn't do
when i first started working at scythe
my male teammates
and my male managers definitely pushed
me to
learn to get out there to speak up i
never i've never been in a meeting where
anybody ignored what i had to say
and they make me feel like i know what
i'm doing and that i am worth
being in cyber security
um i've also at the beginning of the
pandemic found noreen george's mentor
mentee women in cyber security group
we meet
monthly
and it's a group of professional cyber
security professionals
students people just starting in cyber
um we we just get together and we talk
about what we're doing and and if we
need help from someone um or if we need
a mentor or if we're looking to mentor
people
and it's really a fantastic supportive
network i actually did my first talk in
noreen's group because it was a smaller
group with people that i had been with
virtually for quite a while and i was
super comfortable
and it helped really boost my
self-confidence and
made me realize that i can do talks
helping noaa authors overcome imposter
syndrome gives me a lot of confidence
for example me doing these talks on
impostor syndrome i really hope that i'm
making a difference in some of your
lives and that
if you don't suffer from imposter
syndrome maybe i'm helping give you
tools to help other people recover
and learning new things
that's something that i have been doing
since i started this job at site
i do not come from a software background
i was a
blue teamer a security analyst so
working in software development world is
a whole new thing there's a lot i need
to learn but i'm learning it and as i
learn and as i practice i get a lot
better at it
and um
i think that that's really helped boost
my confidence and push that self-doubt
aside as well
so i do still have times where i have
doubts and i doubt my abilities and i
doubt my knowledge
that little troll is just up there like
and you know what i just flick them away
and i'm like look
i can do this i am capable i'm
knowledgeable and i'm awesome
um
and also i need to remind myself that
i'm not going to know everything and all
of the cyber security domains it's i
don't think anybody can there's so much
information out there in cyber
but we each have our own little niche of
expertise
so
i'm going to kick imposter syndrome to
the curb i'm going to get rid of that
little troll
and this is how you can do it too you
need to know your worth know that you're
amazing and worthy and knowledgeable and
you know your stuff that you may be an
expert in
blue teaming or red teaming or purple
teaming
and maybe you're you
lack
knowledge in other areas you know but
if you have a supportive network and you
surround yourself with people who
support you and have knowledge in other
areas
then you can reach out to them and get
help and learn more
if you work in a unsupportive culture or
have unsupportive managers maybe it's
time to make that change maybe it's time
to move on to a different job
and it's okay to fail
um you know what you don't we're not
always going to be successful nobody is
but don't beat yourself up if something
doesn't go the way you wanted it to or a
project you're working on is not going
right
there's no reason to beat yourself up
you're doing what you can you're trying
your best and
you can improve right if you
if you work on a project that doesn't go
as well as you wanted it to
think about the pieces that were lacking
or the gaps and then push yourself learn
what you need to learn um to make it
successful the next time around
don't let it get to you
and again like i said we don't know
everything we need to learn from people
who have expertise where we don't
the people i work with are amazing they
all uh are very knowledgeable in
different areas than i am and i have no
problem reaching out to someone and
asking them to either show me how to do
something because i'm a visual learner
or give me resources
or hook me up with someone else that
could help me if they don't have that
knowledge or if they are really busy and
don't have the time to help at that time
and all of my safe unicorns are
absolutely willing to do this
alyssa miller wrote in conquering
imposter syndrome
accept that it's okay not to know all
the answers and that if you did it would
mean you're not pushing yourself hard
enough have faith that it's not only
acceptable to reach out for help but
it's actually an effective tool
and i completely agree with her asking
for help is not a sign of weakness
asking for help means that you're
looking to improve yourself and learn
more it doesn't mean that you're not
good enough or you don't know enough it
just means you need a little extra boost
put yourself out there if you don't know
if you don't try you won't ever know if
i had never submitted papers to do these
talks i would never know that i was
going to be accepted i would never know
that people were going to
find my talks useful
and it really has helped build my
confidence
so just remember you've got this you
need to get out of your comfort zone
try new things um make a list set some
goals
move away from negativity get out away
from those toxic people in toxic
environments that you may be dealing
with
stand up for yourself if you are in
meetings and people are not listening to
you
or if you're out in a one-on-one and
your manager is reading his or her they
they're
sorry
emails
um
you know be like hey we're meeting here
eyes up here
i'm talking
don't let them just ignore you
and like i said before set goals
um
set some small goals at first think
about things that you want to do that
you've been really afraid to do
and try something try one little thing
and be yourself stop worrying about what
everybody else thinks it doesn't matter
you do you
so i'm going to give you a little bit of
homework
i want you to think about steps that you
can take for your recovery from impostor
syndrome
make a list of uh actions or items that
you want to try that are not in your
comfort zone excuse me your comfort zone
and set your goals try one thing
be successful try another it's
eventually you're gonna realize that you
have kicked that little troll to the
curb and you're doing great and you
don't worry about everyone else and what
they think about you anymore
i want to thank everyone for attending
my talk i really hope that i was able to
give you some tools to help you work
through this or help other people work
through this i hope you really enjoyed
the conference
and have a great weekend
all right thank you so much elaine for
closing us out with a great discussion
on imposter syndrome just kind of
something that's i think pretty much
everyone has and if you don't have it
there's next kcd meme for that probably
um
so in another a few minutes actually in
exactly five minutes we're going to be
rolling into closing ceremonies so i'll
take this opportunity to yet again thank
our sponsors thank volunteers and staff
and everyone for uh participating
um after closing ceremonies i believe
there will be some social uh games so
stick around the discord
uh and uh yet again thanks for
everything cheers