hello everybody
welcome to the diana initiative 2020
virtual event
um my name is jamie and i am a deputy
ceo um you will see nicole later on
today so that's who i am
um
we are um we'll be streaming here all
day um having all kinds of things
happening in our discord uh if you
haven't joined our discord yet please
check your eventbrite ticket
that will have the instructions and the
link of how to join our discord server
for those of you who are watching on
twitch or youtube we are not actually
watching those comments over there so
come on over to our discord uh that's
where we're at today we're interacting
with everyone over there we have
all kinds of channels set up for our
discord server um we've got channels for
our villages which is like the ctf the
career village makers village iot
village lockpick village
all of our sponsors we have a networking
section
we have
pet pictures for everyone who wants to
drop their pet pictures in please do
because that's a fun time for everyone
um we also have um our general chat
which is kind of like our hallway con so
come meet people learn things just have
a good day
so who are we like our mission here at
tdi
um is to create a more inclusive
information security industry
it's
what we live and what we're here for and
to do
so who are we well the diane initiative
is a diversity-driven conference
committed to helping all
underrepresented underrepresented people
in information security we are a
non-profit 100
volunteer organized and run conference
we exist because we are a community
event supported by the community
we all have day jobs
the same day jobs that you all have we
have security engineers sock analysts
code builders blue team red team purple
team you name it we probably have
someone on our side volunteering that
does that job as well so we encourage
you to be kind as it has been yet
another year that has been rough for all
of us uh so please bear with us if
things are not as smooth as they would
like to go
as i push buttons that i shouldn't so
here we are um so we actually have two
events this year
um
we have a virtual event which everyone
is attending here today so hello we also
have an event in las vegas at on august
10th and 11th uh the ticket that you
purchased to access our event today
counts as your ticket for that event as
well so both of them all in one thing
are covered so you don't have to buy
anything extra
so those of you who will join us in las
vegas we look forward to meeting you
with you chatting with you sharing
stories learning new things but for
those of you who don't want to travel to
las vegas because of well
everything that's going on in the world
right now
don't worry that that event in las vegas
is actually hybrid so what that really
means is that we will be streaming out
the talk tracks that for the speakers
that um want us to do that and give us
permission to but we will also have the
ctf live
for you to come and play so it's not
just us only
on premise kind of thing
though i do have our villages are only
on-premise those will be our maker
village our career village and lockpick
village
presently
this year our slogan is take the
initiative we hope that over the course
of the event each of you finds things
that
spark your interest your passion your
creativity you find new pathways
into and through your information
security as well as embolden you to take
the initiative to take that action and
make that step forward or take that
chance
um
i want to stress that the dye initiative
acknowledges everyone is a
multi-dimensional complex being
for those of you here security may be a
job it may be a hobby or it may be a
passion
but we encourage you to take the
initiative
but we don't want to limit you to only
just professional job aspect type things
like make friends here uh
go to networking find a new hobby get
some hands-on things uh learned in our
workshops in our labs you know find
something that interests you so that you
can take that next step
i want to thank our sponsors without
them we could not afford this event this
year making our in-person event in las
vegas a hybrid event
um
you know taking care of all of the
expenses
that happen to make this conference
happen um
see the sponsors over um on our discord
during your breaks they have channels
dedicated them you can go and possibly
chat with them
see about you know what they do what
they have do they have job offers you
know or job opening should i say and see
what they have to offer
so our diamond uh sponsors are microsoft
target department of homeland security
cyber security service our platinum
sponsors verizon amazon security jupiter
network mongodb
our gold sponsors uh remediant intel
security tines aws
toyota recorded future
our rainbow sponsors our thermo fisher
scientific information network
institute at carnegie mellon university
synack google datadog afs red siege
dropbox brooks automation
our silver sponsors are relatively
bishop fox
and our bronze sponsors are
castle security
re-security tenable g research security
innovation bridge crew mandiant security
risk advisors and scope security
all of their lovely logos are all over
this page if you are so wanting to see
what is associated with them instead of
me just rattling off names
we want to thank our
ctf sponsors so our ctf will be kicking
off here soon right after the
announcements here head on over to our
discord channel there is a discord room
specifically dedicated to our ctf um
come over see what's over there there
might be a few things kind of hidden in
amongst the chat over there for it who
knows what they may be doing over there
so come on over and check it out
we want to thank our career village
sponsors um head over to the career
village discord channel today they have
openings for resume reviews uh mock
interviews but get over there as soon as
you can to sign up because i know it's a
first come first serve so those slots
will fill up fast
they also have a panel talk coming up
today as well as an interview
um later on in the day so keep checking
back the schedule
and
check out the discord and you should be
able to like learn a few things maybe
pick up some things for that resume or
maybe a pick up a trip for interviews
we wanted to thank our iot
uh village sponsors
head on over to the discord channel we
have an iot uh workshop area um channel
for that and we will be able to learn
new things find all those
vulnerabilities see what you can do
come on over and check it out
we want to thank our makers village
sponsors um
head on over to the maker village of
course discord channel of course uh
learn new things play with all the
blinky things um
uh the makers village has workshops
throughout the entire day so check on
over on discord or on sketch to see what
workshops are being done when that
covers everything from learning how to
solder for the people who have never
done it before so don't be intimidated
if you've never made anything come on
over and see what kind of fun things we
can actually
make
so
that is
our entire list of our sponsors
um
and we want to welcome you and like i
said um you're don't forget that your
ticket covers both the in-person
event on the august 10th and 11th
all right and let's see if i can go
and make
a technical difficulties right so bear
with me here i gotta find the right
slide of what i'm actually gonna do here
um
so
as i have
got
sorry this is my first time so bear with
me as
i am flubbing and just running with it
so
we wanted to explain our cats this year
so we have our primary logo is three
cats we have a puma we have a
panther we have
a
tiger there
symbolizing us ready to take that
initiative getting on the prowl getting
because we've been kind of trapped for
the last couple of years i mean let's be
honest right we're all been kind of
stuffed in and trying to make sure you
know kind of keep in our little bubbles
but this year we're trying to come out
take that initiative seize
the moment really um
and
this year um our logo actually feed
because every year we ever have
um
our logo it features a mythical animal
um and it emboldens the spirit and
tagline of what our collective mood is
and
rick and recording obviously as i
mentioned previous events
um you know we like them the
the metaphors so we
had metaphors about metamorphosis
overcoming adversity and emerging just
stronger
in 2019 obviously our
logo was the rising phoenix it became a
main crest which actually
we consistently use behind our brand um
in 2020 we had an abstract butterfly uh
with a feminine and celebratory cultural
vibe in 2021 well as the pandemic kept
wearing on uh it's the asymmetry
asymmetrical
uh progression of oregon cranes um and
reflected a feeling of longing um
impertinence and and optimism
and this year as i said um it's time to
stop isolating and start acting taking
those moments like seizing that moment
um and this year it's also the year of
the tigers so it really really plays
into our
and like our theme uh we're coming out
again and it's time to take that
initiative
and help build a more inclusive infosec
industry um and the jungle cats
represent our diverse community
inspiring us to move forward take what's
ours
we are rare we are fearsome hunters we
are fiercely protective of one another
here in our community and we are
stronger together
so collectively we all can roar together
um
so that's kind of like the explanation
of why you're going to see cats not only
here but also in our
in-person event and that's why you see
cats kind of hidden here or there on all
the different different slides
um we have that hash and now if you are
out on
all the socials
and you see us posting here you know
everywhere help us out on our social
media hit that hashtag tdi2022
help with that we're on linkedin on
twitter on
youtube um
help out with all of
where you can hand promote those socials
spread the word because honestly we
can't create a community if we all kind
of isolate ourselves so help spread the
word help promote everyone
it's how we build the community and
that's that's why we exist we are for
the community by the community and
together we are stronger and will
support each other and help seize the
initiative create those opportunities
extend those hands lift
others up
now
if you guys want to go take a quick
break because i know depending on
whatever time zone you are actually in
uh it is either really super early in
the morning and i'm not sure if you're
awake don't worry i don't know if i'm
awake yet but it's okay so take a 10
minute break go grab snacks coffee food
maybe lunch depending on wherever you
happen to be at this time
we'll come back in about 10 minutes we
will have our keynote speaker which will
be maggie mayhem
so please come on back and we will see
you for the rest of our conference and
head on over to our discord and we can
be chatted with all day long over there
and have all the funds over there so
thank you so much