hello everyone
thank you for being at our first
Brooklyn
I hope you like the venue
[Applause]
first time in a new venue is always a
bit
exciting you don't know what to expect
but so far we're very happy so uh
first thing we want to start with
there's a sponsor contest Stephen you
have some prizes to give away
you're gonna draw something from a
magical box
foreign
I think so yeah so I have a key pair
here
it's a symmetric key pair of course
so as we say in Dutch you need an
innocent hand to do this but we didn't
find those so I'm the I'm the victim
here
so we've been counting we have had
57 57 of you who applied to win a book
about threat modeling the newest Bible
of threat modeling I am now
shaking all of you up in here maybe we
can get like the unfortunate people on
the side as well okay so
first
Daniel Noah Johnson
do we have Daniel in the house
okay next
[Laughter]
in the house
Donald Trump no there is fun
okay there is
coming up
[Applause]
so uh congrats
foreign
if I'm pronouncing that correctly
okay
Maybe by Chopin who else have you filled
the form if there's no one here okay
okay we have one two
okay more than two people okay now we're
just gonna keep on roughly okay so there
we go we have
Brian
[Music]
's Health through the
we have Brian in the house
no Brian
congrats
Stephen from Khan's speaker
foreign
so
yeah okay cool then we will keep the
book for Kim over here and then we are
done okay thank you all for joining
[Applause]
and we have a bit more to give away we
have some crates of beer so if you
remembered Us in here
come and find me you filled in the
feedback form
so this is for the people who fill it in
here but of course we're still giving
away tickets for next Brooklyn so please
fill in the feedback form it really
helps us to improve the venue to see how
we organize it and what we can do better
there are also 20 tickets to climb the
saint rumbles Cathedral it's a very nice
Tower very nice view from the top it's
quite some stairs if you would like to
go there come and find me I'll give you
a ticket thanks to the city of Michela
we were able to hand these out so uh
very welcome
I got some stats about the network it
shouldn't be surprising and luckily we
see more and more encryption the wall of
sheep is getting less and less
interesting
we do see many people using corporate
laptops connecting to the Wi-Fi
interesting host names we could find
some information
and we see that many of those laptops
and in general the laptops are not
really hardened as they should be to
connect to
open slash public Wi-Fi's
so thank you for trusting our Wi-Fi
don't know if it's a good thing but
thank you
the talk recordings all of them will be
on a YouTube channel this evening most
of them are already there
so please go ahead look the ones that
you saw
and then we really want to thank you for
being here our sponsors the volunteer
the crew to organize it so thank you
everyone
as again scan this random QR code please
or or visit the link but fill in the
feedback form
thank you all and I see you next year at
the same place