all right
um good afternoon
um it's lovely to be back here
um it's I was here 11 years ago I worked
out at one of the very first
um Brew cons so a bit about me I've been
I've worked as a firewall engineer I
built firewalls I rolled out networks
and then I got sucked back into Academia
about 20 years ago I've spent the last
20 years
pretty much training the next generation
of security people largely based in
South Africa more recently I've now
based out of Norway but in between all
of that I've spent a lot of time playing
with the defense sector telecoms Finance
consultancies Etc which has been really
interesting and sort of quite of a bit
of a privilege being able to dip my toes
back into what so-called real world
problems actually are it also came to
our realization this is my 32nd year on
the internet
um I've been there for a very long time
I didn't quite realize it was that long
um I love packets
um if there's one thing that gets me
excited it's playing with packets
because
applications lie some applications going
to tell you it's the connection's okay
the connection's not okay but
applications lie TCP dump seldom lies
why a shock well we don't talk about why
a shark and it's appetite for memory
um so yeah I love packets I also love
doing things on the command line maybe
that is because I've been using Unix
also for about 30 to something years
um and I haven't got out the bad habits
of like reaching for GUI tools that they
I just can't do it if I need to do
something well there's bash they said
there's Oak I think I've really sort of
extended my viewpoint to Preparing this
talk I've played with some new
technologies like JQ and Json
um most of all I love all things open
source but particularly open source
related things to networks the
background there's a tool that built
with some students a few years ago based
on the so-called spinning cube of Doom
it's a really nice 3D tool you feed it
packets that draws pretty pictures of
what's happening in real time for those
of you that did take a a gander at
reading my bio and wondered what murder
iconology is it's the study and
collection of wooden woodworking planes
all right enough about me
why do we need to care about DNS and I'm
sure many of you have come across this
Haiku it was not DNS there's no way it
was DNS it was DNS
um it really this has been reinforced
years of sort of working through and
debugging and troubleshooting networks
both from an operational perspective as
well as looking some of the security
aspects is DNS is a really underloved
protocol everyone just assumes it's
there and it works but there's a vast
number of people that really don't
actually understand how DNS works and
that really is the first starting point
where we can depart for this talk is DNS
is critical infrastructure when DNS
breaks all sorts of other things break
I had to talk before lunch talking about
failover systems and high availability a
lot of that still today relies on
the operation of DNS
so this is why we're looking at DNS the
entire takeaway and you want to go to
sleep after the slide just take note of
there things break badly when DNS goes
wrong
so the first thing we need to do is talk
about DNS resiliency
um it's almost a miracle the DNS like so
many of the other protocols on the
internet actually still works today it
was conceived
in the Galaxy long long ago and far far
away the fact that we still have TCP
that functions on multi-gigabit networks
designed in the late 1970s DNS is a
little bit younger than that but DNS
resiliency really is an important part
of the internet today everybody expects
it to be there everything else is built
on the fact that you can do something
via DNS right away when you go and start
looking in your web browser the very
first thing it does when loads of sites
it says hey is the SSL certificate yes I
know it's a TLS we use these days but I
was around in the days of SSL and mice
that had balls in them
so the very first thing your browser
does is say does the cname in the the
x509 certificate match the DNS name one
of the very first sort of classes of
attack against encrypted Communications
was hey if we can spoof DNS we can do
whatever we want with the crypto
certificates
well it's got a lot better but it fell
apart because there was the Reliance the
DNS was going to be there to save the
day
the early days of of sort of high
performance networking you looked at DNS
for doing your round robin for doing
your load balancing for doing sharing of
work or being quite crudely but it
worked there was the the entire Reliance
was DNS would be there and would be able
to catch but so little time is spent and
if you look at curriculums at
universities that I'm talking sort of
from undergraduate through to
postgraduate level in most networking
curriculums DNS is just a footnote hey
DNS is something that takes it takes a
human readable name and turns it into an
IP address so a computer can use and
there's very seldom is there anything
really much further
so there's a number of well-established
practices relating to DNS the first of
these is diversification don't have your
DNS servers for your domain on dot seven
and Dot eight within your network block
Works remarkably well but what happens
when your network block goes down
um the worst I've seen is don't have
your two DNS servers sitting on the same
hypervisor your hypervisor goes down DNS
breaks so the and these recommendations
are nothing new it's a you should have
your two DNS servers geographically
separated you should have your DNS
servers on separate
asns separate ipv4 blocks that's how you
go about building resilience and I think
it's important to say that
a lot of what I'm going to be talking
about in the next couple of slides there
are operators out there that have
implemented this kind of resilience this
is not by no means sort of a slight
against all DNS operators out there but
by the same counter they are very small
group that have implemented these kind
of good protections there's a very large
group that has either ignored them
completely or has no idea what's going
on and we'll look at some of those cases
a little bit later on there's the
classic bind operators guide I think if
a lot more people read this and
understood it no matter what DNS server
you're actually using the principles and
the advice that are provided in the Bog
are really really good
so at the end of the day DNS is really
important
and here let me get the disclaimer out
the way
um
what I'm going to be talking about
following on results are imperfect
unfortunately nobody's been kind enough
to hand over the DNS records for the
whole world so I've had to effectively
reverse engineer how a lot of DNS is
actually working so going on the basis
that we've got imperfect data to start
with but doesn't mean it's necessarily
bad it does mean that I'm painting with
fairly broad Strokes as it comes to the
conclusions that are being arrived at
as I started going through the material
and started digging I I got more and
more scared it's actually for something
that is so critical
it's remarkably fragile when you start
digging into what the actual DNS
infrastructure looks like globally and
at a national level so I've taken the
decision there are no IP addresses no
specific domains listed here protect the
potentially vulnerable um it's probably
it's good practice
the at the same time this is not just
one snapshot in time it's about six
months total time being worked on this
and I've been taking snapshots
periodically
the more worrying thing is that nothing
really changes
um so a couple of domains have resolved
in one round of some some and have not
in the other rounds but repainting in
Broad Strokes has been no substantive
change
um in the data and then just really
recognizing the flow of the evaluation
itself in terms of we had imperfect data
so we can't say that this is the fact
that is the definitive results but
rather this is a case of saying hey this
is something we need to start talking
about there's something we need to think
about
um and then the lastly interpretation in
the views of my own keep everyone else
happy about that all right so on to the
far more interesting what was the actual
experiment this actually was sparked
about two years ago in the middle of
covert I was doing some work with some
final year students we were doing an
enumeration of the Norwegian top-level
domain
effectively looking at what is the
uptake of DNS sick the plus side really
really good in Norway largely because
the biggest registrar turns being sick
on by default and with something like 67
or 80 for certain sectors of the um
the main space that we actually surveyed
but after that came the question really
of how diverse are country code top
level domains are
people registering domains outside of
the.com org net Etc are they actually
paying attention to the guidelines the
recommendations that actually come about
um as regarding how we should operate
DNS what and then from that what is the
proportion of DNA servers
say for Belgium that actually reside in
Belgium and I've looked at this for a
number of other countries and this was
really triggered
um by what happened in February
and starting to say well is DNS we
talked about as critical infrastructure
in terms of it's important for the
internet to actually exist but how does
it actually go about impacting when we
have a state of War as with the the
conflict going on in the Ukraine and I
did some scrabbling around at that point
and started trying to get together what
can I find in terms of Russian domains
and we'll talk about about that a little
bit later on but that sort of just
started I started chasing on the rabbit
hole and along the way I ended up
collecting a huge amount of data so
while I've started off saying well where
did the the name servers actually lie I
ended up having a look at sort of bits
of information that came out as a side
effect of the crawling operations that I
built effectively looking at how how
much is DNA SEC actually implemented and
as a sort of extension to DNS that has
been around for quite some time now and
then compare and contrast that with the
CAA record or the certification
Authority record where you will talk
about that a little bit later but
effectively saying these are the people
that are allowed to issue certificates
to me
so if we go back to the Ukrainian
conflict
um February 24th massive sanctions come
into place one of the interesting things
that came out as the Russian government
said
relocate your DNS back inside Russia
there was the potential expectation of a
global isolation and cutoff of the
Russian internet which is an interesting
thing in its own right given that Russia
did exactly the same a couple of years
ago they had a national experiment
isolating themselves from the global
internet effectively to see what broke
so while not completely driven by this I
think this is something we need to keep
in the back of our mind and we'll
revisit some more recent events towards
the end of this so how did I go about
Gathering data
and the first trick was where do we
actually begin this sounds like
something really interesting to do but
unsurprisingly
National registrars are not exactly
happy to say hey here's our entire Zone
file have a go at it if we could do that
it'd be really easy it would have saved
a lot of processing time having to
reverse engineer it
back in the old days of the internet a
very very long time ago if you went to
the Zone file you just issue an ax for
command and the name servers would
happily serve a Zone file up to you that
doesn't work these days except for the
Russian domain a couple of years ago
somebody managed to do that so this
whole process of going about an active
finding domain lists turned out to be a
lot harder than initially expected so I
can't actually even remember all the
places I gathered them from I told some
of GitHub I trolled some off dumps that
had been done I found others where
people had pulled the list by scraping
web pages and so this goes into where
it's and clearly acknowledging that the
data that we worked with is imperfect
but it's representative at the end of
the day I've got around about 10 million
domains that have been looked at so by
statistical purposes it's significant
enough to start drawing some conclusions
one of the challenges with this was
trying to work out the difference a host
name is not the same as a domain name it
can be but it isn't necessary and so how
do we go about where you've got lists
and lists of names how do you go about
reducing them and there's two sort of
large groupings of the analysis that
this was broken down into based on how
we go about being able to simplify these
lists the country code top level domains
have some very very different ways of
approaching things three of the examples
that we look at are the Za domain for
South Africa Au for Australia and UK
they have a very clearly structured
second level
within the country code domains whereas
countries like Russia Belgium Norway
they don't it's a pretty much a
free-for-all
everything's very much flat under the
say for example
um dot Eno
what was interesting is pretty much
across the board as I went through
iterating through it was around about
eight percent of the queries would come
back reliably saying NX domain no such
domain in other words the domain had
expired and this is not unexpected it
just shows that there is a a churn
um
of domains
overall less than one percent of domains
existed between either timing out or
refused after a couple of runs and this
was an important thing as well as one
can't just take one snapshot you don't
know what else is happening out on the
internet so you need to take if
something fails you put it in another
list and you retry it sometime later on
but effectively have run this over a
couple of months and have largely
averaged and aggregated out the data so
what did we actually look for so we
looked at a couple of country domains as
I said the Norway Belgium and Russia as
just a selection of domains Belgium
because we hear Norway because I lived
there and Russia hate well that's an
interesting domain to look at at the
time comparing and contrasting that with
some of the others and these are largely
charged because they are that much more
structured in terms of their second
level
ordering the UK we used code.uk
um australia.com.au and South Africa CO2
today
um but just because they were large
pools but still manageable when one
starts looking at the whole of the UK
domain it actually gets really big I
think the UK the code at UK was about
four and a half million domains are
starting off with about 18 million host
names that needed to get parsed down
through it and then I've complemented
this with the so-called Majestic
Millions so the
so-called top million domain names on
the internet and that's a fairly scary
set of findings in its own right but
some of the interesting things that came
up with the processing is number of
timeouts very surprising the number of
RFC 1918 addresses that were exposed in
the global internet when you start
digging through who are name servers
this just shouldn't be happening these
days and people have known about this
for years but it was an interesting
thing and largely those correlate quite
nicely to why domains were actually
timing out
and then overall refuse connections was
really really small once I actually
factored it all out so to put some
numbers to it this is around about 10
million domains to actually looked at
um broken down there Russia is by far
the smallest the Russian list I had a
huge number of domains however that it
stood out in terms of there being a very
large number of them but either just
timed out or refused connections but
most of the Russian collection actually
only happened from June onwards so one
sort of sanctions that had things had
really escalated there so a couple of
caveats we need to bear in mind this
data is volatile if you do a collection
now you do a collection next week you're
probably going to get different answers
because people update domains people
um infrastructure goes up down Etc and
through the process of this I actually
just kept falling deep and deep into
this Rabbit Hole I've ended up with far
more data than I could actually talk
about in a week standing up and
exploring it so it's been a lot of it is
about how to go about sort of condensing
this down and to sort of sum it up we've
looked at 10 million domain names which
span around 320 000 individual domain
name servers or DNS servers and so the
question is well the statistics and so
we'll flag the with the quote that's
attributed to Mark Twain there's three
kinds of Statistics lies damn lies and
statistics and to make it even worse the
same quote is actually generally
attributed to Benjamin's Israeli as well
also saying lies damn lies and
statistics so is it really a lie but
just bear in mind that this is you can
dress statistics up to be whatever you
actually want and that's really the gist
of a quote
so the question really is about data
quality just because we don't have
perfect data is this not worth looking
at what conclusions can we actually draw
from it and really is incomplete data
bad data and how does it compare to no
data at all and then the second one is
that it's the approach I took saying
there's nothing out there I have spent a
long time searching sort of
industry talks like this I've spent time
controlling through academic journals
and conferences no one's done this kind
of large-scale survey and so I'm going
with the approach of an incomplete data
is better than no data at all
so how do that go about doing the
processing a lot of it boiled down to
cleaning cleaning cleaning and more
cleaning any of you that have worked
with any kind of real world data are
probably painfully aware that real world
data is never what it actually looks to
be in terms of there's always a weird
letter there's a weird character
there's some separator like a semicolon
you're quite surprising semicolon is not
a valid character in a domain name yet
there were hosts returned that had a
semicolon in the middle of their
hostname don't ask me how that happened
but they there it doesn't factor and of
course when you're splitting and
breaking data based on those kind of
field separators things go badly wrong
so my first approach is this is going to
be easy I'll whip out bash bash for Loop
had a list of domains and I fired it
away
well it took about three days to do one
set of queries on 600 000 domains this
wasn't going to work very well when I
needed to do a lot of these so I
reluctantly went and I tried some python
python was a lot better it was 18 hours
but this felt very much like I was
trying to reinvent a wheel and that's
where I sort of remembered a long time
ago said DNS that put together by the
same team that produced zedmap amazingly
fast scanner zdns does pretty much the
same kind of things it's written in go
very very fast massively multi-threaded
solution for doing DNS queries
first attempt
got about 38 minutes for 600 000 domains
moved on I've been about 42 minutes
for a million domains 12 minutes for a
million domains doing sort of the um the
DNS set queries in about 30 minutes per
million domains for doing CAA queries I
think I could run it at least 10 times
faster still provided a build out
infrastructure what I was trying to
avoid doing was having to build my
entire own sort of parallel DNS
resolution infrastructure but rather to
try and do it in such a way that was
also being very nice again being
painfully aware I'm querying public
servers how do I do it in such a way as
to not have any kind of negative impact
so I took a lot of guidelines from some
of the stuff that Google's published for
the public DNS generally kept query
levels well below about 1500 queries per
second what did make a difference was
running some of my own caching
infrastructure
um spun up some VPS hosts and getting
some decent sized caches in place and
structuring the queries made things go a
lot faster if you've just asked for the
NS records for a host all that stuff
sitting in memory you may as well go and
while it's in memory go and ask the
other questions you want to know about
that domain it's going to save a whole
number of lookups and doing those kind
of things resulted in some fairly
substantial speedups
some of the challenges though
um
again raw input data not particularly
clear
we had expired domains absolute Upstream
connectivity problems timeouts
configuration errors I've mentioned
already and we needed to go through as
we're doing this keep a record of what
succeeded and what didn't succeed and it
was around about this time and with the
transition to
to zdns which outputs in a plain text
format but structured text in excuse me
in terms of being Json
it made this a whole lot easier to
actually go about doing and so it's
worth mentioning what some of the tools
were well bash was the PowerHouse
um the nsh if I was running on some of
the other machines
um stead or all the common Unix command
line tools why they're designed to work
with data they're designed to work with
plain textual data they're possibly not
the fastest but they were the fastest in
terms of development JQ a lot of credit
needs to go to that being able to parse
and work with the the Json files zdns
for doing the resolution netcat was used
for some various bits of testing as well
as for sort of building some raw queries
for doing who is um for doing something
enrichment data for that particularly
used the who is service but from Team
simru I'm sure most of you are aware of
that and then the ever present Max mine
geolocation systems so use both of those
for validating as numbers as well as
sort of the country level geolocation
and then match to my share my ended up
having to use some spreadsheets just
because I wanted to make sure I'd added
things up properly sometimes or can said
get a little bit confused about what's
actually going on but all was good
so the approach taken was largely
accurate of going collect as much data
as possible within reason bearing in
mind I could could ask hundreds of
queries but how do you do it in such a
way that you're not creating a negative
impact on the rest of of the ecosystem
um
batch collection helps with the caching
scalability how do we do it you run it
on multiple systems a lot of this was
also run from multiple points without
re-ran I didn't always rerun from the
same IP address and there is some
obvious skew that comes in place there
where you have got large providers that
are providing some kind of geolocated
responses back but they seem to be very
much in the minimal
I work in about a 72-hour retry window
for each run so I'll do the first run
and within 72 hours I would have done
subsequent runs through retrying
anything that timed out refused or
issued with server errors
move the move to Json while very good
also resulted in a massive problem I now
had very very big files and some of the
runs were coming back with sort of more
than 10 gigs in size because Json is
quite a chatty protocol and their DNS
very kindly dumps a whole bunch of other
information into the into the responses
you didn't even ask for like TTL values
SOA record numbers Etc which in
hindsight was actually really nice to
have and that actually opens up an
entire now that I've got all this data I
can go do another bunch of run through
looking at that but
it took a while to actually go about
running through this fortunately JQ is
really fast and on a modern machine with
a little bit of tuning and some
pre-filtering you're looking at probably
10 to 15 minutes for a script to run
through and process the resulting Json
files
so maybe looking to the Future maybe I
need to bend over and decide that
actually this is not something I should
be doing with a collection of shell
scripts but a relational database
actually is probably the better way to
go with it and so moving now into sort
of the the results section Act One what
is the current state of a phase as it
comes to security protocols within DNS
the oldest of these obviously is dnsic
um draw your attention to the quote that
was made Popular by Ronald Reagan of
trust but verify which apparently is a
direct translation of a Russian quote
that he was or Russian proverb he was
working with I'm doing the negotiations
around sort of strategic nuclear
proliferation and sort of managing
nukes Etc during the height of the Cold
War but what DNA sect does is it
provides us with strong cryptography it
provides us with a cryptographic method
that allows for the authentication of
DNS data authenticated denial of
existence we can categorically say this
does not exist
if only people actually went around
using it
it's a really sad State of Affairs if we
think back to the birth of DNS Tech in
I'm hesitant to ask but how many people
were around in 1999 so DNA seg May well
be older than a fair number of people in
the audience
um
2013 was sort of the Heyday of dnsic in
terms of at that point more than 100 of
the country code tlds all the top level
tlds had actually been signed had a DNS
SEC route and the decision was made by
icann that any future domains would be
mandated to be signed
so we're nearly 10 years on from there
why are most places still not actually
using it
um fortunately I'm not the only one
that's thought about this there's quite
a bit of work Chung and Roth in 2017
2019 did some work looking at comnet org
the dot nldomain the dot SE domain well
done to the Netherlands and Sweden
congratulations you are actually among
the top things I've just got I've got a
paper coming out later in the year where
we detailed Norway Norway is sitting at
about 65 percent as well now
but these are very much the the sort of
the exception when we actually look at
the results coming in from the scrape
data from this study it's not a
particularly pretty effect 0.3 percent
of the top million domains
are using the NSC now surely if you
involved in e-commerce and all the rest
you want trust for credibility why are
you not using this com.au 0.35
code.uk coming in
second place at two percent Belgium well
done 27
um it's not great but it's a hell of a
lot better than most of the rest of the
world
um South Africa 0.1 percent not great at
all
so
um we could do a talk entirely about
DNA's sake and the fun and games and
stuff but the question is why do people
not go about implementing it so it's
largely seen as a chicken and egg
scenario why should I go about
implementing DNA sick when no clients
out there go about validating it
um it's one of the things every time I
travel and sort of wherever you try and
have a look are you at a resolver a DNS
resolver that actually validates dnsic
I've yet to actually find one out in the
wild that validates
um so the next thing we looked at is a
relatively new record which is the CIA
record and this is a new record that has
been proposed and adopted and it allows
you to make an explicit statement in
your domain Zone file it says I trust
these certificate authorities I hereby
endorse that they are able and permitted
to go about issuing cryptographic
certificates for my domain it's amazing
how the Zone file has become overloaded
as a trust point you use it for
validating Google for after your Office
365 or all these other things SPF and
all the rest to be shoving to text
records along CNN CAA is a sort of a
variation on this it's a relatively new
domain really only adopted around about
2019.
um the idea behind this is by being
explicit as to which certificate
authorities can issue youth certificates
it should hopefully help cut down on
fraudulent certificates being issued
particularly with the Adventists of many
of the so-called free free domain
um let's encrypt to make use of it most
of the other big ones making crypto zero
trust makes use of it
um zero SSL
some of them won't actually issue
certificates unless you've got the
appropriate records in place so looking
at again the top top what are the top 10
entries for issuance out of the Magic
Million
um
let's encrypt no surprise that you can't
really beat the price of free but this
also provides some insight saying that
you know here's your 50 000 Euro
guarantee if you get hacked maybe that
isn't so important to companies
um bearing in mind that these top
million in theory represent a large
portion of e-commerce
breaking it down a little bit further
of the Majestic
um
million the top 12 domains here
accounted for 93 of the records
but the important thing to notice here
is it's not a million records
um as we'll see in the next ad only
about three percent of the domains in
the magic million actually listed this
these happen to be a breakdown of the
sort of 115 000 entries in many cases
the domains that did have them had
multiple that would allow let's encrypt
and Komodo and Amazon and Global sign or
whatever else it might actually be
the adoption rates
well 3.7 percent is not that bad I
suppose
um it's certainly higher than any of the
others and again welcome to Belgium
thank you Belgium well done
um one percent of your domains are
actually implementing this
is that a good thing it's a bad thing I
don't know
again looking around no one's really
done much work on this I found one study
done in late 2019 that looked at the
um what at that stage was the Alexa top
one million and it had around about the
same kind of results as Majestic so
maybe things haven't really moved on
and so with those two sort of side
little projects out the way which were
largely stumbled across because the data
was there already getting to the the
core of the actual research and the the
core of really what I want to talk about
today is
do we know where our DNS is it's 2 A.M
do you know who actually controls your
dnas do you have any idea what nation
state feels like ruining your day
um because we don't know what's going to
happen
so the real question here is around
finding value the data States I checked
it this morning is sitting around about
36 gigs compressed so it's a fair chunk
of data I admit it's probably not stored
in the most efficient way with Json but
there's a lot of data there and what
I've looked at here really only just
starts scraping the surface and bearing
in mind the the wise words of Donald
knuff
um premature optimization is a root of
all evil I've tried really really hard
to stay away from falling into the
various rabbit holes no matter how
exciting they actually look
um
what I can say in terms of the summary
to this is of all the domains surveyed
all of them are at significant risk of
having a foreign player being able to
have impact the domain and we'll look at
the degree that is
um something interesting that I came
across and I know there's a number of
people that do threat modeling and it's
your passion
um I haven't come across a threat model
or a set of guidelines for threat
modeling DNS
so if we look through the six sort of
domains we mentioned earlier starting
with Australia now Australia is really
interesting it's an island it's the
world's biggest island they call
themselves a continent but they're an
island
but part of that is that they yes
they've got really good connectivity but
they are an island what happens is
submarine cables to Australia are
actually damaged
via earthquake as we saw happening to
some of the sort of the Pacific Nations
earlier in the year with the volcano
blew up there or via malicious Act
63 percent of the name servers this is
not domains of the name servers used for
Australian domains are hosted in the US
in fact 67 of them are in North America
that's basically Canada and the US
seven percent are in Western Europe
um Australia is actually not doing too
badly 20 of the name servers that are
used by its domains are actually located
in Australia and the big asterisk that
of course sits with this as well
geolocation is an imprecise science
noted but what I pull these stats I use
two independent systems the team simru
as well as the um
from Max mind and as well as in certain
cases doing some checks against the
allocations of IP address ranges from
the regional Registries like appnick
ripe Aaron
um Etc Australia not too bad in total 26
000 name servers
um
control the Australian namespace the top
10 makes up 94 of those South Africa 18
000 odd name servers
um South Africa's not doing too bad 14
of name servers are located in South
Africa South Africa also has a really
interesting term sort of topology in
terms of connecting to the internet
there are two or two and a half
um submarine cables one one set running
up the West Coast one running up the
east coast and we've had times in the
past where due to issues it has ended up
cutting out large portions of the
internet
but coming back here 63 in North America
19 in Western Europe
having a look over here 55 were in China
56 in Russia probably not too much of a
concern for South Africa given that
they're a member of of the brics
um grouping
um looking at neighboring countries less
than 10 servers actually are Botswana
Malawi Zimbabwe Lesotho
um so not much Geographic diversity here
as well so I would say forget nation
states aside just from a geographic
perspective there's risk here what
happens when your submarine cables get
cut you're going to be looking at about
70 odd percent of the domains cannot
actually even be resolved
UK was the largest of the domains that
we looked at this is the co.uk domain
about four and a half million domains in
total were looked at producing 68 000
name servers they also control and by
day I talked about the nation state
Great Britain twenty percent of the name
servers are actually nominally located
inside the borders of Great Britain no
surprise 40 to the US
um 43 overall to North America 23 in
Western Europe now to all members of
NATO so NATO allies unlikely to probably
go about turning things upside down
if we look at sort of the geopolitics
currently China's got 142 Russia nearly
300 Iran 54.
what could the potential impact of those
actually be is and this is probably a
reasonable point to raise it is our
national Regulators actually looking way
the domains for critical infrastructure
are located are they is there a mandate
anyway to say that we deem this to be
critical infrastructure you need to use
name servers inside the country we
prefer you not to have
name servers hosted in a country that we
have
let's just say it's complicated
diplomatic relationships with
Belgium 32 000 name servers
only four percent of name servers are
actually located in Belgium
um
probably not too much a problem
47 of them again Western Europe or if
you look at the countries they NATO
countries there's unlikely to be too
much friction
um
in the in the immediate future but when
we look China's got 104 Russia 186 Iran
eight and b y anybody remember your two
letter domains Belarus they've got five
um as well
Norway
um
same kinds of things 56 in North America
20 in Scandinavia 29 in Western Europe
so we can say roughly 59 or 49 are safe
countries
um and it's one can go on and have a
look again presence of China Russia um
and Iran
a Russian Federation now this is where
there's a big star attached and to to
take note this is by far the smaller
sample I was only able to get around 230
000 domains
um resolving reliably I've got more
sometimes less sometimes but on on the
whole around 230 000 domains I do have
an input list of 2.9 Million domains for
this so that that effectively tells you
what proportion about 10 of what I
started with was accurizolving being
small compared to the other
statistically probably the results are
not as significant but this is the State
of Affairs as of August
um 45 of the name servers are actually
located in Russia 40 orange 40 servers
are in China 49 servers are in China 40
in Belarus Ukraine has 223 name servers
which serve around about 8 000 domains
um
draw your own conclusions from there
interestingly 49 in total of Russia's of
name servers serving those 230 000
domains are located in Western Europe
um so far we've seen nothing in terms of
sanctions saying that hey you shouldn't
be doing this is it something down the
pipeline I don't know what the
politicians might come up with in
monstercam and then really to round It
Off The Majestic million represents
roughly 200 countries
40 of the name servers are sitting in
the US Germany comes in second to Ten
Ten Thousand name servers or seven
percent and it drops off um there of
these the top ten only make up 73 so a
big difference to what we've seen
elsewhere and so with the raw numbers
out the way and numbers are there
because people some people like numbers
we can actually start talking about what
are the what are the takeaways from this
um
and we can say well what is the impact
the reflection
is it the end of the world should we all
just like become Wasteland Warriors and
you know Mad Max was our style guide for
what we're actually going to get up to
impact number one and there's five major
impacts to take away from this is
an attack on 20 IP addresses can
potentially take out 75 percent of the
Norwegian domain space
20 IP addresses and they are not trivial
or sorry it is rather trivial to
actually go about determining what these
actually are and to we can't have a
security presentation but of course
without quoting Sun Tzu and being able
to say the Supreme Art of War is to
subdue the enemy without fighting think
about where we are today if you can take
out a nation's actual infrastructure
without firing a shot
um
you've pretty much won massive denial of
service attacks they're cheap these days
you can rent rent a botnet you've got a
nation state you can cook your own
button it up and then say we can either
confirm or deny but this was a fairly
scary fact to me is that around 75 of
Norwegian domains could be taken out
fairly easily
if we look at the UK an attack on the
top five providers
renders 10 percent of the CO2 UK domain
and workable it's about 440 000 domains
um underco.uk it's a lot less only 10
percent
um I haven't gone going to sort of
protect the potentially vulnerable what
are the domains that fall into this
category again it's not difficult to go
about determining but build your own
scraper
impact number three attack on the top
five providers for Belgium
can render 20 of them of the domains
unreachable
um
so again it's nothing special it just
shows you vulnerable
for all the other good things the
Belgian domain space is doing it's still
vulnerable to this
um and if we go back to quote the Dan
Kaminsky made back or 11 odd years ago
talking about some of the major flaws he
found in DNS at that time he said the
data shows that this is most likely
hundreds of thousands to millions of
victims issue and I believe that exactly
the same applies with what the kind of
stuff we're talking about here if you
can take over or or attack a
nation-state's DNS as critical
infrastructure it is going to have a
knock-on effect into the Millions
so what is the big picture behind this
impact number four big DNS providers
know what they're doing they're
resilient they've got multi-homing
multiple IP addresses geographically
distant
they make up a very very small
proportion of the total the smaller
providers often don't the smaller
providers are the ones that are listing
RFC 1918 addresses
as they publicly accessible name servers
no wonder things don't actually work
um
impact five
um there's some some portions of IP ipv4
address space that need to be considered
to be a lot more important than others
and yes IPv6 is out there believe it or
not some people actually do use IPv6 but
given that most of the stuff that I saw
did not support IPv6 I ended up just
cutting that out of of what I'm doing
one of the big challenges with this is
coming back to the the core around
resiliency for for DNS is we say we've
got high availability we can just move a
server
that's fine and we can move brewcon.org
and get moved anywhere else we just have
to update DNS
um to point to the new IP address it's
not that easy when you have to start
moving your domain name servers around
that in itself is a risky process and
create
things so with apologies to George
Orwell and these two pigs all IP
addresses are equal but some are more
equal than others and if you haven't
read Animal Farm it's one of those
really good recommended readings
probably even before you get to reading
The Art of War
so what is the impact we're looking here
in the red spot where we have the
opportunity for a threat a threat
against an asset and there's a
vulnerability that is ultimately what we
need to start thinking about what is the
impact and I'll be the first one to say
I don't have any hard and fast answers
other than maybe we should start talking
about this as a Potential Threat
ultimately a relatively small number of
servers can result in a large-scale
impact so think of this asymmetric
Warfare why take out thousands of
systems when you maybe take out two or
three hundred core systems around the
world and do a significant amount of
damage crippling the internet
um what is the risk of foreign hosted
systems
um is this is this actually something
significant am I actually just being
someone who worries with no apparent
reason I don't know this is and again
it's about starting a conversation
should we regard DNS servers as critical
infrastructure are some domains more
important than others and one of the
things I've done is started is I've
started pulling out government domains I
could tie to governments
um they were a little bit better off but
not that much better off
um there were still some government
domains for some countries located in
some very odd places in terms of their
name servers not necessarily a primary
name server but one of the name servers
was there
um what's the impact of having foreign
hosted domains yes it might be cheap and
here I'm pointing a big finger at the US
they have some of the cheapest hosting
anywhere for a variety of historical
reasons
um and then probably the one of the most
scary questions do we know what we don't
know
um and I would hesitate I would sort of
want to say that I don't think we don't
we know what we don't know about what
the risks are and again waving and
putting a call out is is anybody aware
of specific guides for threat modeling
around DNS and then really just to tie
it into sort of the things that have
happened in the last couple of days I am
pretty sure someone theorized about the
the issues of a leak on the the gas
pipelines but what happens when the
unexpected actually happens
um
what happens when it occurs how do we
prepare for it and sort of not looking
at any issues around attribution or
anything but how do we prepare for these
types of things
and really the devil is in the details
found a really nice quote here from Dan
farmer some of you might be too young to
remember Dan farmer some of you might
have really fond memories of his tool
Satan one of the first real security
scanners out there and if you didn't
like the name it came with a command
that you could run it could renamed
itself a center
um but one of the first real sort of
vulnerability scanners out there Diane
said I was interested in Implements of
mass destruction from an academic point
of view and that to some extent is what
is what I've been looking at here it's
ultimately it's a complex problem
um DNS is amazing it's still amazing
that we've got a technology that that is
that old that works reliably
um it's still surprisingly poorly
understood even when you talk to people
at isps Network providers
things like that
um it's one of those things nobody cares
about it when it works I'm sure many of
you work as Network administrators or
systems administrators nobody really
cares when the network works when things
break everyone comes running and says
well why aren't you doing your job
um it's pretty much the same with DNS
it's not a problem until it's not
working in which case it's a really big
problem
um in terms of the technology DNS
arguably the world's most fantastic
completely distributed data store it's
dynamic as well it's constantly updating
and it works with all technology it's
amazing but the distributed nature of
its of the very sort of distributed
nature of it also makes it difficult to
create momentums around getting changes
put in place how do we care for this big
mess of global system how do we
coordinate things
how do we build competency in it one of
the arguments being that you know how do
we build change things well we've got
rfcs we've publish them obviously people
must do comply with them except they
don't we've got that evidence we just
look at something like dnsic
people aren't complying with it if we
look at the some of the core basic
principles around DNS that have been
around since the 80s don't use private
address ranges for your public DNS
servers and people are still going about
doing that
um the question another question to come
out of this is are all domains and maybe
some subdomains are they all equally
important or can we start actually as
part of a discussion around critical
infrastructure and National Security
start saying
these domains actually are more
important than the others how about we
go about having a more detailed look at
them and say well what is the risk
evaluation around them
and ultimately what happens if DNS is
compromised because it's not just an on
or off situation DNS forms the backbone
for so much that we actually take for
granted today in terms of how we broker
Trust on our Networks
so so what and really this is this is
where I don't actually have some answers
um questions is this really a problem
or am I sort of seeing the proverbial
Boogeyman in the night that's coming out
to scare things
how bad is it I would say it's the the
initial work that I've done
says it's something that I personally
think is is worth digging into more is
it really bad probably not that bad but
again I'm a pessimist where the glass is
cracked all the beers leaking out
rapidly
um it's not a oh I've still got half a
beer despite it being cracked that's
just that's just not me so how do we
make it better
um
discussions with
National search National registrars
craving awareness and that really is
probably the single goal I had in terms
of proposing this talk
um other than of course to come back to
brewcon which is wonderful but to start
start the conversation make people aware
of these things are they things that
people have thought about
um ultimately a lot of longer term
monitoring is needed but at the end of
the day I've actually been left myself
with a far bigger pile of questions a
long long list of questions far more so
than the Fairly simplistic list that I
actually started with
and with that
is the end
um
I hope you found it interesting I think
we've got some time for a question or
two
um if you're interested come say hello
afterwards especially if you are in a
national search or registrar or security
researcher I'd love to have a chat
um out of some of the preliminary work
I'm already chatting to one of the
national registrars around at least
sharing some of the methodology for them
to be able to do some of their own
auditing
all right thank you very much
thank you
hello thank you Barry
um so if there's any questions I see
yeah thank you Barry a very nice
presentation
um some things came to my mind when I
saw your tables with figures for example
U.S frequently comes forward again in
the first or the second
did you look at why this was I would
assume maybe and I hope you can confirm
or say it's not true that because many
of the cloud providers are in the US
Cloud providers is one the other is a
lot of the cheap DNS hosting providers
are they
um so I think in both both those cases
one can say it's possibly an economic
incentive that said the cloud providers
have Cloud address space elsewhere
through the world which is in most cases
correctly registered by geolocation but
you raise a very valid point there and
and then as a follow-up because I'm from
Belgium the the number of the CAA
records stood out 20 something percent
did you look at why that was I haven't
yet it's sort of part of a larger
project I'm actually involved in terms
of trying to look not in terms of only
what the records are but what the
detailed contents are again one of the
things that stood out looking at not
just Belgium but all the CIA records was
the amount of garbage in there
um things that just make absolute be no
sense in terms of the specifications
they were like Google The Google domain
ID keys in there there was I saw a
Microsoft key I saw SPF records
um it's it's weird but it is part of
what I want to look at going forward
there's some other really interesting
work being done by some other
researchers at the moment saying that
actually publishing a CIA record is not
necessarily good for your domain
particularly
if you're using some of the sort of
providers like let's encrypt and you
link this into the whole sort of
certificate trust architecture there's
some good anecdotal evidence that say
for example you spin up a new website
you put a default WordPress install in
but don't configure it you then register
a certificate
and it's all being monitored on the
certificate transparency lists there's
some good anecdotal evidence that you
might well find your site is compromised
before you even get back to do the
configuring
um that's again something I'm playing
with at the moment
hi um thanks for the presentation
actually I don't I don't have any
questions just have a piece of
information that might be useful for you
um in Spain so the dot es domains you
can actually go to the government and
request a full list of all the existing
dot es domains I did not know that thank
you yeah some that might give you yes
didn't work because I couldn't find an
easily available so you can get a full
list you know up to date for today with
all Superman follow that up yeah I can I
can give you you know info how to do
that you need to request say why you're
doing that and they will give it to you
hopefully so they have given to me
I don't know there's any other questions
yeah thank you
um so I was wondering if you have taken
into account
uh or if any of these domains that you
found are known or potentially malicious
I haven't done that cross check yet
because that's it is something to do in
terms of pulling running against
something like the VT the VT API
um I got sort of pretty bogged down and
just crunching through the data but it
is a almost redo the study just looking
at malicious domains I think would be a
really interesting thing to do thanks
for the suggestion
all right I don't see any other hand so
I think I'm going to say cheers you want
to chat to me um I'd be loved it love to
chat you afterwards but I think our next
speaker needs to get all their toys
plugged in um before they talk so thank
you very much I will be around today and
tomorrow
[Applause]