okay we have a little surprise
announcement for you many of you have
heard in the last few weeks that as part
of our globalization and
internationalization strategy we plan to
change the posture of I can from an
organization that is largely operated
from the US so that we can have a new
posture a posture that embraces the
world and so we will be taking the core
I can operations and bringing them to
the world as we have committed so last
week we have confirmed that we're moving
forward with the provision of hubs in
Singapore to serve the asia-pacific
region and in Istanbul to sure to serve
Europe the Middle East and Africa in
addition to our hub in Los Angeles
serving the north and south of America
these are very important changes in I
can and ones that follow through on our
commitment in Toronto to start changing
the center of gravity of I can and to
bring it to the world
and as I have committed to all of you
not only will we we will be building
teams in these hubs but also many of the
leadership team of ICANN will be in
these hubs including myself I will be
for the first year rotating living
across the hub's with my family so we
can give the message that we are going
to the world and in this spirit around
these three hubs we plan to establish
many local engagement centers and these
are important so we can get even closer
to our stakeholders in each region and
so I am happy today to announce that we
will have our first engagement Center
besides the hub in Asia and for this I
would like to first invite our
distinguished guests so Minster Bing if
you could please come up to stage on
behalf of the Chinese government madam
who please on behalf of the Chinese
Internet academy please come up mr. XI
on behalf of the Chinese Academy of
Sciences mr. Wang on behalf of CN Nick
of course our own doctor said only
please come up and from our team I'd
like dr. Steve Crocker our Chairman and
sadly costerton the head of our global
engagement please come on up
thank you
I got you
so today we're announcing the first
engagement center of I can in Asia and
it will be in Beijing
we have we promised and we did
please