fadi Steve want to thank both of you for
joining us here at the conclusion of the
ican 46 meeting here in Beijing Steve
let's start with you the big news that
came out of this meeting occurred during
the public forum specifically the gac
communicate what's the reaction to the
gac communicate the as you said the gac
communicated kind of arrived in the
middle of the public forum which means
that the GAC was working very very hard
late into the evening before and again
assiduously all during the day on
Thursday to to prepare it and as you
said it arrived there's quite a bit of
content in it they cover a number of
points we're we've been working closely
with the GAC over a period of time to
develop a process to make sure that each
and every one of the points in their
community case is dealt with a clarity
so we take the each of the items in
there and we make sure that we
understand it and we iterate echo it
back and then we go through each one of
the items carefully and depending upon
how complicated it is or what issues it
raises it may take longer or shorter but
we want quite a bit of visibility so we
have a so-called GAC register in which
each item is posted and is visible to
everybody and go through a series of
phases all of which has been worked out
in a constructive fashion with them
there's a GAC advice regarding treatment
of names in the that have been applied
for Strings that have been applied for
and there's a certain amount of texture
and substance to it some a smaller
number of saying you know we have
specific advice on these names and then
broader advice about categories and so
forth there are interesting issues in in
both cases that have to be dealt with
and it would be inappropriate for me to
go too far on the spot but we're going
to be quite thorough well yeah I'd like
to add that we heard very clearly
yesterday in the public forum that the
community wish
to participate in the discussion about
the gap communicate and so alongside the
staff analysis that is starting right
now on the gap communique we have
decided to put the gap communicate out
for public comment soliciting the entire
community to give us their input to
ensure that the gap community is taken
seriously but also encompasses our
response encompasses the views of the
whole community steve gak advice is just
that it's advice but it is the
governments of the world talking to I
can so how much weight does that carry
gak communicate and more generally
advice from governments carries quite a
bit of weight and equally it is not the
end of the story of that we have a
carefully constructed multi-stakeholder
process we want very much to listen to
governments and we also want to make
sure that there's a balance the way our
bylaws are structured puts a preference
if you will toward following advice from
the GAC but not an absolute requirement
and lays out a process that if we choose
not to follow the gacks advice we have
to go through a first day an extended
consultation process and then at the end
of the day if we finally are not in
agreement and haven't been able to find
a common resolution then we'd have to
document quite carefully and be prepared
for the next phase of that which will be
the government's expressing their
displeasure and so there's a bit of a
balancing act their body you're going to
post the Raa for public comment in doing
so are you going to lose the ground that
you've gained I believe putting the last
version of the registrar accreditation
agreement for the year 2013 out for full
public comment process is actually
strengthening that agreement it's what
makes it an agreement of the community
to manage how our registrar's do their
work
and to support the registrar's in
delivering the best possible service to
the registrant's we have reached an
agreement in principle during the
Beijing meeting we're very appreciative
of the hard work the registrar's put to
make that happen we are finalizing the
language with them and we hope that no
later than mid next week we will publish
the full agreement we will also
accompany publishing this agreement for
the public to comment on with a series
of activities webinars and the like to
brief the community on what's in the
agreement and engage them and make sure
we hear them as we finalize this new and
very important agreement that includes
some true new breakthroughs in the state
of the relationship between I can and
its community and the registrar's this
will raise the profile of our work
globally and we're very pleased that got
completed here in Beijing that's the
registrar's where are you with a
registry agreement well like many things
contagion is a good thing in this case a
very good thing and the advances we made
with the registrar's have really created
new energy in our work with the
registries we have done very very well
here in Beijing multiple sessions very
frank very intense and I'm very happy to
share with you this at this moment that
we are very very close with the
registries as well and my expectation is
that within less than a week we will
have agreement in principle and we'll
move forward just like with the Raa
we'll move forward with a public comment
period on the registries now many
registries are concerned that this
public comment period will could delay
the whole gTLD program I'm here to give
you an assurance that while we will
include the community in deciding that
this is a good agreement for all of us
we will also do our very best
operationally to keep the program on the
most AB drive fast clip to get
everything ready and ensure the minimum
amount of impact in delay on the program
so what I'm hearing from you is
inclusion doesn't necessarily equate to
delay
in this case it won't simply because we
have some agility and flexibility on the
operational side for example the next
step after contracting was the pre
delegation test to ensure that these new
gTLDs have all the technical
capabilities on the ready to serve their
their register their registrant's and
certainly their registry registrar's now
we could potentially do something about
advancing this step ahead of contracting
finding a way to start pre delegation
testing before the final contract is
done we're looking at all these
possibilities now my commitment is to
clarity and visibility of the timeline
of the program many resources and a lot
of people are looking for clarity in the
timeline so they can get their work done
we're committed to that and we'll make
that happen as early as we can next week
fadi let's talk about the beijing
engagement center that was big news here
this week but talk to me about opening a
center like that in a country that
frequently makes headlines for internet
censorship or internet monitoring let me
be clear we cannot tie the policies of a
country on content to our responsibility
to ensure that all the citizens in all
the countries of the world have the full
access to our capabilities and policy
making processes so they can participate
in them so I am focused with the ICANN
board and the icon staff on engaging
with China at every level we will lean
into this great society with its great
vibrant economy with its 560 million
internet users growing by 40 50 million
per year this is not a community we can
walk away from this is a community we
need to be at the heart of and I must
tell you what happen invasion this week
is quite remarkable for the I can
commune
t we have been brought by china into the
inner most important parts of how china
makes policy and how china embraces
international organizations we are part
of that now and i think how we were
treated in china where we were invited
in the Great Hall of the People are
subtle but important symbols of the new
friendship between I can and China the
engagement center is just a an example
of how we're engaging with China it's
yet another way for us to be on the
ground to be engaged with government
society businesses in order to make sure
that our global policies are part of the
fabric of the new emerging China state
when we interviewed you after the
Toronto meeting you pointed to fadis
emphasis on internationalization as a
priority is a good thing at a board
level how are you feeling about our
progress in that direction the initial
move in that direction had to do with
Africa we followed up with the Arab
region and moving rapidly in latin
america caribbean region and the asia
area the these did the the first couple
of meetings that were held the so-called
mig meetings first in dubai and then in
addis ababa back-to-back were both
extremely successful brought key players
from both regions together created quite
a bit of energy and forward motion the
things that we were looking forward to
you asked about in terms of Toronto are
now in some sense yesterday's news of it
were moved making them happen the more
recent activity with the registry
agreement the Registrar agreements have
occupied quite a lot of time in the last
few weeks and putting that in place and
a tremendous amount of forward progress
across all fronts and a lot of energy
what's your biggest take away from the
Beijing meeting as Fadi said China is
vibrant China is is large fraction of
the total internet population and is
growing it's evident from being here
that the Chinese economy is a very
active this is a expanding positive
confident community here that they
they're not they don't appear to be
boisterous or presumptuous but they are
confident and deservedly so farty same
question your biggest take away from the
Beijing meeting I felt the momentum of I
can at this meeting a great forward
momentum and it's not just momentum and
staff or at the board or in some parts
of the community I must say we have a
new newfound momentum and it's a great
momentum I think it'll propel i can
forward in the next period i also leave
this meeting with some worry about how
we're going to embrace a growing global
i can within our current structures we
have a lot of work to do we saw the
largest meeting in icons history and i
think that's just the beginning as our
engagement activities embrace the globe
and reach out out of los angeles to the
world i see a lot of movement into the
icon community we need to start thinking
how we prepare for that and how we make
sure that we are prepared for the
interest in icons great work it sounds
like you're talking about systemic
changes some of these may be systemic
but the community must get engaged in
that and therefore i launched on my
first day in beijing the conversation
about icons five years strategy that we
are starting right now and i encourage
everyone listening to us here to go on
my I can org and file their thoughts
their ideas start participating where do
we take I can we need to get ready the
momentum is pulling us into great places
but we have to also be ready to embrace
the world gentlemen thank you very much
thank you thank you