all right all right can you guys hear me
okay all right welcome to script all the
things reverse all the malware an
introduction to JSON enhanced reverse
engineering with the aedra so before I
get started I just want to introduce
myself a little bit you so you guys know
what I do I come from a computer science
background software development as well
I'm gonna so see it on the coal fire
systems the federal labs team so that
means on a day to day basis I can be
doing any number of things ranging from
Network or application pen testing to
malware analysis and looking at breaches
all right so what are we gonna cover
today is my goal and then during this
presentation is to take a look at a new
tool that was released by the National
Security Agency back in March of last
year and kind of highlight some of the
features that you don't see that often
in online tutorials on how it works I
think are a really powerful part of the
reverse engineering process especially
for malware analysts so I'm gonna start
by kind of talking a little about what
the problem is during when we do static
malware analysis and what makes it so
difficult I think that's important to
understand why these tools are so
powerful and then I'm gonna take a
little bit of time to talk about deidre
and some of its core features and some
of the things that really set it apart
from other solutions and the big part of
this we are going to look at do a case
study of a real piece of malware that's
been found in the wild take a look at
some of the things it does and ways it
hides from analysts and then we're going
to use Gilders features to take those
apart undo them and learn a lot about
what it's actually trying to do and then
last part takeaways and I'm going to
talk a little about next steps things
that I'm working on that will maybe see
you next year and then open up time for
questions once we're done so we're going
over there first question why is static
analysis so hard it's by this we're
talking about we have a piece of malware
from an incident response or something
like that if you're on a blue team and
we want to take it apart one of the
things we're gonna do is we're gonna
look at it
a binary level and problem with is that
from a analysis standpoint we have a
pretty big lack of context this is the
key to why these things are so hard to
take apart part of this is kind of
inherent to any compiled code once we go
from source code to a binary it's
designed to be easy for a computer to
interpret not for humans we lose a lot
of the context that you have in source
code things like variable names and
function names and parameters and all
the stuff that kind of gets stripped out
most of the time so the job of a reverse
engineer especially the malware world is
to be able to go back and kind of try to
figure out some of that context because
that's how we tell what is this thing
trying to do what kind of things is it
trying to get to and that's that's
really what we're trying to find now
once you introduce a piece of malware
that's actively working against you and
it starts adding things like obfuscation
encrypting itself encoding you know
packing things really get crazy and
there's a picture I think I found it's
actually an emoji that I think
represents a pretty accurate
representation of an analyst when he's
working on a particularly hard by on
what malware there's a lot of been times
when that's what I've looked like all
right so on the other hand
luckily technology had give us as if
benefits is that we've been able to
develop a lot of tools to make this
process easier now in most cases this
involves static analysis tools commonly
heard one is called Ida some of you
happy how many of you have actually had
a chance to use it oh ok awesome so
that's been the big one for people who
are getting learning is a little bit
there's a free version as well and then
there's a also a decompilers another
feature of that isn't that on but we got
a us reverse engineers got a little bit
of an early Christmas present last year
in March the NSA open source deidre
which is a open source completely free
full-featured reverse sound and now
reverse engineering platform for
software and to sum it up it's pretty
awesome
first of all it's written in Java and C
Plus this the B compiler is the one part
that's really written in C++ the most of
the rest the user interface is written
in Java at its core it's a disassembler
and AD compiler it supports 15 different
architectures that's not if you include
variants like 32 64 bit 15 different
types of architectures and we're going
to talk a little bit why that's so easy
indeed draw a few slides in a few slides
and on top of that it's also got a
pretty robust set of analysis
capabilities we can do things like
detection functions in binary code we
can do control and data flow analysis we
can tell what functions are accessing
what variables what focus functions are
calling other functions things like that
which are really useful during their
verse engineering process and they're
pretty critical to what we do it also
does metadata metadata analysis as part
of the analysis process it does all the
things like parsing de binary headers to
figure out a lot of different de that we
can use to determine whether something
is malicious or not and it also has and
I have to admit I haven't experimented
too much with this but it also has
ability to function fingerprinting can
take known signatures of known code
blocks for example binaries from a
certain library and it can take a
executable you put into it and they can
identify okay this is something from I
don't know boost which is a library you
know commonly use it has a bunch of
different tools to supplement standard
libraries on Windows or Linux and that's
kind of like I guess I just flare it so
it's kind of a counterpart to that and
this is one of the really cool things it
also has a pretty in-depth data type and
function database has pretty much all
the different windows API functions that
you might use if you're doing a
low-level Windows programming it's got
them in there it has their names what
kind of types they pass much like
structures that you would use if you're
a C programmer and it can annotate the D
compiler output with a lot of this cool
stuff so as far as features that really
set it apart I think the first one I'm
going to talk about is how it does
analysis of code a lot of pieces of
software that do this
all kind of as one big monolithic
process but Peter takes a slightly
different approach it's completely
modular when when you start with a
binary it's first you start with machine
code which is x86 machine code that will
interpret and instead parses this into
what's called P code this is a
architecture agnostic language kind of
akin to what a compiler would use for
those you work with compiler internals
it's really a register transfer language
and basically this allows us to totally
separate the CPU architecture from
what's happening within the actual CPU
State this is part of the reason why we
have fit for 15 different architectures
because we can just add a new
architecture by basically creating a
configuration file that defines how each
CPU instruction changes the CPU State
and then once we got this P code we can
then go from there and do analysis that
allows us to generate pseudocode not
actual like a level above assembler
which is makes the whole analysis
process trying to figure out what's
going on a lot easier and on top of all
this we have a Java API which is perhaps
the coolest part now I know I adapt for
example has their Python by libraries or
C++ cool part about this is it's on one
level above what you see in other pieces
of software we have the ability in the
gauge or API to work at the level of
okay I want to look at a certain
function and that data once the analysis
is once we've gone through this analysis
process can be exposed and we can take a
look at what's going on do some kind of
whatever kind of analysis you want and
then annotate your disassembly or
decompiler output to show you what you
found or edit it or add comments stuff
like that so it's super powerful just
give you an idea what it looks like this
is an example of a couple functions I
pulled out of to get your API this is at
the Java level there's also a Python
interpreter which I'll talk to you a
little bit more in a little bit just for
example here let me see if I can pull
this I'll do without a pointer
there's this is kind of the kind of
things you'd be interacting with for
example it has an object a class a Java
class for a function this is a piece of
something that you would call for
example use an example a Windows library
function load library for example that
would be something that would you might
bill timed and something like this you
can for example look at the parameters
it takes you can look at what functions
call it what functions it calls we can
even interact with the output of the
analysis and put a comment there to say
ok something else is going on here and
we kind of do that whatever you want and
for example in a CPU instruction at a
lower level we can you know get its
address where is it in memory we can
figure out what instruction is next for
example if you have a bunch of data
that's in between two instructions it'll
automatically skip all that and go right
to the next one and like for example if
an instruction takes data as input we
can see there's a get it get input
objects for example how many of you guys
work with x86 on a regular basis
assembly look at it
ok good number them one there's an
instruction called a push instruction
which is used to put data onto the stack
and generally what you do is you have
push and then the name of a CPU register
and using this get input objects we can
figure out what register that is and in
some cases even figure out what its
value is and then there's also get
results object which basically tells you
what that instruction changes now to
interact with this API you can basically
write scripts either in Java or in
Python using JSON which basically
integrates with Java bytecode
any Java library it can call it as if
it's built-in you can see here from the
screenshot I don't know if you can see
there's out of the box there's more than
200 different scripts that the NS a
included in here these vary from
actually useful tools to just kind of
examples to get you started on your own
project and normally what you do you can
edit it directly in a piece of software
or you can do it in equation of the
clips so you can actually connect the
two and be editing your script in
eclipse and have it go back
or Theodora which is super useful or you
can just write it in the your own text
editor if you want to now to run one of
these you can also see that there's a
column there that's mostly empty you can
actually take get your scripts and bind
them right in there you can bind them to
keyboard shortcuts so if you have
something that using a bunch you can put
in the keyboard shortcut you want to use
and from then on you can launch that
script just by putting it that keyboard
shortcut so it's pretty powerful and it
also has I might add a if you're doing
this and you don't want to actually
write the script out there's also a
full-on Python interpreter as well they
can use it to interact with the analysis
and results yeah it's pretty much access
to it you can do it in the user
interface you can do it in a script
which is pretty awesome all right so now
we talked a little bit on goodra and its
features I'm getting into talking about
spy I this is give me the subject of our
case study really for those of you who
don't know what it is it is a piece of
banking malware that originated in
Russia and I think was around 2009 is
when I was first discovered has a lot of
cool features if you're a cyber criminal
I could do things like steal people's
passwords it had a key logger in it it
could steal inputs from web browsers it
would actually interact directly with
Internet Explorer and inject code into
your webpages so that I could steal your
banking information right off of it it
should be it's detected and should be
detected and pretty much any endpoint
solution nowadays since it's pretty well
known and well studied but it's a cool
that's actually if you're learning want
to get into malware analysis and reverse
engineering it's actually a great place
to start because it has a lot of these
cool reverse engineering or anti reverse
engineering techniques kind of
obfuscation z' that are pretty common in
the malware world but not enough to the
point where it's really a pain in the
butt to take it apart it's just it's I
would like to say it's interesting but
not too interesting so now I got this
binary I'm gonna start and start into
this reverse analysis process the first
thing I'm gonna look at is look at how
it interacts with the Windows system
this is kind of the key if we can figure
out how a binary interacts with Windows
we've solved half of the problem because
we don't have to reverse
the window stuff we know what its gonna
do because there's documentation so at
that point we're gonna look at the first
thing we do is look at the binary it's
got some interesting data in there a
second that get your parses out and one
of things is import tables for those of
you who deal with Windows internals this
is a list of libraries and functions
that a binary needs to you needs to use
because Windows is changing its
libraries all the time and changing the
functions and how they're implemented
where they're gonna be in memory changes
all changes a lot so it could be one one
time you run it if you run it two months
later it could be totally different
place so that guy sends the whole thing
of dynamic library loading and the way
Windows deals with this is it uses
function import tables get your policies
out and we'll tell you what Windows
functions a binary will use I've got
this as an example I've got a legitimate
executable this is actually process
Explorer it's its internals tool and I
can see if I can see pull this up here a
second I could pull it my mouth so I can
point it could you guys see that okay so
we can see that there's a bunch of
different functions close handle create
thread and create process a bunch of
different stuff that it wants to use
this is really powerful losses and
analysts we can tell a little bit about
what process Explorer is trying to do
now process Explorer is I guess a fairly
good example because it tries to do a
lot of stuff it's pretty tightly it does
a lot of interaction with Windows so we
can see there's a lot of different
functions this is just one out of four
or five different libraries that it
tries to use and get draw it does a lot
of cool stuff with this information if
we pull up the D compiler which is one
level above the disassembly at the
pseudo code we can see that it actually
annotates any time we try to use for
example in this a leave critical section
that's in the import table it can
identify that okay this isn't called
leave critical section it renames it in
the decompiler just super useful this is
pretty close to what you'd see in NHD
program and I don't if you can also see
it but it also is able to interpret data
types so for example leaf critical
section I'll go over the mouse you can
see that the first thing in the Windows
documentation the first argument that it
takes is of type LP critical section
this is the Windows API structure and
Diedre has
I basically said oh yeah that must
variable then must be this you can kind
of see it's a little bit lost over here
on the side you can see that variable is
a LP critical section structure and it's
able to put that in as an extra
information now it's a little bit
different if we look at that spy I this
is what we get keep in mind I said
earlier it does a lot of stuff it can
interact with Internet Explorer it is
able to do key logging a lot of things
that it does interact with Windows but
if we look at the list of functions that
it imports pretty sure something's going
on here so just to give you an example
what that this kind of does both in the
D compiler and to the person breeze
reverse engineering it it's not quite as
useful we can see here that all these
functions that we have are just text and
SML values they're used by addres to
tell which functions which they're
basically you have the fu n tells you
that it's a function and the other
digits are where it is in memory so we
got to figure out what's going on here
all right so next step is to talk I want
to take a little quick detour to go a
little bit more detail about how import
Able's work because it's useful I've
gotten here is just an example kind of
what we're dealing with here we've got I
kind of like to think of it like a menu
at a restaurant we've got a list here
this piece of software has a list
hypothetically of software of libraries
and functions it wants to use it doesn't
know where they are what before it
starts so windows when it's launching an
application will take a look at all
these it will load each of those
libraries in this case it was load win32
dll and it'll load when I net dll into
memory and then it will go through and
say okay where are each of these located
so it'll say ok where's file create a
whereas virtual protect and it'll fill
in those addresses so now we know that
where all the addresses are in memory
whatever application has this import
table can say ok we've got all these
different things we can then access the
function so whenever you want to call go
create file a it goes ok we need to go
to then use this function at 7f f
four zeros are eight so something's
going on here move to further on in the
reverse engineering process we're
looking at a little bit of function and
there's something interesting going on
here anybody recognize what that well
this is happening here it's those two
highlighted functions I have so we can
see there's this the first highlighted
line we can see that PC bar one is you
can see that there's a code a pointer to
code for those of you C programmers
basically what's happening here is the
result of this function that's being
called that function 200 400 400 to 0-8
6 is returning some kind of address of
some function in memory is the key part
of what gage is doing it was able to
tell based on the fact that this PC var
1 was used to call a function it knows
there's a function there and then it can
go through and say ok we need to analyze
this like it's code and then later on we
take the result whatever address is
returned from this weird function we
don't know what it does and we call it
with the arguments that are passed so as
reverse engineer from a Windows
perspective we say ok this is doing some
kind of function lookup and if we take a
look at that first function a little bit
deeper we go look at it in the be
compiler we see some interesting text
anybody want to Windows libraries hmm
we might be getting a little bit closer
to what we're looking for this is a big
hint here it's trying to load these
basically what if you go look at this
function it's loading these things in
the memory and doing some other stuff
which I'll get to in a second so we know
we're at least getting a little bit
closer to the right track and if you
look at these this is the
cross-references this is the where this
thing is used this function that we
don't know what it does yet we can see
that it's used in a lot of different
places in this case 9 that tells us that
this is kind of a framework thing it's
using a bunch of different places it's
probably pretty integral to how it works
so I'm gonna skip over a little bit here
now that we kind of got that framed if
we've gotten this far we know where this
is function is probably doing its
function lookups getting the addresses
of all these windows API functions that
it wants to use I'm just gonna go right
to kind of how SpyEye does its its
function lookups and replaces this
window function out windows
functionality i talked about earlier so
basically what it rolls down boils down
to is when it was being developed what
the SpyEye authors did is they took
every single function name for Windows
normally these appear in the binary you
can actually just basically look at it
in a hex or text editor and all those
functions that we saw in the function
import table will show up so as an
analyst I can take a look at it and say
ok yeah this is using this one I don't
even have to decompile it so that's even
starting out that's pretty useful but
what SpyEye does is it hashes all these
ahead of time so instead of seeing all
these strings you see some if you leave
and if you look at the D compilation you
see a hex hexadecimal number I actually
forgot to mention it but you can
actually see this hash right here
there's this 32-bit number this is the
hash that you use is some string that's
been hashed we're going to reverse that
a second so what it does is the instead
of using Windows spy I loads these
libraries into memory itself so it uses
an undocumented function to do this
which actually bypasses or at least at
the time we'd bypass a lot and a virus
checks and basically it goes through
each each exported function in the
library for example if we're
kernel32.dll we'll go through each of
them and usually these functional cups
are done by names so those not names are
included in the binary and it goes
through each one one by one and you've
already you've supplied this lookup
function 32-bit hashes you want to see
it goes through and checks and hashes
each export and function in this library
and sees what it's matched what you've
asked for
and if it does it then okay figures out
what the address is of this function and
returns it basically for in Windows
terms it's get praça address if you if
then you do payload development stuff
like that but it's
a lot of stealthier doesn't show up in
the binary itself and going a little bit
further down this path eventually come
to this hashing function which is going
to be the key to this whole process
going on later on so what it is it's
actually pretty simple it's just takes
those strings does a little bit of bit
shifting and exclusive warring it's up
here and see if you're interested in see
what it does
and from those strings that generates a
pseudo-random not really but value
32-bit value that it uses to identify
this function just an example if you run
this get hash function on load library a
it's going to generate 0 XC 8 AC 802 6
so if you if this malware wants to call
it will library a you're gonna see
instead of load library a you're gonna
see that value so next step how do we go
this we know we have a pretty easy to
get a list of all the windows api
functions that exists you can look it up
line
there's tons of lists of them and we
have we know the encryption function
what you do with passwords when you got
this you generate a rainbow table now
it's a little bit interesting because
the number of different possible values
is a lot smaller just based on the
libraries that SpyEye uses there were
only I think 8,000 well it's still a lot
but there were 8,000 values so this is
something that normally you know take
you hours to generate on a GPU for
passwords but since it's enough it's a
small enough data set here it's actually
pretty quick we can generate it on the
fly whenever we use the function that
we're gonna develop earlier so the next
step of course is to write some code to
generate this rainbow tables and when I
was doing this analysis initially I just
basically wrote it and see because that
was what I was comfortable with for
doing bitwise arithmetic which you can
see is used in the function and just to
show you what this does we tested it out
just to see if this matches up kind of
makes sense so we take the 32 bit value
I have in this code we had from the
earlier screenshot and I have developed
here you can see in the command I have
ahead of time I've got a list where's my
bell stairs of kernel32 functions I just
picked one so actually I forgot to
mention earlier but this zero in this
lookup function that's why I have tells
what library it's fun it's just if it's
zero it's in this library if it's one
it's in another and in this case it's in
kernel32.dll and ahead of time i
generate i had basically scraped off the
internet scraped a bunch of the list of
functions of this library you could
actually if you wanted to use goodra to
generate that list as well by going
right through the actual binary headers
but so we got this list i then basically
do some text processing to generate all
these hashes for all those functions and
basically create a mapping between those
32 values and the names so was that and
then i can just use grep to figure out
okay this nine seven six a nine seven
nine a is it in that file
sure enough shows up we can see that it
says the numerate time format so that's
windows function so we know that when in
this particular case what it's trying to
do is trying to call the numerate time
functions there are two numerate time
formats sorry so we've got a pretty
solid process here we've can go and we
can take any one of these functions take
that value and go look it up and figure
out what is actually trying to do but it
still it still addresses one problem we
saw that earlier that it was used in
nine different places there actually if
you go and look at it there's a couple
different lookups at a dozen slightly
different ways I haven't quite gone into
the deep enough thing to get make sure I
had all them but that still represents a
lot of tedious work of knowing okay
here's the value we're talking about a
program that may have hundreds of
thousands of instructions it still pain
in the butt to go do that so we need to
automate this so all right let's see all
right so we're going to develop an
algorithm about this I want to preface
this by when you're doing this kind of
process we don't really have to think
about this as being kind of interactive
programming I don't know how many of you
guys have had a chance to work with a
system like our for data analysis or
Python like interactively an interpreter
but one of the key things is when you're
working on this it's important to
remember that what you're doing here
doesn't have to be pretty it doesn't
even have to be efficient it just has to
work and usually when you're doing this
kind of stuff it's on some kind of time
frame so it's important not to get too
picky about pro-quality you just need to
make it work and it's even doubly so
with malware because whenever you
develop for spy I if I go and go down
and I'll say working on configure it to
be totally different I have to do
something totally different so you got
really gotta treat this as okay I'm
doing analysis and I need to use this to
support manual review of the code this
just basically takes the steps that we
would do we could do manually and just
makes the computer even alright so
talking about what we're gonna do here
what we're gonna do here we're gonna
take advantage of Windows calling
conventions for those of you don't know
when we saw the function with all the
parameters when there when a function is
called all of its arguments that you
want to pass in this function are pushed
on to the stack in Reverse so we had
argument one two and three what would
happen is that in the instructions we
would see three push instructions we
push the third argument we push the
second one we push the first one on the
stack and then there's a call which
actually moves the program counter to
the routine now we can take advantage of
this when we're going through once we've
done the analysis and gidran it
generates our disassembly and decompiler
we can just basically use those push
instructions to find those values so we
do we've generated we generate our
rainbow tables ahead of time it only
takes takes less than a second so we can
actually just do this whenever we're on
the script and then we sweep once we got
those look-up tables the rainbow tables
generated we can just go through the
store library or the entire binary
starting at the beginning and just look
for every push instruction ginger has a
function to do this I'll show it to you
in a second when I pull up some source
code of the script I've got and we take
a look at it and say okay is it 32-bit
is it pulling pushing a number and if
it's pushing a number we then okay we'll
say okay is it in our function lookup or
in our lookup database and if it is we
basically add a comment in the
disassembly so we can see it later and
rename the function that the push
instruction is in because most of the
ways and I think I'm beginning to
question this assumption now
but I looked at a little bit closer I
think it's a little bit not quite right
but at this point what we're basically
the way I eye does it function look up
says it has a each each windows function
has its function that's my eyes
implemented so basically all that
function does is it uses spy eyes lookup
code to find the address of the windows
API function and calls it so if we if we
rename that external function that has a
lookup in it we can then just say okay
yeah that's essentially like the windows
API function we can move on from there
so I don't know if you guys can see this
okay cuz it's readable yeah questionable
okay I can actually try and let me see
if I can actually do a little bit of
that better let me try this one more
time
we'll start here nope that didn't work
at all how kind of did their so what
I've done here is I is not the entire
script I've just pulled out the parts I
don't I didn't include up here I didn't
include the the generation cone for the
rainbow tables cuz it's just reading
from a file and writing back to it but
what we here we can see that there's
this custom hash which I basically
taking what I've gotten from the binary
and ivory implemented in Python just the
same thing input and get the output I
just want to add at this I actually
meant to talk about this in earlier
slide one of the cool features that we
were talking about how features modular
one of the cool features that you can do
that would replace this is we can
actually because of this fact that we
can go from binary to P code to pseudo
code we can actually emulate the CPU
instruction by instruction for little
sections of code and we could just use
the binary code binary code that was
already in there to do this for us I
didn't do in here because I've only
haven't had much of a chance to play
with it yet but that's kind of one of
the next steps I'm gonna be talking
about later anyways we've got this
function to do that and let's go back
here alright that did not work anyways
that's gonna be little bit more
challenging at work what we do here I'll
pull my mouse first of all this is our
function we currently get the program
that's have active in the editor this is
just basically okay what are we working
on and we just do some a little bit of
setup and our first step is to get the
address of the first instruction in
memory this is the first thing that
successfully just assembled into a x86
instruction and we basically loop
through every instruction in the binary
against doesn't take long it takes maybe
five seconds to run and we first of all
check if it's if it's not a push
instruction we don't care about it we
can go we can continue on and we just
skip the next one and if it is push
instruction we want to get whatever is
being pushed onto the stack so we use I
talked about earlier we use get input
objects this basically says if it's a
register it'll tell you what the
register is if it's a constant value
you'll be able to see that cost
value and if it's if it's a scalar
number as in if it's an integer or a
float we then check about 32 bits and we
get its unsigned value after that's
pretty simple if it's if it's in the
function database that we've already
generated ahead of time we know that
it's a Windows API function that it's
probably trying to handle here and if it
is and it matches and it shows up we
basically take the name of the function
and annotate the source code you can see
there's a set common command this will
show up in the D compiler and the
disassembler and initially this was just
all I did it didn't do any renaming of
functions or whatnot but I added that a
couple days ago I added the renaming and
then finally we get we get the function
that the push instruction is inside
because it's generally one function
lookup and then you call it that's it
and we rename it all right
so the process actually from a for those
of you who are interested from user
interface standpoint we had that
function the script manager I showed you
earlier with the 200 scripts I've got
loaded in there I've got the spy search
spy which is the source code you saw
earlier in the previous slide
double-click it and we see some console
output and it tells you okay I found
that this address I found this windows
function things are going well and the
upper is pretty cool we can see it
before and after this is basically the
code segment we saw where we've been
kind of working on from the beginning
and we can see that there's a couple of
different changes here we can see that
the functions been renamed first of all
so we know that that function more or
less is an analogue for enumerate time
formats and there's actually one more
step you do you could a few buttons and
it also says okay I now know what kind
of arguments it takes so we know what
types there and you can also see that
it's renamed some variables as well
because this basically matches the
windows Doc's now and I think this is
this is one example but I think it's
more illustrative is when you have
functions that call this one because
those will look a lot different we can
see on the left this is before it
started this is another function within
the within SpyEye
because he's a lot different we can see
for example that a bunch of different
variables in this function which
previously were listed as undefined
which is basically deters way of saying
we don't know what this is we just know
it's 4 bytes or 32 bits and since we can
see that the windows functions that
spiah has tried to use have been labeled
and also the types that they take so we
know that since create mutex a will know
that none that lowest arrow since each
object right there is the result of a
call to create mutex a we know that it's
got a certain type based on the
specifications that windows have or that
Microsoft has released for this library
and we can see above in the variable
definitions that or I think it's in
there maybe it isn't that the types are
made to match you can see the wind bool
handle those are all just from what
Ghidorah knows about the windows api and
the fact that we've renamed all of our
functions to match it's pretty awesome
so next I wanna go take aways kind of
what I want you to go away
end up coming away with first of all
Deidre's api is super powerful
it's extendable you can write all this
stuff to it I mean literally what I've
showed you here just scratches the
surface I talked about its ability to
emulate code it's gonna make my life a
lot easier
once I figure it out and future features
are I'm gonna make it even better there
is talk that there is integration with
debugging debuggers in the future it's
been a little while since they said they
were going to do that but that's me
pretty awesome and it's still
time-consuming and tedious but this kind
of automation it's important to learn
how to do it as part when you're
learning how to be a reverse engineer
because without it your effectiveness is
pretty limited because it's just the
amount of time it's gonna take but I
think even with all these tools it's
also important to say that having an
underlying platform knowledge is still
critical to being a good reverse
engineer
along those lines if there's any CISOs
in the room I just want to say that I
cannot encourage you enough to get your
team members using a tool like this
there's no cost to you as far as money
it's open source and the skills that
they will learn if it's even if it's
taking something that's been detected by
an antivirus tool or something maybe
that isn't that kind of a suspicious but
didn't didn't rip any detections have
them take a look at it and learn about
it because the knowledge you'll gain
from that is pretty invaluable and if
you do use it contribute back to it
because the more people use it and
contribute and write code for it the
better it's going to be twitch is really
awesome and with that type of questions
before I just want to go into questions
I want to thank a couple people calling
Coolidge from segment for being
providing invaluable advice from all
this presentation is in the works and
especially my team at coal fire federal
for also providing and put it on as well
all right with that let's get into
questions here for a second I will pull
them up does anybody got from the
audience before I Benny are they in here
yes
ah okay awesome so yes he asked what the
process is for working with a team on a
single Gator process your project is
actually an interesting question because
one of the features that get your has is
actually has the ability to do
collaboration at this point it's kind of
basic so there's a server application
that you can put on a server it can be
on your local laptop it can be on a VPS
somewhere and then that server setup you
add Billy add users to that and then you
as part of the project creation process
you just see that basically they say
okay I want this to be a shared project
say okay the server is hosted here it
goes and it does all stuff I will say
that its features are good but what I
was kind of expecting and what it was
hoping would be was not quite match that
it's a little bit at this point it's a
little bit closer to being a version
control system really tailor taking what
Guidry does its features are you know
check in and check out get code but it
may change at that time you know more
people may develop those kind of
solutions which would be really cool to
see the ability to do like Google Docs
style of reverse analysis reverse
engineering be awesome I don't think
it's there yet but I'm hoping it gets
there at some point any other ones as
far as versus Ida Pro I haven't had a
ton of time to compare the two directly
there's some things and this may be a
matter of matter of perfect that by the
way he asked how does it compare to Ida
Pro as far as in this maybe it matters
of personal preference there's some
things that I like about goodra and how
it lays things out and does certain
analyses that I really prefer I would
say that having in the what direct
comparison I had done it is pretty close
to being the same I haven't been able to
get like a lot of the we talked about
datatypes and windows and be able to
detect those and annotate those I
haven't really been able to get Ida to
do that quite as much I think it may
change a lot if you get hex raised the
decompiler I currently don't have a
license for that right now because
goodra has worked pretty well for me so
far so there's really been a need but I
think it's pretty close
I haven't looked at far as much as far
as performance the decompile ourself
incident C++ so it's not terrible it's
pretty good and so at some point I'll
get to comparing those but it's been
that's it for someone who's getting into
the getting into it it's amazing I think
it's very very near parity even the fact
that you have as many support for many
architectures if you were to buy Ida
with this many architectures and you're
getting close to you know tens of that
well easily tens of thousands maybe
hundreds of thousands of dollars to get
all those so almost the same and I think
a lot of that again personal preference
but it's pretty pretty darn close yeah
yes so the question that was asked was a
what libraries are there any libraries
available as far as skeeter scripting
it's an interesting question one of the
struggles I've had in going through
Gager and learning over the past you
know almost a year is that the
documentation is kind of there but at
really at some point you end up coming
down to the point where you have to read
the Java Docs which they are and they're
very good because Java Doc's are and
that's one of the awesome features of
Java and I will say that as far as
libraries I'm haven't seen any external
ones yet and may just not have seen them
I say in a lot of cases I would question
the ability often when I'm dealing with
the kind of things I might take a script
like that and there's little teeny
things that I wanted to do but it
doesn't quite do so my dinner and my
approach has been take the features
engage your API apply them specifically
to the piece of the sample that I'm
analyzing and then when I go to another
sample you do that process again there
are places where you can generalize some
of that but I at least at this point I
haven't really develop scripts that work
on everything and I think it approaches
to expression in these cases develop for
the software that you're bigger
analyzing you can do it on the fly it
does that be pretty like I said
but as far as libraries I haven't seen
anything out there there is a big list
here
Paulette scripts and I had a chance to
play with but I haven't seen anything
other than that out there you just yet
one more from the audience if there
isn't and I'll go to the slides slide oh
let me see a close-up okay let something
final zero want okay
I know if you have slight Oh up if you
and be able to see my phone might not be
working but yes you able to see
questions yeah yep so a gentleman over
here asked whether we've encountered in
situations where there's been collisions
as far as the hashtag algorithms and I
think this is actually an important
question I wish I had covered look I
probably should cover a little bit more
but in this case there is the potential
for there to be collisions I think since
the amount of data that you're working
with
okay there's eight thousand two billion
possible hash values and eight thousand
instructions the chances of that are
going to be pretty low and it's
something to keep in mind in this case
there was I had a very there was a very
uh in my case it was a very conscious
decision to avoid trying to be too
specific because in this particular case
if I get a pulse false positive it is in
the end of the world I at some point
it's gonna come up and I'm like this
doesn't seem right and I'll see that and
I'll say okay yeah that's some weird
edge case it's more important for me in
this state since there's since spy I
doesn't weigh there's multiple did ways
of doing the same thing to some degree
it's more important that I get all get
all of those or close to all of them so
in this particular I wrote that script
with that in mind which doesn't take
into account collisions or you know
pushing on some value the stack that
happens to be some hash of some windows
function so it's something you should
keep in mind when you're working with
these but in this particular case I
haven't seen anything yet
all right any from the room since
there's not on there yes okay I don't
want ask as far as fingerprinting is
there a global database for like what we
say with flair there are databases
available on github I think there what
I've seen and I may have forgetting
something I've seen in the past there
are the FI DB function and it's the
function ID is the function that is the
functionality what they call in deidre
there are databases available for some
libraries and here's one for boost and a
lot of like the general Lib C libraries
in Linux I haven't really seen one too
much for Windows more the analysis that
I've seen done so far has come from
pulling out the imports and I will say
that in my experimentation with the
function ID so far I haven't had a ton
of luck and getting it to detect with
the databases I've had and so I don't a
really good picture of how it works yet
but there are databases there is there
one that's comprehensive I haven't seen
one yet there are combinations of
smaller ones that are specific to
certain libraries but I guess that is
that answer your question okay
yeah they're out there I can think of
one I can come after I can probably pull
up the one that I have but as far as
Windows I'd have to look somewhere to
find it any others all right well thank
you guys so much come out I'll put my
contact info we'll be up here for a
second ironed out rows on coal fire comm
that'll work
or I do have a Twitter account it's kind
of a ghost town right now I don't really
use them much but I'll keep an eye out
and then over the next few weeks I'm at
some point I'm hoping I need to talk
with people at coal fire to make sure it
and just make sure everything's in line
but I'm gonna try to take the Python
script and put it up somewhere that'll
probably be through their online
presence all right thank you
you