due to technical difficulties a portion
of this presentation was not recorded we
are joining the program already in
progress
alright oh okay
the tactics essentially are a goal of
the attacker like based on the step of
the acute saying the attacker is the
goal might be the initial axis right or
the goal might be to establish
persistence and then the drop down is a
specific technique being used for that
particular attack so actually this is
pretty recent we didn't have a cloud
matrix as before October but October as
you see over ninth this year might have
actually published this it's a really
good start and I really want to actually
contribute to build it more so jamming
writing the code that you see with p1 1
9 0 or the T 1 1 1 1 3 3 6 is
essentially the reference code to the
attack matrix to be attack matrix and is
a we're gonna go through it and I'm
gonna give you some of the attacks that
we see based on the the tactic and then
a specific technique the specific
technique is gonna be the specific
reference code that you see so for
initial axis I mean the first thing that
you're gonna seen in in an attack it's
gonna be initial axis right how they're
gonna get in and what happens actually
is that even though we might have the
best tools in a cloud security to
protect our environment we're still
gonna have issues on a horse Bay on the
host level so you're gonna see all the
time are you're gonna see our CSS
arrives you name it anything that you
can get a code execution or a command
line execution on a server can actually
give you the initial foothold in the AWS
account and how you do that
actually such there's a new feature now
for my W is that might that tries to
stop that but right now it's a little
bit slow in adoption and most of the
people still use the version 1 of the
metadata service and essentially if you
can get a chimeric security on
serve on a wet on an on a public-facing
application then you can request the
credentials the secure AWS security
credentials for this particular account
next we have a technique with through
valid accounts which can be for example
if you there are the having cases of
people having exposed credentials over
AWS in github repos or other places and
then attack you can just grab these and
just go in like a valid user then I have
so the next up I have here it's based on
the attack metrics framework it's
persistence but I'm gonna skip it and
I'm gonna come back to it because what I
think is the next phase of the attack
kill chain is discovery or
reconnaissance you call it what you say
what do you want to call it
because right after when we see an
attacker gaining credential access to
our it'll use environment the next thing
that we're gonna see is he more hair try
to do discover in our environment try to
release trolls try to see the specific
role that they got what access they have
because they don't know usually if it
has got some AWS credentials and they
try to figure out what can I do with
this right they're not really sure what
to do with this they're gonna do the
account discovery the permissions group
discovery and we map all of these in
different techniques and you're gonna
see why this important on the next
session with discovery so next after
discovery we have persistence and then
what if you get access to an account
that essentially you want to get
different ways that you can access again
or continue your access right you can
create new accounts if you have the
permissions you can attach existing
policies and something are really cool
also is that if you have the permissions
to make changes to security groups you
can essentially open up a specific port
for you to open to get to access through
you're attacking machine then the
defensive vision I don't have a specific
technique attached here because there
was not one already in the matrix
framework that they that matter have
published and I'm planning actually to
see how can I contribute to it to add
this so if the attacker has the
permissions and if there
good at what they do they're gonna
essentially stop try to stop logging and
stop the security services like they're
gonna stop cloud so we're gonna see what
cultural ease right after they're gonna
start guard duty if you have it because
they don't want us to catch them and the
last one cadet Alexis were here this SSL
it goes maps back to the initial axis
and it's the way how they're gonna get
the metadata API to get the credentials
brilliance creation essentially overlaps
a little bit with persistence it's a
little bit about the same techniques but
I'm gonna go more about it on the
detection side we talked about discovery
and lastly detection last but not least
right because this can be essentially
the goals of the attacker I mean they
can have other goals as well like an I
don't know potentially have want to
establish it to to have a crypto mining
service and your AWS account and cost
you a lot of money but something that we
look for is if they if the attacker can
get access to a role that has access to
our confidential s3 buckets for example
let's say they might try to get those
files exfiltrate those files and we're
gonna see how we can catch that actually
so cloud shell I cannot see everybody
but please can you tell me if you are
familiar with cloud shell and what it is
all right so it's like 3/4 of the room
really quickly
essentially cloud trail is the service
that records all the API calls and AWS
actions in AWS it's gonna record
everything that happens on the API level
and essentially that's everything that
happens in AWS everything all the
different services connect with each
other through API calls and all of that
is logged in cloud trail so it's really
it's our holy grail of artifacts you
want to say logs you want to call it
whatever you want to call it is really
important for us defenders to understand
how cloud what cloud chilis and addition
the scheme of it so we can put
detections we're gonna see right after
so here is what it looks like
essentially in the beginning we have the
user identity which essentially the
entity that performs any action then we
have additional information about the
event like this is from
initiative in from basic to service and
the event name are you see over here let
me see the event name essentially says
what was the action that happened right
then really important to make
attribution is the user agent and the
source IP address believe me I've been
able to actually find like specific
activity and attributed back to some pen
testers through just unique user agent
you were just that simple it's really
some people may say that I don't want to
look for user agents it's like really
neat like something old we look at all
in the old days but it's really
important to make attribution here and
then lastly really important you have
the request and response elements so
it's the request parameters and response
elements or I don't have it here in
detail essentially the request
parameters she's gonna have all the
information that your request is asking
the service to do and for example if you
would change the security group you
would have the changes of a security
group that you request like open up port
80 and then in the response elements
you're gonna have every time if there
was a change that was successful you're
gonna have that on the response elements
all the time so now let's jump right
into the detection saying I think I have
ok time so for the initial axis I so let
me explain that I have on red I have the
event names that you need to look for in
cloud trail that have high fidelity and
really really good signal so for example
on this first slide I told you in the
beginning that an attacker can get the
credentials through through the metadata
service if you they get access to your
instance right but what do they get they
get the STS simple token service keys
which are like 1 to 6 hours usually they
and then they refresh and they're gonna
get these keys but what happens and
actually this is a really good paper
from Netflix I have a reference at the
end that they describe this technique in
detail they don't give you as I'll give
you over here the query exactly but they
describe it so much in detail that you
can build your own data analysis and
query to hunt for that essentially what
happens
that whenever you get a creation of
these credentials you're gonna have a
cloud Sherlock with an adventurous STS
and then an event named assume role
that's gonna come only from the ec2
instance that requires these credentials
and the thing that is really important
is that these credentials are only
supposed to be used by Verity to
instance they're not supposed to be used
by anything else so then whenever
bespoke sorry let me go back whenever
these keys are being used you're gonna
see a cloud show log with a user
identity that type assumed role like let
me go back right over here and the user
identity type assumed role now if we see
that from very c2 instance that is
normal right but if we see that through
any other resource like a really good
signal would be external IP but even
even through like within a it obvious
because they may like it might be using
any c2 instance then that is a really
good detection for you guys I'm telling
you and you can go up and read a Netflix
paper or have more time to discuss about
it it's really you can build a really
high fidelity detection then on the
persistence side of things on the create
account and occur manipulation something
that has a really good signal is the
create user because from what I've seen
it doesn't happen too often and the rest
add user to group and create access key
they have a little bit more noise but if
you if you can hand for these and like
let's say look for unique IPS or
abnormal user agents that you don't see
in your environment that is also a
really good signal next for persistence
again I discussed before about how
someone can make changes to the security
group or the ingress or the egrets and
essentially you would hunt for these
looking for adventures easy to do easy
to service and then authorize security
group ingress then one of the best ways
to hunt for and put detections for an
attack in your environment is when they
are on the privilege escalation phase
because most of the time they're going
to
I mean and they're gonna get access to
it like probably a low-level account
hopefully so they're gonna try to get
higher privileges so the ones that I
have here in black the event names are a
little bit noisy but if you see a
attachable policy or as usual policy
with on the right over here oh is that
on the right with administrator access
well then that's something that you need
to look for like your user shouldn't be
attaching to this policy normally then
something really cool that I found out
actually this past month is this thing
over here so said people policy version
what happens here is that if you create
a policy for your role or your instance
and you create multiple versions of that
and let's say sometime during your
development phase you're devs
wanted to get admin access because they
couldn't figure out what access they
needed to create something then that's a
version stored for that and if they
attacker if the role that the attacker
got access has the permissions to change
the default policy version they can roll
it back to the administrator access
policy that you that your developer
thought that had deleted in the past so
this is really important to look for
this this has really good signal really
good signal moving on so on the
discovery phase in general
reconnaissance this is these are really
noisy but again if you see any like an
assumed reduction that we discussed
before from an external IP or an
abnormal IP and right after you see
discovery artifacts then this is 100% an
attacker or a pen tester or your red
team someone that is trying to do
something bad I wouldn't expect to see
assumed role from a new IP the rather in
relation to instance and in discovery
like listing roles we generating reports
about credentials I wouldn't expect that
to see as a normal use case at all
whatsoever and then last over here
as general detections what a really good
thing is that if you have specific roles
or users or go
that should always be going through your
single sign-on to go to AWS and using
multi-factor authentication then you can
look for this tag there's a tag MFA
authenticated and if it's false but it
shouldn't be false then in social
another red flag and then something
really important is to look for the
error code because any of although
they've been names that I already showed
you that have access denied' of an
author unauthorized operation and failed
access that should also be something to
investigate I mean it happens especially
in the discovery it happens from
developers but with some data analyses
you can really easily clear those the
cases that are normal for your day to
day out and lastly we have the defense
evasion which is actually something with
really high fidelity if you see and act
like someone trying to stop your cloud
real logs why they're doing that even
more if they delete your trail then if
you have got duty which is actually
really awesome in the beginning I didn't
thought I would like it but I like while
being using it and seeing the alerts
that they deny rate that thing is pretty
cool because it actually detects all the
behavioral stuff based on what I already
showed you on the specific techniques
they try to determine if there is a
different behavior and those techniques
from a particular resource so if someone
tries to stop that from monitoring why
they would do that this is really good -
deleted detections that you can pull
right away in your ALW environment so in
the last one is collection and something
I want to mention here is that when you
when you get object level logging
because you need to have object level
logging in the cloud trail to series
this I'm not really a big fan of the
server access lodging because it doesn't
give you the video that I want on cloud
trail and you can look for let's say
that an attacker is already downloading
something you can look for the eventual
size 3 event name get object and then
request parameters you're gonna have the
file names download it so you can see
any of your confidential files secret
files for downloaded or also in the
additional event data you're gonna see
the total amount of data X which a so
you can see like if you were success
not because right when we do IR or
forensics we need to report what was
stolen right is one of the major
questions of our process so this is
gonna help you a lot of figuring out oh
okay they got access here but we're able
to download anything if I see zero one
additional I've been dead or maybe they
filled that I'm good maybe
I'm sorry that I'm running because I
just have another five minutes I'm gonna
go over here I was gonna put that whole
scenario into place but I'm gonna keep
on skipping this because I don't have
time and I want to jump right in to
operationalise detections so okay really
quickly I showed you some examples of
what to look for for the specific on the
specific technique and tactic to find an
attacker in your environment now in
order to start thinking about how to
operationalize and put it on your soak
in your incident response team the first
thing that you need to do with
centralized aw looks you shouldn't have
them in the different accounts that you
have in your environment you should send
it to your own security account and if
that difficult I'm going to tell you we
have at version media we have about more
than 1,000 AK a unique AWS accounts and
we send them all all the clouds we logs
to a specific account that we the
security team have access to and we can
secure these logs then choose you to sit
right there are some amazing open source
tools like stream alert from Airbnb or I
found another one that I haven't Alice
on the reference and you went from
endgame that you can essentially
streamline your cloud trail logs put
rules and detections with lambda
functions essentially they tell you how
this would work it will be that you
would have a lambda function logic and
your cloud tree logs and based on some
rules you generate alerts and then you
can either send it I can email it to
your distro or send it to a slack board
or to your Splunk or whatever you want
to send it to and create detections that
way then of course you realize the
attack framework to build the detections
because it's really easy to build a
really good picture of the whole attack
rather than just having directions here
and there
the the attack matter framework helps
you a lot on figuring out what are your
gaps what can you take what do you have
defenses on and so on
and lastly yeah I start with the
workflow from the alert and action on
detection sieve you want to so here my
reference is I have the first one is on
the Netflix pay the Netflix paper about
the density they sell compromising it'll
yes I definitely recommend reading on
that if you want to build a really
amazing data analysis detection here
then Rhino labs does an amazing job on
posting a lot of really cool information
about AWS then we have the two open
source tools by Airbnb endgame similar
in varna now swim alert is a little bit
is amazing by it's a little bit
complicated you need someone to maintain
it I believe then varna from endgame
I've seen risk just recently it's a
little bit simpler does it do all the
things that try maletas but i think it's
really good to put what try one of these
and consider them for your sock and to
put detections and alerting if you don't
have a service like guard duty for my
double years that was it thank you have
any time for questions we have to meet
for questions yes so that's a great
question I'm gonna first of all I'm
gonna post the slides right after but
I'm planning to also publish a github
repo with sig Sigma rules that are going
to have all the techniques and then have
queries that you can put your own your
plan or your open source tool to a
personalizes yes dick about goose I have
it on the first you got yeah let me code
the first yeah please
I mean we have a pretty big team hey