hello good morning my name is Lu style
I'm here to introduce our next guest
speaker Colin O'Brien and he's gonna be
speaking of about graphic face detection
and response all right
hi everyone so as mentioned my name is
Colin O'Brien I'm gonna be talking about
project I've been working on for a
couple of years now called grapple so
grapple is a graph analytics platform
that really tries to target detection
response workloads so finding and
removing attackers from networks before
I get started talking about grapple I
want to give a little bit of context I
have been working in detection response
in some form of a nut or another for
about five years now my entire career
but I've had a lot of really different
jobs in that time I started off at
rapid7
I was hired by the insight IDR product
team so that's their detection response
service and my first job was basically
to embed myself onto a data science team
so I was going to be the sort of
security engineer for that team and they
asked me what I wanted to do and I
thought machine learning sounded cool so
they they gave me that job and what I
found was that we did very little
machine learning ultimately and really
we spent the vast majority of time
looking at broken or just garbage data
for whatever reason sources were out of
date data would age really poorly so
security data in particular just ages
really terribly because you might think
that it's Sarah you might think that
like a virus scan happened a week ago
and that data is different from a virus
gain happening a month ago or today so I
saw these security minded data
scientists digging into these massive
data sets and really managing to pull
tons of signal out of what looked like
the the worst kind of noise you could
imagine and I learned a lot about the
techniques that they leverage the tools
and the ways that they work together to
do this after about a year on that team
I started working on the IDR product
more directly so I worked on the
detection team building out attack
signatures for our numerous different
customers these attack signatures had to
you work across pretty much arbitrary
customer environments you can never
really predict your next customer is
gonna be they had to have low false
positives and they had to catch real
attackers I learned that the engineers
who are building these detection x'
leveraged code as their primary weapon
so all of the alert logic did the same
way that our service code or any other
code would have been checked in it would
have been code reviewed it would have
had unit tests the sort of latter part
of my time at rapid7
which was roughly two and a half years I
actually worked a lot on reliability
software engineering and building
services out and so at the end of that
time I decided that I wanted to get a
little more into detection response I
wanted to stop being sort of the ivory
tower vendor that looks down and hands
down detection x' and actually do the
job day to day so I left rapid7 I went
to Dropbox and for two years I was
working on their detection response team
so actually engaging with the red team
and triaging alerts day to day seeing
what sort of problems were being faced
and what was interesting is that it was
a lot of the same problems that I had
seen in that vendor space I saw security
experts being tasked with dealing with
what to me were data or engineering or
operations problems dealing with log
sources that were incorrect or that
weren't being parsed correctly dealing
with log volumes that they weren't
necessarily in the right position to
scale to and so I tried to help that
team out for about two years and a lot
of the lessons learned went into how
grapple works one of the big things that
makes crapple somewhat more interesting
than other products is that it is a
graph based system and so today I'm
going to talk about why I think that a
graph based approach is so important for
security in general but especially
detection response and hopefully you can
walk away with some understanding of why
that's the case okay so before I talk
about grapple I think it makes sense to
just go over what a graph is so graphs
are a data structure that comprised of
nodes and edges nodes are usually things
like entities or nouns right so a person
might be anode edges denote
relationships between those nodes graphs
are a really powerful and generalizable
data structure and I think one of the
easiest ways to demonstrate that is to
take a really basic graph like this
right there's almost no labels there's
no explicit data in a graph like this
but despite that fact I can say a lot of
things about this graph I can say that
the green node has a relationship with
the blue node the blue node has a
relationship with a purple node the
green node has a path to the purple node
with a length of 1 that crosses over
this blue node the reason why I can say
these things is because graphs have this
really powerful property of encoding
relationship information directly into
their structure this is why we see
graphs used a lot in visualization but
these relationship heavy workloads
actually come up all over the place so
as some examples Google search is
powered by their knowledge graph and
this is what allows them to instead of
taking just a plain text search approach
to a search engine start giving you
related information Facebook's graph API
underlies their entire public API you
can imagine why this would be useful you
might want to ask questions like given a
user on our platform who are their
friends what are the posts that they
like and then we can recommend those
posts to that initial user right this is
another very relationship heavy query
graphs are in some more niche areas so
graphs underlie machine learning
libraries like tensor flow tensor flows
an example of something called dataflow
programming where the computation that
you build in your tensor graph is
represented as a sort of graph traversal
and then graphs also tend to really just
emerge from systems without any purpose
right we end up building graphs without
really meaning to and an example of that
would be BGP and the internet right you
have all of these routers acting as
nodes with neighbors that they know how
to talk to and that's how packets
managed to get from one system to
another traversing this massive graph of
the internet a little closer to home in
the financial security space graphs have
been used to great effect for quite a
while now to detect thing
like credit card fraud or scam
businesses and they do this by querying
and building models on tops of on top of
these graphs to understand things like
commonality about locations that credit
cards are used which users have in the
past worked with a business and then why
is this new strange user talking to this
business and and they're sort of a
staple in that world at this point in
the information security world we're
starting to see graphs gain a lot more
traction unsurprisingly given all these
other communities that have been
leveraging them John Lambert at
Microsoft wrote a post a couple of years
ago about his opinions on graphs in
InfoSec and in this post he makes a
statement which many people may have
heard at this point he says defenders
think enlists attackers think in graphs
as long as this is true attackers win
and in this post that he creates
afterwards he talks about an example of
this list and graph based thinking John
talks about how when defenders are
tasked with protecting a network one of
the first things they'll do is start
creating lists they'll create lists of
privileged users like domain admins or
exposed services or high-risk assets
that contain maybe user data and they'll
start to prioritize the work that they
do based on those lists this is really
different from how attackers go about
doing their work attackers are going to
opportunistically land on some asset
they'll compromise whatever they can
probably something unprivileged and
exposed and they're gonna leverage the
capabilities that they gain from that
asset to start moving around your
network and this can range from things
like lateral phishing where an attacker
might compromise your co-workers email
and then they'll send you a PDF and say
like hey look this over and all of a
sudden they're they're taking over new
users and assets on other people's
computers across your network or as John
talks about using tools like proc dump
or meaty cats to dump credentials for
memory and start moving around laterally
and what the attacker is really doing
here is they're abusing trust
relationships right the attacker is
starting off on this network they don't
have these lists of users or assets
ahead of time
know these risk for prioritizing their
doing discovery they're moving across
the network in a very graph oriented way
at the end of his post John says managed
from reality because that is the
prepared defenders mindset and so I
think there's kind of a deeper meaning
here at least that's something that I
draw from this post which is not that
graphs are necessarily better than lists
or lists are better than graphs or
anything like that it's really that when
you have information that so clearly
maps to one model one data structure and
you force that information into some
other model you lose something
inherently right so when we as defenders
take graph information like a network or
like how an attacker behaves and we pull
that out and we force it into lists we
lose actually the most important thing
which is what the attackers are taking
advantage of those trust relationships
one tool that I think really
demonstrates a shift in approach is
bloodhound bloodhound is a tool that
both attackers and defenders can use and
I think that really goes to show that
it's sharing this common model
bloodhound allows you to query and
visualize Active Directory as if it were
a graph and from a defenders point of
view this is much closer to how
attackers are thinking about and taking
advantage of your systems and this
allows you to move away from asking
questions like who are my domain admins
and how do I protect them and instead
start asking questions like how would I
go from an unprivileged user to a domain
admin and start cutting off those paths
another tool that I think demonstrates
this in a different way is cloud mapper
this is built by duo and Scott Piper
cloud mapper is a tool that allows you
to visualize and graph out all of your
AWS resources and policies and this lets
you move away from thinking about
individual policies and how they might
have individual issues or they might
look fine when you're just glancing at
one of them but when you start to
combine them together the way an
attacker would as they chain attacks
across different assets in your
environments you can start to find
privilege escalations or leaks that you
didn't expect
so in the detection response world the
model and the primitive that we leverage
is the event and we do this by
collecting logs which are some sort of
representation of these events things
like process execution logs file
creation logs network instrumentation
that sort of thing what we do is we
collect billions of these every single
day and we store them in what is
effectively a massive index or a big
list called
a sim and we run queries against these
and we look at things like individual
events as they occur and we try to write
queries against them to find something
suspicious if we do find something
suspicious we go back to our sim we
write subsequent queries looking at more
logs the thing is that when you take
some of these logs down and you know
what you're looking for you can start to
see that there's actually a lot of
relationships hidden in between them a
process ID and one log might be a parent
process ID in another log file name
might be shared across them and when we
start to pull these relationships out
and make them more explicit I think that
we can start honing in on more complex
attacker behaviors rather than isolated
events as they occur across our
environment and so a grapple really
tries to demonstrate what we've just
seen it tries to demonstrate that when
we can move from thinking about logs as
our fundamental primitive and instead
more as a building block into an
abstraction that matches what attackers
are doing more closely we can be a lot
more effective as defenders so grapple
will ingest raw logs you can send it up
sis Mon or any other data type that it
supports it's gonna parse those into a
graph representation so a process
execution log might generate a graph
that has a parent node a child node and
an edge between them these graphs go
through an identification process I'll
talk a little bit more about this later
but essentially what this means is that
we don't want a million different nodes
representing the same entity right if we
have a thousand logs coming up about
chrome doing some action we really just
want one node for that chrome entity so
that's what identification is going to
do these identified graphs get merged
into grapples master graph so in real
time as these graphs are generated
they're getting
pinned up into this massive graph
database that's going to represent all
of the entities and behaviors occurring
across your environment and as this is
happening on every single updates this
master graph grapple will orchestrate
your attack signatures or what it calls
analyzers they're gonna look for
behaviors they're gonna look for
suspicious patterns and when they find
these patterns and you've deemed this a
risky enough situation to start
investigating you have a tool that's
really gonna exploit the ability for
graphs to pull in context quickly right
everything's joined together sort of
inherently and grapple calls that an
engagement and so I'm gonna talk about
how all of these things work both in
terms of a sort of generalized graph
based approach and then how grapple
implements it when I talk about the
master graph in grapple it's really what
you see here there's actually more nodes
than just what's here and there's also a
sort of plug in nodes you can add your
own models but nodes are pretty much
what you would expect they have
properties so a file has a path a
process has a process ID or process name
and then there are these special
properties the edges right so a process
has children process can create files
network connections will connect out to
their destinations so identity is really
important not just to grapple but in
general it's why tools like sis monde
try to package identities for things
like logins or processes as baked into
their their processes is possible
grapple is gonna do something very
similar to sis Mon but it's going to do
it on the back end so it's gonna be
generalizable to really any source type
that you send up and it's gonna provide
an identity for every single node type
so not just processes but users files
network connections anything that it can
understand as a node the problem with
logs without identity is that you might
see information like we have here right
three events they all share a process ID
across some series of time you might
think that this is all referring to the
same entity but that's not necessarily
the case process IDs can be recycled and
they're recycled actually really with
with quite
a good amount of frequency so if you
don't have some way of resolving this
it's gonna be really painful in any kind
of investigation so grapple is going to
use context from these logs the
timestamps the event metadata to
disambiguate what these entities are and
provide a canonical identity when you
combine that identification process with
the graph based approach you can go a
lot further than something like an
instrumentation tool like sis Mon we can
coalesce all of that information that
comes up across thousands of logs on to
just that one entity that one node using
its its node key which is the identity
and we can throw away a lot of redundant
information so this helps grapple scale
sub linearly so you might send a million
logs to grapple in my experience across
you know a million logs maybe ten to
thirty percent of that information is
actually unique the vast majority of it
is just the same thing over and over
again the same logs containing the same
Pibb process names if it's if it's
something like sis Mon they're really
really heavy so it's gonna have the
process gooood it's gonna have parent
process information we can get rid of a
lot of that and grapple and this can
compound really quickly so if we have a
master graph with just a single node
it's got a pit of 100 and an event comes
in and there's a process execution where
pit 100 executed a child process we can
immediately throw away some information
right we can throw away the pit and then
that type information is actually
encoded directly into the graph if the
child process creates a file again we're
throwing away more and more information
and if that child process then reads
that file you can see how this really
quickly compounds we're storing almost
none of the information in that log
we're just adding a new edge with a
timestamp this really goes towards a lot
of what I've seen in the field as people
fighting with their data I see this in
security I see this in really every
discipline where you're dealing with a
large amount of data scaling linearly or
worse with your data sets it puts you in
a position where you have to start
throwing data away every year or you
have to ask yourself do I really want
this data source and I don't want people
to have to ask that question I want you
to be able to put as much data in this
thing as
possible okay so detection is really
what I think in in terms of a log based
approach Sims and logs push us in the
wrong direction so I see a lot of
detections that are looking at
properties of an attack the reason for
this is that it's a little difficult to
look at multiple logs especially across
log sources in most tools today and logs
don't really tend to encode a lot of
behavioral information they tend to just
have properties
this makes logs pretty good for things
like searching for hashes or IP
addresses I like those low-level pyramid
of pain io CS but when you want to
actually talk about attacker behaviors
they start to fall apart joining these
logs together is is usually pretty
difficult so what I end up seeing is
people building signatures based on
attacker controlled information if I
want to ask the question where is
exfiltration happening on clients I
can't really represent that in a
generalizable way using logs at least
not very well what I'll end up writing
is something like you know curl and W
get are used for this a lot and these
are the command line parameters that I
expect and if I see these file names
show up then that's my signature but
that's really really brittle every
aspect of that signature that I've
written is based on attacker controlled
information and I see these signatures
all the time not just for X full really
for everything and so you might try to
put some like globs in there or use
multiple queries with ORS and build this
kind of monster query that tries to be
robust but ultimately I think it's a
losing game one way of demonstrating
this is if we take two process execution
logs this is word and PowerShell
executing and there's no properties to
go off of right maybe if the power show
log had command line arguments I could
play that losing game of trying to parse
them and say like oh this you know
base64 encoded data being passed in is
suspicious for whatever reason but as I
said I that that's attacker controlled
information that's not what we want to
focus on similarly word and powershell
are benign you know digitally signed
valid programs right they're executing
in the vast majority of environments and
they're doing so legitimately so
we can see here that logs are hiding
what I would say is the most important
piece of information we have this pit
sort of implicitly joining these logs
together and we can see that it's got
nothing to do with word or PowerShell
executing it's really that word and
PowerShell are executing together right
there's this relationship between the
two that we don't expect we want to
start focusing more on behaviors and
relationships as opposed to isolated
events and properties and we can
generalize this further it might not be
word it might not be PowerShell right
there's a number of ways to get code
execution on an endpoint it might be
Excel loading a macro it might be Adobe
Reader getting owned right and they
might shell out or they might call it to
a JavaScript or Python interpreter on
your system and so what we really care
about is tracking the fundamentals of
what attackers do attackers execute
processes we should be tracking that
sort of information not trying to hone
in on overly specific signatures that
attackers can almost accidentally bypass
when we start to represent our attack
signatures as graphs and when we stop
trying to deal with specifics of attacks
and start to think more in terms of
fundamentals I think we can represent
attacks much more creatively and much
more powerfully we can still leverage
properties so as an example we might
still want that signature forward or
Adobe Reader or excel these commonly
targeted applications with non-white
listed child processes we can leverage
that just fine graphs expose properties
perfectly well but we can also start
asking much more complex questions like
what are The Dropper like behaviors in
my environment a dropper is something
that I've defined as having a process
that has reached out to an external
network creates a file then executes
that same file we're talking about
multiple composite behaviors you would
have to probably join at least four or
five logs from different source types
combine them together and then analyze
them in an in a sequential order right
but in a graph this is really
straightforward so what I really want to
do here is basically start painting our
master graph with risks we want to start
labeling our massive data set and anyone
who's done data science
to work knows that this is essentially
the entire job you start off with some
murky data set you get it into a clean
format and you start labeling it and so
for that I would introduce the concept
of risk another problem I see with
security teams is drowning under false
positives it's a losing battle of
constantly whitelisting anyone who's
done security at a tech company in
particular will note that developers and
attackers do almost exactly the same
things every single day their
motivations are basically the only thing
that differs you will have developers
scanning your network you will have them
basically doing pre vests all the time
running Python running things you've
never seen and so we don't want to have
to constantly be chasing down developers
doing their job instead we can start to
model things in terms of a risk gradient
I can say unique parent-child process
that's a low risk event it's definitely
something an attacker does I want to
track that but it's nothing like that
commonly targeted application one that's
that's a much more finely tuned
detection that I'll probably try to
maintain a whitelist for so what we have
here is what I would call local
correlation these are tightly coupled
attacks signatures but we want to take
this labeled information and feed it
into a model and that's not going to be
a machine learning model it's just a way
for us to view these risks together and
get a sort of arbitrary level of
correlation and so here I had reduced
the concept of a lens this is actually
inspired by a talk by for who's the the
C slide over I gave a talk in 2012 where
we talked about sort of an arbitrary
correlation lens and so I really like
that idea I built it into grapple and
the idea is that you have these
correlation points like an asset a
user's laptop or their user name and
through that lens you can view all of
those other wise disjoint risks and now
I don't have to write signatures like a
unique process parent process
relationship with a unique network
connection I can write those
individually view them through a risky
lens like the asset and see that they
overlap automatically and now we can
build a risk score that takes all of
this into account and risk and grapple
is very simple there's no fancy
statistics it will count all of the
risky
nodes and take the sum of their scores
and for every node that has an
overlapping risk right it's involved in
more than one risk at a time we add an
increasing percentage so 10% for the
first node 20% for the second that sort
of thing and what this is going to allow
us to do is push things like you know
silly anomaly is like a parent-child
process that just happened to be unique
but it's it's an update that just
happened on a computer and those are
gonna fade into the background and all
of the risks that correlate together are
gonna start lifting up a lot higher the
way that these signatures are
represented is in Python my experience
with all of the various domain-specific
query languages out there is that they
were built for one specific purpose and
as soon as you try to move away from
that you start running into problems so
a lot of the time they can do things in
one or two blinds that's really really
cool and powerful and then you want to
do something like a join or you want to
really do anything that it wasn't
designed for and you're gonna start
running into like huge performance
barriers correctness problems you'll run
into the query sizes exploding and that
sort of thing so grapple just uses
Python it's general-purpose Python is
adopted by data science security
communities I have confidence that if in
five or ten years attackers start
changing up their tactics while other
query languages might start to falter
Python is gonna be able to scale an
ex-pro Civet e to whatever they're doing
and so this is what a an analyzer in
grapple looks like here we have that
commonly targeted application this is a
process query where we're saying it has
one of these process names and any
unconstraint child process we have no
white listing on the child processes
right now grapples gonna take that query
it's gonna do client-side query
optimization it's going to ensure it
executes in constant time so it doesn't
matter how much data you have these
analyzers will always run in real-time
in constant time they'll be batched up
paralyzed there's a ton of work to make
sure that you don't have really painful
operations work to deal with and if this
signature ever hits that on response
method gets called next the on response
method can do
things like Khan texting as I'll show in
a minute or subsequent alert logic but
really it's just going to label the data
with some kind of a risk and and a name
I think where Python starts to really
show some power is when we want to do
things that are a little more out there
like it sound silly but counting
efficiently is not something that I've
seen a lot of existing systems do very
well here we're leveraging a
parent/child counter abstraction and
this provides a specialized interface it
hides things like caching the vast
majority of the time this isn't even
going to hit our data Lake so it's gonna
stay really nice and efficient this
signature here is looking for living off
the land type attacks so processes with
parent processes where the process
binary is in system 32 or 64 we're going
to look for any execution of processes
that match that will use our Parent
Child counter abstraction to say has
this happened a few times or less and if
it has that's going to be something that
we want to track I think probably the
best part about using a standard tool
like Python is that you get to follow
standard practices if you were to Google
your Simms name with unit tests you
would probably not find great results if
you found any they would probably tell
you that it's just not supported at
least that is what I have repeatedly
found you contrast that with Python
there's a number of tools for making
Python correct
there's linters for style you can put it
into code review and store it in github
you can get that on github you can run
things like my pie so grapple is
statically typed so you can avoid errors
before it ever runs and most importantly
you can just import the unit test
library from the standard Lib and write
unit tests for your alerts so when
you're whitelisting or you're tuning
over the next couple of years when the
people who wrote the alert are no longer
there and someone else is maintaining it
they can be confident that their alerts
and their detections are still working
properly I see this as a really
significant problem at a number of
companies they have hundreds I've
actually seen thousands of individual
detection x' and they don't actually
have a
way of determining that those work they
might have some end to end like attack
system that were tries to test the
entire pipeline but like coming from a
vendor we just wrote unit tests and so I
wanted to kind of give that capability
to the average security team
I think investigations are probably
where log based systems really start to
fall apart to the point where attackers
take advantage of it
and so I'm gonna do sort of a strawman
investigation of an attack using a log
based system so as the incident
responder I come into work I've got an
alert and there's some process execution
log and it it went off because some
threat intelligence feed has told me
that the hash is evil for whatever
reason it doesn't give me much other
information so in an in a situation like
this there's usually two things that I
want to do first I want to just quickly
see what has this process done I'm not
gonna do like a fully scoped thing
that's something that I'd bring the rest
of the team in for so I'll just see what
it's done and I'm gonna trace it
backwards and try to find where this
thing came from so we'll open up a
search window probably like four or
eight hours depending on when this thing
happened I'm gonna look at like the last
business day or so and I'm gonna start
pivoting right I want to take
information that I have and I want to
gain new context new data so I'll search
for the pigs I want to see what this
process has done and I get all these
logs back right and and some of them are
interesting and some of them tell me
that this thing may be shelled out a
couple of times and this is notable
enough that I'm not immediately
discounting this as being benign someone
to start tracing it backwards and I'll
search for that parent process ID and
what I get back is a ton of logs because
the parent process it turns out was
something like cron or launch D or
schedule task manager right what this
tells me is that the attacker has
probably been on this asset for weeks or
months and they scheduled their final
payload to execute in the future because
of this exact workflow they know that
this is going to really mess with me and
so that's why they do attacks like that
they know that the data that I'm looking
at is going to be severely disconnected
in terms of time from the data that
is gonna tell me where this attacker
actually started off so at this point
I've hit kind of a dead end with
processes so I have to pivot off of
things like the hash or the filename I
want to see where this payload was
actually created I don't get anything
for the hash and I don't get anything
for the file right clearly an attacker
is outside of my search window I really
only have one choice at this point I'm
gonna extend my search window out and
this might be days if I'm lucky
more likely weeks and if I'm really
unlucky they've been here for a couple
of months this is starting to give me
the results I want right I'm getting the
image name creation maybe but I'm paying
really serious prices here for one thing
if I've extended my search window from
four hours to a month every single
search from this point forward is going
to be hundreds of times slower I could
try to play the game of managing a whole
bunch of different search windows in
like 10 different tabs but there's just
no winning with a with a system like
this what's worse to me is that I'm
probably gonna start running into fib
collisions so maybe you're lucky and
your entire investigation can be done
with something like sis MA and using
process codes that's never been my
experience even on Windows systems I end
up looking at the event log I end up
looking at something that has a pid'
without a process go ahead and pit
collisions will happen over this period
of time for a client laptop running any
multi-process architecture program like
Chrome or Firefox or all sorts of things
at this point users are gonna reuse pids
a number of times in a day so when we're
talking about weeks or months I will
have many paid collisions to resolve and
that's that's gonna suck for me it's
gonna really slow things down especially
coupled with those slower search times a
third problem that's a little harder to
see is that the fundamental thing I'm
trying to do here is pivot off of my
data but I don't really have clear
questions I'm sort of just doing like
raw text searches for whatever
information I have and I could try to
constrain those by searching specific
fields but it's it's just very murky in
terms of what I'm looking for and what
I'm getting back so grapple takes a
really drastically different approach
and at the heart of this approach is the
Jupiter notebook so this is again me
stealing ideas from the data
it's community because they've been
doing this sort of work for years and it
seems really silly that we wouldn't like
look at what the experts in data
analysis are doing right that's that's a
huge part of this job and what they're
doing is they're using Jupiter notebooks
these are these sort of super powered
Python environments so if you've ever
opened your terminal and typed in Python
you may have started writing code and it
gives you some immediate feedback right
these are a lot like that but you can
organize your code into cells replay
them modify them you can also do things
like shell out to the command line
really easily you can embed images
markdown and these are sort of the tool
to trade at this point for investigating
large amounts of data we're starting to
see Jupiter notebooks and security a
little more so I believe as your
Sentinel is like pushing notebooks as
how they want people to do
investigations so it's definitely
gaining traction as an idea
so I mentioned those lenses earlier so
as the incident responder looking at
your grapple homepage you'll see a list
of lenses right these are gonna be your
correlation points so different assets
or usernames we're just gonna see which
one is riskiest and I don't have to
worry about like having a thousand false
positives I have a set number of hours
in the day that I can put towards
incident response and I'm just gonna
apply that to lowering the risk as much
as I can right and I think this kind of
goes towards fleas talk a little bit as
well you don't want to be like spending
all of your time gatekeeping and like
hammering things down you want to just
sort of manage risk you want to move
towards a risk management approach
otherwise you're gonna burn out your on
call so if we click on one of these
lenses we get a graph this is going to
in this case contain three nodes with
some relationships between them we can
click on any of these nodes and we can
see any of the properties for things
like these processes or files or
anything that's in here this is a pretty
data rich graph this may have taken in
this case probably tens of logs so
probably like more than a browser screen
worth of logs but because we can
coalesce all of that data with that
identity we can create a very like dense
and compact representation if we click
on the command dot exe here you can see
that the analyzers involved
our that we've never seen anything
called dropper execute command dot exe
before so there's a signature and
grapple that just looks for unique
parents of command dot exe right that's
a pretty fundamental thing that
attackers do they shell out anytime
you're in Python or another language and
you try to P open it's gonna go through
a shell and then we have a much more
constrained signature which is that we
maintain a white list of valid SVC hosts
attackers like to pretend to be
legitimate services like SVC host and so
we're just gonna track that sort of
thing and thanks to the lens these
automatically overlap and we get this
cumulative risk score so in my Jupiter
notebook I'm gonna create an engagement
engagements are like a special type of
lens where you control what nodes are
brought into it and I'm gonna pull in
that first node I'll pull in the SVC
host right and I'm just gonna pull it in
by its identity and this is in the
Jupiter notebook so you would probably
have like two browser panes or even two
monitors one with a jupiter notebook and
one with your live updating graph
visualization at this point pivoting is
really efficient and really simple I
don't have murky questions I want to ask
what this process did so the first thing
I'm gonna say is what children processes
were executed from it this is extremely
efficient there's no search windows to
deal with it doesn't matter if these two
processes occurred across wildly
different timelines this could be months
apart it's gonna be a constant time
expression it's gonna pull it in a
millisecond so I say get children or or
get the parent process in this case to
start expanding it out and that pivoting
is nice and efficient and clear so to
sort of replay a similar situation as
before we would start off with our
jupiter notebook we have this sort of
route of our investigation right that's
our SVC host and we're gonna just do our
pivoting behavior right i want to find
out what is this process done i say get
the children processes immediately
that's gonna show up in that graph
visualization on the left as i'll i'll
show you and it's also gonna let me
display and play with the information in
the notebook itself so i know this thing
is it's probably not great it's shelled
out three times that's pretty sketchy
I'll do that pivoting behavior again I'm
going to climb backwards
up the process lineage right really
simple really efficient we can see that
there's a dropper dot exe we can see
that there's this chrome bxe so this is
telling a really really simple story
right a user was probably fished through
Chrome they executed something called
dropper that dropper if we were to
expand this out further reached out to
s3 pulled it down and all of these logs
are available for you guys as I'll talk
about later and we're gonna have this
graph that looks something like this
now this graph again is going to contain
probably tens maybe low hundreds of logs
worth of data this amount of data would
probably take up multiple pages and your
sim to go through but here we have a
really nice compact representation so
you end up with a workflow that looks a
lot like this at the end of any
investigation you will have two really
powerful artifacts you're going to have
on the one hand a graph visualization
this is going to be really great for
showing teams that don't want to pour
through thousands of logs you probably
want to interact with other security
teams you might want to show an
executive or a manager depending on
what's going on they're not gonna want
to look at logs graphs are nice they're
compact they're visual and even like a
big attack across your environment isn't
gonna be like too unruly of a graph to
visualize the other thing that we have
is our investigation and it's encode the
fact that it's in code opens up tons of
potential the obvious one is that we can
replay it right so if another
investigation is taking place and it's a
you know a very similar situation to
this where we want to take a look at the
children processes and then trace it
backwards we could move that to a
function we could just replay it in line
the idea here is you should be
accelerating as you investigate so one
investigation should feed into the next
one right you should be getting faster
and faster every single time this could
also be training material or run books
so you have a new person coming into
your your team maybe you had a red team
recently go ahead and like start a new
engagement have them play through your
last notebook step by step and explore
that data
Apple has a plug-in system and I've
managed to apply grapple to a lot of
different problems
and in ways that I don't think I ever
would have even tried after being burned
before and taking clusters down and that
sort of thing with other systems so here
you can see an inter process
communication node which is implemented
as a plugin and this allows me to detect
things like SSH hijacking where a
process is performing IPC to an SSH
agent or SSH daemon we can do process
tree analysis so unique parent unique
grandparent processes again this is
applied to SSH we can think see like a
Python process shelled out to SSH the
nice thing with grapple is that it's
going to stack unique parents and unique
grandparents automatically in those
lenses right so that correlation ends up
building up really really quickly the
more unique your process tree is you can
build recursive queries which I don't
actually think other systems even
support but if they did I think it would
be extremely slow but in Grandpa we can
ask questions like given a process trace
that process tree backwards and if we
see a user ID change in that process
tree we're gonna call that a privilege
escalation right so a simple case of
this would be calling pseudo and
changing users but if an attacker had
some sort of an exploit where they were
able to prove esque and spawn a child
process as long as that relationship is
there we would be able to catch that so
I'm gonna really quickly go over how to
set grapple up it's designed to be
really simple so you can clone the
repository crapples open source it's
free to use you pull it down go to the
grapple cdk folder you have to fill out
a dot env file with just a bucket prefix
in organ amiss probably a good idea
something unique and run the deploy all
script and that's really it at this
point it's gonna set up all of the
infrastructure for you there's really
only one more step and it's pretty
simple go to the AWS console go to the
sage maker notebook section grapple will
have already created a notebook for you
so you can just open that up upload or
use the grapple provision notebook and
just hit the play button and it's gonna
set up the database schemas it's going
to set up a user for you and you're good
to go at this point you can send up the
demo data it's in
the repo as well and that's that's
really it so I'm working full-time on
this now grapples open source I'm
certainly curious to hear any feedback
that people have there's a slack channel
or you can just hit me up on Twitter
always happy to hear feedback about it
we got a couple minutes for your
questions cool so I went over here yes I
don't think I could probably say a lot
more but yeah there's there's definitely
interest from everyone has these
problems vendors have these problems
security teams have these problems lots
of vendors are drowning under their data
the same exact way that security teams
are and there there's definitely
interest there yeah yeah so with the
right instrumentation we could
definitely trace it if the data is not
being provided to grapple then you might
have to do like a little work to say
like show me all of the possible places
where the cron may have been set or
where that may have come from but the
nice thing is that if you just fit that
instrumentation there you'll
automatically get that right you don't
have to do any manual work it'll just
sort of be there yeah question over
there
yeah so there's two what's that
oh sure so the question was I showed a
lot of like Windows stuff what other
data sources does grapples support I
think that's like a yeah so right now
grapple the the version that's in the
repo supports two data formats one is
sis Mon so don't just natively work with
system on the other is just a generic
JSON format so if you can map your logs
to that format first and send it up
you'll get things like process and
networking and file work all for free if
you wanted to have custom parse data you
can build parsers and grapple you can
extend the whole thing arbitrarily so if
you wanted to do that we should
definitely talk but I have done like the
SSH stuff was on Linux my colleague is
working on an AWS plug-in that'll let
you ingest things like cloud trail so
really it's it's arbitrary you can bring
your own model yeah and we've got one in
the back over there
yeah yeah so cycles are fine they're
probably so the graph the Python code
you saw is gonna compile down to a graph
query language and it's gonna handle
resolving cycles for you so if there's a
cycle in there it'll detect it but
cycles are natural right a process might
create a file which executes says
another process which IPC's back to that
parent process right so it has to handle
stuff like that and there's work in
there to do it yeah any other questions
oh yeah
[Music]
so grapples built off of a graph
database called D graph which has a very
like graph QL like query language it's
it's at least inspired by I think they
now support graph QL natively so you
could if you wanted to build your own
like grapple analyzer library you could
build it on top of graph QL if you want
to just use like pure graph QL you could
do that in grapple I believe today I
think it's on a version earlier nut or
new enough to support full graph QL yeah
I think that's it cool thank you thank
you thank you for speaking
[Applause]