all right we're just about to get
started with Alan Friedman's talk I'm
going to introduce him one minute early
so he gets the full time he's the
director of cybersecurity at the
National Telecommunications and
Information Administration in the US
Department of Commerce he coordinates
NTIA x' work on cybersecurity focusing
on building communities of passionate
experts to address vulnerabilities
across the software world he's going to
give his talk you can submit questions
to the SLI dot do and he will moderate
those and answer those at the end of his
talk Thanks thank you so much thank you
everyone for joining us I'm a failed
professor who got suckered into joining
government about five years ago over the
last five years we've tried to tackle
some of the fun and sticky issues in
InfoSec where the government doesn't say
we want this as a solution but there is
a clear interest in having a solution
out there and so we've tried to do is
bring together the experts in the world
who know about this stuff to say what
will actually work for us so security is
about unpredictability you're having a
fine one afternoon and then all of a
sudden Katz comes up to you no he
doesn't say your basic blond dose he
says we've discovered a new
vulnerability right this happens all the
time and sometimes it's in the top level
software that you know about that's in
your vulnerability management system but
more often than not it is going to be in
a component that's gonna be a little
under the water level it's gonna be used
as a third party approach so do you have
a chance to survive can you make your
time I would argue that today there are
very few organizations that can quickly
and easily answer this question that can
actually say when they learn about a new
vulnerability in an open-source library
whether you make software or use
software there are very few
organizations that can say we are
affected or we're not affected and if we
are affected here's what we can do and
so our vision here is to actually tell
the story about how transparency can
drive that resiliency that ability to
say when we learn about these new risks
we can adapt and respond properly
so um transparency in the marketplace is
not a new issue right we are used to a
world with lists of ingredients and it's
kind of crazy that we know more about
what's in say a box of Twinkies then we
do about what's in the software that's
running our entire world and even by the
way that's important
fun fact those who didn't know this
Twinkies not actually vegetarian now
what's really important to remember is
most of the time some of us may not care
until there's someone in your life
that's got a food sensitivity that has a
religious restriction that has a way of
life and then it's very important that
that data is available and accessible in
a way that you can use it and that's the
vision of transparency it's not about
forcing particular behavior it's about
empowering good risk based decisions
based on your own needs and this isn't
unique to the consumer space right so if
you are in the chemical world there's
something called a Safety Data Sheet you
run a factory you get a palette of 50
gallon drums each of those is gonna come
with a safety data sheet it's an ISO
standard that says this is what's in the
barrel and this is what you do when it
up ends all over Frank so that you know
what to do with Frank when he's covered
in the chemicals and even the term Bill
of Materials comes from industry it's a
very old term from the software supply
chain er from the supply chain world
which says if you go and buy a 10 ton
diesel generator for your facility today
right that's resiliency that's making
sure you know what to do when the power
goes out it will come with a bill of
materials here's a list of every nut in
every bolt so that you know what the
total cost of ownership is so that you
can do maintenance on it but today if
you buy it it's going to be connected to
the Internet and I would argue that
unfortunately today you have no idea
whether that IP stack is made of the
freshest healthiest ingredients or it's
gonna do things that are damaging to you
and yours so what why should we think
about this for software well because I
would argue for soft
we're knowing what's under the hood is
even more important and it's more opaque
so here's a great project that a woman
named a Saco son at NTT has done where
she sort of said hey we have a single
VAT manufacturer it's rebranded by a
bunch of white box vendors how do you
know what the firmware what the
vulnerabilities in your IP camera are
and these are not these aren't the cheap
ones these are the commercial grade
cameras so this is you buy it comes from
vendor you have to use a project like
this before you can even find out
whether there's a vulnerability hint
there are several very real
vulnerabilities in this exact camera one
of which in fact was a key driver behind
the mirror I bought in that attack that
took down dime but of course software
doesn't just run cameras doesn't just
run organizations it runs large pieces
of equipment and go boom and it runs
small pieces of software that are about
as important as that can be literally a
matter of life and death so as we think
about understanding the software supply
chain it's important to remember that we
can wear different hats I like to wear
hats and it can really transparency can
drive real benefits based on if you make
software you choose software or your
operating software so if you're making
software again first of all you've got
to know what your ship this is something
that surprisingly few organizations were
doing even just a few years ago more of
us are now aware of it
but it's something that we're still
trying to learn how to do better of
monitoring for vulnerabilities but even
just you look at what's under the hood
in some of these large products there
are some vendors that will ship a large
product with four five six seven I've
heard nine versions of the same piece of
software inside one blinking box that's
used in critical infrastructure so it's
not just about security we can tell a
story about quality as well now if
you're buying software seems to me that
a very important question to ask is hey
are you selling me something that out of
the
box will put me in my network at risk so
this is something where we're going for
where we're trying to say here are some
of the questions that we can ask today
or alternatively you can say hey your
user giving me some software what do I
know about it what don't I know about it
so that I can do a more secure a more
targeted security analysis and then
finally of course operating software
I've got something on my network a new
vulnerabilities announced am i affected
is one of those core questions that we
need to ask ourselves but almost as
important is that last bullet which is
if I'm affected and I'm waiting around
for my vendor to respond if I know that
I'm potentially at risk I can take
risk-based decisions of my own I can
tune my IDs I can segment my network I
can take decisions that I think are the
right level of precaution based on the
software in question my network what's
supposed etc etc so why aren't we doing
this already right it sounds like a
pretty good idea we do it in other areas
why aren't we doing it already well one
answer is those pesky lawyers software
licensing is a challenge until a few
years ago I don't know how many of even
the biggest companies in the world could
honestly say that we know we've got all
of our licenses sorted and we're not
shipping any GPL products or anything
like that
I think that in 2020 that's a much
better understood risk there are more
and more tools on the market that can do
this kind of analysis for you turnkey
this is something that lawyers are aware
of this is something that we have a
better handle on today another reason is
that it turns out it's actually a little
bit hard because for this to work for
this to scale we have to have a shared
vision across the entire ecosystem and
we don't have that or didn't have that
until recently and we didn't have it
because it was a little bit of a chicken
and egg problem right no one was asking
for this information so no one was
providing it no one was providing it
soon known was asking for it so there
were no tools to use it now
that is what we economists like to call
a market failure and market failures
mean that your friends the government
get to get involved right who doesn't
love it when the government just shows
up now how does the government
traditionally solve problems well we can
either pay you to do things or beat you
until you do it well and unfortunately
no one gave me a budget or staff so I
can't pay anyone to do anything
and either unfortunately or fortunately
Congress did not see fit to empower me
to do jack so I can't tell anyone
to do anything in any meaningful way so
the solution that we have is we bring a
bunch of people together and I say all
go away if you all solve this problem
and our vision here is act has been
pretty ambitious because for this to
work it has to apply across every vector
if we go and say here's a solution for
the people who buy and build for DoD
land and here's another solution for
this regulated sector and Finance is
going to go off and do it one way well
that won't work because that won't scale
and it means we won't get the benefits
of tooling and mass adoption and we also
have to look at the entire software
lifecycle open source middleware
commercial software embedded systems and
perhaps most importantly the end
customer so we're trying to make sure
this is market driven we want all those
perspectives at the table so we have
this lovely thing that we call the
multi-stakeholder process at NTIA
and if you roll your eyes at the term
multi-stakeholder process on the guy
who's to say it like eight times a day
but it's the term that we're saddled
with and so what we've done is we've
tried to bring folks together just very
quickly to assure any skeptics or people
who are afraid what are we not doing
it's not regulation
again we're not empowered to do anything
although I'll touch back on regulation a
little bit later it's not source code
disclosure it's not standards
development we're not a standards
development process and we're not trying
to solve everything in supply chain
supply
the biggest big enough buzz word that
you too can have your own federal
government process based on whatever you
want to do we're not trying to solve
everything we're looking at this one key
area which is the thin narrow level of
software transparency in a way that is
lightweight and is meant to scale for
all software we've been doing this for a
little over a year I'm very pleased to
see that a few of you in the audience
lying I can't actually see anyone in the
audience right now but some of you in
the audience have been participating and
I think we've made a lot of progress
what have we done we have a shared
vision of the scope of the problem we've
developed some baseline definitions an
emphasis on the fact that it's got to be
automated it's got to have this broad
scope and on this handy-dandy website
which is also going to be on some of
these stickers that we'll give out you
can see some of these resources we've
sort of defined what is the nest bomb
why we should ask them how do we ask
bomb and then can we ask bomb today and
we're still working on now the next step
so very briefly Allen you've been
talking about a nest bomb for a long
time what the heck is it well here's a
toy example of what it can look like
I've got my Acme appliance and it uses
two software components uses exactly two
we know what they are and in turn Bob's
browser we know uses carols compression
engine carols compression engine we know
so the other thing in addition to having
a tree here so we know what the
relationships are which can go as deep
as we want the other thing we're
capturing is known unknowns so that when
you look at this you have some idea of
the completeness of information so we
know that Acme appliance has exactly two
dependencies we have no idea whether
bingo buffer has any dependencies or not
we know that carols compression engine
has no dependencies it's a root in our
tree or a leaf on our tree depending on
which way you draw your treat believe it
or not it took many weeks to figure out
which way we should draw our tree to put
the root at the top or the bottom turns
out as long as you need one way to do it
standards are hard who knew so and we
know that Bob's browser includes at
least carols compression engine it may
include
more so you can look at this and get
some idea not just what you have on your
network
but if you really need to know what's on
your network you now know where to do
further research or where to start
asking questions so now each of those
when I say here are the components what
do we mean by a component I want to be
able to sufficiently uniquely identify
each component so what's the supplier
what's the component name what version
is it right now I need to know whether
it's up-to-date and then by the way give
me the hash so that I can verify that
you and I are talking about the same one
I want to make sure that you didn't just
go download some cloned backdoored copy
on github so we've got our tree we've
got our components how many levels deep
to this tree go Alan as deep as possible
we want as much information as we can
but we also acknowledge that it's going
to be hard to do at the beginning and so
the minimum viable approach is you need
to have at all of your top level
includes tell me what they are and again
I say includes we're talking about third
party code not the code that you write
but what are the components that you're
bringing on board and then ideally in a
magical world if everyone does that we
will recurse our way all the way up the
supply chain and by the way if we're in
an open source world then if someone
really cares they can take on a lot of
that ownership themselves so I've talked
a little bit about the benefits but I
want to flag to more systemic benefits
that sort of capture some of the public
policy interest here one is just
thinking about how having this kind of
transparency will help us when we do
discover something that's far up the
supply chain so at the top here we have
a traditional case of timed or mediation
once we find a flaw which is I find a
flaw we managed to convince the
maintainer zuv that open source project
and so they go and fix it takes them
some time and then they put that patch
out so the people who are using it say
oh look there's a new version of this
let's try to integrate that so it's got
a cascade all the way down in what we
might use the analogy here is a
waterfall
that waterfall is the best way to
develop software right this is the
analogy that we still love to run with
so in a world where we have transparency
the software doesn't magically fix
itself I don't want to overstate it but
while you're waiting for that
improvement for the fix to slowly
percolate down you can be prepared you
can make a decision again based on your
risk and your needs to say we're going
to put in something in line that will at
least make us more comfortable thinking
about our risks this so the other thing
that I like is this is a real potential
to have some changes in the open-source
ecosystem itself where we can start to
create some market driven pressure from
downstream users to say hey let's think
about what open source libraries we
should use and I don't want to pick on
open source commercial is the same way
which ones we want to use because now I
know that my downstream customers and
their customers have a chance to look at
me and ask why certain decisions were
made so a couple of great stories here
I'm sure some of you heard the story of
you have a choice between two projects
one has never had any security issues
whatsoever reported they've got no CDs
the other in the last year had two
public CVEs reported against them
which one do you pick it depends as
right answer but I would argue that
having a CV against a software project
is actually a good sign it means that
they are aware of security issues
they're willing to fix them they know
how to fix them and they're aware that
fixing security issues involves a
broader ecosystem initiative than just
fixing their own code so I'm not going
to delve too strongly to how do we do it
I can just say that we've gotten pretty
close to solving this approach we didn't
want to invent a new standard the good
news was at least one technical standard
out there said hey we can capture s bomb
data the bad news is that more than one
technical standard out there said hey we
can capture s bomb data so our vision
was to make sure that we can reconcile
these two s P DX comes out a Linux
Foundation it's a way of capturing
open-source data it was built to address
licensing issues but we can use it for
our interest in security swig or
software ID tags is an ISO standard
that's great news if you work for a
company that wants to trade around the
world it's a little frustrating if you
want to actually read the spec yourself
and you don't have 390 Swiss francs
handy but the good news is you can go
online and look at mr. 80/60 which sort
of details here's some of the spec years
what are the fields that we should care
about behind swig tags and again our
vision here has been to make sure that
we can have bilingual translation and in
fact there's a third standard called
cyclone DX that's being developed in 200
ASP specifically for the online
application needs
so we also in the past year there was a
proof-of-concept from the healthcare
sector remember I said we're not
regulatory I don't have any power but
we've got friends with power and the
Food and Drug Administration which
regulates medical devices has publicly
said we're going to require every new
medical device that wants to come out of
the market to have an S bomb
well regulation got the attention of the
healthcare sector and so they went off
and said we can we're going to show that
we can actually generate this today but
the medical device manufacturers can
generate the data and hospitals
including you know some of the best
hospitals in America and your
Vesey or sauna and Mayo Clinic were able
to use that data against predefined
risk-based use cases asset management
vulnerability management pre-purchase
risk decision-making that's the good
news they were able do it the bad news
is that without taking advantage of all
the work that I've just described no one
was able to do it in a completely
automated fashion and so that's really
where we're pivoting for for our next
steps this process is ongoing we're
continuing to refine and extend the
model I'm going to talk to you about a
few these challenges around namespace
but we're also trying to collect tooling
this is not just open source I know that
there are a number of companies out
there today that are working to solve
this exact problem for you that's great
I'm from the Department of Commerce my
agency believes in the power of people
making money especially when they're
providing a valuable good or service so
that's what we're trying to do is
capture as much of this as we can about
what's out there today and then of
course awareness and adoption that's
where a lot of you come in how do we get
this message out what are the benefits
how can this help your corner of the
security world and by the way would you
like to do a demonstration would you let
you do a proof of concept we have a
bunch of them ongoing this is your
chance to roll up your sleeves and
actually build something there are a few
challenges were trying to tackle very
briefly naming software is a known hard
problem I would argue that in the
history of IT over the last 40 years
we've successfully solved the
decentralized global name space problem
exactly once and the annual budget of
ICANN is about one hundred and forty
million dollars so we're not gonna wreck
recreate DNS but we can make some
progress we're trying to figure out how
do we do this in a way that is neither
centralized nor requires everyone to
change what they're doing because that's
easy right a lot of the solutions are oh
this is super easy
everyone just do what I do and then
we'll all have the same model how do we
share s bomb data this is again we need
to make sure that it's getting into the
hands of people who need it the vision
here is not to say that there's one way
to do it it's to say here's a small set
of ways this problem can be solved pick
one that works for you
one of the core challenges that a lot of
folks on them especially on the vendor
side are aware of is they said hey just
because something's vulnerable doesn't
mean that it's exploitable right I'm
using open SSL ODOT 9 but guess what
it's for a client-side piece of software
so by definition it cannot be heartbleed
able please turn off the blinking LED on
your dashboard how do we allow that kind
of communication to happen down the
supply chain in a way that means that we
can start to pay attention and focus on
what's really important and of course I
mentioned the opportunity for a proof of
concept where since we have all this
information out there today could you
actually show that this could work for
your organization or whether you build
software or whether you're buying
software or you know somewhere in the
middle what could it what could help you
and what is the site motivation that you
need so taking a step back transparency
is part of the nutritious breakfast that
is going to be addressing the entire
issue of security in the supply chain
right it's messy there's a lot of stuff
there but transparency is going to be
the foundation for thinking about it
there are a lot of different solutions
out there to improve on this but they
all start with making sure that we know
what's actually under the hood of our
software so I have I think three minutes
left for questions you can use your app
I'm going to plea please get in touch
with me that's my email address if you
send me a note saying you want to join
I'll give you a sticker if you tweet
with the hashtag s bum I'll give you a
sticker if you ask the question I'll
give you a sticker you come up to me and
say hi I'll give you a sticker so let's
see does s bomb scope include hardware
and firmware so on firmware I would much
rather debate which of our text editors
is the superior in an objective fashion
then talk about the difference between
software and firmware what I will say is
for firmware did you write it if you
wrote it then it's your software it's
not their party components if you're
using third-party code in your firmware
then that's some
that you probably need to be aware of
and be able to track that hardware is a
different problem in some ways it's
easier especially at the sort of end of
high-end chips in some ways it's a lot
harder especially as you move down the
supply chain into hardware because ASCII
read a dim as a dim as a dim you're
looking at it from manufacturer
perspective you're saying this is just
askew so we're trying to just focus on
the software side of things so let's see
I have a there's a question which is is
an S bomb a tree or a directed acyclic
graph that is a great question
we will leave that as an exercise to the
reader so there's another great question
which is hey couldn't some source code
repository products like say github or
bitbucket think about this and try to
solve this for the entire ecosystem it's
a phenomenal idea I've had the
opportunity to work with a number of
folks from github that are very
interested in this github will do some
of this for you today they will flag
your dependencies that are risky so
we're starting this the challenges of
course while that gets us a lot of the
way it doesn't get us all the way there
especially when we're thinking about
commercial software commercial software
running on your network is sort of quite
the black box side of things other
questions in the room before I I think
I've hit the wrong button here there are
questions the room you can just shout
something out so that's that's a
fantastic question the first proof of
concept they decided for scoping reason
they were only going to use the
top-level dependencies as they've
started to look into this especially for
the art the art haces it's going to be
big and in fact there are a couple of I
know that someone has tried to write
this for one flavor of a Linux kernel
where they've activated will show yeah
listen we found the way we as we compile
it we can actually generate it so for
the large pieces of software this is
gonna be very large and
how many you got no I think it's a great
question
the I'm hazarding so I'd say on the
order of 10,000 components for a modern
operating system but again it's that's
that order of magnitude if you want to
know more about this scope the critical
infrastructure initiative with Frank
Nagel up at Harvard Business School just
wrote a report of the first analysis of
their attempt to do an open source
census the data is heavily built or
heavily sampled on the JavaScript
universe because that's where the data
was classic street light problem but
that gets us some insight into what
these dependency trees look like and
where they overlap on getting the stop
sign so please don't hesitate to get in
touch I'll be out in the hallway after
this afternoon and I'll be around San
Francisco all week so please get in
touch and join us we need your help
thank you
[Applause]