please welcome Bree from Bishop Fox all
right hello security riders we're here
today to consider some aspects of
writing and editing that wherever you
are in your career you may not have
focused on before let's check out a map
of our general trajectory underpants you
the first draft space using guides and
fresh eyes to edit yourself and what to
do if you need more so our first stop
underpants in an episode of South Park
tiny gnomes sneak into kids rooms to
steal Underpants why would they do that
they explain it's step one of their
business plan which is missing a crucial
middle part between collection and
profit my conceit here is that you right
now basically hack all the things in
step one and you want payment and
closure for that in Step three but if
you don't use step two to consider the
quality of your work if you turn in your
first draft as your final draft people
will be less inclined to pay you and let
you move on they'll want to go back to
step one and scrutinize what you did and
make sure it's worth paying for
but if you have a real plan you make
your work with care you look brilliant
in step three you keep everything moving
and most importantly you get paid for
your time and can work on the next thing
for more about what happens when you
miss the middle step you can look at my
cactus con talk from a few years ago
called chaos on the machine it's a jolly
twenty minutes about the value of making
security writing more transparent for
this talk let's just agree that you
should avoid writing breaches with a
double e and we'll focus on the
solutions so what's our new plan it's a
five-step plan our goal is to make
something good to produce quality
content that reflects the quality
research business experience and
expertise that you put into it so first
we're going to focus on you and how you
make things then we got to make a thing
then we need to focus on how to make
things good how to set up ourselves for
success so that in the fourth step we
can execute on that plan on the things
we've learned and do them resulting in a
beautiful thing that does what you want
it to my hope is by recognizing these
steps every time you walk through them
you'll be able to see the profit at the
end of the tunnel so the first step of
our new plan is knowing how you make
things as a writer and the first step of
that is admitting you're a writer you
might categorize yourself as a bad one
but it still makes you a writer
acknowledge that it's an aspect of your
job in emails meeting notes CFPs cover
letters and bugs
reports you write admit that embrace
that before we can achieve a gleaming
palace of paragraphs though we need on
how you write what is your process right
now if you don't have an intentional
process there's still a pattern you can
notice about the time of day or place or
format you choose to write in what keeps
you motivated and what stops you from
trying anymore it may be ad hoc but it's
kept you employable so let's find the
outline of your current underpants known
plan before we flesh it out if you've
never checked in with yourself about
writing start to notice your patterns
and emotions about them just get to know
what you're working with are you great
at starting terrible at finishing big
procrastinator but you always pull it
out at the end somehow maybe there's
someone you go to to bounce rough ideas
off of or someone you know to only show
the final version to you may even find
you're carrying around grammar pedantry
from a teacher that's not doing you any
good take inventory of your writing
assets they may seem small but they add
up to a universe of productivity look at
a recent email blog post or report
you've written and consider what areas
you're confident in and which ones you
avoid or struggle with what's working
for you right now today how do you
communicate on paper over time you may
start to see that you fall into the
extreme edges of the ranges here you
might write to casually for reports or
to seriously in emails you could be so
brief that the reader doesn't feel
they've gotten their money's worth or
you could write so much that they feel
like they've walked five miles and ended
up in the same place these are
independently moving ranges all
combinations are possible basically you
want to be somewhere in the middle on
all of them if thinking about your
current writing style this way is tricky
you can make a list of things you enjoy
or struggle with in writing instead for
example I enjoy giving talks because I
naturally write in a conversational
manner but I need outside accountability
to keep me honest and my talks always go
over by a minute as you figure out your
strengths the strategies that might work
for you will become more obvious like if
you feel lost when you sit down to write
you may need to take detailed notes as
you're doing the testing so you don't
have to remember the facts on demand or
you may need to let the experience
simmer before writing so you shouldn't
beat yourself up for not sitting down
immediately after the event before I
move on I want to briefly address
writers who learn English as a second or
third language as I hope you can see
from this talk already writing is
legitimately difficult for everyone
so tackling it in a second language
takes real focus and work make small
goals so you can celebrate small
victories of progress and look back on
old writing to see how you've matured
give yourself even more time for your
writing process ask for peer feedback
and take notes on what you learn from
each document I also recommend that you
get more formal English in your head
little things like prepositions
irregular verbs and idioms are hard to
just memorize but if you listen to
things like grammar girl structured
podcasts about security old DEFCON talks
or anything else you're interested in
those little building blocks will come
to you more easily when you sit down to
write all right we're all writers before
we can make a good thing we need to make
a thing let's write the first draft how
do you start writing though blank pages
are terrifying here's how you write a
draft you write it jump in do work where
you can do work right now maybe you can
knock out an outline or the main point
of the report in casual language like
hey company don't use that third party
vendor or your scope was a joke do this
test again with a realistic set of
targets in draft two you can make those
phrases more diplomatic
but don't censor yourself in draft one
get the core guts of your message out on
the page on that note the biggest hurdle
I see stopping technical writers is
dressing up their language before
they've put on their underpants be comfy
in your first draft the stiff formal
wear of these phrases can restrict your
ability to move around and early drafts
by focusing too much on the way you
think you should be writing don't worry
about misspellings don't look for better
synonyms just use a verb you can readily
think of and leave a note for later none
of the things on this slide are
inherently good or bad but you might be
over relying on them to sound confident
just consider that they're repeated use
and misuse and they actually be
weakening your points don't use bits
you're not sure how to use just write
down what happened as well as you can
and save the formal wear for the editing
process for the things you don't want to
do or can't immediately dive into in the
first draft mark them as spots to fill
out or improve later I recommend using
comments rather than highlighting or
bolding for this because those tools
eventually lose their power to stand out
and can sneak through to final versions
ok so you've written the first draft now
what well to make things good you have
to make room to make them
like many many business failures errors
often get through because catching
errors wasn't a defined part of the
process if it's no-one's specific
responsibility it's not surprising that
it doesn't happen you have to make it a
deliberate step the biggest point of
this talk is that if you want to improve
your work which is what editing is
you've got to make space for it such a
downer I know and it's good to admit
that you might hold a grudge about
editing it's not the reason you get up
in the morning it's a barrier between
you and the next fun thing and honestly
people can be cruel in their blood
feedback you may have had a teacher
dismiss you as a writer or a colleague
give you a vague comment like this is
bad fix-it reviewing an edited text from
unscaled editors can be demoralizing and
yet editing is such a crucial part of
refining your craft and succeeding at
your job rebound from those literary
traumas by learning to find the useful
feedback below and be grateful when you
get to work with professional editors so
let's make some space for editing we're
gonna focus on three ways here first you
need to know how much time you have
total so you can carve in time to edit
this can seem simple but little admin
tasks can cut off fractions of days and
really affect how well you can finalize
your work before the deadline get that
information up top and clarify when
necessary you need it you need to know
the real schedule so you can plan your
attack and wrap it all up at the end -
you can make space by creating your own
schedule within the official timeline
set up chicken meetings with your
project partners talking through your
topic can often clarify your message and
shake out forgotten points keep the
meeting short and then you can use that
blocked off time to make headway on the
next section or review your work with
fresh eyes while you'll feel that
momentum and build out generous amounts
of time in your schedule for your
colleagues to review your work peer
editing can be rough so keep it focused
by asking for feedback on specific areas
you're working on your introductions
transitions or technical explanations 3
save time during editing by spending
time now to get to know your tools
better all word processors have little
tricks that you may not be taking
advantage of set it up so it's your
friend not your enemy during deadlines
if you're using something daily it's
worth looking up tutorials to get
comfortable with the various ways to
view and format your work for example
how to customize your spell check
settings how to bring the common
functions you use onto the
quick access toolbar shown here how to
use track changes and its different
markup views how to talk in comment
threads how to accept changes okay so we
have allotted time for editing and
you've written the first draft it may
not be pretty or concise or completely
filled out but it has the beating heart
of the message you're trying to get
across now we can talk about making it
good first drafts do not make good final
drafts because they're really you
telling the story to you you can use
shorthand you can assume that the
timeline main sense and just focus on
the parts that interest you because
you're the one who experienced the
exploit it's like if you write a
shopping list that just says milk but
then someone else has to go buy it what
percent what size did you mean almond
milk these are the kinds of
clarifications that a technical editor
would ask you about and that you have to
take a step back and ask yourself if
you're going to edit your own work and
to do that you need to be different from
who you were when you wrote it so the
first thing is let's use some of that
space we allocated earlier to let our
draft rest so we can really improve it
the amount of time here is not crucial
you just want to give yourself a chance
to separate yourself and live a little
so that when you come back you can
experience the document like a new thing
if you edit right after writing you'll
miss boodles of errors because you
haven't distanced yourself enough and at
the same time you'll burn yourself out
sleeping on it really does help but
going for a walk playing a game singing
or dancing can make you feel like you
have something new to offer when you
come back if you're short on time
consume the document in a new way by
listening to it out loud or changing the
format you're viewing
reading out loud or having a computer
speak it back to you is the absolute
best way to edit yourself why when you
silently read something back to yourself
that you've just written you fill in
gaps and you miss words this triangle is
a classic example of that I love Paris
in the springtime oh dang there are two
those in that triangle but because of
the line break your brain kind of half
remembers that little word and lets it
slide during a quick scan but it sticks
out when you read aloud you're so
embedded in your topic that you won't
see or hear these little connecting
parts that you just assume are right
beyond typos there are a lot of
eccentric there's a lot of eccentric
jargon in security that you may not hear
is strange anymore when those terms like
sniffs
run pickling pop up out of context that
can confuse new readers or be
unexpectedly suggestive the words that
make them up don't have to be inherently
vulgar but in InfoSec terms I recommend
watching out for our penetration dump
leak Jack and dangal four of which were
combined in an end gadget headline last
summer according to a hot dongle leak so
a slogan for editors is read stupid
think dirty if there's a confusing or
vulgar interpretation of a sentence
people will find it and then they'll
talk to you about that instead of what
you intended for them to focus on these
phrases make you memorable as a writer
but it's probably not the kind of
attention you wanted so read your work
out loud to hear what it really sounds
like by letting it breathe and reading
it out loud you get to experience this
document like you're totally new to it
and when you hear it for that first time
capture your reactions if something
seems off like this map it's probably
off you don't need to know the solution
to the problem right away but you do
need to mark it before you get too
comfortable on the document again and
forget some questions to ask yourself is
the sentence so long I run out of breath
do new topics appear out of nowhere our
terms used inconsistently are their
repetitive phrases about attackers
attacking and users using right those
initial reactions down even if it's just
a keyboard smash comment in the relevant
place that's what I do on my first pass
you can run spellcheck to mark potential
problem areas - and while we're on the
subject let's look at what guides and
tools can and can't do for you in the
writing process there are so many gray
areas and nuances to language that
unfortunately no one tool can fully
replace a human editor so I recommend
you use a combination of reference works
existing tools and your own custom
checklists during your editing and
finalizing phases the benefit of an
existing tool is it already exists the
possible negatives are that they don't
work with your specific vocabulary or
custom formatting and in the case of a
tool like grammarly they check your
writing remotely so if you're dealing
with client sensitive NDA type
information it's not the tool for you if
you are in the market for some readily
available guidance though I'm going to
suggest to that I helped create the
cybersecurity style guide is a friendly
PDF
with 2,000 terms how to write and
pronounce them what they mean in
different contexts which ones to
consider avoiding this is a page of
entries from bootloader to be sides and
appendix at the back has further
resources for technical writers books I
recommend and other modern style guides
that can support your work the second
tool here is cyber dick which is a
dictionary file that augments your word
processor spellcheck by adding those
2000 terms from the style guide directly
into your local dictionary that can keep
away those distracting red squiggly
lines while you're working on your
drafts these are both available now for
free I made them to make my own life
better and I'm happy to make the writing
price process less painful for you going
forward the reason I recommend using a
combination of reference works tools and
custom checklists to navigate is because
there really are no rules only
guidelines I really mean that English is
a wild and greedy language and there
aren't many hard rules it's good to
reference industry standards but you
shouldn't feel trapped by them if
they're outdated or don't apply to your
situation
sometimes in writing it feels like
you're searching for that one perfect
word or phrase but the reality is there
are a thousand ways to write a sentence
that could serve your purpose many
answers are right it just depends on
your goal your audience and your
timeframe it's an editor's job to keep
the final audience in mind all the time
the changes they suggest are not really
about an editor's personal peeves or
preferred sentence structure it's about
fighting for the user like Tron you want
your future reader to get your message
to do that you need to keep them engaged
focused and on track sometimes this
means cutting out parts you loved but
aren't relevant or rearranging your
structure to explain the basics up top
before diving deep a lot of this comes
down to keeping a specific audience in
mind is this for CISOs developers
Instagram influencers or your elderly
family members even if you hope everyone
will read it you should be a realistic
about what level of reader you're aiming
for it affects everything from word
count to format to how many of those
fancy trap words you feel obliged to put
in the final draft the best way to note
to fight for your user and keep them on
track is to give them context so they
know what you're going to tell them in
what order and why it's important a
comment overall strategy here is to use
parallel structures if you were making
three points you should use a single
system
point one point B and lastly including
sections like a tldr or walkthrough up
top are also good ways to clarify time
and place don't suddenly teleport your
reader without warning laying out these
roadmaps is about setting expectations
and then meeting them if you don't
provide a road map you might lose your
reader in what are called garden path
sentences you the writer know what they
should say but the twists and garden
path sentences mislead until the end
which can make your reader do a
double-take let's look at two the team
found oh the team found something a
vowel and end point oh they found a
sample application where was it hidden
why does it matter
ooh this sentence is not about finding
an application this is about finding
something within the application so
we'll add a little word up top to make
that more clear early on the team found
that the sample application had a
problem in this example the name of the
team application and problem are short
but this type of sentence structure
appears all the time and technical
writing with complicated noun phrases in
each slot and your readers will get lost
if you don't keep them in mind and hold
their hand through long sentences if you
find yourself needing to give extra
context in the middle of an important
sentence I recommend putting it in
parenthesis or its own sentence or in
the footnotes separating secondary facts
in parentheses or note sections keeps
your main message clear and keeps your
reader on the path all right example 2
the overall security of the external
network was excellent sometimes the
sentence itself is clear but it's true
meaning isn't known until something
later if I read this as a client I'm
happy I'm mentally resolving this report
in my head and moving on with my day
next sentence the team extracted 60,000
social security numbers from the
internal network dang you just
sucker-punched your reader it's not kind
like now they feel betrayed you sweeten
them up with a compliment and the rest
of the organization is on fire let's
rephrase this
although the external network was well
secured the team extracted so much from
the internal network now we anticipate
the bad news we're not whipping the
readers expectations around it's the
same core information but you've given
it context you've prepared the reader
and you look like a professional you
haven't ruined someone's day now you've
just laid out the strengths and
weaknesses to a CSO so they can act on
this information this level of paying
attention to sentences that sound
could be daunting but in general editing
technical documents comes down to
simplifying your structure so that the
only thing that reader is having to
spend brainpower on is the concepts in
your sentence not the sentences
themselves break up sentences use strong
verbs pull long lists out into bullet
points and use transition words to keep
your reader flowing smoothly through
your document as you're wrapping up your
close reading of a document go back and
read the beginnings of everything not
just the intro paragraph but the first
sentences of every paragraph and the
headings for each section reading those
bits back to back separate you from your
role as writer again and let you see
what the reader is likely to take away
from your piece in the end lastly go
through a finalizing process you've
decided on ahead of time that uses that
combination of spellcheck pre-made tools
and custom checklists if you can look at
your work in a PDF and scan it for
visual consistency make sure all the
figures look like right proofread the
cover page the dates the heading titles
the table of contents and the figure
numbers to make sure that parallel
structure and consistency is happening
headlines are a common blind spot that's
how you get hot dongle leaks and it's
good to check that your legally covered
make sure that your redacted content is
really redacted and not just covered
with a black bar those can be removed
from PDFs and remove metadata so clients
don't know you name the image idiot
client JPEG you can't edit forever and
there's always something else to
consider improving in a document but at
some point you have to stop there are a
million tips and tricks and editing but
I don't want you to be overwhelmed here
this talk is to help you view the width
of when an editor considers so that you
know in the future that there are
strategies and resources to turn to it's
not just you struggling to write it's
everybody and even editors argue about
what matters most so with you as my
reader as my intended audience in a
movie theater let's take a step back and
look at the big points of editing before
we wrap up the whole talk for editing
read your work out loud capture initial
reactions read stupid think dirty use a
combination of guidance remember your
audience
keep your actions clear by keeping your
sentences short read the beginning at
the end and finish strong with a
checklist so you don't undermine all the
good work you just did what if you need
more than your editorial abilities can
offer
there are amazing freelance technical
editors in the world that can help you
hire them if you do that or if you
already have access to an editor through
your work you should give your work to
them in the best possible condition and
include notes about what's missing and
the aspects of writing you're working on
editors are powerful but they are not
ammunition omniscient so the new plan to
fully dress up our documents in more
than just underpants one learn how you
make things by knowing yourself as a
writer to make a thing in this case a
bad rough draft three make space for
editing and prep your tools so that in
four you can edit and finalize that doc
and profit from your hard work I thank
you for your patience through this
obstacle course of writing writing is
ridiculously hard it's hard for me just
know that there are resources and
strategies you can implement today to
make this aspect of your job less
painful and there are things you can
quantify about yourself that you can use
to decide which of those will be most
likely to help you you're all writers
and I wish you the best as you continue
on your lifetime of writing editing is
hard and I empower you to improve your
own documents thank you for your time
and here are the details where you can
find me in these slides in the future if
anyone has any questions I can answer
them or I'll stick around in the hallway
afterwards
oh so many phones I can't see anyone so
if you'd like to shout you can well we
can all just have a nice time in oh
thanks I brought an entourage
thanks coworkers yeah okay well thank
you everybody
I'll be in the hallway afterwards
[Applause]