hey everyone thank you so much for
coming and thank you to the organizers
for having me so over the past few years
I've spent thousands of hours studying
how various companies had scaled their
security and not just the one-off ad hoc
wins but the things that have truly
systematically scale ibly raised their
security bar so my goal in this talk is
to collect a bunch of tactics and
strategies and create a playbook from
which you can take different parts and
then apply them for yourself in your
company you know whichever parts make
the most sense so I'm going to be
distilling and aggregating a vast amount
of information so over 50 different
conference talks dozens of tools blog
posts and in-person conversations I've
had with security engineers at many many
different companies so these are just
the logos of some of the companies that
I'm going to reference their work in
this talk but there's more I also just
wanted to say you don't have to like
write down every slide or take pictures
of it on the last slide there's going to
be a link so that you can see these
Google slides like right then
and also this talk is recorded so you
know don't stress out about it you won't
be able to read everything so a little
bit about me before we get started so
I'm a technical director and research
director at NCC group we do security
consulting so pen testing for web apps
networks and so forth we've also been
helping companies with their dedsec ops
transformation security automation and
things like that so some of this
material is pulling from that as well
here are some of the things I really
enjoy so if you also like those come up
and say hi after I'd love to learn from
you and chat about it ok so there's some
things that I'm just going to sort of
assume and not get into a lot of detail
I think many people have found the
traditional SAST and DAST are overall
not as useful given the operational time
required from the security team as well
as the cost
I assume you're willing to invest a lot
of time now or sometime at least in
order to reap big security wins later
and I assume your security team has a
few people but not necessarily dozens or
hundreds right so you're somewhere in
the middle you're not just starting but
you're not maybe say Google or Facebook
so again this is not a starting a
security program talk
but if that's your gym here's some
places to start okay so this talk has
three main parts so first we're going to
talk about some sort of big picture
security mindset type things how to
think about security effectively and
then the book of this talk is the middle
section where we're going to talk about
some specific strategies and tactics you
can use to scale your security so first
some fundamentals that are nice to have
then how do you scale that and then
finally what might this look like say a
couple of years in the future and then
finally we're going to tie it all
together
cool so first some mindsets and
principles so first I think everyone
would agree with this first one security
teams are always time and purse limited
so fundamentally you need to automate to
scale and one trend I see at many
companies is that you have to minimize
your nose right you have to build these
nice secure guardrails that allow
developers to do their job securely as
well as just faster and better I think
Austin and the Netflix team talks about
this very nicely in their concept of a
paved road many companies are choosing
to prefer like high signal low noise
tools and alerting so it's okay if we
don't find everything but when the tools
do say something we want it to be
actionable and a true positive and I
think that's an interesting change in
perspective I've seen that a number of
companies so when we're building
products oftentimes we spend a lot of
time thinking about how do we make a
nice UI and user experience for users
but as security team members I think
that we should think of developers as
our customers so how can we fit into
their existing tools and workflow can we
make the secure way easier faster or
just otherwise better than how they're
doing it already right we're introducing
friction into their world when we're
asking them to change how they're
already doing things and lastly this
concept of self-service security so can
we provide tools and services that
developers can use without even talking
to the security team so I wrote about
some of these in a bit more detail in a
blog post you can check out and I wanted
to make sure that I could connect with
the youth in the audience so I included
this so to sort of thematically
summarize this talk broke is finding
individual bugs and woke
is scale ibly reducing risk you heard it
here folks
okay so in life as well as in security
you're always choosing whether to focus
on the now the medium term or the long
term and in this talk I'm gonna push you
very strongly to always be forward
thinking about this long term
specifically ask yourself of my near and
medium-term tasks which of these is
going to provide the most long-term
strategic value can I do a near-term
task a little bit differently to make it
more useful later
and then also what subproblems can I
solve precisely that is a high signal as
well as its scale so maybe there's 50
things you want to find but some of them
you can do very precisely such that you
just handle them and then you don't have
to deal with it anymore and we're going
to talk about that a lot soon another
thing I like to think about is when
you're approaching security there's many
different tools you have in your tool
belt right so you have static and
dynamic analysis you have bug bounty and
pen testing you have secure wrapper
libraries as well as threat modeling you
have runtime detection you have fuzzing
of course that's the song and I think
the point I want to make here is that
depending on what you're trying to do
there are certain approaches that are
just fundamentally better or worse so
rather than saying oh how do I make tool
X better instead ask yourself is to
elect the right even approach for this
problem I'm trying to solve and another
thing that I think is very important is
choosing what to ignore right so there
are some fires that you just have to let
burn at least for a time
so Adams said this on LinkedIn recently
that I liked so the question isn't is
this thing useful but given finite time
and resources should we be doing this
versus something else because ultimately
security and life is trade-offs okay so
another way I like to look at things is
targeting vulnerabilities by either the
complexity of the analysis required to
find them as well as what vulnerability
class they are so let's look at some
examples
so something that doesn't take a lot of
contexts like a lot of algorithmic
complexity to find is does this say web
app have TLS on it you know is it using
the right security headers calling team
dangerous functions is essentially just
greps but you can have some nice
security wins there and then things that
take a little more complexity of
analysis like standard l wast bugs
cross-site scripting and sequel
injection and so forth and then on the
hard side we have these complex
multi-step bugs business logic flaws
abusing built-in functionality and so
forth so when you're first starting a
security program you might say okay let
me just buy a bunch of tools and this is
going to handle all of our problems and
we'll be blissfully happy or you might
say oh let's just pen test all of our
problems away but I think as your
program develops and becomes a bit more
true more mature you're going to want to
make it look a little bit more like this
where you've built some nice secure
defaults which are handling many of the
easy cases and a lot of the medium cases
and even some of the hard cases you have
automated tools that are again catching
some autumn low-hanging fruit but sort
of less you know medium and high
complexity issues bug bounty definitely
plays a very useful role in getting some
continuous coverage and then I think the
the true value of pen test here is
finding these sort of medium and hard
complexity bugs the things that require
a lot of context and tools may not find
and runtime monitoring is useful for
finding some things you just can't
really find easily other ways so just
quickly solve as many of your problems
with secure defaults tools are not going
to solve all your problems but bounty
does give you some nice decent coverage
if all of your pen tests are just
finding these sort of easy type
vulnerabilities you're not getting the
most value from it and run time
monitoring for bugs is useful for
certain classes that you just can't
easily find other ways okay so that was
my opinion let's look at how some other
people think about it so this is from
Patrick and hasta zaps at Cal you talk
two years ago so notice how on the left
hand side we see manual testing per app
threat modeling traditional bowl
scanning is de-emphasized
and then on the right hand side building
a paved road so secure defaults so
service and killing bug classes is
emphasized they gave an updated version
on a different topic but also Netflix
Scott and Isha and notice how the heavy
emphasis on secure defaults and then
notice how that is growing over time so
I think that's very interesting okay so
now let's get into the meat of it so
these are sort of core tactics and
strategies so I'm going to start with
fundamentals and these are fundamentals
not because they're easy but because
they're a if you have a strong
foundation in these you can build very
high leverage scalable things on top
okay so vulnerability management you
need to know where you are now and you
need to know if what you're doing
actually works right something might
sound great and you may invest a quarter
or two quarters working on it and it may
not actually move the security needle so
this is very important so some success
criteria for this you want to minimize
friction for developers as well as
security you want to track
vulnerabilities ideally in the same
system such as JIRA that bugs are
tracked in so developers don't have to
go multiple places regardless of how you
find the bug whether it's bug bounty and
so forth just triage it through the same
process and it's nice to attract
relevant metadata so what are some
examples what code base was affected the
team in organ volved what vulnerability
class in wasp I think is a little bit
too coarse for this I would encourage
you to use a slightly more detailed
taxonomy maybe of like twenty to forty
type things this will let you do some
cool stats that we'll show in a second
also how severe was it how much do we
care and also how is it found as you're
scaling you might care a little bit
about you know what was the root cause
what code introduced it and where there
mitigating factors and so forth okay so
as you're sort of leveling up and
scaling this if there's parts you can
automate that's great many organizations
have found some success building a
vulnerability or risk dashboard that you
can sort of slice and dice by team
codebase etc so this gives you a nice
high level intuition as to where should
I invest my security engineering efforts
and a couple of companies have found
that it puts friendly pressure on teams
to improve no one wants to be the team
where all their stuff is in red
so here's some good talks about this and
the second one Arkady's talk I like a
lot and we're gonna see a couple of
figures from it so the first is this one
so this is open security vulnerabilities
by priority last 90 days so if you are
overall getting better if you're
mitigations and protections are working
they should ideally trend down over time
similarly here when you have open
vulnerabilities by sub team and priority
it very quickly becomes clear oh we
should reach out to this team and give
them some help maybe there's some
systemic issue they're having problems
addressing this idea was given to me by
a M ray of Salesforce so again if you're
tracking you know these bugs were from
bug bounty also what vulnerability class
they were and how much we paid so you
could actually say things like this
vulnerability class objectively costed
us this much money and this can help
perhaps get additional buy-in from upper
management in terms of investing time
and resources okay here are some example
dashboards so this is from a Domino's
app sack USA Talk
so you can see like Oh which of these
sort of micro services might we want to
invest more resources in and you don't
necessarily need to know the technical
details of oh this is what cross-site
scripting is like execs can look at this
and have an intuition about what they
might care about this is from a Netflix
talk again so there's a couple of
columns where basically has this micro
service used one of the security
controls we built for it yes or no is it
a high risk service and then you can
sort of slice and dice on the right hand
side with various filters okay let's
talk about continuous scanning so the
idea is we want to be able to scan new
code with static in dynamic analysis
tools usually static is on developers
machines and code hosting and then
there's a bunch of things you can do in
testing QA so due to time I'm not going
to talk about any of those however in
the backup slides of which there are
about as many as main slides I will talk
about all of these in more detail so one
of the interesting things I found is
this idea of like a continuous code
scanning pipeline is one of the most
popular ideas in dedsec ops many
companies have talked about how they do
it
here is a number just only a knapsack
USA here's a bunch more at other
conferences right so this is all
companies talking about how they sort of
continuously scan code so the details
vary by company but let's talk about
some things they all generally agree on
so first it's very nice to be able for
the security team to iterate quickly so
adding and removing tools into the
pipeline testing new rules generally
people choose to scan pull requests if
you scan every commit maybe there's a
work in progress commit you don't care
about and it's too noisy
ideally scan should be very fast you're
giving developers feedback while the
context is fresh if you're doing more
you know in-depth things maybe that can
be done daily or weekly generally if you
can show tool results within developer
systems for example a comment on the PR
so they don't have to go somewhere else
ideally checks are very high signal if
you're going to auto send it to a
developer without triaging it you don't
want to annoy them because if it's very
low signal and they spend a lot of their
time triaging this generally makes them
dislike you and it's a lot of overhead
time for your team obviously you're
going to want to capture metrics so what
are we finding what's our false positive
rate things like that you'll probably
need to build some deduplication and
whitelisting logic and then finally
being able to MapReduce over all of your
code and life systems it's pretty neat
and we'll show why in a second ok so
also just how to think about this here's
a couple of other good talks and one
thing I just wanted to dive into a
little bit more detail when people think
of static analysis a lot of times they
think about one of these two things
which are sort of on opposite ends of
the spectrum so one is you're doing
something very like sort of easy from a
analysis complexity point of view right
reg X is operating on strings very easy
to run and right or you have very
complex heavyweight analysis was sort of
SAS where you're doing control and data
flow so the trade-offs here you can be
very fast and not very expressive or you
can be very expressive but maybe a bit
slow and noisy but there's actually a
middle ground doing sort of security
linting or abstract syntax tree matching
which i think is very interesting so
here you are source code aware so you
can say like match the
conditional or match this function call
so you can do some of the complexity
obsessed but you're so fast but you
can't do quite everything SAS can do so
I think this is a very interesting space
that I'm optimistic about a couple of
people have given talks about this so
Justin Collins the creator of brakeman
gave the first talk myself and a
colleague gave the second one and
Instagram had a pretty nice detailed
blog post about how they do ast matching
on their Jango mount monolith ok so if
you were going to do this yourself
generally what you're going to do is go
from source code you're going to parse
it into an abstract syntax tree and
there's a couple of ways you can parse
either with a language specific parser a
parser generator like antler or in my
opinion the best approach which is a
parser that handles multiple languages
so if in your environment you have a
bunch of different languages you
probably don't want to find a separate
parser for all of them so let's look at
a specific example of this to make this
more concrete let's say you have a bunch
of node.js code and you want to find
calls to exec where the first argument
is not a string right so like any trusty
security professional you decided to
write a regex for it and it might look
like this but then you might find code
like this where it's on multiple lines
or the end of the function is exact but
it's not the one you meant or maybe it's
in a comment maybe it's in a hard-coded
string and you know quickly you become a
little bit sad like what you want to be
able to do is say find me all function
calls such that the function call is
this name right conceptually this is
very simple so there's actually a tool
that's free it's on github right now
called s CREP or Symantec grep and you
can think of it like a code aware grep
so in this example you could say s CREP
- e exec dot and you're just saying find
me a function call whose name is exec I
don't care about the arguments and it
can also use this idea of meta variables
where you might say find me all
conditionals where the if and the else
body are the same right generally that
shouldn't happen it's a little bit weird
or you could say find me calls to boto 3
dot clients where there's this dict
argument where the values
- the secret access key and key ID are
hard-coded strings right so you have
hard-coded secrets so again the idea is
I have an idea in my head how do we
express this as cleanly as possible okay
so we talked a lot about how so what to
look for one thing is high signal
vulnerability checks and security anti
patterns for example disabling TLS so if
you see this probably it's bad you might
want to block banned or dangerous
functions for example calls to exec or
eval Mozilla has some ESL and plugins to
do that maybe it's not a bug but it's
just some security additions to the code
that's interesting like hey I see you're
doing crypto stuff like maybe we want to
reach out to this development team you
can also alert on sensitive file changes
like the authentication or authorization
flow the login flow things that probably
shouldn't change that much and the
security team wants to know about it
here's a couple of tools that generally
are not too shabby okay so there's a
nice talk by Aladdin of the Netflix
security team about how they deal with
open source vulnerabilities at scale
every language has their own tool
there's a bunch of commercial tools you
can look it up another thing that's
interesting with this move to DevOps and
terraform and so forth there's a number
of security linting tools for those
infrastructure as code things so here's
a couple of examples so key takeaways
from this you want to have the
capability to scan every pull request
code base and deployed service ideally
you're using high signal checks only and
we're not necessarily finding every bug
we're just ensuring a security baseline
I think that's like a key perspective
shift that's useful right so you might
be scanning for missing security
controls in security area relevant
changes okay that's fundamental so what
is it it depends on who you ask but for
me it's a list of the things you own so
code servers databases and so forth so
maybe this is a black box external a
point of view where you're using OS int
and certificate transparency maybe you
give the tool access to your AWS
environment and then it's a
programmatically it figures out what you
own or this last one white box holistic
so maybe you give it a key to github as
well as other tools you use and it sort
of
their API is to figure out what is your
environment look like so the core idea
is we want to know what we own and how
they connect so first thing that's
useful is code and cloud and there's
many things but I would start here so
knowing in each repo what's the owning
team who's the security point of contact
and so forth and then in the cloud
environment what services are we using
what do credentials and roles in network
kacl's look like and so forth and as you
go along it's nice to build capabilities
to get visibility into other assets
being able to for example track code
from when it's in the repo to QA and
staging all the way to production is
nice and so we're getting visibility
into all these different parts of our
ecosystem and being able to query across
things is very nice as well so Sasha
from lyft talked about this at besides
last year and released a tool called
cartography and it's pretty neat
and then our King they're working on
like a commercial version of it
basically and then there was a talk by
Robin Oscar where they also give some
nice overview of the asset inventory
space okay so the idea of cartography is
basically let's enumerate all of our
assets what we own and then represent
them in a new approach a database where
each node is like an entity and edges
are relationships between those so here
are some things you can do you could say
which RDS instances have encryption
turned off which ec2 instances are
directly exposed to the internet and
let's look at a little bit more advanced
but I think more realistic and
interesting example so let's say your
company happens to run something like
struts and you might know where I'm
going with this let's say there's a new
critical RCE
it has a cool page a cool logo and maybe
you're a bit unhappy about it and let's
say there's also a curl POC that's been
released in terms of like how to
diagnose if you're affected so if you
have a nice acid inventory and some of
these fundamentals what can you do so
first you could say okay figure out what
are all the servers I own and where are
they you could then again using this
sort of MapReduce type functionality run
curl on all of those to figure out which
of these are actually affected and again
you can say oh I know which services are
running
so I can actually say oh these
vulnerable ones I actually know which
repo is responsible for those running
services from there you can say oh I
know the owner for those repos and then
you could say oh let's send an automated
email or slack message or created your a
ticket assigned to those people who are
responsible for the repo that is
responsible for the struts vulnerability
all right so we're taking a incident
response scenario that might take hours
or days to respond to and cutting that
down to ideally only a couple of minutes
so this is for incident response but it
could be applied in many ways okay so
let's talk about scaling our efforts
we'll talk about a couple of areas so
many companies find they can't threat
model every story so what do you focus
on there's been a bunch of work in this
space but I think it boils down to three
main areas so one is having developers
fill out self-service security
questionnaires basically here's what I'm
thinking about doing here's the
sensitive data it touches here's sort of
the risk of the types of things I'm
doing in terms of like parsing XML maybe
parsing URLs and so forth and then
basically it spits out here are some
things you should make sure to do and a
risk score so the security team can
prioritize or you could have some
lightweight lightweight threat modeling
in the sdlc itself maybe after they talk
about what features are required for
acceptance criteria you could say oh
also how could this functionality be
abused and then how can we prevent that
and then there's this idea of threat
model as code so the idea for all of
these is basically what should we spend
limited apps like engineer time on okay
so security engineering the core idea
here is building libraries and tools
that are secure by default for
developers and I want to emphasize that
framework and tech choices really matter
right so if you make the right choices
here this can mitigate whole classes of
vulnerabilities later so I included this
picture of the wild wild west because
that's basically where we were in web
security in the early 2000s and I
believe the core reason for that is that
developers had to manually parameterize
queries they had to manually output in
code basically they had to remember to
do something in order to not screw it up
but with object relational mapper --zz
default
output encoding all these things have
sort of systematically reduced these
types of issues over time so when you're
thinking about where do we focus these
efforts generally managing secrets
anything related to crypto
authentication authorization sequel file
system access all of these things are
good areas to start but really it's
broader than this these are just some
examples so just some case studies I
know one company who ported their
front-end code to react and that
essentially killed cross-site scripting
another wrote this data model wrapper
library where all data access had to go
through in order to access any customer
data and that basically killed sequel
injection and the core idea here is if
something is hard to do securely if you
have to just be aware of various threats
just like build is secure by default
implementation and then how everyone use
those one quote from asti like a lot is
hit your security wagon - developer
productivity right so this secure
version ideally have has an even better
developer user experience than the old
way another key insight is if you
integrate security at the right points
you can get adoption much easier so say
for example there is a new project
starter template where every new say
going microservice just clones that and
then starts building if you can put your
security controls into that then
everyone who builds from that is going
to get it for free and you don't have to
sort of convince them to adopt it ok
let's talk about detection in response
so this idea I think is pretty mean VI
essentially it's when a fishy event
occurs maybe a developer is running some
command on a production server you send
them a slack message and say hey was
this really you and then they have to
say you know yes or no and you only send
it to the sock or IR team to investigate
if they said no all right so essentially
again we're trying to free up security
engineer time as much as possible so
what I like about this is we see slack
writing a blog post about it in 2016
then Dropbox writing a blog post about
it and releasing some POC code in 2017
and then Pinterest talking about it at a
different conference in 2018 so we can
see this idea sort of moving across
companies which i think is pretty neat
ok so here's a blog post I like from
Dropbox about how they handle threat
detection
and so basically if something the
sketchy happens there is a cop-caller
which messages this other system call it
alert box which then grabs information
from disparate systems basically all the
context you might want to know then it
sends that to this micro service called
for Rumer forerunner which is running
some sort of heavier analysis and
running a steps in a jupiter notebook
that say for this type of event this is
how we respond and then the analyst is
then given the stupider notebook
environment where all of the data has
been gathered there's all these clear
steps that have already been taken so
it's easy to repeat across every analyst
because the steps of what to do are
documented and also any additional
investigation they do is then saved in
the notebook so you can go back later
and say oh did we do we do the right
thing should we maybe change this
process in the future another idea is
automating sauk run books so basically
rather than manually responding to
everything define your response process
and then have some lambdas automatically
spin up to either call the relevant
security products right run custom
scripts and so forth so Twilio released
a tool called sockless auth0 talked
about this as well and then the AWS
security hub has a nice blog post about
this idea also ok so core takeaways here
if you can push first line triage to
developers or people who are just not
the security team that's nice any
context that the human analyst needs to
proceed just gather this automatically
and ideally you want to document run
books for how you respond to different
events so that you have some
standardization and then automate them
ok cool
we're doing so well we're almost there I
paid a graphic artist a lot of money to
make this because I was like security
endgame we should have should have a
cool thing boom so yeah so that so these
are the you know aggressive long long
term stuff ok so the first thing as one
of my favorite tools and ideas by Travis
of Netflix so when you create a new
service at Netflix it's given a base set
of permissions and then essentially what
repo kit does is it watches how it
behaves over time and then if it doesn't
need permissions it's given it just
takes them away and then watches if the
app starts failing
so basically without talking to the
security team every app is gradually
converging to least privileged and apps
that don't need any permissions converge
to zero so this is pretty awesome more
recently a canard from Salesforce wrote
a tool called policy sentry that comes
at it from a different angle like how do
we make lease privileged policies from
the beginning rather than removing
permissions later
so let's look into that a little bit
more detail why is that so awesome so
the ongoing time requirements from the
security team are essentially none other
than maintaining the tool but the
security benefit and the risk reduction
is huge right like how much work would
it be to manually look at every single
micro service in your company and say oh
like what exact permissions does this
need in AWS right that would both be
point in time difficult and just
impossible over time so anytime you can
find opportunities like this you should
take them specifically we're trying to
maximize the ratio of security ROI to
the ongoing time requirements for the
security team ok targeting vulnerability
classes again this is another slide from
our Cadiz talk so this is
vulnerabilities by category so again
when you're doing vulnerability
management you could say oh these are
the issues we have the most maybe we
want to start there ok so a number of
projects at NCC started like this
hey we're not getting a lot of value
from this popular SAS tool can you look
at how we're doing things and just you
know help us get more value so the
initial ask was like how do we get more
value what does that actually mean
probably it means something like how do
we find more bugs of higher criticality
with less manual time but if we take a
step back I think what we care about
really is just how do we find bugs more
efficiently regardless of the approach
and taking another step back given
limited apps ik engineer time and budget
what's the best way for us to overall
reduce risk and again this is not tool
or approach specific ok so how to do
this at your company so aggregate your
vulnerabilities over the past couple of
quarters or a couple of years group them
by the vulnerability class is well
how you found them and you want to
probably wait by you know how much you
care how severe were they and then think
what can either find or prevent them at
scale so the goal here is minimizing
costs either you know bug banning
pentesting directly or to a licensing as
well as app set time in terms of finding
manually triaging results and so forth
so is one method finding all of your
issues have you had other success
stories in your company that you can
leverage and learn from these are useful
things to think about so let's say again
another example if you can see where are
all the vulnerabilities come from you
might be able to say oh we see this tool
or this say pen testing or bug bounty is
finding most of the issues that are
high-impact that we actually fix or this
approach is finding things that usually
we just mark is don't care so maybe we
want to deprioritize that so let's look
at a specific example let's say you did
a time audit of your app SEC team and
you're like this is sort of how we spend
our time we spend a fair amount of time
dealing with xxe a little bit manually
running security tools and so forth
so let's say hey we were spending a lot
of time on xxe let's like drill into
that more like whoa what are the
subcomponents of that so you might say
okay well we're doing some developer
training we're triaging bug bounties
submissions we're working with
developers to fix the issues as well as
validating that the fixes actually
worked
we're configuring both SAST and DAST
tools to do that and the point here is
all of these are continuous ongoing
recurring operational time costs right
these are things that you're doing that
are preventing you from doing other
things so what if we were to instead say
build a safe by default wrapper library
for parsing XML that disables dtds and
basically if you use this version you're
safe and then you teach developers about
this library and then roll it out
everywhere and then you have lightweight
scanning for every poor request which
basically says hey if you're doing XML
parsing like are you using the library
we wrote for you and then if not maybe
warned or block and then basically
you're done right by construction you
don't actually have to do all of this
complicated bug finding analysis because
you've just eliminated it by
construction
so Morgan Roman from DocuSign gave a
nice talk about this approach where he
describes how they eliminated regex das
xx EE open redirect as well as SS RF
basically by secure by default libraries
as well as ensuring their use right it's
a simple idea but I think very powerful
so let's go back to your app set time so
where we were previously spending time
on xxe we've essentially eliminated that
so now that time we were spending there
we can now start devoting to other areas
so we might say oh we're manually
running security tools like maybe let's
automate that a little bit and then boom
now 50% of your time that you used to be
spending on other things is now free to
invest again in further high-leverage
activities so the point here is we're
basically trying to build a apps X
snowball where we are systematically
becoming more effective and our efforts
more scalable over time right rather
than playing whack-a-mole a bunch of
places we're trying to have compounding
returns on our efforts so again what I
like to say is security engineering is
the compound interest of security right
so you might be putting in some time
here this week and maybe in the next few
months and you don't necessarily see a
lot of value immediately but over time
you are investing in things that you can
build upon and you're just becoming more
effective higher leveraged over time
also when I wrote this slide I wanted to
point out that quoting yourself is kind
of awkward
obviously Ghandi said that okay so
targeting bolon classes use your
vulnerability history to determine where
to invest effort consider the
vulnerability classes like what's
finding them what's their impact what's
the most effective way in terms of time
and money to reduce risk and solving bug
classes amplifies your effectiveness
okay
last topic enforcing invariance
so I think this idea is super neat and
the idea is essentially you want to
enforce or alert on things that either
should always or never be true in your
environment for example you might say
AWS instances should never be accessible
on all ports to the whole internet we
should just never do that so a David dog
had a nice blog post where they
essentially described a system where a
lambda will spin up and auto shutdown
any ec2 instance with this policy you
might say oh we have all of our
developers using terraform so manual
changes should never be made through the
AWS console this should just never
happen so Arkady has a nice blog post
about how to do this with cloud trail
another idea is we should never use
these regions or these cloud services
like in our company we always use a u.s.
East in these three AWS services and we
never use anything else so if something
spins up in another region or another
service this is probably a red flag
either a developers doing something new
that they maybe shouldn't be doing or
it's an attack you can also go further
and do this perhaps per app or per
service and this was described as well
as a bunch of other excellent ideas not
this most recent but the app set Callie
before that by will and Travis of
Netflix ok so the idea here is what are
things in your environment should that
should either always or never be true
either with your cloud environment or
your security controls or code and so
forth and then which of these can you
programmatically enforce or alert on and
the key intuition behind this is that if
you don't need any context to make the
decision right there's no sort of like
oh well sometimes this is ok but you
know there's all these other mitigating
factors which like a human needs to make
so if there isn't that then you can just
programmatically enforce it and then
there is no operational time for the
security team so you just sort of you
know whack that mole once you just don't
have to deal with that anymore and then
you spend your time on other things so
again we are trying to knock off things
from our plate to become strategically
more effective over time
so I would encourage you to think how is
what we're doing now making us more
effective in the future right so if it's
not I would consider D prioritizing it
and then obviously Gandhi also said this
okay so we covered a lot so let's put it
all together so I'm going to talk about
some things you can start doing
immediately like say this or next week
some things you can do in the medium
term and some things you can do in the
long term okay first step one is assess
figure out where you are now so evaluate
the fundamentals are you tracking all of
your vulnerabilities in one system are
you tracking the right metadata etc for
continuous scanning what sort of
capabilities do you have can you roll
out a new tool or remove a tool very
quickly and easily then asset inventory
what visibility do you have into your
environment and I would encourage you to
set up a meeting with security
leadership as well as developers subject
matter experts and figure out you know
based on where we are is there
vulnerability or asset inventory
information that we would like you know
is there promising projects we should do
and then in the three to nine month
three to nine months start building
based on what you've assessed so nail
the fundamentals so here's where we are
here's where we should be to have all of
these covered to build a strong base
from which we can build in the future
and then take on one bite-sized project
based on your historical vulnerability
data and your company's business factors
and risk so the key thing here is
bite-sized project right you don't want
to necessarily say oh let's do this
crazy complex massive project that's
only going to be valuable like two years
from now ideally it's something you can
do in a few weeks or in a few months so
that you can prove to yourself as well
as management and executive leadership
you know it pays to invest in things you
know we spent time building this thing
and look at all the security benefit
we're getting in the future you know we
used to spend a lot of time you know
triaging and fixing all of these issues
now we can spend that time on all these
other things and then in the future so
you've assessed you've built and now you
start scaling so you want to be more
highly leveraged with your time ideally
you can target specific vulnerability
class
and just eliminate them categorically
you can invest in projects with security
high security ROI and minimal ongoing
time requirements for example automating
lease lease privilege or invariants and
again you want to focus on areas that
meaningfully raise your security bar
right so there's things that might be
technically very interesting there's
things that might be fun to work on that
seem like they're going to be good but
are they actually going to move your
security needle are they going to raise
your security posture ok so let's just
quickly wrap up for some reason I
decided it would be good idea to watch
every apps at Kali 2019 talk and write a
detailed summary of them the clancer the
question you're thinking is it took
hundreds of hours but if you would like
to benefit from that you can read it
right there for free also I have a
newsletter where I summarized talks
linked to tools and resources I find
useful as well as write about things I
work on so at least one person doesn't
hate it so you might like it too ok so
thank you so much for your time these
slides are live already you can go right
there I'm happy to chat on Twitter as
well as LinkedIn again there's a link to
the newsletter if you think that that
robot is cute
I have an egregious number of stickers
in my pocket and in my backpack that I'd
be happy to give you and there's some
key insights from sort of the whole talk
in case that helps you with your
question asking and actually since I
have time I just wanted to say a big
thank you to all the people who did the
work that was referenced in this talk
you're really pushing the industry
forward and I and others have learned a
lot and I appreciate it and there's a
number of people who reviewed early
versions of this talk and gave me
excellent feedback so if you like this
talk you know big thanks to all these
people for making it happen so yeah I
believe I have a few minutes left for
questions and also when time runs out I
would be happy to chat here in the hall
etc so thanks again so much for your
time
all right everyone um please give me
join me in giving Clinton big thanks for
joining us if anyone has any questions
just raise your hand real high and I can
bring you the microphone you went over
here
hey great dockland you talked about fret
modeling as code can you explain a
little bit more what that is and how
it's different from just traditional
trip model
yeah that's a good question so the
question is can you provide a little bit
more detail about threat model less code
so there are a number of backup slides
that you can see on this but the idea is
can you express security properties you
want or abuse cases of the system in
sort of a security integration type test
such that they are continuously run as
the application is built that's
basically the core idea there's more
details but yet they're questions
raise your hand real high leave a cos in
the front if someone is gonna start an
application security rave from the
beginning like it's just a free-for-all
what would be a good way for them to
start if you could give them one or two
things to do what would be a favorite
advice that you would give to a company
okay thank you
so if it's a free-for-all where should
you start I think one thing that I
didn't talk about as much in this talk
because it didn't quite fit in his theme
but I think building really good
relationships with developers is
absolutely essential if you can have
just the culture of the company be aware
of security and even have the intuition
of like oh this is a thing that might
have security implication let me go
proactively talk with the security team
then that can go a long way before you
necessarily have built the
infrastructure to have like continuous
say asset inventory type visibility into
who's pushing code and what it's doing
so I would say definitely a bad I think
you can get a lot of nice wins by
tracking vulnerabilities in terms of
like what type of vulnerability was this
how much did we care
about it and and things like that
there's various metrics and
high-leverage things you can do but only
once you have the data so the earlier
you can start collecting it the sooner
you can start doing that but yeah thanks
so much for the question I think we have
time for one or two more I'll see one
right here I don't necessarily disagree
regards to suggestion that if you found
these kind of vulnerabilities let's keep
looking for these kind of
vulnerabilities when you're trying to
optimize your time but isn't there a
risk that you're looking for the things
the low-hanging fruit maybe is starting
to be whittled down and there's you
won't find it there and you maybe have
blind spots other places how do you
balance sort of looking for the things
you haven't discovered versus spending
more time and I've a live with that
low-hanging fruit yeah that's a that's a
really good question and I I don't think
there's necessarily a simple answer but
yeah so the question is here's the
issues you've had in the past if you
just focus on those maybe there's
important things you're blind to yeah I
think it definitely is easy to get
caught up in like oh here's the
historical vulnerability data let's
focus on those and not necessarily have
this be sort of continuously changing
over time I ideally as you're getting
better there are things that were
comparatively less of a problem that you
can now focus on and I think one
interesting unintuitive point that some
people don't think about is like as you
get better at a lot of these things
you're going to start finding more
issues that have always been there you
just didn't know they were there so in
the short term as you're improving from
a metrics point of view in terms of
number of vulnerabilities found it can
actually look worse right so I think one
security metric that is it initially you
might think is great like number of
vulnerabilities found can be deceiving
in that as you get better at finding
them you're gonna find more but yeah so
I agree with your point in that you
don't wanna be overly focused on just
like these issues are things we've had
in the past I think one way to get
around that is sort of holistically
maybe by annually or quarterly like
taking a step back and thinking are
there important business risks that we
are ignoring based on our current
process
there's a like mitre and mist have this
for example the cybersecurity framework
has like different areas and levels of
investment and things that you can sort
of have a standard to compare yourself
against similarly with open Sam but yeah
I think the key is to sort of
continuously relive that re-evaluate
where you are and what makes sense yeah
that's a really great question thank you
all right I think we are just about out
of time unless anyone has one last quick
question No
okay well then please join me in
thanking Clint Clint thank you so much
for being a speaker IP side thank you