want to introduce today's keynote
speaker speaking on what's new or not in
2020 are we making progress on the
intractable security problems we have
Larkin Ryder
she's the interim CEO at slack and here
you go oh all right let's move off the
big picture of my face oh okay Oh
yeah all right I'm gonna go ahead and
start in the interest of time because
the first few slides are mildly amusing
but really I can just stand here and
talk and and that'll be great so I am
excited to be here talking about the
next big thing but I'm going to talk
about the last 10 years of big things
instead in my presentation so we're all
grounded in our history something I know
I need to take more time to do speaking
of my history yes I am currently the
acting chief security officer at slack
and nobody's more surprised about that
than I am
right so how did that happen well I have
to blame in part these two well these
two gentlemen right here in 2004 my
manager decided to flee back to France
for an extended vacation at the end of
the year while we were completing our
survey Knox Lee audit and there was just
one thing left to do and that was to
secure the databases with the financial
statements in them of financial records
no problem right that's that's the core
of what you do for Sox and of course I
had zero experience at that time either
in security or databases so I was the
perfect person to take on this task in a
very small company I didn't mess that up
too badly it turns out so they let me
take a crack at messing with a network
as part of PCI DSS great wonderful you
can feel free to take my slides wherever
you want to if you need to move them and
if I have to work without my speaker
notes it's it's whatever I found of mine
I'll just make something out that's fine
that's what I was gonna do anyway
so that went okay and that led me on to
working in the enterprise security team
at Twitter and then working at slack as
the director of risk and compliance and
then director of product security and
apparently the natural progression from
doing all that is to be the acting chief
security officer great
okay let's get back to where we were all
right and then here we are at b-sides
booth celebrating our tenth anniversary
exactly if this is actually I'm so
excited to be here because this is
actually my favorite conference that I
go to of all the security conferences
that I have been to so far I haven't
found what I like more than b-sides it's
local I don't have to travel it's the
right size and I get to see a bunch of
people who I look forward to seeing
every time I can't walk down the hall
without collecting like ten hugs all
right so what have we done in the last
ten years to bring us here what have we
accomplished well to have that
conversation I want to have that
conversation but first I'm going to
treat you all to a little story so my
husband and I a little while ago we're
looking at combining some investment
accounts right so we had to get on the
phone with the agent who had the
separate account they were all in one
company but separate accounts we wanted
to bring them together the agent is like
okay let me ask you some identity
information so the agent is collecting
like your name your birthday or social
security number etcetera and that miss
Ryder I have one last security question
for you can you please tell me what is
the name of the street you grew up on
okay I you know typey typey look it up
all right all right
Capital D % open question mark smiley
face and lowercase P uppercase number
one you know whatever I had a long
string and I read it off and that was
that was the answer to that question and
then thank you miss Ryder that's correct
mr. Ryder can I ask you please tell me
the name of your first pet and my
husband his eyes get a little wide and
then his shoulders just start shaking
with laughter and he says Rover and that
is what it's like in my house all right
so talking about the attend the events
of the last ten years that shaped our
perception I'm gonna talk a little bit
about some fun malware some great data
breaches and some awesome
vulnerabilities starting right away with
malware remember when I thought about
malware when I first started out in my
security career my perception was that
ruins somebody's day you know that's too
bad that happened to that other person
over there on their one computer and
nobody else is impacted and that's
annoying but I didn't really think of it
as anything that was particularly
earth-shattering world-changing
important all right well let's jump into
2010 okay because that's when Stuxnet
really became something that we were
allowed to become aware of and this is a
really interesting story so we're maybe
talking about 20 million dollars in
centrifuges that were damaged by Stuxnet
but really the implications defy math
here right this is for those of you who
don't know the malware that was
introduced to the uranium enrichment
facility in Natanz so this had the
purpose of disrupting the the Iranian
ability to enrich uranium it was a
program that was started by the US
government and it's it's fascinating how
it progressed if you haven't read Kim's
letters countdown to zero daybook I
really recommend it it's a it's an
amazing read I can't wait to see who's
in the movie all right and then wanna
cry of course landed many years later
this was one of the most dominant pieces
of ransomware for billion dollars were
impacted across 150 countries and then
not Pecha was really fun not really
ransomware this ostensibly was the the
Russian government trying to destabilize
Ukraine I think something like around 70
percent of the infections where we're in
that one geographic location right so
this again like Stuxnet was very
targeted I think the introduction point
was some document that was widely used
for filing taxes in the Ukraine or
something so of course with all malware
it wasn't just you contained to the
Ukraine I bet some of these other US
companies global companies that were
impacted maybe they had to file taxes in
the Ukraine and they were impacted as
well alright so talking about data
breaches here's a list of data breaches
it's a small list compared to the actual
number of daily briefing list it really
focuses on some of the larger breeches
they would look larger if Yahoo didn't
look so big sorry about that Yahoo it's
just how things are when you have three
billion is your your winning number
but Yahoo is is one of my favorite
breeches as well because there you know
there are great records that I've seen
I've seen great presentations about the
Yahoo breach and understanding that this
is a case where we got from
identification you know all the way
through prosecution to conviction for
the people who are responsible like yeah
I hope that's something that we can do
more of if we work harder on our
attribution capabilities in this case
names email addresses telephone numbers
birthday it's passwords and security
questions were all impacted so Adult
Friend Finder is a it's possibly a
different motivation this one in Ashley
Madison maybe you know those are
motivated by people who are making a
moral judgment on the users of these
sites but again you have some very
private data that's being impacted here
as well in this case plain text or
weekly hash passwords were included ok
target takes me all the way back to my
pci-dss roots right so looking at this
particular compromise of these
point-of-sale systems it was one of
those cases where the hackers had to go
in and fix bugs in the point-of-sale
systems that way they were attempting to
corrupt because they had a plan right
they had you know a couple of weeks
before Black Friday to get their malware
in there get it stable get it working
through the holiday season to get the
credit the payment card and debit card
information that they wanted out of that
environment so they made sure that
malware was good they had to of course
have access to the server that was
cryptographically signing all the
downloads to the point-of-sale systems
so you know yay for network segmentation
and then they had to have an exfil path
and this is where famously a vendor was
involved in the breach as well we can
talk about that in a bit
all right so vulnerabilities earning
names there's so many here you're not
going to see your favorite they're just
too many favorite vulnerabilities but
but heartbleed was the one that really
stuck in my consciousness is one of the
first one a memory leak in the open SSL
implementation for the tls heartbeat
extension this meant that anything that
you were actually trying to encrypt on
open networks was potentially available
to someone who had access to that data
stream so very scary because you know
again payment card data passwords you
know private medical history information
anything could be exposed through this
next up were meltdown inspector very
interesting because they were at the
hardware architecture level and of
course if you're working on a in a
processing environment where you have
shared a hardware stack then you're
worried about processes being able to
read the data of each other and then
eternal blue okay eternal blue was
actually the vulnerability that was
behind want to cry and not Petya this
was a mishandled SMB protocol packet
that allowed malicious code execution
and this one was interesting because
this was known for a long time by the
NSA and they chose not to disclose it so
that they could capitalize on it it was
then eventually disclosed by shadow
brokers all right so how have we been
changed by these events well I certainly
just developed an increasing interest in
information security as a result of
being aware of all these things but
certainly we have to think about how
that perception has changed person you
know think about how those events have
changed perception more globally so this
is a study that was done by the World
Economic Forum and it's a global risk
perception survey and you'll notice that
number five and number eight on this
list are cyber attacks so this is the
list of things that they think will
increase and be impactful in the next
decade I think part of that perception
has to be defined by the media so one
thing I've noticed as I read the paper
every day and I do and that's the
sidewalk in front of my house where the
paper actually in physical form gets
delivered every day and these are three
articles that I found related to
information security in that were in the
paper in one day so I think that
heightened awareness is something that
we're all experiencing but the media is
bringing it to into everybody's
consciousness but a lot of other things
besides awareness chain
in the last decade things materially
changed in the way we get our job done
and I want to talk about some of the
trends that I think are reshaping
working lives certainly we have to talk
about the cloud certainly we have to
talk about privacy regulation and the
ubiquity of mobile devices that I see
literally right now pointing at me from
around this audience so talking first
about cloud so when I first started in
computer science my my first job out of
college was testing network equipment
for Hewlett Packard so I quickly learned
that I did not wear nice clothes for
that job because what you were going to
be doing is there was this little mini
data that desks all around the perimeter
and then in the center of the building
is the data center where you go in there
and you actually are installing these
network devices and you're pulling up
the floor tiles and you're running the
cables because that's how networks were
built they were actually built in those
days that was that is not what we're
doing right now right we have switched
completely to virtualized environment
and software-defined networking is what
we use every day and of course the most
important device in that environment was
the firewall that we were using to
protect it but now our perimeter is
really identity security of some
combination of your your human users and
the passwords they use and hopefully
two-factor and probably you know their
devices is our trust anchor and their
email or trust anchor for making sure
all that is working the way you want it
to work as a security professional and
then finally that perimeter because now
it's nice and virtualized is evolving at
an incredible rate you can sign up for a
new service faster than I can run that
cable under that floor for sure now one
of the things that really helps that and
I work at slack which is definitely part
of this problem I realize that is I put
this slide up here with someone else's
company is that we have both free and
paid tiers that are available to your
users so your users are you know having
a great time you know going and finding
whatever it is they need and then
clicking the accept button on those
terms of service and then uploading your
company's private data there whether
they're really authorized to agree to
those terms of service on behalf
your company that might be something
that you want to remind them about and
of course then you have all of that data
ending up in the private cloud right on
that in that in the in the cloud so
you're probably as a security
professional thinking oh what can I do
to make sure I'm tracking all the data
that's ending up in that you're probably
thinking about more cloud services that
you're gonna buy to help you track that
data that's ending up in the cloud or
you know maybe you actually have a
controlled networking environment and a
cosby and you want to go old-school with
that but again what you're doing is
you're bringing more vendors into the
equation and this puts more I'm over you
know vendor vendor risk management
vendor security review was definitely
something that I thought about in 2010
but now it's just like this is like I
need more people for that we need a
better solution as a community for how
we establish trust with all the vendors
that we rely on and that is important
because every vendor that is on this
screen here was material in a breach a
significant breach probably one of the
ones on the list
Fazio was the mechanical service that
controlled the HVAC system that was the
exfil vector for the target
point-of-sale malware all right and of
course vector and meltdown
so we already which we already talked
about right but we're all hosting data
on these shared services so so our
hosting environment it was also a cloud
environment it's also a virtualized
environment so you know basically every
one of my customers was like I need to
talk to the C so now when Spector and
meltdown became a thing because they
wanted to know that their private data
in my AWS environment was being
protected from specter and meltdown all
right so one of the good things that I
think has happened because you can't
just spend all our time talking about
the bad things that have happened is
privacy the privacy regulation that has
come forward in the last 10 years has
been certainly significant we have two
things that are of importance mostly in
the EU we have GD P R and then here in
California we have C CPA so that's the
general data
tection regulation and the California
consumer Privacy Act both of those give
some protections on these areas right it
makes sure that you as a user have
permission or are granting permission
both for the processing and in some
cases the selling of your data you can
have your data removed the right to be
forgotten as it's commonly known you
have visibility to the data that's being
stored about you you have a requirement
for breach notices you have some data
portability so you don't get locked in
in one particular vendor because they
have so much of your data you have the
right to remove that information and
then there are monetary penalties
penalties in my favorite one the right
to private action that means for example
under CCP a that you as the consumer
have a right if you have non-encrypted
non redacted personal information and it
is subject to unauthorized access
exfiltration disclosure as a result of
the business failing to maintain
security procedures and practices that
are appropriate so this is saying that
we as cloud service providers as holders
of consumer data have to make sure that
we're doing right by the consumer with
respect to security or they have the
right to come after us appropriately one
the only thing I don't like about all
the privacy regulation is that it does
take resources away from everything else
I'm trying to do for security because I
have to rush over to whatever that
regulation is I have to you know walk
through that checklist of security
requirements and making sure that I'm
doing all of them and they are vague
they're not prescriptive they're they're
very broad I have to like actually talk
to lawyers about how to interpret them
and whether they really map to my system
of controls or not or you know do I have
a gap and what is everyone else doing
and has there been litigation that's
decided what good looks like about you
know what you do with IP addresses for
example I would love it if there were a
more prescriptive standard that everyone
could agree to everyone could align on
and you know just go do ISO 27001 and
everybody don't be good something like
that all right okay so now let's talk
about bring your own device the mobile
devices are ubiquitous and I love mobile
devices
they are great than easy to use the apps
are just downright almost fun even if
their work based you know it's easy
token based access for getting whatever
you want there are notifications coming
to my device all the time everybody
loves me isn't that great and it's but
from my perspective easy to FA right
this is a way for me to put a second
factor of authentication in front of my
entire you know identity protected
perimeter that will actually be usable
for my user so I'm happy about that
and there are biometrics there which I
have mixed feelings about biometrics are
potentially complex from a privacy point
of view but for users who need it if
they need a biometric to authorize
themselves and keep that second factor
or easy enough to use I'll take it
but there's the problem of loss right
we've had this problem for a while but
it's really more so with the expection
of there's an expectation of mobility
among our employees right so they have
their mobile devices and they expect to
be able to use them for the work that
they do they're putting data on those
devices they're putting the tokens on
those devices that are there potentially
at risk this has increased the use of
laptops in my opinion I think the two go
hand in hand people just expect to be
moving around more and that can create
problems for the company now one is of
course lost it's extremely embarrassing
when you know laptops and devices get
lost and that exposes the information
there certainly for the company I I did
a meaningless study where I collected
five years of data to see you know what
happens to laptops and you know what's
the behavior there yeah cars and bars
pretty much if you're losing a laptop or
personal device it's either gonna be
because you left it in your car or you
took it to a bar and you know I know
everybody does those things just just
letting you know and then there's the
complexity of the fact that you're
putting your company's data on your
personal device whether you're using a
personal laptop or a personal phone how
many people here right now today are
carrying two phones for this very reason
okay yeah that's that's about what I
thought right I mean they're like maybe
it's maybe five to ten percent of the
people here have
probably are doing that because they've
been through this before and the rest of
you haven't been through this yet so
you're not doing it but once you have
you will because if your company ever
needs to take your device from you and
get a complete image for of it
for discovery purposes you are not going
to feel very comfortable about having
that ever happen to you a second time
and then malware is increasingly
becoming something that we have to worry
about in the mobile device ecosystem
humming bad was installed on 10 million
devices this is III won't go into detail
here but that is a that is an Android
system malware I think going back to
2016 and there as many as 24,000
malicious apps that are being blocked
every day so how many are actually being
stalled like it's an incredible
it's an incredible volume and something
that I think we don't have a great
handle on all right I am going to give
you another story here hang on I got to
remember it because I don't actually I'm
not actually working from speaker notes
up here in case you couldn't tell
this was the one where which one was
this Arkady
do you remember damn it Oh oh yeah I
remember so my husband called his credit
union he was he needed to close out his
account so the agent picks up the phone
yes my husband's like yeah I want to
close my account yes there is a charge
for that it's a dollar 95 to close your
account and I'll need a credit card from
you and my husband's what you're gonna
charge me to close my account that's
ridiculous and sir if you want your
account closed you have to pay the
dollar 95 fee but I'm ready to take your
credit card number at any time I my
husband's like no I'm not gonna pay you
for that and the agent hangs up on him
at which point my husband notices that
he has Mis dialed the number for his
credit union and whoever he was talking
to was actually not an agent of that
company just some guy who was collecting
credit card numbers and I don't know
probably more than a dollar 95 at a time
all right so I don't make predictions
about things
if I were to make predictions I'd
probably make these three that we're
going to see a lot more
internet-of-things participation in
virus distribution and botnets I've
heard I you know when I was getting
ready for this presentation and looking
around about things one of the things
that kept coming up was machine learning
because machine learning is all the rage
I can't wait to see the battle between
the machine learning systems that are
going to introduce them malware and the
machine learning systems that are going
to remove the malware I know who I'm
rooting for but we'll see
and then the vulnerability of Skadden
infrastructure I think there was a
recent Senate bill that was passed that
was going to suggest that maybe more of
our critical control systems should be
analog and not digital all right so
these are the things that have been
changing but how have these changes in
the last 10 years
you know impacted the struggles that we
have with information security well I
think we talked a little bit about how
the cloud is changing things but I think
there's some things that continue and I
want to focus now on kind of the
constants the work that continues and I
think user behavior continues to matter
deeply and I'm going to talk a little
bit about detection I kind of have a bee
in my bonnet on detection right now I
always have one on user behavior all
right so this is what I call the
checklist of the impossible this is the
list of things that people tell users
that they always have to do and I call
this the checklist of the impossible
because while it is still important for
security it is also a nassima to most of
the work that our users are doing right
there in the cloud all the time the
cloud runs on links those links are
going to show up and you know
attachments as downloads from those
services all of these are things that I
know most of the people I work with they
have to interact with every single day
so telling them oh you know how you do
your work don't do it that way seems
like an impossible ask to me staying
patched is something I'd like us to
solve those problems I'd like us to
figure out how we can make sure things
just update seamlessly and automat
and without too much user interruption
maybe minimize what level is needed if
that's possible I realized that there's
still 1 million machines vulnerable to
eternal blue so this must be a hard
problem for people right they must
really need our support to figure out
how to solve it all right and I know
phishing is still the top thread action
so I know people are still clicking on
links and entering their credentials but
again we have to figure out how to make
sure that that's something they can do
safely this this is the second half of
that checklist and this is slightly less
impossible right so we can probably
avoid USBs USB drives probably VPN is
barely available for us it's I don't
know I don't pack up my data it's all
just in the cloud right and it's
important to note that the USB that was
the entry point for Stuxnet right so for
those of you who don't know if you're
trying to get software into a secret
facility in Iran you don't have a lot of
network entry points so it is still an
interesting and valid vector for attack
but whatever you're trying to do you
probably have a cloud service that will
let you do these things you don't have
to use USBs to move big files around
anymore but if I could simplify it for
the user if I could make it easier for
them if I could say look they're really
these are the only things that you have
to you know if I had to give a new user
onboarding in five minutes this would be
the checklist that I would use if you
see something say something probably the
only time I was ever directly involved
in a company that was experiencing an
active attacker that was on their
network and attempting to exfiltrate
data came to light because one database
engineer noticed one query on one server
that was running too long on optimized
queries you know on our database tier
that shouldn't be happening hey Joe
look there's this on optimize query huh
bill that's odd
let's go tell security and that is
that attack came to light for the
security team that day could have gone
so much differently for that company I
think this is one of the most important
things we can tell our users all right
use what I gave you please don't go up
and sign up for the free tier customer
data is off-limits that's kind of
obvious and if you don't understand why
I'm adding friction for you tell me that
you don't understand cuz I would love to
explain it to you I really would
my experience is 99.99% of the people
that you work with they just want to do
the right thing and they don't
understand why they they have to choose
between right thing a and right thing B
and you're there to help them
rationalize that all right and this is
the final thing that I have that I am
concerned about detection how much more
time do I have left by the way I have 20
minutes Oh awesome okay we can I can
really I can really grind this axes when
I'm hearing here so let me go back
actually to this slide so I was in a
room recently with a team of other CISOs
and we were talking about metrics and we
were talking about how hard it is to
define metrics for our industry how do
we meaningfully explain the great job
we're doing as CISOs in building a
security program and protecting the
sensitive data that is in our care and
it's hard to find a metric that
represents your progress towards
preventing something from happening
which is what you're really trying to do
as a CSO and one of the things that we
know is important is our ability to
detect when the bad thing happens and so
we were talking about red team and
attacks and you know the time to detect
and and how quickly we can we can do
that and is that a valid simulation or
are we kidding ourselves and in kind of
the consensus in the room settled down
to yeah we're gonna get owned and we're
not going to know it and then we're
gonna get fired and then all the ceases
are gonna stand up and shift right one
company and sit down again
like yeah that's probably what's gonna
happen but man that's that right like
why aren't we gonna know what why can't
we tell we get so much data we know that
the most attacked industry is going to
be health care it's gonna be organized
crime it's going to be a financial
motivation we have a lot of information
that we should be relying on about what
the threats are to the environment that
we're working on and we should use that
data to understand who is coming after
us and how they are coming after us
so here's what it's worth right we even
know how much we need to spend because
we can take this data on what it's worth
to the attacker and we can figure out
how many people they're gonna need what
equipment they're gonna buy how much
they're gonna pay for those zero days so
that that they can get something of
value to them so we know exactly how
much they're spending on what they're
gonna buy we know a little bit about
what what they're gonna buy is going to
look like and what it's going to cost
them we can use that data to figure out
what we should be spending in defense
based on the information that that we
have I know health care isn't spending
that money because you can see how
challenged they are just to provide the
services that they're trying to provide
in this country in order to really do
right by their patients but you know
last time I went to a new health care
provider they had to take a copy of my
driver so they had to look at my
driver's license and I think they took a
copy of it when they copied my insurance
card because that insurance card is just
a flimsy peep a piece of paper that
anyone could make a copy of and they
could say hey I'm Larkin Rider I need a
new kidney by the way and you know it's
it just it's trivially easy unless they
can secure my identity with another
piece of collateral so I understand why
they took it and what I'm hoping is is
they took that piece of paper and they
put it in a file and they locked it in a
drawer and they didn't like you know
upload it to a system but I don't know
for sure right so you know we see how
much the health care industry gets
ransomed and that worries me because I
was talking with a friend and he was
saying yeah my concern is that the
ransomware that we hear about at
hospitals is just the visible example
how the healthcare industry is under
attack but they're really so owned in
every other way that they're working and
they have zero detection so they just
don't know it because detection to be
clear I know it's a hard problem like I
know it is not easy to figure out your
detection story but if this if I'd land
no other message in this presentation
and this is why I put this one at the
end is that we are the people who have
to be responsible for changing that
mindset and that attitude we have to
change that attitude in ourselves and
with the people that we work for how
will you know if you're owned how what
are what are the indicators that you
have and maybe you're like lark and I
got nothing I'm starting from zero maybe
I'm the first engineer at this company
that's thinking about security and I
haven't got a dollar - my budgets name
or a clue of how I'm going to move
forward well I would say start somewhere
right just pick one thing you've got to
start somewhere pick one thing that you
think is important and understand that
one thing in detail get those logs get
new logs if you need them study what
normal looks like and then build rules
on what abnormal looks like when it
occurs
red team rinse repeat so I worked for a
while for Bob Lord at Twitter and I read
a blog post he wrote one time it was
really interesting it was based on the
idea that if you need to build a new
security team and you don't have a
budget for it one of the things you
could do is just find enough money to
hire some red team bring in that red
team don't you know don't do anything to
secure the systems don't put any
preventive measures in place just go in
with the red team and test them and test
them and test them and just keep showing
people how you're owning them over and
over and over again until the people who
actually own the systems and care about
the data and understand what the risk of
the disclosure is they're they'll either
hire their own security team or give you
one I think that's an interesting
perspective I think they're good things
and bad things about that approach and
things that do
don't work in the business that I'm
currently in but it's interesting and
frankly I've always wanted to try it so
if any of you are in that position and
you're the first security engineer and
you're wondering how you're gonna get
through securing all of this
infrastructure you have let me know if
you're interested in try that I'd be
interested to know how that works out
for you all right
so in closing how do we keep on when we
have so much on our plate when we have
so many things you know I put this
presentation together and I'm like oh
man this is depressing like there is too
much here to think about how do we keep
from going crazy with this you know
infinite bag of risks that we all feel
like we have to manage well I have some
ideas for you three really simple things
first of all please recognize your
burden I know I have to spend a lot of
time not thinking about that burden as
the person who is ultimately responsible
at SLAC but every now and then please
stop and recognize what you're doing and
how it's important and how you feel
about that and make sure that you're not
not thinking about it too hard and then
bound your efforts this is a strategy
that I've had to use and I've had to ask
my team to use you have an infinite
backlog of risk that you're trying to
manage don't try to boil that ocean
don't try to deal with it all at once
prioritize ruthlessly and work on the
first thing and let everything else wait
to the next sprint you can't do it all
at once you'll go crazy and then finally
lean on your community this is why we're
here so we have our community with us so
we get to spend a couple hours on one
week talking to the people who really
understand what we're doing what we're
struggling with and how hard it can be
and maybe even get some tips for making
it a little bit better thank you so much
all right do I get to answer some
questions now thank you so much thank
you I appreciate it I appreciate it have
a great day everyone so you're out there
[Applause]