so thank you for joining me here so late
in the day and so close to happy hour
for my talk sharks in the water open
source component risk and mitigation
okay to a good start okay so who is this
Erin guy so prior to moving into
security I was a full-stack engineer
building products and in that journey I
was introduced to the security champion
program from there I grew a deep
fascination and passion for security so
much so that I decided to jump in
full-time and start working as a
security engineer at SCI scence where I
focus on hardening our cloud assets I
manage our bug bounty program
collaborate closely with our platform
team to get in to dig into the
nitty-gritty of our ever-increasing
codebase and build and integrate tooling
that makes sense for us but enough about
me this compass is our meta navigation
table which helps set a course for where
we're going today we'll start with the
component risk landscape diving into the
numbers of the open source software
supply chain which I'm calling OS 3c
mostly because I got tired of typing os
SSC attack surface and why this is
important then we'll make our way to
manually navigating murky waters and how
placing trust and our teams is paramount
to success on this journey finally we'll
wrap it up with Cretan and autopilot
system that will complement the process
that we've already put in place so by
the end of this talk you should have a
solid understanding of the risk how to
navigate the murky waters of the open
source supply chain and how to provide
the necessary context and knowledge to
stakeholders of all kinds across your
organization let me begin this section
by saying that while these numbers may
seem like I am bashing the open source
community I'm certainly not
I love open source I use it constantly
especially in all other products that
I'm building and all the tooling that
I'm building as well so there's a lot of
good in open source software
it increases engineering
city allows for near limitless
extensibility and is generally well
tested however not all components are
created equal and as we progress through
today's talk we'll see why education and
awareness among engineering teams is in
many cases more important than the
automated tooling we love to build into
our pipelines so to fully understand the
OS 3c landscape I think it's important
to first get an idea of the growth that
has occurred from 2017 to 2019 there's
been a 75% growth of newly released
packages across all repositories in just
two years time two of the leading
leaders in terms of percent increase our
NPM and crates do which is rusts
repository so JavaScript's NPM repo with
over 8,000 new people contributing
annually has grown at a rate of one
hundred and nine percent over two years
so from roughly 400,000 packages to now
well over eight hundred 36,000 and as of
today it's well over a million the
fastest of them all though is rust
crates IO package manager growing from
7,000 packages to now over 25,000 in
just two years time this is pretty rapid
growth so much so that the engineering
community has access to almost 22,000
new component releases every single day
since 2018 there's an impressive amount
of work being done across all industries
and most of it is fueled by the open
source community it affords us much more
rapid prototyping and development it
increases our velocity in other words
our time to deliver software has now
accelerated at a phenomenal rate we can
pull down and spin up a database just by
running one docker command we can extend
upon that functionality which is the
core of open source software
we're engineering teams are constantly
coming up with new and unique ways to
use average component building at a top
their software to fit their needs in
general solve open source software has
integrity it's well tested and it's
widely contributed to as with anything
though there comes an inflection point
which forces balance back into the
universe
annually enterprise organizations
download roughly three hundred and
thirteen thousand new OSC releases every
year of those downloads twenty-eight
thousand of them have at least one
vulnerability and with those
vulnerabilities eighteen thousand five
hundred of them have CVE scores at seven
or above and eight thousand of those
have scores at or greater than nine so
the chances of one vulnerable one
vulnerability and one popular component
infecting some of the largest companies
in the world is very real in fact as I'm
sure everyone in this room is already
aware it's already happened and it's
happened more than once in fact open
source components contributed to 31% of
breaches in 2018 these made up a lot of
what could be called a targeted breach
you can make the argument that all
breaches are targeted but we all know
the amount of crap adversaries through
our firewall just to see if it sticks so
when I say targeted breach I mean those
that specify specifically target open
source components so with those numbers
in mind it becomes very clear why
attackers target open source components
but let's dive in a little bit deeper
there is broad adoption among open
source components 97% of code and modern
web applications come from NPM which has
a vulnerability rate of 51 percent so
let me repeat that 97% of code in modern
web apps comes from NPM of which the
majority of the package is downloaded
from there have known vulnerabilities
and this ties directly into what I mean
by pervasive there are of course
different ways we could unpack the word
pervasive in this context instead I'll
just ask by show of hands how many of
you have dependencies you can't update
yeah all right this is exactly the
reason why we see vulnerable versions of
Apache struts still being used in the
wild it's crazy so if you're not
updating regularly it's going to become
more and more painful the ability to
update quickly becomes critical when
adversaries have compressed the times
between vulnerability announcement to
exploit from 45 days to 3 days
and in the case where they are directly
injecting malicious code into open
source projects which is not just
theoretical it drops to zero day
vulnerability so how do we do all this
as a security team well we don't it's
all about placing trust in our teams and
our counterparts across the organization
so the first step in this journey is
don't be in a hab we're not going to be
able to control everything as Frederick
Lee mentioned this morning our engineers
are the experts of our codebase
they're the ones who have all of the
context our engineers and our product
leads our champions and our advocates
remember your development team is not
your white whale so to keep your
application and the people who power to
float above the depths it's our role to
guide the wheel and lean in when
requested and when it's necessary this
comes in three parts building education
raising awareness and creating
partnership for education is all about
finding space if your organization has
lightning talks or lunch and learns or
some other forum in which you can share
that's a great space for sharing the
knowledge otherwise create a slack
channel to share hacks but you know put
together a write-up and outline the
cause and remediation as well lead
in-depth comprehensive sessions about
all the cool you're building in the
dev psych-out space create a time in a
forum to engage no matter what you want
to teach on share your risk evaluation
techniques so help your devs and your
product partners better understand the
risk of a feature or component let them
drive it awareness expose a dashboard
with all the aggregated scan results in
one place open it up for your
stakeholders like your execs your
product leads and your engineers to view
you'll be surprised at some of the
outcomes you can get from that add your
engineering team to your github security
alerts if you're not aware this is as
easy as flipping a switch in your
organization from there you can actually
set up an automated bot that will update
a lot of the components for you
typically if they're transitive you
won't get much help there but at least
you can get the direct dependencies
updated with a bot
slack channels for volatile Ertz share
the knowledge you'll probably find that
most of your engineers will proactively
update the last but not least part of
this is partnership partner with your
architects in your platform team and
your engineers this can help you find
gaps in your own understanding and put
you in a position where they're
comfortable to come to you with issues
communicate vulnerabilities to your
team's the best defense against attack
is sharing what has come before hoarding
or restricting knowledge is not where we
should focus we should focus on getting
better together build a shared model of
responsibility any of you who are
familiar with AWS will be familiar with
this phrase security is about ownership
across many levels not just one has been
mentioned multiple times today we cannot
be everywhere and I don't know about you
but I don't want to be everywhere with
partnership in mind this is a simple but
helpful component evaluation tool it's a
great way to engender the idea of shared
responsibility encourage your team to
use this to evaluate their import prior
to consumption so when was the last time
the component was updated this can
easily see be seen by navigating to the
change log within the repo or typically
you can just look at the file contents
themselves and see when the last time
was updated if you see a component has
not been updated for four years it's
likely not something you want inside
your codebase popularity what kind of
attention does it get from the open
source community if it's on github are
there stars and Watchers how is the
documentation does it seem like you can
work with this and for vulnerabilities I
recommend they go to resources like CVE
details or NIST's national vulnerability
database to search for known
vulnerability within those components
check out the issue tracker as well it's
a primary metric that I like to use are
their maintain errs responsive to the
community do they respond thoughtfully
and help consumers with their product
and their API if it's a unpopular
project there may not be many issues
however it's a popular one and you see
a lot of issues that are not getting
resolved that may tell you that it's not
something you want to work with and
thoughtful imports are the intersection
of them all this is where you can talk
to your Inge team about being mindful
about what they are importing one of the
first things I bring up is the
unfortunate scenario of left pad I'm
sure a lot of people in this room have
heard of that but if you haven't it's an
NPM called package the developer
unpublished it it was an 11 line piece
of code that once it was unpublished
baroque node babel Travis CI and a lot
of the other applications and tools
open-source tooling is all about not
reinventing the wheel but in my humble
opinion there are wheels and there are
blunt tools left pad was a blunt tool
that could have been written instead of
imported applying autopilot is where we
get to chat about that sweet sweet
automation
I remember automation is only a
complement to all the other processes
we've already established like
partnership and education the first
piece scanning is the most
straightforward and why do I say choose
a tool even myself as someone who loves
to build and write code unless you have
unlimited time or resources building
your own scanner is just not a viable
option instead you're going to choose a
tool maybe and even though maybe even an
open-source one you can see if it can
scan itself and this in my opinion is a
wheel no need to spend the man-hours on
something on building something that can
be acquired relatively cheaply you also
need to decide on your trigger will it
be a cron job running in a cube cluster
or will it be triggered by every PR into
your master branch
either way the output needs to be
consumable so configure in such a way
that allows for easy consumption
ingestion this will allow us to model
and reduce unnecessary noise it allows
it gives us more agility so we can
change and react to our software
development lifecycle and a more
predictable and controlled way so it
allows us to act on our own best
assumptions
and even adjust some of our worst ones
down the line we can use it to reduce
noise it's possible to tweak your
scanning tools to reduce the noise as
much as possible during configuration
however there are instances where we
want to have more fine-grained control
building an ingestion API gives us the
ability to shape and transform the data
any way we like and this is what makes
data modeling so important upon
ingestion we need to then be able to
pull out that data and make sense of it
so unless you're using a really cool
tool that can materialize those views
for you on the fly where you don't have
to worry about remodeling your data it's
an incredibly important thing to start
getting right at first so report this is
where we aggregate and visualize in
intelligible ways and distribute to
stakeholders this is a good place to
build a high-level executive dashboard
so there are no more ad hoc reports and
everything will be at their fingertips
and share since we've already
established a partnership with our
engineering counterparts we can work
with them to get deeper insights into
the findings to gain more learning and
then we repeat the process all over
again so thank you besides us F for
inviting me to speak here today and
happy ten years thank you to my team who
is out here and thanks to all of you for
being here today
and I'll see you at happy hour
[Applause]
do you mind repeating that yes so white
source I would say that I've had to
build a whole lot of automation around
it in order to get it to function the
way that I want it to however I would
say that's one of a reasonably
affordable one that for us was on the
market and there's some decent
open-source ones out there as well
a wasp as one
curious how your analysis might change
if you include those security issues
so I want to make sure I understand the
question how would I how would I assign
how would I work with the security
issues
yeah it the numbers that I was using
came from a open source software supply
chain report put out by Sona type if I
were to apply my own automation to it I
would I would definitely pull down these
security issues that I get from packages
I don't know how that would change the
numbers but I imagine it would go up
substantially does that answer your
question yes right it's a hard question
and I say it's hard mostly because it's
something that you need to decide upon
within your own organization the way
that we address it is we look at medium
and up and that's just because there's a
lot of other work that we're trying to
get done and we work on addressing the
medium to high to critical risks first
and that is what we bring up in the
dashboards as well we pay attention to
those lows and we try to address address
them over time but they are prioritized
much much lower yes
yes yeah I would use dependency scanner
which is the one that a wasp puts out
Jeremy long is the maintainer on that
and that's one that I would recommend
it's hard like his continuous monitoring
all those dependencies any ideas or tips
that can help with kind of a monitoring
like that you've decided to use it how
this thing is about
yeah so transitive dependencies are a
incredibly hard thing to manage you have
to go through different layers to update
to find that resolution path to update
and oftentimes working down that path
you're gonna find you'll end up breaking
your product along the way I don't have
a really good answer around how to
manage the transitive dependencies
outside of setting up in something like
a yarn lock you can or a package.json
you can actually set up the resolve
dependencies routes and then I would
just make sure you're not breaking your
sweets there there is a tool out there
though that will actually climb that
resolution dependency for you and update
it in an automated way
I see overtime so that goes back to
reporting and having a visualization or
at least some kind of tracker that way
you can have a an age of a vulnerable
component and that way you can point to
either different teams that are using
this to ask if there's something that
they can use in lieu of this component
especially there's a few out there that
keep popping up for us
that have a boner ability after
vulnerability I don't know if that helps
answer your question yes so what I
typically end up doing there is I meet
with a couple of our engineering
engineering managers and a couple of our
product leads once a month to resolve
things that are coming from our bug
bounty program unless it's critical of
course and also things that our scanners
are finding as well and that way we can
meet on a regular cadence and help
resolve these on a regular cadence and
it feels like a less of an ambush and an
ad-hoc request and it becomes more of a
process that we continue to refine over
time
yeah I'm tired yeah so I think the best
way to do that is to actually reproduce
or find some reproduction of it there's
a whole lot of YouTube resources out
there where you can find people actually
taking well exploiting these
vulnerabilities and that's a nice way to
humanize it and move it further away
from the scanner and move it closer to
the individual level and where you can
actually show this is something that you
can actually do in the wild and
something that we should consider
escalating and moving up the priority
chain and I mean try try doing it
yourself because that's always a lot of
fun to hack on right
[Applause]