I'm really happy to present our speakers
we have Anne Ricketts and Hillary
spriter who are going to teach you about
transforming your presentation skills
thanks very much hi everyone Hey so as a
presentation skills coach I'm always on
the lookout for examples of great
presenters and recently I was online I
was looking for some videos and I
stumble across a video from the 1980s
and this video appeared to be of a woman
in her 80s giving a presentation and as
I watched her I was blown away first of
all her delivery was so confident there
was about a hundred people in the room
and she was owning it it even looked
like she was having fun in addition she
had this great connection this great
rapport with the audience even though
she was doing the majority of the
speaking it felt like a conversation she
was telling jokes getting interaction
and then finally her content was so
simple and clear she was giving a
technical presentation to a
non-technical audience and to make this
idea understandable she had this prop
this piece of wire she's holding in her
hand and this analogy that she was using
it was super easy and engaging do any of
you know who this is
she knows the Grace Hopper Grace Hopper
and what do you know about her you can
yell it out what are some things you
know about her
what's that Cobalts okay bugs yeah she
was a she was a lieutenant crown yeah
she was a very impressive lady and a
pioneer in computer science and I knew
some of those things but until I saw
this video I had no idea that in
addition she was this fabulous presenter
and watching grace got me thinking about
what she was doing in the 80s compared
to what we often do today in
presentations today this scenario is not
super uncommon for internal
presentations I'm sure you all see
presentations all the time what do you
notice about presentations today that is
not engaging
powerpoints okay laptops yeah so if the
audience is on your laptop when you're
presenting that's difficult
we've got PowerPoint maybe a lot of text
the PowerPoint and as the results you
have this loss of connection with with
the audience and we can recognize when
other people are doing that that it's
not great but when it's our turn we do
the same thing because we think well
that's how everyone's doing it well not
anymore in the next 50 minutes we really
want to go back and master the
essentials of a previous time and the
way that we're gonna do that is we've
got three topics we call these the three
C's of effective presentations first
we're going to talk about confidence how
to look and feel more confident how many
of you could benefit from feeling more
confident when speaking in front of a
group okay I see a lot of hands yeah
then we'll talk about various techniques
to build connection and then finally
we'll talk about a few ways that you can
make sure that your message you have
clarity that it's clear and simple and
our goal is that if you're presenting
later today or tomorrow at the
conference you've got something coming
up this week you can immediately use
these techniques to be a more effective
presenter before we go further my name
is Anne Ricketts
and I'm the owner of lighthouse
communications and we do workshops and
one-on-one coaching around the Bay Area
on different communication topics I'm
Hillary spriter I'm also a communication
coach I work mostly with technical
professionals around the bay area who
are working on developing their
presentation skills I'm also a
communication coach at the business
school at Stanford University I get to
work with a set of the students there to
help with their speaking and writing
great let's talk about confidence first
and as we talk about confidence there's
two pieces that we're gonna discuss
there's the external how you show up and
there's the internal how you feel both
are really important I want to start
with external I'm gonna show you a clip
in a moment of somebody who my team
worked with and I want you to see how
the smallest weeks the smallest changes
in delivery can make a really big game
impact and how confident when you come
across this speaker is named Lucas and
he's a technical director at the company
Unity Technologies so let's take a look
in the first clip is before any coaching
do we have audio one second we'll get
audio in this clip I should speak up oh
he should speak up yep voice is too low
there's one second here we'll go back
and I should mention so Lucas is a
non-native English speaker and didn't
want to do these keynotes but everyone
at the company thought he was pretty
good so now all of us in every quarter
he's having to speak in front of this
live streamed audience hundreds of
people in the room quite a big deal
we're good okay let's try it again here
we go Lucas before coaching I think it
should have sound I could stick with us
for these demos because we have a lot of
demos to run through so the next version
of unity that we're going to ship is
five five we've been cooking on it for
quite some time already and as usual you
can get the latest beta version from our
website today all right now let's look
at after coaching not that long by the
way about an hour
[Music]
everybody let's have some fun I'm gonna
show you see today I'm gonna show you
how a scene was made and when I first
saw this scene I didn't really believe
it was put together in a few days let's
take a look I have it open here on my in
my unity editor in Maschine view and the
first thing that you will see is that I
have a whole okay what differences you
can yell it out what differences do you
notice hopefully you got to see clip 1
versus clip 2 the stands confident and
tell me more how does he look more
confident happy to be there yeah he's
his posture is better and he's not in
the first clip he's just pacing around
aimlessly in the second clip we put a
little piece of tape on the stage to try
to get him to ground and it took him a
minute to get there but then he settled
in any other differences you notice
storytelling yeah he's making eye
contact instead of looking aimlessly
around he just looked at a few people in
the audience so that wasn't that much by
the way everyone thinks he got a
makeover we did not do that but just a
little bit made a big difference let's
go over some of the fundamentals of
delivery that we teach people like Lucas
I'm gonna ask you all to stand up we're
gonna do this together
stand up
if we want to look confident we actually
have to do that physically so we need to
ground our feet and that means feet hip
distance apart and weight even on both
feet we call this the ready position
because it's signalling that we're ready
to engage with our audience as much as
possible try not to shift your weight
from leg to leg but just try that shift
from leg to leg now this might feel good
for you but for the audience this will
look a little what what does this look
like when I'm here yeah and maybe
annoyed wishy-washy ungrounded yeah off
balance so just learn to stand even now
another thing often people will do to
self-soothe is will sway back and forth
just try swing feels pretty good right
you might not even know you're doing it
for the audience I can actually make you
feel seasick after a couple of minutes
of this so again try not to sway and
then the third thing we see a lot of is
that people will get very restless and
that extra energy will leak out and
they'll begin to dance so unless dance
me as part of your presentation stand
still so it is okay to move across your
speaking space as long as you do so for
a reason with a purpose and you can just
connect to someone on the other side let
your eye contact guide your movement
walk over to them and then stop and
ground again
and repeat that so from the hips down
very still hands what do we want to be
doing with our hands
yes gesturing so when we're with our
friends and family and we feel relaxed
our hands are just moving I don't have
to teach any of you how to gesture
because you do it all day long but when
we're self conscious and we get nervous
we tend to do strange things with our
hands we might hide them behind our back
we shove them in pockets or we cross our
arms across our our fronts and this does
not look confident it doesn't look
engaging so the key is as soon as we
begin to speak move your hands and a
nice thing you can do just do it with me
connect out to your audience as you
begin to say your first words a
connecting movement once you're warmed
up and your gestures are going you can
begin to use them as
visual aids so you could say it's a
massive opportunity let's do this make
sure your gesture is matching the words
it's a massive opportunity yeah go even
bigger if I say it's a massive
opportunity you won't believe me because
this doesn't look massive so go massive
its massive and then it's tiny tiny
widget yes or maybe if I call it
climbing the tallest mountain I'll do it
really high would you believe me if I
said I climbed the tallest mountain
today No so you gotta make the gesture
match the word and if you're doing
comparisons you can say consider a and
then B do that it was before and now we
have the after so keep the hands moving
next we have eye contact how long do you
think is a perfect amount of time to
make eye contact with someone one second
would look like this how does this look
I'm talking to you here and this is
about a second of eye contact how do I
look
yeah nervous and scared so we need to
slow things down when I'm scanning over
the audience like this I'm actually
boosting my own anxiety because I'm
sending a signal to my brain that
there's something scary out there
so we need to slow it down three to five
seconds they say is the ideal amount of
time to have someone really feel that
you've connected with them the advantage
of slowing our eye contact down not only
does our audience feel that the speaker
actually really connected with us but it
sends a signal to our brain that it's
okay to relax and so they're a double
bonus so if our feet very still our
hands are moving we're making meaningful
connection to our audience and then the
fourth thing we consider is our volume
and when we coach we use a scale of 1 to
5 one would be a inaudible whisper you
couldn't hear me 2 would be always like
this the person next to me could hear me
but it doesn't work for public speaking
because there's no breath to project my
voice then there's volume 3 which is
conversational volume many of us get
stuck in this volume but it's not quite
enough it's only good enough to get to
the people immediately close to us but
not beyond so when we're public
speaking we need to boost up the volume
to what we call volume four I take deep
breaths so I can project my voice the
person furthest away can hear me easily
so there's no effort from the audience
this part you can just enjoy the volume
and then volume five would be shouting
no one likes me shouted out so do not
shout at your audience but we're gonna
go for volume four in our presentation
so now we're gonna put this all to
practice all together so feet hip
distance apart weight even on both feet
we're gonna do a few gestures we're
gonna do a big gesture and we're gonna
say the fun phrase mama lo pop low at
volume four let's try it all together
mam low pop low mama low and then take
it to your heart
Momo Pablo Pablo Pablo and then maybe
emphasize mama lo Popolo mama lo Pablo
yes fantastic so you can take your seats
thank you those are some technique we
use thank you to look and sound more
confident but then and I neither
encourage you it who's presenting later
on today anyone anyone still to present
not too many okay in your next
presentations think of these techniques
to look and sound more confident now we
want to think about the internal
confidence hands up again any of you get
nervous when you present either before
or jeering yes everybody it's totally
normal so there are lots of techniques
that we teach to help people manage
their anxiety but for today I'm just
going to choose three of my favorites
the first is tell yourself I got this
you are all highly accomplished people
many of you have moved from other
countries you've learned other languages
you are all experts on information
security so these are things that are
much more complicated than presenting so
do not stress about all the things that
could possibly go wrong when you present
instead remind yourself of all your
amazing past accomplishments and tell
yourself I got this let's do it all
together I've got this I got one more
time
I got this
it really works second thing is to
breathe now when we're nervous most of
us get stuck in a short shallow fast
chest breath and that elevates our own
anxiety and makes our voice sound a
little thin and bruffey so when you
present learn to take long slow deep
breaths they automatically calm down the
nervous system and the added benefit is
that we can support and maintain our
volume for so we're gonna do this
together by putting our hands on our
stomachs we're gonna take three rounds
of in-and-out and as you inhale you
should feel your stomach expand with
that full breath so let's do it inhale
and then exhale
twice more big long inhale exhale and
once more inhale and exhale whoo yeah I
just wanted to add this seems like
something that's obvious breathe but as
Hilary said we noticed when our clients
are nur our selves when we're nervous we
forget to breathe so one of the things
that we like to teach in our workshops
is that critical moment right before you
start and you launch into your
presentation take a moment breathe take
a look at everybody and then start if
you have that moment of breath right
before you launch in it's really gonna
help you the third thing is focus on the
friendly faces the folks who are leaning
in to listen to your presentation who
are smiling and and obviously engage
with their with your content how many of
you though would focus on will call him
mr. grumpy in the front row any hands up
any of you get distracted by people who
look like this in your audiences yes I
see quite a few hands up so those of you
who have your hands up what might be
some of the things you're telling
yourself as you're looking at this
fellow in the front row what do I do
this dog you what else yes he looks
annoyed you might be saying oh my gosh
she's judging me you think
I mean terrible presenter he's gonna rip
me apart in QA but we don't know this
poor fellow might have indigestion he
might be thinking about some argument he
just had or this might just be his
relaxed expression so do not take your
time up worrying and making up stories
that might not be true instead focus on
the folks who are obviously engaging
with your content so those are our three
very effective tips tell yourself I got
this practice on your long slow deep
breath and focus on the friendly faces
great so we talked about some ways that
you can look and feel more confident and
our second topic is how to build
connection and Hilary mentioned one of
the techniques that's very effective
which is that sustained eye contact
three to five seconds makes it feel like
you're having a conversation and I want
to focus on a few other techniques you
can use to build connection to
demonstrate this I want to show you a
clip of a speaker who's not particularly
connecting with his audience and then a
speaker who is and afterwards we'll talk
about the differences that we see this
first clip is Elon Musk he's speaking at
a conference in 2016 and I show this not
to make fun that the things that we're
seeing him do is something that's very
very common so let's take a look
all right to help welcome everyone and
I'm gonna talk more about about what it
takes to become multiplier of species
and I just a just a brief refresher on
why this is important I think
fundamentally the future is vastly more
exciting and interesting if we're a
spacefaring civilization and a
multi-planet species than if we're not
it you want to be inspired by things you
want to wake up in the morning you think
the future is gonna be great
and that's what what bring his face by
exhalation is all about it's about
believing in the future and thinking
that the future would better than the
past and I can't think of anything more
exciting than going out there and being
among the stars that's why all right do
you feel connected okay why not
okay okay so it kind of choppy a little
bit all the way back there you want to
yell out
yeah he's and he's talking about space
right this is really exciting even says
I can't think of anything more exciting
than being amongst the Stars but he's
saying it very flatly and he's also not
getting off to a very good start in
terms of his content he's got lovely we
call lovely bunch of words doesn't
really mean anything like hey happy to
be here good but not not anything of
meaning now let's contrast that with the
speaker his name is Louie von Ahn he's
the technical presenter and let's take a
look at some techniques that he's using
to connect in his introduction
how many of you have to fill out some
sort of web form where you've been asked
to read a distorted sequence of
characters like this how many of you
found it really really annoying ok
outstanding so I invented that
or I was one of the people who did it
that thing is called a CAPTCHA and the
reason is there's to make sure that you
the entity filling out the form are
actually a human and not some sort of
computer program that was written to
submit the form millions and millions of
times the reason it works is because
humans at least nonvisually impaired
humans have no trouble reading these
distorted squiggly characters whereas
computer programs simply can't do it as
well yet so for example in the case of
Ticketmaster the reason you have to type
these distorted characters is to prevent
scalpers from writing a program that can
buy millions of tickets two at a time
now CAPTCHAs are used all over the
internet and since they're used so often
a lot of times the precise sequence of
random characters that are shown to the
user is not so fortunate so this is an
example from the Yahoo registration page
random characters that happen to be
shown to the user where W AIT which of
course spell a word but the best part is
the message that the Yahoo help desk got
about twenty minutes later
this person thought they needed way this
of course is not a bad as this poor
person who
okay now all right
how is he connecting what's he doing
he's saying you okay so he's making an
audience focused humor shared
experiences self-aware II I made a beta
he's he knows that what he his invention
is annoying to some people he's got some
humor lots of things that he's doing to
connect he also seems happy to be there
he's got some passion and enthusiasm if
we were coaching him what would we tell
him to do hilary slow down louie just
slow down a little bit but so many
things that he's doing to build
connection and I want to highlight two
too that you can use the first one is
dive right in with a story instead of
starting off with your name and your
agenda and you're happy to be here
cut all that and dive right in with a
story that's related to your topic if
you do that not only will you feel more
confident because your content is
interesting and you'll notice the
audience is giving you more engagement
more eye contact but your audience is
really going to understand why they
should listen to you they're
understanding why this topic is
important what your connection is with
the topic so it's a really great way to
start for example do you remember how
Hillary and I started today we dove
right in with the story to remember what
the story's about Grace Hopper yeah so
that was our that was our method to do
this the other way that you can build
connection is to use what's called vocal
variety vocal variety is when you've got
some feeling in your voice some pausing
some punch and words rather than that
dreaded monotone delivery and vocal
variety creates connection because one
of all first of all it creates it helps
the audience understand the emotion that
you're feeling and emotions are
contagious if you're excited we're
excited if you have a sense of urgency
about something we have a sense of
urgency and second it clues it just is
more exciting to listen to so I want to
show you we took a quote for my beloved
Grace Hopper
and we marked it up so that you could
visualize vocal variety we put words in
blue that we would put a little emphasis
on we put words in blue and capped words
that we would really emphasize we put a
slash mark for a pause and a double
slash mark for a big pause so Hillary's
going to read this to you first without
vocal variety and then with so that you
can hear the difference so with no
variety it would sound and no pausing a
ship in port is safe but this is not
what ships are built for sail out to sea
and do new things when I begin to pause
and emphasize pop the key words it
sounds like this a ship in port is safe
but this is not what ships are built for
sail out to sea and do new things much
better the second right yeah a lot of
times we have these key messages and our
presentations because but because we're
delivering it like Hillary did in the
first round your audience doesn't really
get it we want you to practice this so
with the person next you want were you
to read it with vocal variety mm-hmm and
then get some feedback is there anything
you could do to add a little bit more
emphasis more feeling and then do it
again so you each do it two times will
give you about four minutes to do this
go ahead
sorry
together how was that
doing vocal variety good great this is a
you can visualize if you have a script
or maybe you've got a couple key points
that you want to emphasize in a
presentation I like to mark it up this
way this really helps me as I rehearse
now let's get you to practice with a
topic that you're excited about and we
thought that some of you might be
presenting at the conference later today
or tomorrow but it doesn't sound like
many of you are but maybe you could
think about security or your work what
you do your your team at your company
what are you passionate about so what
you're gonna do is with a new partner
you're gonna share your excitement for
that topic in a few sentences for
example let's say Hillary is my partner
I could say something like I'm excited
to present at B sides because when
people present they get really nervous
so if I can give them one or two tips to
make them feel better that's really
satisfying then she's gonna tell me on a
scale of one to ten how convinced she is
well it's pretty good so I'm gonna give
you an eight point five okay it's
probably more like a seven if she's
being honest and I'll do it again and
then switch see really each go two times
and then switch so we'll give you five
minutes to do this please partner
four more minutes
and let's come back was it easier to do
vocal variety when you're talking about
your own work versus a quote yeah I'd
like to get a volunteer to come up on
stage and do it if we have a do have a
handheld mic we could use and do talk
about their work with some vocal variety
does anybody want to come up okay yeah
coming up what's your name
Adrian
all right let's hear why are you excited
about your topic what's that I will
share with it what you practice with
your partner using some vocal variety
yeah so why do you like what you do I
like what I do because I am a citizen
engineer I like what I do because I get
to talk to people every day as well as
being technical at the same time so you
get to have the best boat the best of
both worlds where I can you know be
social as well as soft technical
problems nice job woohoo and I saw you
to use some of Hillary's techniques like
I get to do this and this nice job
how about one more volunteer anybody
want to come up I'm gonna come up come
on come on what's your name
Luciano I could tell from Luciano's body
language that he was like indirect great
lesson thank you hey how's it going
everyone this is my first time
presenting at besides besides a few
times I've been at that card
great conferences great conferences for
my son he's uh he's now his first year
in college and I figured you know what
this is the best time to actually get
into you get him to come in and
participate as well cuz he's gonna get
to the point where he's gonna have to
choose a career right this is probably
the best time to actually get into
InfoSec because you have a lot of new
people a lot of diversity and I wanted
to introduce him not only that but what
he really wants to specialize in is the
legal aspect of site cyber security
policy in law so I brought him here so I
can introduce him to the FF there's
anybody out there from the FF please
come down here talk to me
[Applause]
that was great he had some emphasis and
words he was gesturing I got the emotion
that you're happy to have your son here
nice job nice job okay so to summarize
the connection piece there's lots of
ways to connect but two very effective
ways are to use some vocal variety and
to dive into your presentation with a
relevant story we've talked about how to
look sound and feel more confident and
then Ann was telling us about the
importance of connecting we're gonna
move on to our last topic which is
clarity how to make your content clear
and concise so it's easy for your
audience to understand as communication
coaches and and I hear a lot about three
common pitfalls when it comes to
people's content in presentations and
meetings the first one that we hear a
lot of is that there's no clear point so
by the end of someone's presentation we
understand the topic we have some new
information but we're not sure of the
main take away the second pitfall is
that there is too much information
presented so the audience ends up
feeling overwhelmed and they go home not
actually remembering that much of what
they heard and then the third pitfall we
hear of a lot is that the information
wasn't relevant or if it was relevant to
the audience the presenter didn't
actually connect the dots so people go
home and they don't really know what to
do with all the information that they
just took on so we've come up with a
tool called the focus questions you
should have a piece of paper in front of
you if you don't have one we'll e-mail
you one afterwards but it's a tool that
we give our clients our clients love
this they answer these focus questions
before they begin to create any content
if you use these focus questions you'll
be amazed at how much more clear and
concise your content is you will come
across as a more articulate speaker and
it will save you a ton of time and
energy so I highly recommend them for
times sake right now I'm just gonna
highlight four of the points on here and
the first one is number three the
relevance how is your information going
to Benna
fit your audience and remember that
people are most interested in the things
that matter to them so the first thing
you have to do is make sure you've
considered your audience's needs and
interests and make sure your content
actually is relevant to them and then
the second thing is to explicitly state
how your audio your information is
relevant to the audience don't assume
that the audience understands it
implicitly connect the dots for them so
make the relevance and explicit
statement in your introduction let's
move down to number seven emotions how
are you going to get your audience to
feel something and what do you want them
to feel do you want them to feel excited
or inspired or scared and was talking
about the variety in the vocal quality
that's important to keep the audience
engaged and if you think of the
presentations you listen to that are the
most engaging you'll probably realize
that it's the presentation that makes
you feel a variety of emotions so the
stand-up comedians have a fun demonic
it's called make them laugh make them
cry make them laugh say goodbye puts the
audience to this nice rollercoaster a
variety of emotions
now as presenters we don't necessarily
have to make our audiences laugh but we
do want our audiences to feel contrast
in the emotions as we present if you do
this if you get your audience actually
feeling something viscerally they will
remember you and your content much more
so make them feel something if I can add
here and work presentations it's so come
that contrast is usually the pain of a
problem contrasted with the excitement
the relief of a solution yeah number
eight what is your insight your fresh
perspective on your topic we're often
asked well what do we do when we have an
audience who are already expert in what
I'm presenting on how do I keep them
engaged come up with a new metaphor or
analogy to put a fresh feel into the
topic tell a personal anecdote to put
your own personal touch on to the topic
but come up with something new a new
fresh perspective it can take a lot of
time to come up with these insights but
the payoff
was really big if you do and then the
final one number nine is what is your
main message if you want your audience
to understand your main message you have
to know it first I like to write it down
make sure your main message is concise
most of us have a hard time being
concise it's much easier to be
long-winded but again if you take the
time to write down a clear concise main
message include it in your content your
presentation is gonna land much more
powerfully and again it's gonna be more
memorable so use these focus questions
they're really helpful save you a ton of
time and energy and we're gonna get a
copy yeah I'll email them out and it's a
fillable PDF so you can use in the
future just just fill it out yeah so as
well as our content being clear and
concise and relevant we also want to
consider how our slides are
communicating for us many of us put on
way too much information on our slides
and they actually end up overwhelming
and confusing our audiences more than
they help them understand our content
the thing to remember is that every
single little thing you put on a slide
is demanding part of your audience's
attention so anything that is not
actually communicating meaning remove it
that includes extraneous information
like diagrams you don't reference words
that are too small you can't read
decorative backgrounds take all of that
what we call noise off the slide so that
you have a really clear signal coming
through we have an example of a noisy
slide here it is noisy slide I like you
to turn to your neighbor take a minute
and just brainstorm how would you make
this slide less noisy so there's a clear
message coming through take a minute and
I'll wave my hands when I want you back
come back I'd love to hear some of your
thoughts what do you think why they're
all the words yes so first thing to do
would be to critically think of your
content you can see these messages are
slightly different it's ambiguous so now
I'm confusing you with two messages so
instead think critically what is the
main message and write it on your slide
what other thing would you do yes hmm
how might you convey a percentage more
effective yeah yeah yeah so maybe a
whole different visual would set this up
more effectively other things other
suggestions you came up with
yeah there's extra information yes and
also consider your audience's needs you
do the audience is the audience really
gonna remember all eight data points and
if they're not gonna remember them why
are you showing it so maybe make it less
information yeah there is another hand
up over here yes
yeah the background sucks get rid of all
those decorative gray squares that's
just clutter and noise yes way up in the
back yeah yes it's confusing you and how
easy is it for you to track your eye
from the top of one of the columns and
try to find where it lands on the y-axis
that's not easy so we can see there are
things to be done here's a possible
revision there's certainly more to be
done but here we put one clear message
on top we've got rid of the decorative
background we put the numbers directly
on the columns we've got rid of the XY
access next step might be well how many
data points do we really need or it
might be maybe a whole different visual
maybe a pie chart would be a better way
to do it but think three years
examine whatever is not meaningful take
it off so that the audience isn't
overwhelmed or confused with having to
search through all the noise to get to
the actual meaning so clear concise
relevant content through your focus
questions and clean up your slides
thanks Hilary so today we talked about a
lot of things in 50 minutes we talked
about how to look and feel more
confident we talked about ways you can
build connection and then finally using
the focus questions and cleaning up
cleaning up your slides in order to
provide clarity this can feel like a lot
to think about especially when you're
nervous and you're presenting so our
suggestion is to think about one or two
things to start just one or two things
for example maybe you're going to be
loud be at that volume for slow down or
clean up your slides just a few things
and then once you master those things
then you can add on more later if you're
interested in more information workshops
or one-on-one coaching you can contact
us here and we have some time now for
Q&A so if you have any questions in the
moment we're happy to take it now yeah
oh do we just want to yell out the
questions okay it's a really loud voice
I'm gonna take this me yeah I can answer
that first question for what size of
font what we suggest for your main
message the most important takeaway a 28
bolded thawne serif font so a font that
does not have little tails on it so it's
clear a 'calibri calibri Arial are great
fonts to work with so 28 bolded to make
it pop and if it's not the main message
you can go down to 21 to 24 size font
when it gets down to 18 and lower it's
really hard to read and then you
question whether it's helping the
audience in any way I've also heard no
more than 20 words for the man who does
that right yeah the research shows that
people do not read beyond the second
line of text so if you're someone who
uses a lot of bullet point slides and
lots of text there's a cognitive
overload you'll set up with the audience
they can't listen and read your slides
so move away from really text heavy
slides try to make them more visual next
question
that's so remote presentations are
really hard for the remote presentations
I would really focus on the eye contact
so creating that connection I like to
put a little sticky at the top of my
computer to remind myself rather than
looking at my own picture reminding
myself to look up at the camera that's
helpful also pausing going slower
creating moments for interaction so it's
not just one way and they're more likely
to engage and not be focused on their
work and then and then in person always
one way to engage is to stand a lot of
people are in the habit of sitting down
but you're gonna have more engagement if
you're standing and you when you're
presenting so in a previous career I was
a english-as-a-second-language teacher
and the big thing is volume volume
volume so that volume for and remember
when we had the Grace Hopper quote and
we visualized the keywords if you've got
a loud volume and you're popping
important words that's the big thing it
doesn't matter if you have an accent but
people just need to be able to hear you
and rehearsal is always helpful as well
I think we have time for one or two more
questions we would suggest you might try
to play with using formulas structures
to help you organize how you're actually
going to deliver so there are lots of
different structures but one you might
use is oh you have you ever been to an
interview or an interview and the
interviewer says tell me about you and
your mind goes blank using a structure
could be something like past present
future so you could say well five years
ago I was with company X focused on this
kind of work today I am delving into
this project here with company Z looking
to two years from now I hope to be doing
this so a structure just helps you
organize what you're gonna say and it
gives you a little bit more brain energy
left over for the actual details other
structure
are things like problem-solution benefit
what the what of the issue the so what
why does my audience care about this and
then now what what's my plan of action
so if you use structures your impromptu
speaking you suddenly become a lot more
eloquent and articulate then you might
have been previously if you just go for
a stream of consciousness which will
easily lose your audience we've got some
videos on those on youtube if you look
for lighthouse communications another
thing is just to focus on your
nonverbals the volume slowing down
making eye contact because even if your
contents not that good if you look
confident that's helpful okay one more
question yeah so the question was what
do you do if like a key player a
decision-maker seems to be skeptical or
is asking questions is that right mmm
that's so difficult yeah I would first
of all take a breath and realize that
it's not about you it's about so I would
instead of getting defensive and
shutting down I would take it breath and
tell me more David can you give me more
information can you give me an example
let him talk a little bit and then once
you breathe and calm down you'll be able
to think more clearly on the fly so just
breathe trust that you know what you're
doing and you got this I could suggest
on that too people might argue the facts
with you but they can't argue with your
experience so a comeback might be you
know thank you very much for your
comment in my experience when you have
factors x and y the outcome has been a
and B but I'd love to hear more from you
let's talk afterwards and then director
I contacted someone else move away from
this person and they always see a hand
over here said take away that energy a
little bit thank you so much have a
great conference we're gonna stick
around in the hallway if you have any
questions feel free time
[Applause]