hi i'm sergey welcome to the last talk
of this session so this is joint work
with dominic sherman
jasmine sascha and matthew and
yeah what we did in this paper is
we did a short
online study
about the different textual fingerprint
representations so let me start with a
quote so
there was a
short journal paper
with some
evidence that users don't uh verify ssh
keys so the title is do users verify ssh
keys and the abstract is just consisting
no and that's it so but there was no
study behind it and also it was
anecdotal evidence
so in the top right corner you see like
an example fingerprint of ssh and when
users
connect to a server they should verify
whether they connected to the right
server and it is often claimed that
yeah those are not checked and also
error-prone because if we create like
partial pre-images where most of the
characters uh are the same but a few are
different
uh the users wouldn't even notice and
also
most of them are um yeah it's also like
for the user it's a cognitive load it's
hard to compare
and many people are
saying like
it's like meaningless comparison of
characters
so that's why users are not even
motivated
but somehow this is still relevant
because
most of the messengers which implement
like end-to-end security like signal or
whatsapp they still rely on rely on this
technique because if we don't have aca
infrastructure
if we don't uh cannot implement a
transparency directory um there is no
other way uh to do
the verification so somehow we have to
do it
so that's why we think that it is still
relevant so our goal is
um yeah to study which of those textual
representations are best we are just
testing the textual representations
because um
yeah
you uh could perhaps get a business card
with someone's pgp key on it or
uh yeah your device
your device is not supporting um
qr codes and so on yeah so um yeah the
the best fingerprint representation
uh would like uh produce a high attack
uh detection so if we if the user is
exposed to
partial uh pre-images uh yeah he
should detect if there are some attacks
going on and also without producing a
false positive rate for whatever reason
they also should be efficient the user
should compare them fast and yet have a
low cognitive load and of course we are
interested in the user perception
because there might be some
representations which are um yeah
efficient and um
also have a high attack detection but
the user perceives them
uh yeah to be hard and they also need to
be
robust that means like
if we we want to make them accessible
and so on
so what we tested in our initial um
studies
are those six approaches so we took the
hexadecimal which is like the state of
the art as the baseline because it is
used by ssh and pgp and so on and we
also compare it to base 32 because we
talked to some users and they couldn't
even distinguish the difference between
hex and base 32 because for them it was
just characters and numbers
we also compared this to a numeric
approach just where you have simple
numbers from 0 to
and so on so depending on which length
you choose um yeah then there is also
the pgp word list which was developed
by
phil zimmerman
who
wanted to use this comparisons by a
phone
and chose 512 different words and each
uh yeah so the fingerprint is matched on
the word list so
and as you can see there are also the
examples how the word list looks like
except of that it consists of 16 words
rather than four and all the
fingerprints are longer this is just to
show how they look like
um but there is also the perio word list
which consists like
about 16 000
different words so it's a huge
dictionary which was
derived from the most common words and
movie subtitles uh
yeah minus offensive words and so on
and uh there is there are also different
sentence generators uh
we took one example which is
described in more detail in the paper
which produces grammatically correct
sentences
but semantically they just don't make
sense so as
in this example
yes so our threat model uh how we
produced or uh did the pre-image attack
so in an so the ideal attack would be
for an existing key fingerprint we find
a pre-image and yeah this is
mostly not possible for most of the
hashing algorithm because it would be
very too expensive but also like
infeasible uh if it's long enough
and yeah there are workers rounds so we
generate a partial pre-image so the
fingerprints almost match except of a
few characters and this would exploit uh
people's attention limitations so we
assume that the
people wouldn't check it uh
like
fully concentrated
so and here we have to choose like the
attack our strengths and uh yeah we have
a few assumptions so the fingerprint is
derived from
the actual public key which is used in
some metadata like the creation date
like it is the case in open pgp
so
this is why we don't have to generate
a new key every time
it's just enough to change parts of the
metadata
like the creation date which is also
part of the fingerprint would
uh yeah we would increase
the time and so on so in this case we
just uh assume that this hashing
algorithm needs to be performed
and uh also uh with some key stretching
techniques we could make also the
fingerprint a bit shorter so if we would
take a 160
bit uh
um
fingerprint and use s-crypt on it like
and then truncate it to 112-bit
the users would get a shorter
fingerprints and our attacker is
controlling 80 of those 100 uh
112 bits so that basically means 80 bits
are the same
which is still a high cost to
generate those partial pre-images but
it's not impossible
um
yeah so uh when we do those attacks we
basically have controlled and
uncontrolled bits and the bits which are
uncontrolled are just
inverted so in this case we don't even
try to find uh
the
key or to find the correct key with the
fingerprint we just take the fingerprint
and change a few bits which where we
just simulate the attack
and uh yeah the inversions are taking
place only within logical sequences so
uh if we
have um a an alpha numeric approach we
just change a few characters or if we
have a word approach we change all the
bits inside of words like to maximize uh
the control uh
character so uh yeah uh this would be an
example like for the hex approach where
uh yeah we
changed eight characters uh
so
the study design
was then done on mturk and this was done
like with a controlled experiment where
the user had to perform a task and to
test those fingerprint algorithms and
then we this was followed by a survey
where we asked the user for
usability feedback what he thinks about
those approaches and so on
and yeah so the main task is basically
users have to compare fingerprints and
they just get two fingerprints and say
whether they match or don't match and
after performing all the tasks uh yeah
they are asked
or asked to fill in the survey where we
ask usability questions and get some
more feedback and before actually
starting with a real study we
started a few pre-studies
to find out which parameters which
approaches we take
and in the end we came up with the
factorial design where we tested four
different schemes
um
with schemes it's mean like uh hex and
base 32 are both alphanumeric and in our
pre-study we found out that the users
couldn't distinguish between hex or base
32 or whatever that's why they either
got hex or base 32 but never had to
perform both uh and then when we asked
in the survey yeah they didn't have to
distinguish between those approaches but
they also had to do the numeric and also
for the wordless approaches they
sometimes didn't even notice that some
were
generated words were or the amount of
words was shorter than in the other
approach
and yeah the generated sentences that
means that each user had to do a test
like for one alphanumeric approach for
one numeric
one wordless approach and uh yeah the
sentence approach
so
during that task they just
got a web page where they had a phone on
the left
showing
the fingerprints and a
business card on the right which is the
case with pgp sometimes and they just
have to check whether the security code
is the same on the left as on the right
and just simply say whether it matches
or doesn't match and yeah simply click
on the buttons in the phone
so
more details about
our study design is so
they basically had to do 40 comparisons
which were
were counted in our case in a randomized
order so they could get hex or the other
approach at the beginning and just had
to do 40
approaches and this randomized order is
like
minimizing the fatigue and learning
effects
and for each of the schemes we do
exactly one attack with those 80
where the attacker is controlling 80
bits so
and also we found out in our pre-study
that if we attack like every second time
the users uh notice it quite well and
the accuracy is getting better and
that's why we would need more
participants that
that's why we just do one attack per
approach
we also added a few two attention tests
with obvious mismatches so we show on
the left like
just zero and on the right we show words
which is obviously wrong and
users who are clicking on match on that
uh yeah they
fail uh fail the attention test and are
excluded from the
statistics
and we also provided a few training sets
for each scheme so before actually
starting the study we show how they have
to do and we added those training sets
that's based on the feedback that uh in
the pre-studies some people were
starting to search
for typos
in words and we're not sure and we said
during the training sets that they don't
have to search for typos and the words
um yeah but those training sets were not
considered in the results how long they
took to click
so after that
the users got a survey
where we asked for some demographics and
uh to rate the schemes and they were
asked several questions something like
whether the comparisons with this method
were easy and then they had to rate it
for each of the approaches where we
remind them by showing it
in the brackets um
how it looks like
so uh the challenges we had during the
study is
that we required a high number of
participants uh and would need a lot of
money because we found out that
the users are quite well in comparing
things and most of the users on mturk
actually did a good job in comparing it
so
and there were not that
big differences between the approaches
and also we could not test each possible
parameter so
uh some of the approaches could use
different chunk sizes or different
colors or different font settings
and uh yeah it would
cost too much money as such study would
cost too much money to test all the
different uh
parameters so
we added an additional experiment where
we just tested the chunking but the same
could be done with different font
settings and so on so we used the same
font settings and the same chunking
approaches for all
of the
approaches so
our results were
in the end like we had 1047 participants
who
were participating in this study and 46
were excluded because they just randomly
clicked somewhere and
yeah failed the attention tests
uh it was in general a mixed demographic
so there was a similar amount of males
and females and uh yeah
uh the thing
in the demographics has shown that there
is no real difference based on age
gender or education so it was quite
similar and uh yeah as i said there is a
relatively high attack detection rate
for our chosen attacker for all schemes
so in the experiment results we see the
speed in seconds
as you can see
the best approach and the worst approach
are not that far away
in the median
and
the more important uh column in this
case is the undetected attacks so how
many attacks were performed successfully
and as you can see here hexadecimal
which is like the state of the arc had
uh yeah
ten percent
undetected
attacks so of all attacks happened ten
percent were not detected if we compare
it to the language-based approaches like
sentences or the period list which are
uh lower and the period list was the
fastest to compare this is based on the
fact that they had a large uh dictionary
and the user said just to read nine
words and yeah
um then
there is also a false positive
column and here we see like a different
number in the sentences
that's because
the phone was in the vertical uh
not landscape
so the phone was vertical and the
business card uh was landscape and uh
yeah there were different alignments for
some sentences which were longer and
that's when the users clicked oh it's
wrong even though the sentences were
exactly the same i don't have an
explanation why base 32
produced more false positives than any
other approaches
even though o and zero uh are not inside
so there is no o and no i to avoid a
confusion between
uh o and zero and one and i
um
yeah uh in the chunking experiments uh
yeah we tested the different chunking
approaches and uh yeah we didn't get any
uh significant numbers so even though
there are small differences uh in
undetected attacks those are not
significant the only thing which is
significant is the speed but it's uh
quite similar for all chunkings so hex2
means like in two characters like it is
done in ssh hex three and three
characters x4 and so on
um
yeah as you can see
there is not too much difference uh
in here and in the survey results at the
end we asked them a few questions about
the trustworthiness that was like do you
believe a such system is secure and
unsuper unsurprisingly uh the hex and
the base 32 because it looks like very
random most of the people said they
believe it's more secure compared to
generated sentences even though
those
are
the security is the same
and regarding the usability the language
based approach uh
the better rating but here as you can
see the differences are not that far
away
we got a general feedback that most of
the users
were annoyed to do this task with any of
the fingerprints so even though they
like the generated sentences more
they still
would rather skip it
and yeah the limitations
are like um yeah as i said there is no
guarantee that the easiest approach will
still lead that the users will actually
do the fingerprints and also there are
uh some validity questions about mturik
as with any emters studies
because the
people have more experience or
are more technical persons compared to
the average population and is also
younger
and
is in general used to visual and textual
tasks so because they do it
a lot of tasks like this
yeah
and
uh yeah as i said we didn't test all the
different parameters uh because
otherwise we would have too many
conditions to test and this would be too
expensive
so
to conclude my talk um yeah as we can
see the
hexadecimal approach even though it is
the state of the art has shown the worst
performance of all approaches uh it has
a lower attack detection rate is also
slower than most of the other approaches
and is perceived to be more annoying by
most of the users and the generated
sentences produce the best result
because yeah they have the highest
attack
detection rate
and the users perceive it to be more
usable
and numeric was the best approach
without the language-based systems so in
that case whatsapp
the right choice uh in their
implementation actually we didn't know
that
whatsapp will actually implement it so
when we submitted the paper this was a
few weeks earlier than
the announcement of whatsapp that they
are using this fingerprint methods
so
yeah
that's it and yeah i'm happy to answer
your questions
[Applause]
we have time for questions
thank you for your talk a brief question
on open ssh keys
uh there is this option that you can
activate that will show you a sort of
graph ascii graphics yeah when you're
logging into an ssh server you didn't
look into this like why and really just
the textual approaches oh yeah i already
forgot the title of the target so the
thing is that um
yeah it is first of all harder to
generate like
the attacks on this um yes
visual fingerprints and second of all uh
yeah there are people with visual
impairment which probably cannot see
this uh
ascii art thing that's why we said we
are just focusing on the textual
approaches and the textual approaches
are also more robust in that sense that
you can compare them via phone and so on
thank you
hi uh tabeshwar there from georgetown i
just had a quick question about the
amtrak so you showed a screenshot of the
study so was the phone image rendered or
was it just text on both sides because
if it was text oh no it was not text it
was uh rendered that they couldn't just
copy paste and do it automatically or
something okay and another quick
question so for the amtrak study usually
the aim of the people is to just more
tasks and get more money so did you give
any reward or any uh like more money to
the people who guessed it right so they
had a motivation to do the study right
instead of just clicking yes no yes no
yeah we didn't do that because in the
real world
people don't
are not motivated to do this on whatsapp
either so that's why we wanted to make
it like
more comparable uh
yeah but okay thank you
all right uh so if we don't have any
more questions i want to thank all the
speakers again from the session
you