hi so this is a talk on a new type of
chosen ciphertext attack we developed in
order to exploit a vulnerability we
found in apple's imessage protocol
imessage is of course uh apple's intane
encrypted messaging protocol it was
first developed in 2011
it is now deployed on about a billion
devices um handles a peak of about 200
000 messages a second
um and it was really sort of the first
large scaly deployed uh end-to-end
encrypted messaging protocol prior to
this most messaging was sent in fact
over sms which of course has no
encryption whatsoever um
and
it's sort of interesting that we kind of
think of
messaging as not being that important of
course these kind of things are actually
relied on by by activists and oppressive
government regimes and stuff to to sort
of protect themselves and sort of from a
technical standpoint it's interesting
because it turns out that imessage the
encryption protocol isn't actually just
used for messaging turns out that apple
uses it uh in handoff which syncs the
state on your browser from your desktop
uh to your phone um you could see why
you might want indian encryption there
and then apple uses it in uh one other
undisclosed product that they mentioned
existed when you were discussing
mitigations with them when we disclosed
the attack but they wouldn't actually
tell us uh what it was
um
i'd like to think that it was the apple
car but realistically there's probably
something involving the iwatch i don't
actually know so what do we mean when we
say indian encrypted right well if
you're sending a message from one device
to another over a network or using a
server right you can basically have
three options of how you can send it you
can use no encryption in which case your
message is sort of exposed
you can do what i think we'd all come to
expect uh you can do transport
encryption where the link from the
client to the server and from the server
to the recipient is encrypted but the
message itself is not so it's exposed on
the server and then and these are not
mutually exclusive you can do end-to-end
encryption where you encrypt the message
on the device
and it is not decrypted by anyone it
cannot be decrypted by anyone until you
get to the recipient right and this is
sort of the gold standard this is what
imessage sought out to do this is what
signal and whatsapp do this is even what
facebook messenger now has a uh
deployed version of doing for only on
phones um
and what we developed in in this case
was an attack that for some types of
imessages reduces the security from the
setting where you have indian encryption
over here to the setting where you only
have transport encryption right because
uh at that point then the message is
only protected to the extent that you
can't break the links on the encryption
uh or that you can't get into the server
and this may not seem that significant
you may think that that's a fairly
secure scenario i think a couple of the
other authors in the session might
disagree with you about trusting tls at
least as is um but uh okay that maybe
that's not that big of a threat in your
head and you're probably thinking the
server here is probably pretty secure
it's like 102 devices it boxes it's not
going to be that easy to get into and no
one would care but for a cloud-based
service that's handling you know
hundreds of thousands of messages of a
second across a large geographically
diverse area
this schematic is really inaccurate
because that little box there is
actually um
something far more complicated right you
might expect you know to involve
multiple servers or even multiple data
centers and you might maybe you should
be a little skeptical about your ability
to secure something like this just off
the bat because there are a lot of
things that can go wrong
um and for those of you who recognize
where this slide is actually taken from
you should be incredibly skeptical of
your ability to secure this if you're
the kind of thing that nation states are
interested in because they have very
well resourced very smart motivated
attackers who will go look at your
architecture and gleefully point out
that in fact you have no encryption in
one particular step and they can read
all of your messages in this case this
diagram is actually taken from something
against google for gmail but uh
funnily enough gmail doesn't have any
encryption but nonetheless these kind of
attacks apply you can imagine someone
doing the same kind of thing to an
ending encrypted message
encrypted messaging system right so this
is why you want in-demand encryption
right it really is important right so
how does imessage get this um imessage
is really the simplest protocol you
could probably think of there's no crazy
properties for forward security as an
otr there's no overly complex uh
you know trippy triple or quadruple or
sex tuple jiffy helmet handshake
whatever it is that signal slash
octolodon was up to these days
there is simply just a directory server
that distributes public keys and then
you encrypt your message under the
recipient's public key and you send it
via apple's push notification network
and the question of course is is this
secure right there's some questions
about you know how apple distributes uh
keys and does device registration and we
examined uh
that found some
floss and other people were discovered
and confirmed they're still there and
found a couple of other other ones but
the main question is you know what is
this encryption and is it actually
secure right and so interestingly this
is actually documented apple did in an
irs security white paper they published
a while ago give you a very short like
paragraph description of what their
encryption format is and that format is
very simple uh an i encrypted imessage
consists of an rsa ciphertext encrypted
under the recipient's public key
the ciphertext is uh 1288 bits so you
can't fit a full message in there so
they don't
they uh just encrypt a symmetric key and
then they encrypt the actual message
using aes under that symmetric key with
aes encounter mode and then for good
measure they signed it with the cinders
public key right with an ecdsa signature
so you know who it came from and so the
interesting thing is from this one
paragraph description you can actually
conclude that there are several things
wrong and the protocol is in fact
cryptographically broken right this is
all you actually need to see to know
that right
and so what what's the what's the catch
what's wrong well first of all you may
remember that you you ought to be using
authenticated encryption these days
right and that maybe that means you use
uh as in gcm mode maybe you use ocb
maybe you just use an hmac but this is
not this is as encounter mode right so
it's not an authenticated cyber suit
itself um and i'm not hiding anything in
the schematic queue there is no hmac in
here anywhere right
and some of you may be thinking well but
there is a signature right and i
actually suspect maybe one of the
engineers at apple was thinking this too
uh and that's that's authenticated right
we're signing the thing we know who it
came from that's that's authentication
in the standard definition right and
indeed in most uses you might be able to
think that uh but it turns out that
remember how i said there were two
things wrong here well
uh
the sort of the second one is that
there's an identity misbinding attack
which means that if alice is sending a
message to bob and i grab it i can strip
off alice's name from the envelope
information strip off her signature put
my name and my signature on it and then
send it to bob and bob will think it's a
message from me
and this seems sort of like a pedantic
objection it is a type of flaw in in in
protocols right uh but it's not really
clear what this would do to the
confidentiality of the protocol right
because that's not there's no way you
should be able to use it to actually
read what's in that message you've just
managed to send it to the bob and made
him think it came from someone else
but
the thing is that if i do this attack
i'm not limited to just replaying the
exact message i got because once you've
stripped off the signature
i can do whatever i want the cipher
ciphertext and then sign it as if it
came by me
and so this means the ciphertext is
malleable
and this should actually worry you
because if you remember um if you've
taken a cryptographic class there is
this very complicated definition of
indistinguishability under adaptive
chosen ciphertext attack which is sort
of the you know the basic gold standard
for what you want for a secure
encryption scheme um and it basically
says that if you have malleable
ciphertext
you can't meet this definition um
and
great so now we know that imessage is is
technically textbook broken based on
merely the nice paragraph description
they gave us but it's not really clear
how you were going to exploit this
because this this game involves a
attacker who has oracle access to be
able to decrypt any ciphertext they want
to just literally ask for the decryption
provided it's not the one they are
challenged on and the natural reaction
to those of you on the you know the
system side of this or anything is well
that's unrealistic no one would ever
build such a system and if you did you
deserve to get owned um
well okay so how do we how do we go
about translating this into practice so
consider something that's maybe a little
more plausible suppose instead of having
an api that said uh you know hey what's
the decryption of this message we had an
api that said hey is this message valid
is it the right link is it encoded
properly etc
and
this still might seem a little
unrealistic because again why would you
add that api
but it turns out in fact that this
actually does happen just sort of
indirectly right this is an example of
an actual stack trace someone posted to
stack overflow going hey why am i
getting this and it turns out right that
this is an example of a padding oracle
attack this
system is probably encrypting a cookie
is vulnerable to exactly this type of
thing it's called a
format oracle attack um and
it turns out that you don't directly
have to have an api that exposes this
right this is the server wasn't very
well configured it's reporting stack
traces and such but you can infer that
there was an error maybe by a side
channel by a violent timing or by the
fact that the server didn't do the next
step that it was supposed to in the
process like say you know supposed to
email you after you submitted something
um and so this attack is actually
practical and it's used quite a good
degree of effect
um and so seemingly we have some good
news here right we can come up with an
actual exploit except for the fact that
uh
there's no panic right this is aes
encounter mode right as encounter mode
is a stream cipher you generate a bunch
of random bits using aes and you xor
them with your message right and this is
very good for us from the point of view
of doing malleability because if you
want to flip an arbitrary bit in the
plain text that's being decrypted you
just flip the corresponding bit in the
ciphertext right you don't know what the
value of it was but you know you flipped
it
but this also means there's no padding
right so we can't mount a padding oracle
attack right we also can't mount out of
the other variants of this that people
have developed there was an xml one
there's a font encoding one um none of
these really work directly here
so
it's not exactly clear
what we should be doing right um and in
fact in order to actually exploit this
in order to get a proof of concept we're
going to have to develop a new type of
uh format oracle attack right and
unfortunately this is where we leave the
the realm of what apple nicely
documented for us because we need to do
two things to get a format oracle right
we need to figure out some format that
we can exploit and how to flip it to
actually get errors that tell us what
the ciphertext the contents of the
ciphertext are and then the second thing
is we need to actually be able to do
that remotely which means we need to see
the errors somehow right
and this sort of begs the question what
is in this box right what is the actual
format
and so this isn't documented right there
was a a sort of partial reverse
engineering done by quarks labs a while
ago they also found some some issues
with how uh
keys are distributed um but
we basically had to finish this off
right you have to go stare at the raw
messages and like write a bunch of
python code to parse them and figure out
what's going on and if you do that and
it's a painful process you recover
basically this diagram and this is a
fairly complicated format actually right
it's at high level it's a gzip binary p
list binary p list being this uh
proprietary sort of format apple uses
for for for serializing data
and it's kind of interesting because
they went to a lot of trouble to save
space in this right because the push
notification network didn't want to deal
with large messages so they compressed
the thing and they actually stuffed part
of the message uh into the rsa
ciphertext right because i said it was
1288 bits you're only putting a 256-bit
aes key in there so you have some
leftover space so that space actually
has part of the message genuine um and
the rsa subjects by the way is actually
correctly done it's rsa or aap and you
you can't uh mess with them um
and so this is just sort of interesting
looking at it it's not quite clear what
we can use for format oracle but if you
start looking you notice that this might
be we might have a few snags
uh the first one is that there's the
sender id in here and remember this is
the cipher text i'm showing you this is
not the full message format with the
envelope information which of course has
the sender the receiver the date and
some routing information on it this is
just the encrypted point part of it and
that itself includes who's sending the
message which doesn't make much sense
because you can't read that until you've
decrypted it and after that you've
already had to validate the signature to
do this so you don't need this
information here in here and apple
actually is trying to save space so why
are they
they wasting these bits
uh and it turns out right the worry
about this might is well placed because
it because if you mount the identity
miss binding attack i just articulated
earlier
um
the system will reject the message
because the
uh id on the outside of the envelope
that i replaced with my signature on it
won't match the id on the inside that's
encrypted because i haven't changed that
and so apple rejects the message and
this i think is because some clever
engineer realized that there was
anything hiddenly misbinding attack and
added a counter measure
well that's really unfortunate
except for one point they weren't quite
clever enough because remember the
problem about ciphertext variability
this is in the cipher text it's not in
the oap part of it if the message is
long enough and so we can just flip the
bits in it right we know what it is we
know the value and so we can actually
flip it to be my id instead of the
attackers instead of the the centers
rather and
then this countermeasure amounts to
nothing right because it will it will
correctly have the information on both
sides of the message and it'll validate
so this is just an annoying speed bump
but it's interesting nonetheless um okay
so we still need a format oracle right
we could mess with the actual binary
plist
but that's compressed so
maybe it's better that we target the
compression itself um because that's you
know the next layer of the onion um
and if you start doing that well
what is the compression format it's gzip
gzip for those of you don't know is
basically a header
a compressed data data stream that's
compressed with deflate which is the
actual compression algorithm and then a
coc32 over the decompressed data and of
course when you get the message you're
going to decompress the data compute
your own crc32 and then check that it
aligns with the uh the one that was set
with the message right this is just how
gzip works in general this is nothing
special about imessage
and
this is problematic right because we
need to flip bits in here and that's
obviously going to change what the
decompressed version is and the crc is
not going to align so again another
speed bump
and if this was a cryptographically
secure hash we'd be in deep trouble i
probably wouldn't actually be able to
give this talk because we wouldn't have
an exploit we just have an interesting
observation of apple didn't quite do
things correctly
uh luckily for us unluckily for apple uh
coc32s are actually cc and general are
quite malleable right it turns out that
c or c of a xor with c r c or b of b is
equal to the c o c of message a x over
the message b
right technically this is slightly
different if you want to deal with
non-zero ivs but it doesn't really
actually change them
so it's not exactly clear what you do
with this observation right well
if we have a message that we don't know
the contents of and we have the crc
which we also don't know but we have the
encrypted version of it right and we are
flipping a bit
in the message and represented that by
xoring another vector in with the bits
set the high that we want to flip right
this is basic xor we do know the crc of
that thing that we're flipping and it
turns out that we can based on this
exact uh equation
get acocc on the valid mutated message
even though we don't know the contents
of the message and we don't know the
original crc because we just xor in the
coc of what we're flipping um plus the
actually the length of the message in
all zeros because if it's a non-zero id
um xor that in to the encrypted uh crc
because the encryption's just done via
stream cipher when you decrypt this
actually persists through and the coc
validates
so okay we've avoided another speed bump
that's good um
but there's a problem that
we still need a format oracle right and
in fact uh luckily for me what i just
told you is not quite accurate um it's a
little more complicated because remember
we're decompressing this thing that we
export together and flip right and that
means that the bit you're actually
flipping might move right it might even
flip multiple bits and then we don't
know the crc correction to actually do
the reason for this is that deflate
which is what's used uses huffman coding
right and so there's a static for small
message there's a static huffman table
um that is used to encode all these
symbols and it's done by frequency and
so if you have say e i and h in these in
these things and given some relative
frequencies flipping one bit uh in the
huffman symbol is going to get you the
next like similarly frequent symbol or
something right and that might not
actually be the adjacent one in ascii
space right so the bit you flip here is
not actually when it decompresses the
bits that actually change
and this makes our lives more
complicated but it actually is a really
a good thing because this means we
actually have a format oracle we can use
right we can actually learn the contents
of the message based on the coc
correction the way we do this is we
guess what the character in the message
is we flip a bit in the cipher text and
we guess what the resulting change was
in the decompressed message right and
that guess is probably gonna be wrong on
both counts so we try again
and eventually after far more than three
actually uh you will probably guess
correctly and you will now have some
idea what the contents of that message
that character in the message is because
you actually know that the crc is valid
um
you repeat this a couple of times to
deal with false positives and then you
can move on and you can do this
iteratively over the entire message
uh to discover the contents right and so
this is this is the basic trick we're
using the fact that uh gzip errors if
the crc is invalid and that we can
actually make corrections to the crc to
validate what's going on to validate the
message
um
so
just a second for those of you like
following along at home um this is not a
compression oracle right uh
compression oracle is a possible chosen
plain text attack that leverages the
fact that you can just on any generic
form of compression doesn't matter how
it works you can look at how the message
size changes if you put in maybe guesses
as to what uh the other part of the
message is
we can't do that here we're doing a
chosen ciphertext attack and it actually
only works for a specific type of
compression which is uh gzip with a
huffman encoding um so they both use
compression but they're completely
different attacks just just to clarify
um all right so that's nice we now have
this format we can we can exploit we
have the technique we call it a gzip
oracle um
but we still need to be able to observe
when that works right we need to see if
this works or doesn't
uh and
that's a little hard because imessage is
not nice enough to send uh you errors
when you send someone a message that
doesn't uh work right doesn't say i'm
sorry your message could not be
delivered invalid crc please try again
um
and so
we need something right there are read
receipts right if you send someone a
message uh you can tell if they read it
uh
that has two problems with it first of
all it requires that someone actually is
there to read the messages
right which they might not be and second
um
we're going to have to send a lot of
messages and so if you see like two to
the 10 or to the 18 messages getting
sent from someone the game is probably
up
so we're trying to do a realistic attack
here and that's sort of a complete
non-starter um
so we need something else um
luckily it turns out that if you send a
large message in imessage or if you send
a message with a video or a photo as an
attachment um apple's push notification
network as we saw are sort of space
sensitive they don't want to send that
so instead they upload it to the icloud
encrypted under a symmetric key and they
send you a brief notification which is
effectively hey you have mail at this
url with this key to decrypt it and then
when the phone gets that and
decompresses the decrypts and
decompresses the message it does a
download to icloud and um
there doesn't request an icloud and
downloads the message and the cool part
is we can observe this and we know if we
see this request that our message was uh
correct
and if we don't see the request after
some time out we know that it failed and
so now we have our
error oracle we can observe this
remotely
um
it actually gets better
we don't
remember how i said we wanted the
stealth attack we can block the response
to that request from icloud and then you
can't download the attachment and it
turns out that imessage fails silently
in that case right it doesn't display
anything doesn't display a question mark
you know broken unicode box or anything
nothing you never see the attack
happened um and so we can do this entire
thing stealthily more interestingly
we can actually do this even if we can't
observe this request directly because we
can mutate the message and make the
request not go to icloud but go to an
attacker controlled server say you know
i8cloud.com which fun fact matt actually
uh registered just as a proof of concept
um
and so yeah this is nice um this is the
attachment message it's a little big
it's a little complicated um but you can
see that there's a key in there that we
uh probably want to read out this is
what the message is encrypted under so
if we can read this out of the message
we can decrypt the attachment there's
also the url that points to where you're
downloading it
unfortunately this message is a little
big and so the attack gets a lot harder
because uh
gzip it turns out remember i said it
uses static huffman tables well that's
true if the message is small if the
message is large it dynamically computes
the husband table based on the frequency
of the characters in the message
and this message happens to be large
enough for that and so this is a problem
because we can't do the crc guess and
check attack when we don't know the
huffman table and so this is actually
the hardest part of the attack it's the
most expensive part of running it we
have to somehow recover the
cover the huffman table and i don't
really have the time to go into the
exact details it's a pain you basically
have to leverage the same crc error
error issue but do it on known plaintext
and do some complicated stuff to search
for edges between variable length
symbols um
right so once you have that the attack
is fairly straightforward you get a
message somehow uh you change the sender
id you use the crc guess and check
attack both to recover the huffman table
and then to read out the attachment key
right this this key right here um and
then given that you simply decrypt the
attachment message that you've
downloaded from icloud um
right so we did actually implement this
um it takes two to the 18 queries um and
remember i said you have to wait when
you make a cipher text you send a send
to them all from ciphertext to see if
you get this request
well
you usually that happens pretty quickly
like
290 sorry 390 milliseconds um but you
have to wait to make sure if you don't
see it until you're sure that it
actually fails it's not just being slow
and unfortunately there's some
variability on this it's a very long
tail and so the maximum we have to wait
is a second right and so on the naive
proof of concept code we just wait to
see this we have to space every query
out at one second and so that takes 70
to 73 hours
um if you uh improve on the code and you
do backtracking where you send in a
bunch of messages at once and then uh
leverage the fact that most of these are
not going to require
trigger requests most of them will be
bad
and then when you see a request you can
backtrack over the last like tin that
you sent in to find out what it is you
can do this a lot faster in about
probably 35 hours but in either case we
actually executed the attack with proof
of concept code against a real system um
and we recovered 232 out of 256 bits
which is you know pretty good you can
brief force the rest of them uh but of
course this is on one sample ciphertext
that we just happened to pick um and so
maybe it's not clear if this attack
actually works you know in general but
unfortunately we can't easily test it a
bunch of times so instead what we did
was we wrote an emulator that emulated
how imessage validated ciphertext
um and we
actually tested that against the real
implementation and then we ran a huge
number of about 10 000 simulated uh
attacks
it turns out that for uh
about uh 34 of the time we cover all 40
bits of the message uh this encryption
key this and the attachment and
for uh about 25 of the time we recover
uh all about 24 bits of it so the
interesting thing is if you plot the
number of queries it takes versus the
number of bits we recover the attack is
actually fairly efficient when we
actually get it to work
but as you as you go down um
and start failing and recovering enough
bits it actually starts getting worse so
this tells me actually that the proof of
concept code we wrote has some room for
optimizations um
so how do you fix this well ideally you
deploy something like axelot or a signal
which has you know forward secure
properties and a nice nice system if you
didn't want to do that you could use
authenticated encryption use aes dcm or
ocv mode
and or just include an hmac but the
problem is this breaks backwards
compatibility right because both ends of
the protocol both ends have to be
upgraded and if you have a billion
devices and there's a bunch of different
versions and a bunch of different things
that's a problem so that gives gets us
into the question of real board
mitigations um and uh for those of you
who've ever done that this is kind of a
tire fire you're kind of trying to
develop
a the smallest minimal band-aid that
doesn't break anything but actually does
protect against the attack um and
uh very briefly we sort of uh
we gave two proposals one of which was
to fix the uh
the uh identity miss binding attack that
apple had um but that was a little
sensitive to how you did formatting it
didn't work the actual mitigation we
propose which is what's deployed is that
uh
you blacklist rsa cipher texts because
the rsa ciphertext is unmarriable so
you're going is invaluable so you're
going to get
this rsa ciphertext and then multiple
versions of the as ciphertext with like
bits permuted in it and so if you see
the same rsa ciphertext twice you know
that someone's running this attack and
you can just discard those responses so
this is deployed in irs uh
nine three plus and os x um it took
apple about four months and 30 engineers
to deploy and test this because it takes
a large amount of time to actually
validate these things
um
and yeah uh that's sort of i have to
give up a lot of props because while
this was going on the end of it they
were dealing with uh this as well uh so
with that
i'm actually just going to take
questions
thank you
[Applause]
uh kenny patterson from royal holloway
thank you for the great talk and i
really appreciate the great work that
you guys have done on this paper i just
wanted to point out that the solution is
not really authenticated encryption this
is a public key primitive what you
really want is a sign encryption scheme
which you can build from authenticated
encryption with the appropriate use of
public key encryption and signatures
right and actually if you look at the
encryption literature which clearly the
apple engineers manifestly failed to do
you find out that including the identity
as part of the plaintext is one of the
counter measures you need to prevent the
identity miss binding attacks that you
pointed out so the what's really
interesting here is that the cryptal
literature is very clear about how you
should design a system to achieve the
security properties that imessage sets
out to to have right and so i think one
of the one of the interesting things
someone once asked when i was giving a
talk on this like why do we have this
weird mix of rsa and ecdsa for
primitives right you'd think if you used
one if you use ecdsa you use some fancy
you know alcohol whatever elliptical
falcomold scheme i think the answer to
this is this sort of was designed based
on the menu of apis that whatever
cryptographic library they're using i
believe at the time probably opened an
ssl though not anymore um was and those
primitives just don't exist as far as i
know even in implementations
so that's sort of i think how we ended
up in this situation
so i would like to ask
two questions about rsa so have you
tried panicura cladducks against rsa
ciphertext like manners attack
so uh
we as far as we could determine this was
rsa or ap and it was implemented
correctly so i think those attacks
shouldn't be uh viable but in all
honesty we mainly went for the the one
the vulnerability that we saw that we
knew would have uh traction
okay and the second question also uh
airside oip is static
defense or you cannot do some backwards
compatibility to pkcs 1.5 so that you
could uh maybe
execute black in background attacks
yeah you might be able to do that
actually i'm not entirely sure
okay
thank you
i also have one question um so when
explaining the attack you also said that
you're dealing with false positives but
didn't go into details can you maybe
elaborate on this oh sorry the false
positive is what uh when you had when
you explained the uh the decryption so
your actual attack and you said that
sometimes false positives can happen
right so what can happen is of course
you're not guessing as to what the
actual character was and what you
changed it to you're guessing as to what
the xo of those two things were and
occasionally that could of course be
valid for something else and so what
happens is you make a couple of more
guesses as to the character was this and
i'm now going to change a different bit
and it's going to be permuted to a
different symbol and so if you do that
two or three times you get a fairly high
assurance uh that
it's the right guess
let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]