hello everyone
thanks for attending my talk it will be
about egalitarian computing by
egalitarian so uh we with my author alex
biruko far from western europe for
university of luxembourg so the problem
of uh doing egalitarian everything is
very
like
prominent in western europe
and this is about how computing should
be equal for everyone why computing
should be equal for everyone
well because we are talking about
attackers and defenders the problems
with the comparing attackers and
defenders is that attackers might always
have
been much more powerful they have more
resources they are more viable and even
one weakness is sufficient for a
successful attack whereas uh
defenders have to protect all of them
and attackers can spend much more time
so defenders are in a much weaker
position and
should
spend more resources
and
we can of course as defenders can harden
the protection for example increase the
key length in the crystal systems we use
and sometimes try to restrict the attack
vector for example by limiting the
exposure time of a web server so
limiting the number of
online password attacks but this uh
doesn't always work
for example well the secure
cryptographic algorithm with the very
sufficiently long key is a good solution
for quite a lot of protocols but quite
often we just don't have the keys we
have to rely on such an imperfect
mechanism as a human memory and uh
human memory it can memorize mainly
passwords the passwords are very
important instruments
but
the passwords don't have very low
entropy and as a result brute force
attacks become possible for example uh
attackers may try to guess a pin for
a mobile phone or for a credit card
the question is
if we have some secret with very low
entropy can we withstand attackers
and the
additional problem is that
this slow entropy secrets are very much
easier to break on special hardware so
many people really underestimate the
power of special hardware but on the
example of bitcoin it's very clear that
by using dedicated asics one can win up
to like 30 000 factor in energy costs
which is like the dominating
of the total running cost of the attack
this effectively means that if
we use just a normal uh
normal soft normal hardware like laptops
or servers whereas attackers switch to
asic our keys our passwords our pins
effectively loses a lot of security keys
lose 15 bits and passwords effectively
become three lower case later shorter
and pins if they are just of digits they
lose five digits
so we uh suspect that asic equipped
attackers are the threat from the near
future and we if we're going to protect
uh
from them we
have to design some sort of proto set of
protocols that would withstand potential
regression of special hardware
so and uh the problem is we have to slow
down attackers without slowing down the
defenders
this means that we should use the
features of x86 architecture or wherever
the defense is going on uh in order to
prohibit in order to make the switch to
other architectures inefficient for
attackers
one of the solution popular since 2003
is the use of memory intensive
computations
because uh when you or memory hard
computations when you use a lot of
memory because when you want to
implement an algorithm that uses a lot
of memory on this on a chip
then uh quite big uh the very big
proportion of area will be devoted to
memory and chips will never no longer be
as they will they will become much more
expensive compared to just chips that
implement the logic and with large
memory on chip the asic advantage will
effectively vanish
the question is how to uh devise an
algorithm that uses a lot of memory in
irreducible way and how to
um how to
use this algorithm in many different
protocols
of course when we talk about the
algorithms that use a lot of memory this
amount of memory cannot be reduced
an attacker shouldn't be able to compute
the same thing with less memory at the
same cost that's why we introduced the
notion of well we use the notion of
time-space trade-off meaning that if
how much the computation time how much
the accommodation complexity increases
if we
use less space and there can be
different sorts of trade-offs linear
trade-off means that time and space can
be traded equally meaning that an
adversary can use smaller chips but for
longer time and efficiently you could
save on the design cost so linear
trade-offs are not
desirable we need something better we
need f to be super polynomial or even
better
so one some earlier works of using
memory hard functions for
uh increasing the security of practical
protocols is one of our earlier design
argon 2 the memory heart hash function
the winner of password fashion
competition so the idea is to when you
hash passwords use as much memory as you
can in an irreducible way and apparently
after many investigations the time space
trade-off is sort of exponential so
when you reduce the space the so the
logarithm of time is uh equally traded
for
the inverse of space
so that the time increases exponential
of the space reduction
another example is the design of
so-called aqua hash it's memory card
proof of work so the proof of work you
know from the previous talk on bitcoins
the crucial feature of this proof of
work is that even though for computing
their proof you need a lot of memory to
verify the proof you don't need a lot of
memory it's asymmetric in this sense
and with fast verification the idea
inside is the generalized dirty problem
exactly you need to find a solution to
the truth of the cake soar by playing
with different x1 x2 and so on which are
all hashed and stored together you
should get a zero string
and interestingly that
a proof that
shows that you have used 700 megabytes
is only 120 bytes long and
takes about two seconds to find
so interestingly but not the topic of
our talk that almost any np complete
problem is a good candidate for memory
hard proof work
the egalitarian computing concept is
about using memory heart primitives in
different areas
because well
the problem uh
the word equalitarian comes from the
original paper on bitcoin where it was
dreamed that every user will be able to
mine bitcoins on his own laptop this is
apparently not the case the bitcoins are
currently mined on the huge farms
attached to
uh
he drop
electric power plants or some places
where you have cheap electricity and
apparently only a bunch of people
control a huge amount of mining power in
the world
so
argon 2 made password hashing more
secure but apparently with using a lot
of memory
you can make other protocols equally
secure so
for example or many password-based
protocols like key agreement or secret
sharing and password-based encryption
can be made more secure proofs of work
can be improved even compared to
equihash
if we use
memory hard proofs of work because they
will allow again
users of regular laptops regular
desktops to mine and be competitive on
the market of
cryptocurrencies even client puzzles for
denial of service protection
can use a lot of memory meaning that
adversaries with special hardware cannot
compute these client puzzles more
efficiently than
regular clients
so the concept of a glittering computing
ensures that legitimate users and
attackers are equal
because they effectively have to use the
same platform well of course if you
design a special asic that has
some small computing core and a lot of
memory you can make it very similar to
the x86 architecture but then what's the
point you can just use this regular
laptop
so the summer second advantage will
be present still but it will be much
much smaller advantage
the idea of how we
propose to implement this this concept
in practice is that if you ever have a
scheme uh where some
exact output value is not that important
for example you have encryption but the
output of the encryption is not that
important just important that uh the
encryption scheme is secure um in some
traditional sense of security like
semantic security against the
chosen platform or signature schemes
where you can
play a bit with the algorithms and still
making it more secure then we propose to
amalgamate this construction and augment
it with adding
argon 2 computation imperial or any
other memory heart function whatever
your favorite is
the idea is if you already spend some
cpu time for encryption for
sign-in for verification of signatures
why not use it uh for uh why not fill in
the your why not working with the memory
at the same time because it will bring
the protocols additional security if
they are trying to be broken on a
special hardware
for example on the top of this
scheme you have well suppose we have
some computation which undergoes a
series of transformations like whatever
transformation it's not hash function
every transformation would work
transformations h1 h2 like t different
steps and the idea is that you compute a
memory heart function
at the top of it and you feed
uh the out the intermediate values of
the memory heart function its memory
blocks into the computation
and sort here and then effectively any
adversary would try to repeat this
protocol with different values of in and
out so suppose he do some brute force
guessing there he would have to compute
this argument to function or any other
memory heart function in parallel so any
chip that computes uh this
scheme would have to contain a lot of
memory for this memory heart function to
operate
and
this can be used in different
environments for example you can compute
memory hard you can obfuscate the
computing by computing so-called memory
hard bits
when you
when the
original non-obfuscated
branch statement is replaced by uh
x sort some
some bits which are the
bits in the memory of a memory heart
function
another example a bit more interesting
and from my point of view so called
memory heart encryption
so
we look primarily at the disk encryption
so quite some time uh when you encrypt
your own hard drive
you the there the key is derived from a
password the idea is that you would be
able to decrypt the hard drive even if
you lose computational power if you just
have the password in mind so you would
be able to recover it the problem is
that
this
encryption is
and decryption
doesn't uh take uh doesn't take any
memory the idea is just the disk space
is uh partitioned into chunks and every
chunk is encrypted with a standard
encryption algorithm say yes and the
counter mode or the cbc mode or xts mode
whatever and
any attack uh suppose that bursary
steals uh your hard drive then how would
he try different passwords he would take
passwords one two three four five uh
compute derive a key from it and then
try the ski for decryption he decrypts
only a small block of data
and
and checks if the result in plain text
has sufficient redundancy if he decrypts
for example
a word document or any other document
that has redundancy
the problem is that even if you use the
memory heart function for key derivation
there's this encryption keys can still
be computed offline pre-computed for
example on memory device but the trial
decryption can be still doing memoryless
by uh taking this pre-computed keys from
other
from other machine
and our idea is uh where where we follow
uh greg zavruha's earlier proposal from
2015 is that not only the key should be
derived from with the memory heart
function but the encryption itself also
should use
as much memory as you could then if
sufficient memory is used
then uh trial decryption cannot be
done without memory and then the
adversary would have who would want to
brute force passwords would have to do
it on the same machine almost on the
same machine where
the cipher text is stored
so the idea of
gregor was to use the all or nothing
transform by ronda best where the chunks
uh
the data chunks are decrypted are
decryptable in two passes and for the
second pass it must be fully decrypted
and kept into memory
and then the memory is inevitably bound
to the chunk length
our idea is to improve on it and use the
memory heart
function not only for the key generation
but in the middle of the process of
encryption
to make the decryption run on some heart
on the same hardware and being
irreversible so you can see it on this
picture
so
uh here at the top is the memory heart
function that has been computed and
here uh this m1 m2 are message blocks
that are to be encrypted the idea is
that you can you
encrypt the con the memory blocks and
use it uh on some random key and use it
as the key stream encrypt the memo the
plaintext blocks and then encrypt them
again on some key password derived key
and eventually you store this random key
in the very last block
so the idea is that and you also
feedback the ciphertext blocks back to
the argon 2 computation or any other
memory heart function computation the
idea is that you can uh use much more
memory because the
the argument computation is faster than
encryption you can you use much more
memory than you use for the chunk and
you can make this memory and chunk size
independently and
there is no way to pre-compute either
part of it to try the decryption
offline
for example if the encryption is aes
then we can fill four or six times
faster memory than you compute aes and
for example if we work with one megabyte
chunk and we can tolerate one tenth of a
second for decryption then we can
effectively use 256 megabytes of ram
which is quite a prohibitive factor if
we tolerate one second then we can use
up to two gigabytes of frame which would
be prohibitive even for bat for botnets
this is not and our last example is the
egalitarian proofs of work so one
example you have seen already this
equihash thing
but the subject of another work and
our new proof of work
is based on argon 2. interestingly the
proofs of work have to satisfy quite a
lot of properties so it's not easy to
build them even if you have a memory
heart function in the pocket so
the proofs of work have to have a
symmetry they have to be hard to compute
but easy to verify they have to be
amortization free meaning that every
next solution is should be as much
expensive as the first one if memory
hard hardness has claimed that the time
step space trade-offs should be
sufficiently steep time and memory
should be tuned independently the best
algorithms for memory heart functions
should have already been found
and uh
also interestingly that the progress
free property that chances to find the
solution do not accumulate over time so
that uh the solution finding is some
sort of a stochastic process some sort
of post-on process where every time you
do
every small portion of a second to do
computation you have nonzero chance to
find it you cannot spend 10 minutes to
find proof of work because it would
stimulate centralization in
among cryptocurrency minors and also be
ideally parallel unfriendly meaning that
if you employ multiple cores they will
not uh
your implementation will not be
more energy efficient
interestingly that different proofs of
work they miss uh one or two of these
properties for example the bitcoins is
not proof of work equihash
is not so much progress free and if you
employ a regular proof of space
then they don't have that nice
trade-offs and
they
every next solution is not as much
expensive because there are several
interesting attacks on them so
if you just employ a memory heart
function for proof of work and follow it
with
so-called difficulty test if you first
run it and then apply a hash function at
the very end to check for the leading
zeros
then the problem is that it doesn't
allow a fast verification so to verify
it to verify the first scheme you would
need a lot of memory also for
verification that's not nice there are
concepts like proof of space where you
compute
some memory heart function then compute
miracle 3 over it and the miracle root
determines which which memory blocks you
have to open to prove that you computed
it properly but there are some subtle
things here so if you
supply the nonce for proof of work as an
input to this proof of space then there
is a called grinding attack that
allows to
repeat only small parts of this
computation to pass the difficulty test
so suppose you make one comp you
selected a nonce you have made a
computation but in the end you
eventually failed with having say d
leading zeros for the output then
the idea of the attack is not to
recompute the whole thing from scratch
but exploit the fact that not all blocks
are opened by this procedure you can
cheat by
trying
only the very last block until you
succeed and there is a very big chance
that this last block will never be part
of the opening and not only the last
block but the block before last would
also work
our idea is to
build a similar but more secure
construction on the top of argon 2. the
idea is that we select the nonce only
after the merkle tree is computed and we
open a certain number of blocks like 100
different blocks
the thing is
the parallelism is still possible here
but
since we select
and open random blocks here
the any parallel implementation of this
proof of work would have to have a very
high memory bandwidth with random access
to memory and this problem is considered
to be hard so
even the best
gpu do not have a memory bandwidth more
than one terabyte per second and we
think that if we employ like 100 cores
here then this bandwidth will be
exceeded so we don't think that
special hardware would be
very helpful in implementing this scheme
and the benefit of it is that it's very
fast in terms that
if you
feel what two gigabytes it will take
only one second because they are going
to is very fast and fill in memory
so
these are several examples of
how egalitarian computing can bring more
security to different protocols
interestingly so it can make
the ski it can make six letter passwords
that were deemed insecure before they
can still they can become secure again
if we uh hash them with the memory heart
function and deploy them in the memory
heart protocols the 80 80-bit keys can
be secure again because
if we employ them in memory hard
constructions then special hardware will
be no benefit so for example we can we
have heard that the des cipher was
broken on a special hardware on fpga but
we didn't hear that
the key was brute forced on a regular
laptop or a server that's still too
expensive so denial of service attacks
are also made harder with this concept
and blockchain users can again be
regular miners
so this or this concept it suffrages a
lot of users and make finally the
defenders equal to the attackers and
make
our defenses much
much better
so uh very similarly to as it happened
uh more than one hundred years ago uh we
uh the concept of egalitarian computing
will hopefully bring uh more
security and
more equality
to regular people
thank you
[Applause]
you have time for questions
so i'll i'll start things off so i
really like the idea here and it seems
to work well given the current computing
um
economics and availability the question
is is there a counter egalitarian
computing where an organization that has
say many billions of dollars and has an
incentive to break crypto and won't name
any particular organizations
could construct hardware that would give
them a bigger advantage and then
actually have more of an asymmetric
advantage because they have hardware
that no one else has that's designed
around these kinds of memory hard
problems
is there a fundamental reason why that's
not possible or it's just the economics
of it
so could you repeat the question exactly
um so the question is if the nsa wanted
to spend
20 billion dollars
trying to break memory hard functions
could they do it
well i think they wouldn't break
the functions with 20 million dollars
they can build special they can build
hardware that be very close to regular
servers but
they will be it will be efficient by a
small factor maybe by the factor of 10
or 15 so it will probably not worth the
cost that's the whole feature so uh the
special hardware will still be slightly
more efficient but not to the extent
that it will uh worth billions of
dollars spent for this purpose
so is there a fundamental reason why
building
that there there couldn't be a design
for special hardware that makes these
memory
hard fun you know you're not designing a
custom basic now there's a lot of
history in building custom basics to
make um straight-line computation more
efficient
why someone with enough resource
couldn't do something to make
large-scale memory access more efficient
well no
fundamental
barrier probably
but uh well uh if uh such uh
construction appear in the future
i think we'll
i do not have any inside information
that the nsa is working on this so i
think i think we're safe for a while i
think it
i hope to make sense given what we know
now so thank you uh any other questions
so do we have a speaker for the fourth
paper
[Applause]
yes give the tree again