I thank you very much for the kind
introduction this joint work together
with a team or who is in Germany and
ampere who was a student in Birmingham
and today I will present together with
Flavio paper locket and Seleucid on the
insecurity of automotive remote keyless
entry systems so if you look at the
typical cocky you I have two main
electronic components in there
one is the immobilizer which is in
passive RFID system running at 125
kilohertz with a range of a few
centimeters maybe and this mobilizers
have a very long or attacks on
immobilizers have a very long history
here at using it so if you're interested
you can look into this today we will
speak about the system which has not
been looked into too much and this is a
remote keyless entry systems rke systems
it says this buttons here on the remote
control that you press to open or lock
your car or to access a trunk also or in
the u.s. sometimes sounds alarm these
are active UHF systems at high frequency
with a higher range and say
unidirectional so the remote just talks
to the car basically they can sometimes
be integrated with immobilizers and we
have a so-called hybrid system or they
can be completely separate so and we
were curious also partially motivated by
unexplained caste cases of car safe
without signs of or theft from blood
cars without signs of forced entry
houses may be possible and how a
security systems were so back in the day
when this was introduced we had
so-called fixed codes where you just
sent a fixed UID and the button that was
pressed to the vehicle and then the car
would execute this action and obviously
such systems are vulnerable to simply
replay a text so Oscar can just
eavesdrops a signal from a high range in
this case we have high frequency systems
replays the system and open the vehicle
and the ranges are then the range up to
a hundred meters reading so these
systems obviously not good this is why
industry has reacted and invented
so-called rollin codes which are based
on cryptography now so we have the
shared secret both in the car
and the remote control and houses is
used the shared secret is used to in
some way or CENTAC 8 so encrypt or Mac
maybe account our value together with
the press button and then on every
button press this counter is incremented
to give freshness and to prevent relay
attacks in this way so if you want you
can think of it this is a nice circle so
you have some current counter values and
only counter values and the future are
accepted within some validity window and
the encryptions then ensures its
adversary cannot simply increment the
counter himself
so there are many realizations how this
is actually done in practice that's just
an illustration so I said Oscar has no
opportunities to break the system unless
he does one of the following two things
and this can be either attacks of
cryptography or attacks the key
management and in this presentation will
give examples for both cases where the
texts are still possible I will talk
about the key management part a bit more
Flavio boards a crypto path so a very
brief history of attacks on our ke
systems roundabout in 2007-2008 we have
seen many attacks on key log garage door
openers they are also rolling code base
first there was crypt analysis which
however was sort of impractical in this
keyless entry scenario because you
needed 2 to the 16 codes to basically
extract the key and afterwards in 2008
we had a side-channel attacks on the key
diversification which were more
realistic a different line of research
our attacks on so called passive keyless
entry systems is a this keys where you
do not have to press a button anymore
they are vulnerable to relay and then in
2014 we have seen a few attacks on
actual vehicles one was an attack biases
other on around about 2000 to 2005
vehicle based on some mathematical
techniques and later there was last year
this road Jam attack
which is based on a combination of
intelligent jamming and replaying
however in the cases that we'll talk
about this will not apply
since the button function is actually
authenticated so it's included in the
cryptography so if you eavesdrop a close
signal you could not turn it into an
open signal in our cases this brings me
to the first case study which is the
system employed by the VW Group so for
those who do not know VW Group is formed
of volkswagen audi is CH Gouda plus a
few luxury brands such as Porsche and
all in all that they have around about
10% worldwide a market share so it's one
of the leading automotive companies the
system is widely employed the
immobilizer system called mega Moss has
some history at you snakes if you do not
know you can look into this however the
rke system is completely separate so
there's no mega Moss used in the keyless
entry system here we have looked at
vehicles between roundabout 2000 or
earlier and today and found four main
schemes which we call VW want to BW for
in the following of the presentation
however there are a few more remaining
niche schemes where we suspect the I in
a similar way vulnerable so when
analyzing this remote keyless entry
systems in general you first need to
eavesdrop signals and there are various
opportunities for this one is to use
software-defined radio such as is very
low cost dvb-t sticks or also an HEC RF
maybe us appeal the other option is to
build purpose design systems like this
Arduino board which can be built for
round about 40 dollars which can receive
and transmit data and is also as you can
see battery-powered a typical VW rolling
code would look like this you have some
preamble at the beginning then start
pattern and then the actual part
carrying the data so we looked at this a
bit in a black box fashion and could not
really figure out what was going on so
we continued to reverse-engineer ECU
firmware for this we first had to find
the correct issue for each of the
schemes VW one
to vw4 extracts the firmware from the
microcontroller reverse engineers the
cryptography using tools like Ida Pro
for those who know reverse engineering
this is similar to the software world
and then from there we got access to the
full cryptographic algorithms and also
the utilized keys so I'll only briefly
talk about two of these four schemes one
is this as a to more recent schemes one
is vw3 and we found out that the rolling
code is basically constructed like this
year you have a cipher called odd 64
which you probably do not know we later
basically found the cipher and some Atma
data sheets in a high-level fashion we
have not looked at it really deeply
cryptographically and this odd 64 sci-fi
is then used to encrypt encrypts UID the
counter value and the button value and
afterwards a button value is again sent
in clear text for some reason what you
already can notice is UID is never sent
in clear so the car has first to decrypt
to basically get all those values which
sort of suggests that something may be
wrong with the key management here and
indeed this key case reads that you see
is just the same key and all vehicles
made under this VW scheme so there's no
key diversification had all been
employed and it's just one symmetric
secret it's also interesting to note
that actually all the w3 cars have to
decrypt all the codes in their insanity
this VW tooth system is just same cipher
same system slightly different packet
format and a different worldwide key and
the system before that we w1 is just
based on linear shift registers again
with global secret so we did not have to
open the box of trip analysis here at
all the newest system that we looked at
is called VW for users if you compare to
the previous slide only the exteriors -
instead of odd 64 but nothing else has
changed so the cryptography is fine it's
a secure standard cipher
but again we have one worldwide key k4
in in this case since summaries this
means the adversary can just eavesdrop a
single signal get the UID value gets a
counter value and from then create a
clone of the original remote control
with this knowledge of those global keys
and I'll also have a small video
demonstration for you you see a folks
van Passat and first of all now the
original owner opens vehicle with this
remote here we have open and close but
one signal would just be sufficient
basically and now for demonstration
purposes we actually place a remote
control on the car and have this
sophisticated eavesdropping and sending
device it's similar to Arduino board and
this has now if stop the key and can
generate future use of signal and can
based on the global key generate future
signals such as open closed open closed
and so on so now the case actually this
counter is for values ahead of the
original remote so how many times does
the owner now have to press four five
five actually so you have to press five
times such that the counter in the
remote control again catches up with
with the key with the car so under the
fifth times the car works again with the
original remote this affects a large
amount of VW vehicles this is a list of
vehicles that we could actually identify
so we have audience list you have
Volkswagen C art scooter
so in summary probably most of the
vehicles manufactured between two
thousand or ninety five however and
today the only exception is the newest
platform that's a go of seven or MQB
module logically about kaznia some
german word a platform which allegedly
uses better cryptography and more
importantly maybe better key management
actually so before I hand over to Flavia
just to summarize this part we have seen
the cryptographic algorithms
a bit improving over time from this lfsr
to add 64 to X TIA
however just secure crypto doesn't make
a secure system if you have a bad key
much key management and in this case we
could just reverse engineer su firmware
gets this global master keys which makes
attack very practical and very scalable
and a said only the newest system if you
have such a vehicle is allegedly more
secure so so much for this failures in
key diversification and now Flavio will
tell you a bit more about problems with
cryptography thank you hi so we look
into another widely use remote keyless
entry system so-called high-tech tube is
used by several comics including a
Romero's heathrow and Mies and fourth
row show Mitsubishi
Renault Opel among others in contrast to
the to the BW systems these do have a
different key per car key so we need to
work with the we need to develop some
crypt analysis for for retrieving the
secret key
so back in at least 6 2012 ever dueled
Bala and myself proposed an attack
against the hi-tech to immobilize
decipher was known before so we did some
crypt analysis and this attack required
knowing the UID of the of the key
required 136 authentication attempts
from the car and 5-minute computation on
a laptop while speaking with the
manufacturers this attack was not deemed
a really a practical car only for the do
2d this first requirement that you have
to gather the UID of the car key but and
because of the immobilizer system is a
passive chip you need to be really in
close proximity typically 2 centimeters
from the victim to read the UID of their
key so it will say well yeah this is not
really a concern is not that practical
okay now in the remote keyless entry
context
this this high tattoo cheapest use is
often integrating the both the
immobilizer and the remote keyless entry
system in one chip although they have
different cryptographic keys but the
first thing we notice is that the UID is
the same for both interfaces so this
allows you to eavesdrop the UID of the
MIDI mobilizer through the remote
keyless entry system but this you can do
at a much larger range which which makes
the immobilizer attack already
a lot more powerful but yes in the
remote keyless entry context 136 traces
it's not really practical I would say
because you would have to wait so many
times that the owner pushes the car key
and you will have to be listening in
there so you you wouldn't deem that as a
practical attack so we we went back to
the drawing board and work a bit harder
on the on the attack and we develop a
completely new attack which is now
correlation based but first we needed to
figure out what the protocol the
authentication protocol actually was we
knew what the cipher was so we start
simply observing at the signals being
sent and just just trying trial and
error until we got the the right the
right guesses here is what it was quite
simple it sends a UID a button and
number a counter value and then a Mac of
all the previous values and then as here
C which is just a checksum to detect
transmission errors over-the-air these
this mark is basically just some key
stream generated by a stream cipher
which is initialized with all the UID
the button on the counter and the and a
shared key okay
so this attack that we that I'm going to
describe now requires a four to eight
traces which you can collect easily as
as David just mentioned with an Arduino
inexpensive arenal device we built
ourself which cost about $40
if you want to speed up this harvesting
these traces you could do some how neat
trick reactive jamming so I mentioned
that there is a checksum at the end of
the message so if you are listening with
the with this device until the last bit
of the Mack and then you start sending a
lot of noise
this will jam the checksum and then the
car will ignore that message but yet you
were able to record this whole trace
because the checksum you can compute
yourself so two things may happen either
the own the car owner realizes that the
car didn't blink the lights or so and
then pushes the key again and then you
get an extra trace for free or the owner
doesn't realize that the car didn't
receive the signal and walks away with
the car unlocked in either case the
adversary wins so I'm going to now I
have to abstract a bit of the crypto
details but I will try to give you a bit
of the flavor of the attack and how does
this work this is the high-tech 2 side
first you can see it's based on a 48-bit
lfsr non-linear boolean function which
produces one key to one key one bit of
key stream with every clock tick as I
said decipher as you can imagine is
initialize with all the values the
counter the button numbers the symmetric
key and then it's run to produce this
this Mac which is what gives you the
security in the product so the attack
goes as follows you first will get a 16
bit window there on on the left side of
the lfsr and we we are going to score
our guesses based on correlation as I as
I hinted before and we will compute for
each guess a score based on the ratio of
inputs to this boolean function that
produced the correct key stream bit and
then we will start shift in this window
around and keep on computing the the
score for every offset
and then we really do this for each
offset and we go on like that
once we have all the score we take the
average score for the guests and then we
will keep a table of fixed length and
we'll discard the the guesses with with
low score and then we move on and we
extend this window by one bit now
seventeen bit 18 and 19 and so on and so
forth until we get all the 48 bits from
the internal state of decipher this
sounds a bit complicated and actually
I'm simplifying really a lot because
when you want to do this on many traces
you need to compute the keystream and to
correct the counter the difference in
the counter value in the internal state
but I just want I'm just happy if if you
walk out of here with a bit of the
flavor of how the attack works so this
runs in about one minute on this laptop
and music male 2 percent so knows no
specialized hardware whatsoever and
computes the 48 bits secretly there are
a few practical limitations something I
didn't mention before in the
authentication protocol only the 10
least significant bits of the counter
being sent over over-the-air but all 28
bits of the of the counter are being
used to initialize the cipher and for
the authentication protocol so you will
need to get guess this whole counter but
this is surprisingly easy because for
all the cars we tested which are quite a
few all the key start from 0 so and 10
bits is 1,024 key pushes so yeah it's
not so hard to guess how many thousand
times a victim has pushed the button
especially if it's a recently relatively
new car if it's a car from this year
you're pretty sure the most significant
bits will be either 0 or 1 right and for
all the Indy cars we tested the count
the most significant bits were at most
10 so you can basically run the attack
so many times and find out another
problem we found is that well if you run
this a type that I just described on the
immobilizer
then for traces are enough because the
india10 dication protocol for the
immobilizer you have
random nonsense with this because here
you you have a counter there's only one
bit changing often in in the state and
you can see I have a few real traces
from a real car key and if you see there
are two consecutive valleys there and if
you look at the map you would expect a
cryptographic match to be completely
randomized but if you look at those
values with the naked eye you can spot
that they are really they look pretty
much alike so there are only a few bits
different so the cipher is so bad that
it makes our attack less efficient
because we only get a few bits of
information with with consecutive traces
so that means that in the context of
remote keyless entry system we need a
few more traces typically eight to
recover the secret key okay Tom going to
show you a demo now of this attack from
beginning to end as you can see there is
the Arduino board connected to the
laptop I'm going to first collect a few
traces you can see on the screen
probably there the traces of
there we go but there is the key now we
are going to program that he and the
counter value that we have served on the
traces into this Arduino board which has
cube which has two buttons one to open
the car and one to love it you can see
the car cannot tell the difference
between this Arduino board and a and the
original right
so we tested this this attack known on
many many vehicles which we got from
friends and and colleagues which who
were kind enough to lend us their car as
you can see is quite at least some
eighteen vehicles and quite a few 2016
cars so yes we are running out of time
so I will just move to the conclusions I
wanted to say that as always we engaged
in responsible disclosure we informed
the buzzwagon group of our findings back
in December 2015 and NXP Semiconductors
the the manufacturers of the hi-tech -
transponder back in January 2016 and I
can say that the communication has been
friendly and constructive so yes you see
it is a bit surprising that a hi-tech -
is still being used in vehicles from
this year since the Hydra - cipher has
been shown to have deficiencies for
quite a few years now yes and we hope
that this research will explain several
cases mysterious cases of of theft where
there was no sign of forced entry but
yet things were missing from cars or the
cars themselves and then the insurance
was puzzled or was sceptical about those
claims thank you
that's an easy technical question the
counters are the different for each UID
or is it one for the for the car so the
question was if the counters are
different for each remote yes
essentially yes yes would have always if
your wife opened your car you would have
to press ten times again that's so
that's what I thought the other question
is you might know the answer or not want
to answer but are you aware whether
these systems were designed by the
engineers within the automotive industry
or whether it was it outsourced was it
some other company they have some
technology that they bought in usually
these companies have some suppliers that
design the systems we don't know if it
was true as a specification of the car
companies or if they just externally
bought it with a high-tech - system I
think it's a system basically specified
by an XP originally but automotive
manufacturers of course free or was free
to also modify the system times they
took a small differences so regarding
the Volkswagen I mean the immobilizers
they typically use different keys per
key right so there must be a mechanism
in place to to hold out individual keys
/ p4 so as when you communicate it with
folks form have they given you any
explanation why they are using one
worldwide key I mean how stupid is that
oh we were when we initially looked at
the systems we were also very surprised
to see this and we have never found any
easy explanation I mean I mean the only
lame excuse could be that they don't
have a mechanism to roll out the keys
into the key fobs but money immobilizer
say this has to be there yes the
immobilizer system in fork swung is
really completely separate so you have
this glass transponder which has no
connection to the Archaea system so
probably said some reasons that they
didn't have this hybrid chip okay
simplistic to system has a keeper car
key let's say a different key yeah so
actually I also have a question so can
you elaborate a little bit on your
experience with responsible disclosure
Express especially you know comparing
this how things have changed comparing
to your previous experiences with a mega
Mo's attack yes so by now we we knew the
technical people within within the
companies and that helps a lot so I
always get getting to a company through
the technical person's help a lot and
they understand why we're doing this and
then then the the climate is very
different yeah all right great so if
there are no more questions let's prank
two speakers
[Applause]