thank you dr lesson and
thanks sebastian's great talk on
sench good morning everyone my name is
dave i'm from university of florida and
i'm here to present our paper making usb
great again with usb filter i would like
to thank our co-authors
nolan's gave adam bass kevin butler and
patrick trainer
so first we would like to thank our
advisors who provide solid funding to
make this solid head and ask us to wear
this hat during the
presentation so here is my head
all right so
what is usb and why usb was great so usb
is short for universal serial bus with
the 20 years of development it has
replaced a lot of old technologies so
for example uh at the left corner no one
can find the ps2 ports which were for
keyboard and mouse uh in the current
laptop or laptops
and it also has been evolving from 1.0
to the latest one 3.1 and type c
in usb 3.1 the speed can be up to 10
gigabits per second which is fast enough
to support most external storage devices
and even gpu cards
usb is truly ubiquitous
virtually everyone can find usb ports on
every computer which includes desktops
servers routers switches right and
essentially there are tons of different
usb devices so we've got usb shoes we've
got usb fridge
everyone just love usb
but what is the problem so um
in oakland this year uh
there's a paper talking about
people just plugging the usb device or
the flash drive they found somewhere
without a second consideration so
this makes usb flash drive a perfect way
to
propagate the malware and even breaking
into the air gap so the the most famous
example is
the stock net uh malware which can be
find within the usb flash drive
and this malware is able to destroy the
industrial control system of a nuclear
plant
and for sure more recently we've got bad
usb attacks
so basically battery usb attacks allows
users to add a new functionality within
the usb firmware so for example a usb
flash drive can behave like a keyboard
and inject malicious script into the
host machine
but actually we've got tons of
usb penetration tools available in the
market for a year one of the example is
usb rubber ducky which is 39 bucks i
think
it looks like usb flash drive but
essentially it is a programmable usb
keyboard
and for sure we've got some solutions
right so one of the solutions is to
physically block the usb port
this is really common for a security
sensitive environment for example for
governments
national labs or mentally military labs
but before we start to use super glue to
destroy our usb port we probably want to
know
something deeper about usb
so the way for the usb host machine to
recognize the device
is called usb enumeration so when the
device is plugged into the host machine
the host machine is gonna ask for some
information and the device is
responsible for all this information for
example the manufacturer the product as
we can see this device is a kingston
flash drive
and then the device got a request for
some functionality which can be
satisfied by the operating system
and as we can see this device is
requesting a storage device since it is
a flash drive in bad usb attacks
unfortunately this device would also
request a human interface functionality
which is required
for all the keyboard or any other input
to usb devices
and then if we look into the usb device
we realize a usb device can have
multiple interfaces so each interface is
a standalone functionality so for
example in a usb headset we probably
have more than three interfaces
one for audio uh the other for speaker
and the last one maybe for the volume
control
and if we look into the interface we'll
see a bunch of endpoints
which are grouped based on the direction
of the usb communication so if the
communication is from the usb host
machine to the device then it is out
otherwise it is in which means
the communication is from the device to
the host machine
so once we know the device the interface
the direction of the usb communication
the real communication of the usb
happens within the endpoint
then the question is what is the basic
communication unit within the usb wires
so it turns out it is a usb packet
so for example every time when you type
a key on the keyboard there will be a
usb package encapsulated within the
keystroke and delivered to the host
machine
similarly
if we want to read or write a file saved
in a usb storage there will be bunch of
usb packages encapsulating the
corresponding data
and in bad usb attacks
the storage is also able to send out the
keyboard usb pad
usb package
so
basically inspired by net filter within
the lens kernel
we we were wondering if it is possible
to control the behavior of usb devices
by controlling the usb packet
and here we go uh we designed and
implemented usb filter so usb filter is
a kernel component working under the
host controller so which means we
basically trust the kernel and it has
two other kernel components
the right one is usb filter modules
which means system main or developers
can write
new features and plug in these kernel
modules into usb fuse
filter dynamically and before usb filter
is able to filter each usb packet it
would query the root database which can
which contains all the policies for the
packet filtering and within the use
space
we provide a user-based tool called usb
tables
which is to manage all this policy and
rules
one cool feature of usb filter as
one can see
it is able to correlate a usb packet
within the kernel with the i o
operations of circuit applications in
the user space
so to uh to achieve this goal we
instrumented um a bunch of general usb
devices drivers to trace back the pid of
the originating applications for certain
usb package so for example we did some
hacking within the usb driver to recover
the pid
but before we designed implemented usb
filters we set up some goals to make
sure it is not just a firewall within
the lens kernel so the first goal
is complete mediation which means we're
able to mediate all the usb packets
within the host machine
the second goal is temper proof
that means no use space program can
bypass or disable usb filter without
root permission
the third one is verifiability while
we're not able we're not able to
formally verify the kernel
implementation but instead we're
focusing on the rule consistency verify
verifiability that means before each
rule is added into the kernel we want we
want to make sure there's no conflict
between this neural and all other
existing rules within the kernel
so basically these three
goals are the
properties of a
reference monitor and then the last
the fourth goal is granularity so in
general we want to provide as many root
constructions as possible to enable
system in to write powerful and flexible
rules
the last one is extensibility
just like the usb filter module we've
mentioned before
we allow system main to write new
features and plugging them into usb
filter
so first let's look at rule
constructions so basically we've had we
have 21 rule constructions and we
divided them uh into four tables the
first table is the process table which
has all the information about this user
space process application
for example we've got pid ppid ui dn
command line
and then the second table is device
table which has all the information
about this device like manufacturer
product serial number and some physical
connecting information about this device
for example where this device is plugged
into the bus number the port number
and then the third table is packet table
it has
the properties about this usb pack for
example if this is a
keyboard packet or if this is a usb
storage packet
uh what about the direction if is in or
out and what is the endpoint which is
responsible for the communication and
the last table islam which is short for
linux usb filter module and we will talk
about that in later
slides
so before
we can talk about rule consistency we
need to talk about uh something else
because the way we look for rule
consistent verify of verification is to
look for the conflict between any two
rules
so
we need to define
a general conflict at first
here is the formal description so what
it says is
if root a is a subset of rule b
or
put it in another way if there's a usb
packet which matches both the rule a and
root b we will say there will be some
general conflict between ru a and ruby
so for example
if we have a rule saying that blocking
all usb ports and then we have another
rule saying that blocking usb port 5
then there will be general conflict
and depends on the
the final action of these rules which is
either allow this package or to drop
this packet we have weak conflict and
strong conflict so if
the action is the same then we call it a
weak conflict otherwise it is a strong
conflict the reason why we talk about
all all these different conflict
definitions is our current
implementation is
looking for general conflict which
provides
the strongest
consistency checking but in reality we
probably can just look for strong
conflict and allow weak conflict so the
whole rule consistent tracking is
implemented as a prologue engine which
turns
the the rule policy checking into
logical reasoning
and then here is the linux usb filter
module it is essentially a user defined
extension for usb filter so to write
alarm all we need is to include this
header file and then one can write a
cool current module so it is a rule
construction unit which means once the
alarm is plugged into the usb filter one
can write new rules using this long as
we have seen in the root construction
table
and essentially llama is a way to look
into the usb package may encapsulate uh
other packs like scusi command ip
package or
human interface device package like the
keystroke from keyboard
so here we show a
simple alarm implementation to detect
viscosity write command so sagasi is the
protocol used by most usb storage
devices so to read or write a file
within a usb storage the usb package is
able or needs to carry the corresponding
sc command and the data inside to finish
the real job
the core implementation of this alarm is
only 28 lines including space and
comments
so the first thing is we look at the
direction of the packet we want to make
sure this is packaged from the host
machine to the device
then we want to make sure this packet is
large enough because we want to know it
has to contain some
some skus command inside
and then we want to make sure
this packet has something rather than
just a usb packet header
and then we extract the op code of
discussing command from this usb packet
we look at this op code if this is a
discussion rec command we return one
otherwise we return zero
so in general uh
the usb filter
has changed 27 kernel source files
including four new files and 23 modified
files all the changes are across usb sc
block networking subsystems
we also design and implement a use space
tool called usb tables which has an
internal prolog engine to do root
consistency checking and we provided 20
rule constructions which covers almost
all the useful information which can be
provided by the kernel
so the first case is here to show how we
can stop bad usb attacks using a usb
filter
so one common bad usb attacks is to
allow
non-input devices to type like keyboard
or to move like a mouse
so the first rule we need is basically
to allow our own mouse to move like a
mouse
then we've got a second rule
that means we allow our own keyboard to
type
then the last one is seeing that we will
drop all other
keyboard or mouse package for any other
devices
the second case is to show how we can
pin certain applications to certain usb
device
now the first reason that we allow
application skype to access the web
camera with this serial number is b44
blah blah and the second rule is is
saying we're gonna drop all other
packets for this device so this case is
really useful because we prevent any
other
malicious programs in the user space to
uh from accessing the the usb vap camera
and to stop that exfiltration from the
host machine all we need is essentially
one simple rule so within this rule uh
we are using the alarm we we introduced
before which is able to detect the sc
command within the usb packet
so all we need is this simple rule uh
then we can drop all the usb package
which contains viscosity command and
we're able to make sure no data can be
written into any external usb service
devices
and in this case we show how we can use
uav usb filter to disable certain
functionalities within the usb device so
here we show how we can disable
the microphone functionality within a
usb headset
this case is really useful because in
security sensitive environments
the speak of the microphone
functionality is forbidden so with the
help of this rule users can bring their
own usb headset
and using them without worrying about
breaking the security uh the security
requirement
and then here uh we've got something
much more interesting
so as we know like um the cell phone can
be malicious
so we want to make sure the cell phone
can only
uh
be charged when they are plugged into
our machine so here we show
an example for the nexus 4. so what this
rule says is if this is a nexus 4 cell
phone we would drop any other usb packet
which makes
a perfect charger for nexus 4.
for sure the
nexus 4 can lie about its eye intensity
so thanks to bad usb attacks the nexus 4
can claim itself as an iphone which
makes this useless and then we've got
another rule here so what this rule says
is
no matter what kind of device you are
as long as you plug into that bus number
with that part number we will get a rid
of all the usb traffic so that makes
that port a perfect charger port
so basically
we're safe to charge the cell phone
well to to understand the performance
overhead introduced by usb filter we
conduct a series of
evaluation using
adele machine with a
intel quad-core 3.2 gigahertz cpu and 8
gigabytes memory and and intel usb 2.0
uh host controller
uh running ubuntu
14.04 lts with kernel version 3.13
so uh first we measure the scalability
of usb tables since it uses a prolog
engine to to do the rule consistency
checking so uh
before we add a new rule into the kernel
we measure
the overhead uh of this action when
there are 20 base rules
and 100 base rules
so
it turns out the result is almost the
same
the overhead is 5.9
millisecond this is the result of
compiling prolog into the assembly code
directly
and accordingly we measure the overhead
of package filtering for usb filter when
there are 20 base rules and 100 base
rules in the kernel
as one can see
the overhead of usb filter to do
filtering
is linear to the increasing of the
number of rules
and when there are 20 base rules in the
kernel to filter each usb packet we
probably need 2.6
microseconds
well based on our experience 20 base
rules is fairly good enough to cover
most
common usb devices for example within
these 20 rules we covered
keyboards mouse web cameras wi-fi
adapters flash drives and etc
we then run file bench by operating 20
files with main file size ranging from 1
kilobyte to 100
megabytes
so
as one can see
the throughput of usb
is comparable with the throughput of the
stock kernel
this table shows the corresponding
latency
during the file bench uh benchmarking
and when the main file size is less than
one megabytes
the latency of usb filter is almost
negligible comparing to the stock kernel
but when the file size increase we can
see some latency as well this is
reasonable since usb filter needs to
look into each usb packet and try to
match with one of the 20 rules saved in
the kernel
and then we give a
five times rung for real world
workload including creating and
installing a key vm from a usb
flash drive
running web browser benchmark for chrome
using a usb wi-fi adapter and scanning
virus
within a usb flash drive using clam av
and then we
double get a linux kernel
4.4 zip file
as one can see
basically the performance of usb filter
is comparable with the stock kernel
the ability to correlate the usb packet
with the io operations
of applications within the use space is
vital but sometimes we just cannot have
that information so one example is the
interrupt concept
so for example when a key is pressed on
a keyboard
this corresponding usb packet does does
not have any application to to be
associate associated with since uh the
key stroke happens within the interrupt
concept that means for the keystroke we
probably cannot use process information
to write a rule
and similarly we have instrumented
a bunch of general usb device drivers to
recover the pid information but some for
some usb devices which requires
vendor specific drivers we need to look
into each driver to cover that pid
information if we want to leverage the
pid within the rules
the current implementation of
usb filter is to put itself in the
request pass
during the filtering which is the pass
which is the usb communication pass from
the usb host machine to the device
machine
this works for usb 1.0 and usb 2.0
because basically usb is a master slave
protocol but for usb 3.0 it is possible
for usb devices to initiate the usb
request so we probably need to consider
putting usb filter in the response pass
as well
the general overhead of usb filter to
filter each usb packet is 2.6
microsecond
it is fast for usb 2.0 but it may not be
fast enough for usb 3.0 so in the future
we are thinking about leveraging a
berkeley pack filter to accelerate
the speed of
usb filter for package filtering
and for sure we need more useful lumps
to enable system in to write more
powerful rules
regarding the usability issues
usb filter is targeting administrators
or assistant means
because it is not that easy to write
useful usb filter rules since it
requires some knowledge about usb in
general but we're hoping um the linux
distribution team may be able to provide
some default default rules such as the
linux rules and which can help users to
customize these rules based on their own
working environments
so in this talk we have seen
why usb was great
why it is not great and then we design
and implemented
usb filter which is essentially a usb
layer firewall within the kernel we
provide the corresponding user space
tool which is called usb tables
it has a prolog engine and it is used to
manage all the tools from the user space
so with usb filter we're able to defend
against any bad usb attacks we're able
to limit the behaviors of
usb device by only introducing a minimum
overhead
so please
go to this website download it and have
a try
and hopefully with usb filter we can
make usb great again thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thanks dave
we're still running ahead so please step
up to the mic and ask
interesting or difficult questions
to dave
otherwise i'll have to ask shallow
questions for for 10 minutes
hi cynthia irvin
um
when you were looking at your rules and
uh doing your verification
uh did you look at any formal safety
properties that you were trying to
enforce
um since we're not focusing on the
implementation side we just look for the
rule consistency checking so we just
want to make sure each rule
if you allow me to come back to the real
thing
right so we just want to make sure each
rule does not have any conflict with
existing rules before it is added into
the kernel
okay
so um
then essentially
your rule set could potentially
leak
correct
i'm sorry i don't get well
you you have a situation where you
you're showing that your rules are
self-consistent but not with respect to
some security property that you're um
attempting to enforce
correct all right
uh okay i one one thing i wondered about
is in your rules you need to
actually name the um you have to provide
a lot of information in your right right
for usb tables so if you've never used a
device before and it could be dangerous
how are you going to come up with that
some of that information
well um basically
so let's come back to the rules
yeah
so i think the usb charger rule is an
example here if we're not able to
leverage any information or we do not
know any information about this device
all we can do is to leverage the
physical information about the port like
where the device is plugged into
and then we can write some rules like
for any phone so as long as the device
is plugged into this port
we would do something so basically by
leveraging the physical information of
the usb port we physically partition all
the usb ports and do some
traffic through there and so the then
there i assume there's some form of
logging i guess actually you would be
able to see
um
look at your k messages and see what the
device looked like and right
from there okay we can't do that as well
okay thank you thank you
nice talk thank you
uh one question
so in your usability you mentioned the
usability point uh and targeting system
administrators right uh i was wondering
uh whether you had any experience doing
any study about
uh
mapping the physical usb ports to the
actual logical bus and uh port numbers
so what i'm trying to say here is for
example my laptop has six usb ports and
three
eaci controllers and depending on where
i plug my device it has a unique bus and
port number
so i'm wondering if you write a rule
which you specify a bus and port number
uh
is the user going to have to plug that
you know particular device on that
physical port always how's that
have we done some you know study on
making sure that the administrator knows
exactly to plug the device there and not
anywhere else well this is a great
question um because like there's no ex
explicit mapping between the physical
port number and the the virtual or the
logical port number right so we need to
plug in the device to know like okay
this physical port has the port number x
so there is an enumeration sort of
phrase that you right we need to know
that information okay so how does that
do you basically plug in devices on
every physical port and you sort of
educate the right data because basically
this is one time effort right you can
use one trusted device to try all the
ports then you have all the information
then you know how these physical ports
are mapped into the logic port number
then you can write wouldn't it be
wonderful if usb controllers had a
method by which you could actually
program it to say glow a particular
number on each of the ports so that it
enables people to that is fantastic but
but yeah well that's the ideal world
let's hope for it thanks man that's a
great idea
if there are no more questions we're
almost caught up but i have a single one
i know the linux kernel is run by
project people with strong opinions but
right what you think would happen if you
were to offer this to them uh for up
streaming
well um actually if we want to upstream
this thing uh it has at least well we
have at least to do two things so first
um
as you can see from this architecture
figure
we introduced a new now link socket
and most kernel developer would object
this idea because just like when
everyone wants to introduce a new cisco
people would say no
so we need to find a way to leverage the
existing modeling socket to do the
communication and another thing is
i mentioned within
the future works
the current performance is maybe not
good for usb 3.0 and we need to
leverage the bpf to accelerate the
performance
similar case happens within the kernel
development
for example the scam secure com secure
computing which is a cisco filter uh it
has been proposed like
uh 10 or 20 years ago but no one cares
until recently a google developer has
refactored the whole implementation
using bpf and now it is in the kernel
and is a great component for the linux
links container
thank you thank you
so one more question i'm back again just
a quick question
you had mentioned that uh
you know verifiability as one of your
sort of goals
uh i was wondering is your
implementation in in c i'm assuming yes
uh you had mentioned you were you had
touched four new files and touched 23
odd inner kernels i was just wondering
do you have any metrics on the actual
number of source lines that you have in
your implementation and how you've
how do you think it's sort of conducive
towards uh you know actual you know
source code level of verification to
establish your properties
uh
like a normal developer we do not
provide useful documentation for the
changes
sorry about that man
uh but but i'm i'm assuming i have
access to your github right right you
can look into the current appreciate
let's give dave a big round of applause
for the talk and also for the