thank you for introducing me so i'm
mariano graziano i'm a security
researcher for cisco and today this talk
is about a framework to detect and
prevent any kind of spraying attacks
this is a joint walk between university
of milano between cisco and eurocoming
funds
so let's start with uh the definition of
spraying what is spraying so spraying is
a generic common payload delivery
technique that has been specifically
designed
with the goal to bypass the address
space layout randomization
that is an operating system protection
to randomize the base address of the
code and libraries
so over the years security researcher
has shown how to spray the heap how to
spray the kernel pools or how to spray
the just in time compiler pages
and
over the years
basically
we know how to spray these memory
regions but we can also categorize
spraying depending on how that on how
the attacker is playing okay so for
historical reason the first method is
uh
the so-called traditional code based
brain okay in this case
uh the scenario is that the operating
system has the aslr so the other
specialized randomization that is
enabled
but the data execution prevention
is either disabled or not supported okay
nowadays it is not so common but first
for historical reason i have to mention
also this approach so in this case
anyway when as aslr is in place the
attacker needs to
guess or anyway know the
address of its payload okay
so in order to increase the probability
of success of the attack one of the
possible ways is to fill
the
the memory of the target application
with hundreds of thousands of copies
of
of the payload that in this case is
either the shell code okay
so then another another possible case is
the so-called jit strain
in this case um the idea is that the
attacker wants to bypass both slr and
that execution prevention
in this way um
in this case the attacker basically is
using um
the executable pages that are as that
are dynamic that are generated on the
fly by the just-in-time compiler
then for the case of data spraying and
and then for um the stack pivoting the
main idea in this case is that again
okay the attacker wants to bypass both
slr and that
but in this case uh it fills their
memory with data but in this case data
is in the form of blockchain so we have
hundreds of thousands of copy of the
same opt chain
then
the
one of the first
gadgets of this rock chain perform the
so-called pivoting so this means that
the stack pointer is changing two points
to desperate data okay
so
in the last decade the spraying of
phenomena has been studied a lot by
different researchers and from different
different perspectives
now i'm going to talk a little bit about
the relative work for the defensive
solutions we have
a couple of good papers about possible
defensive solution for the hip strength
for instance we have neutral we have a
bubble
it has a different approach but
all these approaches uh
basically they are all all application
specific so they just work for instance
for one specific browser or sometimes
they only work for a specific javascript
engine
then we have also a couple of good
interesting papers about the jit spring
like
gtech or gt fender lobotomy and we have
also here some um
browser developers that
like another talk yesterday at usinix
they show that we have
like the code blinding or the nope
insertions
in the browser
and anyway all all these approaches have
been bypassed by motivated attacker or
again they are really application
specific like they work only for indian
explorer
or even if they are more comprehensive
they just solve one instance of the
strain problem like in this case the jet
stream
then we have the problem with that we
have some defensive solutions for data
strain
with some companies that propose like
microsoft that propose emmet and it is a
more generic
solution in order to harden applications
and among the other things i've really a
really interesting feature that is the
anti-pivoting
then we have again some
solution proposed some by some browser
developers
like the isolated deep or delayed free
that anyway they hindered about the
exploitation in which the strain is one
of the is one of the steps but again
these
solutions are either application
specific they work only for a browser
or
they solve only a single instance of
destroying problem
so at this point should be quite clear
that
we need a kind of solution that is able
to cope with all the possible spraying
implementations
so we what we would like is to have a
compressing scalable solution that can
defeat any form of springs and ideally
should be also operating system agnostic
so it can work transparently both with
linux and for instance windows
so at the first site if we want to
design such a system i mean such as
spraying a defensive mechanism
the design at the at the first site it
seems really simple
because if we think about the strain
definition okay the first
characteristics come up in our mind
is that when an attacker performs spring
it basically is allocating a large
amount of memory in a small in a small
amount of time so uh
mistakenly one can think that we can
perform a really uh
basic waste exclusive such as stocks and
if we look at these graphs basically we
have in green in green and in red
the behavior
of some normal browser activities like
we have a user that
is browsing like google google maps
youtube and another user that has a
other tabs open and there is a
browsing like for on
news website
and here we have the the memory uh the
memory behavior then we have engraved
the attacks or the destroying attacks
from with a default um exploit taken
from the default configuration from
metasploit and we can clearly see that i
mean the behavior is completely
different and we have a large amount of
memory allocated in a small amount of
time
so
we have to keep in mind that we cannot
design also such a system with such
simple logistics because
the tattoo control the two important
parameters the attacker
can control the size of the allocated
memory and the attacker can control the
speed so the time of the allocation
so a motivated attacker can
can can mimic basically the behavior
of a banana of a banana of a benign
application and these are what we see
here
basically uh we can mimic the
the normal uh the normal browsing
activities
so
we need a way to create a more complex
system okay
so we
we try to list some important goals to
define such an important system so
the first
the first goal should be to have an
independent is to to have a system that
is a completely independent from the
memory allocator
so in this way we can plug our system to
any kind of application from ranging
from a browser to a pdf viewer
then
we need
we need a system that is operating
system agnosis so can work again
transparently on windows and macro
effects then
we want a system that it's modular
because we want to plug
many plugins uh that implements summary
sticks to detect to detect the different
instances of a spring
and last but not least we want a system
that has a
low overhead because we want to deploy
it on a real system machine or at least
the overlap to be reasonable compared to
other hypervisor solutions
so this is the architecture of the
system that we design
so let's imagine that someone is
visiting a website that can be either
malicious or benign but anyway the
important part is that at the given
point there will be some kind of a
location okay
so this allocation is generally for an
api then it's translating a system call
and then it's going down to the kernel
up to the page tables at this point
our system this is uh that is a
hypervisor based is able to intercept
this memory request
and this memory request is forward to
the first component of our system that
is called the memory tracer
then when a given memory threshold
um
is reached
the the memory tracer component
basically activates the second component
that is the attack detector that is the
component in charge of detecting
possible spraying attempts
now i will talk in detail about each
component so i will talk first about the
memory tracer and then about the attack
detector
so in order to understand the semantic
of the memory operations in the guest
operating system
our our framework
needs to monitor all the memory
operations that happens on
the paging structures of the monitored
application
this is a possible thanks to the
feature provided by the intel algorithm
that is called the extended page table
in short
ept so in order to understand then the
natural of these operations this kind of
operation are like the creation the
modification of the elimination of a
memory page
in order to understand the
the nature of this operation we
need because we want to know if these
memory operations is attaching directly
the paging structure or is creating
like a normal new memory
page like we can see in this picture our
framework basically is checking
the page directory the page the page
directory entries and the page table
entries
in particular we check the bit
permissions in order to understand if
the page has been created modified or
eliminated
and
in order to understand if the memory
operation is happening
on the page in structure itself we
monitor the page directory
if the operation instead is just
creating a page in a normal memory page
we check the page tables entries
then as i said before if
our system basically monitor all the
paging structure but if we do that for
the system-wide for the entire operating
system or we do it
for multiple applications at the same
time during our experiments we
we this a huge overhead okay
and this is and this already is somehow
problematic because one of our goals is
to have
a lower or at least a reasonable
overhead okay
so we try to investigate these this
issue
and what we notice is that even if we
are monitoring a single a single process
what uh what we expect is that we only
notice the memory violation
on the paging structure only for that
particular process
but actually we notice that the kernel
at the same time is modifying
the paging structures of also of other
processes
so what we want
so first of all this is something that
we noticed though the first thing to do
is to try to measure this problem that
we call the interference problem so the
first experiment that we do
that we did was to measure the ever the
overhead for a single process in this
case we choose the internet explorer 10
and the overall in this case was 22 okay
then we try to measure the again the
overhead for the same application but at
the same time we were monitoring um
either two additional
applications like acrobat reader or and
firefox
and in this case the
the overhead for the application is
jumping from 22 to 63 okay so basically
we are increasing a lot it's increasing
a lot then
the overall ending is something that we
we need to solve
so
we
we've been streaming a lot and we come
up with
a possible solution that is we that we
call the micro virtualization
it is the main contribution of this
research
so the idea the main idea of micro
visualization
is to create a memory sandbox
for
every monitored application
so um
more in detail the micro virtualization
is based on the intel hardware assisted
virtualization uh features the vtx and
in particular it heavily relies on the
extended page tables feature
so at the process creation our system
basically selects a set of physical
pages that are related to the paging
structures
and we monitor only these particular
pages when the process is actually
running
how this is possible this is possible
thanks to the so-called extended page
table pointer
so at every process which basically
we we change
the these this pointer to points to the
set of physical pages that we want uh to
monitor
so this means that we create
an ept pointer for every application
that we want to monitor
so now we will talk about the second
component that is called the attack
detector
this component is activated only when we
reach a certain activation
threshold
and it's important also to notice that i
mean this detector is implemented
with many plugins okay
on top of the memory tracing system so
anyone then can plug its own plugins and
implement its own heuristics
so the first
the first uh plugin that we implemented
is called the malicious code detector
again here is the scenario is that the
operating system has aslr that is
enabled
but
dep is um
is not activated
so the idea here is that we randomly
scan
the allocated pages so far for that
particular application
you know and we look for um evidences of
shell codes there are several approaches
in the literature like a paper from
access 2010 or using security papers
from 2011 the important part is that we
can port these heuristics to our own
plugin on top of our memory tracing
system
then another plugin that we implemented
is called the self-impacting shell code
detector so basically here we want to
detect
any possible um
unpacking behavior so this means
the common unpacking behavior is that
when you write a page and then you
execute it so basically we we are
we search uh on the memory pages this
particular behavior of write and then
execute and we implement these logistics
that is again the is not an already it's
taken from a paper from access 2007.
then for the data for we have the
another plugin that is another use case
for our framework it implements a data
screen detector
again
in this case
what we want to do is we scan
the memory pages allocated so far for
that particular application
and we
we
we implemented
an heuristic that checks the frequency
of the code pointers
and
but again we can put also other previous
approaches as a form of plugin in order
to detect data strain
so now let's talk about the experiments
that we did the first experiment
either that we did perform is to measure
the overhead of the first component that
is the memory tracer that is the only
component that is always active
so what we did is that we use this quest
width that is a benchmark suite
that
basically stress their location in the
location
and in particular this application will
some create a program that
simulates a lot of allocation allocation
and we did it for windows 7 and linux
3.2
and we found with an allocation the
location speed over on average eight
megabytes every two seconds we measured
the overhead and we had for windows 7 24
and for linux 25
only for the memory tracer but this is
this is the worst case because we are
using a stressing suite
then another experiment that we did
is
to measure the overhead
uh for our system
uh by changing the activation threshold
that is that threshold that is in charge
of activating the second component that
is performing basically the the checks
for the possible spraying attempts
so we start with a really conservative
threshold over 100 megabytes and we went
up to
a threshold of 400 megabytes as expected
i mean the the lower is the activation
threshold the higher it's the
is the overhead because we have more
uh switches between the memory tracer
of course and the attack detector
then we did a couple of experiments to
measure the effectiveness of our system
so in this case we took
six different at six different
attacks six different real exploits
that we carefully choose
to be a representative for the possible
strain implementation
so and in fact we rank from some
plain shell code spraying to the data
spraying with of course with rob
and then we also choose different uh
applications like browsers like internet
explorers of firefox to pdf reader and
to up to flash player in all the cases
our system was able to detect and
prevent the spraying behavior
then another
experiment that we perform is to assess
the accuracy of our system
so in this case we took uh one uh 1000
of benign pdf and then 1 000 of
malicious pdf
we configure our system with really
conservative threshold of 150 megabytes
and we
and for the case of the pda over the
pdfs we we were monitoring only the pdf
viewer
in this case our framework graffiti was
able to
detect with any false positive and then
false negative all the attacks
and then we did the same the same
experiment with by monitoring a browser
with the same conservative threshold and
we visited the top 1000 alexa website
and here was we were expecting is of
course to not find any any possible
attacks and this is what happened so we
didn't have again any false positive or
any photo negative
then at the final experiment given the
fact that we want to deploy a real
system on a real user machines we
install our system on two different
machines
and we ask to two users to use our
system for one week for the daily
activities so they they were using on
average for eight to ten hours per day
our system
we
specifically we configured
our system to monitor uh the browser
that these users were using that there
was internet explorer 8 on their
operating system that was windows 7
and we set and we set up a really a
conservative threshold of 150 megabytes
and also in this case we for the attack
detector we activated all the three
plugins that i explained before
then after one week we check out we
check the results so the users visited
more than
different websites
the attack detector has been activated
more than fifty times with an average of
eight times per day
interestingly we know this i mean
surprisingly we noticed that we had 12
hollers on pages that at the end were
benign so these are real i mean false
positives
and we investigated this issue and we
discovered that it was related to the
data spraying detector plugin
and then we performed again experiments
by improving this plugin
uh
the plugin was only checking the
the code of the the frequency of the
code pointers we are we perform an
additional check if these code pointers
uh basically uh contains a rope gadget
and in this way we filter out
these
these false positives so the important
part here is to understand that
the plugins can be improved a lot
as a conclusion
uh here i present uh graffiti that is
that is a
framework that is a should be the first
efficient and comprehensive solution to
defeat any kind of possible spring
implementation
we i described
the main idea of the micro
virtualization
so in order to create this kind of
memory sandbox for a specific
application and then most importantly we
are releasing our tools as open source
and you can download it from this
website uh feel free to try it through i
mean send us your pull requests or i
mean create your own plugins on top of
our memory tracer and if you do it
please let's keep
let's stay in touch
so that's all for me
thanks for your attention and i'm open
to any questions
[Applause]
no takers
i have one for you um it seems to me
that you're equating a process in an
application in in your framework
but some of the browsers i might have
misunderstood this but browsers like
chrome they have this multi-process
architecture
which seems to me that might look like
multiple applications to you and if so
could an adversary try to
distribute his spring attempt over
multiple taps which would have their own
processes and and thereby go undetected
yeah i mean for yeah for chrome
expression should be i mean a little bit
more different also with like also more
modern browsers because now every tab is
a single process so probably you should
have to configure
the system for these different process
so this means that you
with micro virtualization you are
protecting all let's say all the
different tabs
but then the track again is on the
single tab
and then i mean there is a the same box
so now all the modern browsers have a
sandbox remember sandbox so then you
have to escape from the sandbox and then
you have another attack so now even more
chaining more attacks together in order
to escape and then run code inside the
operating system
i understand but let's say that for a
given given amount of data you have
x percent a success rate if i then spray
a tenth of that in 10 10 taps i might go
below your threshold but viewed across
the tab the same likelihood of
succeeding with my exploit
but every tab is a different process
right yes but only one of them has to
successfully exploit
the process yeah but okay yeah of course
but i can tune i mean you can tune the
the interesting part of our system that
you can tune the
threshold right so basically if
if you put a lower
if you're a little really paranoid and
you mean and
in the world there are this kind of
attacks what you can do is to lower the
threshold so in this way i mean you have
a little bit uh
more higher overhead of course but you
are protected
right right
um just kind of a follow-up on that if
uh the
overhead that required using separate
eptp pointers for every process
had to do with
the shared pages between processes
wouldn't a browser that's opening
or
the turning of every tab in a separate
process
reintroduced that overhead even with um
having a separate ebtp for every tab
no i mean what we notice is that if we
were using only one apt we added these
huge overheads so we try to debug
investigate a lot this issue
and is probably related to the shared
pages
but
most interesting probably something
related to some optimization on the
memory subsystem inside the kernel
okay
so
and then what we noticed is that if we
were creating
more
say
more apt for the different process that
we are
monitoring we were filtering out
the huge part of this overhead that
software was related to some shared
pages between the user application and
the kernel
but it's something that i mean for the
future work we are still investigating
because
uh you know
it's it's something that for us was just
a shared page
okay but then you were asking about uh
um
[Music]
your question was in two points right
one about the overhead uh of the
interference problem and the other part
can you rephrase please is uh
if
so
there's still going to be
uh
it seems like the colonel would still
have to do a lot of extra work that
would get caught
on a
forked or copied
process from the
from the brow from the original browser
process
and it seems like that
work would be the same as the overhead
that you would see
[Music]
using just the single
eptp because it's the same uh
page table rec page table entries that
have to get
uh amended
because they were copy on right and now
they're
uh being changed for the new process
yeah that's one of the points something
that we were investigating for the
future work well what we're trying to do
is just to do an apt only for the kernel
and monitor what's only happening for
the candle because what we don't have
clear at this point is i mean why
sometimes the world is getting so high
okay
it's something that we are i mean
actively investigating
and if you probably will check out the
github
hopefully we are gonna commit something
soon
okay
i have another question um
so the vm func instruction um
that allows a
guest to request a specific eptp
i believe that uh
runs
in ring three so it's an unprivileged uh
command did you do any tests to see if
you had a piece of shell code that just
kind of sprayed
uh vm funk
um would it crash the
just i mean that's an interesting point
no we didn't do it but it is something
that it could be really interesting to
do
which what
part of the system crashes when you do
that
yeah well
most probably yeah
thanks for your point it's something
that we're gonna do
all right let's close the session by
thanking all the speakers one last time
[Applause]
you