i present the paper enabling proofs of
data replication
and retrievability in the cloud
it's joint work with frederick
armcknecht from the university mannheim
and
ludovic barman who was a student at in
our labs
and
my colleague at nhlebska sankarami so
it's in a
framework of
a joint project which aims to build
a secure
storage cloud and
now the scenario you
all know
of cloud storage so users have data
users upload them to the cloud and are
then at any time
have the possibility to retrieve the
data by sending a request getting the
data back
and
we look at such kind of
block or file based storage as dropbox
google drive onedrive are offering
a main concern of the users which
prevents them from adopting the cloud
and also corporate users i will say a
bit more later is a data loss so in this
list of
the cloud
security alliance
data loss is up at number two so data
breaches
uh
another concern we are not
looking at data breaches here so we
assume data can be encrypted and there's
no functionality or sharing needed
but then data loss directly comes at
number two and it is joined
with malicious insider
and
yeah
one
solution which is very known in the
cryptographic literature and security
literature is
a proof of return ability
originally or sometimes also called
proof of data possession
in a proof of retrievability
um
a user will send a challenge to the
service provider kind of asking is my
data still there and then get back a
response which
gives him a proof
that the data is still there so i mean
trivially it could be
the
that
the user downloads this data and checks
if it's there but
of course the the protocols try to do
this very efficient so how do they
generally work the user pre-processes
the data before uploading
it he applies some erasure coding
so that he doesn't need to be concerned
about every byte of the data
and then we'll add some texts which are
kind of homomorphic
message authentication codes or
homomorphic signatures of some blocks
and then stores all of those data at the
service provider
and then
he can issue a challenge asking for
certain blocks
if they are still there the service
provider will sum up those blocks and
the according text
then because it's homomorphic
the service provider can aggregate all
of it send it back and the user can
check that this is indeed a response
to his challenge and it is a valid
response based on his data
yeah i mentioned already you can do this
based on homomorphic max which is kind
of
a x
a times x plus b
those are rather
quite efficient you can also do it based
on homomorphic signatures those
protocols are a bit more expensive but
they have the advantage that you can get
a public auditor
auditing of
of a cloud storage provider so then
everyone would be able
to verify the proof
um
okay what
should it guarantee of course
such a protocol needs to be correct
meaning if the cloud is doing everything
correct the user will accept and
we have
the other requirement of soundness
or extractability how it is then called
for this specific case
which means that if the verifier accepts
so if the user from this short protocol
gets
ok my data is still there then indeed
the data should be extractable and it's
usually shown that
an algorithm which can create the valid
responses
can be transformed into an extractor
which can extract the file from the
service provider
the adversary model we use is that
the user is honest
well it's the user's data we are
concerned of and he will not corrupt his
own data
and
the service provider may be malicious so
we do not use a fully malicious model
here but adopt the
rational adversary model where the
adversary's goal is
to save cost i mean no one would do
business with a fully malicious service
or a service he doesn't
trust but on the other hand we know all
of those services are
private
for profit entities so they try to offer
this service of course as cheap as
possible and
we have learned
that
you cannot prove that security measures
are really needed so they might skip
some of them and put the danger
the data at risk
which would not be what the user wants
but
yeah there we come also already to the
to one of the
problems
namely
uh the drawback of a poor is well if the
user gets the notification now the data
is not available anymore
he cannot do much more than panic so
it's too late the data is already lost
what the user actually wants to know is
that
necessary security measures
are in place and how to use a gear
against data loss you you simply have to
have a backup somewhere so the user
could have kind of
two
providers he uses
and checks with the proof of
retrievality with each and if one is
lost he recovers it from the other
provider
and
uploads it again to to one provider but
then of course the user will do a lot of
data management which is not what we
want
but well the providers are doing exactly
the same
if if they offer a high
storage
with a high durability they replicate
the data by themselves
and
um
yeah
indeed this is then what the user would
like to know is my data really
replicated
we also hear this a lot when we talk to
corporate customers
who
want to adopt storage so
what they are concerned of is
that from from this third-party service
they would like to know that they apply
all the security measures which need to
be in place
and
this is certainly an obstacle because
with the in-house data center they can
easily check
but with the third party this gets more
difficult
um and
yeah so this
initial question if my data is still
there
rather transform then in the into the
question is my data
really sufficiently replicated
as my contract with the with the service
provider
is saying
and yeah now
we
learned a bit already how this proof of
retrievability works the question is how
can we apply it to multiple replicas
uh in a
standard way like if the replica are
just exact copies of the original file
this is the difficult or not possible
because or it doesn't prove the
existence so if i vary now
the multiple replicas
because they are all the same the
service provider can answer them all
just by having the original file
so this approach
will not work
another approach
already known
for a while by called mulleidale is the
multi-replica pdp
and
there the idea is that the replicas are
encrypted
copies of the file which the service
provider cannot replicate by himself but
the user has to
first
create the copies and group them in a
different way and then upload all of
them and
because then for the service provider
these are simply different files
you can run a proof of retrievability
over every file and then of course check
that the file and the replicas are still
available
we see some
disadvantages with this
method first
we again put the user into the data
management into the one who is creating
the replicas
this is a bit an unrealistic assumption
and
it also puts cost on the user for
uploading this data
several times
but as well to the provider
for
whom also there's quite some cost
associated to to having enough bandwidth
now to have maybe the four five times
times the the incoming
data volume
so we used
some of those numbers really to evaluate
so
from
cloudfare
there are some data published what
it costs for big providers to have
incoming bandwidth
and yeah
based on this
we really can see there is cost
associated to the to the upload
another drawback certainly comes
because it is
restricting the business of the cloud
provider
and
if you look for example at amazon s3
pricing so amazon offers the standard
storage
which which has very high
durability it's very
highly replicated and has the reduced
redundancy storage which is
which might be even not replicated and
therefore offers just 99.99
guaranteed that the data is
is not lost
and if you
compare the prices you see it's not so
much more expensive to use standard
storage which clearly shows that
for replicas
the amount charged to the user is
much less
than for the original file so kind of
the profit margin only goes to the
original file while the replicas
are given much cheaper at
the cost of of the actual storage
by the provider and will clearly
customers wouldn't pay twice or three
times the price if they want to have
replicated so this business model makes
sense
but of course this only works if the
provider knows those are replicas like
in the mr pdp
it could easily be that
the user claims it's a replicas because
it's differently encrypted files but it
actually is not
so
what we did is we come up
with a generic model for such an
mr poor we call it a poor tool proof of
redundancy and
proof of replication and retrievability
which extends the standard proof of
retrievability
so we have as in the standard
retrievability the the
protocols to store data and the protocol
to challenge and verify the challenge
which we
put together in a verify as one protocol
but the two new protocols we look at is
first replicate
so this will come later when i explain
our protocol so replicate should
enable
the provider to replicate the data by
himself
or we have check replica which would
extend the mr pdp
by enabling the provider to verify
that the uploaded data are indeed
replicas
the security definitions again as it's a
proof of retrievability we have want
data extractability so we want to know
the data is still there
and the second
notion we created and defined
is storage allocation which guarantees
that the provider really needs
as much space
as would be needed for the
file and all the replicas
and
well as it is a
rational adversary then
it
only makes sense for him to store the
replicas because the storage space is
consumed in any case
correct replication again for the
mrpdp-like protocols
the definitions in detail you find in
the paper
so then
i come to the
towards the protocol we designed and
which is called mirror
so which asks the question what what
needs to be done so the that the service
provider could replicate the data
by himself and
of course that's kind of a dilemma
because
we have seen
we have this challenge response and the
verify and there we would like to
find the cheating service provider who
was not replicating but is now
replicating on the fly
so this
responding should be rather costly if
you have not replicated before which
means the replication process
needs to be associated with some cost
time wise or
computation wise
on the other hand for the store
replicate we of course want to have the
costs
rather low so if we upload something the
service provider needs to replicate
everything but of course this should not
take forever
so
this needs to be there needs to be a
fine balance found between the cost high
enough so that we can catch
him during the challenge response but
low enough so that
replication is possible
and
the
kind of primitive we use are
cryptographic puzzles
so those are
functions which consume a certain time
to to solve and
kind of two
famous ones are out there one is
given a value find a brie image
according to a hash function
well this is very difficult to
apply here on the one hand it's of
course elegant because you could have
the data and the brie image of the data
would be the replica and you can easily
from the replica create it back by by
hashing while it takes a while to
replicate it to find the pre-images but
to find pre-images you would need to
reduce the block size to a very small
very small
very few bits and
also you don't have homomorphic
properties so in the proof of
retrievability it is it will not going
to be
efficient so we followed this second
approach there are those rsa based
puzzles
now they are not related to the data
directly but
we can combine them in a homomorphic way
so that we keep all those properties
and
this matrix gives an overview how we
combine it so we multiply it from the
puzzle we extract some blinding factor
which basically is the solution of the
puzzle and multiply it
to the data
to generate one replica so d11 to dn
s
is the file split into blocks and the
blocks split into sectors
and one sector is kind of like then the
size of the rsa modulus
and
yep now it's turned out to be quite
difficult to come up with the right
parameters so the basic rsa puzzle
is saying
you compute g to the x for for very
large x so x is a 2 to the l
modulo n
and
how you do this if you cannot factor n
is that you do a
successive squaring modulu n so you
really have to
compute it with this
huge exponent
but if you know the factors of n you of
course have a shortcut because you can
apply
module of phi of n in the exponent and
then just have a standard exponentiation
with a
kind of 2000 bit exponent while x could
be much larger
however it's difficult to apply it
straightforward because
the exponents need to be very small like
if you have 2000 bit exponents
replication of
a 100 megabyte file is already taking
several hours
so exponents have to be extremely small
but then of course you do not really
have
a good trapdoor because then
modulo 5n so if it's smaller than 5n
there is no
advantage for the user so we looked for
another way and how we could involve
several of those puzzle solutions
to
obtain
one blinding factor
and
well if you
use kind of multiply several of those
puzzle solutions together you kind of
end up
with a structure very similar to a
linear shift register
just
transformed into the
multiplication domain
so
we have
kind of the puzzle solutions with the
exponents s1 s2 s3 2s8
for the example of a
register of length 8
the register is given by the
coefficients
c1 to c8
and now what you do is you take the
first cell
raise it to the power c1 then multiply
to the second cell raised to the power
c2 and so on and
multiply everything up and get the next
blinding factor g to the
s9 um
so this is um
kind of yeah
ls lfsr which is transformed in the
multiplica multiplicative domain
and you can have the
according shift registers for the
exponents and that's really a standard
shift register with multiplying the
coefficients and adding up
so this is much faster to compute the
exponents but you could give out the
public one
which is expensive to compute for the
blinding factors
and it is not possible to transform the
public one into the secret one so
now
besides that you have to multiply the
public one and
only do additions in the
secret one
we could apply another
kind of another trapdoor
if we choose
a shift
polynomial which is
not primitive
so means that
yeah it has some redundancy and
also the
sequence of blinding factors of course
will not
have the the
full cycle length it could have but a
shorter one so it produces kind of a
sequence which could be already produced
by a much shorter polynomial
so exactly this we apply here we use in
the public
lsfr a multiple of the feedback
polynomial of the secret one
so the lsfr gets much longer
but it again cannot be transformed back
because it's not possible to factorize
this polynomial
as we are in an as a group and cannot
compute inverses there
so
then
and
yeah in fact the parameters you choose
the secret one just needs to be length
two
and the public one
can be up to length 15 or longer so we
get quite a good difference in
the effort it takes
to compute
the blinding factors if you know
the factorization and if you compute the
blinding factors if you don't know
now this is exactly what we do here and
we we do we use two pairs of
shift registers one forward
starting so computing the blinding
factors from the first to the last and
one backward computing them from the
last to the first
which
guarantees that for every so if you try
just to to get one block
somewhere in the middle you you have to
compute all of them
all of the blinding factors before and
the one chain and all of them which
follow afterwards in the second chain so
you kind of have to compute always the
same amount
of
blinding factors no matter which
position you look at
yes the parameter choices i i mentioned
so the rsr modulus 2000 bit
the poor usually takes 40 challenges so
that's not dependent on the file size
because we apply the erasure code
before so that's
there's the variability
and then
just use
a two length two lfsr
for the private and the 50 length 15 for
the public and the exponent and the
private one is around 70 bit
70 bit
there it shows that the cost
for computing for answering this
challenge
for the
service provider is
exactly the price which it would cost to
store and file of the according size
on amazon s3 so there we have the same
cost for answering the challenge if you
don't have replicated
as it would be to store simply store the
replica
so if you frequently challenge
the length of 70 would be well suitable
besides that it's then the same cost of
course
there is the timing
so usually on the right side you see it
takes around two seconds for the server
to answer a replica but if
the
if the server has not stored the replica
it takes him at least three seconds and
this can be very well noticed
creating a replica is kind of
reasonable so
times
go into the few hundred
seconds
and
then i conclude so we we introduced this
proof of replication which we have
ability as a new notion extending the
standard poor and i think bringing it a
bit more towards
realistic
settings
we have developed this solution mirror
and we have there a new puzzle a new
asymmetric
tool
built on lsfr so this we we haven't seen
before that you construct such a public
lfsr
which which you which has
redundancy because the the polynomial is
not primitive but you cannot transform
it back to the to the short polynomial
which we also think has could have many
more applications
and yeah this all
is the building block for for the vision
of having this transparent cloud
services which
you can verify and check as if you would
have your id in-house
okay thanks
[Applause]
great and if you have a question please
come up to the mic and state your name
and affiliation
hi uh greg savarucho microsoft
so the gap between um
uh you know
the honest cloud server and the cheating
one is is one second
um
like in your parameters it was two
seconds to do it honestly
can you talk about the trade-offs if you
wanted to make that
larger
um well the thing is if you want to make
it larger now for for cheating this
protocol just
there's a challenge which just varies
limited blocks
and so the cloud
provider only needs to compute those
limited blocks
now if you make those few blocks more
expensive
there's the risk that at the same time
you also increase the the replication
cost
so it's kind of
um
i think you you find more analysis in
the paper so
this is also one idea which we have in
in where is the matrix here
so for replication you need to compute
all the blinding factors
so what what you ideally want is that
even if you just want to give back one
block as an answer you should need to
compute all the blinding factors because
then
so if you increase the number of
blinding factors you need to answer one
block
this does not cost you more for
replication but this increases the cost
for for answering the challenge that one
block so on this
you could play
but yeah kind of the parameters i
have shown is
also the optimal spot we have found okay
thanks
i actually have one question about
systematizing this work um turning it
into an actual system so very few cloud
providers
storage providers also compute right
many may have a compute node but there's
associated costs with those things and
one of the dominant causes are actually
doing gets
so
would it actually is this economically
viable or does it make more sense to
just like compute a mac or the data and
do one get
so
i i think i mean there needs to be some
computation simply to manage all this
storage so
you don't need a full-blown ec2 for for
sure but yeah
my guess or my hope is that there will
be more storage also available more
computation in the storage clouds
available also because there's simply
more transparency
requested by the users
i'm unaware of any cloud provider that
would adopt a pdp or por scheme because
it somehow admits that they're being
dishonest right i think they would much
rather just say like yeah we'll provide
nine nines and we'll call it a day
yes
you have to see maybe not in this pure
form i would expect some maybe hybrid
things
some third-parties kind of poor ideas
but some secure hardware
guarantees so
some some nice combination of it i would
in the end expect
great razer please
reza kotm
i don't have a question just the comment
um so i'm one of the uh
authors of that paper mr pdp that you
cite yes published in 2008
i just wanted to let you know that we
actually had a follow-up work
after that in 2013 which does something
very similar to what you're doing uh
shifting the burden
from the client to the cloud provider
for creating replicas especially when
some of those replicas fail and they
need to be recreated
it's
somewhat similar we don't call it
blinding we call it masking and i don't
know if you're aware of it you don't
cite it so this was in 2013.
i can send you the the point if you send
it to me fine we are happy to look into
it thanks thanks
great let's thank our speaker one more
time
[Applause]
you