hello everybody i'm santiago a second
year phd student at nyu and i'll be
presenting this paper on admitting
commits and committing omissions
this work is basically
about the design flow that we found in
git
and i'm going to talk about how an
attacker can
exploit this vulnerability what can an
attacker achieve when he exploits this
vulnerability how we fixed this
vulnerability and how these fixes have
made their way into git
before moving forward i'd like to
introduce my collaborators anil and resa
from ngit and justin captos my advisor
before starting i'd like to
talk a little bit about the rules of the
game maybe not all of us are familiar
with how git works or what git really is
so i'll start with a story about
a
repository in the center at your left
and two developers you can see on your
right hand side what's the state of the
repository in the center in the
in the of the repository that's on the
center
now
git is a distributed version control
system this means that every developer
has their own copy of the repository as
a local
this also means that every developer has
their own perception of what the state
of the central repository
when the first developer works
he commits locally and he performs some
change some changes to the source code
and then he pushes the changes this will
add a new commit object to a new branch
called feature
that maybe will be pulled by the second
developer will be reviewed and may be
merged into master after the second
developer pushes the changes into master
we see that the updated state of the
repository has changes from both feature
and master
now maybe the first developer wants to
pull these changes tag a release
and push the new tag for
package maintainers and users to
fetch the newest version of kit
of the software
now
what i want to
emphasize is that these repositories can
be compromised
while we were having a chips in
guacamole
tuesday night someone was trying to
actively break into a
the github account of a developer for
requests which is a
ca
well a
general
http request framework that also handles
ca verification
i
i agree with him and i quote that a
crafty attacker he says a government or
a powerful attacker could just sneak a
little back door that would be then
propagated into systems running in
almost major tech corporation
and exploit them afterwards
now this is not the first it hap first
time it happens the linux kernel was
hacked
there was a man in the middle between
china and github
between users in china and github
the ruby gems was hacked
sourceforge was also hacked
uh a couple of weeks ago
fasthop was hacked and it deleted the
mbr
entries of many people
the adobe was another
major hack
the fsf was compromised f pro ftpd
google
red hat
now i want to
reiterate on this uh compromises happen
compromises on source code happen
because they're really attractive to
attackers
now
luckily we have git and we have some get
some security features we get
the most
well-known is hash chaining right
if someone compromises a repository they
cannot
put changes for that far down into the
history and expect them to be propagated
it also means that if someone tampers
with the commits
the history will
fail
to tell to
to verify
now
we also have git commit and tax
signatures that prevent attackers from
creating new commit objects to new
attack objects so every change in the
history could be authenticated and
attributed to a user
we also have a push certificates which
is a relatively recent edition i'll talk
a little bit more about this later
they're not so popular i haven't seen
them in production yet
however things can go wrong
i'd like to
show you how things can go wrong with an
example i was trying to install django
1.9.3 in my own modified
github server
github repository and for some reason i
ended up with django 1.4.11
interestingly if you try to verify the
tag
gpg verification passes so everything
should be fine i'm actually running code
that's uh that's valid code right
if i ask for a little bit more detail i
realize that i'm actually getting the
right the wrong tag i'm getting 1.11
needless to say
django 1.4.11
is
vulnerable for more than eight remote
code execution vulnerabilities
and i also got the false impression that
everything was
going smooth because gpg verification
told me everything was fine
now
why did this happen
let me introduce you to the problem then
the problem is that some git metadata is
not signed if we run tree on the git
metadata folder we'll see that some
elements such as objects which are git
tags and git commits
are actually signed that's what gpg gpg
signing does
there's some other stuff such as
references which are pointers to this
tag and commit objects which are not
signed
this is our target
now an attacker with right access to the
repository could be a malicious
developer that doesn't want to want to
authenticate any actions or it could be
someone who broke into a repository
could modify this information and make
it look and change the state of the
repository into something that maybe
may cause unintended actions
of course after these attacks are
performed it would look like a regular
git operation so they're really really
subtle
with this knowledge and having seen that
these attacks can be performed just by
slightly tweaking what's on the
reference files we came up with a
metadata manipulation attack taxonomy
we
found a catalog of seven different
metadata manipulation attacks
for in the interest of time i'll only
focus on the first three which i
think they will convey what exactly is
happening with these things
and if you want to learn a little bit
more about the rest you can of course
read the paper
now let's go back to a central
repository that's compromised you see a
little devil there
there's a buggy branch there that says
do not merge maybe it's experimental
code maybe it's apples duplicate it go
to
and someone is
asking the repository for to know what's
the state
now maybe the repository wants to
equivocate then because it's malicious
and will change the reference pointer
that was originally master to this do
not merge branch
of course this will make the developer
think that there's new changes upstream
and actually git will automatically
merge this
after this happens then we manage to
trick the user into committing and
signing a change that contains a
vulnerable bug a vulnerable piece of
code into the production
analogous to the example that i gave you
in the beginning of the talk
there's a tag teleport attack in which a
reference is teleported into another
place in the history of git
in this case we have a tag that's known
to be vulnerable think about django
1.4.11 and we also have a version 1.1
which should be running smoothly which
should be
trustworthy to some extent
now a developer wants to
install
version 1.1 because that's the trusted
one or the
non-vulnerable one
and again the server may want to equip
it
this attack teleport attack simply
requires the attacker to move a pointer
back into the
previous stack
of course this will be installed and
most of the package managers in which we
tested this simple attack
uh resulted in a clean installation of
everything
even in conda that actually you can ask
it to verify gpg signatures
anyway
in addition to this there's other types
of attacks this is
a rollback attack a rollback attack
requires an
well will just be so that an attacker
pulls back
in the history sort of like rewinding
the building into something else
imagine there's a developer
that just made a new feature
that went through the code review and
some bug was preemptively found by the
developer that's above
now he committed he committed the fix
and he pushed it to the feature branch
so
the resulting merge should not happen
the bug it's fixed right by the
subsequent commit however an attacker
could lie about this
we could rewind the branch
and upon merging we have a vulnerable
piece of code again in production
now
this is pretty much what you can achieve
with these kinds of things it's a really
simple attack it's just tinkering with
what's on the reference files you could
present you could
include buggy code into production
by tracking
people into merging things you could
also
make package managers or users or even
get some modules during initialization
and include the vulnerable vulnerable
version of the code you could also omit
the security patch like it was on the
rollback attacks
and
delete
delete references and other things
that may just result in annoyance
now
seeing this we
we and all of the team with try to find
a way to fix this
we
recognize that this is actually really
similar to fork consistency attacks
now the problem is that we cannot use
for consistency attacks because of two
main reasons
first of all they tried
for consistency systems most of the time
try to
create a
consistent state of every single element
within all of the repositories the
problem with this is that this doesn't
play well with some distributed systems
also some other
consistency systems assume that you will
be able to call home
every
30 seconds every 10 minutes and if i for
example wanted to write some code in the
playing then i cannot use a
for consistency system
now
given this and given that git is
actually really smart in the way it
synchronizes and identifies which
elements are
needed to synchronize then we piggyback
on git
we also assume that uh some
like large
scale attacks like four star attacks are
not a concern because if you divide
two groups of developers separately they
will if they don't see changes from each
other they will start wondering that
something's wrong we've got element
we've got tools like mailing lists bug
trackers slack irc
etc that can let the developers
coordinate from the outside the trick
here is that all of the attackers that i
presented are actually
temporary they are reconcilable fork
attacks the state of the repository
breaks and changes for
five minutes at most or something and
then it comes back to a state in which
everyone agrees that everyone everything
is fine
we also assume that the repository can
be initialized on the route of trust
this is although
key management is an issue and there's
many clever solutions in how to handle
this we're assuming that
this can be integrated this can be
integrated into a system and actually we
integrated
key management into our system in a
really simplistic way
now without further ado i'll introduce
my solution
we'd like to
we have three main goals when we thought
of our solution first of all we wanted
to preserve all of the git workflows
this means that if someone is using git
send email to send a patch to a mailing
list that should work or if someone is
using github or gitlab or whatever that
should also work this means that you
that we cannot make assumptions in how
people should use git
we also align with what's uh
git's philosophy of supporting older
versions and backwards compatibility
right now if you are running a server
with kit 2.9.4
you can talk with a server running 1.7.0
and vice versa this means that
we couldn't make any drastic or like
disruptive changes into the way that pac
protocol worked
and we also want to provide the
increased security partial adoption
scenarios this is also a really
realistic thing because
by no one's
not everyone's going to use our solution
at the offset we introduce this and
we'll eventually start providing greater
benefits as people start using
we also
we also focused on these three qualities
that
and we are sure that if we provide these
qualities then we are able to prevent
these attacks and many
and
ensure
that the repository cannot equivocate on
the metadata files
now if you see these three uh
characteristics you'll see that
preventing modification of committed
data is actually provided by git
ensuring that con consistent repository
state is provided by something that we
designed called the reference state log
and we also added something new that's
called a non-spec which will ensure that
all of the
that the repository presents fresh
information
now in the interest of time i'll only
focus on the reference state law
reference to state log is a really
really simple protocol or addition to
get
instead of doing a regular push which
only sends the objects this is what you
should see here
it also pushes a signed statement that
says
this is the references that i'm changing
this is what you should be seeing now
when these changes make it to the other
side then
the objects are transmitted as they are
usually done and there's also some
consistency assurance that the
references were changed by an
authenticated user
now a reference state log is basically a
series of rsl push entries
these rsl push entries contain really
simple information which is what's the
reference that's changing like branch
master
what's the
actual commit object in which the branch
should be pointing to
a hash of the previous entries so that
an attacker cannot remove rsl push
entries or it cannot change the ordering
of the entries or anything of the like
and finally a signature that
authenticates the user
that made the there's a specific change
we then with this really simple solution
we made a prototype we did something
that's called the git extensions
it's pretty much a
script that you have to the path and you
can use it as you would use any git push
or get patch operation
and we made it so that the reference
state log lives on a separate branch in
the in as a special branch in the
repository this means that
we didn't change any of the protocol we
didn't
actually do anything weird to get we
just managed to
send the the rsl along with the regular
push
as long as you would write get secure
push instead of git push
now synchronization is really easy
if we go back to the example
from which i started in this uh
presentation
we had the developer worked and
committed locally and this time he'll do
a git secure push
instead of only having the feature
branch added to the to the repository we
also have a new commit that contains all
of the information about this rsl entry
when the other developer
does a secure
secure pull or fetch
he'll
be able to
verify and ensure that all of the
references are in the right place
once the merge is done that's what
happened in our example before
and the push is made back to master and
new rsl entry with a new state of the
repository is pushed when the other
developer pulls
he'll be he or she'll be sure that
the state of the references are correct
now verification is really simple
on the rsl we just want to be sure that
all of the entries are signed by a
trusted party
we also want to make sure that the rsl
entries are linked together this is just
doing simple
uh hash chaining in the same way that
git does right now and also that the
references are pointing in the right
place this is what we wanted to achieve
in the first place right
now with our prototype we evaluate it
and check whether our solution is
practical and how
how much would it cost to provide these
kind of security guarantees to users of
git
we
we basically
checked that the uh
that the solution was proper this means
that
if you want to perform any of these
attacks you would have to
you have to have an attacker that
contains a key that can authenticate the
change in the rsl
or an attacker that could be able to
present older versions of the rsl to a
user and that's why we added the
non-space
with the non-spac none of the rollback
attacks should happen and the
teleport attacks shouldn't happen with
the rs with the teleport or deletion
attack shouldn't happen with the rsl
push entries
we also explored and compared our rsl
and nonspark here compares to other
solutions push certificates are similar
to the rsl in that they contain
uh similar fields but they are not
changed together and they also change
the way that the
well they extended the way that pack
protocol works so you have a
bigger well you need a newer version of
git to be able to use push certificates
they also
since they do not have something that's
equivalent to a non-space then rollback
attacks and duplication attacks also
cannot be prevented either or something
really important to notice is that also
push certificates do not have a default
distribution mechanism this means that
you may have to
have a separate server or some other
instance of something to be able to host
and to distribute the push certificates
to other users
we also
made sure that the partial adoption of
our defense which is one of the goals is
is achieved and we see that although all
the attacks are possible we reduce the
attack surface by
only allowing commits after the latest
rsl entry was made this is similar to
just reducing the number of rough
gadgets that someone can use
we also checked the storage size
in the right hand side of the
of the table you'll see that most of the
time this is under one percent that this
is actually less than what push
certificates require
we also check the network overhead is
less than 25 kilobytes
uh and
it's double round through time but this
is
this will go away once the complete
solution is part of the git
pack
protocol then we
made all of this theory and this is what
like where usually uh regular theory
paper ends
but we didn't stop there we
reached out to the git community we
presented these issues and we started
the working with them in order to fix
what they call the low hanging fruit
first we
we refactor the get tac pgp verification
code you should be seeing these things
in version 2.9.0
it was really really well the world is
not painful but really thorough or
unlike expensive and time-consuming
effort because
they do care about their code they will
not let the single white space go
through and the commit message must be
perfect and not ambiguous and everything
should be fine
after
eight iterations of the same six series
batch series of six patches i finally
made it through and now you have a
pretty much all the groundwork for all
these fixes to be there
we
started trying to fix the
ge tag teleport attack which is
the simplest
attack effects because there's already a
header an element in the git tag header
that tells you which tag is this so
adding a simple a quality check sheet is
really simple
we also start exploring how to fix the
rest of the things
and uh
will it
will mostly imply taking push
certificates which is their
mature solution and integrate them
somehow into this
uh non-spack our cell ideology or like
design constraints
we also started exploring if these
attacks are possible in other version
control systems
we realize that the bit keeper doesn't
support gbe signing which was a pretty a
little bit disappointing uh but we also
saw that mercurial and monotone support
gpg signing to different extents
actually monotone is mandatory
and
these two other version control systems
do prevent the metadata manipulation
attacks
this doesn't mean that they are not
vulnerable to other types of attacks
this just means that you cannot tinker
with the references and expect people to
do unintended operations
now
i'd like to wrap up with the following
uh take away points
first of all first of all do not trust
infrastructure
uh if the repository is presenting you
with this information
be sure that this is actually
information that should be proper for
example
github added the pgp verification
service but it could really lie to you
right you should be really verifying all
of this information locally with a
keychain that you can trust
now
dpd signatures on git objects and tags
is
currently not enough this doesn't mean
you shouldn't be doing that actually
it's way better than nothing we
also checked with our signatures and
everything was used on
on popular repositories and it seems
that the usage is increasing which is a
really uh good news
also do not use references for things
like
cloning from installing from using pip
or something
because these things can happen to you
but you should be uh
you should be using the xiao one which
provides you a tight boundary binding
between what you want and what you
what you want and what you get
also and also like update kit there's
also changes there that will make your
life better and easier
that's pretty much it
questions
so no one understood anything or
uh so i had a question while we're
waiting to see if anyone else does uh
you mentioned
that uh use of sign commits is
increasing yes do you can you say
anything more like is it still fairly
low or
is it is it uh do you see it in
the packages we would think are sort of
most security relevant uh so yeah
actually it's it's interesting because
uh
it depends on the community and actually
the
kinds of people that use this uh
speech
software for example
the one that we found with the highest
commit rate was
metasploit
they have a
70-something percent and this is
actually
it means that one in every four commits
assigned which means that if they are
pushing
uh one and every four commits the
history is completely
proper it cannot be tempered
we also saw that for example if you
check the linux kernel there was pretty
much no signing whatsoever until about a
year and a half ago and now
it's hard to tell uh which push which
commits our pushes and which are not
you can you will only see uh
certain signatures mostly on merch
commits and actually done by torvalds
himself
this makes it so that you see less than
five percent or something in the signing
ratio but it also
doesn't provide a like the complete
picture because
if torvalds is merging a patch set of 40
different commits then the signature for
the merge commit actually applies to the
40 commits that are there
hi
joe tam from syracuse university
um so i'm wondering um
how you handle the freshness problem
let's say alice push
version one and then she pushes version
two later on and bob owning wants to get
the latest version how can you ensure
bobcats
version 2 rather than version one
yes so this is handled by the
addition that i didn't introduce in the
talk
it's called the nonspec it's uh
to keep it really simple and we can talk
a little bit more about it after the
talk
you put the random number into this
non-spark and this will be used to
verify when you get the next version
when you pull the next time if you pull
and you don't get the
your nons back then you have been
completely forked from the history and
you could
safely go to irc or to the mailing list
and complain that somewhere someone is
equivocating
so seems like you assume uh in the
scenario you assume there is a channel
combination communication channel
between alice and the bob
um sorry i couldn't understand that
could you repeat please i mean do you
assume there is a communication channel
between alice and bob directly without
going through the repo
oh yeah that's a
sparse i know that's a
realistic assumption i haven't worked on
being in any project in which they don't
even have like a google group
thank you
let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]
you