okay thank you very much
yeah i'll be speaking about new hope for
post quantum key exchange and this is
joint work with erdem alchem who's at
aggie university in izmir in turkey
leo duca who's at cwi in amsterdam in
the netherlands
thomas potman who's at infinion in
munich in germany and myself and i'm
also in the netherlands in the
university of nijmegen
let me start my talk by a quote and it's
a quote from about four years ago by
mark katchen who's doing research at ibm
and he's doing research on quantum
computers and
on well eventually building a large
universal quantum computer
and in 2012 markets said that
in the past people have said maybe it's
50 years away it's a dream maybe it'll
happen sometime i used to think it was
50.
now i'm thinking like it's 15 or a
little more it's within reach it's
within our lifetime it's going to happen
so why would we care as cryptographers
if somebody builds a large quantum
computer
well
essentially it means that if
researchers do that if quantum engineers
and physicists are able to build such a
computer large enough maybe in the next
two decades then that's the end of
crypto as we know it
or maybe a bit more specifically it's
the end of asymmetric crypto as we know
it
and the reason for this is that in 1994
already
ashore published an algorithm which
already in the title of the paper um
well says it's doing two things two very
special things namely it's factoring
integers in polynomial time on such a
universal quantum computer
and it's computing discrete logarithms
in polynomial time
on a big universal quantum computer
now these are essentially the two
problems that all of our current
asymmetric crypto is based on
so for example this would mean a
complete break of rsa of algamal
dsa defeathelman key exchange all the
elliptic curve variants thereof so ecdsa
ecdh
hdsa whatever you want to come up with
so
that's pretty scary
um but well it feels like it's still
like one or two decades away right so
you know let's maybe do some research
let's get some cool stuff done and maybe
we can find solutions to this
but actually the situation is even worse
imagine an attacker has been named in
the question and answers of the previous
talk for example attacker using large
data centers to record internet traffic
encrypted internet traffic today
and then maybe in like one or two
decades when this attacker has a large
quantum computer it's just going back
and decrypting all that traffic that has
been recorded before
now
honestly for some of the communication
that i have on the internet which i
encrypt
in 20 years i probably don't care
anymore but for some communication some
people really do care and that would
probably be exactly the communication
that this attacker would target
now sometimes when you're when you're
looking at this kind of attack where
somebody's recording today and then
later looking back at it people say wait
wait wait we have perfect forward
secrecy
um that's a great concept but it doesn't
help
so the idea in perfect forward secrecy
is to use long-term keys only for
authentication and use short-term
ephemeral keys for encryption and the
idea is that if the long term keys get
compromised for example by somebody
breaking into my laptop and stealing all
my keys it's not possible to just go
back and use those keys to decrypt all
old information because it has been
encrypted under short time ephemeral
keys that have been immediately deleted
however that doesn't help against a
cryptographic break because you can just
go back to all the recorded traffic and
break one of the key exchanges after the
other that's a linear slowdown but
that's still not particularly good if
you have a polynomial time algorithm to
break stuff
now not saying that perfect forward
secrecy is bad we definitely want this
it's giving us a very very strong
protection against a real life real
world issue so what we want today
is
post quantum perfect for its secret um
crypto
and obviously if we want this we can't
build it on the problems um that i wrote
down be above so we can't build this on
discrete logarithms as in
diffie-hellman for example or elliptic
curve discrete logarithms or factoring
so there needs to be some other problem
which we can use to build asymmetric
crypto and more specifically that we can
use to build ephemeral key exchanges
that quantum computers as far as we know
do not completely break
here's that problem well at least the
problem that i will use for the rest of
the talk there are some others
so the problem that i will use in the
rest of the talk is called the ring
learning with errors problem
and i will use this slide to introduce a
bit of notation so what we will need is
one mathematical structure that we're
working in and that is this ring r key
and the ring argue that simply
polynomials in a variable x
and
all the coefficients are taken modulo
and integer q
and then so that the polynomials don't
grow arbitrarily in multiplications we
reduce them modulo some polynomial and
that polynomial is x to the n plus one
okay
so then we need chi to be an error
distribution on this ring so typically
something that chooses with small errors
we will come back to that in a bit
and then we have a secret we always have
some secret in asymmetric cryptography
well in almost all of cryptography
that's s and that's just an element of
this ring
and now the attacker is given
pairs of a and a s plus e
where a is uniformly
sampled uniformly at random from this
ring rq
and e is sampled from this noise or
error distribution chi
and the task of the attacker is to find
s
so that's the problem that we're going
to base the crypto on that i will be
talking about
there's two very common choices here one
very common choice for kai is to use the
so-called discrete gaussian distribution
it's very nice gives a very nice
mathematic properties it allows to prove
certain properties here
it's not so nice when you have to
implement this so typically when you
implement a high quality discrete
gaussian you end up with either
very inefficient
implementations or implementations that
leak through timing information about
the values of this noise distribution
which is something that we really want
to avoid in the real world
um i will come back to this later
because we decided not to do to use a
discrete gaussian
then there's a very common optimization
and that is to use the same a for all
users
so you don't need to you re-sample this
every time
you just do this once and you compile it
into your software
we also didn't do that and i will also
come back to that later
let me give you a bit of a history of
how this ring lwe and some variants of
it have been used this is completely not
a complete overview of the history you
can find like typically tens of papers
every year being published in this area
um but it's sort of a bit of the history
that builds up to well what i'm
presenting in this talk
in 1996 um hofstein pifer and silverman
presented the entry crypto system which
is still around today um you could can
be seen maybe as a bit of a predecessor
to ring lwe it can maybe also be seen as
a bit of a competition so it's similar
but a bit different but that was sort of
the first cryptosystem that is well that
survived and that is still um that
appeared in this in this realm
um off related to ring lwe then in 2005
regev introduced an lwe based encryption
so that's learning with errors without
the ring and essentially then
polynomials turn into large matrices and
vectors
so that means that keys typically become
quite a bit larger
and you can think of the ring lwe
version as a specialized version of lwe
where these large matrices have a
certain structure that allows us to
compress
well compress the
matrix in 2010 lubashovsky pyker and
regev introduced ring lwe and then also
while based on ringwe ring lwe-based
encryption
and two years later dingshier and lin
showed how to transform this into a key
exchange protocol
this was improved by picard in 2014
in particular pycat showed how to obtain
keys that are not biased
and
interestingly in this 2014 paper there
were no parameters that you could just
take and implement this thing so i'm
looking at this from a person who's
writing some cryptographic software from
time to time that paper was not actually
telling you what to really implement um
there was a follow-up in 2015 by boss
castell and eric and stabila and what
they did is they chose parameters for
this key exchange proposed by picard in
2014 and they implemented this and they
integrated it into openssl and showed
that you can actually in tls do post
quantum key exchanges using this
approach
now the parameters that they chose were
well this ring r q as i showed it before
polynomials of um
n coefficients
with each coefficient being an integer
mod q where n is 1024.
sq they chose 2 to the 32 minus 1. for
those if you're interested that's not a
prime um it's obviously a 32-bit integer
um and as a noise distribution that
chose exactly what i mentioned before
this discrete gaussian with a
standard deviation sigma of something
like 3.19 t
and what their paper claimed
was that they have 128 bits of security
but only pre-quanta
so they did not look at okay so what
happens if an attacker has a big quantum
computer as far as we know the attacker
doesn't break this in polynomial time
otherwise while we would be in very
serious trouble but that doesn't mean
that a large quantum computer can't do
anything they didn't analyze that they
just said well pre-quantum currently 128
bets
and then they had a failure probability
in there which was extremely small so
something like 2 to the minus 131 000
this idea of a failure probability is
essentially that if you make the noise
too large then at some point everything
will fail if you make the noise too
small it will become insecure
um very obviously if the set or set the
noise to zero you get um you can solve
the whole thing just with a gaussian
elimination and if you make it too large
then it doesn't help so basically this
noise balances between security and
failure probability and the failure
probability was enormously small
okay so what we decided is let's
reconsider this and let's see whether we
can do better in terms of security in
terms of performance and let's see where
we get and whether we can make this
maybe a bit more practical because the
performance
well we will see numbers later was not
as good as it can be
before i look at what we did let's look
at the protocol because this is a pretty
nice well sort of easy version of how
this how this key exchange works
so again up here you have um you have
the system parameters as i mentioned
then before with the the other
distribution and then there's some
global system parameter that's this a
and as i mentioned before they use this
optimization of saying here's a global a
then
alice the server samples some
s and e and actually s is also sampled
from this noise distribution that's
common way to do it and then compute b
which is a s plus e so that's exactly
this computation that we saw before
which is then handed over to an attacker
and yeah this handed over to attackers
sent over the channel
and then bob receives this and does two
very similar computations here to
compute u and v
and then sends u over to alice
and alice multiplies that by s and by
two and then obtains this term
this is this two a s s prime plus 2 e
prime s
and bob on this side has a similar value
that's this v bar
which is well you take the v value and
then you put it through a randomized
double function so this randomized
double function that has a bit of
randomness coming in and that is exactly
ensuring it's this trick by to
make sure that in the end you have an
unbiased key
and then what bob gets is this v bar
which is well this two a s s prime plus
two e s
e s prime plus 2 e double prime
now these terms here that's sort of the
large term that's this
term that both have the same and then
behind there there's some error terms
so the idea of this key exchange is that
both parties have a value which is well
similar but not the same
and then one party sends a bit of extra
information over this
v prime here
and this v prime is then being used to
agree on an exact value
okay
now our contributions was that first of
all we said we don't really need a
failure probability which is that
terribly
low we don't need 2 to the minus 131
000.
um we discussed it with a few people
who are actually um well working on tls
libraries and we heard that 2 to the
minus 60 is just fine
if something happens with probability 2
to the minus 60 there's failures that
happen more often than well you just
retry you just agree on a new well you
run the whole thing again
then we came up with a very tight
analysis of what the failure probability
actually is which allowed us to choose
the other parameters to actually get to
this failure probability
we decided to keep the dimension so 1024
as as a dimension n
but choose q much much smaller
now typically in cryptography when you
make parameters smaller things become
less secure
and here exactly the opposite happens
when you make q smaller the intuition is
that then the noise matters more
so what you care about is how much does
the noise matter in relation to the
value q so if you make q smaller
everything becomes more secure also
messages become shorter and well if you
work with smaller values there's some
speed ups
um we decided to analyze the post
quantum security so we said we're not so
interested in what can attackers do
today but what does an attacker do
breaking this maybe in a few years with
a quantum computer
um then we said we don't want discussion
noise because it's really hard to sample
and quite a bit of the inefficiency
of this bcns proposal that i showed
before came from the fact that they were
using a discrete gaussian
and we realized that you need something
which looks kinda gaussian but it
doesn't have to be a real gaussian so
you just say okay take two k-bit
integers a and b
compute the hamming weight of them and
then just subtract the hemming weights
that looks kinda awesome
and that's just good enough
and there's a proof that this is good
enough in the paper
and then we said we choose a fresh a for
every protocol run which is obviously
making things slower i mean if you need
to sample in ua every time it's
definitely slower i'll come back to why
we did this later
and then we encode polynomials that we
send over the channel in the entity
domain so basically you can think of
this as we take a polynomial and run an
fft over it
and that allows us to do very efficient
multiplications and actually save a few
of those fft transformations which is
the main arithmetic cost
and then we implemented the whole thing
um and well i'll say a bit about the
speed later
so now i can't really talk about any of
these contributions in very much detail
the paper has very nice pictures on all
of this i can't show those that would
take too much time so we'll give a bit
of an idea of what each of these
contributions means and then see where
we end up in the end in terms of
performance and security
first this is what our protocol now
looks like you see that up here there's
no system parameter anymore what we get
instead is that alice the server
is taking a seed and then is expanding
this seed through shake 128 that's an
extendable output function from the fib
202 standard
and then while
parsing this into a uniformly
distributed a
and sending the seed over so that bob
can do the same on that side
and what also changed compared to the
previous
protocol is that while choosing noise
from a different distribution
and
down here this error reconciliation
works in a different way
and i will come back to that so we don't
have this randomized doubling anymore
this is now replaced by something that
we call help rack it's a somewhat of a
generalized version of this and then in
the end
both part parties have a value while v
and v prime
they're very similar as before except
that the factor two is missing and then
they have this vector r of
reconciliation information that they
used to extract k a key uh k here and
that one um as part of the protocol we
put through a final hash we use chart
three there
that's essentially the protocol
now this error reconciliation well as i
said we agree on a somewhat similar
value on both sides and we need to have
the same well we need to extract a
common key from that
and
what is
known is that well you need to send some
additional information this r you can't
do it without it's by the way a very fun
exercise to think through why you can't
spend a few hours thinking this through
and at some point convince myself that
it's really not possible and i think
everybody working in this field at some
point did
so what is known is that you can extract
one bit from each of the coefficients
that you find in the literature it's
also known how to extract multiple bits
from
each coefficient and then essentially
that means that you need to choose
slightly lower noise and that means that
you're lower the security but we wanted
to do something else because we had a
1024 coefficient sitting around and we
won the post quantum symmetric key so we
wanted 256 bit key
and so what we did is we showed how to
extract one bit from multiple
coefficients and increase the security
and the idea is well specifically we do
well one bit from four coefficients of
this noisy polynomial
and it's a method that is inspired by
error correcting codes
what you find in the paper is sort of a
two-dimensional intuition for this and
then really what is happening is a
four-dimensional thing
and then we generalized piker's approach
this with this randomized doubling um to
obtain unbiased keys
okay so error reconciliation works
let's take a look at post quantum
security
and post quantum security is pretty
tricky because many of the algorithms
that
we know to solve this problem it is not
entirely understood how
costly they are for real parameters
so there is some asymptotic estimation
estimates but it's not it's not so clear
if you throw in real parameters like
this will be the runtime and in
particular not if you do this whole
thing post quantum because we don't even
know exactly what the quantum computer
will look like
so we said okay the best algorithm is an
algorithm called bkz you don't need to
understand anything about it what you
need to understand is as a black box
it's calling an oracle multiple times
and that is the shortest vector problem
in a smaller dimension so that's this
svp oracle here
we just said well
we don't really care about how often we
need to call this oracle let's just say
call it once everything else we give to
the attacker for free and we just want
to know how long does it take the
attacker to solve this
sap oracle once and that's what we call
the svp core svp hardness
and then we look at the asymptotically
best algorithm for this in the ram model
so we also say
if the attacker needs a huge bunch of
storage for this we give this storage to
the attacker for free we only care about
the runtime here and then we look at the
asymptotic runtime and just assume well
that's that's going to be the runtime
and the best known cost for this is
well 2 to the 0.264 n
for dimension n
um the best plausible quantum cost we
also analyzed and essentially the idea
behind this best possible quantum cost
is that before even running anything the
attacker needs a certain set of input
and that is generated classically on a
classical computer there's no quantum
computation involved and the amount of
inputs that it need the attacker needs
is this so that's what we say that's the
even if you can find some cool speed ups
in the later runtime in the sieving well
you first need to have the input
okay and then we analyzed this we
analyzed this for uh the proposal by bus
costal and eric and stabila and we
analyzed this for the new parameters
and
what we see here that the
best known classical attack without
involving a quantum computer we get
a bit security of 86 for bcns and almost
300 for new hope now as i said this is
for shorter messages and
well we will see quite a bit of faster
computation um and even if we go for the
best plausible so not even currently
clear how this would work um post
quantum or quantum computation algorithm
we get something like 200 bits of
security here
now
this does not mean that you can actually
break bcns in 2 to the 86
as i said before we give a whole lot of
things for free to the attacker so it
could well be that the analysis that
bcns got with 128 bits of security is
just fine if you try to get a somewhat
tighter analysis we just said we want
lower bounds on the
on the bit security here and
be done with it
okay
now i mentioned that
um we don't pick a fixed system
parameter a
and one reason for this is that it's
very hard for
um cryptographers to agree on a fixed
random system parameter
if you if you ask around here then
everybody would somehow probably come up
with some system parameter and then
afterwards you have to agree and
everybody who comes up with one
parameter needs to convince everyone
else that i don't have a backdoor
it's not so easy
um there is this so-called nothing up my
sleeves approach where while you take
some
digits of pi for example you feed them
through a hash function and even then
you can write scientific papers about
how to attack this approach so it's
really really hard to get cryptographers
to agree on this
even if you manage to do this
there's another problem
and this other problem is assume that
lattice script analysis really improves
and
there are
possibly really big improvements ahead
it's not like
it's really well understood how hard
these things are
and let's say maybe there is an
algorithm in say 20 years maybe 30 years
that can solve these problems
but not almost free but maybe it takes a
year to compute
now if you choose a fixed a you do this
computation once which costs a year
maybe under each supercomputer in 20 30
years and then afterwards you can just
break every single key exchange
because the computation that you need to
do the expensive one only depends on a
now if you choose a different one
different a for each key exchange then
you would need to do a computation of
one year for each single key exchange
which is an additional safeguard
so this attack that i just sketched is
in the spirit of a lock jam attack where
you also had like this huge
precomputation done once and then once
this was done and you had this this
pre-competition results sitting around
you could afterwards attack well every
single diffie-hellman key exchange
if they were using the same system
parameter in that case the prime number
um so as i said solution in new hope is
well expand and fresh seed every single
time
and then we'll expand it through the
shake 128 gigs off
you can cache this so if you have a
server that is really bottlenecked by
computations then the server can just
say i'm caching this for an hour and
then an attacker in say 20 30 years with
this advanced algorithm that we don't
even know that will exist needs to break
one needs to do one year of computation
per hour it's still not so bad
one word of warning you must not reuse
the keys and the noise so this s and
this e and this
s prime e prime and e double prime
um in diffie-hellman in or elliptic rift
if your helmet it's common optimization
to
reuse ephemeral keys for like an hour or
so
which in ssl libraries is happening on a
somewhat higher level now if you replace
this or if you add in
post quantum say new hope key exchange
there make very sure that you're not
reusing these secrets then things become
insecure
okay i said we implemented the whole
thing
and the multi the costly operations in
there are these multiplications in this
polynomial ring
and we chose parameters such that we can
do this through something which is uh
well a very very efficient number
theoretic transform so essentially the
idea is if you have take two polynomials
you send them through an fft then you
multiply coefficient-wise and you do
then an inverse fft of the result
and fft in a finite field is well
becomes an entity and this one is really
really fast
and because we're sending polynomials in
ntt domain we don't on one side first
transform back and then on the next side
transform again to entity domain we just
leave it there which saves us
two of the required entities
we came up with a c reference
implementation um and when writing this
we really kept in mind that this should
be portable also to small embedded
devices so we only use 16-bit and 32-bit
integers um except in um catch-up so in
the
in the final hashing that is inherently
64-bit arithmetic so we left that from
the implementation that the catrick
designers came up with
um
there's no division operators there's no
modular operator in the whole thing so
the whole module of arithmetic is done
just through multiplications
we use a trick for efficient reductions
inside the entity modular reductions we
use montgomery representation
and for this noise sampling what we use
is chacha 20 which is very portable very
fast very easily protected against
timing attacks
we also optimized this for large intel
processors and used the av x2 vector
instruction set
basically through all computationally
expensive tasks
so the entity is vectorized the centroid
binomial sampling is vectorized
error reconciliation is vectorized noise
sampling
ah here we use as256 for noise sampling
because on all these processors there is
aes 256 in hardware or as in hardware
and
as you can see it doesn't matter these
are compatible this is a local decision
how you sample your noise it's a local
your local secret so you can just use
whatever you have sitting around as an
efficient rng
so here's the performance as opposed to
the performance of a bcns so you can see
that our c reference implementation of
the key generation and this well shared
key computation on the client side is
about an order of magnitude faster than
the bcns proposal and then our avx
implementation well is still well a
factor of three roughly faster than our
c implementation
um
for the shared key we unfortunately did
not get exactly to the
order of magnitude speed up but still
it's quite a bit faster about five times
faster
now these numbers here include on both
the server side and the client side this
um
this generation of a on both sides which
bcns don't have and which at least on
the server side we could cache but well
we didn't really bother
if
cycles don't tell you all that much on
intel processors to give you an idea the
currently fastest thing that you can use
for key exchange in tls that would be
the x25519 elliptic curve scalar
multiplication and if you use purely
ephemeral things with no caching then
each part you would need to do two
scalar multiplications so two times this
so in other words
new hope is faster than what is
currently
included
okay now at this point of the talk
i should maybe answer the question
whether you should be using this and
then i would give you a super biased
author opinion here whether you should
be using it and i'm very lucky that i
don't have to do this
because it is currently being used
um
so on july 7 google announced that they
would be running an experiment um it's a
two-year experiment between
chrome canary and some google services
and
they're running tls with a new key
exchange
hybrid which they call cec pq1
and that hybrid is using exactly the
x25519 elliptic curve key exchange that
i mentioned before and new hope
and well if you can run google canary
which i cannot because i have linux and
it's apparently not supported then you
can see pictures like this where
actually you see that the protocol is
tls 1.2 with the key exchange being
something that uses new hope
now
google here is actually doing exactly
what we would also recommend namely yeah
you should be using it if you need post
quantum key exchange ephemeral key
exchange now which might be because you
have users that really care about long
term security or because you want to
experiment early to figure out whether
the larger messages so messages become
larger compared to ecc
whether your system can handle that
that's actually what google wants to
also try out with this experiment
then the second thing is you should
always combine it with a key exchange
that we're currently using so x25519 to
be sure that you're not lowering
security by using something which is
still it feels a bit experimental and
then the third thing is google said
they're doing this for two years and
they're hoping that there will be
something better in two years and i
would say this is entirely realistic so
if you do it then write it in a modular
way so that you can plug in something
else
if you're interested in this if you're
interested in learning more about new
hope or if you're interested in playing
with the software um it's both online
software's in the public domain
both for download on cryptojedi.org
and
after we put this paper online several
people well followed up on this
there's now more software um there's
software by um by adam who's also an
author of this paper and philip yakubite
and myself we optimized this also for
embedded arm processors
um yawning angel
optimized it in go uh isis lovecraft
wrote a rust implementation rusevlay
wrote the java implementation and only
very recently i learned that alexander
farrar is wrote an erlang implementation
of new hope
so
i know that most of this code is in
public domain for the ones that i didn't
write please double check on the on the
respective websites
if you have any questions about this
then of course i'm open for questions
now you can also write us an email to
newhope cryptojedi.org and for now i
thank you for your attention
[Applause]
[Music]
um
sorry diminishing culture luxembourg
what are the units of cost where you
measure the security
um
so that would be the asymptotic
complexity of
the
of the sieving algorithm
and then this is hiding all kind of
linear factors that you might want to
want to throw in there so this is so you
would need something like two to the 199
operations where these operations are
actually pretty large things
but we give those large things to the
attacker for free we just say it's an
operation some
small atomic operations
as far as i understand not all that
small and they also involve pretty big
access to pretty big memory even if you
want to do it but let's say
small in in some sense of small yes but
more costly than for example in a call
to aes
interesting how much memory just for
curiosity
how much memory
i don't know
i'd have to take a look at it
mike mike petula from west point hi
peter um
two related questions uh have you talked
to any other tls implementations other
than boring ssl and then are we going to
see this in salt as well
um we had a bit of an exchange with um
the
people who did the bcns implementation
and we also discussed whether we should
integrate it in openssl now i myself
have very little experience with writing
code for open there's some code that i
wrote in openssl but other people
integrated it
and i looked at the at the integration
openssl i found a large cascade of if
devs where i realized that it's very
easy to screw this up and i decided that
if we're doing this i'm interested in
helping with this
but i'd really rather have someone who's
really familiar with openssl
will we see this in salt
i think currently our priorities for
salt are others
i think maybe at some point when salt
goes completely post quantum
i would hope that there's something
better than that but it's not entirely
impossible the is the post quantum uh
some time away
do you think or maybe post questions
um i don't see this happening this year
okay i'm not going to hold you to it
okay thanks peter
uh kenny patterson from royal holloway
um i got a bit confused about some of
your security analysis so could you put
slide 10 up for me
thanks
uh
i think it was like 10.
yeah okay so
um i guess the first question is
and you didn't explicitly mention this
but i assume it's true do you have a
security proof that reduces to the
hardness of our of ring lwe for you
there is a security proof in the
original um in the original paper by a
pie code yeah and does that proof carry
over to your slightly different protocol
um
there is so we don't have this
average case to worst case reductions
with the parameters that we choose
we do show that if we don't use gaussian
noise that the advantage of an attacker
is
small so you can say if there is an
algorithm distinguishing
with gaussian noise then the same
algorithm has a so with a certain
probability then with a certain slightly
lower probability you can also
distinguish uh with with this noise
because the binomial distribution is
close to the gaussian distribution yes
right but that's not the same as a
structure you shouldn't be using this in
signatures though
so in signatures this is a completely
different situation so this is something
um which actually even if you use it um
for
if you did a cca transformation of this
to to reuse keys at some point and have
long-term keys it's not entirely clear
to me what happened so this is something
only for purely ephemeral for the purely
ephemeral situations at least i won't
make any statements beyond that so let's
suppose that we assume that that proof
carries over
let's be optimistic
you have this quite conservative
analysis here where you're saying well
let's just count the cost of one
svp oracle and call that the the
security of the scheme
but if you take into account the cost of
the reduction in the security proof then
maybe you go in a different direction
with your parameters completely so can
you just say a little bit more about
that for this audience and what what's
what's missing there okay so if you if
you look at the at the tightness of of
the reductions the parameters are not
chosen to take those into account what
we're looking at is the best algorithms
that we know to solve this problem
and not another problem that it's being
reduced to but just much smaller or
something like that um also something
that i should mention here we look at
this ring lwe instance as an lwe
instance right that was my next question
yeah
very good so you're implicitly assuming
that
ring lwe is just as hard as lw and i
would really want to see much much more
research on this so any phd student who
reads a really cool topic encrypt
asymmetric cryptanalysis i think this is
really
something extremely important to look at
because um this is not clear that this
actually holds at the moment there are
no better algorithm there's no algorithm
that would exploit the structure
but i would be extremely excited to see
such an algorithm okay because that
would really improve our understanding
so the chair isn't stopping me asking
questions yeah last time there's no one
behind me so you talked about the uh
the number of cycles you needed to run
the key exchange protocol you didn't
talk about the bandwidth consumption i
wonder why about the amount of bandwidth
that your protocol consumes when you
send messages on the network so um what
we're sending
is about two kilobytes in each each
direction okay that's improving by a bit
more than a factor of two compared to
bcns
and it's
way way worse than elliptic curve
department like ten times or something
but almost hundred times hundred times i
mean you get 32 bytes which way elliptic
enough cryptography okay so um yeah so
i think what we will have to live with
at least from everything i understand
right now in a post-quantum world as
things will become larger messages will
become larger okay
thank you very much thanks
uh hello jose fernandez up with uh
uh echo polytechnic
um
i'm um there are applications where um
uh
that where key exchange is not gonna cut
it but you're gonna need certificates or
you know some certificate based
public key
implementation so i'm wondering
[Music]
what is standing in the way of having of
using this as a certificate based public
key infrastructure is it just a
certificate size or is there something
else that i that you didn't talk care
about um so you mean using this was
long-term keys basically that have
signatures on them yeah
um the very basic idea is that
what an attacker can do if you so you
choose your long term key and i'm
communicating to you and i can choose
noise such that with relatively high
probability the key exchange fails
and this probability depends on your key
now i keep just sending you messages and
play with the noise and then
keep learning about your key if i do
this plain thing
um now if we do this ephemeral then i
can learn something about your key by
doing this but also afterwards you throw
it away
the key exchange failed and it doesn't
matter at all
but you can't reuse the keys for roughly
that reason um there are transformations
for this but this is
something beyond the paper that we that
we currently have okay so it's because
of the noise model and the fact that
it's not deterministic as in
standard pki uh it is really because
this has only a chosen plain text
security and no chosen cipher text
security
so let me take one last question so the
failure probability you you settled on
was 2 to the negative negative 60. which
still strikes me as a extremely low
failure probability
um because the consequences of a failure
are just try it again right there's no
security loss there's no big harm so if
you set it to say two to negative eight
some ridiculously high failure rate
would there be benefits of doing that
given the cost of failure so though
um
you can so if you do this then the
obvious thing that you can do is you can
increase the noise and then you get even
more security
um now this is not necessarily something
that we're still aiming for at something
like 255 bits while at some point you
say it's enough
um what you can maybe do is you can make
the dimensions smaller and what the
paper has is we have an instantiation
with n equals 512
and we're aiming for the same error
probability a failure probability sorry
and we don't get 128 bits of
post-quantum security with this
conservative estimates
now we could have argued that
somewhat tighter analysis would still
give us
good security there and then we could
have maybe said that 2 to the minus 30
for example would still be okay and
increase the noise a bit and puzzle this
together
um for me the only reason to use this at
the moment is really long-term security
and
i'm expecting
some advances in encrypt analysis there
so i would really want to go for really
conservative parameters in particular
because
it feels like there's no reason to not
do it the only
message has become roughly half the size
but it somehow feels more comfortable
for long-term security to stay away from
that
thank you so let's thank our speaker
again
[Applause]
[Music]
you