thank you stefan and as stefan said i am
advaith nadkarni and i am going to talk
about making data secrecy enforcement
practical on android
so these operating systems like android
and ios are very different from your
traditional windows desktop for instance
on android
applications are security principles and
simply what that means is that
applications execute with a small subset
of the user's overall security
privileges and these privileges are tied
to their identities our security
principles
so this is very different from your
windows desktop where an application
executes as the user and has all the
privileges that the user has on the
system
now since applications are security
principles on android
applications cannot normally access each
other's data
so
when the user wants to combine different
applications applications must share
data and i'll give you an example of how
the sharing takes place
so say you get an email in an email
application and the email consists of an
attachment now you click on the
attachment and the attachment opens up
in a document viewer and this
flow is very seamless
what's happening in the background is
that the email application is sharing
the attachment with the document viewer
now this sharing is really useful you
could then convert the attachment to a
different format or you could sign it
with your physical signature and you
could even export it back through the
email application all within staying in
the same workflow
at the same time this sharing can be
risky
what if one of these applications say
the document of your application decides
to become malicious or is compromised
and exports your data to a remote server
on the internet
so the question for us is
how do we enable this data sharing
amongst applications while also
preventing such unauthorized disclosure
of data
now if you look at it the problem stems
from the loss of control over the flow
of shared data that is the email
application can control
sharing of data but once this data is
shared with an adversary it loses all
control over what the adversary does
with it
so since this is a problem of
controlling the flow of one's
information the solution is
information flow control right think
about uh think about the secrecy model
like bellapadla
now
information flow control has been around
for over four decades but it has seen
very limited use in commodity operating
systems
and one of the reasons for this is that
most information flow control models
require a centrally administered policy
and what this essentially means is that
a system administrator sets the policy
for systems objects and objects now
while this is reasonable to assume for
system data
what about application specific data
like email attachments and notes and
messages
a system administrator cannot be
expected to reason about third party
applications like email gmail and
whatsapp let alone the secrecy policy
for the data
so for application specific data we have
decentralized information flow control
or diffc
this c allows applications to become the
data owners for their own secret data
and essentially these data owners can
create the security classes to mark
which of the data is secret and which is
not
they can even define the policy define
the secrecy policy for the security
classes that is they can define the
arrangement between these security
classes which defines the flow that is
possible between them
and more importantly they can define
what declassification means for their
own security classes
now to simply say this declassification
is the removal of the security policy it
is the removal of the label and data
owners can control when the label over
this over the secret data might be
removed
now to go back to the email example the
email application can easily protect its
data by specifying a simple security
policy and the policy is as follows
the email applications policy allows
every single data owner in the system to
access and share his data with one
another to give the user utility but at
the same time only allows the email
application itself to declassify this
information
now we are not presenting the first
distribution for android but we have
been
working on integrating the scene to
android for a while so in 2013 we gave
the first district system for android
that was aquifer and aquiver focused
mostly on dc policy for android
now right right about the same time
another group from cmu gave their own
distribution system for android and
proposed a non-interference proof for
the difficulty system
now most recently shu and witches have
provided maxoid which gives some
interesting storage level enforcement
primitives for devc on android
now while we've learned a lot of
valuable lessons from these existing
systems
what we have learned the most is that
it's very hard to make deci enforcement
that is both secure as well as backwards
compatible with unmodified legacy
applications
essentially what we observed was that
if you want to make if you want to
provide really strong secrecy guarantees
then you risk breaking applications
but if you want to continue if you want
to work with unmodified legacy
applications then you have to loosen
your security guarantee somewhere
so prior approaches have exposed three
main challenges in diff reinforcement on
android namely determination of the
subject granularity and labeling
precision
the label change and propagation logic
and network declassification in a
network driven environment
and i'm going to explain all of these
challenges individually and then we're
going to look at how we resolve these
challenges in our system
so for subject granularity we have two
options
you have the fine grained programming
language variable that has the obvious
advantage of precision right find
maintained tracking is extremely precise
but at the same time fine graintain
tracking is
susceptible to implicit flows in code
there is flows that occur not due to the
explicit transfer of information but due
to control flow
now for security what you really want is
the granularity of the operating system
process
the process is completely mediated by
the operating system so all the flows in
and out of a process go through the
operating system but at the same time
the process is a very coarse grained
abstraction
especially on android many instances of
the same application may actually exist
simultaneously in the same process and
these instances may be taking part in
completely unrelated user tasks and
dealing with completely unrelated user
data
so when we restrict these different user
tasks with the same secrecy policy or
with a superset of all the secrecy
policies we actually have a lot of false
positives
so what we really want for this
reinforcement in terms of the subject
granularity is
the security of process level in
tracking without the false positives
now in terms of label propagation again
we have two options
there is a class of system that proposes
explicitly defining labels and
explicitly changing labels on subjects
so if there are two subjects p and q
and if p and q have different labels
right now
such systems expect p or q or both to
change the labels in time for any
communication to occur
if
the pnq don't adjust the labels in time
then the call is simply denied
now explicit flows are very hard to
model in android because on android most
communication is user directed and most
sharing between applications is usually
directed so applications aren't really
aware of when they're going to be part
of such communication
what we really need for android is
floating labels or implicit label
propagation
so in floating labels
communication between different subjects
is always enabled but what happens is
when p calls q the restrictions on p are
propagated to q
so the restrictions propagate in the
direction of the flow of information
now while this is exactly what we want
on android because we want seamless
communication and while this propagation
of restriction looks
secure floating labels as they are are
far from being secure or practical so
i'm now going to discuss an attack on
floating labels that has been discussed
in literature for a while
so say you have
two processes p and q
and p has read the secret data bits 0 1.
now p has also acquired the label l 1
that is associated with the secret data
now the objective of this attack is for
p to propagate the data to q without
actually propagating the label
so obviously p is not going to directly
call q because that would propagate the
label l1 to q
instead
q creates two workers q one and q two
and these are also processes or subjects
in the system
now these workers note that there are
two workers for two bits there's one
worker per bit
now all of these participants in the
system agree to a set of rules
the first rule
is that the workers q1 and q2 will call
q back at a predetermined time interval
the only reason when they won't call
back is if one of them gets a call from
p first
the other rule is that p will call the
ith worker of q q i if it wants to
indicate a zero at the i pit
so in this case since p wants to
indicate a zero at the first bit
it calls the worker q one
now at the predetermined time interval q
one and q two must both call q back but
q two is the only component that calls q
since q one has already been called by p
now at this point q has gotten a call
from q 2 which allows it to guess that q
2 signifies the bit 1 since
since q 2 has called it must not have
been called by p
so q correctly guesses the database 0
and since q2 symbolizes the bit 1 and
the absent call symbolizes the bit 0.
now floating labels are not only not
secure they're also not practical on
android
so say you have a component or a subject
that provides a shared
service to other different subjects in
the system and let's assume all of these
other subjects have different labels
so initially all of these subjects in
the system call a and a accumulates a
label that is a join of all of the label
since we're using floating labels this
is the exact enforcement that we want
now when a replies to the calls by all
of these subjects
this used label that a had accumulated
now propagates back to all of these
subjects
so what we really have here is a huge
label that no single security principle
can declassify
which is propagated to most parts of the
system that are not isolated and this
problem is known as label explosion and
this problem is especially serious on
android because on android the component
a could be anything it could be a
service or a content provider component
these are actual android components that
are shared amongst applications
it could be a file that is shared by
multiple instances of the same
application irrespective of whatever
secrecy context they're in
and it could also be a general purpose
application like a pdf reader or an
image editor that's called from many
different secrecy contexts by other
applications this problem of label
explosion is really drastic on android
now we're going to talk about the
challenge of network declassification on
android so like i said before data must
be declassified before it is exported to
the public domain and the network is
considered to be public
now there are two primary ways in which
declassification is being done right now
the first way is to query the data owner
to declassify the data so essentially
you call back the data owner and the
data owner either allows or denies a
declassification
the other approach is for the data owner
to actually specify a small set of
security principles that can declassify
data on its behalf
now both of these approaches are
problematic the first approach is
problematic on android because android
is extremely network driven right you
have many applications that are
continuously connecting to the network
and in such a network driven environment
it is very inefficient to continuously
call back the data owner
the other problem is that when you
specify other security principles to
declassify your data for you you then
include them in your trusted computing
base and this is dangerous other than
that using only a small subset of
applications to declassify data
prohibits the user from using a
third-party client to export data to the
network so the user is prohibited from
using a third-party email client or a
third-party cloud client to sync with
the very servers that any other regular
permitted client would do
so now that you've described all the
challenges i present veer
a different system that provides secure
as well as backwards compatible
enforcement for android
now our system viewer uses two
techniques for such enforcement and for
solving the challenges that we described
before the techniques of lazy poly
instantiation and domain
declassification
now paul instantiation is best
understood in our context when you
compare it with explicit and floating
labels so to give you a brief recap in
explicit labels when p calls q
p and q have to adjust the labels in
order for the call to take place
otherwise the call is simply denied
in case of loading labels the call is
always allowed and the restrictions are
simply propagated from the caller to the
callee and we've already seen the
problems with the simple propagation
now when you combine floating labels
with poly instantiation the following
happens
the current instances of p and q have
different labels and p is going to call
the component q
but this call is not delivered to the
existing instance of q instead a new
instance of q q prime is created in the
secrecy context of p that is with the
label of p
so what we are essentially doing here is
we are making floating labels context
sensitive that is we are creating
instances of different parts of the
system say components or processes or
files for every different secrecy
context whenever the call demands it
so why is this lazy well first of all
like i said paul instantiation is event
driven right we only do it
in succession of a call
and the other thing that makes it lazy
is that the operating system keeps track
of all existing instances and a new
instance is created only when it is
required only when it doesn't exist in
the required secrecy context
so if a new call came in for the
component queue again and in the secrecy
context lp
that call will be delivered to the
component instance q prime that is
already created in the context lp so a
new instance would not be created this
time
now paul instantiation is resistant to
the data leak and floating labels that
we showed before so the figure on the
left is the data leak in floating labels
and the figure on the right is how it's
going to happen with poly instantiation
so again p wants to transfer the data
bits 0 1 to q without actually
transferring the label and q has created
two workers for this job
now note that q's workers currently have
the label have an empty label whereas p
has a label l1
so when p calls q 1 instead of the call
being delivered to q 1 a new instance of
q 1 q 1 prime is created in p secrecy
context and a call is delivered to it
so as a result when the time interval
comes for q's workers to call queue back
only q1 and q2 call q back and q will
always get these data bits 1 1
irrespective what the actual data is
because we always keep creating context
specific instances of queues workers
it is also easy to see why paul
instantiation makes floating labels
resistant to label explosion
since
no single component is ever going to
accumulate labels since we are always
going to create
instances for every different separate
secrecy context you're never going to
see a label explosion you're never going
to see label accumulation in the first
place
also
if we paul instantiate processes which
we do
then you will never have multiple
secrecy contexts coexisting in the same
process for every separate secrecy
context you will always have a separate
process so you get process level
labeling without the resultant false
positives
now we designed poll instantiation on
android in terms of memory and storage
for memory we created separate instances
of processes as well as android
components
in terms of the caller's label
and
on android developers can specify a
mapping between processor and components
so developers can specify a component to
run in a specific process and we can
maintain this mapping in our approach
but per secrecy context so we cannot
really maintain cross-context secrecy
mappings and it doesn't even make sense
because in every secrecy context every
process and every component is available
so that mapping can always be made in
that particular secrecy context
now in terms of storage
we created context specific layers for
each secrecy context to access the
storage
so every label has its own layer through
which to access the default unlabeled
file system and layers cannot and
processes in an unlabeled label secrecy
context cannot directly access the file
system
so for transparent storage access
processes in label secrecy context can
read from any file unmodified file on
the default file system
but once they try to modify a file on
the file system the file is copied over
to their layer and then the future
modification and future reads and writes
are made to that copy of the file
so why does this work on android
well on android the developer is forced
to adopt a very stringent application
model where the application is composed
of specific types of components and
where each of these components has its
own specific api and more importantly
can be called in only a certain specific
number of ways
so all the communication between
components is initiated through a system
service the activity manager service so
this communication essentially is
indirect
when one component calls another
the activity manager chooses the instant
of instance of the receiver that should
actually receive the call
so the caller can specify who to call
but not the instance that should receive
the call so there's this fine
distinction between specifying the
component's identity versus specifying
one of its many instances that must
receive the call
and we extend this exact indirect call
mechanism for a context specific quality
instantiation
now there is also direct communication
in android through the binder rpc but
again for such communication take place
you first need to establish a connection
between two components and for that you
again need to go through the indirect
route
so we can still leverage poly
instantiation that way
finally
i'll present the primitive domain
declassification that we use for network
declassification on android and the
intuition behind this is very simple
so in android's network driven
environment
it makes more sense to reason about
where the data is going to be delivered
rather than what client is performing
the export
so what we really do is we allow data
owners to reason about trust in terms of
web domains on the network rather than
applications on the device
and whenever whenever data is to be
exported to one of the domains trusted
by the data owner the data on a security
tag is simply declassified
we implemented a system on android 5.0.1
and our implementation is open source i
encourage you to check it out
we use the flume policy model the
specific policy model for implementation
but then our mechanisms as we've
described in the paper are policy
agnostic and can be adapted to suit
other policy languages
we ran some micro benchmarks for our
performance evaluation and micro
benchmarks for common operations such as
starting components or reading writing
files etc and we did not notice any high
overhead in terms of the absolute value
when we compared the performance of our
system with that of vanilla android
we also evaluated the scalability of
starting a single component when a large
number of its instances already existed
in the system so we started up 200
instances of a component and then
started the component just to measure
how long it takes to start it and we
noticed a very linear rise in the start
time of that component even for the
final instance where we started up 200
components the
start time was only delayed by 50
milliseconds now in the paper we
described why we described by the start
time of a single component is affected
by its concurrent instances but the
concurrent instances do not affect the
global start time i would encourage you
to go and read it
now we executed a case study with a k9
email application an application that is
a very popular email client and the
objective of this case study was to
separate personal and work email data
within the same application
simultaneously
so what we did was we configured canine
email to use both the user account as
well as the enterprise account like many
of us do
and then we simulated business data
through an application known as bcloud
so we created the b cloud application to
import some business contacts and
business documents onto the device
now what bcloud does is that before
sharing this data with any other
application on the device
it creates a policy and enterprise
policy for his data and the enterprise
policy is a very simple domain
declassification policy
it says that vcloud's data should only
be exported to the domains belonging to
bcloud.com that's it that's the policy
now to run the case study we shared some
data from the b cloud application with
the k9 email application and the data
opened in canine emails compose window
now in the compose ui we added contacts
we had tried attaching documents but we
did not send the email instead
we switched back to the home screen
now we opened up another application and
shared some unlabeled data with k9 email
and repeated the procedure of attaching
contacts and attaching documents
then we quickly toggled between the two
instances of k9 email in both the
context and sent out both the emails
now a general observation was that
instances of k9 email existed
simultaneously in both the context in
the secret context of bcloud as well as
in the non-secret context
now specifically in the enterprise
context of vcloud we observed that we
could see data from the label layer that
is b cloud layer as well as we could see
the unlabeled data from the unlabeled
file system whereas in the unlabeled
instance of canine email we could only
see data from the unlabeled file system
also in terms of network export we
observed that in the business context
canine email was constantly being denied
connections to the personal accounts and
this is essentially domain
declassification in action
now we also observed a couple of caveats
of our approach where we run this case
study now like i said before we observed
that we could see labeled as well as
unlabeled data in the label secrecy
context but at the same time what if the
user wants to see different kinds of
label data in the same context what are
the user wants to see medical and
financial and enterprise in the same
context
in that case you would need an
application that actually accumulates
labels rather than suffers from poly
instantiation so essentially you would
need an application that is a system map
that can be trusted and can override all
instantiation for its uh
for its workflows the other caveat that
we observed was that updates made to
files on the default layer were not
actually being propagated to their
copies on label layers so essentially
what we observed was that the contacts
from the unlabeled context that we saw
in the enterprise instance of canine
email were actually their old versions
the updates that had been made to the
contacts on the unlabeled layer had not
actually been propagated and this is
actually a very hard problem that
results from using a file layer copy and
write mechanism
so to summarize we need diffic on
android if you want to keep using
application data sharing without the
risk of unauthorized data disclosure
at the same time enforcing dfc is really
hard when we can't solve the problems
associated with floating labels
so our approach makes floating label
enforcement context sensitive thereby
making it possible to use on android
that said there are still some open
challenges now we've already discussed
the first two challenges of a
centralized perspective or propagating
changes made to the default layer
the other challenge is that of instance
explosion so an application could launch
a denial of service attack on another
application by starting a large number
of instances of that application and
that is possible and we're trying ways
to rate limit instance creation in order
to prevent that
the final challenge that we're trying to
deal with is that of defining trusted
domain so defining trusted domains for
domain declassification that essentially
is a policy specification challenge
so with this and my talk and i'll be
happy to take questions thank you
[Applause]
questions
uh oh lins fernandez university michigan
um so when you explain uh floating
labels with poly instantiation
um i don't understand why i think on
flyer slide 15 and 16 why w prime cannot
just
uh contact
the
the recipient of the pits
could you repeat the question please
like on on slide 15 or 16
uh when you introduce floating labels
with uh poly instantiation
um yeah why can't why can't that q prime
yeah just contact q
so q prime is a fresh instance of q1
that is created from a static copy of q1
so android components always have a
static definition and new components are
created from the static copy and q prime
is just a copy of the component q1 now q
prime is just like q1 and q2 q prime is
programmed to contact q
only if it has not been contacted by p
first
so since q prime has been called by p it
will not queue back call q back that is
the whole point of this attack now if q
prime really calls q then q gets the
label l1 and the attack is defeated
i see but but um p has called q prime
here right
right p no p has called so the way this
works is that p calls q one but the call
is intercepted and diverted to q prime
and the operating system does i see okay
okay so actually it was a call at q one
right and p is completely unaware of
this he's even unaware of that it has
actually been delivered to q prime yeah
thank you
university very nice work first of all
uh two short questions
the first about the network network
declassification and creating
of labels so applications today uh make
more and more use of web views to
integrate like platform independent
languages
and web users can interact with the
system through java bridge code so
in declassification and creating labels
when you have web views with potentially
different origins do you consider this
or
i mean this could be a cool extension
for or right yes i see a point so
what whenever we start a new instance of
an
application or a component we started
based on the caller's context now if
there are calls from different context
the webview will be re-initialized so we
do
to some extent we do pauline instantiate
webviews but they're just
created as a part of their parent
activity instances okay but it also has
to the wave work back so if data's
coming in from the network you also
probably have to so if data is coming
into the network it'll still coming keep
coming into the instance that is already
active that instance won't be disturbed
you'll just create another copy that
will execute that particular call and
the way activities work is that they
react to the call right so if there's an
activity that has a webview it is also
going to react to a call that it gets
based on what the calls attributes say
okay so it is going to initialize the
babies according to goal anyways and
secondly a very short question um
you create the instances also based on
the labels assigned to files
um
i presume these labels are persistent so
if the file is
if the application that created this
label is de-installed you might have
like dangling labels that right might be
a problem then that have to be cleaned
up or
right so
while instantiation partially solves
this problem so an application can only
leave dangling labels to its own
internal files which are deleted anyways
on android so on android if you'd say
internal directory or if it's your
external directory it's deleted when the
application is uninstalled so the files
don't remain
now when it comes to common files that
the application can write to those files
are still context specific so we are
still looking for ways to
use other applications super user
applications for the user that can
actually allow the user to pick a
different label and view files of that
label so the files would still be
accessible and you're right the label is
persistent so otherwise there would be
dangling cables but that's still that's
still a part of the usability aspect of
the operator that we're looking into
okay thank you
hi great work amir ramadi from
university of michigan uh
the poll instantiation doesn't really
take care of the dead man switch side
channel does it so if for example q1
knows that
it should be contacted by p
in a given time
and if if such a contact isn't made it
knows that it probably gained
that
label then it would then it could still
transfer to q that's so this hasn't
happened yeah i see the point in trying
to make so if q1 knows that it's
supposed to be contacted by p in a
certain time
and
if p already has a label cp already has
a label l1 even if p calls q1 the call
will not be delivered to q1 but it will
be delivered to another instance of q1
so that instance of q1
will be labeled accordingly so it will
not escape the label and this existing
instance of q and we'll still keep
thinking
that
uh will still keep will still be
ambiguous it won't know if the data if p
even exists or if p has made the call or
if we already have the secret data true
but doesn't that instantiation create an
obvious time difference timing side
channel so the time it takes to
instantiate
compared to the time when q1 the
original q1 would contact you there
would be a difference in timing right so
it may so it may create for a
conventional system but for android
where most of the communication is
indirect
application components cannot really
observe the time for instantiation
before they're actually instantiated
so before you instantiate it you don't
know actually when the instantiation
started there is no way for a component
to know when the call was actually made
unless
unless it has some communication with
the caller
okay thank you
all right thank you very much