thank you for the introduction
and as you already said i will be
talking about the temporal linkability
of micron a expression profiles and i'll
start with with a quick primer on micron
a micron ace and micron expression
so actually micron a's
are part of the research field of
epigenetics
and
micronase are small non-coding rna
molecules which regulate most of the
human genes and that means that they
regulate basically what the cell does
and also what type of cell it is
and micron a expression this is just
real valued number for each of these
micronase which quantifies how much of
these micronase are active in a given
cell or tissue
and let's have a look at the most
interesting properties of micrornas
so micronase are highly influenced by
external factors such as aging diet
environmental chemicals
or also childhood development
and as these external factors change
over time also the micron expression
changes over time
also micron expression reflects the
health status of a person
they influence highly how a cell works
and what kind of cell it is
and as such it is unsurprising that
biomedical researchers found
associations between micron expression
and various severe diseases such as
cancers or heart disease alzheimer's
disease and so on
so let's have a look at a comparison
between dna and micronase
so while dna
contains mostly the blueprint of the
body every cell in the human body con
contains the same dna
and so it just tells the cell what it
potentially can do
the micronase
they
tell the cell what it really does and
they regulate the gene expression or in
a computer analogy it would be like dna
is the hardware of the body where is the
micronase are the software of the body
and while dna is fixed over time except
for rare mutations the micronase as they
are influenced by these external factors
they change quite a lot
and dna can predict the risk of getting
certain diseases sometimes
but micron a actually it reflects the
health status and can tell whether you
carry a specific disease at a given
point in time
finally
the last difference between those is
that dna actually has been researched a
lot so far as you can for example see in
this survey from 2014.
so it is quite remarkable that micronase
have we have been largely overlooked so
far despite being so
so influential on our health status
and when we started our research on
micron a expressions and also the
linkability we asked biomedical
researchers what they think about
potential privacy threats
and they said
actually this temporal variability of
these microneed expressions shields them
from any privacy threat and that was one
of the motivations why we also started
with this
line of work
so
this is the end of the primer and
we can go to the actual research
questions i will answer in this talk
of course
this research is based on
micronexpression based data
as it is used in a lot of studies
nowadays and also in hospitals so it's
also increasingly used in the medical
practice
and the first question we're going to
tackle is
that the microneed expressions are
actually linkable over time so if they
are vulnerable to linkability attacks
we're going to look at two different
attacks
i will go into the details later on
so and if
we find out that these are vulnerable to
these kind of linkability attacks can we
protect this kind of data
of course if we protect the data we also
have to be careful
that if you protect the data still
this data is somehow useful for
researchers also for making a diagnosis
so these will be the three main research
questions i'm going to answer
but
let's first of all look at how an
adversary could get this kind of data in
the first place
so typically a person goes to the
hospital they take a blood or cell
sample or tissue sample of that person
and they measure these micron expression
profiles
then depending on whether it's done for
research or just to make a diagnosis the
data could be for example
be uploaded online into a public
research database which everyone can
access
of course they strip off the names of
the patients but still everyone can for
example on this gene expression omnibus
download micron a expression profiles of
real persons
moreover this kind of data is also
increasingly available on the black
market
for example between 2014 and 2015
cyber attacks against healthcare
companies have increased by more than 72
percent and since
already more than 400 breaches
of medical data have been reported only
in the us the largest of them may be the
one of anthem where almost 80 million
records of patients have been leaked
so let's have a look what the adversity
then can do with this kind of data
the first
attack we're going to study in this work
is
a very targeted one called
identification attack
where we have the sample of one person
and we want to
find this person for example in a public
research database
and of course the samples can be from
different points in time
and also it could be that the sample we
have
is from the person where the person was
healthy and we want to find out whether
now
it has a certain disease
um by just looking at
whether whether we can find that person
again in the public research database
and the second kind of attack we're
looking at is more broad and so we have
actually two databases and we want to
find the corresponding samples so which
sample from left hand side corresponds
to which sample from the right hand side
so let's say
and we carry out these two attacks on
two different data sets
the first one consisting of 29
participants
healthy athletes
and
the
samples have been taken before and after
exercising and the time period in
between is exactly one week
and we measured more than 1 000 of these
different micron a's
from blood and plasma based samples of
these athletes
the second data set
we used
contains 26 participants all of them
lung cancer patients
and there we have much more points in
time to be except eight
and the
time period in between of the
consecutive ones is always three months
but you so we measure measured again the
same number of micronase but only on
plasma based samples
if you now would say okay this kind of
dataset seems to be small
actually it's quite huge for these kinds
of longitudinal studies
you have to know that one sample
for example one plasma based sample of
one person at one point in time already
costs several hundred dollars
and also
every of these 26 participants has to go
to the hospital every three months and
kind of just skip
one appointment because of birthday
party or something like that
so this is actually one of the largest
datas that's available out there
and since we have this huge number of
micronase measured
we first process preprocess this data
to get a smaller number of dimensions
and one reason for that is because some
of these micronase are possibly
correlated and the other reason is
because some of these micronase are just
uninteresting for linking them over time
and what we do is we apply a principal
component analysis with whitening
which first of all provides us with unit
variance
also it condenses the data into smaller
dimensional t m and we have to choose
this m
and also the components of the resulting
vector are then
uncorrelated
on the right top corner you see this
rktj and this is just the notation for
such a vector of all the micron a
expression values
of the individual k at time point t j
and then this principle component
analysis
out of this vector produces another
vector where all the components so there
we have only m components and all the
components are linear combinations of
the old vector
and one main advantage of
pca is that it tries to condense the
data into these smaller dimensionality
with minimal information loss
okay let's have a look at the first
attack this targeted one
called identification attack there we
have on the left hand side so in this
illustration on the right hand side but
the left hand side
blue
dot
the sample of the one target victim
we want to find in the database on the
right-hand side
and we use the pre-processed data so
these vectors of
the we get out of the pca and we measure
the euclidean distance between
this victim and each entry in the
database
and we choose that one as corresponding
that minimizes the euclidean distance
so let's have a look at the results we
get out of that
this graph on the left-hand side shows
on the x-axis the number of pca
dimensions we choose so this m
and
on the y-axis it shows the success rate
and that is the percentage of
successfully identified individuals
and the blue bars so it's measured on
the first status of the blue bars uh is
the success rate based on the plasma
based samples and the
potentially red bars but they look a bit
weird here um
they are
the success rate on the blood-based
samples
we can see that we can achieve success
rate of up to 76 percent on the
blood-based samples and the success rate
for the plasma based samples is
lower it's around
30 percent maybe
but still for the blood-based samples
they are able to achieve quite a high
success rate here
and now we compare these plasma based
samples the blue bars
with the plasma based samples from a
second data set
remember that we have eight time points
which means that we can measure the
success rate between all of them for
example between the first and the second
and also the first and the third and so
on and so we can get actually a lot of
different success rates and then this
graph we show the minimum and the
average of all these of these
combinations and all the maximum
and there we can see that the highest
average success rate we can achieve
between these combinations is around 22
percent where there are also some
combinations of time points where we can
get a success rate of up to 42
and if you consider that the
time period between the sample series
at least three months
it's still quite reasonable what we get
there and also comparable to what we had
on the other data set using the plasma
based samples
and if we compare them side by side we
can find some other interesting
observations for example
the highest success success rates in
both data sets occur at a similar number
of pca dimensions
and also if you look at the principal
components we get our
get out of the pca
we see a huge overlap between the
micronase there
and that basically means that an
adversary could first
quite easily guess a good number of pca
dimensions and also knows that the same
micronase probably
lead to a good high success rate for him
okay let's move on to the second attack
the matching attack
so here we have two databases by the way
they don't have to be equal in size but
for simplicity in this talk i will
assume exactly that if you want to know
more about the other case i refer to the
paper
and in the illustration on the right
hand side
i denoted both databases so
as so each database
is a set of nodes here for example the
blue nodes are the is the database from
time point t1 and the green nodes is the
other database
and then we want of course to minimize
the we want to find an assignment that
minimizes the sum of the euclidean
distances
written as a formula that looks like
this
and if we represent this as a graph
as shown on the right hand side as a
bypassed graph we can apply a graph
algorithm that runs in n to the power of
three
and we get out as an assignment that
could look like that
so
we get an assignment that minimizes the
sum of the euclidean distances
let's have a look at the results we get
out of this matching attack
so the structure of the diagrams is the
same as before but now it's the
different attack
and
here
remarkably we are able to achieve for
the blood based samples and success rate
up to 90 percent
again the plasma based samples perform a
bit worse but still
almost 50 percent there
if you compare that with the other data
set again it's quite comparable with 30
percent
uh on average
as the highest success rate there and
there are also some combinations of time
points where we get more than 50
actually
55 of success rate
i can also hear the number of pca
dimensions between both data sets where
you get high success rates is quite
similar
and also there's an overlap between the
principal components
so the main takeaway of this slide
probably is that
we get on these blood-based samples a
success rate up to 90
and using these data sets we also
post other questions
for example
we tried to extrapolate the results for
larger data sets so to see how it
evolves if we would have larger
databases
available
and in this graph on the right hand side
you see on the x-axis the size of the
data set that we are officially vary
and the blue line again
are the plasma based samples on the
first data set and red line are the
blood-based samples and we see that
the success decreases quite sharply for
the blood
plasma based samples but for the
blood-based samples it's almost linearly
and if you explain that to for example
120 participants we see that for the
blood-based samples we still have
success rate of up to 60 percent
another question we looked at was
um how does the success rate evolve
with the time period in between the
samples so if the time period between
the samples is three months or six
months and so on
and so this
is measured on the second data set and
there we see again minimum average and
maximum success rate for increasing time
periods
and
the red line in the middle the average
shows that
it almost stays constant within the
first year and even within the first 15
months
and if we now take all of these results
together and look again at this
common belief of
a lot of biomedical researchers that
there are no privacy threats
i think that we clearly have shown that
there are privacy threats and this
belief is just
unjustified
this was then the motivation for us to
go further and try to
try to protect this kind of data
and for that
we investigated two different counter
measures i represent now the first one
probabilistically sanitizing micronic
expression profiles
and that means we add noise to the data
in a probabilistic in a
probabilistically and fully distributed
and also differentially private manner
providing what we call ep genome
indistinguishability
and to do that we draw noise from a
multivariate laplacian mechanism
and then if we added this noise to the
data the data could potentially be
published online for for example in this
research databases
but sometimes randomization or
perturbing the data is simply not an
option for example if you
want to have a diagnosis in the hospital
the doctors will simply refuse to add
noise to the data because that could of
course somehow influence
the diagnosis and that is not something
you want and therefore we also
investigated the second countermeasure
of hiding non-relevant micron
expressions and non-relevant means
nonviolent for example for the diagnosis
because only some of the micronase are
associated with the disease
and
also this countermeasure has one
downside
i will
go into detail of that
in a second
there are correlations between micronase
and that means
even if you publish only a subset you
could
use the correlations to infer
information about the hidden ones
and as i hinted at in the research
questions we are not only trying to
prevent the linkability of the samples
but we also have to look at the utility
of the data so we want to preserve the
accuracy of a
of classification
diagnosis as diseased or healthy and
usually the biomedical researchers in
the field use a radial svm classifier as
shown in the illustration below so this
red circle indicates the diseased
persons and we have two of them in the
circle and the other are lying around
and then if we add noise to the data of
course
the points could move
and suddenly one person that was
actually healthy is classified as
diseased and one person that is actually
diseased is now classified as healthy
and we want to prevent that and
therefore we measure also the accuracy
of such a classification
on another data set
this other data set has a lot of
participants more than one thousand but
only one point in time and one each of
these participants
has one of 19 different diseases
okay
let's have a look at the results
the results i will present in a second
look similar to that so here we have a
disease for example multiple sclerosis
and a blue line indicating the accuracy
of such a classification
and the 99.2 percent
are the maximum achievable accuracy here
for a subset of
40 microns for example
then we also have a red line that
indicates the success rate
all right and on the x-axis we vary of
course the number of published microneed
expressions
and
for the success rate is in the worst
case scenario and that is
we use the matching attack
and we assume that the adversary knows
the best number of piece a dimensions to
use for this attack
and then if you have both of these lines
we try to find a good trade-off between
the accuracy
and the privacy or the
success of the attack
and for example for multiple sclerosis
here
we think that this could be a good
trade-off
so at seven micron a's the success
decreases relatively to the 90 percent
that are maximum
possible
by 54
and the accuracy in this example
decreases by only one percent
let's have a look at another disease
glioma
the accuracy the baseline accuracies of
these
92.7 percent here
it should be a point um
it's actually below what we had for
multiple sclerosis but that's just
disease related
and
here we can find a trait of
at this position for example
so
we only publish four micronase but we
get a success decrease by 80 percent and
again
as for the case of multiple sclerosis
the accuracy decreases by only one
percent
and
now i'll add to this graph also what
happens if we assume that the adversary
can infer correlations perfectly so we
have now another
line in there
and there we assume for example if one
micronase published in the line below
that now the adversary
in knows perfectly all the correlated
micronase and there we see that
the success can have a gap between these
of more than 20 percent
and so
one has really be has to be careful when
hiding
micronase
that
one also
takes into account possible correlations
and further further research into this
area of these correlations between
micronases needed
let's move on to the other counter
measure the probabilistic
standardization
again the structure of the graph is
similar to before but now on the x-axis
we have the amount of noise which is
determined by the privacy parameter
epsilon
and this is again multiple multiple
sclerosis as we had before and
here we think that this could be a good
trade-off and if we compare that side by
side with the hiding mechanism we see
that
the red line which is the success rate
and is inversely proportional to the
privacy
is here lower than on the left-hand side
for the hiding and that actually means
that the privacy
with the noising on the right hand side
is better
and if we compare it in numbers we see
that
in this trade-off the success now
decreases by 63 whereas for the hiding
it decreased by 54 percent and the
accuracy decreases here by
0.65
whereas for the hiding it decreased by 1
and we can get even better for other
diseases so for example here stomach
tumor
we can find a good trade-off at this
position where the success decreases by
while the accuracy decreases by only 0.2
percent
and if we now take these results they
can look
at our research questions
i think that we successfully answered
the first research question so are
microneed expression profiles vulnerable
to likability attacks
as yes they are
up to 90 success rate
for blood-based samples should convince
everyone who thinks that they are not
linkable okay if yes and it was yes how
can we protect this kind of data
noising would be for example one option
but as i said sometimes it's not an
option and there we propose the hiding
and using the noison we can
often
reduce the success of the attacks
to almost random guessing
and finally
can the candy protection mechanism
somehow preserves the utility of the
data is it still useful for diagnosis or
for research
and
there we saw in our evaluations at least
on our data sets that noising in general
provides a better privacy utility
trade-off
in our dataset for 17 out of 19 diseases
and most often for most of the diseases
the privacy could be doubled
whereas the utility decreased by less
than one percent
so i thank you for listening to my talk
and i hope
that you have some interesting
[Applause]
all questions
we have time for a few questions
hi i was wondering whether you guys have
stefan sorry for microsoft research
great talk interesting i i do not know a
lot about this area my guess is some of
many of us don't
i was wondering whether you've tried to
look at the
economic cost of these things to try to
do like some sort of you know cost
analysis as to when you lose so for
example your statement here on this
slide in the appearance on several sides
utility cost is less than one percent
can i put a dollar amount to that what
does that mean
yeah so utility we measured the utility
as
the so the question is clearly you know
losing privacy uh there is a cost to
that and one way to measure cost is to
dollars i'm not saying it's the best way
i'm not saying that's the only way
that's one way people do it in practice
and and so so you lose privacy on the
other hand doing this kind of medical
analysis we gain something right there
are some diagnostics you talked about so
that's again you can look at that in
terms of in terms of dollars so i was
wondering whether you could do some sort
of economics analysis where you can sort
of trade off these dollars and see what
the right balance is
this seems like a very interesting
approach we did not do this
i think it's quite hard to do it because
how would you
somehow
measure the
the cost and dollar for privacy because
you don't know of real attacks maybe and
you don't know how the attacker
in the end uses the data so it's hard to
measure that
by talking to people who think about
these things like yeah okay thanks think
hi jonathan walsh lockheed martin this
is very interesting i wonder it seems to
me that this could be applicable to a
lot of different categories of this type
of data i wonder if you could comment on
if there are other types of medical data
like this that your approach could help
make these types of determinations and
assist in increasing privacy in those
areas
so yes i also think that it's applicable
to other kinds of data
we did not look into other kinds of data
yet
but we're planning to also
apply this to other kinds of epigenetic
data and other medical data in general
yes
pascal in your counter measures
you use the
accuracy of your matching attack
as a metric for privacy
uh can you make a case for why this
particular matching attack is an optimal
attack for an adversary who is aware of
your defense mechanism
so i wouldn't say that it's an optimal
attack
i would think that
you could
potentially improve this attack so it's
rather a lower bound
for an adversary
and
actually i'm pretty sure that you can
still improve the attack
all right very very exciting and
disciplinary work
well this brings us to an end of the
privacy session as well as and for this
conference let's thank all the first
speakers once again