welcome everybody i'm marco gazelle i'm
presenting
our work on specification mining for
intrusion detection in network control
system michael laboretos where emmanuel
zambon juan aman robinson frank cargill
i want to start with a few words about
network intuition detection so since the
80s
intrusion detection has evolved you know
a number of different approaches
among them
anomaly based and specification based
intuition detection have gained
attention for the capabilities to detect
previously unforeseen attacks
so
sorry for that
if anomaly-based uses
leverages a learning phase to understand
what a normal behavior is within an
infrastructure specification based usage
uses a different approaches
and instead of a learning phase
we leverage some functional
specifications and documentation to
understand what a normal behavior is and
we use this as a reference point of the
reference to understand what is
malicious
specification based
is a nice approach it's a nice tool but
it has some drawbacks
um
sorry
sorry i cannot do anything
one of them is that not only not all the
infrastructures we want to monitor come
with specifications so of course we need
the specifications to use specification
based on money and intrusion detection
the other drawback is that usually
deploying a specification-based
intuition detection system requires a
substantial human effort so you need a
person that reads the specifications and
then manually write the rules that uh
that are included in the intrusion
detection system so our goal with this
work was to heat the deployment of a
specification-based intrusion detection
and
automatically create the specification
rules
okay
so
to do that to achieve that we
design a specification mining approach
and of course the uh
our
our main
sources of information are the network
traffic we're gonna monitor and the
documentation the functional
specification the configuration files
and
an intrusion detection system that works
with this specification mining approach
go through different phases first of all
the intrusion detection system has to
understand what
we have on the network so like
fingerprint devices understanding roles
of the devices and their purposes
then it uses this information to
go and check if there are documents that
explain how these devices should behave
and when we have extracted this
information from the documentation we
can define some detection rules some
specification rules within the intuition
detection system
and after that comes the detection and
of course the alerts
um
so we cannot apply this approach
uh
to all the infrastructure generally
apply this approach to any
infrastructure but we notice that
network control system suits this kind
of approach
so networker control system is a growing
technology and
generally speaking
network control system are those systems
was constituents are sensor and
actuators and you have controllers
managing the sensory actuators to
manage monitor a physical process
controllers
implement the control process by
exchanging communication over a network
as i said network console system are a
growing technology and you can find them
basically everywhere you can find them
in critical infrastructure as industrial
control system in iot smart cities
within building automation system and
even in in vehicular networks
for this research we focused on building
automation systems so all the system
that within a building
monitor and manage services such as
heating ventilation air conditioning
lighting
energy consumption even security so with
smart lock smart cameras
and we decided to focus on these systems
because this is going to be
likely uh the next low-hanging fruit for
crackers so if
nowadays maybe
an attacker need a crowbar to enter your
house in near future it's
plausible that these attackers may
access the houses through building
automation systems
and there are already researchers
that have
categorized kind of attacks you can
pursue against building automation
systems and there was a nist publication
categorizing these attacks within these
three
classes snooping so the idea is that
attackers may want to gather information
within
a building automation system denial
service you want to
make some controllers unavailable
process control subverting when an
attacker wants to completely subvert a
physical process monitor by a building
automation system
um so
we knew
i i talked about these two sources of
information now let's see what kind what
this means within building automation
system
for what concerns network traffic we are
going to monitor bacnet bacnet is a
protocol
that allows controllers of different
vendors to exchange information with
each other as you can see is a really
comprehensive protocol it implements uh
different layers of the isosceles stack
what we're going to monitor is the
bacnet ip so the implementation of
bacnet over udpip
and i want to tell a couple of things
more about bachness so how it works
there are two main
principles here objects and services so
the idea is that every controller every
smart sensor
implements different bacnet objects that
allow to describe any characteristic of
that of that device
such as for example here in analog value
and every object has different
properties
further describing
each aspect of the device
buckness services are used instead to
exchange information between two bacnet
devices so any device can ask
for a specific object and some specific
properties and
make a computation
out of the results it gets from there
from the other device
for what concerns uh documentation well
building automation comes with the
heterogeneous documentation in the paper
we analyze different kinds of them here
i want to talk uh particularly about px
protocol implementation conformance
statement
in fact we noticed that
every
every bacnet device comes
with a protocol implementation
conformance statement document so the
vendors
has to tell
what this device implements of bacnet
and
these documents are just pdf files in
which you can find description of the
device and for what concerns bacnet you
find the services implemented the
objects the properties that operators
can use if they are deploying this
device in this in their infrastructures
as i said we had
other kind of documentation we analyzed
and we used but for a lack of time
i i cannot talk about them so you can
find the details on the paper
um so we know what we're gonna monitor
from one side we have bacnet from the
other side we have peaks and what we
needed were testing facilities and uh
we uh had two build we had access to two
building automation system was for was
at the university of 20 in the
netherlands the other one was at
lawrence berkeley national laboratory
um
to implement instead to implement our
the ids's we we deployed in these two
facilities we used bro framework and we
use also some
python programs i'm going to discuss in
a minute
uh so
with
to to to implement this approach we had
to give uh to the ideas the the the
mechanisms we had to implement the
mechanisms to do system discovery
feature lookup and real definition so
i'm going to go through them step by
step first of all system discovery so we
need some mechanisms for the ideas to
identify community device devices
communicating on the network and
determining the roles and
purposes and
we implemented several mechanisms and
embedded this mechanism within the idss
here i'm going to discuss about a couple
of them
first of all we noticed that bacnet
exchanged a lot of information on the
network that are freely available if you
have a parser that actually
can can parse
bacnet application
messages so bro didn't have this this
feature we implemented the bacnet parser
now is available on the main broad
repository we use this bacnet parser to
analyze the messages
and we use this bacnet device object
analysis to understand what devices
we're communicating on the networks in
fact you can
see a lot of these messages on building
automation systems just flowing around
just because controllers need to keep
information of each other and this is
nice because in this real property
multiple services you can see a lot of
information about uh which is the vendor
of the device that is communicating this
uh that is sending this message you can
find the model of the device so you have
a lot of information there
and
this information actually allows us to
link all the bacnet objects we see on
the network to a specific device in fact
thanks to the
bacnet address linking mechanism
we see that
the bacnet address
gives us an information about which
device belong to which
sorry which object belongs to which
device and this allows us to have a
clear overview of what's going on on the
network
so we implemented this approach and we
were able to
fingerprint 98.6
of all the devices that were on the two
infrastructures and basically 99.9
of the objects we saw on the network
then we used this information to search
for documentation so we
had a couple of choices we could
search for documentation over the
internet so the peaks are freely
available over the internet there are
suppositories for that and we had also
access to uh private repositories of the
operators to find further documentation
so basically what we did was uh
implementing and developing some python
programs that were
using the information and like the
keywords found on the on the network to
search for documentation and pinpoint
which document which which peaks belongs
to which device
and we with this we were basically able
to uh find epics for every device that
was
deployed on the building automation on
the milling automation network
what we had to do then is to understand
what's in the peaks so
we
the the pixels have different templates
so that was
kind of difficult to to parse the pixels
in a
general way but we noticed that all the
pixels shared the same structure so
basically we
again we
developed a python program that was able
to go through the the pdf and just
pinpoint all the information about the
specific uh bacnet device
and with this we were just reading the
peaks and storing all the information
about services object properties and all
the characteristics
and
so we had this information stored and
the last thing we needed to do is to
translate this information in
specification rules that the ids can use
so to do that
we have to
make a reasoning so we
we knew that controllers were very
important on the building automation
system and we knew that these
controllers share some some properties
so there were every controller had a
limited set of variables to fulfill its
functions and all these variables were
of predetermined types and there were a
limited set of services accessing this
variable so in the end we
uh kind of
uh
create and uh
develop this this abstract rule saying
that we want to know which type of
variables are in use we want to know
what which values these variables assume
and we want to know the methods that
that are used to access this specif
these variables
and so the idea is that we had this this
type rule and we
developed a rule that says
what a type is in a building automation
system and for us a tie for example was
the bacnet object or the bacnet property
that are in use
so when we have this bacnet type rules
implemented within the ids we could
automated the mapping of the information
we found on the feature lookup to all
the rules we created so basically the
idea is that the ids was able to take
all the objects he found in the pix and
map these objects to the rules saying
that a specific device can use just the
objects that the ids identified within
the documentation
so recapping we had
an idea we had two ideas deployed in the
two building automation system and these
two ideas were able to
find information on the networks
use that information to search over the
internet and on private repositories
about the documentation that
links to the devices communicating on
the network and they were able to map
this information to the rules we
to the general rules we gave to the
intrusion detection systems
and with this in mind we run the
ids's for two months
and we
had some results so the ideas raised
some uh alerts
and i mean we didn't find any malicious
activity per se but we found some
interesting
activities going on and specific and
it's
worth to say that i mean those
activities were unknown to the operators
so we actually
improved the knowledge the operators had
of their of their networks
and
for example we found
a couple of devices uh using a an object
that wasn't supposed to be there so the
documentation didn't say anything about
this uh proprietary object that those a
couple of siemens devices were using so
we asked to the operators they didn't
know what this was and but then we
figured out that basically siemens was
um allowed to enter to access the
building automation networks and do
his own its own analysis on some of it
of its devices so basically
this object was unknown to the paretos
because it's unknown in the
documentation but siemens has his own
its own mechanism to to to to make
analysis on its devices
and basically i mean this already says
something about what an attackers may
try to exploit without the operator even
noting
even knowing that this is actually
possible because there is no
information on the documentation
uh we found a lot of forbidden
properties so again there were objects
that were not supposed to have these
properties but still we found a lot of
readings on properties that weren't
supposed to be there and all of this
were misconfiguration the operators
didn't know that this was happening and
actually we kind of confirmed all these
misconfigurations even in bacnet because
sometimes backhand gives
errors about unknown property
but in any case even
this activity was unknown to to the
operators
and
the most important thing
uh we found a property that according to
the documentation wasn't supposed to be
writable and still we found a message we
found an activity that was exactly
writing a property in a specific device
and then we again we went back to the
operators we found out that it was an
operator using some custom tool trying
to write the property so it was a
mistake and in the end we were able to
tell the operators that do this was not
supposed to happen
so i want to discuss a couple of points
here about what we found
because we had also
a big discussion about
configuration mismatches
versus security relevant events so what
we found were indeed configuration
mismatches so in the documentation there
is some
the documentation says something and in
the network we found something else but
still i mean what we found
can be uh activities the attackers may
want to uh go through to harm the system
i mean the forbidden properties the
forbidden objects uh can be examples of
an attacker snooping around trying to
gather information from the network and
the writing of course was uh could have
been an example of an operators trying
to
subvert the
system current functioning so
i mean in the end the operators
agreed that this uh
what we found was was interesting for
them and they asked us to deploy the
system stability on their networks
another discussion we had was the it was
about the attack coverage of course i
mean if an attackers want to do
something
managed to attack to harm the system by
playing within the specifications we
cannot detect that so in this case
probably the use of other solution
with the specification-based intuition
detection system we
we implemented
like
anomaly-based standard anomaly-based
intrusion detection can help to
overcome this problem
finally
we discussed in the paper about the
generalization of this approach beyond
bacnet-based building automation system
we studied
a couple of different technologies in
building automation systems like knx and
loanworks and also in that in those
cases we have all the
principles and assumptions holding
because
those two technologies allows us to read
the network again and
the two technologies also
propose some standard documentation that
can help the operators to
to manage their networks and in our case
can help us to build an intrusion
detection system and we even go beyond
that and we studied
how
and if this approach was feasible for
industrial control system in that case
you have documentation
and
and controllers and the possibility to
read the network
and
in vehicular networks again controllers
within the cars that are communicating
with each other and we have also in that
case some documentation that help us to
understand what should be uh what this
communication should look like
in the end i want to say that i mean we
studied network and control technologies
because
this is attack
this is a technology is rapidly
spreading and most of all i mean uh
this
relates to a multitude of heterogeneous
devices and i mean when we have these
uh smart environments with such an
heterogeneity we need security solution
that can quickly scale up to all this
and
manually doing manually tuning security
solutions for that is not gonna it's not
gonna be feasible
and
our approach was exactly uh
paving the way towards this kind of
solutions so we automate the
specification mining and rule
description and we obtained a
specification based ideas that was
really efficient to deploy and was
automatically adapting to the
environment by
understanding what was going on by by
itself
and said that i
will be
happy to answer to any questions
thank you
[Applause]
very interesting work
uh i was i was just wondering where you
plan because yeah i see you have planned
to enlarge what your current what your
current model is but i was wondering if
you have other plans to expand what your
model of specification is
because especially for industrial
control systems a lot of the time you
you want to know that the system behaves
as
as conforms to policy for the
engineering system for example
that particular field might be
within the specification of the protocol
read write
but by the engineering specification it
should be read only so do you have plan
to expand your definition of what a
specification is
yeah thanks for the question uh yeah
first of all i mean
the
specification we the the the rules we
used in the end are many more than what
i showed here but i didn't have time to
discuss them so you can find
a little more already on the paper what
you said about the policies definitely
that's really interesting development
first of all it depends on how you find
these policies we tested this approach
trying to search for manuals for example
and trying to use uh natural language
processing to understand
a little more about how an
infrastructure should behave
if you manage to
find this information on a document like
manual
yeah you can try to uh
yeah you can try to develop so so
typically in industrial control systems
you have the integrator that implements
the system that has a huge binder with
engineering diagrams seeing this
this does this and matches with all the
the the specific registers and stuff
like that so you
this documentation is typically
available at some place
yeah thanks
hi uh greg zabrucha
is any bacnet traffic encrypted and if
it were i mean could your system still
provide value
um
thanks well no
but i have to say bacnet has uh the
possibility to encrypt the traffic so
it's in the standard the interesting
thing is that nobody used them and no
vendors implement the encryption so
basically of course
if the traffic is encrypted and we
cannot read the traffic
all the system won't work but
as far as i know
no infrastructure use bacnet encrypted
traffic
and so devices don't authenticate
themselves to each other absolutely no
that's a
juicy part for the attackers basically
you can probe
freely every device that you find on
your network and you can ask information
on your own i mean you can do whatever
you want there okay thanks
rich johnson and carr
i noticed that um your detection based
on specifications
will detect things that are out of spec
but what if an attacker is acting within
spec and just changing
devices
how would you extend to
detect that kind of activity
yeah as i said i mean we we're
definitely looking at the specifications
so if an attacker knows
that it can harm the system playing
within the specification our
work won't
alert any malicious activity that case i
can say header you have better
specification you can have improve your
documentation if the the operators have
better documentation we can try to
improve our specification
but i would say that it's more likely to
have
this approach working in parallel with
standard and normally based intrusion
detection try to overcome this problem
with a different approach
[Applause]
you