hello everyone welcome to
my presentation
this is actually our recent research on
ransomware it's a follow-up project on
our previous study and ransomware that
published last year at timba
so
the first question is uh what is the
ransomware attack transformer attack is
a class of
malware
that locks the digital resources of the
user and request money
so after a successful ransomware attack
the user has two options one is to pay
the ransom fee with
the hope of receiving the data back or
permanently losing access to the data
so if the user agrees to pay the ransom
fee
he will receive the
private key that is generated remotely
by
the
in the cnc server
and can be used for decrypting the files
this is a typical
ransom node that is shown to user after
successful ransom and a ransomware
attack
depending on the ransomware family or
the geographical location of the user
a different ransom note
can be shown to the user
so
the the attack is very straightforward
and it's very simple and it has been
in the wild since uh last decade but the
recent resurgence of this class of
malware has resulted in
increasing concern on how to detect or
defend
against this class of malware
for example the recent attack on
hospitals across the u.s at least three
hospitals were impacted
by ransomware were on the news and
universities canada were also
was also impacted with ransomware and
last year police department in
massachusetts had to pay the ransom in
order to get the data back
so the there is a
no
estimation about the financial cost of
ransomware but a recent report shows
that uh in just three months more than
two million dollars were the amount that
they
uh made
by
uh data extortion from the user
so the attack is
has a impact
and it's a destructive and make
users suffer so the question is how we
can detect or defend against this class
of malware
there are at least three approaches that
can minimize the risk of ransomware one
is and the most important one is
educating the end user
for example having a reliable backup
policy for the user can help them or
teaching them for
having a
safe
browsing on a web for example not
clicking every links they see or
opening every attachment that they have
in their email
and two developing
tools that help
defenders and reverse engineers to get
insight about internal
behavior of a ransomware for example how
the crypto system works how the keys are
generated
how the keys are maintained by the
crypto system
and the three is
protection approaches that
can sit on the end user machine monitor
the white system and
detect ransomware and kill once it start
encrypting the user's data in our in our
in this slide we're talking about the
second approach which is
a detection tool that helps researcher
and
reverse engineers to
get insight about internal behavior of
this class of malware
so this is our thread model in our
thread model we
assume that a ransomware like any other
classes of malware
can use any techniques to attack the
user for example they can inject code
into the context of benign application
in order to evade
some
well-known
detection techniques or perform
encrypted communication with the cnc
server to consult about the client and
for example
get the
private key the public key and three is
uh
that we we assume that it can use any
customized or
standard crypto system in order to
attack the user file
we also assume that the os kernel the
hardware and software stack and the
kernel are
free from malicious code this is
actually a fair assumption
because all of the ransomware samples
that are in the weld are
in the user mode and they don't attack
the kernel driver in caramel
so
in our approach
and the tool that we develop
is
try to detect ransomware and analyze
them during the detection phase it's not
an end user
protection approach
and it can be
used on top of dynamic analysis system
as a public service
and provide insight about uh the
ransomware and it can be used for sample
sharing about
for
uh reverse engineers for researchers and
uh
for the defenders
so but the question is how we can detect
a ransomware sample
unlike other classes of malware that try
to be as stealthy as possible
in ransomware attacks
that when you are infected with
ransomware you are informed that you are
infected
or there are some uh
distinct behavior that advancement has
because encryption for example is
involved in the attack there is an
entropy change in the content of the
files right
or because the the malicious process
wants to
encrypt as many as file as possible in
order to maximize the chance of
res getting
money from the user
you see iteration over the files or you
see a modal dialogue that shows that the
user is infected so if we use this high
level heuristics and
translate them into concrete defense
approaches it's possible to detect a
significant number of ransomware in the
wild
so the rest of this talk is actually the
introduction of the tools and techniques
we used and the evaluation of our
approach to detect ransomware
so our our approach is
a system that
assess in the kernel
and perform wide
system-wide process monitoring and the
interaction of the process with the file
system
and for
requests like read and write we get we
calculate the entropy of uh the data
block
when they want to
for example
touch a file we i collect some other
things that i'm going to talk about in
the following slides
so in order to
detect ransomware we have to address two
classes of ransomware one is
cryptographic ransomware that attack the
user files and the other is desktop
locker that simply locks the desktop
so in order to
detect cryptographic ransomware we
generate a fake but attractive
environment for the malware to run and
then sit in the kernel and look at the
interaction of the
process with the file system so the
question is
why we generate fake
user environment
there are a couple of reasons for that
the first reason is we want to make the
dynamic analysis system as relaxed
realistic as possible
and two we want to
protect the operating the the analysis
environment from a certain user
environment fingerprinting techniques
that
a malware can use for example and static
environment analysis is very
straightforward for the malware to
find out for regardless of the fact that
the sample is running in a bare metal
environment or in a vm right
so in order to do that we uh we want a
strategy
so
uh
in order to generate the content we
generate files with real uh
and valid content
the
the content look real realistic we
distribute them randomly but
meaningfully on the disk
and the metadata of the files are
designed to to simulate uh
real
user files for example the creation the
modification
and the access time
are designed in such a way that
the malware cannot easily detect whether
it's automatically generated
so we generate the content with and sit
in the kernel
and
run the malware
and log
the interaction with the file system so
we collect the time the process name the
process id
the request in form of irp
the argument of the request
and the entropy of
the data buffer in case is read or write
we analyze a
wide range of ransomware families
during our analysis
and we found that regardless of what
or how a ransomware
attack
the the user and in order to compromise
it or
being installed in the machine the
low-level file system activity are very
similar
for example
crypto locker and crypto wall are
two different ransomware families
but because they were using the same
crypto api they were generating very
similar i o activity in the car in in
the low level uh
file system request so
based on that we
categorize all the samples that we have
based on their file system
access request and we
find out there are only three different
classes based on the current ransomware
attacks and the first one for example
opens the file
and reads the low entropy data and
overwrite it with a high entropy data
and in the second one
what happens is that an encrypted
version of the files is generated and
is
saved in
some part of the disk
and the original file is simply unlinked
or deleted from the disk
but the attacker found out that it's
easy for the victim to recover those
data
uh that were unlinked from the decks so
uh
they changed their strategy and uh once
they generated the encrypted version of
the file
they
overwrite the original one with the
random data
a form of secure deletion
on the original files
these are three ransomware families that
follow
those i o access requests for example
crypto wall
read the low entropy data and write
overwrite it with high entropy data
a file coder
simply deletes the original data by
unlinking from the desk and
the third one world
uses a different
cryptosystem and overrides the original
data with
some random
bytes so having a
sort of secure deletion
function
in addition to
those three different i o requests
because the attacker wants to
maximize the chance of forcing the user
to pay
the malicious process
encrypt as many files as possible so you
see iteration of where the files
regardless of what
extension a file has you see exactly the
same requests among different files
by the same process
that was actually our approach to
detect crypto
style or
cryptographic ransomware
in order to detect uh
desktop locker ransomware we what we did
was that first we
take a snapshot of the clean state of
the system
and run the malware
and
then
capture
another snapshot
of the system
so if and ransomware attack has happened
there is a ransom note that's shown to
the user
and
because it is shown to user and is
persistent there isn't a structural
change between the
the content of uh pre and post attack
images
so we define a score called the
similarity score
that
compares the structural differences
between two images so the the the
similarity score is between zero and 1
the values close to 1 means that there
is a huge
structural change in the image and the
value is close to 0 means there's
not significant changes in the
content of the image
in order to test the system and uh
run the
our tool
to test with real word
samples we use kaku sandbox
the reason was that
in order to provide it actually provide
us with basic
sandboxing services
and we use windows xp for that because
it is mainly supported by
kaku but
uh unveil can be installed on any uh
operating system any windows operating
system
by just attaching to the file system
driver
we use the
windows kernel drive driver framework
which is formally supported
way to
develop
monitoring services like antivirus
companies and the
antivirus scanners and also
backup software use some or less the
same approach
and for those that are
in uh
malware research they know that uh
running and and finding an active
malware is very hard it's not easy
so in order to make
the system uh resilient against this
fingerprinting techniques we actually
what we did was uh making kaku more
resilient about this
fingerprinting by changing certain codes
to in kaku sandbox in order to return
fake response to cert certain finger
printing techniques like for certain
processes or
registry keys
of course there are more sophisticated
ways to fingerprint their environment we
were not able to do anything about them
but these are the more straightforward
approach that we were able to
address
we also
use other
antivision measures
like defining
multiple ntfs drives or changing the ip
address or mac address these are the
things that we did
you can
check out the paper for
more details about
our configuration
we tested the system with our label and
data ground truth data with 3500
malware samples we collected from uh
public repositories anabes
and to security companies
from those 35 000 samples
1900 of them were active during the
analysis
and we also use uh some benign
application including the
ransomware-like
programs for example
uh
this script aes script s delete in order
to make our data set
having
both
benign and malicious data set
this is actually one of the false
negative cases that we had you see
and a structural change in the image
but because it's not the the
similarities score is not significant
because it's transparent
uh we were not able to detect that so
in order to detect these cases and have
a higher
coverage of the data
we perform an
test by varying the the similarity
threshold and we found that at point 32
we
have the highest
recall was 100 precision on the label
data set which means that if we detect a
sample as ransomware it was a 100
percent
ransomware
we also test our approach with unknown
data set on samples
we collected
1200 sample unknown samples every day
from animus
we
created an infrastructure with 56
unveiling enabled machines
on eight servers and ganache cluster
what the
same threshold that uh
i talked about in previous slide
we tested the system with 148
distinct samples and our
approach a new detection is
if
we detect a sample as ransomware
and we
submit it to virustotal
and if virustotal report reported as a
malware or a ransomware
it's it was not a new detection but if
none of the av scanners uh detec report
anything malicious about that we detect
it as
label it as a new detection
we
continue to submit uh the
samples we detected as ransomware six
times to virustotal in order to see
whether the detection rate changes
we define a score called a pollution
ratio which is between zero and one
and the values close to one means that
all the av scanners in virustotal were
able to detect a sample and the value is
close to zero means that none of the
samples were detected
by av scanners so as you see in the
first submission 72 percent of the
samples had the
pollution ratio zero means that none of
them were detected by av scanners in the
first submission but in the second
submission the pollution ratio changed
significantly
and
as you see in the subsequent submission
there is no
significant change on
the pollution ratio meaning that a
sample is detected either by a large
number of
avs scanners or
only by by a small number of them
this is the summary of our detection
result
uh we got
we have false
zero false positive cases uh at the cost
of uh not detecting all the
ransomware in our data set
and uh
as i mentioned 72 percent of the sound
poles were new detection
and we detected uh 9.2 percent of uh
9.2 percent of the sample that we
detected with ransomware including
uh crypto
um cryptographic ransomware and desktop
blocker around 20 of those were desktop
locker
during our analysis we also found a new
uh ransomware family
uh we call this silent crypt the reason
we call this all encrypt was that
after successful attack
uh
it the the process showed an uh ransom
note
and uh claimed that they are silent
team so we used the same name for that
uh what happens with that uh it
performed some
sort of user fingerprinting in order to
see whether they're running in a bare
user environment or in a
analysis or in a real user
computer
and
after consulting with the server and
receiving the key
they started
encrypting the the user's file and as
you see in the third row which is the
right operation it performed
some
techniques in order to evade uh
potential behavior-based approaches like
imposing delays artificial delays
between
uh their operation
after a couple of rides they
uh
imposed some delay and then started
again
we submitted the sample to
av to virustotal and after two days they
started reporting it as malicious
this is uh
also
the google result in that time we the
first one is the
the the submission i had to uh youtube
about demo of the attack the other are
relevant to
google results
so the conclusion of this work is that
a ransomware is a serious threat
and the
unveil introduces
concrete models concrete detection
techniques to
analyze these class of malware
detecting a new ransomware family uh
shows that this approach
is useful in practice and can be used
without implementation costs on top of
anti
analysis anti-malware
tools and dynamic analysis system
uh of course our approach is not perfect
but
we continue to improve the work
uh
this this field of research is an
adversarial research so we try to
improve it and make it a public service
for
to be used by
researchers and
defenders and reverse
engineers thank you so much i would
happy to have a question answer
[Applause]
questions
hi um i'm ryan from google um so i had a
question about your false positive rate
you said that you had like nine thousand
new detections but
zero percent false positives how did you
compute that
how did i calculate that yeah
okay
so for the desktop locker samples that
were around the
300 samples
three thousand samples we did it
manually by just checking uh
the post attack images if we see that
the post attack image is a ransom note
we uh
call it we report it as a
correct detection
and uh
for
crypto style ransomware
we what we did was checking uh sorting
the files automatically and finding
whether uh
there is an iteration of where the files
for example the file the first file
files and uh see the
if the
the content of the file has an entropy
change so in our detection
uh we use entropy to double check our
result we didn't use entropy in order to
uh
as a function as a feature to
report whether sample is reservoir or
not we use it to double check whether uh
the sample that we detected as transfer
is in fact massive or not
like could couldn't you also use an
entropy just to
like detect it as well
pardon couldn't you use the entropy to
detect it as well
uh
as a detection feature so it a
very good question uh the problem with
this uh is that there
can and there are
certain cases that they have already
high entropy for example
the file is a compress file has already
has not very high but it has high
interviews so the change between the
read and write the entropy of the read
and write is not meaningful in order to
report that as a change in the entropy
of the file in order to report it as a
ransomware so we tried not to use that
in our detection but use it as a feature
to evaluate our result
okay thank you
very nice work and just a quick question
these ransomware samples when you run
them on your environment
they almost always immediately start
attacking
um what if they actually wait
um how long do you need to run them
and yeah how do you trigger them okay
so uh
like uh other
um dynamic analysis system our approach
is also vulnerable to installing code
we run the samples for 20 minutes
and
with the assumption that
the
attack will start after 5-10 minutes
but if
it wants to wait for two days one days
five hours so we were not able to take
anything
but if
the sample
start in 10 minutes after 10 minutes of
running the sample
and show
a malicious activity you were able to
detect that
so typically in your experience um how
soon does the attack start five minutes
one minute ten minutes so and we
actually experiment that uh in our
first
phase of this project and we found that
after the seven to ten minutes they
start doing activity this this is
actually what happened in our case
okay thank you
so uh so this is just another uh
question about the nhp um
check
i don't know if you mentioned it but how
many samples did you look at
to kind of get a good feel for what the
threshold should be or
is it comparison for just
a straight increase
well uh
good question uh
for
for the
entropy change uh we
we checked uh
a couple of uh samples like uh
two
250 samples and uh we found that
because the samples that the the suite
file or the honey files that we were
using were mainly text
and we found we we saw that for example
an entropy change from four
from fourth 30
to
that it's changed to
for example
uh above seven means that a high entropy
change but as i mentioned we didn't use
that in our detection because
it it it was uh something that can be
evaded by the malware in future so we
didn't use that in detection but for
example for the text file uh
we were able to
confirm uh that for example there is a
huge change in the entropy this is what
we can say
thank you
all right let's thank our speaker again
thanks
[Applause]
[Music]
you