alright so there's some room at the
front for those just coming in and
you're in room 2 as you know we're going
to talk about X rat so a deeper dive
into X right monitoring China's
interests abroad with surveillance and
with mobile surveillance where so our
two speakers are approver Kumar she's a
security researcher I look out spends
most of her time uncovering and exposing
threats as he emerged in and around the
mobile space and we also have a resume
of scenes at immunity she's a security
researcher and reverse engineer with
experience working in different domains
of security and I'll stop there BIOS
there because I want to give them the
floor and the time to speak to you guys
thank you very much thank you very much
for coming I know it's been a long
conference this is the second day this
is a Friday afternoon everybody has
enjoyed themselves last night at the
party and are understandably quite tired
so I'd like to thank you for coming
along and melting your brains with some
Android reversing so this talk is kind
of linked to the previous talk and I see
a couple of people that were there in
the previous talk so I hope you enjoy
that they're sort of attached to each
other and you saw the big picture you
saw all of the details of the context of
some of our investigations last time and
right now we're here to tell you about
really just a particular mobile family
mobile malware family and go really deep
into the Android reversing and Intuit
all its technical capabilities and
hopefully this is a good exercise for
all our security researchers here so
just to give you a quick overview of who
we are my name is apoorva and this is
our Izu and we are security researchers
at lookout our focus is mobile malware
whether it be iOS or Android malware and
we spend all of our time just as Kristin
showed in the last slide or in her last
presentation that we spend all of our
time looking at the malware looking at
its context understanding how it's being
used but then also just immersing
ourselves in each family
and trying to understand why these
malware developers are doing what they
do and why they do it how they do it so
today we're gonna talk to you about two
different ones
Kristin already mentioned accessor em
rats so I hope you guys are taking notes
there will be a test and then we will
start to deep dive into exFAT and we'll
talk about its technical evolution how
hard it was to actually see that
evolution and categorize it talked about
its communication how it talks to its c2
infrastructure what the C to
infrastructure says to it as well as
some of the context around its
investigation and what that tells us
really about the malware so this focus
of this talk is really about what it can
tell us about the malware how we can use
that context to sort of flesh out more
of the malware capabilities and details
so XS or M rat if anybody could stand up
and just tell me what they remember
about the previous slide but accessor M
rat was discovered in 2014 it was widely
reported it had two components Android
and iOS
Kristin already went into a lot of
detail as to why it was built the way it
was but I'll tell you a little bit about
it again for the new people in the room
so it had an iOS application which we're
not going to talk about at this point
but it needed a jailbroken device it was
a it was installed through a city a
package but what we're going to focus on
today is really the Android component
and that was a two-stage application it
had a sort of benign front and it posed
as a code 4hk application code 4hk is a
nonprofit organization in Hong Kong and
it advocates for transparency within
Hong Kong so it was of interest to a
particular set of people within Hong
Kong as you can imagine it was
discovered in 2014 as I said during the
pro-democracy protests within that space
and during the umbrella movement so it
was a two-stage Android application it
contacted a c2 server called accessor
comm which is exactly where it got its
name accessor em rot em rot is obviously
mobile rat rat for any beginners in the
room is a remote remote access trojan so
it looked like this it was sort of when
it was running it disguised itself and
as soon as it got installed it asked to
install a second application called
system thread basically posing as a
system application on Android and then
it would disappear into the background
so as I said before it was widely
reported and this is an example of a
message that was received by one of the
pro-democracy protesters the people part
of the Occupy central movement and they
received a link something like this
which downloaded a sample of X s er M
rat so there was a lot of reporting
around it there was a lot of chatter
around it at the time and this
particular article goes into how the
code for HK organization claimed that it
had nothing to do with this particular
application so it said we don't have an
Android application and we know nothing
about this particular application which
is how we know perhaps it was they
didn't source it they didn't develop the
application themselves so while this
reporting was going on me and our Z we
were looking at this rat and we were
trying to understand it and break it
apart and while we were doing that we
came across a different variant now
depending on who you speak to and how
they classify malware it's not too much
of a science it's more of an art people
see different similarities and different
code structures and realize totally
different things
X rat is can be considered a variant of
X s er M right but we classify it as a
different family regardless of those
very very specific details we're gonna
go into why we think X rat is different
how it's exactly different and explain
to you you know perhaps some of the
motivations behind the actor and how
they've changed throughout the year
so we're talking about an application
that started in 2014 we've also written
a blog about this because I know all of
you read our blog very very carefully
and have already caught up on this
particular one in 2017 in the middle of
2017 and we've blocked about it
extensively it's not a new family but
it's still worth talking about and I'll
go through why the blog basically talked
about really the high levels of this
initial version of X rad that we saw and
some of its capabilities some of the
interesting things were exactly what you
expect a surveillance where I found me
to be so surveillance we're Kristin
again went through that in her talk
previously but it is an application that
sort of targets a particular group of
people and exfiltrate
as much information of a mobile device
as they can within the context of mobile
malware obviously some people call it
spyware but don't get the two options
confused it has to be I have to explain
that distinction just because some
people will call it spyware but look out
and we we call it surveillance where the
interesting thing that wasn't
surveillance we're like about X rat is
that the last sort of set that you see
over there which says it repeatedly
downloads and deletes large files trying
to exhaust mobile data supposedly that's
runs counter to a surveillance where you
don't want the person to know that
you're on their device but that seems to
be quite a nuisance it it starts to
raise red flags for the user so that's
an interesting point to point out about
extract so let's take a look at one of
the more recent versions and then we'll
talk about the evolution as a whole X
right
in the context of a sample that we
received in May of 2019 has sort of two
main aspects of its structure and
functionality it has a class called a
protocol class which is basically an
enumeration
and it has two things in it it has a set
of things that that have a suffix c2s
which we suspect is clients a server and
another set that is s2c which is server
to client so we call the CTS one's
actions these are things that the client
can execute actions that it can perform
on an infected device and STC wishes
commands that it can receive from its
server so the CT server or the command
and control infrastructure can come back
with 45 different commands and tell the
client or the rat to do whatever it
needs to do so some of these things
overlap but they're not necessarily the
same what's interesting on this slide is
the icons that it uses so again just
like its older cousin accessor em rat X
rat uses sort of the generic Android
Android application to try and blend in
obviously that's the image for the
operating system so it can't be anything
bad but there's two interesting samples
that have a slightly different picture
and the fact that they're so rare and
have a different icon as well as
separate titles may tell us something
about where else we can find this
surveillance where and perhaps what it
was used for the graph that you see is
Lookout data for when samples were
acquired by lookout and you can see the
different spikes in 2017 when our blog
came out again in 2018 and now we're
seeing a much more consistent use of a
malware so it's still being used as
still being handled and and and that's
interesting to take note of it is a
surveillance where and it's a spyware so
it's gonna take everything it can
possibly take from your device and as
we've already established as IVA has
established in her keynote if you take
control of a person's phone you take a
control of their of their lives so it's
got everything for you it's got exactly
what websites you visited who you called
what meetings you had what applications
you have on your device
what files you've downloaded all your
passwords all the files and then
passwords to unlock those files all the
pictures that you have taken of your dog
and your cat and your family and your
co-workers all your recordings of
wherever you take your device these are
not difficult to do but we see these
every day in every single surveillance
where so this is just a wide range of
things that x-ray can do and what
generally applications can surveillance
for our applications can do the
interesting thing to look at this slide
is the WeChat databases in the keikyu
data so x-ray is particularly targeted
to people who have those things on those
devices so it could be people that are
inclined more inclined to use
applications such as WeChat and QQ you
could probably tell that there's a
particular area of the world where these
are more popular than others so let's
get to the act of the evolution of it
and how we decide to categorize it again
it was very hard it's running for a long
time and a lot of these categorizations
was actually very hard to categorize
based on code structure for all the
researchers in the room you know most of
the time you look at the changes in code
to try and classify and categorize
malware so but this was very hard to do
with X rad the code looks largely the
same throughout all versions there are
small minor differences in one or two
samples and those are the ones that we
want to focus on but it was easier
actually to categorize them into three
separate categories which we call
versions and it's based on the
configuration files found in the malware
so we're gonna look at dates of the
configuration files that the date in
which they were last modified version 1
was a little more like a baby its
configuration files were very simple
they were plaintext
they had no office keishon they were
found from they were lost modified from
sort of
December 2014 to June 2018 so even you
know fairly recently there were about 3%
of the samples that we observed it had
some interesting and human analysis
mechanisms which I'll go through and it
had a second stage so version 2 which
comes along next is more like a toddler
I would say it was about 92 percent of
observed samples so this is the one
that's really favored by the x-ray
developers it's configuration files were
des encrypted if there was some sort of
minor office keishon and emulate a
detection within it which again we'll go
through it had some persistent
mechanisms and it had some new commands
and it we see this version up until
today it's quite a detailed one and
quite a change from version one now the
thing that you have to realize about
version 1 and version 2 you can see if
some of the things have been have
disappeared version 2 doesn't have any
anti analysis mechanisms so this is
interesting why did they move away from
that then let's look at version 3 and
version 3 is more like an angry teenager
and it's about 5% of the samples that we
saw and the last modified dates of the
configuration configuration files were
from October 2017 - April 2019 they were
a in ke s encrypted and they used
multiple encryption keys not only one
but you can see that actually some of
the things were taken out and some of
the things were put in it's not
necessarily that it was just increasing
its level of obfuscation every single
time so with that let's deep dive into
some of the technicalities and I'll
start with sort of the quick ones which
are the anti analysis and anti detection
mechanisms so the most interesting one
was the self-destruct functionality
effects rad this I believe was also seen
in MRIs and what it did was it cleaned
up certain files and directories
depending on the sample it could
basically wipe your phone if it wanted
but depending on the sample that you
looked
it cleaned up different files and
directories and that's an interesting
point to make why was it different from
it it almost appears like it wasn't
mass-produced right it was each sample
was kind of created that way for a
reason
it had antivirus checking so it had an
anti-virus check and if it found any of
those anti viruses on the infected
device it would disable all of its rat
functionality it didn't want to be found
it had some emulated checks so
BlueStacks is a popular Android emulator
it's looked for that it looked for
particular IMEI numbers if if you're not
into mobile devices that's the sort of
unique identifier for mobile devices so
it looked for particular IMEI numbers
that are linked to particular emulators
now while this isn't a complicated check
and some emulators probably can get
around it this is pretty good for I
don't know 90% of dynamic analysis
engines that are out there it also did
the usual when I say usual it's because
we see it every day it hides its icon at
high selectivity there's nothing really
on the screen that will let al a user
figure out that there's something
running on their device the last thing
is that it acts it put all of its
exfiltrated data the updates of its
itself as well as its debugging logs all
in hidden folders in the SD card
probably due to size the last thing I
want to talk about is the anti analysis
mechanism so this was really interesting
the initial versions as well as accessor
mrad and crashed the popular tool decks
to jar if you've never reversed an
android application before decks to jar
is a very popular tool used to convert a
dex file which is how an android
application code exists in an APK to a
jar file which can be easily reversed so
what it did was it had a zero width
instruction at the beginning which kind
of threw off the tool and crashed it
this was moved away from
I it's interesting because maybe it it
is signaled that they didn't really care
whether people were looking at it there
are better tools out there as well
perhaps the people who were trying to
reverse them didn't use text ajar it's
just interesting to see and to get into
the mind of the person developing this
tool why did they get rid of that I
guess I'll we'll talk about the
configuration files and sort of how they
changed now hello everyone so I'm gonna
just jump into the configuration file I
prefer mention them couple of times now
let's see what - but but what are they
what do they include so basically
configuration file is a file in the
asset folder of the package it will
include information about the server or
the c2 or the command control it will
include an IP and if include port I'm
not going to talk about version 1 of
this family because as approver said it
was a baby and it was in plain text so
there's no reason to bother you with
that it's readable so everybody can just
like go and look at it
version 2 however it starts encrypting
these information is it in the asset
file the asset file in this case is
called strain dot XML the string that is
used to generate the decryption key is a
double base64 encoded string it's hard
coded in the function that does that
decryption and encryption it's called
this util and the decryption algorithm
that is used is DES encryption these are
some of the samples of the double base64
encoded and des keys that we observe
through these families gonna go move on
to version 3 now so version 3 takes it
one level higher in terms of
complications so in this case the file
is called cantata and I it's still
located in the asset folder of the
package it still includes the CTO
information how
ever this time the decryption key is
also included in the configuration file
it's the first line of the file and
second line is the IP address and the
third line is the port of the CTO server
another thing to note about version 3 is
some of the code is hidden in another
file in the same asset folder this file
is usually called base based on a PK
based at BTC but well the name can
change any time and this asset file is
xor encoded it can easily be decoded
using a key which varies across
different samples these are the two AES
encryption key sets that we have
observed through the samples that look
at acquired okay so now let's talk about
the more interesting stuff commands
commands are what the server instructs
the infected device to do and these are
the common commands across this family
we have reported this in details in the
blog that we published in 2017 these are
typical surveillance word commands
you've seen them approver talked about
them Kristin Kristin talked about them
so I'm not going to repeat the
information but just take a note that
these are all surveillance for actions
requested from the device so now let's
move to more interesting stuff so I'm
going to mention three sets of commands
that approval and I saw we recently have
seen them and we thought that they are
interesting so my purpose of the talk is
to walk you through them and hopefully
at the end of my talk he will agree with
me why they are interesting and then we
are going to make a conclusion of how
they can be used exactly starting with
the first command it's called do
intruder so do intruder the purpose of
the command is to direct the infected
device to make multiple HTTP or HTTPS
requests to an arbitrary host and port
by changing arbitrary sequences in that
request
it also logs the request and response
for certain keywords and if
found them it will report to the server
and also logs the response from that
request syntax of the command is like
that a separator is used to separate the
fields I have memorized the name of this
many times and I now forgot it so it
just looks like that section Marge okay
so the first field so it has the command
that comes from the server obviously it
has certain fields the targeted host the
targeted port that the request has to be
sent to a store path which is a string
to a file system to which is string
which is a path to a file system on the
device keywords don't be mislead with
the program the S it's just one single
keyword there's couple of flags in here
is SSL is R and header and it's a
response they are all boolean type and
there are two fields in this request
that in this command that also include
multiple fields those are requests on
bar and they are both basically 60
base64 encoded so now let's deep dive in
the function and try to parse this
command we are the client we have
received this now let's take it step by
step so first thing we want to separate
the fields so we can take a look at them
and secondly we want to start with the
more complicated ones the ones that have
multiple fields in them so we're gonna
start with war variable it's also
separated by semicolons so we are going
to split it in the same way that we did
for the command then we are going to
generate several dictionary lists
zero-to-four dictionary lists basically
from this war variable dictionary lists
also is separated each field is
submitted by each dictionary separated
by a colon
two fields field zero and field one
fields ero is the string to be replaced
and field one is a stream to replace
that first field so feed one if it
starts with a fine path indicator which
is a slash that means that this is a
five path this is not a stream don't do
not use this to replace the string just
go search the device for this path
obtain the file that is located there
grab this and just try every single
string that is in that file and there
obviously delimited by newline slash or
insulation okay so now we have a
dictionary list we know what strings to
substitute what strings to use us to do
the substitution but where is this going
to be applied so we're going to now
parse the second field of the request
which is called request it is a standard
HTTP request it is separated by Sarah of
two of them to separate URI on headers
from the body if the body doesn't exist
that's fine then the request just has
one line so we are going to refer this
to the original request or or I request
as am Algar calls it so now we are going
to check how many dictionaries or
substitution streams that we get if
there is zero we're just going to go
move to the next function it
interestingly is called Craik HTTP then
if it's not zero then we need to parse
those fields and replace the request
with all the combinations of the
dictionaries this is going to gonna be
done in nested loop and the matter is
gonna make sure that all this all the
strings are going to be replaced so
basically think of the exchanges as
placeholders for the strings to be
replaced so if there's for dictionary
that means there are four places in the
original request that we can replace
with any string that the server commands
the device to do it
so next step we are going to call cray
HTTP we're gonna pass this modified
request to it as a first parameter and
then we're going to use everything that
we used to generate the current request
as the second parameter for information
so now let's dive into the crack HTTP
and see what happens after remember
there was a is round header so this
basically is gonna be checked if the
server wants to add random headers to
the request we're gonna do so by
generating an x-forwarded-for and client
IP and then populating it with random IP
address the purpose of X for the for and
client IP usually an HTTP request is to
signal the receiver of the request where
this request is coming from it's usually
used for the device that are coming from
behind the proxy and so in this case we
are replacing it with random IP
addresses so obviously we want to hide
where you're coming from if there's no
random header generation required then
you're just gonna dive into the next
part which is using that request that we
generated and we will send it to the
targeted host and a targeted port
construct instructed by the server now
next part we had one string it was
called keyboards and we are going to use
that to search the response that we are
receiving from that specific host and
port whether we find this keyword or not
we are going to tell the
command-and-control server about it I
did find it or I didn't find it and
we're gonna log it with the response and
then we're gonna check it's a response
set or not if it is set we're going
we're going to like this and store it on
the path construct instructed by the
server if it is not true then we're
gonna move to c2 - to login everything
for the c2 and this happens every 100
this whole function that I explained to
you is called HTTP files by Malvern so
we are going to call it a fuzzing
attempt ok next command do port MAP this
one the purpose of it is to direct the
infected device to act as a proxy
between two arbitrary who are some port
it's way simpler than the previous
function it only has four parameters two
IP addresses two ports what it's gonna
do is to get the first IP and port
generates a socket socket listen and
that port and do the same thing with the
other IP address and now all it needs to
do is to transfer data between the two
okay I was supposed to highlight it
before explaining it but next command
and the last one that I'm going to speak
about is to repeat this one directs the
infected device to perform an HTTP or
HTTPS requests optionally with a
slightly randomized header and deliver
the response back to the server in a
form that is displayable in a web
browser to repeat a simple targeted host
targeted port to flags is SSL and is
random header and a request again
multiple fields in the request and
base64 encoded so let's parse this
command first thing what does request
include and let's break it into a stand
standard HTTP request we can also do
some trimming on it on it basically
means that if the HTTP body does not
exist which is kind of treated as one
string or one line then we're gonna
check if is random header is set and
we're gonna do exactly what we did for
the first function that I explained
adding x-forwarded-for or client IP and
populating both of them with a random IP
so the replace function here in the code
that has user agent user agent random IP
basically does nothing but generate a
random IP so user agent is just a
mislead so now we are going to send a
request to the instructed host
uninstructed port if is SSL is set we're
going to do so in a HTTPS format and
then we are going to wrap all of the
data that we sent and processed in HT @
HT tml tags and we are going to call it
find out read Val and the next step we
are going to report to the server that
this was being processed and we're going
to basically report that find out read
file back to it so now we talked about
these three commands and you already
have heard me saying HTTP HTTP requests
arbitrary fuzzing and these are the
commands that we previously showed to
you and these are all surveillance word
commands so one good thing what does
this set of command has anything to do
with surveillance for commands we're
gonna wrap this up as my conclusion so
new commands new purpose that's what we
were a probe on I've ever brainstorming
about because so one thing that did not
we could not get was was receiving a
response from server so basically we
don't we didn't have the server the see
tools that we obtained from the Mallards
we try to communicate with them but they
did not reply back to us for any reason
it could have been certain conditions
that we didn't meet it could have been
our geolocation but for any reason we
didn't get any data so because of that
because I have not seen any data actual
data or actual strings coming from the
server or in commands coming from the
server I cannot be certain about what
exactly is intended by these three
commands however reverse engineers
always say the code is there just go
read it and it did read it so the next
step for us is to conclude something
there are some potentially potential
there's some potentials for these three
commands the first important the first
theory that we have is that an adversary
can use these commands to gain access
behind the firewall now imagine you're
an enterprise company you have all the
securities and then one of your
employees is just kind of download one
of these rats and they're jailbroken
Android device are not part of the
policies of the company now that device
is inside your firewalls is able to
tunnel every information outside your
firewall and nobody's gonna know about
it so this actually will be some even
introduced it introduces some enterprise
risk secondly with HTTP request multiple
sending fuzzing everything that can be
used to scan internal networks again you
have a device inside the network you can
just like try scanning sending arbitrary
request multiple hosts and ports around
you observe the response and try to get
some information about what's around
your device and basically just gather
information about okay so if in case of
an enterprise what other devices are
there who else gonna get into or what
else can I do with this information
and after reconnaissance always comes is
there any wonder ability is there
anything that I can exploit here what
version of the iOS server or Apache
server these hosts and ports are sent
are using how can i engineer my requests
to exploit them and the malware can't
just not go and try the it's not for
theory which is not impossible is to
send multiple HTTP requests to single
and single host and port to the extant
to exhaust resources on that device so
basically denial of service or tossing
that device now let's take it one step
further let's assume that the malware
has infected multiple device and now
it's going to use all of these devices
to send
request to one single host basically
distributing this denial of service
attack and create a DDoS attack so the
questions are we think there are two
scenarios possible here so number one
which is stronger is that the authors
are now changing their scope authors of
extract
they're changing their scope servants
fear is not sufficient enough anymore
and they are adding new functionalities
now they want to go beyond servants were
and do other stuff as well Jiri number
two
happens all the time specially when the
malware has simple code other trade
actors steal the code and add their own
functionalities to it so this could be
totally a different actor and it's it's
it has potential for more investigation
and research basically okay so we
process the commands now let's look at
the communication protocol what happens
between client and server I'm going to
take one of the client actions and talk
about Connect which is basically the
send the first connection that happens
between a client a server which is
basically the malware is installed on
the device now the boys wants to check
in with the CTO and say hey I am here
and this is the information that I have
for example this is my IP I'm in this
network if you want to use this IP to
tunnel to other hosts do so so the
connect sends gathers bunch of
information about the device and
constructs a packet that has one opcode
which is basically telling the server
hey this heads-up this type of
information is coming your way next
field is zero it's referred to target
forum honestly I'm not sure what is what
it is for third field is the length of
the packet again this type of
information is coming your way
heads up this is the length of it be
prepared and information is going to be
followed so a bit fine a packet
shows the size of those fields of co2
bytes length target for two bytes length
four bytes and the rest of packet
depends on how many but whatever bytes
that is specified by the length this is
the snapshot of the pcaps in version 1
and version 2 those are the fields that
I just talked about so in version 1 and
version 2 the opcode of the connect
server has changed the target form is
the same the links varies so they may
not be sending the same amount of
information to the server in the connect
function and the rest of it is just the
packet this is version 3 the angry
teenager so this one follows the same
protocol has a command target form
length and final data but for finer data
it takes takes it one step further and
it is encrypted and then gzip stat
information and then sends it to the
server
okay large amount of information and
technical analysis so what we wanted to
do what now was to switch gears and talk
about sort of a little bit of the
context of this malware and when I mean
context there's one apps aspect which
we've spoken about before and which
Kristin spoke about in the previous talk
which is attribution but what we also
want to talk about is what all of this
information and all those small little
details tell us about this malware
itself and also about what more you can
find using this information so I wanted
to give you an idea of what the C to
infrastructure looks like it's still
live today and this is one of the more
recent ones that's still online now the
picture makes it look way more hectic
than it really is it's not this
fantastic it looks like there's actually
something hiding there and there's a
picture and there's some restricted
access and some target located
and from translating very generally
information at the top of the page and
in the rest of the page if you keep
scrolling down which is in pictured here
it seems to be just a blog site it's
it's a website that whole certain
conversations between developers of
different things which doesn't really
make sense but it's it's live and it's
working but and this is just a front if
you take a look at some of the
subdomains it's hiding some apks an apk
is obviously an applique Android
application and this was modified on the
4th of April of this year so even if we
don't know much about what this malware
is doing and how it's doing it we know
it's still being handled it's still
being worked on it's still being perhaps
manipulated by the actors or by the
developers whether it's the same ones or
not web.config web.config didn't really
come back to me with anything and this
is a hallmark of accessor em rat and X
rat the servers are very locked down we
don't hear much from them we can you can
and then this is like built into the
code structure you can send a lot of
data that the server will accept
anything you give it all that all your
data it'll take it but it will never
come back with something or it'll come
back very rarely and and this is sort of
consistent with most of the way that
this actor operates or the actors the
other thing that we can tell with the
limited information that we have is a
geolocation of some of those servers of
course that doesn't tell you too much
about actually where the actors are they
can easily use VPNs and connect through
different areas but what we did notice
is they were about 43 servers that we'd
seen in total somewhere online in
somewhere offline but 11 of those the
vast majority of those were actually
located within Hong Kong and they were
sort of a smattering around in the u.s.
now you might think well this doesn't
really tell me much the actors could be
anywhere but the truth is that this is
actually consistent with XS or M rats so
for years since 2014
seeing the same pattern it could be that
somebody sort of trying to hide and
things like that and these might be
false flags but it is interesting that
certain things remain the same there's
some consistency there which may suggest
that it's still the same actor employing
and deploying these tools then there's
other smaller little things that I
wanted to draw your attention to and I'm
interested to see what you guys think
and what your theories might be about
these things but what's interesting is
the titles of the applications when I
say titles I mean application names it's
when you download something and install
it on your Android device this sort of
words that come below the icon these
titles were particularly interesting and
I'm gonna take a quick look at what
accessor Emre titles said about the
family and as you can see the titles are
very like generic things system thread
and system I am and system ADB which
isn't so weird
which is a little weird but the others
seem to be quite normal right they look
like things that may perhaps be required
by the operating system if you're not
familiar with Android but the one that
stood out especially to the researchers
multiple researchers that were looking
at extra accessory Brad was the second
one on the list there that says code for
HK those were about 11 samples out of
the 1101 that 114 samples that we saw
and and that's the one that stood out
everything else looks generic and looks
Android II and then there's code for HK
which is probably particularly targeted
at a certain set of people that are
interested in that particular
organization which may lead you to
believe how it was being used so let's
do the same thing with X rad and these
are the titles that we saw we saw a lot
more samples 328 and all of them are
again these are legitimate processes
system UI is the thing that runs on
Android so if even if you're quite a
tech-savvy person maybe it might not
raise that many red flags but we'll go
into that later the one that is really
interesting are the last two at the
bottom there and the rendering isn't
perfect on the last one there but
it's difficult to say what those mean
without the context of the people that
are being targeted so code for HK was
really popular right it the umbrella
movement was going on in 2014 there was
a lot of reporting around it there was
so much context that you could see as an
external observer but x-ray it had only
two samples that were whose titles were
in Mandarin or Taiwanese or Chinese some
Chinese language and so what we did was
we took one of those let's say we took
the last one and we threw it into
lookouts data suddenly so what came back
and we found four samples with that
title alone and three of them were the
legitimate application there's a
legitimate application for a website
called Lion travel it's a company that
specializes in travel tours around
Taiwan and what you have to realize is
if you're not within the situation and
if you're not within the context of
where this malware is being used it
probably doesn't ring too many bells but
maybe you're the person who uses Lion
travel for your Tours and Travels and
buys your parents a family trip to
Taiwan and perhaps the people at the
employees that lion travel use a
particular airline or have a certain set
of people that they know quirks and
ideas perhaps they book travels for
somebody important it would be
interesting to go down these little
small threads and pull them and see what
comes out at the other end and that
forces you to think a lot more and
immerse yourself in where these malware
are being used so that's just like it an
interesting tidbit of information which
I'm sure if you pull on that thread if
you go home tonight and pull on that
thread you might find something
interesting definitely reach out to us
and let us know what you think so I'm
gonna summarize our little talk today I
hope you really enjoyed it accessor mrad
we talked a lot about it it's been
reported quite quite a lot it was a
multi-platform tool and it's
masqueraders code for HK it was a
multi-platform
tool X rad isn't too different it
appears to be used by the same people
could there be an iOS component that we
haven't seen yet maybe I haven't poked
the server as long enough
there's obviously code similarities
they're so similar in fact you can't you
almost can't separate the samples
looking at the code structure the
infrastructure is still live and it has
very recently uploaded an apk still
being handled it's still being used
let's find the links that link back to
that perhaps there is a Twitter handle
that's sending DMS to interesting people
about hey why don't you book your tours
to read through this website or this app
so I guess the larger picture that I
wanted to get everybody to start
thinking about is that the mobile field
we know changes a lot changes a lot more
than any other field that we've seen in
technology and it turns out that mobile
authors may need to keep changing their
tool set just as fast and the
interesting thing looking at FX rad so
there are many different mobile families
that keep changing right but why we
focus on X rad was that they didn't only
just keep changing as an increase in
complexity they kept moving laterally as
well
they dropped some things that perhaps
weren't interesting or weren't worth
maintaining they added other things some
of their particular applications had
some commands some of them didn't so
were they really telling tailoring their
applications to suit the people they
were targeting but these lateral shifts
turns out can be just as effective and
the way that we know that is because
it's still being used it's still being
handled it's still being worked on it's
not a dead malware family we keep seeing
new samples every single day we've seen
six in the last 10 days so thank you
very much for sticking out with us it
was a lot to handle so your prize is
little puppies thank you
you