alrights y'all you are in room 2 and you
are about to hear a talk on say free
online sex arm reduction in queer dating
tips so if this was not our expectation
now's a good time to change rooms and
the talk will be led by norman Sherman's
Norma Seamus is a security and privacy
RM reduction specialist they work with
activists globally and they have a focus
particular focus on sex workers queer
trans and gender non-conforming
communities norman works as an
independent consultant and they are a
member of open privacy's board of
directors so yeah before it's really
great to be here at North sac and to
have actually a day where we had a
keynote that was talking about some of
these issues of users and the talk right
before with Alyssa talking about some of
the ethics that are involved so I really
appreciate that this is I'm here at this
track in that sense and before I
actually dive into the topics I wanted
to start with a Content Advisory and I
know we have the code of conduct but I
want to just make make sure it's clear
that this is a sex positive talk that
focuses on marginalized communities so
my intention is to have this be an
inclusive space that's free from stigmas
around the use of tech for sexuality and
with this since I'm talking about harm
reduction my work draws on examples of
sex work sex education and drug use
homelessness in sort of a broad big
picture sense and it's there's nothing
explicit or graphic in terms of
discussions of sex acts or drug use but
I want just to give people a heads up
that that's part of what we're gonna be
talking about so actually as Elissa
hopefully sort of frame things I want to
have an idea of who's thinking about the
users in tech right now is there anyone
in the room that's actually working or
aimed at users so I see a couple people
let's have like maybe one or two people
just do a quick shout out of what
they're doing
here please raise your hands cuz my
visual memory is not the best oh okay
well I'm Florence I'm working with query
't were basically were building website
for queries in a feminist aching of way
to give them at work I was online is
pretty awesome I'm Harlan I work for the
United States digital services and we're
helping remember people who live in the
u.s. better access government services
of all kinds hi I'm Maggie I'm a Mozilla
fellow this year and I'm also Tori's
user advocate and I'm also working on
anti harassment initiatives awesome yeah
thanks everyone for who sort of shoutout
for sharing and in part when I was
thinking about this is that we have also
be sorta like large categories and I'm
not certain if everyone who sort of
spoke up what their exact role is but we
tend to have like UI UX designers we
have people on the product teams that
are thinking about features we have
policy folks that are thinking about for
example anti-harassment policies what
they look like but the security team is
generally not thinking about the user or
if they are their thing about the user
in a way that might not be the most
positive you might be thinking about the
user as a potentially malicious actor on
a trusted network using language like
that insider threat maybe right that's
the sort of language that security folks
use so the question really comes down to
who's thinking about the users safety
security and privacy in tech and this is
the question that I've been interested
in with my work in tech in particular
but it comes from before that because
I've worked with in marginalized
communities for quite a long time and in
those spaces Tech is not necessarily a
solution but it sometimes a new form of
oppression or a new risk that comes out
so how are we actually sort of grappling
with this and we see examples that even
though they're people who are thinking
about this they're not necessarily doing
a good job we see for example with uber
they had sent out this email recently
which is a check your ride every time a
mail to remind people to make sure
you're getting into the correct uber so
that you know they're telling you to
check the license plate the make model
the drivers photo and it's actually it's
really nice that they made this but the
context of why they made this email was
someone got murdered for not getting
into an uber for someone they thought it
was an uber and it wasn't and it also
the way that there was have responded it
only focuses on a very specific scenario
one where the user is inherently at
fault
it doesn't look at or talk about some of
the other publicly discussed cases that
have happened with things like driver
assaulting users with things like
drivers going out of their way to make a
higher fare things like that and I'm
sure that some of this has to do with
the question of liability which I know
again came up a lot during Alyssa's talk
and that's something that is I'm sure
again in the back of the minds of all of
these companies with how can they do
some this messaging with that
another example is around what we talk
about cyber flashing so there have been
high-profile cases of airdrop being used
to send people images so the example of
what this looks like is the the middle
picture with the censored phallus
there's a headline from from Huffington
Post that notes you know that again this
is a sexual offense and a recent article
from Rob pakora raro who's saying in
this article that Apple could fix the
airdrop issue with some technical fixes
and this has been something that has
been an issue for like four or five
years now this is not a new issue and
it's really interesting because some of
the technical fixes are not necessarily
very difficult one of the things that
Rob mentions in the article is
you can have a time limit for accepting
from everyone but most people often
focus on the user should have known sort
of like terms and services but or the
user has the control and they've just
configured it improperly so you know
these are some of the people thinking
about users and tech and security and
perhaps another high-profile case is
grinder grinders been getting a lot of
flack recently and most recently with
this article talks in part about the the
current case of Herrick versus grinder
in the US that's about a grinder user
whose ex created a fake profile and sent
a bunch of people for hookups to to the
plaintiff and this gets into me like a
very complicated case that involves
what's the platform's liability with
this that has now been a lot of
discussion in in the US and other places
but it sort of opens up this idea or
this perception that with these sort of
continued issues that platforms are not
thinking or don't care about user safety
so how can tech or security better
support user safety and this is where I
enter and I come from this approach of a
harm reduction approach and I know I'm
not the first person to talk about harm
reduction within security the I think
one of the earliest examples is in 2012
violet-blue gave a talk about harm
reduction focusing on hackers as a
population for harm reduction work has
anyone seen that talk there's so there's
only a couple of people so I just wanted
to put that out there that there are
other people to potentially go see which
is really great but I'm also taking a
slightly different focus because I'm
focusing directly on the end users of
the app and not on the hackers
themselves and to start with harm
reduction I like to start think about
where it came from this tweet
very helpfully to me enlike succinctly
notes that harm-reduction was started by
sex workers queer and trans people of
color people who use drugs people in the
streets saving their own lives and all
the intersections thereof not by public
health folks and they note sort of
respect the origins because when people
talk about harm reduction they
immediately go to talking about public
health because the public health
programming is where harm reduction has
really entered into policy and so those
become the very easy examples for people
to think of but my own experience and
approach really comes from working with
marginalized communities and being a
member of some of these communities so
that's I have potentially different
perspective than just this policy route
and my work is deeply indebted in that
sense to these communities that I've
been a part of so the aspects of harm
reduction and a quick and easy way of
thinking about it is simply that it's
aimed to minimize harm from activities
these activities are usually illegal but
they don't have to be it's explicitly
opposed to stigmatization and judgment
around the activities and this is a
really important point because so often
people who for example use drugs might
be stigmatized and say that they deserve
it whatever happens because they're
using drugs it's not about ignoring the
harm that happens from activities so
it's very upfront about that and it's
about putting the power in the
communities those at risks in their
hands and there's even recognition of
new forms of harm that can come with
harm reduction approaches what I mean by
that is for sex workers who carry
condoms if you carry more than like two
condoms and you're stopped by police
that can be used as evidence of
prostitution so you know using harm
reduction methods like using condoms
when you're meeting with someone to have
sex with them can also then be a
way to put someone at a new risk so harm
reduction is also upfront about that the
the key parts are also at sort of a
higher level is that they're opposed to
abstinence approaches so saying that
it's either this or that you know you
can only have one of the other and it
also recognizes the larger structures
and systems that are in play and that
means that you're taking an inherently
intersectional approach or you're
looking in a broad way at what's
happening what's harm reduction for a
white sex worker might be different than
what's harm reduction for a black sex
worker because of the way that the
police interacts with the sex worker for
example so part of this is that the fact
that harm reduction inherently
recognizes the power of pleasure and
when I'm talking about pleasure here I
don't necessarily mean just sex drugs it
can be a more abstract idea like being
able to dress or be the person that you
want to be or how you feel you are it
can be you know the ability to take time
off of work and just like have some
downtime right so when we when we put
things in this approach that says you
have to either do something that's
pleasurable or you have to be safe most
the time people are gonna do what's
pleasurable and so it creates again this
this danger potentially where people
might know risks but say essentially
the risks because what's
pleasurable is more important and no
one's trying to tell them that there are
other options and so I'm going to run
through about four examples of harm
reduction programs to give an idea of
what this looks like in practice the
first one our needle or syringe
exchanges and this is one of the classic
examples of harm reduction and when we
think about this from a public policy
perspective or public health perspective
one of the goals of needle exchange
programs is to reduce the spread of HIV
of hepatitis and other blood borne
illnesses and the basic idea with needle
exchanges is you either go to a place or
potentially like a van but you're able
to give use needle and get a new one
usually for free there might be some
like small costs involved but the goal
is that way you're not sharing needles
and if someone's infected you spread an
infection to a lot of people it's not
trying to get people to stop doing drugs
or the other uses of needles and
initially these were actually seen as
illegal people doing needle exchanges
and syringe exchanges were could get in
trouble with the law because it was seen
as supporting drug use right and you
know part of this as things have moved
forward part of the goal of needle
exchange programs has been to change the
laws so nowadays most needle exchange
programs are legal and Canada has even
started piloting needle exchange
programs in prisons which is pretty
radical actually that they're having
this recognition and they're willing to
sort of go that step and that has like
governmental support and so the so we've
moved forward to make what they're doing
more acceptable and oftentimes people
are working at these stigmatizing drugs
at large so working on things like
decriminalization or legalization
another prime example of harm reduction
programs are safer sex and reproductive
justice and usually people talk about
this is just safer sex but I think
within the u.s. context of what's going
on right now with abortions it's really
important to note that part of this
includes safe access to abortions and to
other things that are linked to
reproductive justice into linked to like
family planning that's also a big piece
of harm reduction so I'm assuming some
people have had some variation or have
been exposed to some variation of safer
sex education through knowing that
condoms might be a thing but sometimes
these also don't go far enough there are
additional types of protective equipment
prophylactics like dental dams and
others
people use there's things like prep
which is pre-exposure prophylaxis to
help spread HIV and that's been actually
very effective and there's also having
access to regular STD STI testings to
help ensure that you're not spreading
infections so those are some examples of
harm reduction programs within the safer
sex and reproductive justice world but
there's also things that are will say
human or behavioral practices that
people are able to adopt and this can
include things like negotiation of
sexual encounters prior to having sex
with someone and this is very common
within kink communities to ensure that
you have things like safe words set up
so while you engage in sex that might be
more dangerous you're able to or
actually seen it's more dangerous to be
able to sort of stop pause and you know
cease the activity to help make sure
everyone is okay
it can include things like sex workers
charging less for someone to use condoms
because economics is a reality it can
include things like not brushing your
teeth or flossing before or after oral
sex and even though that's a relatively
minor risk of exposure usually when you
brush or floss you do have a little bit
of bleeding in your gums so again
there's all of these different types of
sort of small practices that are built
into the harm reduction approach and
sorry I know I can do like a whole pride
talk on the sex ed but we're gonna like
you know sort of move on but if anyone
has any of these questions I'm happy to
talk afterwards or around and another
example and this is moving away from the
traditional examples that people talk
about - talking about homeless
communities and a lot of my experience
comes with working with homeless youth
and a drop-in center is a place that's
not a shelter but where someone can go
during the day to get services and some
of the services that they provide are
like access to food clothing medical
supplies it can be computers so they can
communicate with people so they can
create resumes it can be a mailing
address
in the in the US I'm not sure how
accurate it is in Canada but in the u.s.
mailing addresses are still a necessity
to get certain parts of government
services so having a mailing address is
really important they can offer skills
building opportunities one of the the
places that I'm familiar with used to
have a screen printing workshop for
example where homeless youth can help
gain actual like sort of vocational
skills or learn how to do screen
printing and they if they sort of did it
long enough they can also create their
own art so they're given opportunities
that expression and they actually made
money off of this they gain not only
skills but they gained a form of sort of
economic independence and some of them
will even offer street outreach after
their clothes will go out and they'll
provide things like the access to food
though clothing medical supplies they'll
provide that to people living on the
streets who might not come into the
drop-in center and the last example I
want to give is humanitarian assistance
for border crossings so this example is
quite specific to an organization in
Arizona called No More Deaths
or No Mas more at this and they've hit
the news actually recently in the u.s.
because the folks that are working for
no more deaths are being targeted for
surveillance and harassment by police
and other legal cases for doing this
work and what the work that they
primarily do is so exactly what you see
up here on the screen they provide food
and water for people crossing the desert
and having lived in the desert I can
tell you even in city centers where you
can easily go and pick up water from
like a gas station or a corner store
people die every year from dehydration
and heat so if you then imagine you're
crossing a desert where you don't have
that kind of infrastructure support how
important the water is for people to be
able to stay hydrated and continue
walking and at the moment there's a lot
of again a lot of Congress
nations around what's what's going on
there's a lawsuit about whether this is
considered legal or illegal activities
the organization says that what they're
doing is legal and they provide legal
supportive services
but it's an example right now of what's
of some of these conversations is sort
of in real-time as something that's not
necessarily explicitly called harm
reduction in the same way that other
public health programs are is being
debated
so harm reduction is inherently radical
if you hadn't picked up on that well we
were talking about no more deaths
there's been this very strong xenophobic
anti-immigrant anti-migrant rhetoric
cropping up in the US and globally it's
not just in the US unfortunately and so
while the media and other policy folks
are trying to dehumanize people who are
crossing and part of this is language of
saying you know illegals that the goal
of no more deaths again is simply to
view them as humans who deserve to live
and provide water and that's really
radical in this context and in this day
and age and harm reduction actually does
exist in the in the text space as well
and so I want to show at least a couple
of examples so that we can you know see
some of these ways that this is already
being integrated the first one is
talking about sort of social media and
privacy I have a tweet here that I wrote
a while ago in response to research that
Dragonic Arion did on the surveillance
and intimidation against people
live-streaming police brutality in the
US and the the tweets just simply noting
how important it is to have access to
live streaming into social media
platforms beyond just connecting people
because this is about preserving
evidence right and why people who have
been advocating for delete Facebook
which has been such a common refrain
especially after the Cambridge analytic
conversation just doesn't work in those
situations but it goes beyond jazz
sort of preserving evidence it links
into the way that we think about
connection as well I I tend to do a lot
of work in places where Facebook's free
basics which used to be called Internet
org is active and what that means is
that there's people who have free access
to Facebook they have free access to
like Instagram but they don't have free
access to email so things like Facebook
become a very important way for people
to connect to each other to family to
family abroad things like that so when
we talk about things like delete
Facebook we're also than assuming you
know there are alternatives that we have
and so part of this humanization process
is noting these other sort of examples
and thinking about these people you know
that we're not necessary part of their
group but we can see them as deserving
of connection in the same way that we
are the other example is talking about
intimate images what people might talk
about is revenge porn and a very common
refrain I hear is if you don't want your
nudes online just don't take them or
don't send them and this is to me a
perfect example of this abstinence
approach within tech it's saying that
you can either do something like you
know send a send a sext or you can sort
of not there's no in-between and it
ignores the way that sending nudes send
sexting people can be an important piece
of someone's self identity it can be a
way that someone can help feel okay with
their body and have body positivity and
really again really powerful ways of
identity and things that are really
important beyond perhaps just pleasure
and sort of an intimate moment between
other between individuals who are at a
distance and there's an organization
called coding rights that has an awesome
zine called safer nudes that talks about
this and does a very positive sex
positive take on it so I highly
recommend if you do sext or you're
interested in safer ways in terms of
talking people about sexting to take a
look at that zine and I want to
highlight also the Facebook's response
to revenge porn because this was quite
controversial but they were actually
trying to do harm reduction at a
platform level whether they talked about
it that way or not that's really what
was going on and so Facebook's response
if you're not familiar was saying send
us your nudes and we'll hash the image
and if that hash appears we'll like stop
it from being uploaded or spread and
again it's really great that they're
trying to do this harm reduction
approach it's unclear if you they a they
talk to people and like sort of built
and designed with them and supposed to
just talking to people and then building
on their own and it also ignores the
fact of like trust and the world that
Trust plays in this and whether people
actually trusted Facebook enough
especially with some of their other
issues but it meets a really great
example of moving away from this
conversation of perfect security or
perfect privacy that we tend to talk
about so before I jump into the case
study I just want to see if there's any
questions about the harm reduction
approach cool if I can happen let's make
it a video hashed and kept off of
Facebook because it's revenge form porn
can I also submit the video documenting
the police abuse and have that kept off
of Facebook as revenge porn sorry I I
might I might not be following well I I
can rephrase but yeah it was if we send
some content to Facebook and we
determine like this would be
objectionable to have it shared because
it's an intimate photo well the same
technology could be used to censor any
Content that they would deem
unacceptable got it yeah I mean so yes
so we're the this comes down to a
perhaps a approaches right and this is
where I'm talking about the Facebook
revenge porn is will say an example not
necessarily an example that want that
needs to be followed or
the only way of you know sort of going
about this because like you bring up
there are there are issues of them being
able to potentially censor or use this
as a way of having you know using let's
say AI I mean learning other things to
automatically remove content and some of
this actually you saw with YouTube but
taking down videos that were evidence of
human rights abuses and war crimes
because of like sort of AI and things
like that so again in the same things
that are used potentially for some of
this harm reduction stuff can also be
will say misused in sort of other ways
the the key difference or the key thing
I would like to sort of promote with the
thought of harm reduction is how harm
reduction is aimed at putting the voices
of the at-risk communities at the
forefront so one of the reasons I noted
it was unclear whether Facebook designed
this with people who have had
non-consensual spread of intimate images
is because if they didn't really Center
those voices and design with them I'm
not sure whether that's gonna be a
long-lasting or a good solution right
and so if our goal is to sort of really
reduce harm and build something that
will last that's not gonna necessarily
the right route does that help
cool we can talk afterwards so okay so
let's uh let's jump into the start was
there another hand that I saw oh
sorry my computer just went to sleep so
we'll jump into the the case study in
just a second and so we're talking about
queer dating apps here and this work
really comes from a project that was run
by asana regos from article 19 and
looking at apps and abuses that were
going on in Egypt Lebanon and Iran and
so I wanted like also like preface is
right now that even though I'm the one
here talking about this there are so
many other people that were involved in
this project that I'm not necessarily be
able to name them in part do like safety
issues but like this is not like me
doing all of this work and there was an
entire coalition and people who like
volunteered time to do this so the
background of this is it really started
back in 2014 in Egypt after al Sisi took
power there we had reports of using
social media and apps like Grindr to
trap gay people and we were told that
this was linked to geolocation and at
the time you had include security had
published their research on tinder and
geolocation another researcher created
Grindr map that was able to identify and
locate users of Grindr and the apps had
actually responded or said gay dating
apps had respond it's like scruff Hornet
Grindr all did like user safety
awareness little pop-ups and so we're
jumping in and starting sort of slightly
from that or we designed from that and
we started with the users that was that
was our main goal and we wanted to
basically help them connect queer folks
connect in these countries and if they
want to hook up to do that but our main
goal is to understand again what's going
on and how their connect
so our methods we used a lot of
different types of methods landscape
overview so this is like desk research
tech usage and awareness survey and
again that had heavy framing on
geolocation features that's probably the
least qualitative part of our
methodology we did interviews including
sort of group conversations we had a
legal review of court cases we did
security and privacy analysis and we had
this direct collaboration between the
security privacy experts I should put
experts in quotes because there's lots
of sort of questionable advice that's
given and the queer communities
themselves and in particular for the
interviews those were actually run and
helped designed by some of the different
vocal groups that we worked with I'm not
going to name them right now due to time
but if you were interested there are a
few that are public and so our initial
results showed that it's not only dating
apps that were being used for hookups
and dating and this was especially true
in Iran due to censorship and so things
like Grindr were censored so people
tended to use things like Instagram you
know cuz you used what you have
available to you
participants were largely aware of the
risks they were even doing things like
GPS spoofing and sort of other methods
to try and protect themselves the GPS
spoofing is a little questionable
because sometimes people would roots or
jailbreak their phone which could expose
them to greater security risks so that's
like also part of this harm reduction
approach is noting that by not giving
advice people could unintentionally
putting themselves or making themselves
insecure putting themselves at greater
risk or danger there was also this
tension between anonymity and the lack
of trust among users and I highlight
this because we didn't really go
necessarily anywhere but I think this is
a common conversation that's going on in
all these platforms how do you think
about like sort of authentication of a
user beyond let's say like a password
right so you can know if it actually is
a person if it's a bot and then how do
you build that trust
in these digital spaces and perhaps in a
fun way the participants weren't only
interested in digital risks they wanted
other information about you know sex add
legal as well so I'm going to go through
a couple key results the first one is
that participants wanted to use the apps
despite the risks and this is I think
probably the most important result when
thinking about why take a harm reduction
approach the typical approaches to
security we're not addressing the
participant needs there was a lot of
conversation about like why don't you
use encryption why don't you just update
your phone and they were based like
that's not that's not what's going on
here and in part because the primary
risk were other users on the platform
and so that's one of the reasons when
you were perhaps starting to think about
why traditional security advice was not
working is because they weren't thinking
about the risk that the users were
facing they were thinking about perhaps
like risks to the system right and the
app platform so again something like
end-to-end encryption or using something
like signal or another secure messenger
would have done nothing to mitigate the
risk of the other user being malicious
and this one actually really surprised
me is that people like book the
location-based aspect and the reason
that this surprised me I think is part
because within the larger conversation
around privacy in the US and Canada and
Europe we tend to be so anti
location-based services we talked about
it as creepy all of that but what we
what we were learning is that vocation
is really important for safety decision
making for some people they want to be
able to meet up with people in their
area so that way they can meet up in
person for other people there was a risk
because you might be able to be
identified based upon your last name of
having meeting up with people in too
close of proximity so you'd want to make
sure to meet up with people further away
so you might not communicate actually
with someone who's close to you
there we go so and so we also did like I
said we also did this legal analysis and
asana
the principal investigator as I
mentioned earlier is the one who really
developed this methodology around sort
of looking at the evidence but we can
sort of think about it as legal
forensics trying to pick up the pieces
of what we saw with what was being used
to understand sort of what's going on
and to be able to identify things to
waste to reduce harm from what's the
evidence that's being used and the what
we saw were that accounts were created
explicitly for entrapment or identifying
suspects and so that can be people will
say infiltrating a group message apps
screenshots and water marked pictures so
some of the apps used to have watermarks
were used for blackmail potentially for
like blackmail are also blackmailed to
arrest someone and since the context
that we're talking about did include
checkpoints having the presence of the
app on the phone was a risk in itself
because at a checkpoint someone might
take your phone say open it and they'll
flip through and they'll say oh you have
Grindr or you have whore net or you have
these images and so that was also a key
risk perhaps like importantly and
similar to some of the conversations
with sex work and how sex work is
policed is that no sexual activity was
needed for the arrests so they had other
ways of going around this so even in
places where homosexuality wasn't
outright outlawed they used other other
laws and again there were other ways of
bending the laws or interpreting the
evidence to be able to do arrests so we
found that understanding the digital
evidence was action a central point to
basically understanding sort of
adversary methods or what's going on and
so if we hadn't done this we couldn't
have made some of the recommendations
that we did so in the one of the key
recommendations that we had was this app
cloaking feature and app cloaking is
something that came from work that was
done by the Guardian project and the
guard
project had designed for Android a way
to change the icon of the app so it
didn't look like you know that original
icon and so again if space is just
changing the app icon and that was a key
recommendation especially for that part
of having that presence of the app on
your phone to follow best practices for
Transport Security and I sort of chuckle
as I say this because if we think about
where the ethics involved and like
trying to build some of these things in
through the process this is
theoretically something that should have
been done from the very beginning at the
time that we did the research in the
conversations none of the apps had used
SSL pinning and/or certificate pinning
and I don't think any of them were even
using HTTPS or secure transport for
their images for their media servers um
which is which is huge when we know that
images are being used as evidence
working with the local community is like
a key one as well and that goes to parts
like centering those at risk and
increase the safety with the geolocation
feature and we provided some potential
recommendations but we also noted that
this needs a lot more research so we can
we were not saying to get rid of the
location feature which is part of the
initial response in 2014
apps would also at that point time give
you the option to turn off location
services so you're not reporting your
location to the app so within the
implementation what we had sort of done
as a results of this I should say other
than coming up with that list of
recommendations we actually worked with
Grindr to implement some of the
recommendations and among the fun things
that came out of that is a new method
for app cloaking on iOS as I noted the
Guardian project had only done work on
Android but with the work that we had
done we had now not again a new way of
doing this for iOS which was sort of new
research or a new feature in that sense
and the creation of non tech resources
again these are things that were
requested by by the communities that we
talked to so context specific legal
information localized sex health fact
sheets and these were in the languages
that they spoke
so the question is where do we go from
here in terms of harm reduction like
what's how do we actually apply this in
practice and I think one of the first
things is to recognize that security
privacy and safety are not binary and so
again there's not this idea of a perfect
security or perfect safety or perfect
privacy that there are there's the
spectrum and that you know people will
do their own analysis around this focus
on understanding and humanizing
the users so often we I think
stigmatized and we don't think of the
users as humans and I know that this is
part of the role of designers but not
everyone has designers and even when we
have designers they're not necessarily
doing the best job when it comes to the
humanization part in part because
they're building personas and other
things that develop mental models that
might exclude other users right and so
there is already a tension within design
and design itself you know needs to be
it perhaps part of this conversation
with that there are no edge cases in the
sense I've been in enough conversations
with security privacy folks where I've
heard people talk about the most at-risk
or marginalized users as edge cases and
if we're thinking about dehumanizing
language this is a perfect example of
that sort of dehumanizing language we
need to move away from stigmatizing user
activities I'm sure I would not be
surprised I'm not going to necessarily
ask anyone to raise their hands but I
would not be surprised if there are
people in this room who have thought or
said things like a user clicked on that
fishing link that was so obvious they're
so stupid why do they do that and that's
an example again a stigmatizing user
activities as opposed to trying to sort
of understand and build with them and
this is the this is a part that Alyssa
had mentioned as well that we were
talking about which is incorporating
user safety not just system risks into
threat modeling and system design some
of those traditional security parts
but of course this brings up really that
question of who owns user-centric
security and privacy and safety within a
company and within the structures that
we have due to like where security and
privacy teams are usually placed there
under things like compliance which is
good you know I shift that approach they
might be based within organization or
company operations which means that
they're not thinking about the end user
of the app or the platform and even if
they're based within let's say the
product team as in the product teams the
one who is building this they might not
necessarily have the power or ability to
sort of implement some of these things
because the security team might need to
be the one who signs off on everything
you know so there are a some of those
tensions even within where security and
privacy can be placed there's obviously
the design teams maybe have a role the
product or app teams could as well and
the product teams those were actually
the folks that we were talking to at
Grindr they were the ones that were sort
of the owners internally and I want to
perhaps leave with the question of what
would it look like to bring harm
reduction to your work and I think this
is an important question in part because
I've talked so much about we'll say
these more social scenarios but I also
strongly believe that harm reduction as
an approach can be used and brought into
the work that people do within corporate
environments and I would hi would highly
encourage people who are in sort of
enterprises or corporate environments to
think about ways that they can bring in
and incorporate harm reduction and the
implications or what that means into the
security work that they do
so I guess thank you and we'll go to
questions
you