hello and welcome back and please join
me in welcoming Philipp Lahm oh dang who
is a researcher at the Canada's national
research concerns oh he's going to be
presenting on quantum cryptography right
implies for a society
thank you and thank you all for coming
to my talk fair warning it's probably
gonna be the most theoretical talk of
the conference and there might be one
other talk that competes me in terms of
theoretical Ness and it's the 130 talk
on elliptic elect an elliptic curve
cryptography so I'm gonna present post
quantum cryptography my goal here today
is that you get all the we get out of
this talk a high-level understanding of
what's post partum cryptic is better and
it's an echo hello hello so so yeah so
my goal is that you get out of this talk
a high-level understanding of what is
post quantum crypto what are the types
of problem that were interesting to
solve with post come to Uncle Joe so
without further ado let's jump right in
and before going into post quantum
crypto one a lot at three quantum
cryptography basically the Golden Age of
cryptography uses the 1970s with these
two guys Whitfield Diffie and Martin
Hellman that introduced New Directions
in cryptography and for those of you who
know this paper these new directions are
essentially public key cryptography or
as symmetric cryptography and the
problem is the introduce is basically
digital signature and public key
encryption
they didn't propose a real scheme that
implements those ideas they just
proposed the ideas and so that this was
something interesting to do in crypto
but it's those three guys in which I
made an atom and that first proposed the
first real scheme for public key
cryptography cryptography and we know
this scheme RSA is based on the hardest
a factoring hard numbers and it's one of
the most used today and we've come a
long way since then so there's
this whole field of public key
cryptography that allows us to do plenty
of things like online shopping or just
allow us to to have a trust
infrastructure on the Internet
so the things we can do is a basically
exchange public encryption digital
signature is certificates you know who
you're talking to over the web and it's
based on very simple ideas is that you
have some problems that are harder to
that are easy to compute in one
direction but that are hard to inverse
so for example this is the example that
you take on on the Wikipedia page for
for diffie-hellman key exchange
you have a listen Bob that want to share
a common seek secret but they only know
there's a public paint color yellow and
they each have their their secret colors
which is a blue so let's say red and
blue and by mixing those colors together
it it first makes the yellow and their
secret color then they exchange the
resulting colors and then they mix them
again and now at the end they get the
same color which is a common secret and
the assumption is that is hard given
this shade of blue to recover the two
colors that we use to obtain that shade
of blue and so there are many ways of
mixed mixing paint that we can think of
the most popular is our factoring and
discrete log the speed log is what's
used basically in a elliptic curve
cryptography and really any so-called
trapdoor permutation allows us to do
this kind of cryptography these kind of
tasks and I'm gonna talk a bit more
about what what I mean by a trapdoor
permutation later in the talk
so now fast forward today we have plenty
of devices all connected to the internet
and these devices all use cryptography
in some way or any other if I have a
SmartWatch that's receiving updates from
software updates from let's say the
Apple server then Happel has to the code
that's updated
- this watches is authenticated you said
a public key certificate and even the
server that pushes the update is
authenticated using public key
cryptography so what we have essentially
is a chain of trust where we have this
certificate emitting authority that that
we all know and entrust and which was
this certificate authority to to verify
the identity of Apple before issuing a
certificate for apple and then i po can
each verify the identity of Facebook
before issuing a certificate to Facebook
and Facebook and then sign its binaries
using its certificate but then what
happens is that if you have really
powerful factors that are capable of
breaking the root of this of this chain
then everything collapses and that's one
of the threats of quantum computing it
allows you to it would allow you to emit
fake certificates and just fake any
essentially any identity on the web so
now a bit more about come to keep
computing of course I'm referring to
Shor's algorithm which we'll come to in
a few slides but beforehand I'd like to
give you really brief overview of what
kind of quantum computing is about and
what it can and cannot do so quantum
computing the really the most important
aspect is that you can have a
superposition of a lot of states of
quantum states so let's say I take a
photon I make it go through some kind of
semi reflective mirror and then that
that mirror lets the photon through on
one side if it's let's in horizontal
polarization and it goes to the other
side to the bottom side if it's in
vertical polarization and of course I'm
not a physicist so I only catch this in
a very high overview but what the thing
is about quantum cryptography about it
about quantum mechanics is that this
photon can be not in either of those
places but either to two places at the
same time but another very important
aspect is that you cannot see the photon
at both places at the same time you have
to as soon as you look at it it
materializes either in a right eye or in
the left eye but not in not involve why
is this useful for computing well you
can think of those two positions as if
the photon is on the upper upper row it
even codes zero if it's at the bottom I
mean it it encodes the one and I can put
those true okay quantum computer do some
very in intensive compute function so a
function f that's very intensive to
compute an input zero and even port one
so now because I have those two pads
that are computing in parallel I get a
superposition of the two outcomes but
then again I can only look I can only
get one of the two outcomes because as
soon as I try to look at those photons
one is one is going to disappear it's
gonna collapse on one of the footpaths
but it's still useful to compute some
functions in superposition one of the
things that you can do and that's use
that the main tool behind Shor's
algorithm is that you can have this kind
of State this is a notation for for
saying that it's a superposition over
all input A's and here my function is
just the modular exponent modulo n right
for some basis X and I can put that
through a procedure that's called
quantum Fourier transform and then I get
some output those are probabilities of
observing those value so here you can
think of it as I have a probability 1/2
of seeing the photon here and 1/2 of
seeing the photon here but now I have
many values and I have some
probabilities of observing some values
and so what UFT tells me is that these
peaks in probabilities are going to be
related to the structure of the function
in this case it's going to be the period
of the function so this is a function
but since it's modern it repeats itself
every so often and so the the amount of
steps after which it repeats itself is
given by one of those Peaks and each of
those basically is a multiple of that
value right so now that we have QFT we
can introduce Shor's factoring algorithm
which is conceptually really simple so
the algorithm in a nutshell is you just
pick a random value lower than the one
you try to factorize over here you want
to factorize n and classically like
without the company quantum computer you
know how to factor n if you know a value
are such that you take X to the exponent
R and it it's congruent to one modulo n
so this is using a classical algorithm
if you know this R then you can factor
you can factor n efficiently so I've
already briefly mentioned that that this
function f is a periodic function and
the quantum Fourier transform gives you
essentially the period of this function
so you just apply quantum Fourier
transform it gives you the R with good
probability and then you can factor
using the classical algorithm and so we
saw in the last slide that we have we
had many peaks and some of them are good
values for R some of them are bad values
but the essence is that you have a good
enough probability and you can just
repeat that process enough time and
you're gonna find this R eventually and
the time the the the amount of times
that you have to repeat this process is
polynomial in the number of bits of n so
it's a polynomial algorithm to factor
large numbers I so this breaks
cryptography essentially once we have a
computer on computer everything that we
use as photography on the Internet
is threatened so the aftermath of this
is that factoring discrete logarithm so
I I just showed you the algorithm for
factoring but it's the same essentially
for discrete log except it's a bit more
conflict actually it's a lot more
complicated so I didn't have time to
present it so those tasks are easy for
quantum computer and we rely on the
hardness of those tasks to do
cryptography so public encryption and
digital signatures are broken in a world
where a quantum a scalable quantum
computer exists so this includes RSA de
feel men a digital signature is anything
basically on elliptic curves symmetric
cryptography is okay so Shor's algorithm
doesn't tell us anything about symmetric
key crypto and there is another
algorithm that has an impact on those
namely shores Grover's algorithm but you
can basically ignore it by just doubling
the key size so those are arc okay and
hash functions also are not threatened
by Shor's algorithm a bit back over but
it it's at the same time so you just
have to increase the security parameter
so now we're ready to look at what what
we do when we can't do factoring we
can't do diffie-hellman discrete log we
have to propose new problems that are
hard and this is what post quantum
crypto is about so I mentioned briefly
trapdoor permutations at the beginning a
shorter permutation essentially is
essentially a function that's easy to
compute in one direction so if I if I
have X I can compute f of X very easily
but it's hard to invert so if I have an
output Y and I want to know which which
X produced this output Y this should be
hard to compute on a classical and a
quantum computer but what a trapdoor
function means is that if you know some
other input which we named a trapdoor
then this is easy to invert and so one
way to think of this would be if you
have a Lego set it's very easy to base
ambolyn lego set to obtain the pieces
but if i have the pieces it's very hard
to to reassemble that set unless I have
the the instructions that tell me
step-by-step how to reconstruct it and
not all of the functions that not all of
the problems that are used for post
Compton crypto are of this form but if
if you have a function of this form then
it's it's easy to do public key crypto
because your public key is this function
and I encrypt this way too to obtain a
ciphertext
decrypting is hard unless I know the
secret key which is the trapdoor to my
function right so this is give this
gives you essentially this is
essentially a abstraction of what we
want to look for to do public key
cryptography so now the problems on
which post quantum cryptography reside
so the first one is lattice based
cryptography Zoar a lattice is basically
a set of point in vector in a vector
space and those points so are specified
by a basis B 1 and B 2 so the points are
all the linear combinations of B 1 and B
2 and they span the whole space so now
you can you can think of those points as
going in continuing to infinity in each
direction and of course so this is an
example in 2d but in practice you want
to have many dimensions so that the
problems become becomes big right so
there are two problems that are
conjectured to be hard for lattices the
first one is to find the shortest vector
in the lattice so in this case the
Shorter's vector of Miletus starting
from the origin it's just this this
vector at this point and this is B 1
minus 2 B 2 and the other problem is to
find the closest vector problem so I
have a point that's not on the lattice
but that's between points of the lattice
let's say this green point and I want to
find the closest point which is the red
one
so those are the problems that are
conjecture to be hard but they are
problems that are easy to solve if you
have a good basis so so a good basis
would be like the rectilinear basis that
we all know like vectors that are
essentially orthogonal to each other and
that are pretty pretty short and a bad
basis would be vectors that are very
long and very close to each other so if
they all point in the same direction
then it's hard to know how to combine
them to obtain the shortest vector in
the lattice so how do you do encryption
with that well actually you can do
signature also but I'm just gonna show
you how to encrypt so the encourage the
idea
there are many schemes also proposed for
this problem but I'm I'm just gonna
prepare a present one to get the
intuition so the idea is you pop your
private key is a good lattice and you
probably kiss a bad lattice for for that
for the closest vector problem your
message is a point on the lattice so you
have to find a way to encode the
specific message as a point on the
lattice to encrypt you take that point
let's say the red point is my message so
to encrypt I'm gonna add a random noise
vector that's gonna push it in a
direction so now here the green point is
my cypher text
so my cypher text I send it over a
public channel with the public key is
hard to decrypt because I have to find
the closest point but with the private
key which is the good basis this problem
becomes easy I can find the red point
that's closest to my cypher text and I
can decrypt the message right so this is
lattice based cryptography the next one
we're going to look at is hash based
crypto hash risk you've toad is only
signatures for it and it's based on a
scheme that's called Lamport one time
signatures I'm sorry I have to go a bit
quicker because I'm running out of time
so Lamport one time signatures are
signatures that that are only secured
for one instantiation of the other
signature the work as follows so let's
say I want to assign a message as three
bits then my private key is going to be
three pair
of values and which value I choose for
the signature is gonna depend on those
bits so the first bit is one so I kept
to think it the second value here the
first value here because the second bit
is 0 and the third value because it will
read the second value of the third pair
because the third bit is 1 and this is
my signature so we can already see what
it's called one time signature because I
leaked essentially half of my key by
signing by signing a message and to
verify well I'm gonna use the following
public key which in which each of those
wise is a hash function applied to that
X so like this and I'm gonna take the
corresponding wise and check if the X
hash to the same way that's in my public
key so I can verify using that public
key signatures because those X's are
part of the the signature but can I
cannot Forge a signature because I don't
know this this other X why I couldn't
sign a 0 0 1 for example because I don't
know this X unless I know the private
key and to know this X without the
private key I'll have I'd have to find a
pre-image to this y 0 1 and this is a
this is a problem that's hard if you
have good as functions of course you get
the problem that you can only sign once
with a given key so you have any keys
that you need to take care of if you out
put some thousands of ash per seconds
thousands of signatures per second is
gonna be a problem there are some
solutions to that which is to use a tree
Merkle tree structure to generate many
keys from a given key but the problem is
that those schemes are stateful so you
have to remember what's so yeah you have
proceeded to generate many keys and you
have to remember what's the key that
you're gonna do you're gonna use next
and there's also a scheme that uses
pseudo-random number generator for for
those key generations so this is hash
based signatures the next one again
sorry I have to go quickly to
those I didn't leave myself enough time
there's the other one are based on
multi-view multivariate polynomials so
the problem is the following I have this
polynomial so it's multivariate Croat
rhetoric polynomial so multivariate
because I have many variables quadratic
because I have at most two variables per
term to my power is at most two and the
the assumption is that it's hard in
general to inverse those polynomials so
I have a given output it's hard to find
an expert and input X 1 X 2 that's going
to give the specific output and how do
you base encryption on that what are you
going to choose a function that's
basically a collection of polynomials
and I'm gonna encrypt the message by
well I know I'm going too fast so those
are all polynomials that are that are
supposed to be hard to invert in general
but I choose them so that I know how to
invert them I choose them with a
specific structure that tells me how to
invert them so I take a collection of
those and then to hide this structure
that gives me how to efficiently invert
them I'm gonna hide it with two other
polynomials that are also easy to invert
and gangam I'm going to a sandwich that
function between those two other
functions so this is my public key the
sandwiched function and so this is a
general instance of a problem so this is
just from the from the attackers point
of view this is a random polynomial and
the goal is to invert that polynomial
but from the from the harness from the
person that has the the the private key
which is those the description of those
three functions then it's easy to to
involve so how do you do encryption with
that well to encrypt you apply P on in
input so the input is a as let's say
your message is a bunch of variables
with some given values
to encrypt you just apply P and not to
decrypt given this private key which is
s F and T you just invert those three
polynomials and you get the clear text
from that procedure so it with the
private key you can invert efficiently
but without it you cannot and finally
the last problem post quantum problem
that I'm going to show you is code base
cryptography code base cryptography is
based on a error correcting code and
it's based more specifically on the
harness the hardness of the coding of
random linear code so I can specify a
code base by by a matrix G so this is an
example of the Hamming code for those of
you who don't know much about a
recreating code so this is the Hamming
code and to encode it for this word 0 1
1 I multiply the world times the matrix
G so the first part is the identity so I
recover my word 0 1 1 but then the
second part is what we call parity bits
so here I have 1 1 0 so I'm gonna have 1
+ 0 1 times 0 plus 1 times 1 plus 1
times 0 times 1 so I'm gonna get 1 and
for the other part it's 0 1 1 so I'm get
0 times 0 plus 1 times 1 plus 1 times 1
but it's it's an it's an XOR the
addition so I'm gonna get 0 and these
are my parity bits that that can tell me
how to detect an error but I don't know
with this code I cannot correct an error
I can only detect one but in general you
know you have this code space and those
green dots are my code words and I
encrypt I take this one anchor if it's
not the right word I take this word I
send it in the code space to add some
redundancy to it and then I sent it over
a noisy channel which is gonna introduce
some noise which is my red dot and to
recover the original message I have to
decode so sense and the noisy message to
the the green dot which is a code word
and then I can recover the original
message so this is not an encoding that
that's secure this is not encryption
this is I think we done didn't see to
correct errors but you can build a
crypto system on that your private key
is an efficient decoder for for let's
say this a recollecting code and the
public key is a random generator matrix
or random matrix of this form for the
same code space so the the hypothesis is
that that is hard in general to recover
the green dot from the red dot if you
don't know if you don't have an
efficient decoder already so to do to
build a public key cryptosystem from
that you take the clear text you send it
as a codeword so you you take your W you
you encode it as C and then you add
errors so adding a rose is encrypting
anybody can generate code words with the
random generator the generator matrix
the public key anybody can add noise so
anybody can encrypt but only only with
the efficient decoder can I remove the
errors and recover the original field
text so this is the idea behind code
based cryptography so the main takeaways
of a talk is that public key the public
infrastructure that we know and love
today on the Internet is threatened by
quantum computing there are alternatives
for the problems that are breaking
broken so RSA fokin discrete log is
broken but you can replace them by some
of the problems that represented such as
the lattice based crypto which is
currently one of the most flexible
alternatives hash based crypto so I
indicated in parenthesis that it sold
well all these a good thing in
cryptography it means that it hasn't
been broken since its invention in 70s
multivariate cryptography is pretty fast
it's useful for embedded devices
code base crypto also it's pretty old
there's been schemes that have been
proposed a long time ago and there are
other more recent proposals well recent
and some other roles that I didn't have
time to talk about your to take away is
that we have to act now to implement
post Compton crypto to standardize it
and Christian is going to talk a bit
about that in the next talk and also I'd
like to finish by citing miquellee Mosca
from the University of Waterloo and he
uses this this equation a lot of time it
says if X is if X plus y is greater than
said then then we're in trouble
and what is what are those variables
well X is the time that your data needs
to stay secure
y is the time that it takes to implement
post quantum crypto and Z is the time
that it takes until we have a quantum
computer capable of breaking RSA so if
it takes more time to replace the
infrastructure and keep the data secure
X years then it takes time to build a
quantum computer then the data that
that's protected by this system is going
to be it's going to be compromised all
right so this is it thank you
[Applause]