so
um Brian will tell you that I'm quite
cantankerous
actually I don't think he said that he
said something much worse but I am quite
opinionated and
my daughter says that you know
says worse but quite frankly the one
thing that annoys me more than anything
about this
wonderful industry that we work in is
one word
sophisticated
because we've all heard the term and and
typically what sophisticated means it's
a byproduct for
yeah there's nothing we could have done
and you know you've seen it before when
any attack happens typically what
happens is we know about the company
that's been compromised and the one
thing that everybody is desperate to
know is who did it
and we care about who did it not because
we want to learn about their ttps and
share that with the industry so we can
actually protect everybody no why we
care about that is because
it's interesting or perhaps for the
organization to be able to say there's
nothing we could have done this hack was
far too difficult for us to stop
I actually think
this is complete nonsense and
the reason why I think it is that is
because look we've all seen charts and
graphs like these in fact
um we produce that some time back but
ignoring the fact of that we see these
particular statistics and we hear about
these wonderful groups apt-40 Mustang
Panda fancy bear
and we wrap this up in this mystery that
we've got this
quite frankly nation-state groups that
are going out and carrying out attacks
they're using computers like
script kiddies or they're using attacks
like organized crime groups and
we kind of make this assumption that
because they are nation states because
they are doing the bidding of government
agent entities
that some way shape or form they are
more capable than anybody else out there
now a few years back I had a remarkable
opportunity to actually observe a
nation-state group in operation
see because the great thing about
working in the vendor space is
I'm no longer a Cesar
and
but the downside of this is that
typically what will happen is if there
is any breach if there is any attack
anything that's even remotely successful
typically what happens is we get a phone
call and we say your software didn't
stop this ergo it is entirely your fault
and I will tell you that that happens
more times than I care to mention and
usually
it happens around about Christmas just
as I'm kind of settling in to start
eating and watching Polar Express
so a few years back I got a telephone
call from an organization and they said
look
we've been compromised and your
antivirus software didn't stop this
and I was like okay let's have a look at
it and typically the reason that this
happens is because
they need somebody to blame
usually it's their jobs on the line
usually it's the CEO or the CIO that's
saying well why did this happen and it's
of course it's much easier to blame the
vendor
and so what happened was there was a
long-term Espionage campaign that we
managed to uncover and all of this was
done really to try to determine how the
adversaries got in and fundamentally to
show the organization and say Hey look
maybe it wasn't just the technology that
was a failure perhaps
perhaps you have to shoulder some of the
responsibility as well that is a very
interesting conversation usually
now in this particular case it was
remarkable because as we started to
don't under undertake the analysis what
we found was that the the adversaries
had been in there for seven years
it was a nation-state group in operation
for seven years and part of the reason
why I think attribution matters and I'm
just you know going to get to this is
because
it was because we were able to attribute
this to a nation-state group that
finally this got the attention of the
CEO
because before it was just there's
anomalous Behavior there's anomalous
traffic and now all of a sudden it was
there are State secrets that are leaving
this organization and have been for
seven years
but of course we had to address
the elephant in the room which was why
did our antivirus software not stop a
nation-state group for seven years
so that was an interesting discussion
because of course
my first question was
hey there have been alerts in your
environment did you not think about
responding to them and the response I
got was yeah but we get a lot of alerts
said okay well what did you do with
these alerts oh we turned them off
it's still your fault by the way it's
like yeah I appreciate that
and then we had to do something
remarkable which actually has never
happened to me in my career because
typically from an incident response
perspective
the first thing that you want to do and
the first thing that the client wants
you to do is throw out the adversaries
get them out of my network now
it's reasonable
but the challenge is and this is the
biggest challenge we face is that in
this particular case and in most
particular cases
if there's an adversary in your
environment for seven years
they will establish additional
persistence mechanisms they'll have more
back doors in that particular
environment that you probably don't even
know about
and so we then had to have a very
awkward conversation with the CEO to say
do you mind leaving the actors in the
environment
sorry did you just say you want to leave
threat actors to continually steal
exfiltrate data that are Nathan's secret
and continue to watch them and let them
do it it's like yeah that's exactly what
we want to do
and I can tell you that you know we talk
about attribution as a kind of badge of
honor or as a vehicle to be able to say
well there's nothing we could have done
or perhaps to generate PR and press but
in this particular instance it was
imperative because
this actually allowed this particular
organization to acknowledge the fact
that they were dealing with a part in
the English but a sophisticated attacker
and by doing so we were able to identify
about 20 to 25 additional back doors
that we hadn't accounted for
and what was even more remarkable was we
actually found additional staging
servers and we actually found the data
that had been taken and stolen out of
this organization
and it became a hugely political issue
because the prime minister's office then
ended up sending Consultants on site to
double check our work to make sure we
were doing the right thing
but what it gave me for the first time
ever actually is the opportunity to sit
and actively watch
nation-state criminals and and not
hackers because I that term can't be
used for this but these are criminals
working on behalf of a nation-state
stealing information
and for the first time we actually got
to watch how they work I was actually
sitting on their shoulder
and and what I realized very quickly is
they don't actually work very hard
so
those are the hours they worked I mean I
don't know about you but that's a pretty
decent work-life balance
because you don't work weekends and so
if you want to work for a nation-state
group working out of Southeast Asia
it's only like five days a week and you
only need to do a couple of hours now
and then and you just come in and steal
some data and then
go skiing or whatever you do right it's
I kind of realized that actually
we're not necessarily dealing with
the most
maybe the word is committed but
certainly not the most committed threat
actors out there
and of course when we start to consider
the types of threat groups and the type
of nation-states out there
we kind of make this assumption that
okay there's only maybe three or four
countries that are actually doing this I
mean if I was to say to you which nation
state groups are the most active
you would say
I heard of China
I heard of Russia right typically
countries that have red flags
[Laughter]
but the reality is and you know we
actually
fundamentally got an insight into this
Market into this industry with the
hacking team and the gamma exposures
because like citizen lab actually
published details of customers of
organizations that sell offensive cyber
tools
now this is the first time that we ever
got this and what we see and what we
witness is when we talk about nation
states we make the assumption that
they're all sophisticated
but we never really talk about I don't
know
Mongolia as a threat actor group but
they were one of the customers we never
really talk about organelle countries
such as
Paraguay
and it kind of reminds me of that Lily
Allen song like everybody's doing it so
why aren't we and
the harsh reality is when we talk about
nation-state groups when we talk about
sophisticated attackers
everybody is doing it
genuinely everybody is doing it
and if you don't have the internal
capabilities to develop the code
yourself
you can Outsource it and you can buy it
from commercial cyber security companies
maybe not cyber security companies but
you get the drift right
you can buy it from commercial companies
or
as we've learned you can basically
follow security researchers on Twitter
and download exploit code and then just
run that yourself
and so one of the things that I urge and
encourage us as an industry is to move
away from like rhetorics like this and
we've all seen this and we've all grown
up with this you know the capability
graph where people turn around and say
well there are script kitties and then
there are organized criminal gangs and
then you have nation state groups and
the level of capability goes up and down
depending on which bucket you sit in
it's
and it has been for a while
we need to start to accept the fact that
the cyber crime ecosystem
is made up of capable technical people
that are effectively guns for hire
and whether they're working for nation
states or whether they're working for
organized crime or whether they're
working for ransomware groups
ultimately it's a Payday for them and
we've kind of saw that with operation
Tovar a number of years back
you know so like we have to start to
move away from this and you know when we
start to think about this that's part of
the reason why we're seeing a level of
capability and investment and Innovation
from ransomware groups really escalate
and go through the roof
so you all remember Colonial pipeline
Colonial pipeline of course was the um
dark side or black matter ransomware
group
and historically we would have been told
well you know these groups are lower or
less capable than nation states and of
course back in the past ransomware was
well we'll send an email and somebody
will click on it
but actually if you look at the level of
capability and the kill chain that is
used by ransomware groups it is actually
really quite capable
so this is the dark side uh modus
operandi
and what we see in what we witness and
and this is why security has become so
difficult
is the tools that they're using aren't
malware per se they're not you know
known bad
they're using Enterprise tools against
you
and the challenge required to protect
against these types of attacks
is to cut outwards to identify the
signal in the noise
if you use RDP in your environment they
do as well
if you're using VNC they do as well how
do you determine amongst the 27 000
Powershell you know implementations in
the environment the two or three that
are actually got a malicious payload
much like today we're seeing the growth
and rise in data exfiltration
if you remember a couple of years back
when Kaspersky published the carbonack
report these were attacks against
Eastern European Banks and I think the
urban myth goes there was a CSO that
actually saw data leaving his
environment and for some reason it was
going to China and he said oh that's odd
that shouldn't be going there and that
kind of begun the investigation
that's not happening anymore
the exfiltration of data are using
Enterprise tools like our clone and
sending it to legitimate cloud services
and so if you're filtering or you're
looking for you know traffic to known
malicious C2 infrastructure
that's not happening because what
they're doing is they're using your
tools against you
now I would argue this is sophisticated
but it doesn't look sophisticated does
it because it's not an O day it's not a
pegasus spyware it's not a hundred
thousand dollars to kind of carry out an
attack what it is
it's using tools that we use every
single day against us
and our challenge as an industry is to
be able to identify amongst the millions
and millions of events that you get a
day the two or three or four
that are potentially malicious
and I will tell you the challenges that
these attacks are only increasing and
the number of alerts that we have in the
environment are only increasing
you know as Dave and Miko have said
earlier the number of systems we have in
our in our own homes are going up
let alone our own environment and you
know remember
I I used to give a talk on iot and I was
I always used to ask the audience and I
said how many iot or how many IP
addresses or how many devices do you
have in your home
and on average it was about 20 to 25.
I think I'm at about 65 now most of them
in my daughter's bedroom
and there was one guy that put his hand
up he says I have 250.
well that's like I bet you're single
laughs
but that's the challenge
Even in our own homes the number of
devices we have that are going up and in
our own environments they're going up
and all of these devices are creating
alerts and every single one of those
alerts that I've seen when I get called
in to do incidents are being ignored
and it's not just nation-state attacks
um the soda nakibi gang carried out an
attack against an organization I had to
investigate again blaming me for their
failing
and I had to tell them and I said well
judging by the investigation the
attackers have been in your environment
for seven months
and they compromise an external RDP
server to get in
the response from the CIO is it's still
your fault
is it all right you do know the password
that you had on your external RDP server
was welcome one two three his response
was still your fault
and that's the challenge that we face
within the industry today
the same tools the same miter attack
techniques the same capabilities that
are being used by nation states are
being used by ransomware groups why
because it works and because it's
successful it's a darn site easier to
use
our clone than it is to send it to a
established an infrastructure hosted
somewhere Shady at a bulletproof hosting
site and potentially get blocked
that's the challenge that we're facing
within the industry today
and thread actors today
I have to stress
are watching what we do as an industry
the biggest issue we face today is the
asymmetry of information we as the
Defenders
publish exploits on online we release
stuff on GitHub we talk about and we
release vulnerabilities out there
usually on a Friday night at 4 30. thank
you very much
um
and the threat actors are out there and
they're watching what we do and we've
seen that we've seen the use of tools
you know this particular attack was
um the Microsoft DDE issue and within
four weeks of that vulnerability being
posted we actually saw activity from
fancy bear targeting organizations in
Western Europe
they don't need to buy o days they don't
need to develop exploits because we do
that for them
and there is no way that we're going to
get around it because we need our
followers especially now that we're a
mastodon and we have nothing and we're
starting from zero but that's the
reality it that's the reality of the
situation that we have
is there is this asymmetry of
information
and so my ask of all of us today is
simple
when we start to think about
attribution when we start to think about
who's actually behind the attacks and
we've heard about data sharing we've
heard about information sharing
first of all if we're going to be
sharing information let's make it
actionable let's make it usable
if we're going to be talking about
threat actors let's start to share the
ttps that are used by the groups
right
let's because this sounds crazy but
many of these threat groups and these
apt groups do have
not necessarily a signature set but they
do have an MMO
moreover if we're going to be sharing
information let's talk about the tools
that they're using and if you're going
to be using an MDR provider if you're
going to be using a cyber security
company talk to them about the fact and
say hey look we don't use mimikats in
our environment for red teaming so if
you see that in the network you can
block it
as part of the onboarding
iocs let's actively start to share this
information amongst us as an industry
and let's make it more difficult for
them
you might recall a couple of years back
there was these you know DDOS extortion
tactics and they were going after the
U.S sorry UK financial sector and they
went after Bank One Bank two bank three
and Bank four using the same Mo the same
tactics
that can be stopped if we're just a
little bit more open about what we share
and the timeliness of sharing that
thank you very much
any time or did you wanna
it's okay
the track like that
hey how's it going I have very good talk
there thank you just just a quick one in
regards to the Deep Harvest aspect so
he's found additional 25 back doors
there and obviously you were noticing
that they weren't really monitoring
inside the environment when you started
closing those back doors was there an
influx of the activity or
yeah so actually we had to do we had to
um plan what we call a strike day
um and so one weekend what we had to do
was we had to effectively bring
everybody on site we had to do a
Kerberos golden ticket reset because we
were concerned that well they have
completely poned the active directory
environment we identified those back
doors and then that one day
everything was shut
because the challenge was uh and if you
remember I think it was the bank of
Taiwan heist where they used Hermes
ransomware to cover their track what we
were concerned about was
if they knew that we were onto them they
were going to burn the environment so
the strike they had to be coordinated in
a way that we closed everything off shut
out shut them out as quickly as we could
and then monitor the environment to make
sure that we hadn't missed anything but
um yeah that was a very very stressful
weekend
I can imagine and did you see any
activity of them trying to get back in
or was it just once it was closed they
kind of just gave up
all right well I haven't named the
customer so I haven't named the
organization so I can say that we hadn't
seen them go back and then all of the
work that we said well once this is done
we're then going to go through an
exercise with you around rebuilding your
environment strengthening your security
and you have to do investment they said
yeah thanks we'll get back to you so I
expect a call but
um I don't know when it's going to
happen but yeah as far as they were
concerned it was fine but what was
interesting was we actually got the iocs
um and then we tracked the prevalence of
the campaign across the globe because
obviously we had like Global Telemetry
and the campaign that we saw wasn't just
directed at that one organization it was
actually a global campaign against
defense contractors all across uh Asia
and Western Europe so they're still
active and the same tools were being
used but we published all of the iocs
and made it available to all of our
competitors as well perfect thank you
anyways I think you've got one more
hi there um you mentioned that uh
adversaries are using more living off
the land and Cloud infrastructure
does that imply then that attribution is
getting harder over time or are we just
moving on to different methods
that's a great question
um
using with technical indicators is a
Fool's errand
um and so we're actually
reevaluating our attribution policy but
what we can do is we can use uh during
that earliest earlier pyramid and start
to indicate or have confidence
indicators as to who we believe to be
behind that one thing that we've made a
decision on is we won't actually say it
was country a or country B we say a
level of confidence and the likely
threat group behind it
you know we're not we're not law
enforcement we're not the government
we're not here to point fingers at
countries what we are there to do though
is reveal the methodologies that we
believe specific threat groups are using
and share that methodology with the
industry so yeah we're quite circumspect
about it
um for that reason
all right
thank you very much thank you