hi I am Tiffany Jernigan I am a
developer Advocate at VMware
you can ask me what that means if you
don't know afterward but includes doing
stuff like this so yeah
I have my Twitter up on there on further
slides there's also my Mastodon which I
wish it was shorter but you know it's
the whole thing but it's there so yeah
I'm going to be talking about like
getting started with kubernetes users
and permissions without just using
cluster admin
if all right come on
I try to
there we go
all right so we have two different types
of authors authentication or authen
which is who are you so it could be any
one of you people it could be like a
robot or whatnot and then there is
authorization or Aussie and that is what
are you allowed to do for instance you
could be like hey you are you Bob are
allowed to be at this conference and
attend someone's talk but no you're not
allowed to throw like food at the
speaker or something like that
all right so first I'm going to talk
about authen and provisioning users
so kubernetes is very flexible here you
can use TLS certs maybe with your own CA
or not but since the kubernetes API
server doesn't support revocation you
should definitely use short-lived certs
don't have ones that are like here I'm
going to have this last for like five
years and cross your fingers and hope
nobody else gets access to that instead
of trying to do something maybe that
like you get a new one every hour or
something like that you could also use
oidc tokens with any oidc provider it's
something like in-house for instance
like dext or key cloak or SAS like OCTA
and then that in turn can plug into your
Cloud's IAM for example you can map your
cloud provider users to your kubernetes
users
you can also deal with service accounts
to provision users as well so as a
little fun note in kubernetes you don't
really create a user
you give for example create pods
permissions to say Bob and as long as
someone shows up with a valid search or
like an oidc token for Bob
then they can create pods
so there's like two main site things
that interact with like kubernetes that
are either humans which I as far as I'm
aware is probably all of you
um and then there's robots I don't know
we'll see
um so for humans you can do things with
like TLS uh ODC service cans Etc with
robots that's basically usually used
with service accounts
so starting off with certificates so the
commands here show you how to create a
certificate signing request you might
see that listed as CSR in short in a lot
of places
this example is using openssl because
it's super widespread and you probably
have it on your machine by default I'm
using a Mac and it was already there I
didn't have to download anything many
folks though might prefer using
something like CF SSL which is
cloudflare's or maybe they want to use
Vault or some other certificate
Authority and that's usually shortened
to ca
and then after that you then transfer
the CSR to the CA and depending on what
kind of cluster you have this can be
done differently
so for example if you are using a
self-hosted cluster or you're using like
Cube ADM
basically where you have access to the
nodes of the control plane and if you
want to do like some experimentation
here is a specific example that you
could be using
this example assumes that we have a
cluster deployed with cubeadm for this
one and that the ca Keys live
specifically in Etsy kubernetes pki on
the control plane
and you get and then like for instance
the one two three four you could have as
something actually meaningful to you
so another method with certificates is
going through the CSR API so this is
what if you want a deal certificates
this is the route you'd have to go down
if you're using a managed cluster since
you can't actually get again inside of
the control plane on a managed cluster
like this one works for managed and
self-hosted basically
um so the CSR API is in the kubernetes
API so you can get certificates from it
it basically makes kubernetes act as a
CA
and this is what you would apply with
Cube cuddle it might be a little harder
to read back there there's a bunch of
lines but basically what it's doing is
it's giving you the request which is
that uh file that we the CSR file that
had been dumped out from openssl
previously
and it uses that so like this whole part
dealing with the CSR API you're
interacting with kubernetes with Cube
cuddle
so after you create the CSR then you
need to actually go and approve it
so you could do Cube cuddle certificate
approve and then like my thing is like
user Eagles a Lovelace the user equals
is just so that like it's not required
you could just have it a Lovelace or
whatever you wanted there it's just so
like if you were searching and you
wanted to go based on what you're
defining as a user you could see all the
people are like that
um and then what you need to do is to
retrieve the certificate
so then you just do a get on the CSR
you'd get the search and then you would
do a base64 to code on user.drt and then
you give that file back to the user
so once you actually have that
um then you can pass in your key and the
CRT file over to cube cuddle config
which is basically adding the
certificate and the key to your
cubeconfig file
all right so now certificates are out of
the way for a bit so the other one of
the other things is tokens
so if you have a conceptual
understanding of TLS then you probably
have one for oidc as well
things are different depending whether
you're using a self-hosted cluster or if
you're not and if you are there's two
flags up there that you need to add so
one for the oidc issuer URL and one for
the oidc client ID
on manage clusters you want to use the
oedc with the provider basically there
is often like a quasi transparent
like integration with IIM and generally
that is with using oidc under the hood
and it will then automatically be using
IM or something else and just like do
that for you
um there's some links that tell you a
little bit more about it like one is
like it's specific for
um uh eks but obviously there's there
should be guides for all the other ones
as well there's just kind of limited
space on this slide so I just picked one
um so and then if you're not using a
cluster like that then if you are say
already using something like Vault
inserts or you're just like truly
invested inserts already you probably
still want to just keep using TLS starts
versus starting and trying to figure out
everything with tokens whether I do see
and if you're not already using TLS
darts you may not want to get started
there just for that at that point
um service accounts are typically used
for say like processes programs sources
that are running autonomously on a
cluster but nothing's going to stop us
from using them to manage access and
permissions for users
even if that's not really what they were
meant for in the first place but you can
do it so for the demo I'll be doing I'll
be using them for demo purses and you
can too
um if you don't like want to go the
right way through like setting up a
bunch of Hoops to actually deal with
setting up TLS certificates or IDC based
authentication so like if you're
especially just trying to start and
figure stuff out of the beginning it's a
really good way to go about it
um so a service count is yeah it's just
a user with some funny looking name
thing there um it's like system service
account and then whatever namespace that
you're in and then the name of the
service account
so then there's since we're talking
about tokens in this space so there's
also service account tokens they are
Json web tokens or jots
they're like oidt tokens but they are
generated by the kubernetes control
plane specifically it's a controller in
the controller manager
and by default
um kubernetes will on like if within
your container pod uh kubernetes will
automatically place the token in that in
a file specifically under that location
which we'll actually take a look at
during the demo
and that token is a token for the
service account of the Pod that that
container belongs to
all right
so enough about
that type of auth now let's go to the
other type of so we're gonna look at
Aussie and specifically role-based
access control or our back for short if
you hadn't noticed there's a lot of
acronyms they love the acronyms
so a high-level idea of it on kubernetes
is that first you define a role or a
cholesterol so like a role would be
specific to a namespace a cholesterol
would be well for your cluster and that
is a collection of permissions like
things that can be done so things like
listing pods creating deployments
setting the scaling for like a specific
deployment and a bunch of other things
after you create that role or cluster
role then you would like it exists but
it doesn't actually do anything so you
need to be able to bind that role or
cluster role to say like a user or a
group or a service account with using a
role binding or a cluster role binding
if you're wondering oh hey what can I
actually do so say my resource is a pod
what can I do with a pod like how do I
see whether I can do a get or a list or
a watch or a patch or whatever those
things are you can actually find that
out using Cube cuddle and it'll
basically spit out a thing of what you
can actually do with it
and you can depending on like where the
group is like maybe it's in V1 maybe
it's not if you're wondering hey where
is located you could just do Cube cuddle
API space API resources and figure out
where it's located
all right so this is the default service
account that gets created for whatever
namespace you are creating so this is
cnsc because that's a short abbreviation
uh for this conference
um and then it just creates a default
one
then here is an example role for getting
pods so you can see like in resource you
have pods and then the verbs are again
list so the reason you have both is say
if you were like I have an nginx pod if
I have just git I could do a cube cuddle
get pod nginx if I try doing keep get
I'll get pods it doesn't it can't do
that any of the list
and then you need to have the roll
binding so you can see that this
basically has the role that get pods
roll and then it has the service count
which is the one that I've been talking
about
um there's also fun stuff with auditing
and of course I noticed that I hadn't
fixed this before we got here and I
didn't fix it now the first line is
supposed to say Cube cuddle off
space canine dash dash list
um I'll fix that later but um and then
there's a bunch of other tools that
aren't specifically built in that you
can get like plugins for
all right so demo time
after I fix that
there we go let's pretend that never
happened
all right
I clear it and then it just comes right
back all right so first uh let's make
sure that I did delete the namespace so
if we get namespaces all right cool so
there's just a bunch of the initial
stuff so if I do okay create namespace
of like Cloud native security con
all right
um so there's this really cool tool
called Cuban s that Ahmed Al Balkan
created that makes it so that you can
switch between name spaces that you're
currently in so you don't have to do the
dash n and then give it the namespace
every time which can be really annoying
so if I do a Cuban s
and then that so now I am in that one so
I've actually just ran Cuban s you can
see that I'm specifically in there okay
so I'm just going to create some
deployments
we will see why in a bit
how's the internet everybody
all right so I'm just they're both using
nginx because they are
they spin up I don't have to do anything
weird to make sure that it stays running
and whatnot
all right so if I did okay get odds oh
yeah and I can't remember very much of
this uh the K is me being lazy and
aliasing Cube cuddle 2K because I don't
want to type that
I already like my tab completion and
everything else so um all right if we do
a k get pods
you can see the two that are running
there right now
so like basically
um however my cluster is set up I have
an effect like cluster admin permissions
I can if I wanted I can go and delete
these I can scale the deployments there
are there all that fun stuff
how about what if we go inside of a pod
so if I do
oh my gosh
okay so there's this cool thing called
nyx3. Dev it basically ends up giving
you a container image that has these
things that you list with slashes
installed in it already so like shell
Cube cuddle curl JQ it's really handy
the internet was nicer to me when I demo
on this
all right so now if we tried to do a
cube cuddle
oh my God
oh my goodness
okay
so I'm on the same cluster
but now it's it's throwing up and saying
I can't do this so like it might be hard
to read because of how it's wrapping it
but basically it's saying that my that
weird name my user like with my name
space of cnsc and default which is again
the default essay that gets created uh I
don't have the ability to uh list like
pods in this namespace
so basically we need to fix that so we
can do that by creating a role in a role
binding so we don't right now we don't
have to create a service account because
well
I'm just going to use the default one
so if I do K create role
all right so this thing I'm just calling
it get pods verb is just whatever type
of action you're going to be doing so I
want to be able to do a get and I want
to be able to do a list and I want it
specifically for the pods resource
so I created that if you want to take a
look at it
um we can see basically the API groups
the resources are pods and that I want
to be able to do a git in a list
so then
now so we have the essay we have the
role now we actually need to bind them
together so if I create role binding
so this one you give it the role and
then you give it that service count so
that's the name of the service can that
where you have right now
so now if I do a cube pedal get pods I
can actually see them
okay so that's cool so now let's it has
has anyone tried using like Dash V6 or
like UPS the verbosity on a cube cuddle
command before
all right see two people all right so if
we did the get pods again if we do Dash
like V6 you can actually see what
address is being used for these requests
so if I go and copy this
I could go and try doing a curl I'm
going to do test h k which is
technically Dash insecure because like I
know this is my cluster I trust it this
is a demo um I don't really like I'm not
worried that whatever the API is there
or is giving back to me is like garbage
or some crazy stuff
for now
um so if I do Dash K and then I give it
the URL there so okay now it it's
failing so like what's going on here I
just did a cube cuddle command to get
pods I haven't uh I have my role binding
everything but it's telling me I can't
do it if you specifically look there it
says that you are system anonymous
it's because it doesn't actually know
who you are
so in order to fix that you need to
actually give it the service account
token
so and remember that this right side is
within a pod that's in this cluster if
we look in
this one location
we can see this lovely token this
looking at this you're just like okay
it's a bunch of gibberish like I guess
that's your token if we go and copy this
and Slide the correct direction there we
go if you go to jwt.io you can actually
dump it your encoded stuff in there and
dump it out and actually mean something
um so I'm not sure if it's really
legible so basically you can see I need
I'm using a gke cluster
um you can see the namespace is the NSD
tester is that pod that I am currently
in
and then my default service account and
you can see all that there
all right cool so we have that great so
now what we do with our new with our
curl is now we give it a header
so authorization Bearer I always could
do this wrong okay I need to save my
token
so I can just call it like this
come on laptop I have faith in you
sometimes
no faith
fine be that way
what did what did you say I did
uh
oh yeah
whoops
tired all right okay token
um yeah so uh back to what I was saying
is we and so we do if we do the curl
give it Dash h
a
authorization
bear
token
I did I throw
this is why people shouldn't let me type
all right so if I pass that into JQ and
gave it the items
dot metadata dot name
man this is so slow
hello
okay yeah so there you can see the pods
that we had before okay so with the
whole dash k thing let's get rid of that
now if we look in this same folder
oh my goodness hello
trying
not okay wow all right
um You can see here that there's a CA
CRT file in here so instead of this
lovely Dash k
we do see a cert
oh my goodness
and it still works
okay so um as of one of the more recent
versions of kubernetes service account
tokens are bound by default
so let me show you what that means so
this token basically is bound to that
pod so if I were to go over here
and basically I'm creating another pod
just like the other one and
so if I were to go and just make token
equals to that same thing oh not not
that
and then if I go and copy this exact
command
you can see that I can still run it
right
so now what happens if I decide that I
don't want this pod anymore
depending on how slow my internet is
um this might take a million years to go
away
go away
um but yeah so that wasn't a thing
before like it I think I can't remember
specifically it may have been 1.21 but
you'll need to verify that
um depending okay wait
let's see
all right it's gone all right so now if
I were to try doing that again
I now got unauthorized because that
token was bound to that pod and it now
has vomited and no longer works
okay
so that's just like that basic stuff
with that so and since everything's
going slowly I'm going to see what I can
quickly get through in the next I
believe I have 10 minutes
because
technology it loves you and it hates you
all right so we were using a default
service token so now let's go and create
one so if I create a say so I can call
it scalar
um basically what I'm going to do is
create something that I can go and scale
a deployment
so if there's some built-in cluster
roles and cholesterol bindings for
instance like there's like if you did
like I'll just do it okay get a cluster
roll
grab video
maybe I shouldn't try doing a thing like
that and getting her up but there's a
thing that you have that is called view
so I could do K create cluster
roll binding I can give it that cluster
role that already exists which lets me
view a bunch of stuff and do nothing
else it's basically read permissions and
give it to my service account
and while we do that
everything
okay so if you are specifically dealing
with uh if you're trying to create a pod
with a specific service account since
this one isn't the default one anymore I
there used to be a way to do dash dash
service count I don't know why I got
removed I wish it didn't so now you have
to actually do the overrides which is
special so yay Json
um so then I give it that
I swear it's way faster an hour ago
I hope everyone's first day of this
conference is going well
um yay okay so if we
do a
oh my goodness
hello letters
I guess worst case if this if this
actually fails I can walk you through
what actually happens because I threw
all this stuff into my slides too
oh my goodness
I feel like I've gone back to the early
2000s
okay
well that's there we go so get all
doesn't actually do get all but it gets
a bunch of stuff so my view is letting
me see all of that stuff
um I'm not going to try typing in if I
were to try deleting stuff right now it
would fail I'm not going to try that
because I'm just gonna fail so
um what I want is to be able to create a
deploy a way to scale so I could create
a role
all right so
so I can call that scalar because I'm
lazy um so when you're messing with
something like replicas uh you which or
like scaling you would do a patch so it
gets the resource of deployment slash
scale and then I want to do it only on
the nginx one because you're a member of
nginx knife web
so I create that
I guess while it's doing that if I do a
cute pedal
Bill deploy except the problem is I have
typing issues
so all right scale nginx
replicas equals two
yay internet
so what will eventually happen if I run
that right now it's going to vomit
because I don't have the permissions to
do it oh wow unable to connect to the
server
yeah internet
there we go okay
raise your hand if you had a demo be
this painful at a conference sweet
thanks for commiserating
okay so if I tried doing right now it
says that I can't patch deployment scale
in there so if I go and create that roll
binding
now I can scale that and if I were to
try
scaling web
it fails because I specifically named
the resource
okay
so now okay we have that but right now
I'm using like view that means I can see
everything what if I only want to be
able to just get that specific
deployment so what I would want to do is
first delete
uh that cluster role binding if I were
to try
scaling this back down to one
I can't because like in order to be able
to actually do anything that I have to
first be able to see it I can't actually
get it so what we could do is we could
do an edit on the role that we have
called scalar
I can use my really terrible VMS Vim
skills copy this
paste it
change that to just deployments and get
so now theoretically
I can scale that but so if I did a cube
cuddle get
like say if I tried get all again
I can't do that if I did a cube cuddle
get deployments can't do that if I want
to do nginx I can and I can scale that
and that's basically all that I can do
with that
um
let's see
yeah so I think that's everything for
that part
um and if you just wanted to see what
would happen if you did the Raw
um it's kind of like thrown out the
show's a bunch of stuff but like say
what for instance Services slash proxy
you can see what the verbs are that you
can actually go and use and then also
now that I have these permissions if I
do a cube cuddle
off
can I and then you can do what you can
do a can I and then like do a specific
thing there's also eventually a way to
do dash dash list
maybe if you hit enter more than once
it'll make it work
there we go okay
um so you can see down so there's a
bunch of stuff that is here by default
um that you will normally see like the
ones up here apis Etc but the ones that
I these ones here
are specifically there because I added
them with my role in my roll binding
okay
um if we go back over here
oh yeah so yeah demo that that just
happened
um it's kind of janky I will try making
it look better when I actually post it
but I thought it would be useful for
because a lot of times people post
here's my code for my slides and then
they put the word demo and then it's
like well if you don't have to say you
don't have a video or you don't like
watching videos
okay where's the demo so I attempted uh
last night
um to do this so basically it goes
through every single thing that I did
today
um hopefully there's nothing wrong that
I have comments and stuff in there too
but yeah it's just all basically all
things with the default namespace uh
service account balance service account
tokens
um creating new essay like Factory roles
so like as in like using that
cholesterol that's already there as you
noticed even in my demo I did not give
cluster admin permissions don't do that
and scalar
and yeah it's just a bunch of slides of
that
um this is so I learned through uh
Bernard's talk that apparently you can
actually there's actually a way to like
put a review on the sched app didn't
know that
I don't know how many people actually
are logged in and it only has smiley
face sad face or a line so you don't
have to log in so here's a little link
thing I would super appreciate if you
could give me some feedback because I
would like this is my second ever
security talk and I want to improve on
what I'm doing
so
yeah
thank you everybody
[Applause]