good morning everyone almost lunch time
um and I just want to say thank you for
taking the time to come here today we're
going to be talking about this platform
as a service abstraction known
affectionately as Batcave and we're
going to be talking about how it is used
in one of the largest Federal Healthcare
organizations one of the largest federal
agencies but specifically we are focused
on delivering Health Care oriented
applications and and how we're doing uh
our software security supply chain
security things like that through this
particular approach so for introduction
sake I'm Rob wood I'm the Chief
Information Security Officer and hey
everyone Jed Johnson I'm a tech lead
with the defense unicorns and a platform
engineer on the Batcave project awesome
and so CMS for anyone who is not
familiar with it it is the centers for
Medicare and Medicaid services so
basically what we do is we manage the
back end the payment backbone for all
the payments that flow through the
Medicare and Medicaid systems along with
some other supporting programs like uh
chip which is a focused on childhood or
a child Insurance programs we do
clinical clinical standards for
hospitals across the U.S all like 6 000
or so of them and as well as a bunch of
other things and so all in all our
programs cover over 130 million people
across the U.S which is a pretty decent
amount of Phi pii just sensitive stuff
that we have to make sure we are
protecting so
as you might imagine doing that at scale
inside the federal context comes with
challenges there are challenges from uh
the federal compliance standpoints
you've got fedramp you've got atos
you've got lots of bureaucracy uh you
know it's it's almost uh it's almost a
meme or I'm sure people have meme that
uh all of the
all of the red tape that you're kind of
swimming through to do anything in a
large Enterprise let alone the largest
Enterprise in at least the country
potentially the world that is the U.S
federal government and so you know we
have a lot of developers thousands of
developers all working across different
parts of the organization it's Federated
it's disconnected Loosely coupled
different missions different priorities
all of that stuff and there's a lot of
uh a lot of waterfall development still
happening there's a lot of agile
Transformations which is really just
translated to uh more affectionately
like agile fall because
you're kind of just delivering in
Sprints or you're tracking a waterfall
project in jira and you kind of wrap it
up and call it devops and and you know
you kind of move on and that's not what
we're aiming to do we're aiming to
actually enable faster more efficient
more secure software development so
our solution or part of our solution to
this problem is the bat cave which uh
because every good government program
needs an acronym it is the continuous
authorization and verification engine we
just needed something that mapped to
something fun and exciting for Branding
purposes so that's what we came up with
and so this is really CMS has one of the
largest cloud footprints in the world
um mostly on AWS I'm on Azure and so
there is
there is a very large Cloud footprint
that we're already working with and the
Batcave is really an opinionated
abstraction on top of the CMS Cloud
program that's Tech that's process
that's onboarding that's people that's
policy all of that but it's an
opinionated abstraction trying to
alleviate some of the the double work
and uh and leg work and prep work for
compliance and authorization processes
that people have to go through in order
to get something done and built on like
inside of the the Enterprise
um and so some of our goals
uh we have many but we want to we want
to help people move faster naturally we
want to help people do it more securely
naturally we want to make sure that
things are compliant because we have uh
office of inspectors General to reckon
with and Audits and and all of this
stuff that we have to deal with that's
all important in the federal context but
really at the end of the day if I could
draw your eyes to the bottom right of
this slide is about empowering and
enabling continuous delivery like true
continuous delivery in the federal
context not we want to deliver something
so we're going to pause and wait a month
and do a security impact assessment and
make sure we do a controls like a mini
audit that's not continuous delivery
like you need to make a change because
log4j just came out you know like the
log for Shell issue just got released
and you need to
change your application right now we
want to be able to do that without the
bureaucracy getting in the way so Tech
supported and process supported
so I want you to kind of rewind yourself
in time back to like March 2020. so
we're all sitting around maybe we're in
an office maybe you're you know you're
out at the mall you're out at a bar and
covid-19 is just starting to kind of
float around the world that's coming to
the US it's there's like 10 to 20 cases
and then the White House issues a decree
Nationwide shutdowns Nationwide
shutdowns everything is going into
lockdown mode so businesses stop
businesses stop bringing people in all
of that stuff happened really really
fast worldwide especially in the US and
so now imagine you're inside of a
federal agency and you want to like you
have a responsibility an imperative to
start contributing to the problem to the
solution in some meaningful way so you
go through and you do your ideas you
start generating things and
in the federal contact at least in CMS
we are heavily supported by contract
partners
and so to get to a contract partner you
can't just you can't just sign up with a
credit card you actually have to prepare
a proposal like a procurement package
put it out uh people have to submit bids
to it all of it like that is a whole
long process in and of itself uh another
thing that has been heavily uh glorified
over memes the the slow Federal
procurement process so call six months a
pretty aggressive timeline because these
are extraordinary circumstances and you
kind of keep evolving
um you kind of keep evolving now let's
say you've awarded your contract you're
starting to do uh design work and
onboarding people and background
checking and the contractors then hiring
the folks that are going to staff the
project and you're starting to really
like this idea is really starting to
come together and so you know from there
you're starting to like set up the
infrastructure you need you start to
make some some design decisions around
what you're doing and then rewind all
the way into the future and you've got
your thing built and now you have to go
through a three to six month ATO process
which is also like that's that's
somewhat quick in some agencies and
what I want to really try to drive home
here if I could do this without falling
off the stages is uh look how much these
the problem space has changed from when
you were over here and you started
coming up with your ideas for how you
were going to fix the problem the
assumptions that you made
then and the assumptions that you now
have when you're when your app is live
are radically different we're talking
Millions upon millions of people
affected or potentially facing like
lethal outcomes because of one
one strain of a virus in covid-19 and
this is like one Healthcare
emergency sort of situation that
agencies like CMS are contributing to
there's the opioid epidemic there's
there's uh you know these more bespoke
diseases that are starting to have like
outbreaks again and and this is the kind
of thing that federal agencies need to
be able to responsively and nimbly
respond to situations so let's say we
get all the way to the end of that and
we need to start making changes quickly
in the in the order of magnitude of
hours and days not weeks to months to
quarters we need to be able to do that
and do so in a way that doesn't throw
the baby out of the bathwater of all the
compliance security resiliency
requirements that are necessary in
operating in the business of the
government that is like we can't forego
that because real people you know it's
not like you're going to lose your you
know your cat videos or your you know
your food logs or whatever like you're
gonna like we're in the business of the
government so we have very real things
to reckon with and contend with and you
know like presidents come and Congress
comes and they you know there's hell to
pay if you don't do something that you
were asked to do from those upper
echelons of government so this is our
flywheel and I'm not going to walk in
detail through all of this but you'll
see terms on here like marketing and
sales and customer enablement and value
and all of that and we are really
thinking about the ecosystem that is CMS
hundreds of fisma systems which are
composed of different web services and
applications and database you know like
data tools all of that
we're thinking about this from a total
addressable Market space really trying
to lean in and instead of bring the
hammer down like most cyber security
organizations do and say
thou must adopt this platform because
there's people are just going to ignore
us that is inevitable like that's
typically how it goes in security when
security teams start going in not
empathizing with who their stakeholder
or customers a customer is on the other
side and just making demands you might
get short-term compliance but long term
people are going to hate you resent you
ignore you and so you're not going to
really move the needle and so we're
really leaning in on this concept and
this is more like this is part of a
broader culture shift inside of CMS
inside of our cyber security
organization that is focused on
empathy over the person on the other
side of the of the conversation the
developer enablement the person who's
struggling to just get something done
because the app that we provided them
sucks
um because it takes 20 seconds to load a
page because it's not accessible from
some Network segment you're in all of
that stuff like focusing on value
invest in value start to spread the word
like really trying to build something
that people find valuable and letting
that create virtuous Cycles is really
the kind of Cornerstone of our
particular flywheel so with that we're
going to transition into some of the
technical bits of how the Batcave
actually works so all right very good
hey everyone again my name is Jed
Johnson and I'll be talking about some
of the engineering implementation of the
Batcave platform so to begin with the
back a platform is built exclusively on
open source software and Partnerships
in particular we leverage an open source
product called Big Bang and this is
maintained by a United States Air Force
organization called Platform One and big
bang is the core Tech that the Batcave
is built off of and it's what has
allowed us to go from zero to prod in
less than six months and so big bang
itself
is a declarative Baseline of
configurations and applications used to
create a secure kubernetes based
platform so when we think about what all
is necessary to build a platform things
like logging and monitoring runtime
security pipeline tooling Etc Big Bang
provides secure hardened containers and
configurations for these core platform
components right out of the box
and additionally these hardened
containers and configurations they come
with oscout documents mapping their
implemented security controls to nist
853 so by adopting big bang and
organization can inherit a number of
these security controls and the goal is
to have in terms of nist 853 and 80
secure platform on day one of
development
at the same time while it's great to
have open source tooling like big bang
it's very rare that Open Source Products
will do exactly what you want them to do
right out of the box so here at Batcave
we have a contribute first culture
meaning that if an open source product
is lacking a feature or we find a bug we
will engage with that community and
oftentimes
we start the conversation by creating a
GitHub issue and in many cases the issue
that we create isn't on you know that
particular product's roadmap and so in
those cases we'll actually go in and
make the pr and fix the issue
also when using open source
there's always this option available to
create a fork of the product and while
there are cases when Forks are warranted
in our case it is an organizational
strategic imperative that we contribute
back Upstream so for example I mentioned
that big bang provides hardened
containers of Open Source Products so
let's say we want to use grafana to
visualize some metrics data
grafana the application receives
periodic updates from its developers
right like bug fixes and security
patches things like that
when these updates occur the Big Bang
team
brings them in creates a re-hardened
container a re-hardened version of
grafana updates its secure grafana Helm
chart and I take all of this as a
batcave developer and deploy it onto our
platform so as a result with with very
minimal effort on our part and using
this open source ecosystem
we get these bug fixes and we get these
security patches virtually for free just
by updating a single dependency and that
is big bang
if we were to create a fork of either
Big Bang or grafana this would
effectively double the work on our teams
in because now we would be the we would
be the ones monitoring that Upstream
grafana repo for updates and we would be
the ones maintaining this secure grafana
Helm chart so contributing to these
Upstream repos and building the
relationships in the open source
Community has been absolutely critical
to Batcave success
all right so now I'd like to introduce
the core Tech stack of the Batcave
platform that which we call the utility
belt and the utility belt is the set of
core services that run on every bat cave
cluster and this includes things like
our monitoring stack and logging stack
runtime security Etc and each one of the
apps that you see here contributes to
our platform's security control mapping
so first we Deploy on AWS eks and once
we have this bare eks cluster up and
running the first thing we do is install
flux and flux is our continuous delivery
tool for deploying the platform
we use flux to take all of these
CMS bat cave specific configurations we
overlay them onto a big bang Helm chart
and then deploy it all as a flux Helm
release and this single flux Helm
release will deploy the entirety of our
platform
so next the platform stack is deployed
in a particular order such that we
establish a security Baseline before
installing anything else in the cluster
so to do this the first thing we do is
install kyverno as our admissions
controller and kyverno allows us to
write policy as code that all of the
other resources in the cluster have to
adhere to
so then we install a service mesh using
istio this allows us to regulate all
Ingress egress and lateral Network
traffic and finally we install our
monitoring and Metric stack which is
Prometheus and grafana
once these apps have been installed to
establish that security Baseline the
rest of the platform the rest of the
apps and services you see up here
they're installed in parallel and again
all this is happening from a single flux
Helm release
and lastly once all of these core
services are deployed and healthy we use
Argo CD to deploy an app teams
application Argo CD will aggressively
reconcile drift so if someone attempts
to modify an application's configuration
once it's been deployed Argo will
automatically revert it back to the
state defined inversion control so in
other words we use Argo CD to deploy
tenant applications using this
declarative git Ops model
okay so at this point all of the
infrastructure and configuration this
code has been written it's all sitting
up in GitHub and the big question is
how do we want to deliver this platform
to the app teams and depending on what
app team you talk to you know people
want different things some application
teams already have platform engineers
and they feel comfortable managing an
AWS account and operating a kubernetes
cluster other app teams don't have any
platform engineers and they would rather
have a platform as a service fully
managed type of experience and of course
you also get every you know opinion and
use case in between those things so
after many iterations we ended up with
these three delivery models
the first and earliest model we have is
this single tenant platform as a service
and in this scenario each app team has
their own cluster that we the Batcave
team will manage and operate
and this model is really meant for app
teams who maybe have limited cloud or
platform expertise and also maybe they
have a higher budget and I mentioned the
budget piece because you can imagine
running your own eks cluster including
all those utility built apps you just
saw plus your own app like this can get
super expensive right that said if your
app is is truly Mission critical like
maybe it does warrant this single tenant
isolation model
that said like many app teams don't need
this level of isolation for example if
you're running a relatively low traffic
internal facing web app you probably
don't need an entire eks cluster to
yourself so in order to be a competitive
option for this other Market segment of
app teams we also have a multi-tenant
platform as a service model this model
Works especially well for entire
organizations that want to migrate their
entire Suite of applications to run in
the Batcave and of course the cost is
just going to be considerably less than
that single tenant option
technically speaking with this
multi-tenant model each app is separated
by namespace and each app has its own
dedicated node
by separating the apps by node this
allows us to mitigate the blast radius
in case one of the apps malfunctions so
for example if one of the apps has a
memory leak and it eats up all the
memory in one of the nodes and that node
becomes unhealthy and goes down the rest
of the apps running in the cluster
should be unaffected
and finally we meet some app teams who
already have platform Engineers who have
experience with AWS and kubernetes and
they express
and interest in Batcave to use our code
as a baseline for their own set of con
for their own set of security controls
and assessments for those teams we can
just give them an overview of the
Batcave platform Point them to our code
up in GitHub and let them dig in
now looking at these three models as one
of the engineers who has to implement
these different delivery models and then
operate all of these very different
clusters I can tell you firsthand like
this is too much right
having this many delivery models does
not scale very far past our current size
what we'd like to go in on is a fully
managed platform as a service model that
is multi-tenant and I I think sometimes
folks get hung up on this idea of
multi-tenancy and and for good reasons
but I think using that verbiage that
phrase like multi-tenant is actually a
bit of a marketing faux pas on our end
for example
when you deploy an app on Heroku or even
AWS do you know or even care if it's
multi or Singleton on the back end for
things like databases yeah sure you
might care but for the stateless
application itself probably not all you
care about is that your app is deployed
it's healthy and it's accessible
and that's the beauty of those platforms
the back end of the platform is
completely abstracted away from those
development teams and they can focus
solely on delivering value to their user
base
also from a platform engineering
perspective what we've discovered is
that whenever we onboard a new app team
it is so much easier to just spin up a
new node for them rather than an
entirely new eks cluster we can onboard
these teams so much faster and with way
less overhead
and lastly the the number one concern
that keeps coming up is this idea of
balancing developer Freedom versus
platform opinionation
more developer Freedom means more
options and more control for the
developers but this comes at the cost of
not being able to inherit security
controls from the platform and as a
result it's going to be more work on the
app team so in other words they pay for
this Freedom of Choice with their time
but with a highly opinionated platform
Rob can sign off on 80 or more of the
security controls as soon as an app
onboards
this enables us to give those app teams
the the flexibility and the control
where it matters most which we believe
is at the app tier
and that's the real value out of Batcave
we want to enable an app team to inherit
as many security controls as possible to
reduce this amount of redundant toil all
across CMS
all right with that I'll pass it back to
Rob to talk about what we've done so far
all right so
most recently we just re we just hit a
milestone around getting our full and
independent ATO the reason why that's
actually important is the way that
control inheritance ends up working in
the federal government is you kind of
you pick and choose things from these
packages these compliance
and if you have this this more General
broad
um
package where the Batcave is just a part
of it then the people on the other side
of that work the developers the
information security people who are
embedded in those teams still ended up
have to kind of go through and pick and
choose in the GRC tools like this
control applies that one is only
partially applicable this one doesn't
apply all of that stuff as opposed to
having this more modular approach and so
having our own full and independent ATO
is one of those examples of a back-end
process enabler for our teams
now right now we're heavily focused on
that production level multi-tenancy
model this is also something fairly new
for CMS most of the time segmentation
has sort of been a very rigid construct
we're going to segment you into
different AWS accounts
um you know your prod account your
staging account your test account and
your Dev account and um and that becomes
very very expensive over time especially
if resources are not optimized inside of
those accounts which oftentimes they're
not and so uh sort of Shifting where the
segmentation happens to the namespace
layer inside of a cluster and a node
that is just it's way more efficient way
more cost effective and so we're leaning
pretty heavily into that because we have
a lot of groupings of systems that are
fairly
on the same they're in the same sort of
bucket and category with regards to risk
and functionality and portfolio owner
like that the person who pays the budget
for that thing and so like this is
something that we're really uh really
trying to optimize for right now
um a couple other things that are in the
very near future slash being worked on
now integration with other stuff inside
of the office of impatient technology so
other components of the cloud program
writ large uh single sign-on onboarding
being able to generate design diagram or
architecture diagrams and that sort of
thing onboarding your logs and stuff
into Enterprise monitoring and
operations all of those other things
like the ATO gets a bad rap for being a
big Blocker in terms of getting stuff
out the door
but there's all sorts of other stuff
that happens either before or after the
ATO that also is a huge strain on
development teams and it's just not as
just not as gnarly or you can't say it
as easily as ATO and so
so we're really trying to make sure that
all of those other things those
orthogonal pieces are integrated through
this sort of middleware Enterprise API
that we're that we're building right now
and then the last thing which you'll see
on the top here is uh our security data
Lake integration so this is part of a
broader cyber security objective that we
have right now so
the show hands of folks who are familiar
with like Splunk deployments and stuff
like that all right so normally
uh my condolences uh normally the
the way you'd like deploy one of these
things is it's like it's anchored in
these little pockets of the owner of the
thing of the team that manages the
Splunk cluster now that's not a
limitation of Splunk that's a limitation
of how teams typically deploy these kind
of tools and so when when you start
introducing this like Network this like
Federated Network segment Dynamic and
and security versus operations and
ownership and all of that creates all of
these like silos and and that you
basically have to like reach across and
get approval to reach across to do
anything with that data and so taking
from
taking from uh like the the Lessons
Learned in like marketing teams and like
big data teams and stuff where they're
basically they've collapsed all those
organizational silos around how they
manage their data into you know think
like big data Lake tools data breaks
snowflakes uh redshift things like that
and they're optimizing more on not like
building detection and response
capabilities in cluster but rather the
streaming ingestion pipes the ETL
pipelines that are bringing data in so
that way they have good structured data
with which to work and then they're
focused on re-skilling upskilling their
teams to be more like data analysts data
Engineers for example the last startup
that I was in
uh was this company Simon data it was a
marketing company you might think why
why in the world does marketing have
anything to do with federal health care
and it doesn't except for the fact that
I think most uh so I'm wearing all birds
right now now I could buy my all birds
off of an Instagram ad I could buy them
off of I could go to their website I
might buy them in a retailer I might see
a Facebook ad instead of an Instagram ad
and marketing similar to security and
this is a dynamic that exists in almost
every industry is you know all those
things represented different pockets of
data they lived in different places they
didn't synchronize with one another and
insight glean from Instagram did not
yield to insights or more targeted
advertising in the website or in Google
or what have you and marketers the team
that was marketers were more like
copywriters they're buying ads they're
doing stuff like that similar to cyber
security we had a lot of policy people
and a lot of operations people we didn't
have a lot of data engineers and
software Engineers so really we're
trying to take that same concept think
all the data that we as cyber security
people operate with and and will operate
with in the near future s-bombs
compliance uh like scan data you've got
vulnerability scan data you've got
pipeline outputs you've got
um you've got like uh like configuration
uh like scan data on your SAS tools
you've got Asset Management data both
from specific tools as well as
normalized in in some means you've got
maybe training data you've got logs all
of that stuff and you apply that to
scenarios like log4j where you could
kind of touch all those different parts
of the of your data ecosystem and if
they live in different places you can't
do that efficiently and effectively and
so this is really about like upskilling
our team to be able to do that more
effectively all built on top of like a
data data Lake back end so one of the
big things here is making sure that the
Batcave natively integrates with as a
data producer onto the data Lake and
then eventually as a data consumer
pulling stuff out of the data Lake to
enrich the stuff that we present back to
the dashboards and things like that to
the app teams so next slide
all right so a couple of the big
accomplishments that we're pretty proud
of at this stage
80 of
that says 100 it's not 100 it's 80
um Chris Hughes would beg to differ I'm
sure he would uh
there we go okay I like that answer
better
um it looks nicer so 80 fully inherited
of our 853 Baseline uh which we refer to
as ARS because you know we can't just
call things consistent names
um so
uh there's also a lot of
correlation and uh connection points
happening between Batcave and platform
of service and Engineering emphasis and
policy so one of the things that falls
under my group is we write policy that
informs the agency and so starting to
write policy that aligns with the road
map that we have at Batcave and and
other parts of these of the security
organization like when and where we're
going to start ingesting s-bombs where
you're going to be sending your logs how
you should be doing like if you're doing
continuous delivery how should that work
and so basically laying the groundwork
for adoption and value creation
here and then also this is something
that it's a little near and dear to me
given like I used to do a lot of red
teaming work in my former uh Consulting
life and so from day one we brought in
what's referred to as a purple team so
that's sort of the the
think red team think blue team sort of
sits right in between those two things
and they're acting as an interface point
between testing and like adversarial
emulation and testing and security
operations and detection and response
and then platform engineering like right
in the middle of that and like one of
the things that's an emphasis for this
team is not only like figuring out how
things are going to break like that's
important but taking the way that things
break and turning those translating
those into regression tests so that they
can go back and do the UPS like Upstream
deployment pipelines so that when
something breaks and we know it's going
to break that thing doesn't start
breaking again in the future think like
uh you you may have heard pen testers or
people who do security testing complain
that like they come back the next year
and I found the same things in the
client environment and that's annoying
or you know they they just you know they
uh they block my cross-aid scripting
payload and all they did was like filter
on my one thing and I just changed one
character and it worked again and like
so that sort of dynamic of regression
testing where every time that we do it
we're raising the floor on the overall
resiliency and security posture of the
platform and that that benefit is then
inherited by the tenant apps that go on
top of it
all right so this was
I'm going to spend a ton of time on this
slide but this was a one of the lead
Engineers for one of our early adopter
customers now this particular customer
was they were working in um in an
on-prem environment so deploying all
their stuff in a brick and mortar Data
Center and they were planning a
transition into AWS and so right off the
gates like they were they were looking
at like an 18-month time frame to do all
of that stuff to re-architect some
things re-architect their app to embrace
and work with like Cloud native
Solutions stuff like that set up their
new uh build deployment pipelines and
all of that stuff so we got our Clause
into them early on in these planning
migration discussions we knew some
people there and this is part of our
like early marketing strategies
internally and like we took their
18-month road map and we ended up
shrinking that down into like two and a
half three months and like that alone
like is is awesome and so something
we're really proud of we hope that it
can go even faster than that for future
migrations for future customers because
we learned a lot
um we're a little clunky like going
through this initial engagement
um you know because we're like basically
working within this broader construct of
other oit uh office of Information
Technology uh resources and so like
figuring out how best to work and
collaborate with them in the service of
the customer is something that like
we've learned a lot through this initial
engagement others like it and we're just
folding that back into the program so
every single run we're going to get
faster faster faster and more efficient
um all right so a big thing like
throughout this whole
talk we've been emphasizing
people and Partnerships and teamwork and
collaboration and so this is like this
is part of like part of this is doing
inside of like doing it inside of the
CMS context then part of it is working
across other agencies so across HHS I
think HHS is a collective cabinet agency
is one of the biggest in the government
I think FDA CDC NIH and HHS proper like
that covers a lot of the federal budget
and a lot of basically everything like
any time that you're interacting with
anything in the healthcare space in a
hospital
um or or what have you one of these
agencies touches something about that
and CMS inclusive so like sharing out
code Lessons Learned getting like design
Partners in early so we can start like
thinking about what other operating
divisions slash agencies are gonna like
the needs they're gonna have so we can
fold that in that's really really
important and then this other
bit like really leaning into a culture
of openness so this is something that's
important for our security team writ
large it's been uncomfortable for a lot
of people just being more transparent
being open sharing my deputy and I for
example we do monthly ask me anythings
we're like all of you if you wanted
could could join next uh next month like
we don't restrict them to anybody
um and we do and nothing is off the
table like you know we've talked about
wine and whiskey and some of them we've
talked about career advice we've talked
about uh security policy we talked about
tech stuff
um people try to like stump the chump on
you know like and we do all these things
live and that it makes people really
uncomfortable but what we wanted and
this program is a part of that is about
making security more accessible and and
like being able to con to empathize
through real world connection with other
people and that's just that's a real
important cultural value for us
um so with that we just wanted to say
thank you for taking the time this
morning to spend with us uh these are
all LinkedIn links if you have any
interest in following along with any of
the rants that we do or things that we
post on there
um and I think we have some yeah we've
got a little bit of time for questions
and uh yeah thank you so much everyone
[Applause]
yeah
are there any customers that have like
like a tenant application that would
have uh operate in that space
um right now
right now I don't think so
um they're more
um
like they're more like a traditional
apis or web applications stuff like that
I imagine that like yes we will get to
that like get to that place because
those sort of applications do exist
um in CMS the you know one of the things
that we've been trying to be very
cognizant of is like taking on the right
customers
both in terms of like status and and
influence inside the agency early on but
also like Tech complexity because with
every customer that adopts that's
burden reduced for not only them but for
us and for other parts of our I.T office
and so you know we don't want to get
muddled down in like a super complicated
deployment early on and we're we're not
going to learn a lot of like
replicable lessons and stuff like that
to other customers but you know we're
trying to so we're trying to be very
intentional now so that we can layer
like lay the groundwork for scaling and
I feel like you know that we'd have to
kind of pull out like what are the what
are going to be the bits that are very
applicable to a pipeline you know where
that like the pipeline is really going
to benefit that kind of app where does
it run and all of that stuff and so
um so not yet but I imagine soon
good question
all right go ahead
yeah so so like there's layers of that
across uh across like the AWS accounts
and stuff uh as you might imagine
um in some cases things that are like
internet facing and stuff do have laughs
in front of them
um which I think they're like I think we
could stand to do more of that even
internally
um you know like that runtime sort of
security introspection stuff
um and it's it's it's a growth area for
us in terms of like doing like basically
layering those in more places and it's
not even about in my mind like blocking
you know malicious traffic I think
one of the big benefits is being able to
create like these virtual patches it's
like you find something and before you
can fix it in code you can get like a
virtual patch out to like prevent a
thing from happening or like block you
know a cluster of ips that are that's
doing something or a pattern of of
traffic and then you know basically buy
yourself some time to fix the issue in
code and so like that's something that
like generally speaking not just for
Batcave deployments is is like quite
relevant for our like security
engineering teams
um
yeah
it's a good question
all right well thank you so much
everyone we're gonna like be hanging
around for uh the rest of the day so
come and chat and uh come get stickers
if you want them and uh yeah have a good
rest of the conference
[Applause]