thank you everybody for joining us today
we'll be talking about how to secure
your software supply chain at scale I'm
heimel and I'm a software engineer at
Yahoo security team and this is my
colleague hi I'm jungko also from Yahoo
security team and our security team is
on also known as the paranoids and here
is a logo for identifying us we are very
excited to be here
all right so here's the agenda for today
by the end of this talk we would like to
show you how a lot of the existing open
source tools can be deployed and
integrated with your existing ecosystem
and also some of the policies one can
create to
uh Safeguard again some of the supply
chain attacks
so let's get started so what is the
software supply chain
software supply chain is
made up of everything and everyone that
touches your code as part of software
development life cycle
beginning from application development
to CI CD Pipeline and eventually
deployment to production
it also includes information about the
software
like components uh the source the people
who wrote The Source Code and sources
where they come from it includes
information about the known
vulnerabilities supported versions and
so on basically everything that touches
it at some point
so what is the problem and what are the
various attacks that are possible in the
software supply chain
there are quite a lot of places an
attacker can Target your infrastructure
starting from compromising your Source
Code system example being the php's git
server when they were attacked or
compromising your build system uh
resentish example being the solar winds
attack or they could also trick users to
use bad artifacts which is known as typo
squatting and that's been happening
often in package managers
so why is software supply chain security
important to us these are some of the
recent attacks and headlines related to
software supply chain security
at the bottom you can see the most
recent attack on Pi torch where a
nightly version of pytorch which was
released during the holiday season most
likely had a rogue package which was
able to siphon off some sensitive data
from user system this attack is known as
dependency confusion and that's been
affecting a lot of the development
environments and package managers
right at the top uh you can see the one
for where there was a well-planned spear
fishing attack
uh where they were able to attack more
than 130 organizations and were able to
get around 10 000 OCTA and 2fa
credentials
so here's an obligatory side showing you
some scary figures
industry data suggests anywhere between
85 to 97 percent of Enterprise code base
is using open source
this means that most of your application
consists of code that you didn't write
the vulnerabilities in third party or
open source dependencies can pose a
significant security risk
supply chain attacks are on the rise and
according to the recent report by sonar
type the supply chain attacks have gone
up by 742 percent uh year over year over
the last three years
three out of five companies have been
targeted uh due to the supply chain
attacks based on angkor's report as well
so what is the industry doing in order
to secure software supply chain
actually quite a lot
so there are a lot of great tools and
resources especially open source and
proprietary with a wealth of security
guidance and resources that can help aid
In One Security Journey
recently cncf technical Advisory Group
also published a document that lists
down all Publications and references
that could help one in their Journey
especially it has information like the
policies security assessments use cases
and best practices
however it can be really hard and
intimidating to find the right choices
for your company or your situation
especially when a lot of these tools
either have overlap of functionality or
one tool depends on the other
in a in a company where the
infrastructure is already set up it's
really challenging and difficult to
figure out how to integrate these tools
in their existing ecosystem
when we at Yahoo were starting our
journey in software supply chain
security we faced a similar conundrum
and my colleague here will talk more
about what tools we used and how we
integrated in our existing ecosystem
thanks Hano Yahoo indeed has a large
software span system we are supporting
yahoo.com which is amongst the top 10
visited website in the world we have a
lot of services and products serving
high low traffics
internally there are about 60
000 build jobs running and about 5 000
images published to the registry on a
daily basis
and at the same time there are more than
700 kubernetes clusters running more
than 100 000 ports
and that is still now the whole picture
of Jaco's software suspension there are
still a lot of other kinds of artifacts
not being deployed to the kubernetes
Clusters like to the on-prem virtual
machines so Yahoo suffers a bench and
scale is large not only in the direct
quantity but also in terms of
tuning choices
within Yahoo we have different teams
with different requirements and needs
and each team may have their own path to
deliver their software
so this diagram lists some of the major
tools we are using on Yahoo from source
code management tools build systems
artifact stores and finally the
deployment environment
the variety of tools makes securing
software suspension of Yahoo challenging
so we must simplify the problem at hand
when we first started our journey we
decided to Pilot the security measures
and produce real value in a certain
software suspension has we choose the
cloud native path that is a GitHub
Enterprise a source called measurement
tool screwdriver as a build pipeline
internal site registry as artifact store
and finally kubernetes as a deployment
environment
for those who are not aware a
screwdriver is a sales lady platform
build an open source at Yahoo you can
also find this product on the cncf cloud
native landscape website and it is also
widely used internally at Yahoo
okay so as we all know software's
pension security has a lot of aspects
even if we have only one path there are
still a lot of security controls and the
best practice to follow
uh but luckily we do not need to start
from scratch because we have already had
some fundamental security controls in
place like static code scanning Ripple
Branch production to progress reverse
and so on
so after evaluating the existing
security controls and open source
standards we realized there were three
major gaps
firstly even if we have static code
scanning to check the proprietary code
we are not able to detect the
vulnerabilities or open source
dependencies
so we decided to introduce software
conversation analysis essay to fill this
Gap
in addition we are not able to check the
software and block the deployment after
the code is released from the Repository
so to fill this Gap we decided to
add two checkpoints in our software
development lifecycle while in the build
stage another in the deployment stage
we will work you through for this Recaps
what did we do in the following slides
uh first software conversation analysis
also known as essay
as Hannah said earlier
most of most of our application consists
of code we didn't write
traditional code scanning will just look
at the flow and logic of your
proprietary code and reports if there is
any potential vulnerabilities it will
not look how the open source
dependencies
so that's why we need a several
conversation analysis to fill this Gap
because those tools can those tools will
only focus on the Open Source
dependencies on their basic check
they can identify the women's Source
dependencies package names and address
check against the vulnerability database
and finally report
if they find any issue they could also
probably raise per requests to bump up
the version of your open source
dependencies which will in most cases
can feel fix the potential
vulnerabilities
so by applying essay tools we make the
progress of detecting and remediating
vulnerabilities or application code much
easier
uh however the images that will be
deployed to the kubernetes Clusters will
always have components other than the
application binaries
like base operating system and any other
package you could add
so having a
build-time vulnerability assessment to
hand to scan the whole image is very
necessary because it can not only catch
the vulnerability not solved in your
application code allows you the uh
issues in those actual components that
are integrated during the build time
in practice we use saved and drive to
generate s-bomb and vulnerability data
to do the assessment we also provide an
option to block a specific pipelines if
we found any severe vulnerability so in
the next time if another log4j crisis
occurs we can take actions and prevent
those vulnerable images from being
published to our registry
okay so uh after we have some Garage in
place in both vertical management tools
and be also some we would like to check
all the images that will be deployed to
our kubernetes clusters
uh so there are there are a lot of use
cases for example uh if an image is not
signed or it is from an untrusted
registry or it still contains any
unsolved vulnerabilities we can block it
or at least inform the inform Engineers
for those violations
to achieve the deployment time
verification we utilize a dynamic
animation control in kubernetes
it allows us to implement HTTP workbook
that can receive admission requests
check against predefined policies and
finally decide whether or not to develop
deploy a resource
and in practice we use both Yahoo
proprietary webhook and Kevin to achieve
our goal
so let's talk about some of the tracks
video during the deployment time
first one is ensuring prominence of
images exists
provenance is a bunch of records that
tell you various this image comes from
it can include information like who
commits the code which Ripple and branch
is this image originally from build
information and so on
we collect our prominence data from
GitHub screwdriver and registry
basically covers all three major steps
or software suspension
and those data are stored in the you
know provenance database
and this provenance store is based on
Graphics which is an open source project
that standardized provenance format
along with API and back-end solution
so here's a demo for showing you how
permanent staff can secure you from some
attacks
okay in this demo we will deploy we will
deploy three images the first one does
not have problems the second one has a
complete pronouns but it is problematic
the third one has a complete opponence
we designed the three policies to verify
these three image deployments
correspondingly and the first two images
are the malicious cases and service a
positive case a good case
so this is the first one
this image is uploaded directly by
attacker to the registry without passing
through the expected cell CD pipeline so
in this case our web hook cannot get any
problems data from our database
so it will reject the deployment
yeah this is a enormous set you can see
there's no resource repo or build job
information phone
and the second image this image is build
and uploaded from a forked repo with
malicious changes in this case even if
this image has a complete problems but
it will show this image is already
originally from
forked rival another transl
so our workbook will still reject this
because based on our policy
as you can see in the
error message it says Source Ripple
mismatch
we find it is from a first repo but
actually
uh
we expected to hear from a trusted
Ripple
okay lastly this image is
built from a valley source and pipeline
finally located in a trusted registry in
this case this image has a complete
provenance and the provenance
information has no problem so our
Macbook will allow the deployment
okay this is the end of this demo and
second check is the image signature
we want to make sure all images have
been deployed to kubernetes clusters are
signed during the in the in the build
system because it can help us verify the
integral integrity and publisher of the
images
Yahoo currently uses a self-managed
long-lived keys to sign the image
certain images
and this signing file has been
integrated to most of our standard
templates that builds and publish images
signing mechanism has been existing for
a long time but there was no enforcement
to verify the signature before
deployment so this chat can also fill
this Gap
here is a demo for this
firstly because the signal check is
directly integrated to the web hook so
there's no policy shown as a previous
demo
in this signal check demo we will deploy
two images
the first one is no sign in the build
pipeline so our webhole cannot find a
signature attached to this image in our
signature database
so it will reject it
and the second image
was signed in the field system
so our web hook will allow the
deployment
okay so here comes the third image first
image first and check
the motivation behind this check is to
encourage people to upgrade their image
regularly because an older image will
usually have more vulnerabilities
and if you didn't update your image for
for a long time
by the time you have to make the
security fix you may find the
patch data is to heal genius very
difficult and risky to make the change
lastly by regularly updating your image
you have to trigger your build pipeline
so by doing so you can notice your build
pipeline issue in time
to achieve the image first name check we
utilize the camera and Camera policies
here's a another demo for the first news
track
firstly this is a cavern or policy for
this track you can see it is it's just a
block any image builds more than six
months ago
you can also find this policy on the
keyboard no official website
okay in this the demo will also deploy
two images the first one is build about
a year ago so it is too still
in this case uh caverno will reject it
simply because it feels more than six
months ago
and
the other images built within a month
so Kevin will allow it
Okay so
the checks will be worth showing you uh
in the deployment time or in the units
build time are by no means expected to
be the full story
we could choose to evaluate nearly
arbitrary policies with necessary data
so for example if we want to achieve
vulnerability check during the
deployment time
um we are actually interesting
vulnerability data to our Graphics
database so that our web hook can fetch
and validate vulnerability data along
this provenance data and for this the
next two checks they can all be uh
achieved by applying a single criminal
policy
okay so here's the end for the details
and demos now my colleague ml will
summarize our work so far
thanks younger so just a brief summary
on what tools we have been using and uh
the timeline on how we reach there we
started our journey by around mid-2020
when we started our journey not a lot of
Open Source tools and solutions were
available so we built a lot of In-House
tooling and also used graphius as the
provenance store
by by early mid 2021 we were able to
collect most of the source provenance
and around 10 percent of the built
Providence were through our build
pipelines later 2021 we open source
graphius RDS which adds supports to
postgres database with graphius
ah early 2022 six store had emerged as a
really promising uh solution for both
signing container images and also a
testing software so we started exploring
that internally
for some of our build pipelines and
while doing that we were also working on
adding deployment checks which jung-ho
showed earlier so we use both kivarno
and Yahoo's proprietary policy checks
later that year and beginning this year
we've Incorporated some of the cosine
functionality to our existing build
pipelines and are also working on guac
for visualizing the s-bomb data which is
generated by sift and gripe
so what did we learn from our journey so
far
given the hybrid environment at Yahoo
with different teams learn working on
different projects and different tools
we faced quite a few interesting
challenges and few lessons were learned
during our journey as well
the first one is enhancing existing
developer workflows automatically
if the tool being built can do its job
behind the scenes or if it's it can be
integrated with the tools itself
it reduces the onboarding and learning
efforts by developers and by doing that
we reduce the friction between the
security team and the development team
because they don't need to update their
projects on a regular basis and this can
be done behind the scenes this also
helps us in reducing the time we go to
market or we go to actually the
deployment time
ah an example to Showcase this lesson is
when we started collecting the
provenance uh as mentioned earlier we we
use graphia so we integrated uh Source
metadata collection as part of GitHub
web books and for getting the build
metadata we integrated it with the built
a down step so any build which runs in
Yahoo was able to send the provenance to
the graphia store that way it gave us
around 70 to 80 percent of provenance uh
the remaining 20 is because they don't
use the standard tooling
and the same when we tried to do for
admission web hook uh the problem is lot
of the individual teams and owners have
their own clusters running and in order
to add the webhook to their clusters we
had to work with individual teams that
that took a lot of time because the
priorities were different and eventually
it took us around six months to make the
webhook as default
so that brings me to my next Point uh
that is and one of the most important
lessons we've learned is around adoption
uh and Adoption of tools and services
like the admission web hook across the
company
if even if there is a small portion of
the company which is not onboarded to
using these tools we may still be
susceptible to software supply chain
attacks so we need to ensure that
everyone in the T company uses or gets
onboarded to the admission webhook
and example for this being we made the
webhook as default for all eks
deployments uh but there were some other
teams which were using non-standard
tools or different deployments so for in
order for them to be onboarded we had to
either create a Helm chart so that they
can install it manually or we needed to
get behind them to make sure they can
actually adopt it so it's still a
challenge and we are still working on
increasing the adoption within the
company
a follow-up to that is follow up to the
pre-planning is ensuring that there is
enough visibility of the project
if we need to convey the business value
to the execs periodic status of update
of the project to the stakeholders is
important and along with selling the
overall mission we also need to
demonstrate the incremental value of the
project
the next one and an important one is
embracing open source Technologies
a lot of the solutions or tools which we
use for software supply chain security
are already available as part of Open
Source tools so embracing open source
source Technologies is quite important
uh we we should engage with the open
source community and also try to make
meaningful contributions that increases
the expertise in that and also gives
back to the community
and the last one is around continuous
feedback so performing continuous
testing on your solution and getting
periodic feedback from stakeholders is
important ensuring the requirements and
use cases are covered is important to
the success of the project
yeah the this project has truly been a
team effort and there are few folks uh
for we would like to thank just for the
guidance and yeah thank you
[Applause]
questions
good
sure so
ah oppa is a great tool and it's quite
powerful so when we started our journey
we we started working with oppa but as
we proceeded we we realized that uh oppa
is so powerful and the needs what we
have is not as uh granular which oppa
offers and also uh it as learning a new
language since oppa needs to have some
expertise for learning the language uh
it wasn't easy to adopt and add more
policies uh because at the end of the
day it's not just the security folks who
would be adding the policies but we
wanted to make it such that any admin
could add more policies to their own
clusters
so by using our in-house and keyword
policies it it's quite intuitive and
self easy to learn but in the future we
may revisit Opa if if we think that's
the need but
yeah for permanence check as I show in
the in the demo so there are basically
three uh Nursery maybe about several
checks so we can check the uh Source
repo information and build pipeline
information and kind of what what uh
what registry is it from
and actually for the performance but not
from products but during the
um there's other kinds of
the data storage in the graphics
database is a vulnerability data so we
can just fetch one ability data along
with the prominence data it is no
problem but we can check with problems
we can sell some policies that we want
to block a certain vulnerability like a
severe survey so actually basically
there are four kind of checks for a
provenance part
yeah deployment time check on three
proponents were for vulnerability
so I can take that so internally we do
mirroring of most of the open source
packages and repos so we eventually so
obviously it doesn't go through our
build pipelines because those are open
source so we won't have provenance for
those builds but for artifacts and
making sure those are internally signed
that's what we will make sure we do it
as part of provenance check
okay can you speak to the amount of
effort it took to do this like how big
is the team that implemented this
yeah that's a good question so uh it's
always a challenge to get a lot of folks
working on things like this because it's
unless you are attacked there's not a
lot of value you can prove to the execs
so I would say around four to five
people uh working on this and this not a
full time or that's not the only project
they work on so it varies and I would
say around 60 percent is worked on this
project over the past three years or so
part of Yahoo is that is that like
people 60 of somebody who spoke to them
pictures or platform engineer
ing so we are the paranoid security team
so within that we are the engineering uh
pillar so we work primarily on building
security and devsecops tools to uh make
sure the infrastructure is set up so out
of that around four to five of us work
on this part
I want to add on that because we have
already finished most part mostly the
coding part or the infrastructure
building part now we are more focused on
how to increase an adoption number how
to collect those numbers from our system
and make a list of them that inform the
engineers to improve the the their
system
good
I'm sure your Jenkins information
for the wrong repository right
yeah so uh when a CI CD job tries to
push an artifact which it generates to
artifactory or oci registry we we need
to make sure or we need to explicitly
ask the artifactory to only allow
artifacts generated by pipeline X
instead of pipeline y being sending it
to it so if let's say there is a node
package which has authorization to
be created by pipeline X ah
artifactory would have that information
so we can map the image ID with the
pipeline ID and that's how we ensure
that only the images which are marked
will be allowed to be published as part
of the pipeline
yeah does that answer your question
right
has an authorization like we internally
we use a product called Essence it is
also versus a product is uh kind of our
back our back system this is also a CSF
product so you can find in this in the
in the website and every time we send
the prominence to the graphics database
we actually send a kind of a mission
required to the essence and if you can
guess like a permission they can just
put the performance into database
otherwise the gear cannot
so yeah that's what we did
okay that's the next one yeah
yeah I think those decisions were made
way before we actually did it and that's
been happening for a long time but we
are now now with cosine and six store uh
being widely adopted we are looking at
exploring that solution of having either
short-lived keys or ephemeral keys by
going the keyless route to use those
instead
yeah personally it could be just use
cosine with long-lived sign keys but
finally we can gradually uh add some
record infrastructure to achieve the key
less signing so here's uh it's not that
easy path to go but it will gradually
work towards that
no
yeah I don't think it's a requirement
and I may be wrong again but we are
working with the right folks within
Yahoo to make sure that we change
because it's been you always been around
for so long uh it's and the open source
tools have been coming in recently as
well so it's a change of say uh learning
curve as well so that's what we're
working on
sorry good
so we we've just started collecting
those and doing the vulnerability checks
the plan is to tie the s-bombs with the
freshness policy so that as as we ensure
that an image or an artifact cannot be
deployed for more than six months uh
which is a stale image having an s-bomb
which uh is older than six months Also
may not add value because we won't have
any artifacts which are running for old
which are older than six months So the
plan is to have it either for a year or
so because teams may have exceptions or
allowed they are allowed to deploy an
older image so but yeah we that small
policy question then uh developer or an
uh engineer question I feel like so yeah
and we are now sending the vulnerability
data or s-bomb data in the build time to
any database right now we are actually
collecting the vulnerability data about
relative from an unsynchronized resource
to to uh to uh for the vulnerability
data it's not from the pure stage
it looks good
images
those checks or policies and the second
one is on the freshness
how do you determine the freshness
state or some
or something sure so to answer your
first question uh so we we use
internally gripe and sift to generate
the s-bomb and vulnerability data and
currently it spits out lot of
information about vulnerabilities so
ranging from critical to medium level
and we use that information along with
the information which the vulnerability
team within Yahoo generates which which
may determine not all vulnerabilities
are critical to Yahoo and it can
shortlist those so we then determine
based on the vulnerabilities which Yahoo
marks at as critical
and with what shift generates and then
based on that we make a decision whether
to block that image or uh just report it
and continue processing
database
right now it's implemented internally
because this is more of a build time
check and not deployment that okay the
time is of the essence so but I think we
are out of time but thanks for your
question
ah you had a follow-up question as well
we can
it's also a great time and just based on
create time right now we have a plan to
check all the components create time of
every components uh yeah we are just
working on that we haven't have a final
solution for that
we can take the questions offline I
think we are out of time yeah yeah
uh
sorry can you repeat the question once
more
so we currently integrate our the SD
command with screwdriver provides with
all the standard templates so before it
gets published to artifactory uh We've
integrated that SD command to all all of
the existing pipelines so it gets
scanned and determines whether to
proceed to publish it or not
so yeah we use as mentioned gripeshift
to get that information and some
propriety code to figure out whether to
push or not
I think we are done thank you guys thank
you guys
[Applause]