my name is Mark Hahn I'm a Security
Solutions architect with qualis if you
want to follow along with the slides you
can take a look at that URL there in
blue at the bottom you can pull that up
on your phone if you want to keep the
slides up while we're looking at that
it's got speaker notes if you um press
sort of at the bottom of the mrap
presentation you'll see speaker notes
and this is hi I'm Ted Hahn I'm his son
we are a father-son team and we like to
do these presentations together we're
having some fun with it I'm a site
reliability engineer a Consulting site
SRE I help a number of small startups do
Cloud native write security AWS all of
the you know stuff around kubernetes
clusters
um whether that be you know the basic
setup to running large distributed apps
on them
cool
so uh this is our presentation on kubet
LS it's a tool that helps you achieve
Mutual TLS by injecting certificates
into every pod
in 2002 we built a the original version
of this it's a web admissions web hook
pod which mutates the Pod
and we've updated it to take advantage
of new changes that are coming in uh in
newer versions of kubernetes so in
particular there's a feature called
cluster trust bundles that allows you to
set the the scope of trust for for uh
cluster
so
um let's start off with what is a trust
bundle um you know I imagine some of you
have been to the various spiffy talks
um so you probably have some idea but at
the same time I don't think any of them
defined trust bundle particularly well
um a trust bundle is
at its most simple a trust bundle is a
bunch of CAS
um you probably already use a trust
bundle that is you know your browser's
web CA store
um that's a trust bundle but that is a
very broadly scoped trust bundle
um we want much smaller scope trust
bundles um typically we want trust
bundles per organization
um or even two or three for your
organization
um so
this is yeah so this is what uh
essentially you know you're familiar
with this this is how web certificates
work this is how
um https TLS certificates work
um so at the bottom there there is a
workload certificate that workload is
probably a web server
um and that web server is signed by some
intermediate cert that then in in that
certificate that you get back from your
your signing Authority typically
contains both your workload cert and
then the intermediate search the chain
up to uh to a CA and then at the top
level there is that root certificate on
most systems that you're running your
phones your your laptops your Linux
servers that are deployed in your in
your Cloud architecture and on your
clusters that root CA contains about 160
different Cas
um some of which you know some of which
are just well next slide oh no
um so some of which you know and some of
which are you know the Peruvian Central
Authority go ahead
um so what what do trust bundles allow
you to do
um so trust bundles
you know allow you to verify that
somebody is saying something right
um web certificates contain contain
claims typically Sans
um and web certificates you know verify
that the trust bundle has said these
things
um so what trust bundles will allow you
to do is to make the make well they'll
make your Docker images smaller and
they'll allow you to much more rapidly
update uh
trust bundles such as the web root of
trust currently you build the web root
of trust into the very base most layer
of your Docker image
um so you've got all of those things and
they're actually you know sometimes even
the majority of a Docker image the
Google distro list image has just four
things in it of which the trust bundle
is the the largest by far that's not
true for most Docker images but you know
that is that is one of the base most
layers but sometimes that trust bundle
changes right
um just a few months ago trust core was
removed from every web CA
um you know is is in the process of
being removed I think they have like two
or three more days before they're
disallowed
um but that is still embedded right that
certificate is still embedded to all of
the docker images you built last week
um cluster trust bundles can be mounted
like config maps and you will Mount them
like config maps on Etsy SSL to update
the web route of trust dynamically so
you can keep up keep that up to date
regardless of when your Docker image was
built
um but more importantly
trust bundles can be mounted like uh
like config maps and you can have a
bunch of different trust bundles for all
of the different little Scopes that you
need
and so that's what we're looking for is
to try and limit the scope of trust so
as we said you know your that top row of
CAS of of root Cas is essentially the
the web root of trust and the trust
that's in most Linux distributions
Amazon Linux Google District list Alpine
you name it it's got 160 of those what
we recommend and what what our opinion
is you know on your clusters you
basically want a very limited set of top
level Cas you want essentially your
internal private certificate authority
to be your root of trust and no others
maybe maybe a partner or two but not on
every server that you've got so what we
what what we're looking to do is try and
Implement uh provide a way to implement
easily
trust bundles that let your scope to
just the part in blue and not the 150
items in red right there's no reason
that that any server should have to
trust
you know a a Peruvian Cafe website but
your your system would accept that
Peruvian Cafe website's TLS certificate
because it's got an intermediate chain
that Roots up to
um the the Peruvian root Authority which
is in your trust bundle and and part of
this point is not that you shouldn't
trust those all of those web certs but
you should trust them for when you're
going to the web for most applications
for most of your internal calls you are
not going to the web you should be using
a trust bundle that is scoped to your
internal Network
um so the the web to root of trust will
still be around it just won't be the
default for most of your applications
right so in our keynote this morning we
just added this slide
um the the presenter Zach um Zach
Zach butcher mentioned you know trying
to get to a zero trust architecture
these were the five points that he made
Coupe TLS helped to implement those
first three points very easily so we'll
show you how this works yeah so Coop TLS
automatically injects certificates that
provide workload identity onto every pod
and every container in the cluster
um they provide uh privacy by TLS
encryption they provide authentication
by TLS Mutual encryption and
authorization comes very quickly from
that
um simply because you're you know once
you have those identities those per pod
per service account identities
authorization becomes a a very quick
layer
um so how do you do how do you do secure
networking on kubernetes well you know
in the last talk there was a number of
of they they went over a bunch of those
ways
um any number of talks here are going to
talk about
um different ways to do that so uh the
two most common ways are these first two
sub bullets is one is you're using
sidecars and
um we're not a big fan of side cars they
don't they don't cover all the space
um they're complicated they're typically
managed in Enterprises by teams that are
not your application development teams
so they're orthogonal to your
application architecture uh the other
thing is that your your secure your
application security architecture should
be designed in your application and one
of the one of the 12 factors in the 12
Factor app is that there's a sort of a
single point you're you minimize
dependencies and so if your security of
your application Arc textures depending
on not only your application but also
these sidecars now you've got two points
that are that are doing that not a
single single dependency for it
um
the other choice is some kind of cni
complex cni thing with with Calico or
something where you're trying to limit
network access and who can who can send
packets to who and again this is at the
wrong layer it is in your network
architecture your your application
security architecture is now dependent
on your network architecture and and the
two have to change in sync and that can
be very difficult so neither of these
two ways are very
um they they're difficult to manage
typically in most organizations you have
two separate groups that do it and so
there's a lot of communications got to
happen our recommendation is the right
way to do this is that every service
speaks TLS natively so it doesn't send a
packet anywhere unless it's over a TLS
link and to do that you need
certificates in every pod so that you
can create that TLS Connection in in our
demo in our demo repository which is
linked at the end of this presentation
we show different examples of how you
configure your service so that it speaks
TLS natively how to get how to get that
private key and that certificate bundled
into however your particular language
does web servers and it really is
usually that simple as you know when
when you are making a grpc connection
you have to specify I am doing this the
insecure way or you can specify I am
doing this the Kube TLS way we provide
just a grpc dial option that makes it
you know just picks up the right place
picks up the right certificates for your
cluster we provide a Java version of
this as well that yeah and if you've
ever gone you know Google how to do mtls
with Java like half of it is how to
create this not half it 90 of us how to
create the certificate and and ten
percent of it is like here's the Java
code that just simply uses that that
certificate private key and we've
simplified that 90 down to five percent
right
um one of these days I'll get around to
writing the python version
um yeah but so
um the nice thing about TLS everywhere
at the application Level is that there
is no chance of it being sniffed
whenever it is leaving your pod and in
fact your applications uh you know
memory space it is TLS encrypted it's
TLS native it's encrypted and it's
mutually authenticated everywhere you go
so yeah what is what is Coupe TLS at at
its most basic it is it is an admission
controller it's it's a mutating web hook
configuration object inside of your
kubernetes cluster what what that means
is the kubernetes cluster is going to
based on the filters that you set up in
the in the in the yaml for this object
it's going to send every pod request to
our
um to our service it makes a web call to
our service we return beta data back to
the the kubernetes master we modify that
incoming pod request add the certificate
secrets to add certificates to it that
contain the secrets so that they're
mounted on a file system visible to that
pod and so all that pod has to do is
pick those certificates up for book from
a well-known location
um and so this is the building blocks of
uh
um trust architecture so yeah it's got a
private key a matching private key and
it's got a sense actually the trust
bundle so it's got the root certificates
that you care about for this pod in
there which is basically just your
internal CA in most cases we'll talk
about the different types of patterns
that you'll use
that bottom bullet will get replaced by
the cap when it's doing cluster trust
bundles when that feature is added to
kubernetes and then all you need to do
is provide a secret and a key and this
is the building blocks of an
architecture that we'll talk about yeah
um yeah I think we've already mostly
covered this but your application should
speak only TLS
um your your organization itself is a
zone of trust
um right there is no such as thing as as
zero trust but you can make your
application to application connections
the start of a zone of trust and once
you have done so the you adding the the
you know identity aware part of allowing
things to connect uh becomes very simple
right once you have the the core
identity
and encryption provided identity and
authentication provided on every request
um the rest of this you know just falls
into place
so this is an example of how not to do
it which is basically just the side card
pattern we think is flawed because
there's open text it is as the previous
presenter mentioned like if somebody
somebody is a muck on your network which
you know I mean you have to think of
that as a valid possibility
um you have to assume breach and so if
you assume breach that clear text
connection can be sniffed and and used
in in various nefarious ways so this is
why we don't like this architecture we'd
rather that that application pod speak
TLS so that's encrypted well before it
hits any of your network architecture
inside the code inside the running
application it's encrypted before it
hits Network and just to be clear this
is hard to sniff this is not this is not
easy to happen on the other hand
istio fills open
um if your side cars aren't injected
your application will still try to talk
and the proxy won't be there and it'll
just talk to the network
um that's a problem that's that is
actually pretty much the Crux of our
argument and istio fails open you don't
want that and there are ways to like
bypass the the network if I have a rogue
app that's on that's been deployed to
the cluster I can ignore the fact that
there's a sidecar there and talk now you
can fix that with complex cnis but those
are complex dnis that you know yeah
um yeah
so this is our opinion this is much
easier to uh to implement in our opinion
although this looks as complicated as
anything else this is just a set of
repeated patterns done the same way with
slightly different regular pre-planned
variations on what they are so here's
yeah so this this is what an app looks
like right it has it is serving
something and it is acting as a client
um and it does so with you know
certificates provided but as or
certificates chaining up to your trust
bundle
um it connects to you know it has an
identity on your network
um and that identity might tell it might
say you know I am the server for x and
that identity might say I am the client
that has this service account
um and you might just you know put both
of those into the same client
certificate
um as kubetls does it just creates a
client certificate
um a client slash server certificate for
each pod when it comes up it figures out
which Services it should be valid for so
it adds the DNS names the appropriate
DNS names to it as DNS Sans
um and it adds the the service account
in uh as both the common name and the
spiffy
um sort of style ID
um and probably more as we you know
figure out and turn add feature Flags to
to make this work in interesting ways
um there's still some you know question
about how exactly those identities
should be represented though spiffy
seems to be a pretty clear you know
pretty commonly used
so there's another way to to apply this
same pattern so this would be talking to
Partners on the web so
um there are two different ways to do
this we prefer the way on the top
because we think it's it's it's more
long-term robust but let's talk about
that so what you do is
um in your internal service and their
internal service you trade trust bundles
and that way when their API server uses
its internally generated certificate to
talk to your server you're going to
validate that certificate that you're
going to do an mtls Mutual TLS
authentication of the incoming clients
are with the trust bundle that that's
been injected into your pod that trust
bundle in this case is your partner's
trust bundle and therefore you trust
that certificate on on the calling side
there your partner's API is going to
make a call to a web server and when
that web server sends back the hello IM
server XYZ essentially hello I am blue
server internal API it checks that blue
certificate see if it's valid and it
does so against your trust bundle which
is the blue trust bundle and so it says
yes this certificate chain matches
cryptographically so we we're good to go
we'll accept you know what we believe
we're talking to the correct you know
blue server and that yellow certificate
that we send down the line the blue
server is able to validate that yellow
server as belonging to the yellow
company
um the other way to do this is basically
not to trade trust bundles but trade
certificates that works just as well
because the blue server will be
validating a blue certificate against
the blue trust bundle that works uh the
problem with that is that you want to be
able to rotate your certificates pretty
fast and that means exchanging
certificates with your partners on a
regular basis say every 60 days every
every month every week like whatever
your
aggressive certificate rotation plan is
you're probably not going to get down to
seconds with that probably not good
seconds but the upward but your
certificates your your Cas aren't going
to change all that often so that's
something you can do yearly and then
still rotate your certificates you
rotate your blue certificates as fast as
you want they take their yellow
certificates as fast as they want
YouTube pretty much don't care what
you're doing operationally so that's why
I just care that you trust each other
you care that you trust each other
um so here is the details on what a TLS
certificate
um looks like
um so we we start by you know being
called as a web hook we look up the
container services so
um one of the the flaws in our model is
that whatever Services the pot is
associated with when it starts up are
the host names that they get uh if you
create the service after you create the
Pod then you're out of luck if you
change the Pod afterwards you change the
labels on either the Pod or the service
after words and change the services it
matches to then you're out of luck
which is fine so long as you don't do
that very often it's also fine if you
move away from doing the DNS Sands and
start moving to a model where rather
than authenticating the services you
authenticate the service accounts that
you're trying to connect to
um and that's sort of the the step that
you want to go to eventually
um but for the moment you know DNS Sands
is is really easy and compatible with
everything
um so Coupe TLS then creates a CSR
um csrs are an object a top level
cluster level object in kubernetes
um and you can use them to do
certificate signing and approval
um it will approve or uh its controller
to approve will approve and then it
attaches uh it attaches a secret to your
pot by way of mutating your pod
um and respond back to that with to
kubernetes with that
um yeah so these are the the key fields
that we use in in uh the x509
certificate that we're creating and
injecting into into the Pod
um so uh the common name is the name of
the Pod so common name used to be the
website that it served for but now that
has moved to the sand the subject
alternative name so we've used sand many
times without defining it but the sand
is the subject alternative name and
that's the list by which most of your
HTTP mechanism will validate like am I
talking to server X if the sir if the
certificate that server X presented you
contains the sand that says serverax
then yes you're talking to them I know
by the way that it it cryptographically
chains up to the root right that's what
we do so uh the name of the Pod and the
subject alternative name it's a DNS with
the names of the service the name of the
Pod and any other DNS name that makes
sense uh based on the flags that you
give Coupe TLS we also throw in a a the
ID is based on the service
and so you can use this with with your
spiffy IDs we set the key usage so in
n8x509 certificate there's a field that
says how can you use this key there are
a couple of values there one is this is
a root CA this is a this is a signing
typically an intermediate CA or this is
a web server or this is a a client
certificate and we set them both you are
a web server and a client certificate so
that you can use the same certificate on
either side on the client side or the
website we do the same thing that let's
encrypt does yes that's that's what's
important
um and then it also you know has the
identity of the root it's signing up too
um so let's do a demo demos are fun yes
uh apologies to Semisonic here yeah for
the lyrics
um let's mirror this and let's make this
a little bit bigger
that big enough can people read that it
probably helps if I move it up so you
can actually see what's going on
um
so I already have some of the pods
running but I am going to delete it so
that we can see a fresh one
so what we've got is a a greeter service
and a greeter client that will demo
um and they agree it's the hello world
example it's the grpc hello world
example but modified to use TLS nicely
as we want it to
um so here is
our pod
and we can exec into it
um
and look at its
uh
look at the certificate that has been
generated
uh it helps if I
get my Flex quite right
cool
so here is a certificate
um you can see its issuer is
our issuer and that will match up with
the ca certificate that it's also
provided in that file system you can see
that
the DNS names it's got its uh the
service name it's got the Pod name and
it's got a spiffy uid
um
and it's just a standard TLS
uh client server server
RSA at the moment I was putting around
with adding uh ecdsa but you know close
enough
um and this more or less works and you
can see
the CSR that was generated
a few seconds ago when I deleted this
pod
um you know Kube TLS went through the
process of creating this CSR ish
approving it
um a signer that we've set up for this
which you know you can use cert manager
you can use an external signer or you
can use a very basic one that is here
for this demo
um all of those work it it's agnostic to
the actual signer
um which you know allows you to provide
your own or or do something better
um and then we can just you know
create uh call a service
uh
yeah oh yeah
so the greeter service the greeter
client that's just a batch job that runs
and exits into the Pod runs and and and
then shuts down and because the job
kubernetes doesn't restart it but saves
the logs and so we can examine the logs
after it's run yeah and so you know this
just connects
um it connects to the the appropriate
name
um it gets the greeting and it also sees
uh the service account that we've been
running as so if I were to modify my
greater client
um I can set the service account name
that has chosen a very weird
indentation
here we go
can you stop for one second yeah so
scroll down a little bit we've got some
stuff coming out but when you look at
the um
um
okay yeah I don't know what you're
pointing at yeah no I was
um
so we can create another version of it
with a different service account running
is a different service account
and
now it has this other identity visible
to it again through the the coupe DLS uh
certificate and that this through other
identity is not it's not our client
saying that that is the server that it
is connected to that has said You know
here I know who you are I can verify Who
You Are
um so what else is there that is
interesting
um the other thing that's sort of
interesting is that you know it's mtls
right if I override the CA and I use
some other random self-signed mtls cert
oh geez
how did I screw this up
there's a mix of tabs and spaces and now
I am realizing it
to fix this
oh yeah
cool
I don't know why you have a caps lock
key
you can create yet another copy of this
and this one will fail because it is
using a
self-signed certificate
um this one is actually failing on the
client side because it's signed by an
unknown Authority but we can have it
fail on the uh
on the other side when we present it an
unexpected key
um and if we go look at the logs of our
oh well okay the debug logs are not
working it should have printed out
that we got a failed connection from
this other server that we denied a
connection right actually so the first
the first failure was when we saw the
other side certificate like when it sent
us our certificate when it sent it
server hello certificate I am server XYZ
along with that certificate we looked at
it and said that doesn't chain to our
certificate Authority so we're closing
the connection from the client side the
second error was we accepted that
certificate because it did chain up and
then we sent it an invalid certificate
that didn't chain up to its cluster
trust bundle and so the server closed
the certificate on that side it says use
of closed network connection which means
we tried to write because we thought
this was going to work but the server
closed down on us because it didn't
trust our certificate
um cool I think that's all we have a
couple of wrap-up slides yeah
um so yeah let's move back here yeah
there we go yeah
um
this makes it really easy to you know
have certificates populated and have
certificates populated in your
applications namespace so your
application can make use of certificates
rather than trying to wrap it in some
Network layer that does this all
magically
um you know their their advantages to
both kinds of magic we like ours yeah
um we think all your developers should
learn how to use TLS and mutual TLS like
we think that's that should be the price
of entry for being a programmer on the
on cloud native but also that we should
make it simple enough that they can know
again you know your your mtls demo is 95
playing with certificates we've
collapsed that down to certificates are
provided for you just do the right code
yeah
um and you know there there is some
agnosticism to Identity policy
um we intend to provide a reasonable set
of defaults that you can flip on and off
um and hopefully one day it will you
know be what just one but at the moment
there's still some some question
um once everybody's establishing
authentication through uh mtls then the
authorization layer becomes you know
relatively easy you can see who you're
talking to so then you can pick what
their actual authorization level is
uh and I think there's so other future
directions
um private Keys should be generated on
the nodes and never leave the nodes
currently they're created through
Secrets
um that's sub-optimal if they were
generated on the nodes then this then
the private key material would never
leave the nodes
um that would be great
um so we're planning on moving to a CSI
model there is not ready for demo but
there's some work on that
um so that the so that rather than
mounting a secret you mount a Kube TLS
CSI that just generates the C generates
uh for you the private key material when
when the node comes up and the rest of
it happens uh pretty much the same way
but it happens on the Node rather than
at a central set of PODS yeah on your
cluster so because it happens on the on
you know those that logic is on every
node and the private Keys stay on every
node
um never getting transmitted even though
it's being transmitted by the by the
kubernetes control plane in TLS we'd
rather just not transport those those
around yeah
um and this should be built into
kubernetes
um but you know that's our opinion we
like it yeah the trust plus the cluster
trust bundles is one step in that
direction we hope it's a huge step well
we we hope that will knock down those
dominoes and move forward yeah cool plan
for world domination
um yeah here is our repo here is our
presentation slides and here is the
session feedback link so sorry to keep
you from the vendor Booth crawl so there
should be beer available now
soon but thank you we're here for
questions okay
[Applause]
uh yes though in a branch yeah
I I will be glad to help you run that
demo on your cluster if you would like
to if you look at the
ticket yeah
go ahead
um yes but we're not confident enough in
the code quality yet to do that
um
mostly because I wanted to make the demo
work yeah
cool
thank you very much question in the back
um so we work with any CA that provides
a kubernetes signer
um so the
that is a very short list at the moment
that's cert manager
um but at the same time there is also a
not even in the branch but a a super
super janky demo of here is how you use
a awsca to provide a kubernetes signer
uh that I you know spent 20 minutes on
last weekend so let's let's talk about
it I'm I'm glad to to do the work to
make that work and I do intend to do the
work to make that work Microsoft has CA
like parts of their Azure CA are exposed
in their in their AKs stuff right oh
then then that'll then it will just work
yeah
it should just work but if that's
already if that is already exposed then
yeah it should just work
um
right so I've I've tried it with you
know our own CA and I've tried it with
uh cert manager and I see no reason why
it wouldn't work with the other CA that
I've used which is the hash record Vault
signer
um for csrs and that like anything that
is a kubernetes CSR signer will work you
know unless there's something really
weird about it
yeah yeah
cool
excellent question thank you
you get an extra beer yeah
um yes and no I mean the the simple
answer is that a trust bundle is all
equivalent
um in most SSL implementations and that
means that you want to be careful about
what you put in us in your ca list
there are additional like
I I do believe that you are getting at a
leading question about how openssl
handles CA pems which I well
yeah
oh yes of course
yeah and that that answer is no that
answer is very clearly no
um and if you start your application and
then we and then you want to rotate
certificates the answer is still no
um your application unlike with some
other things like it doesn't pick up new
certificates on a regular basis we don't
provide a rotation mechanism of these
secrets
um what should you do about that
kill your pot kill your kill your pod
kill your pot every 30 days yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
no no no pretty pretty simple
um yes
but at the same time like we're we're
going for the the least common
denominator here of we don't expect yeah
yeah we we don't we are absolutely limit
limited by all of the limitations of
your open SSL Library whether that be
openssl Libre SSL go Lang's ago SSL
implementation whatever you're using
whatever yeah please not bouncy castle
yeah okay
cool
well we got the one minute I think we
yeah
we're good yeah so time to turn off the
mics