hello everyone I'm Emily Fox for those
of you that are familiar with me you
probably see me pop up in a lot of
different open source communities in
addition to the cloud native Computing
Foundation today though I'm going to
talk to you a little bit about the
history behind this event for those of
you that have been in the cloud native
security for a while now you'll know
this event is very near and dear to me
it's basically my baby I love this event
because it was my first big project that
I volunteered to assist with when I
joined the open source community and it
was also kind of the first time I had
heard of the security technical Advisory
Group however at the time they were
called the special interest group for
security
it was 2019 I was in Barcelona attending
kubecon Cloud native Con Europe and it
was there that I was introduced to Cloud
native security and this group they were
evaluating the security posture of
several Cloud native projects I was
researching at the time for a project
that I was working on it was there that
I attended to talk from Justin cormack
on Project Security reviews
in addition to kindly answering all of
my barrage of questions both on camera
and off camera he mentioned to me that I
should probably check out this group
they were still young in the cloud
native space the foundation was still
kind of growing and ramping up they were
looking to break new ground and develop
new practices to allow us to apply
traditional security practices into
Cloud native technology stacks and
really Drive What mattered in this
growing community space and as always
open source is always looking for
contributors and Technical advisory
groups and special interest groups are
no exception so you'll hear me refer to
them as the security tag or sync
security throughout this talk but
ultimately it's the same group of
fabulous people
so I started lurking in their meetings
just like dialing into the zoom sessions
trying to understand a little bit more
about what they were talking about what
they're trying to accomplish reading
their docs asking clarifying questions
to make sure that I understood the
direction that this group was heading in
they had a
ask to fulfill their mission and their
Charter but
enthusiastic encouraging and flexible
and understanding like we're still
trying to figure a lot of this stuff out
but ultimately what we needed to do was
figure out how do we prevent
unauthorized access for cloud native
applications and workloads in a way that
makes sense for all of the adopters in
addition to the maintainers of these
projects and as long as our work aligned
underneath is the three primary focus
areas of the charter
we were Unstoppable
the charter was set up so that the tag
could fill the Gap in security guidance
instruction and tooling and well just
generally provide information that
wasn't there at the time organizations
were leveraging Heritage and checklist
security requirements completely
ignorant of all the possibilities that
cloud native could provide from a
security perspective so we set out to
Define how to protect workloads to
ensure that they're still usable where
security is not a noticeable hindrance
to the user or the engineer's workflow
we also needed to figure out how can we
take the existing security control
bodies and apply those principles to
establish a common understanding and
corresponding tooling to help developers
really meet those security requirements
but perhaps the hardest and most complex
yet we're still trying to solve is how
do we break down the complexity in
audits because Auditors really need to
have an understanding of how Cloud
native architectures are supposed to be
developed built and operated in a secure
manner
oh and do that for every single domain
because kubernetes is just one of the
many faucets of cloud native security
and you can make an argument that due to
the Natural complexity that kubernetes
has it is its own domain of expertise
the stickers on this slide are just a
couple of the domains that we still need
to do explore at the time and they are
their own domain expertise areas
oh and we had we couldn't really fit all
of those into the cubecon cloud native
con security track and talk about
kubernetes at the same time there just
wasn't enough space and many of these
domains hadn't been approached from a
security perspective in 2019 we needed
an Avenue and a place to explore and
kind of Drive content along these areas
to inform adopters and maintainers about
how we should be doing Security in these
specific areas we needed that Avenue to
build up Security in Cloud native
because it is more than just kubernetes
it is a multi-objective
multi-constrained problem space with a
lot of different domains it spans the
entire sdlc and whatever comes next we
have to be prepared for it
so Michael Ducey one of our community
members at the time who he had
previously been running some local
devops days and was really into the open
space scene he filed issue number 209 in
June of 2019 to propose a one-day event
that went beyond the current security
track at kubecon there were 14 of us
that jumped on board for that issue when
we started planning we used the GitHub
issue to plan all of our meeting notes
and a Trello board to figure out how the
heck do you run a conference and how the
heck do you figure out what an open
space schedule should look like for a
security conference
we had a lot of amazing submissions and
we were able to gather to pull together
an amazing day of talks as well as a
full open space schedule to really drive
a lot of discussions Ian Coldwater in
Coldwater and Duffy Cooley started our
day off as a throwback to kubernetes
talking about kubernetes defaults and
how do we move forward in that space
if you look back at the first open space
schedule in the first Sig security day
talks you'll find a lot of the same
topics that we talked about in 2019 are
still being talked about here today but
the difference is that now that we know
more we can share a lot of those
learnings with our peers and colleagues
and build on top of each other's
learnings
and you'll also find out we talked about
software supply chain security attacks
before it was cool we talked about
defaults we talked about compliance and
machine learning and it was a lot to
cover in just a single day event
it was a huge success the program
committee and myself and the other
colleagues were stoked to hold another
one and make it bigger make it better so
in 2020 we held one for Europe because
we wanted to ensure that the European
audiences security concerns and Care
abouts were similar or at least
addressed within this conference and
then later that year because that one
was a success we did the same thing for
North America in 20 and 2020.
what we did though is after that initial
event we performed a retrospective to
really understand going from day one to
the second event and the third event to
get community members feedback we had a
lot of interest from folks so Twitter
chatter was strong excellent uh
discussions by community members and the
open space Arena and then
we we got a little hint that people
wanted something a little bit more
Hands-On they wanted workshops they
wanted tutorials they wanted something
to allow them to take the theory of
cloud native Security and apply it into
practice so
that's what we decided to do with that
North America
we held a CTF and it was fabulous if you
were here yesterday you heard Andy and
Andres talk about how we executed those
ctfs and how our community members
responded and that's kind of been the
thing with a lot of this is partnering
with new community members on what we
can do to make this a positive
experience for everyone making sure that
they have those Lessons Learned and that
they can take them back with them to
their companies and organizations with
the correct skills to uplift their
overall security showing how attackers
can compromise containers in a fun and
engaging way
and it's not just the attendees that get
a lot of value from this event
individuals that run these events and
participate in the open source community
they're leveling up their skills they're
able to identify gaps and challenges
being experienced by adopters through
discussions with their colleagues and
peers and hallway tracks or in open
space talks they're also able to
strategically leverage some of that
event content to drive attendees like
you to talk to each other figure out
what's going on in API security how did
you all solve this most recent
vulnerability what are you doing to
improve your software supply chain and
what is the evolution of that look like
for your company over the past four or
five years because ultimately we're all
trying to do the same thing uplift
security
and we've been able to increase
Industries attention to security and
Cloud native over these past four years
because and we're going to continue
doing it because there was and continues
to be a gap and while that Gap is
significantly smaller we're still
growing this space and learning and
uncovering new areas to explore you can
see from the metrics on this slide we've
doubled the amount of security projects
and products in the cloud native
Computing foundation's landscape we've
increased the amount of Security reviews
on projects that we had we even had a
major review process revision and we're
talking about doing another one to
really drive more value to maintainers
as well as adopters and it's because of
the First Security day and all the
security days that came after evolving
into this conference that allowed us to
provide a place for security
practitioners to exchange learn in a way
that was not addressed by the previous
security conferences
this conference is an Avenue to share
your experience and to learn from others
I would like to see it continue to
expand Beyond just Cloud native security
into open source security because both
of these are complementary fields and as
we see more maturity in Cloud native
security tools projects guides
documentation and resources we're seeing
them applied outside of cloud native
architectures
this event has grown because of
attendees like you and those that came
before you but it was started because of
the cloud native security community and
in particular the volunteers and
passionate members of the security
technical Advisory Group who have driven
more content from their work into this
conference and this is the work that
moves Cloud native security forward
connecting members solving problems
establishing best practices and sharing
what we've learned I want you all to
take this opportunity to network with
your peers talk about some of the
challenges you're experiencing and how
you've solved them as a throwback to the
original open space and collaborative
nature that this conference started from
thank you
[Applause]