thanks folks okay
so
um a decade ago
I was sat on my own in this semi-deralic
data center in uh in Manchester
um bootstrapping an open set public
Cloud on a rack of second-hand Hardware
bought on eBay
and over time we rebuilt that data
center we built a team and we built a
real platform with real customers
but there was no kubernetes there was no
docker everything was pretty good for
its time everything in Version Control
orchestrated using puppet but there was
lots of brittle bash scripts that needed
regular tending
and we took that platform through the
iso 27001 security certification and the
experience of managing security back
then was pretty difficult there was lots
of manual work
external scans using things like nessus
custom vulnerability checks in nagios
and very limited tooling for automation
and the point of all of this is that the
cycle of Technology change moves pretty
fast and it's only getting faster
um the difference in the next decade is
likely to be significantly bigger than
in the last one
so I'm going to talk about five things
that could potentially change the way we
think about security
even more dramatically over the next 10
years
so at this point a huge disclaimer this
is in no way a prediction or investment
advice history is littered with examples
that most things in technology very
rarely go in the direction we think
they're going to
so you're going to hear an awful lot
about Keys about certificates and about
signing this year and it's a fairly safe
prediction that uh artifact signing in
our software development lifecycle is
going to become pretty much standard
and public key cryptography has served
us well for more than 30 years it's
underpinned all of the innovation in the
web and Internet space
but there may be problems in
cryptography approaching
so this is a quantum computer and
quantum computers not only look cool
um but they work very differently to
classical computers they replace the
idea of bits our zeros and ones with
Quantum bits or qubits based on the
properties of quantum mechanics
and unless you're a Quantum physicist
most of quantum mechanics is completely
mind-bending for normal humans but most
folks might be familiar with the concept
of Schrodinger's cat this is a thought
experiment about hypothetical cat that
can be both alive and dead at the same
time whilst it's in a sealed box with a
fatal radioactive element and it's a
pretty Macabre example but it does
illustrate how particles can be zero or
one or both at the same time and it's
this superposition phenomenon that that
quantum computers are based on
and quantum computers are theoretically
very good at certain classes of problem
that are very hard for classical
computers and factorization of prime
numbers is one of these
um this is a visualization of Shaw's
algorithm developed in the 1990s by
mathematician Peter Shaw and it's widely
viewed as a proof that quantum computers
could potentially break public key
cryptography including diffie-hellman
key exchanges and algorithms like RSA
and this might be theoretical but some
researchers think that this could happen
in the next decade on a day known as Q
day when most of our cryptography would
be broken our certificates would be
vulnerable to man in the middle attacks
and our encryption would be cracked
now there's a lot of different actors
involved in building quantum computers
including nation states and three letter
agencies so we may never actually know
that this has happened
and it's serious enough for governments
to take action with a move towards new
kinds of algorithms resistant to this
threat of quantum Computing post Quantum
cryptography and in the US niss the
National Institute for standards and
technology has been running a
competition for the last few years
and the algorithms were selected in 2022
and they've all got very cool names um
any algorithm With The Star Trek
reference has got to be good right
but at some point it's likely we'll all
need to switch our keys of certificates
and our infrastructure over to these new
methods
so um coming back to signing I don't
want to take
um once you start signing everything
what we're really doing is building
chains of trust
and the reality of any chain of trust is
that there has to be something at the
bottom that we can actually trust
and it's obviously very important that
we trust our build systems the things
that produce our artifacts and there's a
couple of different dimensions to this
the first being can we trust our build
to always produce the same thing
now this may be maybe kind of
non-obvious but there's not necessarily
any guarantees that the thing you're
building is exactly the same every time
you build it
and if it's not exactly the same then
you can't really guarantee its validity
even slight differences May introduce
unexpected Behavior or even new security
vulnerabilities
and this can happen if you're using
timestamps if you're ordering is
volatile and for a whole host of other
reasons so how can we ensure that our
builds are completely deterministic
well this reproducible builds concept
has been around for a long time and it
aims to do exactly that it's a set of
software development practices aimed at
creating bit for bit identical artifacts
every time we run the process
and lots of large open source projects
already practice this but we again hit
the issue of what can we trust
if we use pre-built binaries in our
build pipeline can we know that those
aren't compromised
and with that in mind some folks have
started talking not only about
reproducible but also bootstrapable
builds where our entire build chain is
also built and can be verified
so before we build we build the thing we
use to build but where does that
actually stop
can we trust pre-built operating systems
now there's a trainer thought that even
the smallest general purpose operating
system is now too big to be auditable
and verifiable by a human
and there's lots of interesting work
happening in this space with projects
trying to build the smallest possible
thing that can boot hardware and build
compilers which can then build other
things and so on
and these are generally written in
low-level languages with the aim to be
human auditable so at least some
programmers are capable of reading and
understanding the entire code base and
we're talking about really really tiny
in the order of a few hundred bytes
so now we're really off down the rabbit
hole of trying to find something
somewhere we can ultimately Trust
um even if we can boot Hardware with
something tiny that we can fully audit
can we actually trust the hardware
now you might say at this point that no
one cares about Hardware anymore right
we're all in the cloud but the cloud
still and always will be just someone
else's computers
and the world of silicon is notoriously
proprietary there's lots of proprietary
features built into modern chipsets that
you may never even know about and in the
hardware space we're operating almost
entirely on trust not just the chips
themselves but all the tooling to design
and build them is also proprietary and
unavailable for us to verify
and that's one of the things that's
driving the creation of Open Source
silicon and there's lots of interesting
projects in this space and from open
risk with the aim of creating a fully
fledged open source processor to more
specifically security focused projects
like open Titan who are building an open
source design for route of trust chips
and for validating hardware and software
and these projects are all about having
those designs available for folks to
verify and audit
and there's an argument to be made that
computer architectures have remained
relatively unchanged for more than 30
years yes they've got smaller they've
got more powerful but fundamentally the
way the CPU Works virtual memory paging
multitasking operating systems are all
quite similar and we're still using the
same paradigms in programming
and these architectures have features
that could be considered contributory to
certain classes of vulnerabilities
particularly around memory safety
so are there changes in computer
architecture which can reduce the attack
surface
well there's a team at the University of
Cambridge in the UK who've been
developing a new instruction set Cherry
capability Hardware enhanced risk
instructions which is designed
specifically to mitigate software
security vulnerabilities
and the way Cherry works is by
introducing a new set of processor
Primitives that provide a mechanism for
fine-grained memory safety and process
isolation directly in the hardware
so it's a combination not just of
Hardware but of tool chain support to
reduce the amount of vulnerabilities
that an attacker can exploit so
basically the idea of least privilege
but highly scalable highly efficient as
it's done directly in the CPU
and Cherry's been around as a concept
since around 2010 but there's now
Hardware that actually supports it in
the form of this Amarillo board
and there's lots of development going on
to widen the ecosystem of software
support for this new architecture
so we've talked about cryptography we've
talked about build systems we've talked
about hardware and architecture but the
real elephant in the room is the rise of
artificial intelligence and specifically
large language models now unless you've
been living under a stone
um you will have seen a lot of traffic
about chat GPT since it was released
back in November
and the growth in users has been
unprecedented and millions of people
have been trying it out and you know
whatever your your feelings about chat
GPT in general if you actually used it
it's clear pretty quickly that this
technology is going to be truly
transformational for how we interact
with computers entire Industries are
going to be disrupted by these abilities
to write complex text based on limited
human input
and pretty quickly after the release
people started to experiment with having
chat gbt write code and again the
results here have been pretty
extraordinary given relatively small
inputs chat GPT is already capable of
writing mostly correct complex
applications in multiple languages
manipulating data between formats and
translating programs between different
programming languages and even writing
programs in fictional programming
languages
and whilst it's not about to displace
programmers just yet the field is moving
incredibly quickly we're really only a
few weeks into the AI Revolution and
it's already clear that's going to drive
massive change these models can't reach
out to other systems yet or to the
internet but that'll almost certainly
change
and a lot of researchers have been
talking about the idea of conversational
programming where we interact with
models based on what output we need and
not on how to achieve the result
and the AI model will get to that result
by any means it deems appropriate
um but this raises some kind of
fundamental questions about the future
of application software
if the future involves computers writing
programs for us where we only really
care about the output then the question
arises about why computers would use
high-level programming languages at all
um commuters don't know anything about
programming languages languages are
basically abstractions to make it easier
for human programmers to program
computers everything's either
interpreted or compiled down to
something the computer can actually run
so since such a huge proportion of our
issues with software supply chain at the
minute come from how we assemble
applications from packages and libraries
perhaps the era of AI generated programs
will solve that problem for us
most likely though it just introduces a
whole new raft of security issues we're
still back to our starting point about
trust can we trust our AI model and more
importantly is it plotting a robot
takeover of the human race
so to return to the disclaimer some or
all of this talk is highly likely to not
come true predictions are notoriously
difficult in technology and yes this was
me 30 years ago so what do I know
um but I'd like to leave you with a
quote from that famous future allergist
Dr Emmett Brown
um your future is whatever you make it
so make it a good one thank you
[Applause]