all right you guys ready to get started
chat about this stuff if I was to do a
quick poll of the audience who here
knows like the Json schemos of image
manifest and that kind of stuff getting
down to that low level details
I know I know a few of you do okay we
got about 50 50.
I think everybody Rose their hand I'd
probably know so that's probably the
part of the challenge here so welcome
this is going to be modifying the
immutable and so we're going to talk
about how you can attach artifacts oci
images by that we're talking about
everybody's been saying stuff like
generating s-bombs and we're talking
about how we create the s-bombs other
people are saying how to consume the
s-bombs this is saying how you can
connect those to your image and start
shipping them out to people who needed
to blame later on and so let's chat
the background of me I'm not going to go
through the full details I do work for
boxboat got other people here I'm sure
someone's hiring all that good stuff but
the important details from this one are
that I'm an oci maintainer and a lot of
this work comes out of the oci we've got
a working group we were going through a
lot of efforts on this stuff and on some
of the slides and the demos you're going
to see use a little tool called reg
cuddle it comes out a reg client project
and I'm the maintainer of that one so
when you see that that's me just picking
a tool because it's what I know
all right so for the background for
those that didn't raise your hand on the
underlying stuff you probably already
know the container images have like file
system layers they've got their own
config
you've probably done like a Docker build
at some point and then probably change
to other build toy and trying different
stuff out you've probably seen it
there's a shot 256 checksum for like
pinning an image to a specific digest
and so someone can't change it in that
way and you might have a rough idea
what's going on but not quite
and I'm sure at some point you've come
across multi-platform images
where someone's saying we need to start
building for all these Mac m1s out there
because everything else has been built
for all the Intel machines and so
under the covers there's a lot going on
in oci so I want to hit a little bit and
make sure you understand what's
happening under the covers because
that's going to apply for when we
actually start talking about how we
start to attach things together
so under the covers the important detail
here is that everything is happening in
oci when you push it to a registry is a
Content addressable store and so what
that means on the first line is I'll
take a digest and if I curl that digest
the name of that digest from the red
stream pull down that blob
pipe that through a shot if it's a 256
checksum it's going to Output that same
value and so it's the digest of the
content itself is the name of the
content and that's how you do the
content addressability
fancy name there in this case I'm
looking at a layer and so you see a
whole bunch of the files in the layer so
it's just a compressed tar file so
that's like half the image right the
other half of the image is going to be
your Json config what user am I running
it as what are the commands that I'm
kicking off when I start this container
up if there's a history in there you can
see all the previous historical steps
environment variables all that stuff
that all gets passed as a Json blob same
idea content addressable story you just
serialize it into a byte array do the
digest on that and now you have another
address for that blob as well and these
resources blobs registry doesn't care
which Throne to blob so Json tar binary
text whatever it takes whatever you want
to throw in there as long as it just
maps to the digest of the string you
gave it
so now you got these two pieces we need
to put them together because an image
not necessarily one layer might have
multiple layers and it's got to config
and so to assemble them together what we
have is an image manifest yeah another
piece of Json here we're looking at so I
know this probably gets a little bit
tedious but bear with me for a second
where we've got the config descriptor
and that descriptor has the digest we're
talking to we've got the layers in there
that we're referencing and so in this
case I've got a single layer that we're
talking to and you put those two things
together you put them in the Json you
serialize a Json you calculate the
digest on a Json now you have the digest
of your image Manifest this is the PIN
digest whenever you say I want to pull
an image by its digest this is what
you're pulling if you ever change one of
the layers you change the content of
layer you change the layer digest and
that changes this digest as well because
it's all included in there
so that's how you make that structure
graphically it looks a lot like this
where we've got a tag the tag think of
it as like a symbolic link you can have
multiple types when you have the same
thing you can have a tag that used to
point to one digest and the future
points to a different Digest
and then that points to your manifest
that manifests is immutable because it's
referenced by the digest all this
content is referenced under there
so pretty pictures I feel like that
wakes some people up sometimes I know
I'm holding you right before the coffee
break and so it's going to be a little
struggle here
immutability is the nice feature we get
out of all this so when you do this
you've got a Merkle tree you've got a
dag a directed Ace like the graph out
there and you've got the the content
addressable store we already talked
about you put all those things together
and you get this immutability so in case
uh in case I'm going too far back into
the college days the Merkle tree is when
you have a data structure that has a
hatch itself and his content all his
child nodes are hashed and so when you
already change it and so that was that
structure we were just looking at there
okay so far hopefully nod's in the room
we probably got a little bit too deep in
the weeds for some people but that's
kind of where his talk is going
another PC here that's important are the
multi-platform images
and so to do this we have a different
kind of manifest
that different kind of manifest just has
multiple descriptors for each one of the
different platform specific manifests
and so it's a manifest of manifest
so you have this hierarchical pointing
and when you do this when you're looking
through that array of descriptors there
and you say okay which one do I want to
pull you have to put something in there
that can identify one versus the other
and the way we're identifying it from
the multi-platform Manifest is we put
the platform in there and so you put
that extra field in there you say this
is the platform for arm the other one is
a platform for AMD and then we're going
through looking for your manifest you
can pick it from the list and the
runtime just does this for you
transparently under the covers
but importantly this has its own digest
as well so you can serialize this one
you'd send that digest in there and when
you send this to your runtime the
runtime knows how to figure out its own
platform under the covers
all right graphically we're now up to
this
where we've got our tag that's pointing
to the multi-platform Manifest that no
CI lamp is called an index and so you
have a index just the terminology is how
to pick that points to multiple
manifests for each one of your platforms
that points to each of the configs and
all the layers out there so we built
this nice big graph
I know you put one last piece on this
puzzle and then we can actually get into
the fun part of the talk
and the last piece is that for the
longest while we've been able to push
artifacts to a registry anybody ever
hear about pushing a Helm chart to a
registry or something like that if
you're want to pushing Helm chart to a
registry you just push a blob and their
blob I think they actually happen to
push a tar file out there a compressed
tar file but it could have been anything
they wanted to you push that blob and
the thing they change is the media type
that is on that config descriptor they
change that media type on that one piece
and that tells anybody running it that
this no longer container image we're
trying to run with a container image
runtime but this is some other tool that
should be looking at working it even
though both of these are image manifest
we just kind of overload that one tool
out there just so we get that
portability
so we ever learned that but otherwise in
this example here I made a little
electron bill of materials and I just
said that this does contain electrons
ship that and I can attach that to any
image I wanted to if I decided to
okay so that's all the fundamentals this
is stuff that already exists out there
people are doing this today their Helm
charts out there their container images
their multi-platform images this is kind
of the underlying Burns of what's going
on under the covers
the challenge oci faced was we're saying
okay great we've got all these s-bombs
out there we've got all these other
tools how can we associate one to the
other and if anybody was in here for
Roses uh bit her conversation earlier
the discussion went hey we're shipping
the container images out there we really
want to ship the s-bomb alongside of
them and somehow associate the two
together
because it's not the best if you say
we're going to have this since
repository of all the s-bombs that some
government agency manages for us I know
I come out of the DC area trust us we
work for the government might be a
famous term out there but I'm sure a lot
of people in here are like no no we're
not going to trust them
so trying to get a centralized entity
isn't going to necessarily work trying
to have every person go out to a
different place to try to figure out
where this s-bomb isn't going to work
you don't want to like figure out okay
it's under the released uh folder over
on GitHub for this one project someone
else put it on a website no we want to
ship these things together we already
have a way to ship an image
we can already ship other artifacts
within the container registry we just
need to associate the two together
so the challenge we faced was how do we
modify this immutable thing
because our container image is immutable
it can't change
but we want to be able to say for this
container image what's the s-bomb what's
the signature what's all this other data
out there and we had a few requirements
so the working group was spun up and
said here here are your go-to
requirements and some of those things we
were looking at was efficiency we want
to make sure we weren't making a whole
lot of API calls
other challenges we were looking at were
how do we both attach and detach content
if you start shipping out an image you
might say the Upstream had it signed
with their signature but when we brought
this in-house and we brought to our own
registry we wanted to sign up with our
own ID we don't care about that Upstream
signature so we just don't want to pull
that in-house or maybe they had more
metadata than you even wanted to include
or you need to have added extra metadata
it wasn't there
so a lot of different challenges along
those lines we also we couldn't predict
what everybody was going to include you
could start including cat pictures with
all your container images you wanted to
and we didn't want to try to write the
spec for how to attach cat images to the
image to container images
gets a little complicated
so the nice thing about this problem is
that we weren't faced with the
impossible we actually had multiple
Solutions out there and some of them
were already being used and so our
challenge wasn't how to create this it
was how to pick
um and so the first option you're
looking at was the auras team was out
there and they said we're going to make
a new artifact manifest we're going to
push out to the registry and have a new
definition that's not going to have this
config blog because we don't need that
but we just have our own little Blobs of
whatever needs to go in the artifact
we're going to have the subject here
we're going to put in there and that
subject field is just another descriptor
has its digest and that's going to point
back to them which we're extending but
now from our manifest on the left hand
side of the screen there's no way you
can go from that Arrow back to the right
so now we need to add a new API and so
we add the new API this refers API that
when you query that with our manifest
digest on from the left hand side it'll
spit back the list of descriptors for
all the Manifest on the right hand side
of this picture
so that's how he made that mapping we
were going to have to add something to
the registry a couple pros and cons of
this one I mean it was nice and
efficient you had the API and the
registry is going to do it all for you
but none of this is going to work on
existing registry a day any registry out
there that doesn't know what that
artifact manifests that blue box on the
right looks like it's going to reject it
because while they accept any blob at
all all those green boxes they'll take
whatever you throw at them they don't
care about that part when you're a
manifest the registry is parsing it
because it's doing stuff like garbage
collection it's doing all that
Association cleanup is doing some
validation in there so if you push
something in there it doesn't recognize
it just rejects it so that was one of
the big challenges we looked at for this
so he said well it's easy enough to
change this a little bit oci has the
model where we say you can extend any
manifest out there you can take a
manifest that has five Fields you can
have six field into it that's got some
extra structure in it and as long as you
parse it and you see the field you
recognize you can work with it and
someone else's seat knows how to process
the morph Fields they can do their thing
and so we could add the subject field to
an assisting manifest and so now we have
another way to make this back reference
so now we can push this thing that's got
this back reference in it
using an existing media type just extend
it a little bit to a registry that means
it's now portable we can push this exact
same manifest to a new registry or an
old registry and it moves from one side
to the other and back and it's all
nobody cares everybody just it passes
from one to the other we still have the
challenge we can't find this though
without having this new API and this new
API would be a new feature you have to
add to the registry so we're halfway
there we're not quite there but we're
getting there
and so the last thing we were looking at
that I'll go over is that we were saying
we could add a custom tag
and this comes from the state store
group if anybody's seen cosine I think
there might be a few people maybe sign
some images might have been up on stage
earlier people talking about stuff that
need to be signed
so they came out and said we're just
going to have a special tag that is the
digest that manifest on the left again
we like that digest it's a nice
immutable thing we can always reference
so we just make the tag with the value
of the digest you had to change a little
bit of the syntax a little bit so you
change the colon to a dash so it gets
parsed as a tag instead of as a
reference or as a as a digest itself
for you to change that one little bit
there now you can reference it as a tag
and now anybody can use that to look up
some abstract thing whatever that tag
points to and the thing with your point
to would be maybe the Manifest in this
case that we wanted to use maybe it's
pointing to a list of manifests
something like that but you could just
make that pointer in there so we had a
couple options
different you know a b and c and the the
question you might be saying is okay
well you threw a whole bunch of options
to ask which one do you pick and the
answer that is yes
and for we do have some people laughing
out there and then the reasons yes
because we we picked them all week we
couldn't choose we're bad at making
choices
um we're bad a lot of things but making
choices is definitely one that we're not
experts at
so at least as part of the release
candidates and this is still up for
debate on the first bullet point is that
we did add the artifact manifest and so
I'll put a big asterisk there we're back
and forth right now it's it's probably
going to get there eventually but if
you're writing something new right now
there's some disclaimers that I'll go
through later on
we add the subject field and not only
the subject field to the new artifact
manifest but we added to the image
manifest and so you can extend things
like we said so that went in there we
add the new refers API so there is our
API is going to go on a registry server
but this is only going to be on new
Registries to implement the new feature
that we're talking about
so for all the Registries that don't
implement this if you're a client you're
pushing this stuff up there the client
is now responsible for maintaining that
tag anytime they're talking to a
registry doesn't have a new feature
so with this we now have the full
backward forward compatibility we've got
a nice solution and graphically it gets
a little busy a little bit busy and I
actually had to take some of the arrows
off here to make it flow a little better
so those subject lines there will go all
the way back to the Manifest on the left
but what we have is you pull your
manifest from the version three you go
down you say here's my digest for the
Manifest that B3 points to let me go out
and see if there's anything that refers
to it and so you go hit the repairs API
and if that exists great it's going to
come back out with this index nice thing
about that index is that data data type
structure that already exists right now
and all the specs so we didn't have to
invent anything new at index that's what
you're talking about just a bit ago is a
Manifesto manifest so you can just point
to as many of these as you want to which
means we can have a whole lot of
artifacts we're all referencing at this
point which is great
and oh by the way if it doesn't work and
we have to fall back we use this tag and
the tagging point the exact same data
structure so the clients don't care how
they get the data structure they're
getting the exact same data back from
the registry whether they're talking the
new stuff or the old stuff
and the reason we want the new stuff is
having the registry manage this for us
is great but in case it doesn't the
client can manage it we at least have
something that's functional
all right before I go too much farther I
get a lot of questions on this next
topic which is hey you talked about
adding the subject field to the artifact
manifest that you just added you talked
about having the subject to the image
manifest they'll refer to a single image
but hey what about the multi-platform
images right and people people keep
asking that question can we have that
subject over there so the multi-platform
manager can point to things
and the way I'm going to start that is
to say the picture on the left exists
where if you're saying I've got an
artifact and I want to extend a
multi-platform image with some metadata
you want to sign a multi-platform image
you want to add an S1 at that level you
can do that you can sign at the top
level or you can sign each individual
manifest you probably want to do both
but you can do that
it's the picture on the right that we
don't allow
and the picture on the right that we
don't allow the reason we don't have an
index that points back to something else
is because at that point you know from
the index you're creating both the
subject field and potentially all the
child fields which means you can predict
both of those descriptors or not predict
you know exactly what both those
descriptor values are and the way you
walk this even though those things both
point to the left the way you walk this
is in a circle
and we were talking about earlier we
made this uh this dag structure the
directed acyclic graph I didn't really
go into the whole what that means but
directly acyclic graph means is acyclic
there's no Cycles you don't want loops
loops are bad in the CI land
so what's happening here is you have
this V3 tag you have queer the V3 tag
you pull the image manifest there and
you say tell me everything that refers
to this image manifests so logically you
walk over to that index on the right
then you say tell me all my child nodes
from this index you go walking back to
the known left repeating infinite and
that's no good
the other nice thing we try to focus on
here with all the change we're making
was to say hey Registries need to do
some garbage collection even though we
don't specify in the spec they still
want it and so the logic we put out
there was to say that as long as you
have the Manifest exist that you're
pointing to keep the artifact that's out
there so even though the artifact itself
isn't tagged
the Manifest it points to us still
exists so we can say don't garbage
collect it we're still in use keep this
artifact around and so that makes it a
lot more efficient so when you have a
registry out there and you've got all
this stuff sitting up in your repository
you don't have to tag every one of these
individual artifacts keep them from
being cleaned up later on it's nice to
know as long as the image is there all
the metadata is there with it
so we made all his definitions a bunch
of pictures if there are people back
there like to see the code as well
here's the low level Json and this the
Json use in the fallback so I actually
go through and show you if I pull an
image I get the digest that image I
Define that tag with that tie just in
there and I go query this manifest API
for that tag where I get back as an
index and in that index the important
thing here is note that we've got a
descriptor that says here are the
different entries in my manifest and
I've got some metadata I pulled up so
the metadata I pulled up is going to say
here's the artifact type and the
annotations
and the reason we want to pull up the
artifact type in the annotations is that
when we get a list of all these manifest
that extend our image you're going to
have a signature you're going to have an
s-bomb from Cyclone DX you're going to
have an s-bomb from spdx you're going to
have a attestation of the build process
I went through you're gonna have a whole
bunch of these manifests you don't want
to pull each one of them figure out
where it is
and so we pull that metadata up and so
this is the refers API is going to do
this for you on the server or if you're
a client you're managing this you're
going to do it yourself and the place
you pull it up from is from the Manifest
of our actual artifact itself
sense of artifact itself we mentioned
earlier you change that media type on
the config and that's how you know what
this artifact is so we change that
config a little bit you can put
annotations over there you can put all
kinds of other metadata and as long as
that's subject is there that creates
that association between the two
so I'm sure I'll up here we're thinking
this is you know fantastic you show me
all this low level detail that I
probably don't even care about I'll give
you good news there's code that just
does this for you all out of the box so
you don't have to write any of this
yourself right okay that's the good news
hourly show it off and I did tell you
that um some is going to have some of my
code in here there are other options
I'll show you some of the options as
well but let me spin up two Registries
I'm going to define a few variables here
that are going to be used to reference
these two Registries and one's going to
be listed on Port 5001 the others can be
listed on Port 50002 and I'm only going
to use some oci media types for my stuff
and so I went through a little bit of
effort to make sure I didn't have to
keep track of Docker media types or CI
media types and other kinds of things I
just kept it simple so I made two
different media types there
the first registry I'm spinning up is
going to be the cncf distribution
registry listing on Port 5001 that
registry has not been updated so that is
going to be an ociv 1.0 registry that
doesn't have any of the new features yet
so this is as is today if you want to
talk into a registry out in the cloud
today is probably what you'll be talking
to something like this that doesn't have
the new apis doesn't have the new
artifact
and so anytime I push something up to
here I got to do it the old way
the second registry I'm going to spin up
is called zot so I'll come up in another
line here the zot registry has been
updated they jumped early on this
release candidate and wanted to show off
that they can do some new latest and
greatest features so I'll show how that
one works
and like I say their registry supports
the new artifact manifest their registry
supports the new Reapers API and that is
that latter one that we really care
about and so that API is going to be
interesting you also see me turn off TLS
turning off TLS is fantastic for demos
not great for production but just makes
my life so much easier so I did that
and lastly I need to put an image out
there so I went and grabbed an image out
from Docker Hub and I'm just kind of
doing a little bit of self doggy
fruiting I just kind of grabbed my own
image because I knew that I had on the
oci media type so I just wanted to keep
it simple and I want to keep a single
platform so I actually went through and
found the descriptor for just a single
platform Outlet so I didn't want to go
through like a multi-platform index and
get too complicated I like things to say
you know as complicated as all this text
is I wanted to keep it at least somewhat
simple
all right so I'm going to copy this
manifest over from the internet back
over to my local registry and then you
can see the manifests up there in my
local registry now and this is like I
say single platform manifest oci image
B1 all that good stuff all right that's
just the setup so we haven't done
anything fancy yet that's just the
initial setup and this is the part that
everybody's going to like is that the
part you have to worry about if you're
attaching stuff is a very short slide
here I'm going to run a stiff command to
generate an s-bomb so I want to have an
example here and pick your tool I just
happened to pick this one because it was
very easy simple one-liner I'm generally
a cyclone DXs bomb and this is again
where I'm getting in my reg cuddle
command where I say I want to do an
artifact putting so I'm going to push an
artifact up to the registry I'm setting
the subject line and I'm also going to
start setting some annotations some me
types other things to say this is what
this artifact is because otherwise it
doesn't know it just kind of puts it up
there a little abstractly and that's not
any good
so I push it up there with all those and
I'm going to do a second one as well so
we can see what two of them look like
together and so the second example I'm
going to push up there is going to be
spdx because I don't want to pick
favorites if you ever pick favorites in
a room of security people with an s-bomb
it's chaos
so I don't like chaos like things nice
and simple and peaceful
so now we have two artifacts you're
getting pushed up here and for anybody
that's generating stuff that needs to
start shipping your images this is it
you're done
that was all you had to do and your your
job is out you know finished and
complete
and the nice thing is once you have done
this
from the end user side when they start
pulling this stuff they don't know where
to look
all they have to know is they can list
the artifacts on image and this will go
out and hit that refers API the refers
API isn't there it's going to look at
that fallback tag and there's we have
two manifest that lists so let me scroll
back there a little bit you can see that
it is an oci image manifest or sorry
there is a descriptor in there with that
this is an index
of multiple images first one being the
Cyclone DX and the second one down below
is going to be the spdx you can see the
annotations you can see the artifact
type all that detail we need to be able
to query this stuff later on
programmatically query the stuff later
on
so again this was a tag because it was
on the fallback registry so this tag
does exist it looks a little ugly so
this is why people don't like it they
don't want to see all these tags out
there the one nice thing is we only have
one tag so there's not like a Sig tag an
annotation tag you know all these other
things we just have the one tag for
everything
and then if I go and query that tag with
a manifest get you're going to see it
this is going to look very familiar it's
going to unless you had really
short-term memory loss here it's going
to look identical that's you know three
lines up and in case that was like too
fast to go by I'll even scroll up there
and show you that there it was here with
the Manifest list scroll up a little bit
there was a previous one they're the
same
because that was exactly how we queried
it
all right so whether it's artifact list
or the fallback tag we're getting the
same thing with the Manifest kit as well
so from that the big challenges that's
great I want to actually fetch my
Cyclone DXs boom SPX something like that
so I've got the artifact get command
here where I say get me an artifact that
has this subject field that points to
this image so I pass the subject and I
pass that and I say filter and only show
me the thing with this one media type
for the artifact
that's now as long as I keep these media
types predictable I can do this and
there's my S1 right just that easy
so for the end user all I have to do is
memorize that last command they have to
know everything in between they just had
no last command of when I see an image
run this command I get the s bomb and
I'm done
so that's the nice part that's the easy
part if you ever want to do this with
curl I won't go through this entire
slide but I will tell you that all this
stuff if you don't turn on
authentication on your registry server a
lot of stuff gets easier if you know
your media types and advances stuff gets
a lot easier when you don't know all
that and you try to implement that with
curl it gets a little ugly so that's
where the tools come in nice and so
that's where people start writing tools
on top of this but you can actually run
these low-level queries get the Manifest
pull the digest out of one of the
entries and go through all that if
you're curious I'll leave that for later
on all these clouds are up online you
can go replay all these presentations
later on but I don't want to bore you
too much with the curl details here
I do want to show you though that we had
two Registries right and I only showed
you what was going on one registry let
me copy this artifact from a V1 registry
to the new registry of the new release
canvas stuff that has the Reapers API
and if I do that copy is quick because
it's all local on the same machine I run
the list command and you'll see I get
the artifact list back
so I'm able to query this listing of all
the artifacts associated with my image I
copied everything over in one unit if I
do the tag listing I don't have that
digest tag anymore I just have my one
app tag
and if I even try to go back and query
that tag and try to pull it I'm going to
get let's see do I go up on that one so
yeah I'm going to hit the Manifest API
and I'm going to hit that API for this
one digest with that little fallback
digest we had that's going to come up
with say not found four four didn't even
exist so manifest unknown right there on
that line
so without that you might be saying okay
how that happened well you saw the big
pretty picture earlier on I just had to
hit this new API called refers
I hit that query that API and suddenly
what I'm getting out of this was that
manifest list so now that's the same way
you get the data two different
Registries two different methods to get
the data but the same data on both of
them
so that's the beauty of this
all right one last bit of detail here
for anybody in an air gap environment do
I have anybody in like DOD air gap
environment kind of stuff that has to
worry about that one two three four okay
handful if you're at the oci layout is a
great method to move images around on a
file system whenever you copy them so
you can just copy an image from a
registry into the structure it puts it
into a directory on the disk you can zip
it up ship it around and I can do the
artifact list in there now it's just a
directory so I do have the tag in there
I don't have a registry server
generating that API response but in that
directory there is an index that
basically represents all the tags inside
the directory this is the equivalent of
having a repository on a registry on
your file system and you can just copy
your stuff all around
so if you're curious about that another
good side to come back to later on if
you want to look into that and see a
little bit more details there
all right I'm going to keep jumping
ahead because I want to save a little
bit of time in case people have
questions or want to heck with me later
on
but there are other tools to do this
because I think a lot of people say you
know great you show me all the reg
cuddle commands there's another tool out
there called orus so if I said auras
discover on this thing you're going to
see all those manifests listed in there
or all the different uh artifacts are
associated with my image and same for
both Registries whether I hit it on the
new API or the old API it's able to find
it so that's working great and also
you're saying I did also my laptop well
if I go hit the GitHub container
registry in a production environment
right now and an image that I've pushed
they're all up there right now and so
I'm doing this as part of my GitHub
pipelines today right now on an image
that's out there in in the real world
and again I could also go through so let
me show you real quick on what that
artifact is it's um I've got three
different things attached to it I picked
out Docker star generating some of their
attestations on things so I got that
attached to this I've got the again the
2s bombs as well so a couple of those so
as many yes moms or as many artifacts
whatever you want to attach attach
everything you want to
and also not just reg cuddle I could
have also done the aorus Discover
command again on GitHub container
registry and it's going to say hey
you've got all these different artifacts
associated with this image
cool so we've got a way to do this we
got commands to do this we got tools out
here
um which we do what's the next steps
where are we going to go so for registry
servers this is all a lot of the stuff
is still new we're still creating this
stuff so if you are a registry and you
don't filter on unknown Fields what I
mean by that there's this new subject
field we just added so some Registries
are a little picky about what data comes
in oci says you're not supposed to be
but there there are a few people that
are doing that so we're working with
them we're getting really close I think
unless they've already done it they may
have and there's also
um the new the config media types have
changed there were some Registries that
were saying if it's a config me you type
this not a container image I don't want
to allow it
Docker Hub just recently turned that off
and that was awesome for people who
wanted to do like Helm charts pushed up
there that kind of stuff we're finally
able to use Docker hub for this stuff
additionally
um the new artifact manifest we'd like
to see support for that but that comes
with a big asterisk I'll get on that in
just one second here and the enable the
refers API so that's the thing that I
think we're really pushing for right now
is to get Registries to start adopting
this like I say release camp this is
just coming out the door from oci we've
been having means and trying to get this
stuff getting to a ga release we're
still a little ways off from that but
hopefully in the not too distant future
so anybody's running a registry or
saying let's let's get this stuff out
there and standardized
I think the more important part is for
the people running clients right I think
we probably got more client people in
here than registered people
so if you're a client and you want
portability to go from one registry to
another
use that image manifest we did say
earlier on that slide there's this new
artifact manifest we created I keep
throwing asterisks on there part of the
asterisk is that we're not really quite
sure how and when we're going to
transition to that and so we're still
working through those details right now
and the the other part of that is that
any registry that hasn't been upgraded
couldn't accept this manifest and so for
portability use the old image manifest
for a long while to use this install
transparent you don't know when you're
pulling a Helm chart that this came with
an image manifest you just know you got
a Helm chart so who cares what manifest
it is for a good long while at some
point it'll be nice to have things or
artifacts look at like artifacts some
things their image look like images but
we're not there yet it's going to take
us a while to get everything upgraded
the other important thing that fallback
tag if you're writing a client of your
own you have to do that management if
you're using someone's written the
client they're going to do this all for
you and you know you just use their apis
and their tooling they'll they'll
implement this for you but when you have
this stuff that's being implemented on
the client side and not the registry
doing the refers API what they're doing
is they're going to have to go up to
that registry and manage that tag which
means if the tag is already there
someone's already pushed an artifact you
have to pull down the existing list of
all the artifacts add your new entry to
that list and then re-push the new list
if anybody's ever thought about systems
where you're doing like a whole lot of
things going on simultaneously you might
be thinking race conditions and that is
one of the downsides of this is that you
can have multiple clients out there
pushing this stuff and clobbering each
other in the process that's one of the
beauties of getting this done service
however is the client-side
the the other important part here is the
artifact type when you pick that if you
look to the artifact types I was picking
with the example with the exclusion of
my example early on I was picking some
media types that were well known they
came from Ayanna they're registered up
there so if you go and look at Cyclone
DX niana they've got their list of here
all the media types been registered with
us I picked those for all the media
types I used that way anybody else is
using the same queries can find this
same Cyclone DX s-bomb no matter what
image it is as long as every image uses
the same media type it's easy to find
from one image to the next image in the
next image so yes people use some very
predictable media types and hopefully
that comes from the project itself
saying this is our media type that we've
standardized everything on
additionally we asked to use annotations
very responsibly that's one of the
challenges we're pulling those
annotations up from the Manifest up into
our listing and there are people like to
put a lot of stuff in an annotation
um I'm sure people have been on the
kubernetes had has probably seen a lot
of abusive annotations before on on your
side as well and container image
manifest they're not overused too much
yet but I think they're going to get
there before too long and what we're
seeing from registry operators is saying
if we've got to index all this details
so we can generate this API response
we're just going to start rejecting
Manifesto they start cramming too much
data in there so if you want that
portability be responsible only put the
data in those annotations that you need
to be able to do these queries on
yourself don't put the whole world in
there be nice to the registry servers
they'll be nice to you
all right so the catches
um the big catch here is we're not done
we're still implementing this stuff and
so as it's still being implemented the
Registries the clients all this stuff is
at various stages
there's still some debate on if and how
we're going to do that artifact manifest
type we spent three hours of Glorious
fun meeting time yesterday back and
forth and we're still not quite to a
final solution we'll get there we're
going to work it out but uh it's just
going to take us a while to sort out how
we want to figure that out
um but for anybody that wants to do this
today like I say I'm doing this right
now in my own images I I trusted enough
that I'm putting it out there so you can
try it out you can at least do some
experiments see how the code works for
you and this is the nice way that I
think we're going to see for going
forward into the future of how you want
to have these things ported passed
around all these s-bombs signatures
other metadata passing out their image
in a way that we can now associate the
two together and ship them together and
transform so I hope we're going to get
to that point
and so with that I know that was a
little bit of Speed Run I know there's a
lot of little code but hopefully that
answer at least some questions that the
future is here for what we're doing and
it's been a long walk on the oci to get
to this point it's been a long painful
walk for some people in the back of the
room
um but we're getting there to the point
we're actually ready for I think end
users to start using this so I hope that
some people get a little bit of
inspiration from that
so with that throw it out there for any
questions
[Applause]
go ahead
[Music]
do I see it as distribution
discoverability or both and I would say
yeah both because not only can you ship
your s-bomb and move them around from
one place to the other and keep them
associated with the image itself but you
can query that image with a listing and
say show me everything is associated
with that image and you may not know in
advance what all these different
artifact types are they're going to be
associated with the image there can be
new stuff that appears the next day that
wasn't there before and so it gives you
that discoverability
yes have
I had the recursion discussion dig into
a little bit more where you're going
with that
you can do that absolutely and because
this is a directed acyclic graph there
is always an end there is always a
bottom to that path and so you can go
down as far as you want to go you can
have a signed s-bomb that's not signed
with s-bomb type but just an external
signature type if you want to and that
would be an external artifact associated
with the s bomb this and associate with
your image you can absolutely do that
any other questions
okay all you gotta do now is just turn
on you ready toddy go ahead
when can we start the spec for which
part
for the cats um
I keep putting cats in all my
presentations so I think yeah we're
right there we're ready to do it let's
let's knock that out next week
all right
it's got to have those and I need to
include those on every one of my images
from this point forward all right I saw
the stop sign I think my time is all up
if you've got any other questions for me
I think we're just at a coffee break now
so I don't want to hold you from coffee
or tea or anything like that but feel
free to ping me in we'll chat later on
thanks
foreign