so first I want to thank you all for
coming
there will be parts of this talk that
have some technical portions but at the
same time we're also want to dive into
some of the organizational side as well
so
with that let's jump in
um so first let's start a little bit of
talk to talk a little bit about reality
versus assumption so one of the problems
that we have is that as the the industry
tends to change over time our
Technologies change
and that creates a gap between the the
assumptions that we made and in time the
reality continues to shift away from
those assumptions and many of the
attackers actually find their uh their
opportunities within that particular
within those gaps
and so of course there's different
effects I don't have to jump into what
the effects are here because we're all
very familiar with it but uh
also when part of the problem we have
with organizations is that the the
regulations and policies that we
generate will often osify those
particular decisions things that were
valid at the time
but those assumptions are not
necessarily valid two or three years
from now or further on
and so a couple examples of things that
we used to do in the past was we used to
have like static Network architectures
assume that they that they didn't move
we put in uh various diagrams and so on
and assume that that's exactly what it
what it looks like
uh we would track our our services and
ports using things like IP address and
ports uh rather than looking at a
different type of identity
things like Network segmentation were
were mandated but they were mandated
across across certain boundaries that if
once you're inside then those boundaries
don't protect you anymore because the
the attacker has access to your
sensitive to your sensitive systems
and so
as so part of the drivers of what we're
looking at for things like zero trust is
that we have things like uh the security
posture is starting to shift where we're
looking for more granular uh parameters
we're looking to
move away from reactive and move towards
something that's actually proactive
so we're not trying to just respond to
the incidents but instead are trying to
work out well what how what incidents
are we seeing now and how can we
actually adapt adapt to them
and
the reality is that slow adoption of key
Technologies is becoming a risk not
necessarily only to security but also
becomes a business risk as people gain
more capabilities over time they cannot
perform your business so we have to
balance this between
what do we adopt and how do we secure it
but do it in a way that over time
we don't put ourselves in too much in
too much risk
and so with that change comes comes risk
um just for a quick definition of risk
usually we look at one definition
there's multiple definitions of it but
one definition is you look at the
magnitude and look at the probability so
what is the magnitude if something
happens how bad is the how bad is that
thing going to affect the uh the system
or or your business
what is the probability of it happening
so you have to actually look at uh look
at both and the question then becomes
how do we actually start looking at the
blast radius of a given failure
or of a successful attack and if you
start looking at things from a blast
from a blast radius perspective uh that
actually gets you a bit closer and
you'll see a little bit more as as we as
we move forward
and but at the same time we also want to
constrain the complexity because as we
move towards the zero trust system the
systems we bring in have a lot more
complexity than they used to because
they're a lot more granular so you have
to make sure that what you're doing
Works across across a wider a much more
diverse set of systems so
let's jump into a into a simplified
definition of zero trust so this
definition actually comes this is
something I wrote up before the nist
definition existed
and so the uh the way that I would tell
companies at the time uh before we even
before we would call it zero trust or at
least with this particular area is
we want to establish an identity
and when we talk about identity we
specifically mean a cryptographic
identity you can bind against
so we already have this with users so
users we every application used to have
its own identity eventually we got a
single sign-on so that we could conform
all we can have all the identities
managed to a single location
and then eventually we got Federation of
those identities so that you could have
a single identity that manages your
external third-party services so if you
have to shut down an account or you have
to change a password or add two-factor
authentication it works across all of
your services we want to do the same
thing with with workload identities as
well we want for the workloads to have
cryptographic identities that are con
that are continuously that are
continuously
read
redeployed and reissued
but also doing in a way that we can
Federate across multiple multiple
systems and once you have a
comprehensive identity system for your
workloads
and they're able to identify each other
using that then you can actually drive
it towards policy and that policy allows
you to consume the identity and you
write your policy so that you say
application a is allowed to send these
type of messages to application B and
there's labs and these type of responses
so instead of looking at the IP address
and port or similar you're actually
tying it down to this cryptographic
identity has these these capabilities
and we also want to have control and by
control we typically mean automation
you want to have the automated
deployment of these systems you don't
want to make them you don't want to set
it up so somebody has to manually do
something you want to have
not only automation of the deployment
but you also want to have automation of
the of the observability and up and
automation of some of the responses
and so
but before we can really drive into we
also want to look at contrast the
difference between perimeter defense
where we were at and in zero trust so
the simplest definition of perimeter
defense I can give you looks something
like this something untrusted goes
through a security control and is now is
now connected to a trusted environment
so everything on the left is untrusted
goes through the security boundary and
then once you've passed that security
boundary you're now in a trusted
environment
and typically it looks something like
this in practice where you end up with
trusted networks and you have vpns in
the center and you may put firewalls at
the VPN level but generally once you're
in the network uh not to say there's no
controls but the controls are are
limited
and what we want to try to push towards
is something that looks more like this
where you have secure connections the
the networks are untrusted it doesn't
mean they're uncontrolled but they're
untrusted and you want to create secure
connections between the workloads where
the workloads are validating their their
respective identities
so we want to shift from something that
looks
like this
I'm sorry so this is the general census
to as to what what it is so once an
attacker comes in because they're in
untrust untrusted network
and then they don't necessarily have
access to everything that's in there
because they have to go through
additional controls
so we want to push away from something
that looks purely like this
towards something that looks more like
this where the controls you have
controls that are effective that are
closer they have more context
if you have something that is like an on
the
on the right you have uh that the
attacker trying to connect into a system
that they don't have access to
the controls there have more context in
terms of what it is they're trying to
protect so you can actually put more
fine-grained rules in terms of uh in in
terms of what's allowed or not allowed
on a per uh per service per
communication basis
there are some risks here as well one of
the ones I'll call out immediately is
that there's a first not just from the
complexity side but there's also a lot
more processing in here as well so you
have to be careful not say hey we're
gonna put Gates everywhere because
that'll also that also fail you end up
with a lot of latency and in some
scenarios that latency is unacceptable
to to the business context
um there's techniques that can be used
to to avoid that we'll get into some of
them uh later on but I just want to
point out that you want to find a
balanced approach where you're checking
things coming in and going out in
effective locations but you don't
necessarily have to do it in every
single transition point of that where
some or some bit comes in one spot and
then you're you're running these really
expensive rules so just as a heads up
so again how do we achieve this going
back to the identity policy and uh and
control
and so
uh when we look we can use a previous
example that we've had again with uh
with user identity
and so with user identity we mentioned
about single sign-on does everything
require a login that you to use that
many third parties don't actually
support single sign-on so that's
actually ends up being a major gap for
for them so this actually becomes really
difficult with uh with major Enterprises
that have controlled information where
or very sensitive information where a
developer or user might log into a
third-party system to do their to do
their work that is not in your
necessarily inner control and if they
leave the company how do you shut down
those particular systems so there are
gaps that exist there but for the most
part these tend to work really well one
of the things that we have been pushing
for as an industry is to stick with the
standards so there's a lot of custom
standards that are out there but if as
more people
circle around JWT around saml and
similar that that means that you have a
single set of of or a smaller set of
things you have to comply to and it
allows for a lot more integration
so we started talking about workloads
and how do we establish workload
identity in a zero trust environment
these are the basic uh the basic steps
so you have to establish what's called a
trust domain so a trust domain is and
you'll you'll see a an example of it
soon but you think of a trust domain as
a set of things that belong to the same
uh family of of services like could be
like an application or it could be a
business unit or it depends on where you
want to draw that scope
uh you would test your workloads are
inside of them you then establish policy
in terms of how they can communicate
with each other and then you establish
the uh you can then Federate and
establish trust across trust domains so
in one scenario you could say let's
establish a trust domain and we'll use
standard so we'll use standard pki in a
scenario so we'll set up a CA and that
CA will represent AE trust domain so
every CA you set up
independently is uh is a separate trust
domain
the next thing you do is you then assign
you then assign that pki you you
register each workload and then workload
results in the next 509 certificate
and and that x519 certificate allows
that is you're basically a testing
you're saying this particular workload
follows my process I have I have a
tested that it meets my patch set that
it's on a device that I that I own and
control that the device meets the the
set of requirements so uh so there's a
lot that can go inside of the
attestation here in the more advanced
scenarios you actually tie them to
things like that if you're on premise to
the TPM so how would you get
cryptographic uh at the station that
that thing is what it is
in the case of cloud you might tie it to
like your AWS identity document or your
gcp workload identity so you want to tie
it to something that's cryptographically
uh sound if when when you have the
opportunity to do so
not every system can do that but uh but
many systems do have that capability
and so once you have that in place you
can then write your policy
and your policy in this scenario you say
this particular identity is allowed to
perform these particular sets of actions
so in other words this one's saying that
some front-end service is allowed to
make a request to some storage service
you're pulling the information directly
from x509 something that you've already
validated and you're making a
determination on what you want to do
with it so now this one is an example
from open policy agent but that's not
the only one that's out there so you
have things like kiverno you have uh
there's a new one from uh I'll forget
the name of the company but there's
there's several there's several
companies out there that are starting to
produce uh both open source and
proprietary that you can bind into it so
the main point here is not to say go use
Opa uh although that's not a bad choice
the main the main thing here is that you
have something that is declarative
you're explicitly saying that this
particular workload based upon its
cryptographic identity of what's within
the certificate is allowed to talk to
what it's allowed to do and who is
allowed to communicate with
so
once you have that in place
you also you can add then establish
trust between organizations as well so
we have this scenario two Cas and so if
I trade Cas between between each other
that means that I might have something
from one system uh workload on one
system it can communicate to Something
in another environment another
might be a different application in your
company or might literally be a third
party organization that you're that
you're integrating with so as long as
you can share those Cas and you can make
sure those Cas hit the workloads you can
then vow you can then check the identity
especially if you're using Mutual TLS
you can actually lift the identity
straight from the TLs transport so
you're not asking for a long living
token
that can be stolen and reused instead
you're saying I have this x509
certificate and I am using it actively
in this communication and eliminates a
man in the middle attacks as long as TLS
remains Unbroken
and as long as your keys are strong
enough
and so
uh and and in this particular scenario
you can see I've actually have an
example where the domain has been
specifically set so I can say this
specific domain for this identity is the
uh is allowed to make these particular
choices and what's really nice about
this is that we have the previous
example with the front end and the back
end service
this allows us to specify the exact name
of the uh of the organization or group
that I'm working with so I can actually
treat it I'm not creating special
tooling for a third-party organization
I'm using exactly what I used before in
order to in order to validate the
third-party systems
and
so
um
it's so when you start taking a look at
at applications
the Assumption like all what all this is
leading towards is that you're not
assuming that the network is secure what
you're doing is you're actually taking
the control bringing it closer to the
application
there's some debate as to whether the
application itself should do that should
own the control or whether you should
have something wrapped around it like
maybe you stick Envoy or or something
similar around it but in both cases
you're still bringing the control closer
to the to the application to the point
where you can where you have that
context of what the application is
trying trying to do
and so uh if you look at an advanced
version of this uh this is actually
where I think many of the systems are
starting to head towards is not just a
connecting to B
in this scenario we have a multi-party
edge compute and uh there's also several
other examples of this as well you can
pretend that the center part of this is
a is connected to with uh with a 5G Edge
environment
that's a whole thing that's coming
that's coming forward as as 5G
infrastructure starts to roll out so
they got the radios out but they still
have the back-end infrastructure they're
trying to deploy once they get the
backend infrastructure you're going to
see lots of edge data centers and inside
of that edge data center you might see
things like firewall as a service
intrusion detection as a service data
loss prevention as a service things
various companies have put in that end
up going through like Equinox or equinix
or some other similar type of company
the main point here is not is not to
promote that but it's to point out that
you that you have multiple things that
your system has to Traverse to so it's
not just my application uh talking or my
workload talking to some kubernetes
service in the cloud there's also things
in the center that you have to consider
the identity of as well like how do I
prove that something went through a
firewall how do I prove that something
went through a data loss prevention or
through or to other environments and in
some scenarios some of those Services
may be done as a service so how do you
how do you demonstrate that
so there are answers to this uh one one
example is within spiffy I didn't write
it in this particular slide but within
spiffy there's work that's going on to
look at that Transit of identity and
it's a really good example of transitive
identity missing from from Mutual TLS
it's like you take three services in
let's call them a b and c a connects to
B with mutual TLS so they validate each
other B connects to C and with mutual
TLS and they validate each other how
does a validate C there's no you have to
trust B that it's doing that's doing the
right thing there one of the things that
we have is we're able to uh is there's
ways to build up a miniature chain that
basically says like what's the audience
of the next thing I'm connecting to and
has another thing that receives that
validates that it that it received that
particular token from that and you're
able to like build up this miniature
chain on the Fly for for a particular
use case so you can prove that things
have gone through so there's work being
done in that in the community to solve
that but I want to point out that is
currently a gap that you'll see in many
systems is that there's no way to to do
the transit of identity an easy way
so I mentioned about wanting to push it
toward the identities towards the
infrastructure and that also includes
when you make those initial connections
you want to make sure that in time we're
going to start to see these identities
permeate to things like the VPN Gateway
and VPN concentrators
and this actually produces a really
interesting uh effect because if you
listen to a lot of the proponents on
zero trust you'll hear everything needs
to be on the network
everything needs to be collectible like
we want to make sure everything can be
connected with each other but the
reality is that when you look at many of
the regulatory systems many of the
regulations say that you have to have
certain additional controls you can't
just throw everything on the network or
publicly and also
there are sometimes bugs we find in
mutual TLS so we also want to have
layered we also want to have a layer
defense
and so
so you can't just make the assumption
that your Mutual TLS is going to save
you in every scenario so we're still
going to have vpns we're still going to
have these type of things that exist but
I but I believe the best case scenario
is that we work out paths to make to
make these particular things work so
that we have those initial connections
come in we can establish those
connections on the Fly there are
testable they they can get built is when
needed when you no longer need them to
go away and everything has a
cryptographic identity you can track
which means that you end up with
something that from an infrastructure
looks like this
you're driving something an identity
that drives all the way from the
hardware TPM up to the app but that same
identity has become compatible with the
infrastructure and similar
I'll give a few moments for a couple
photos
so let's dive into the actual
applications themselves and talk about
how applications can move towards uh
towards zero trust and so historically
you have something that looks something
like this and I should actually be a
little bit careful on how I word this
because I'm not saying that there's no
authentication that occurs at all very
often the client will have a user
Identity or something similar that it
uses to prove that who they are it goes
over the firewall the application server
is responsible for validating the the
JWT to make sure that it that it can log
in
and assuming that's not broken that that
gives you something that's defendable
um but the problem is that what happens
when this particular system has been
compromised the application server can
they do a scan of can they do a scan of
the database can they do a horizontal
attack on others and gain a foothold
into other environments that might be
more sensitive
and so the question is how much again we
mentioned before what is the blast
radius you have to ask the question and
when you're designing a system what is
the blast radius of this particular
component is compromised what is the
blast radius of that compromise
and so what if we were to tie in the
same things that we mentioned before but
tie them down to the application so a
client comes in has a JWT we're able to
say that a particular system has to have
a JWT but also the application server
and database server all have their own
cryptographic identities as well so in
this scenario in the database server
I have a an identity and that identity
is sorry so it's saying I will only
receive things from the application
server that has this specific identity
and I will only process the request if
the JWT of the user has been forwarded
to me or an equivalent that is an
equivalent token that's been swapped out
through some third-party identifier
so I have something that's
cryptographically provable from the user
before I process so that application
server has been compromised if it tries
to just arbitrarily access the database
server and it doesn't have that external
identity that's attached to it that
should that should go to my
observability platform and tell me I
have a problem so it increases the the
risk to the attacker and reduces the
value of the attack to the to to the
attacker again not saying that this is
100 perfect and and impossible to break
but it's a large part of security is
about economics you want to try to
increase the cost to the attacker while
simultaneously keeping the constraint of
the cost to you and you want to decrease
the value so that it so if someone is
successful they you minimize the value
they get out of it and so it turns into
an economics game it's like how
expensive is it to break into a system
so I'm tying it in this identity
Provider from that JWT that we mentioned
that's actually coming from a
third-party environment and not not from
your your system so your application
should never be
as much as possible you should not be an
identity provider it should be an
identity consumer that also goes for the
workload identities
the workload identity thing that
actually issues out the certificates
should not be in your application that
should be something that your
application works with presents evidence
that hey I'm an application server I
have this this image hash I have this
TPM that I can prove et cetera et cetera
and
so that way that when something connects
in you're like in this scenario you
don't actually have a way to Mint the
token yourself so it becomes difficult
to to impersonate
so one of the standards that I'm uh that
I'm a promoter of is uh is spiffy and so
spiffy provides a structured way of of
providing an expire online certificate
on how you structure that out
and also allows you to generate JWT off
of that so that you can then identify
your applications either through either
the x509 or the JWT path both of them
are important you want to always have
mutual TLS impossible using xyline
certificate
the JWT is useful for the transitive
identity problem that I mentioned before
again not a perfect solution but it
gives you a little bit extra that you
can bind against in order to say hey I
have something here that proves that I
at least spoke to the originator that
that had access to that token
um and so
uh once so let's let's back up a little
bit and uh now that we've given a
definition for zero a definition for
zero trust and of course this is not
comprehensive there's a lot more if you
Reacher than this definitions through
the season definitions or they talk
about how to get the devices actually
provisioned how do you get the user
smart cards or similar or they talk
about data they're actually still trying
to work out what to do with data yeah so
it's like well something will happen in
the future but like there's a lot there
but when you're trying to establish a
new paradigm that new paradigm is not
going to you don't want to start with
everything you want to start with one
thing like started with Identity or
start with policy you don't want to just
jump and like jump all in and so the
very first thing that I like to focus on
is actually work is actually looking at
the organization like you actually want
to have a conversation with the
executives too so you get that bio like
nothing will happen without the
executive buy-in uh actually if you ever
take a cissp that's actually one of the
big things that they talk about is you
have to have executive buy-in
and so when you're talking to a CSO what
is the purpose of a of a CSO so granted
we're at a security conference so I know
many of you know the answer of that but
at the end of the day it's not just
about improving your information
security it's also about constraining
constraining the risk and making sure
you constrain the cost of that risk so
that the business can continue to do
business
so information security 101 I'm sure
you'll see this slot this document
everywhere the confidentiality integrity
and availability confidentiality you
want to keep your secret secret
Integrity you want to make sure your
data remains uh untampered with and
availability that you can access it when
you want
uh which is conveniently CIA
so if you if you have trouble
remembering it just remember CIA it'll
help lead you towards this
um so the way that they tend to do this
is they tend to push towards that setup
policy uh there's also a term Overlord
here so from now on when I mention
policy unless I explicitly say it's like
an open policy I explicitly mean
organization policies at this point so
policy are things like how do I all all
devices on encrypted devices or sorry
all data arrests must be encrypted like
that that's a simple simple policy
standards are like how do you do that
well our standard is we use AES with
this with a specific key size procedures
here's how you do it in Linux here's how
you do it in Windows here's how you do
it in Mac OS these procedures must be
followed guidelines are best practices
like best practice might be something
like if you if you're if you're
resetting a password maybe you trim the
the drive you don't really need to but
maybe it's the best practice you do and
so
so once you get executive buy-in or once
you're pushing towards that the next
thing you want to do is you want to find
out who all your who owns the policies
and who and who and who wants the
standards because the the reality is
that if you're looking at a zero trust
implementation it's very unlikely that
you what you're implementing and not to
say that it will meet the policies but
you will almost certainly not meet the
standards you will not meet the
guidelines which means whatever you do
is going to be outside of those
standards and guidelines that have been
established because it's a new paradigm
so what you have to do is you have to
enter into a conversation with the to
work out what are the policies what are
the current standards what are the
current guidelines and again this goes
back to the executive buy-ins that way
that you can work out who do you need to
talk with so you can learn what is
necessary for your infrastructure
and ideally you want to try to find a
Greenfield application where it suits
really well and where you want to
experiment with it and get the green
light from uh from the uh from your
Executives of whoever's allowed to to
make that final decision
and before you write a single line of
code you actually want to Loop in your
security teams now this is something
that I think is a good practice even if
it's not zero trust
you want to Loop in your security teams
early on your application design because
usually what happens with application
teams is they'll start developing and
then they'll hit a brick wall and it's
like well you have to do all these
additional things to comply and in the
meantime your application security
standards have actually suffered because
you're not bothered to bring in the
experts and so having those
conversations early on means that the
the cost of of implementing and getting
to that to that secure place not only
are you going to be more likely to hit
the the standards and get that approval
but you're also going to have a lower
overall cost so it's important that you
get that that you that you get into the
habit of working with or if you're on
the infosec side to be receptive to that
as well so if you're on the other side
of that like please if you have a
developer comes around and they're
trying to get to you to follow this
pattern like please help them out
because that's how you get that's how
you get the transformational change
um aren't you architect it you start
something small I recommend identity and
mutual TLS says initial starting point
because even if you don't add the policy
the fact that you have membership uh
that is cryptographically verifiable uh
improves your total security posture
just flat out it just improves it just
if that's all that you get out of it and
then you iterate
so once once you have that initial first
thing you want to do and you've and
you've worked towards getting an
implementation you also want to make
sure that you look at the observability
every single action you do has to be
something that's observed and that
second line I put in there of a tree
falls in the forest and you did not
observe it did it really fall well you
can add you can change that word to tree
fall too if you had a security incident
or security breach just because you
don't know about it doesn't mean it
didn't happen
uh and the and so
even worse if if it's discovered and you
don't have information to show what the
scope is you have to also assume the
worst case scenario which it might be
like oh everything is gone
so
and the uh you're actually part of the
reason why I recommend you look at
observability as a as a an or as a
mandatory part of your first step is
because it turns out that observability
is often defined based upon the previous
set of practices so the number of places
that I've seen where
the way they identify their service is
actually IP address import so you come
in with just use a simple example not
even looking at the zero trust side I
just come up with kubernetes that IP
address is is going to be reused across
so many different clusters so that iPad
or support I'm not going to say is
meaningless but it's pretty close to
meaningless like you're not going to be
able to you're going to have a lot of
extra work to try to work out and if you
look at what the Pod has access to
the pods Network only sees its private
IP address it doesn't know what its
public IP addresses and so you just
don't have the information as the
application so this is why I recommend
you if you focus on on adding that
observability early on is because it's
something that is crucial and you have
to find out what those gaps are so that
your so that your teams are able to
build it into their into their sock and
various other and various other systems
and so
uh you'll likely still need to capture
the IB address and port to comply with
the previous tooling but the way that
you deal with that is you add the the
cryptographic identity you had before
you add it as a as a uh as a field
within your within your observability so
that way it gives you something to start
with doesn't break your existing tooling
but it gives you something you can bind
against
the third part is after you've
implemented something as small as it is
you want to document it and you want to
talk with others about it generally what
from an education perspective I I tend
to recommend my teams do three things
they design they have their initial
architecture documents that they wrote
and you have to be careful here because
you don't want it to devolve into a uh
into a waterfall method you want it to
be iterative and so those documents need
to change over time as you learn more as
well but you want to make sure that you
actually have something that you can say
here's what we did
and then the reason for the for the high
level deck
of slides is that especially on larger
organizations when you're trying to
convince others to to follow in the same
path as you or you want to or how to
integrate with your system
your your Architects are not going to
have time to read through a 50 or 100
100 page document describing all the
details so you want to have something
that's that's short to the point that
gets on the the high level information
but also give them a pointer to where
they can find the details when they need
to
the reason for the baseball cards
um that may sound like a useless
exercise but again executive buy-ins
your if your Executives say you know
what this is starting to look like a
cost center we're going to back out well
you're you're done so you want to have
the the the cards there so that way that
you're you're describing to your team to
your executive teams you're managing up
the chain giving them what they need to
know in order to in order to continue
green lighting you and at the same time
making sure that you're enumerating the
business value that you that you have in
terms of like well we spend money to
implement zero trust but these teams
were able to accelerate because of these
particular reasons we're able to get to
Mark to Market faster or we're able to
integrate faster because uh because of
the score we were able to prevent and
discover these additional attacks that
uh if you're in a production environment
so you can actually give numbers to say
like here's here are things that we were
able to mitigate simply by the design of
it
and also make sure to present to others
not not only at conferences but also
internally you set up time to to meet
with others to to discuss
um on the side the reality is a very
large organizations will have uh we'll
have Legacy infrastructure like if
there's many up many systems will have
many startups that grow into large
companies will sometimes have a model
platform that you can work on and you
can make all your changes there
but most Legacy systems actually have
like you you pick the technology it's
probably in there especially the older
companies like they'll have mainframes
they'll have very major supported
version of Microsoft they'll have
they'll have various Linux distros in
there
uh so it's like and you pick the
database it's probably in there and so
when you start looking at it from from
that perspective you don't have a single
thing that you have to to work on so you
have to actually
and not every system can be retrofitted
with with your trust and so in those
scenarios you don't want to just say oh
that's going to stay as perimeter
defense
what you want to do is you still want to
issue out an identity so you might have
a system that you can't like say it's a
Mainframe you can't modify the Mainframe
but you can give that that application
that the Mainframe is running on you can
wrap it around the proxy and give it an
identity and say this system this
Mainframe can only receive messages from
these systems and can only communicate
with these systems
so you now have something there again
it's not uh it's not to the level that
we would love to get to but it gets it
still is a compromise it gets you to to
a place where you can still reason about
it with within the broader environment
and one of the things that I found is
also useful is
I would just split the inter and in
intra communication uh and I'll use
kubernetes as an example uh just to
split those two into two different areas
so like intra service communication is
things like I have a pod that wants to
communicate with another pod uh how you
secure that you want to have some
flexibility because many applications
are actually bound to the infrastructure
that they run on like there's certain
applications that you must have istio to
run it will not run without istio same
thing might happen with with Kuma or
Linker D or similar so when you have a
vendor come in and they say well we're
using this specific service Mission
that's what it works with like you don't
have a choice at that point
um and by separating out the treatment
of inter where inter is like I have an
application communicating to another
application across boundaries
the reason you want to have that in
place is that it allows you to also
bring in the previous things that are
Legacy so that way that when you have an
application communicating
that application you can still reason
across those boundaries and it also
gives your infosec something to bind
against that is a little bit easier than
every single micro every single service
so you can say the developers will state
what the application is going to do
internally but once you start Crossing
those boundaries then you the
applications have to go through some
through some policy that is controlled
globally by infosec where the infosec
can say uh yes this communication is
allowed or not allowed you can actually
write those policies as pull requests so
the developers will say I want to
connect a to B and then the infosec
person is the person who reviews it in
approves or rejects it and if they
reject it they can give feedback as to
why I was rejected so they can iterate
on it which turns into the entire policy
as as code
how you do that is for another
presentation there's so many different
ways to do that but that's the pattern
to to uh tuning towards
um and then you want to you want again
going back to the automation so
automation is just a set of control
loops that that manipulate state in some
way so you observe the state perform an
action You observe the action you report
on the action and you repeat this over
and over again
uh so
part of the key here is that when you're
working on a larger environment if
possible you want to generalize what
you're doing so you don't want it to be
bound to your specific application and
every single application has a slightly
different way of doing the exact same
thing
so if you can generalize what you are
doing as part of the automation then the
initial time it's expensive the second
time it's still expensive but it's way
cheaper the third time you're basically
getting it for free at that point and
also gives a central place where when
you update the system you're not you're
not updating each one to spoke you're
updating one spot and then you have a
path towards updating everything across
the across the environment you do have
to be careful there because it also
allows you to uh to quickly roll out
your mistakes too
but that's part as part of the process
is you want to get into into good
cultural habits of like doing good code
reviews and testing and similar so
uh and then back to back to the
education after you've done that you
want to educate your your team because
at the end of the day uh Silo culture
will break you and I'm serious like the
fastest way to to destroy a as a zero
trust uh environment when you're trying
to roll it out early on is to is to
treat everything as a silo
and so
um again to reiterate you have this uh
this process of repeating that
information like of going through the
same process over and over again
and so at the end of the at the end of
the day though and this is really what I
want to drive the point towards like
I've shown you a lot of information uh
in terms of like what zero trust like
how can you get initial section how do
you how do you communicate how do you
set up some initial processes
but at the end of the day there's not a
single culture or single technique a
single thing you can bring in that's
that'll transform you because at the
because these are Paradigm changes
they're your Paradigm shifts that we're
seeing here
and without the so you need to focus on
the people you need to focus on the on
the processes and if as an organization
you sure if you're a vendor you can sell
tools to help this but it'll ultimately
up to the to the consuming organizations
to make these particular changes and
anything you do to help them in that
cultural shift is is really where you're
going to get that that value because it
is ultimately about the processes and
and about how do you people looking at
the blast radius when they're developing
people looking at at uh what is the cost
of what I'm doing what is what what are
what's the level of granularity
constantly asking these questions as
they're architecting
um and also driving that communication
with your peers so with that I want to
thank you and I don't know how much time
we have for questions so I don't think
we have time
um so thank you very much
[Applause]