today securing user server access in
kubernetes
hi I'm messim I'm an engineer at Dallas
kill and I'm Mike atrovsky I'm the head
of product at tailskill we work at
telescale today we're here to talk about
a specific problem that you might have
which is allowing users to access
internal services that you have running
in a kubernetes cluster
so we're talking about the network
security of connecting users to services
and kubernetes we'll cover first what
kinds of traffic you might need to
protect in kubernetes and why you might
have that kind of traffic going to your
cluster then we'll specifically look at
users accessing internal services in
your clusters that's the focus of this
talk so we'll look at the security
properties that you likely want for
protecting access to these internal
services and we'll go over the various
options that exist in and out of
kubernetes for protecting this traffic
and then compare those so analyzing
which options work for the security
properties that you actually need this
talk is geared or meant for Network
administrators or security teams using
kubernetes with some understanding of
how kubernetes works so let's jump in
there are many kinds of traffic that
might be going to your kubernetes
cluster first it's the traffic that you
need to get kubernetes working the
traffic between the components of
kubernetes like from the cube API server
to the control plane in the control
plane to the cubelet in your work your
nodes or pod to pod Communications
hilariously I gave a talk on exactly
this topic four years ago now at kubecon
and I've forgotten all of it but if you
want you can watch the talk the traffic
that's managed in kubernetes and is
mostly has authentication integrity and
encryption again watch the talk if
you're interested
our second kind of traffic is traffic
from a service to a service such as from
like a front-end application to a
database this can be both intra or
inter-cluster it might be coming from
another kubernetes cluster if the two
applications are in different trust
domains or hosted on different platforms
or just managed by a different team or
if you're using like a microservice
architecture and the full app runs
across multiple clusters this service to
service traffic is often controlled
monitored and secured using a service
mesh
Third Kind of traffic here traffic from
a user to a kubernetes control plane for
when a member of like your devops team
or info team is accessing the control
plane to manage cluster configurations
you can hit the IP of the cube API
server directly and authenticate to
cubectl but many folks secure this
connection with something like Sebastian
and then lastly traffic from a user to a
service that you're running on
kubernetes if this is a web app for
example then this could be an end user
of your application who's trying to buy
a dog toy or on your website or if it's
an internal app then it's an employee of
your company trying to run a Check
processing job or something like that in
a bank branch and if it's a public app
you might use like a load balancer to
manage direct access to that service
so thinking of those like four kinds of
traffic that we just talked about
you know security folks and those are
the typical Solutions we also also also
mention security folks worry a lot about
how to secure access from a user to the
kubernetes control plane like with good
reason you know mostly because apps is
in the control plane would give you full
control over the cluster however we're
not here to talk about that because
there's so much guidance on that topic
but what we are talking about is that
last item there a user accessing
internal applications that you're
running on kubernetes because there's a
lot less guidance on how to do that and
how to do that well
an internal app that you're running on
your kubernetes cluster is different
depending on your circumstances some of
the other options listed here like a
service mesh or Bastion or a load
balancer might apply to how you protect
traffic from users to internal services
um so you're asking like do I really
need guidance on this topic uh probably
um the kubernetes docs unhelpfully tell
you that your service may or may not be
public and also it may or may not be
authenticated I'm not a bad at the docs
like there's so many potential options
that you can have here so it's on you to
implement a solution
um all right so what are some examples
of kinds of apps that you have these
internal apps that users are trying to
access
there's many internal services that
might be in your cluster when you're
running a service in kubernetes there
are a lot of other things that you run
alongside your actual service that you
need to maintain and then be able to
access
anything that's started by Cube system
so databases monitoring logging and
tracing other tools those should only be
accessible to your info team and if
you're in the kubernetes dashboard or
like the web UI that's another
monitoring service that's only meant for
your info team
you might also have some other internet
applications for your organization that
you you know manage and host on
kubernetes just like web apps for your
customers maybe there's an easy way
internally to look at a metrics
dashboard or look up the employees in
your company in a Wiki of some kind
and so do you really need to secure
access to these applications well
probably they might include sensitive
information that could be used to learn
your organizations
data like customers or financials or at
the very least they probably shouldn't
be public and these Services shouldn't
necessarily be accessible by everyone at
your organization so you are actually
going to need some kind of way of
authenticating or restricting access
even internally
so let's look at some criteria and these
are these are the criteria we came up
with right um when you're hosting an
internal application there are several
security properties that you're going to
want the service to have
first visibility this is hopefully
self-evident but if you're hosting an
internal application it should well
actually be internal you want something
that's not publicly accessible and
restricted to a set of individuals who
are part of your organization
authentication this ensures that you
know and verify the source and
destination of the traffic that is you
verify the user and the service they're
connecting to
authorization stricter than just
visibility authorization ensures not
only that your service is internal but
only the right individuals in your
organization have access to it
you could also build authorization into
each of your applications rather than as
part of the Central Access solution but
that's putting a lot of a lot of work on
each of your application teams
encryption by encrypting your traffic
you're preventing just anyone from
reading it encryption ensures that only
the authorized parties can actually read
the traffic so that any unauthorized
party that intercepts traffic can't read
its contents
load balancing if you're running
multiple instances of a service you want
to load balance between them so that
you're not overwhelming a service in any
one node
This falls into the availability part of
security
and traffic filtering your service might
not allow all traffic to access it you
can fill the traffic for unusually high
requests like in response to a DDOS
attack or to rate limit one user who
might be limiting another user's ability
to use a service
internal applications might also filter
traffic based on other criteria like
location maybe you don't have any
employees in Australia and so it's weird
to see traffic coming from there
and lastly auditability you want to
Monitor and log information about the
traffic going to your service so you can
ensure it's acting as expected
you also need these logs in case you
need to review access as part of like a
security incident
and there are other criteria here that
we haven't mentioned that aren't
necessarily you know purely security
focused you're going to you're going to
want to have for users connecting to
internal Services
um namely latency and availability but
like I said we're going to focus on the
security properties
so let's keep these criteria in mind
when evaluating solutions for accessing
internal apps
all right so what options do we really
have
um the first couple options laid out on
this on this slide are kubernetes
constructs they're what kubernetes
provides out of the box with cluster IP
and then on top of cluster IP you can
use a kubernetes load balancer which
allows you to load balance traffic
hitting a service across multiple
different instances of that service the
traffic could originate from either
outside or inside the cluster
kubernetes Ingress which allows you to
Route web traffic from outside the
cluster to Services running inside your
cluster and kubernetes network policy
which allows you to restrict access to a
given service
the next set of options we're going to
consider are some of those that we
mentioned earlier that you're typically
used for other kinds of traffic in
kubernetes so a service mesh which
allows you to Route traffic between two
Services which could be in the same or
in different clusters
and a Bastion to enforce traffic to a
sensitive resource that goes through an
audited and controlled entry point like
restricting access to the kubernetes
control plane
and lastly we're going to throw into the
mix some more generic options for
protecting traffic between users and
services at layer three where the
underlying network is encrypted or
untrusted the first is ipsec which is a
protocol for encrypting Communications
between endpoints and then wireguard
which is a more modern tunneling
protocol for end-to-end encrypted
connections and those can be used
Standalone or as part of VPN type
Solutions
so I gave you two lists a list of all
the criteria and a list of all the
options
so you know what we're going to do we're
going to compare them
it's a very exciting talk
all right
thank you Maya so
let's dig in so as I mentioned the basic
building block for services on
kubernetes is a cluster IP service right
which basically provides a stable IP and
DNA stands for accessing Bots within a
cluster
uh the virtual IP is shared among the
pods a all the traffic router to that
ipe will be routed by the cluster to
that pod or to any of the replicas uh
the Pod if the pods go uh come in or are
scaled up or scaled down uh though those
pods get removed from the service
destinations uh the traffic keeps
working fine you don't ex you shouldn't
see hiccups with that point however the
cluster IP service is internal only to
the cluster it is not something that you
can hit from outside the cluster without
doing some
additional steps
the other thing is that cluster IP also
does not provide any encryption all it
really does is that it takes your
packets of that your application would
get normally and it just gets it from
like different sources from like
different parts of the cluster different
nodes different pods
it also doesn't do any authentication or
authorization out of the box you need to
add authentication and authorization to
your application layer
uh
unlike cluster ipe Services load
balancer services are actually publicly
visible
uh these Services basically take a
cluster IP service which is pointing to
like multiple replicas of your pods and
it gives it a public IP
uh the problem is that that IP is public
which really means that anyone on the
internet can reach it so it puts even
more onus on this application layer to
add authentication and authorization and
to do traffic filtering a lot of sases
actually do something similar not
necessarily in kubernetes but they have
IP allow listing and uh so that you can
only restrict access or you can only
access the service for using some
well-trusted IPS
yeah
the third type of thing that we use to
build all these Services is kubernetes
ingress which is a collection of routing
rules that specify how traffic is routed
to the service within a cluster so you
could imagine that you have a web web
page which is uh
running your toy app or your uh internal
banking system or
CI system or anything
and you could expose all of those as
like different services with different
load balancers and all of them could get
different IPS but instead you could use
kubernetes Ingress which provides a way
for you to reuse some of those like use
a single public IPS and public instance
and Route multiple domains behind it
it also allows you to do traffic routing
based on paths not just host names uh
some of the some Ingress controllers
like nginx and traffic uh provide
authentication and authorization using
oauth and jots
but it's still really uh and the really
nice thing that they provide is GEOS
encryption which is that any traffic
hitting your uh hitting that service
will get automatically get a HTTP assert
or and make sure that those that no one
in on the public internet can intercept
your traffic and see what is going on
without doing like no one can man in the
middle of your thing
uh
the fourth type of thing that we use for
all of this is kubernetes Network policy
what this does is that it says uh for a
set of PODS or a set of or namespace or
set of services it can restrict what uh
traffic goes in and out of that pod so
you could say that only a namespace can
talk within itself you can say that only
these pods can talk only like the
front-end pods can talk to the back end
pods uh only the back end ports you talk
to the database pods and you can
restrict access using that
you can use the network policy in
addition to like kubernetes load
balancers or kubernetes Ingress to
further restrict who can access it but
really all this provides is a way for
you to secure servers to service
communication it really doesn't help
much with the user to service
communication because the user users are
on the public internet and they're going
to be reaching over the public internet
so you would need either to do like IPL
listing like I mentioned earlier or you
would need to do something more fancy
like
uh authentication and authorization on
like different parts of the user
identity
the other really interesting thing
development that happened in kubernetes
or in this space was a service mesh what
this does is that in typically in
kubernetes when you have pods
communicating with each other the
traffic is Flowing between them is plain
text it is not encrypted it is not some
it does when you're sending traffic to
someone on in your network in your
cluster it is not necessarily you're not
always there's no way to guarantee who
that traffic is coming from you could
spoof the traffic you could spoof the
IPS you could do a lot of you could do a
lot of
funky things in order to get around the
restrictions however what service
measures provide is that they run you
use a sidecar proxy next to basically
all of your pods
that side of car proxy will intercept
all of the traffic and make sure and it
will commit when it's communicating with
other services it will form mtls
connections or Mutual Tios connection
and make sure that the communication
between the services is strongly
authenticated and you know that two
services are really
that when you're talking to a service
you're guaranteed that it is that
service that you're talking to and
you're also guaranteed that the person
who's calling you is the or the service
that is calling you is that service
uh
yeah
back over to me so um the next option we
have is the Bastion so Bastion host is a
server running an application like a
proxy or a load balancer that serves as
the entry point to an internal service
um traditionally the combastian is the
point of entry to your network it's the
it's the hole in your firewall and
following a traditional Network model
because it was a single point of entry
to everything in your network and
everything inside of your network wasn't
encrypted or authenticated since this is
before zero trust Trends then the
Bastion was particularly strongly
protected so once you got past Sebastian
then you were just into the network
so a Bastion is meant to be a single
bottleneck for anything that needs to
flow into an application and by forcing
all the traffic through a Bastion you
can then have a single place to enforce
authorization and authentication do any
filtering you want to do and then log
access
um so it's your point of entry yeah but
it's also your your point of policy
enforcement
typically a Bastion is often just like
openssh set up on a host U.S agent to
the host and then from there you can
reach the resource that you're actually
trying to access so in terms of
visibility Sebastian has to be publicly
accessible which means that others at
minimum know that it's there even if
they can't actually access it you can
authenticate users to the host on based
on SSH username and password keys or
certs and use this for authorization
decisions although you might also be
running a Bastion with like a single
user that everybody logs in as and so
you might not have that if that's if
that's what you've set up instead opensh
is encrypted so you get that
bastions don't have any notion of the
services that you're connecting to they
just say like oh you're on the network
now you're in so and then and so they
don't try to load balance or in any way
or do any kind of like sophisticated
traffic traffic filtering you know once
once you're in
and if you're using openssh open SSH
lets you log messages about what the SSH
server is doing
there's there's obviously more complex
Bastion offerings on the market now
which have better logging simple to
manage authorization and some traffic
management like I mentioned but um
and there's also hosted proxies that are
provided by the cloud provider so if you
have something running in a cloud that
might be the better solution for you to
have it managed to manage for you on
your behalf
all right so those are the options that
were that we're considering that are you
know used for other kinds of accessing
kubernetes
so now let's talk about kind of generic
connection and protection options
um so ipsec
ipsec is a layer 3 protocol for
encrypting information between two
endpoints it's used for transferring
data or as part of a traditional VPN to
encrypt traffic when it's on an
untrusted Network ipsec can encrypt the
whole packet in like a tunneling mode or
just a data packet in a transport mode
which allows you to inspect the headers
for like more complicated routing you
might be wanting to do in your network
to use ipsec you need to have both the
source and destination host that you're
connecting from into perform a key
exchange to establish a tunnel of which
traffic is then sent so for users that
are connecting to an internal service
that means in practice that each user's
device will need to be able to initiate
an ipsec connection so for example by
installing a client on each of those
users devices this is the most common
implementation I'm not using ipsecond
like a standalone tacky way but by using
it as part as a protocol on a VPN ipsec
vpns are a common way for users to
access internal Services no matter where
they're running not just on kubernetes
but they could also be used to access
Services running on a Commerce cluster
so if we're looking at ipsec and IPC
vpns for this use case
in terms of visibility ipsec doesn't
care where it's connecting to as long as
they're reachable so if you if you you
can have a service on only you know
private IPS but you'll need your VPN to
have something like not traversal to
actually make them accessible
ipsec provides authentication and
encryption of Ip packets it doesn't
provide authorization natively but
probably if you're using an ipsec VPN
that's exactly what it's doing it's
giving you authorization
ipsec doesn't have any built-in traffic
management like a notion of load
balancing or traffic filtering some of
my PSI vpns if they're using
concentrators which is kind of like a
Bastion you put all your traffic through
there to get access to other stuff on
your network then they funnel all the
traffic through that Central Point and
in that case a VPN concentrator might
allow you to do some load balancing or
traffic filtering
and lastly auditability again since
ipsec is just a protocol you don't get
any of this for free but with an ipsec
based VPN you can expect to get network
logs of which users are accessing which
services in some cases you can also
introspect the actual traffic like the
packets So Not only would you know
metadata but a connection like you know
Alice is connecting to the hiirs system
but specific information like which SSH
commands are being run by a specific
user on a specific box
and the last option we're going to
consider wireguard so if you're not
familiar with wireguard wireguard is a
layer 3 tunneling protocol that lets two
peers privately establish an end-10
encrypted connection wireguard uses
public Keys rather than public IP
addresses to identify peers so as peers
move connections can still persist the
only thing you actually need to
configure is which peers you want to
communicate with
like ipsec you need to have both the
source and destination host that you're
connecting to and from perform a key
handshake to establish a tunnel which is
then used for for traffic to encrypt the
traffic that's being sent so again for
users connecting to a service each
user's device will need to install
wireguard however compared to ipsec wire
guard is explicitly designed to optimize
for security performance and ease of use
and so wireguard given it has like
opinionated modern photography there's
very little things to configure the only
thing you really do configure is like I
said the set of peers that you're going
to connect to you're not picking
protocols for encryption all that kind
of stuff
so looking at wireguard connecting to
internal services
wireguard like ipsec lets you connect
Two Hosts anywhere as long as they're
reachable and can continue to connect
even if an IP address changes as I
mentioned so a user could like initiate
a connection to their database on their
laptop at home bring it to the coffee
shop and finish their work and then the
connection will still continue with no
hiccups you can also connect to private
IPS like with ipsec if the VPN that
you're using offers something like Nat
traversal
wireguard has built-in authentication
and encryption Margaret uses the stream
Cipher Cha-Cha 20 and encryption for
encryption and poly 1305 for
Authentication
authorization is managed based on the
configured list of peers so if a device
has a peers public key then they can
communicate and there's but there's no
other authentication built in again like
with ipsec vpns that are built on top of
wireguard would add authorization that's
what you're using a VPN for
and like ipsec wire guard doesn't have
any built-in traffic management for load
balancing or traffic filtering again if
you're using a VPN and it's in like that
concentrator model like that funnel
model then you might be able to do it
use it to do load balancing
and like ipsec there's a theme here
there's no built-in logs or monitoring
for auditability of a wire guard based
connection but you could expect that
from a VPN that you're that you use that
it's wiregrade based to have to have
those kinds of logs
right
um so let's do something a bit more fun
let's do a demo yeah uh
so since I work at TL scale we're gonna
demo tail scale
using tail scale to reach a kubernetes
service internally
uh in this tail scale is a
wireguard-based mesh VPN mesh Network
means that traffic doesn't go through a
concentrator but connections are
directly peer-to-peer so you get better
latency you you're not there's no single
point of failure uh
and it because it's based on wireguard
all of your connections are always
encrypted from like one device to a
different from any device on to any
other device it will always be into an
interoper
so in this demo we're going to set up a
service in uh kubernetes
uh then we're going to set up uh
something that we just are about to
release yeah we're dropping something
we're dropping some new stuff soon not
CVS yeah hopefully
so uh yeah we're gonna use we're gonna
install the telescope operator uh and
using that tailsql operator we're going
to expose the service to our tlnet and
let's see what that does
okay
so I'm gonna
I'm sorry this is going to be annoying
because I have to change this place
can you see the same thing now okay cool
so
I have
bigger okay so I have this
mini Cube cluster that I created
yesterday it is about 17 hours old
you can see that it has nothing running
on it there's only the cube system
namespace which has pods running on it
there are there's just
it's it's a blank cluster there's really
nothing here
so the first thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to create this service called
classes
and this will get me some parts and
we're going to hope and pray that the
parts come out quickly and did it okay
so uh then we are
gonna expose that service
and you can see this and I'll just show
this to you
so it's literally just a simple
deployment it there's nothing fancy here
uh it's just running in web mode
and I can show you the glances service
this shows again standard nothing
interesting I'm going to now apply this
and we can see that as we were speaking
talking about this earlier we have a
cluster IP that we can now read well if
we were in it in the cluster we could
hit it if I do this
oops
nothing will happen but what I can do is
I can do port forward I have port
forward somewhere
yeah there you go
and then I can go to localhost 5000 and
I get this fancy thing that works right
but obviously this is running on my
local machine and that's not useful
right so what we're going to do
is we're going to now apply slightly
we're gonna create the operator which
so this is the kubernetes tail scale
operator that we're just releasing
and you can see that things are coming
up and things are there and as the
telescope upper starts it joins my
cluster oh it joins my tail net
you can see that this I have tail scale
running here and there's the operator is
here it's not that interesting yet we'll
we have some plans on how to make this
more interesting but anyways back to
this
so now I have the kubernetes operator
line I'm going to do a diff of this and
this now
to show you that all I'm doing is
basically
making a load balancer class I'm
changing it from this is mini Cube
running on my laptop I'm going to say
that no make it a load balancer instead
of a cluster IP and use a tailscale load
balancer class I also tell it to use the
demo hostname
so let's do that
so you will see
that details here operator has spun up a
new pod
and has given me a
a URL that I can hit okay so I'm going
to hit this URL on my machine and this
is not going to work but this might
hopefully maybe
if I'm lucky
oh it does work
right no Port forwards no nothing I have
something that's running on this
um I hope that it doesn't isn't always
this slow but I guess Wi-Fi
it's fine
uh while we wait for this to do stuff
what we're going to do is we're going to
use a new feature and this is this is
not part of the operator that we're
about to drop this is coming soon but I
it's in a branch somewhere that I'm
working on but
what this does is so there's a I'm sorry
yeah
it's it's like literally ours old
so we're gonna and this is the other one
which is
glances
funnel
with this the only difference is that
this is another annotation that I add
and as you can see from it what it does
is it uses the new uh new feature in
telescope called funnel
and it will allow you to have a public
IP on your machine
on my laptop sitting here
in this booth all right
okay it loaded yay
now
what has let's see
yeah it seems to be working okay
so now I can go to
this
and if I do that
it starts to get a certificate
wait what
it's doing stuff
but in HTTPS cert and doing DNS yeah it
sets DNS locally and now what I can do
is I can get off of tail scale
I'm no longer connected to Telltale
and if I'm lucky in the Democrats are
with me this should still work
and
and maybe not
Maybe
we're in limbo we're in limbo we're
hoping that it works
maybe Carl has a better luck
that's very small yeah I'm just
so as you can see it did do stuff it did
uh the it hasn't it has a public IP it
did stuff it is it got the certificate
uh and I'm sorry the internet is not
great
but uh you guys can right now go to this
this URL
as you can see on your phone and it
should work you can hit his laptop you
can hit my laptop my service is running
on this cluster so this is
obviously this is not you would not
expose an internal service like this but
you could use
you can use sales skill to expose the
service running basically anywhere in
the world uh either on kubernetes are
not in kubernetes and access it from
anywhere in the world without doing any
port forwarding without like I'm on a
public Wi-Fi in some conference and it
works
nice thanks
yeah don't kill the service yet so
people can hit it yeah I'm trying not to
um yeah so I think there is that's not
what I wanted the um
so it was spinning up a service of a
load balancer class type on on
kubernetes adding a true telescope
Network which then made it accessible to
anybody else who's on your telescale
network who has authentication
encryption all that goodness
just like you would want for an internal
service and then if you wanted to make
it publicly accessible like if you were
trying to share a link with a partner of
you know something in CI CD that you
were developing or that type of thing
you can just share you can easily get I
am um trying DNS and https and then go
from there
while we figure out how monitors work
because that's actually harder than what
Messengers did apparently so okay you
also type really fast
okay where was my presentation
[Music]
I think I think I lost it
s lights
okay cool
yeah I'll make it happen
oh
no that didn't work either oh I see give
me a sec
dragon
the other way click the next slide for
doing the wrong way
there we go we have something oh
live demos are fun
and these aren't lived almost fun
I love that the live demo is easier than
than fixing slides
all right so we did a demo
um again thanks for the demoism so we've
covered all the options that we had and
none of them provides all the properties
that we were looking for which is not
shocking nonetheless let's go look back
at the options that we considered and
how they stack up and I'm sorry that the
text is so tiny there's too many options
and two criteria
so for the kubernetes constructs you
know combining kubernetes cluster
services with load balancer gets you
load balancing that's it it gives you
inbound connectivity from outside the
cluster to Services running inside of it
combining kubernetes cluster services
with kubernetes Ingress gives you
encryption and load balancing you can
still
you know you can Route traffic into a
cluster with TLS that terminates at
Ingress which may or may not be inside
the cluster
with kubernetes network policy you can
restrict which Services inside a cluster
can communicate with which other
services including restricting a service
to only access accept traffic from
Ingress
then for the set of options that are
typically used for other kinds of
trafficking kubernetes service mesh does
it everything or it can in some cases
depending on what you're trying to do so
why shouldn't you use a service mesh for
the user to internal service use case
well you can again you just need a user
to install the service mesh agent on all
user machines which
ends up looking a lot like a VPN right a
Bastion is a single point of entry to
your network it typically provides
authentication authorization encryption
and auditability but it sits on the
public web and it might have some
traffic management capabilities if
that's something that you need
and then for protocols that are used to
protect traffic that we talked about and
are typically used as part of a VPN
ipsec gives you authentication and
encryption and ipsec-based VPN will
typically provide you with authorization
and auditability and may have some
traffic management options and similarly
wire guard can be used anywhere that you
wrote traffic but only gives you
authentication and encryption with
authorization based on public Keys a
wire guard based VPN will typically
provide you with authorization and
auditability and might have some traffic
filtering the main reason to favor
wireguard over ipsec in this scenario is
just a simpler configuration right with
better connectivity as the user changes
between between IPS
wireguard-based vpns with a coordination
server rather than a
um yeah with the coordination server
like Tesco can also use natural to allow
you to Route traffic to private private
IPS
so the option that you should choose for
your application doesn't only depend on
security properties right as I mentioned
earlier you also think about you know
latency availability usability it's a
huge reason to decide what to do for
your internal users as well as ease of
management of whatever solution you pick
but there isn't a clear winner so I have
this very you know every solution has
its trade-offs I know it's a very
unsatisfying conclusion to this talk but
here we are nobody wins but also nobody
loses which is
um all right if you want to learn more
about some of the content we covered
today check out these links
um there's a community's documentation a
link to the operator that messum demoed
and you can get a link to these slides I
will leave this here and then I'll put
up the next slide which is a QR code for
some feedback
great
yeah so uh tailskill provides uh has its
own uh Apple system so you can restrict
access to like uh you can say like uh
Maya can reach my laptop or I can reach
her laptop but no one else can so you
can and the authentication is based on
your identity provider
so it'll be like Maya tillscale.com or
whatever or her email is yeah is going
to be able to reach my lotto
not your browser but your machine so
there's a tail skill client that you
need to install on your machine
and you log into that which will
authenticate you to the using your IDP
and give you credentials
yes
or is it all around
uh to find uh
if I wanted to expose an application
I want to
at all then
um
no not really so you can you can make
um you can write access controls based
on users groups that includes groups
from your identity provider IP addresses
uh tags which are kind of like a service
account like a service account
um that type of thing
um so you might say something like you
know like my can access Finance machines
or people in the you know Dev team can
access the production Network
uh you can also restrict based on
important protocol
yes yeah
any idea that
tastes like
uh not that I know of uh you can I don't
know about that but I know wireguard's
padding is very well defined and very
small yeah like if like if wire guard
breaks they have to redo like if the
underlying encryption breaks they have a
way of changing like a version number
but then like everything else every
single bit is used basically right
there's no there's nothing over there's
no overhead I don't know about if he's
like yeah neither sorry yeah
yes
yes so tail scale has a feature called
tailscale SSH which does basically that
so if you can install if you install
jail scale on your nodes you can
restrict who can access your nodes and
as what user and it runs its own SSH
agent on the machine so it gets a lot
more fine-grained access you can there's
also a Mode called check mode so you can
say like Maya needs to re-authenticate
every four hours in order to reach the
servers you could also just run any SSH
traffic over any either ipsec or
wireguard and that should work fine but
then you have to manage the client the
you know user names and passwords or
keys or whatever it happens to be
there's no reason that wouldn't work for
for both ipsec and wireguard-based
solutions
any more questions
cool
if you have any feedback
there's a QR code
[Applause]