hi everyone nice to meet you today my
name is FEI Huang I came from a social
security
so today my topic is about kubernetes is
a perfect platform for enforcing zero
trust security
let's get started
so let's use the famous log4j
vulnerability as an example I think
everybody and urban knows that first a
lot for gcpe was discovered on November
2021 only one week after that right
there's a real world exploit attempt was
reported
and then of course the patch was
released a few weeks later in the next
few weeks and months we keep seeing new
patches uh published but at the same
time new related cve are also reported
so for the companies I mean we have a
lot of clients customers they have to
keep patching their applications keep
waiting for the new patches right
so this whole process takes a few weeks
or months or even more I think yesterday
Brian mentioned there's a cve not being
patched after 15 years that's kind of
crazy so they all obviously we all
understand this is a chasing game we
call this reactive security model
so we have to scan monitor detect
respond based on real incidents we have
to keep waiting for the new patches this
is working but I don't think it's
efficient I don't think it's enough
right
so how about the CVS that without
effects how about you know can we
prevent log 4G like critical security
issues even before it's been discovered
the answer is yes please think about
this how about we can detect attack
at the network entry point even before
it hits the real application
how about we can block the command
control Links at real time
and we can block any suspicious process
of file system access no because this is
a never-thinking process before it could
be a remote code execution it could be a
crypto Miner
and the idea is we should minimize the
attacking surface right at runtime and
we should lock down the behavior of
every Running part
so we call all those good functions
proactive security model or zero trust
the security controls
so why kubernetes is the perfect
platform for this new security model
let's use a real workflow think about
that see a developer could Define the
security manifest into a yaml file it
can even Define the application runtime
forward policy into the Yama file as
well because developers is the only
person know how this container is going
to talk couldn't communicate in the
runtime so those information can be
checked into the git repository same as
their source code right and then the
build pipeline going to carry it over
all the way to the writing clusters
choose a new vector-like Solutions we
will be able to pick up those security
Manifesto also the policies directly
from kubernetes at runtime then
Federated the policy out enforce it
right away the beauty is this whole
process can be fully automated you know
oh I mean you can see that the
kubernetes does make a security solution
much smoother much stronger and much
better that's that's why
so I would like to use two real customer
profiles to emphasize runtime zero trust
security control is very important
a customer which is a fortune 200 in the
price another one is a fully SAS based
Financial Service online bank right
interestingly they all run their
containers in multiple complicated Cloud
environment they have you know Cloud
hybrid Cloud multiple cloud on-prem or
even on Airgas environment so it does
require security to be managed scaled
the same way
so the multi-cluster Federation and also
the security management is is needs to
be supported
another strong requirements is you know
those applications in production are
mission critical
basically you know that company's most
important assets it does require you
know they have a strong runtime
protection in place so they use zero
trust runtime protection with security
Automation in place to make sure it's
not slowing down the devops process
and
there's also compliance requirements in
in the play right uh for the uh those
Mission critical you know workloads
there are all kinds of compliance
requirements in different countries
different Industries so to satisfy that
they use the layer 7 container follow
with buff and DRP enabled which does
help them to pass auditing from for
example stock 2 PCI DSS or HIPAA
so due to the time limitation today I
mean I can only highlight a few things
about zero trust for kubernetes for more
details please feel free to stop by our
booth at the solution showcase we also
have a free ebook from this QR code you
can download so that's my presentation
today and thanks everyone
okay