okay hi good afternoon
um
who's enjoying the conference
oh about half of you who's who's learned
something new
well that's great yep that's the reason
we're here
and I have one more opportunity to to
maybe try to share something else that's
a little new
uh so welcome to my session on teaming
at a station for the cloud native world
with parsec
um
a title that was so long that it
actually had to be truncated off the end
of the digital display just outside of
the room
um it is a long title but I'm going to
try to justify all of the parts of it as
we go through
so quick business card so my name is
Paul Howard I'm a principal system
Solutions architect with Arm based out
of Cambridge in the UK I've been with
arm for a little over four years now and
I focus on solutions that span the
hardware and software and try to get the
best out of both so if you're wondering
what is somebody from the CPU
architectures company doing at a cloud
native conference hardware and software
working well together is very important
um
I clearly need a higher resolution
selfie
or maybe the picture's fine and I just
look like that in real life
um so so
a lot of my work is investigations and
prototyping but also open source
development and I'm actually one of the
founding maintainers of the parsec
project which is a cncf Sandbox project
um other
facets of my online presence you can see
there and you're welcome to make use of
them so if you want to connect with me
or follow up on anything you hear this
afternoon please do
so here's what I'm going to cover
so this is a session on parsec but it's
a session on new directions in parsec so
there isn't going to be time today to
cover parsec in depth uh it's not going
to be a deep dive on parsec architecture
I will introduce it I'll go through the
motivations for it
um because maybe not everyone here is
familiar with it yet but also because
some of that context and introduction
will help with the main topic of the
afternoon which is at a station
so I'm going to talk about some future
work in parsec to expand its feature set
into the world of attestation and I'm
also going to bring in another open
source project called Verizon
an operation lives and breathes at a
station and is concerned with the
verification of attestations so I'm
going to be talking about parsec for
evidence Gathering and veraison for
verification and we're going to see how
these two projects can be combined
and then we'll see to what effect and
I'm going to focus on two examples that
I think are particularly interesting and
hopefully relevant to us
the first is the use of attestations as
part of establishing a secure Channel
between two entities where we're working
with the industry on an extension to TLS
1.3 the built at a station
into the handshake
and the second is going to bring in
another cncf project namely spire and
talks about how I think that Spire can
consume the work that we're doing in
parsec and Verizon
to
to do
a new
a new way of doing hardware-based node
data station
I will I hope leave some minutes at the
end for Q a I don't mind being
interrupted briefly so if I need to
clarify or just repeat something but
let's save more involved questions for
the end just in the interests of running
to time
okay so let's begin here with the cloud
native Edge so what does this mean
well Edge Computing nodes were
traditionally gateways so in an iot
application the role of a Gateway is to
sit between the endpoint devices that
are typically non-ip devices and to talk
over those local protocols so think of
your Bluetooth your zigbee modbus those
kinds of things
Gateway can gather data from endpoint
devices and it can deliver actions or
commands over those same protocols and
then of course in turn the Gateway is an
IP capable device it's on the internet
it can go and talk to services in the
cloud
as for the kinds of compute workloads
that would run on Gateway as well those
tend to be embedded very tightly
Hardware integrated singular of purpose
flashed in the factory and they would be
doing things like protocol translation
and the compute power of devices like
that would generally be quite modest
so that if you like is the Gateway model
of edge computing
so what's a cloud native model
so as the number of connected devices
increases so too does the volume and the
complexity of the data that they
generate and back hauling that kind of
volume of data for processing centrally
in the cloud starts to make less sense
economically or in terms of performance
or even sometimes the regulatory reasons
and what this means is that we see a
drive towards processing more and more
of that data locally at the edge
on edge Computing nodes that have more
compute capability built into them able
to run more sophisticated workloads
doing things like ml inference or Sensor
Fusion
so if our workloads are more
sophisticated then it means that they
are looking more and more like stuff
that we're really used to deploying in
the cloud The Edge becomes more like an
extension of the cloud rather than this
very rigid locked down embedded Gateway
that we have over here
so the edge becomes a place where we
want to roll out and orchestrate
applications and services just like we
can in the cloud and so for this reason
we can call this a cloud native Edge
so Gateway model
Cloud native Edge model
and that's great
but we do hit a challenge when it comes
to security and it's because we
encounter this Collision of Worlds so
the edge sits precisely astrides two
very different engineering paradigms the
world of the cloud and the world of iot
devices
in the cloud we have rich workloads in
high-level languages we have
multi-tenancy we have cicd we have
containers and orchestration everything
is very fluid very portable we don't
even really see the hardware platform
much less care about it
we're just writing and deploying
software
now in the world of iot is very
different
we're dealing with devices that are
running outside of the cloud
they may be in tamper-prone environments
they're also far less uniform
there's lots of platform diversity and
suddenly you can't escape needing to
know a lot about the platform and the
hardware
and a great example of where this is
true is in the application of
hardware-backed security
if we are in a temper prone environment
then secure assets like secrets and
private keys are really going to need
hardware-backed protection
and hardware-backed security is very
platform specific some Edge nodes will
have something like a trusted platform
module the TPM there could be some other
kind of Hardware security module or a
secure element
and
there's also the possibility that
discrete Hardware of that kind is is not
cost effective or it complicates the
design of the device too much
and we might then choose to build secure
services in software
but isolated from the rest of the system
using isolation features that are built
into the CPU and we'll see an example of
that later on
so we have fragmentation
and this throws up roadblocks when we
want to be Cloud native the apis that
they offer are very low level they're
very device specific they mean that
you're writing code in the C language
with an embedded mindset tightly coupled
with the hardware and needing quite a
bit of specialized knowledge so it's a
world away from that high level portable
code that we aim to write if we really
want a cloud native Edge
now up until recently the best available
solution to this fragmentation problem
with Hardware security was the pkcs11
interface also known as crypto key
and even today you're going to find that
that is the incumbent solution for cases
where application code needs to be
bridged to Hardware security
and we find that all manner of shims and
bridges have sprung up both proprietary
and in open source making it possible to
use pkcs 11 to talk to TPMS to hsm's
secure elements and so on
and it's okay as far as it goes but it
doesn't go far enough
for a cloud native Edge experience and
this is for a few reasons
you'll find actually as soon as you try
to deploy in this way the pkcs11
implementations are notorious for
following the standard imperfectly
and even with that aside
it's still a very low level developer
experience we're either having to write
code in C or we're having to use
something like a foreign function
interface to bring that up into another
language all of those crypto and Key
Management functions
so it's still still a very close to the
metal way of interfacing with Hardware
security
so improving on this status quo is the
role of parsec
ncf sandbox project this is why parsec
exists now parsec is more than just an
API like pkcs 11 it's a microservice
that handles all of that interop and all
of the low-level details of Hardware
security on a whole variety of platforms
that is growing over time
where possible it cuts out all of those
nasty pkcs11 shims it can talk natively
to the TPM API it can talk to secure
elements and other Hardware Security
Solutions
and if you need a new one
it's open source go contribute one
and if you have an interop bug
go fix it Go contribute the fix and
everybody benefits
now the parsec API is not defined in the
C language this one is language neutral
so parsec defines it as a set of
serialized contracts on a wire and this
means that it can be surfaced into
programming languages in more creative
ways ways that are more fluent and
idiomatic for consumption in that
language
so at the lowest level we're only
transacting bytes on a transport with
system calls we're not bringing in a lot
of C crypto functions
and the use of IPC and a microservice
means that the client's applications
can be in containers we can even have
multiple logical applications sharing
that service in a multi-tenant fashion
if we need to
and the vision for parsec is that we
just want it to become part of the
platform really we want it to become a
supported package in Linux distributions
in yocto recipes it's a it becomes a
pervasive low friction path convenient
portable high level and evolving and
improving over time through expert
Community contribution
okay let's look at a reason why all of
that's useful
so suppose we have an edge Computing
device that's going to run some
workloads that are rolled out to it from
the cloud these workloads could be
containerized modules for example so
think of a technology like AWS green
grass or Azure iot Edge
and we want these devices to be
provisioned and registered securely with
the cloud we want to be sure of their
identity and the provenance
we can do the provisioning step like
this we can create a private key on the
device
and a corresponding public certificate
which is then chained to some CA and
shared with the cloud so that the cloud
can trust the device
and then at runtime when the device is
in the field it can talk to the cloud
securely by means of a mutually
authenticated TLS connection the cloud
and the device share their certificates
with each other the device
proves ownership of that private Key by
signing for the TLs handshake
and then finally the secure channel is
established which is foundational to
whatever else needs to happen in the
product stack and deliver and execute
those workloads so you'll see this
pattern or some variation of it in
systems that need to do secure
onboarding
and it's a great fit for parsec because
on the edge devices
those private keys are resources that
you absolutely want to protect ideally
we would want to provision these things
directly within a hardware enforced
secure boundary and then access it later
to do the signing
and then if parsec becomes the default
low friction path for achieving this
then I think there's a greater chance
that customers will adopt Hardware
security because right now the lowest
friction path is the out-of-box
provisioning solution that's offered by
the product Stacks that normally means
generating your key pair in the cloud
and then importing it onto the device so
it was never provisioned within the
device and you don't know where it's
been in the meantime
and it could be stored just as a file on
disk protected with nothing more than
file system permissions
so what pasta games to do is offer a
comparable level of ease and simplicity
but gaining a stronger security stance
as a result and this is the kind of use
case that it supports already
and so we take the next step
and this is one of the more exciting
opportunities that we have with parsec
and we have it precisely because
parsec is not locked against a fixed
crypto API like pkcs 11 it's its own
project its own microservice it has its
own API that can grow organically and
the opportunity that we have is to grow
pulsec Beyond doing only key management
and cryptographic operations while still
providing those crucial platform
abstractions for portability
so we've seen that we can provision our
private key with Hardware protection
and we can use signatures in TLS to
prove ownership of the key
but we are only proving ownership of
that key we aren't proving anything else
now TLS is going to work
whether that private key is Hardware
protected or not that the signature
proves ownership of the key but has
nothing to say about the history or
provenance of the key and nor does it
have anything to say about the overall
state of the platform it's Hardware it's
firmware or any of the other components
that are running on it
and so the answer to that is to ensure
that the private key
is attached to a platform that we can
vouch for
we can vouch for it because we have a
chain of measurements of all parts of
the system going right back to the
device's hardware route of trust and we
can verify all of those measurements
remotely you may recognize that that's
remote attestation it may be familiar to
you and the remainder of my talk is
going to be about how we can take the
existing portable key management and
signing capabilities of parsec and grow
those out to include the kinds of
Primitives that we need to support
remote attestation flows while
maintaining that abstraction and that
portability
and then I'm going to talk about how we
can make use of those capabilities once
we have them
okay let's look a little closer at the
components of a remote attestation flow
there are essentially three aspects to
it so we have endorse a test and verify
and this flow diagram indicates where
and how those stages take place
endorsement is the process by which a
manufacturer or provisioning entity can
make a statement about what is valid
if a device has these properties this
platform State this configuration then
it's trustworthy
and the provisioning entity makes these
statements to a separate entity the
verifier or the verifier service
this verifier service then becomes the
authoritative database of valid devices
and measurements and configurations
manufacturing can then deploy a device
to the field and that device might then
go and register with a cloud service
much like we saw a couple of slides ago
only now it can do more than just prove
ownership of the private key it can also
Supply a package of signed evidence to
attest to its own state and its own
configuration
the cloud application or service then
relies upon that so it becomes the
relying party and that Reliance is based
on this critical final strut in the
triangle which is verification
so the devices signed evidence is
presented back to the verification
service which receives the
manufacturer's endorsements for that
device which had received the
endorsements previously
the verification can then match up the
endorsed characteristics with the actual
presented characteristics and if they
match the verifier can tell the relying
party yes we can trust this device it's
a known good device it's an unknown good
state
now verification Services exist in the
ecosystem some device vendors provide
them some product Stacks come with them
as being readily available but I want to
take the opportunity today to bring in
this other Linux Foundation project
called Verizon
is not a cncf project it's actually
being nurtured within the confidential
compute Consortium which is a different
branch of Linux Foundation but it is
open source and it is relevant to us
here because Verizon is concerned with
the verification part of the process
Verizon is in fact a set of reusable
components or building blocks that can
be used to accelerate the development of
verification services
that offer a high degree of ecosystem
compatibility by adhering to Open
Standards it defines apis for
provisioning and for verification
now I can't go into detail on Verizon
today but I do want to bring it into the
conversation because the work that we're
doing on attestation in parsec is aimed
at matching the capabilities of parsec
to those in Verizon
so in essence it's making it possible
for a parsec enabled a testing device to
bring its evidence to a Verizon based
verification service
okay let's come back to parsec so why is
parsec in the picture
well we've already seen its role in Key
Management so that we know that the role
of parsec is to provide Simplicity
abstraction portability in the face of a
diverse Hardware ecosystem
and these things continue to matter once
we're talking about attestation
because it turns out that attestation is
also device specific and causes us
similar problems if we want to code if
we want our code to be portable
okay let's concentrate on two different
route of trust Technologies not the only
two that passer can work with but we are
focused on these two for attestation at
least to begin with
so we have trusted platform module the
TPM here on the left and then on the
right we have an implementation of the
PSA route of trust
now PSA stands for platform security
architecture and PSA certified is a
widely adopted security standard for iot
the PSA route of trust allows the
device's foundational security to be
built in a way that is cost effective
and not necessarily reliant on discrete
Hardware module like a TPM so it can be
built out of software or firmware
components typically integrated by
silicon vendors into their sdks and
isolated from the rest of the system
using an isolation technology that's
built into the CPU
so arm trust zone for example would
provide that kind of isolation
and then we have these small packets of
functionality we call trusted services
that run within as architectural
isolation boundary
conceptually it's comparable to the TPM
but the implementation is different and
then of course the apis are different
and the data formats are different
and so again it's a fragmentation
problem and we're back very much in
parsec territory needing a common
abstraction that allows client code to
be portable and simplify it
so when I talk about taming at a station
in the title of my session that's what I
mean
in those boxes we can see examples of
the data formats used so a TPM will use
the TPM 2.0 data structures a PSA
platform uses something known as the
entity at a station token or eat
and we're doing some work in parsec
right now to expose both key attestation
and platform attestation apis that can
work across these distinct route of
trust back ends and they're going to
work in terms of a common encapsulation
format that uses something called the
conceptual messages wrapper
now this wrapper is being nurtured by
the rats working group which is one of
the ietf working groups that focuses on
attestation these wrappers are
self-describing and they're keyed on a
registered media type which makes them
an ideal format to convey between the
components that don't want to hardwire
themselves to any single physical
representation
so they can deal with multiple
representations they can dispatch to the
correct kind of processor by peaking
first at that media type and then
assuming that the rest of the data is
organized according to that type
and the slide has a link to the ietf
draft that goes into much more detail on
how that works because I'm
that was really just a lightning
presentation of it
um there's a there's a lot more to it
so these common encapsulation formats
can be applied end to end also
throughout a net a station flow for all
stages for endorsement for verification
as well as for Gathering the evidence
so parsec can provide them for all
platform types beginning with the two
examples shown here
and Verizon can consume them so it's a
nice story for bracing these two open
source projects together
okay so for the last part of the
presentation I'd like to look at two
areas where we are applying this work
and let's look at the attested TLs
proposal first
this is another one that's being
developed within the ietf some of my arm
colleagues are contributing to this but
also in collaboration with engineering
teams across the industry so there's a
link to the top at the proposal in the
ITF data tracker where you can go and
read in much more detail and go and look
at the lovely ASCII artwork diagrams in
The Proposal
we looked at TLS before it's obviously
foundational to the connection between
an edge Computing node and the cloud so
until you have a TLS connection you
can't really do anything else TLS by its
nature excludes any peers that cannot
prove ownership of the correct private
key
now the attested TLs proposal goes
beyond proof of key ownership and brings
attestation into scope for the handshake
phase now there's a real Elegance to
this because it makes attestation a
prerequisite to the establishment of the
secure Channel
and it means that by the time you have a
secure channel the device has already
been attested and verified so it's a
very neat way of excluding devices that
can't prove themselves to that level
it closes a threat window that might
otherwise exist if you set up the secure
Channel first and then do attestation
afterwards
that doesn't mean it's going to
necessarily suit every kind of workflow
full secure channels but the onboarding
use case is one example that I mentioned
earlier that might benefit from this
kind of approach
so the diagram is a simplification the
ietf proposal has all of the details but
I do want to stress what's essential
about the proposal you'll probably be
familiar with TLS based on x509
certificates
but what this proposal introduces is a
whole new credential type so it means
that attestation evidence can be used as
an alternative to x509 making use of
some of the extension facilities that
are present in the design of TLS
so that then allows us to make use of
the common abstractions and wrapper
formats that I talked about on the
previous slide the secure channel can be
established based on that same trust
relationship between the manufacturing
entity the testing device and the
relying party on the verification side
which again I've indicated can be built
using components from the Verizon
project
okay other details I've had to gloss
over you can go and read about them
follow the link all of this work is of
course being done out in the open you
can follow along with a POC effort for
this and that's that's going on in
GitHub I've got some links assembled on
my final slide which we'll look at in
just a second
but before that let's just finish up
um and talk about another potential
application of this work which I was
discussing with the Spire Community just
towards the end of last year now spire
and parsec already share a little bit of
history and there is a YouTube video
with myself uh and Andres Vega talking
about the use of
um spiffy identities when calling past X
so the parsec can work in a in a
multi-tenant fashion
um that was in 2021 I think for the cncf
production identity day and it's on
YouTube
but for today so let's look at Spire no
data station
so Aspire has workload as a station and
node as a station no data station is to
verify the provenance of the compute
node on which a workload is running
and Spire has a plug-in architecture
that allows nodes to be verified via
different characteristics
so one of those verifiable
characteristics could be a hardware
route of trust that is on the Node
and there are no data station plugins
available today that can already use a
hardware route of trust if it's based on
a TPM
but with the new attestation functions
being added to parsec which is portable
it raises the possibility of doing no
data station based on an abstract route
of trust using a TPM when it's available
but using other technologies that might
be on the platform such as the PSA route
of trust that I mentioned before
and you have that similar client server
separation that we saw in the case of
TLS so Spire node data station is
separated into an agent plugin and a
server plugin so the proposal here is to
create an agent plugin that consumes the
parsec apis and a server plugin that
consumes the Verizon apis and there are
go client libraries for both parsec and
Verizon
now there isn't a POC of this in the
works just yet but I am really hoping to
get one started and it would be great
for the past second Spire communities to
come back together so if you're
interested
do please come and talk to me because
I'd love to engage
okay so that's it some useful resource
links there you can follow all of these
if you download the deck thanks once
again uh for coming thanks for listening
and if I've done this right we should
still have some minutes left for any
questions or comments
foreign
yes
uh sorry can you ask again
okay so the question is is there
anything for runtime attestation as
opposed to boot at a station
um so I think anything that you can
measure
is potentially in scope with this work
so yes boot
at a station
um is is generally what you think of
when you
think of Hardware route of trust and
platforms like a TPM for example
um but with with what we're proposing
with past second Verizon
um
both are extremely flexible so there
definitely a scope for measuring
components within the system that are
not just the bootloader not just the
firmware but potentially going beyond
that to Encompass other things as well
okay
um if there are
if there are no other questions
um thanks very much uh that QR code is
my session feedback code
um if you love the session please go and
tell me uh if you hated it please
remember how busy you are and you don't
have time to fill in feedback forms
and enjoy what remains at the conference
and have a safe trip home
[Applause]