we're here at ICANN 57 with the
leadership of the 2017 nominations
committee from left to right we have
hans petter Hollen the chair to his left
stephan van gelder the associate chair
and to his left say he jameel the chair
elect hans petter let's start with you
what is the role of Nam calm yeah the
noncom is appointed by all the
supporting organizations in icon in
order to select half of the members of
the board so we go out and look for
candidates that are outside the normal
crowd that are involved in the sporting
organizations in order to make sure that
we get the good diversity on the board
we have some bio requirements to make
sure that there is at least one
candidate from each region and no more
than five and in addition to the border
requirements we also look for candidates
for there is some of the supporting
organizations and new this year for the
PTI what are the board positions that
need to be filled by the 2017 9.com so
this year there are two open board
positions for three-year terms so as we
look at the geographic diversity there
are no hard requirements at this point
in time so we're actually looking for
people from all over the globe and we're
looking for people that can bring
experience to governing the icon
organization moving forward Stefan are
there specific changes for the non calm
now that the public technica public
technical identifies the PTI is formed
yes this is a year of great change for
the non calm and for the whole community
because we are now post-transition so as
you've just mentioned the PTI the public
technical identifies is a new group that
will take over the IANA functions once
it's fully incorporated and we the
noncom are tasked with selecting to that
board as well it's a five person board
we are tasked with selecting two seats
to that five-person board
and we will start doing that this year
with one seat having a two-year term and
one seat having a three-year term so
that we build in the rotation that we
need for that board as well so the
noncom has just seen its workload
increase and it's also going into
uncharted territory but it's a natural
and logical extension to the very
important work that the noncom does for
the community so he'd what are the other
leadership positions and why do they
offer offer opportunities for people to
get involved it's a very good question
because apart from the very important
work of selecting appointees to the
board the noncom has this responsibility
of actually filling certain positions in
three other organizations supporting
organization advisory organizations
within the icon structure so the first
is the gns oh and I'll come back to
these in a second then there's the a
lack and then there's the CC NSO now the
gns oh basically makes policy with
respect to all generic gTLDs and imagine
the fact that you drop in somebody into
that this shows that it allows the I can
structure to function without
crystallization or gaming of groups to
create monopolies they have their own
processes by which they elect them
bringing representatives of course they
have some of them have diversity
requirements but this enables the NAM
come to a point individuals who will
bring new ideas and views to the
policy-making process with a Gina so for
instance also within the a lack there
are various different regions in which
appointments have to be made and again
dropping someone into those you see it
gives the enablement to the community at
large to apply if they have the criteria
to be able to come directly into these
positions not necessarily coming up from
bottom up this allows a nice mix between
the policy processes of those who are
part of the sort of the hardened
community as it were in some sense or
those who are coming up through the
organic process versus those who can be
dropped into this and said well you know
there's a complete different view let's
actually see where this ends up at the
last one is the CC NSO the advantage of
being appointed to a slot within the CC
NSO is that you wouldn't be able to get
to that because you have to be part of
some national ccTLD structure and
dropping someone into that actually is
very beneficial both to the two giving
more new views as it were to the ccTLD
structure so I think that's very
important appointments it's an
opportunity for folks for who have the
capability and understanding they don't
have to necessarily have a technical
understanding of these things but to
come into these positions and try to
provide some more substance in different
views to all these organizations sounds
like you're saying it's a chance to to
helping facilitate chain absolutely and
that change is not going to come
necessary from the community that is
constantly coming to icann meetings are
involved but from somebody from outside
I think that's very very important
hans-peter let me ask you this
accountability and transparency r at the
heart of I can talk to me about noncoms
work in that arena this is at the heart
of noncom as well of course we need to
keep candidates and candidate data
confidential because otherwise people
may not apply for these positions but we
have over the last year's and I'm also
want to continue that this year to be as
open as possible which regards to
process and with regards to what we are
actually doing so the noncom has a
public website non-conductor I can dot
org where we will publish all our
processes and we will also publish
report cards with the progress of our
work moving forward in addition to this
we have an open meeting and we have an
open meeting and at every year every I
can meeting to talk about and solicit
input from the community about what
we're doing and this year it's actually
also a review coming up so there will be
an independent reviewer which is
currently out for bid by by icon and the
noncom has already set up a working
party to to work with that reviewer so
that we will have an independent review
of the afternoon come in the comic cycle
very important work gentlemen thank you
very much appreciated
you