joining me today is becki Berg co-chair
of the cross community working group on
framework principles for future
cross-community working groups thanks
for taking the time to speak to us today
Becky hi sir could you take us through
the background to this initiative sure
um we the I am a member of the CC NSO
Council and for many years SEC NSO has
used this cross community working group
approach to resolve issues in advance of
policy development and we had gained
quite a bit of experience with it and
and the gns have started using that the
approach as well until we collectively
decided it would be good to look at
across community working groups that had
worked really well and those that hadn't
worked quite so well and try to figure
out what the differences were and
developed some best practices for CCW
G's to increase the likelihood that they
would be successful so the gns o council
adopted the final framework and thirteen
to Victoria this year could you take us
through the top the key principles that
contains in the final framework well
they're very commonsensical in a way the
most important thing is to actually
start by defining what you want to do
what your goals are what your output is
likely to be what the scope of the topic
is how you will make decisions in the
group going forward and to agree on that
through Charter development but then all
of the participating SOS nacs can agree
on can review and then agree on that's
the most important thing to decide in
advance what your what your goal is and
how you're going to operate and get
buy-in from everybody obviously more
recently
we've noted the need to actually think
about the kind of expenses and the
support that you're going to need and
lay that out in advance and then you
know to have really clear working
methods that that get there the most
important thing though really is but is
the Charter is getting that charter
right from the beginning so with both
the CCN som the gns or now having
adopted the final framework how do you
think the community will go by
implementing and operationalizing with
well i think that people are beginning
to look at the outcome look at the final
recommendations that have been adopted
and and then go back and look at ongoing
CCW G's to see whether they've really
got that the points covered the the
recommendations are they're not
mandatory they're not written in stone
there's the need for flexibility because
every CCW g is a little bit different
the other thing is I believe that when
people start talking about collective
work they're going to have this
checklist to kind of think is this the
right vehicle is a CCW G the right
vehicle should we be having some kind of
birds of a feather discussion group
instead but this will serve as a
checklist to help people decide whether
the CCW G is the right vehicle and then
to sort of go about setting it up
and you know burying the application
where it makes sense to do that but it
really is a sort of a checklist well
thank you thanks for see here's to the
work of the CC WG and have a great week
here in Hyderabad thank you