swagatham nimesh karim and welcome
welcome to I can 57 being held in
hyderabad or shall I say cyberabad today
gracing us with their presence at this
opening ceremony is the honorable union
minister of law and justice and
electronics and information technology
mr. ravi shankar prasad an honourable
minister for information technology of
Telangana mr. KT Rama Rao Thank You sirs
for joining us today also joining us in
the hall today we have our distinguished
chairman of the ICANN board dr. Steve
Crocker president and CEO of I can your
own marby and member of the number
resource organization executive council
mr. Paul Wilson the icon community is
made up of many different stakeholders
and I see that amongst us here today we
have members and representatives from
various I star organizations industry
civil society technical community and
academia and government thank you for
your contribution and making I can into
what it is today and I welcome you all
to I can 57 the icon public meeting
returns to India after eight years much
has changed in this time today over
three billion people are connected to
the Internet India has over 400 million
Internet users it is in this context I
share with you some numbers related to I
can 57 as of last evening we have over
3,000 registered participants from a
hundred and thirty nations and from
India we have over thirteen hundred
participants
stood now I take this opportunity to
welcome several Indian business
associations to I can 57 I welcome
NASSCOM and DSEi I welcome CII is Pai co
AI i am a I and many newcomers to I can
57 we are really happy that you chose to
be here today and finally welcome to all
participants who are joining remotely
before we move ahead I shall take this
opportunity to thank our hosts the
Government of India including the
ministry of electronics and information
technology Ministry of External Affairs
national security council secretariat
Ministry of Home Affairs the government
of Telangana national internet exchange
of india BSNL tata teleservices we also
acknowledge the kind support of GM our
airports and cyber bath police