my name is Joe Grande I am a hardware
hacker in like to engineer
basically design stuff and break stuff
I'm today I mean it a given talk about
the J tell you later which is a tool
that I've recently designed that will
help you identify
a on-chip debug interfaces and useful
things on
pieces love target hardware so I'll get
get right into it
and explain everything as I go I went to
demos today
and sorta interspersed the demos with
some the lecture
and is a two-hour workshop we actually
have
sometime at the end above the lecture to
actually get
a people involved you guys can come up
here experiment I have a few
different J tag editors I'm a few
different target devices that you guys
can
Inc plug into either with your laptop or
my laptop and just going to experiment
with stuff so
part of the session is meant to be an
open kind of hands-on experience seeking
to play with new hardware and tinker
with things that
you might not normally get to tinker
with up so that's why we we have the
same extra time
so the agenda we're gonna go through I'm
kinda introduction
%uh look at some inspiration for the
project talk about
identifying interfaces on a circuit
board so what our interface is well how
can they be
how can they beat located wire they've
been useful and then once we find those
a talk about why manually locating these
interfaces a sort of hard-wired to
allege a tiger there's actually
a useful now go into the design
requirements and summer the actual
hardware and firmware design details
above the unit
I figured I you know a lot of tools that
are out there sort of these black boxes
aid is getting you use
but the J tabulate it was meant to be in
open source platform that you can
build from scratch if you honor build
with the a get a
a bear circuit board assembly yourself
and really does make it
completely opening completely accessible
so I think you're going into the details
of the actual design and why it works
the way it does
but will this help you understand the
two on the better you understand a tool
the better you can use the tool then
we're going to specifically
but two different on-chip debug
interface is one of them BJ tag
hence the name Jay tell you later that's
a industry standard
debug interface RN talk about that first
and will also
mom talk about you are interfaces for a
synchronous serial interfaces
us those are the two types of interfaces
that the Jade I go to concurrently
detect
and then we'll up over time hopefully
add more functionality and kinda more
features
they're going to limitations future work
and then open up for that kinda hands-on
workshop
we will take a break at ten o'clock
a for 15 minutes so on ship the bike
interfaces are certain a well-known
attack vector in the in the hardware
space
if your harbor act: usually what are the
first steps that you do when you're when
you're attacking hardware as you get
access to the circuit board you say okay
where where are their interfaces were
can i connect to on the board
that might give me extra functionality
or might get serve as a stepping stone
for me to do other things like extract
data or manipulate the system
a there's plenty of examples above
recent hardware hacks people using these
debug interface is so it's really
it's sort of an Achilles heel and
vendors know that but vendors and
engineers need
these interfaces to develop the product
into actually work with their products
so
you know they don't really want to
remove them because gonna make their job
way harder
so we can take advantage of the fact
that anything that's there for engineers
gonna be great
from the attack point of view sometimes
the vendors try to do
since they know that that that attackers
and hackers and go after these
interfaces the China obfuscated in some
way maybe they say okay
we need to have RJ Tiger face on there
but let's cut some traces
during production once we're done
programming the device
once we're done testing the board are
less remove some resistors from the
board
or maybe they try to implement up
password protection which is sorta
there's no standard for
for passive protection on on interfaces
Cesar all their own security
usually as we know rolling on security
isn't good and maybe they'll be other
ways that you can find
a to defeat that Pastor protection the
one problem is that identifying on-chip
debug interface is actually
I can be time consuming it can just be
really annoying
I and and potentially difficult
depending on the integration of the
board
%uh how much stuff is on the board how
how much access you can get to different
features on the board
%uh and and sometimes you might not have
the equipment you might not have the
a desoldering equipment or the
oscilloscope or a logic analyzer that
you might need to manually probing try
to figure out what interfaces are
so sort of requires a some somewhat of
an engineering
skill set but to to figure out these
on-chip debug interface is so
what I want to do is make that you know
a little bit easier and simplify the
process
did to detect these interfaces and to
bring more software focused
non hardware people into hardware
hacking and I think this is one of the
first steps is trying to get people
know to use a tool that will give them
something
in that thread tools all about the kind
I help them through the process
so I did have some inspiration up for
the project but
there are few things that it existed
already as far as proving the concept
love can you enumerate through a bunch
of different
unknown test points on a circuit board
and try different pin permutations to
see if there's a debug interface their
up but none of them were so they're all
kinda packed together in hand
not not really suited for what I wanted
to do and I want to have a platform that
it had to share with people
a in at least have a little more control
over what it was doing
but hunches Jaytech finder was the first
he gave us a presentation back in 2006
about you know having a set up on known
test points on the board
and having a platform I think it was a I
Atmel base development border something
that he was using with with some set a
Buy opens
and he prove the concept he could
actually
minute be late the pans and go through
so certain pre-mutation to detect an
interface those are prove the concept
which is really cool
%uh there are some other work J tagging
on RS 232 in um
by guy named Ed hacker who gave a
presentation at
Chaos Computer congress two years ago
maybe
that sort of refined on hunches work
but it was hardly know based on Arduino
is a sort of a microcontroller platform
obvious microcontroller platform
it had limited I hope and it didn't
really have the features I want it
didn't have good input protection
acted to protect the jet angulated also
to protect the targets are good for that
you're connecting to
since you don't really know what you're
looking up to you and have good
protection there
but it but it took another step further
so I got some inspiration and said okay
cool I noted I know it's possible
on let's try to let's try to make it a
little better
if we can and then the darkest hour fast
track
project on which is a program that was
funding
hackers and small businesses in in the
United States to do kind of
a novel research like new research it
without having to deal with all the
bureaucracy of the government
says it okay cool I'm gonna try to
propose developing the J tag you later
for this project
and get paid to do build stuff which
would be awesome
so I wrote this whole proposal on did
also the research on how the system is
gonna go together
submitted to work it actually got
rejected
said shucks but by that point at RT done
all that base research so now it's just
a matter of designing the things I like
I forget I'm a dude anyway
and that that I can you share with the
world
so the first step that we need to do
regardless if we have
J tag later or not is look for
interfaces on the board look for things
we can actually tap onto
but solder wires on to connect up the
connectors
and see if there's something useful for
us sometimes they will be sometimes they
won't be and that's part of the are
tracking process up and going through
and
and narrowing down the important
information
so personal look at it external
interfaces these are things that you
don't necessarily have to even get
access to the circuitry for
which can be really handy a lot of times
maybe may be on the first unit that your
hacking with you have to open up and see
where that
pins are and see how they come out but
eventually you know if you can do an
attack without having to physically open
up the product
that just makes it that much cooler up
to extend their faces are things that
would be accessible to the outside world
without having to go directly onto
the circuitry those are normally things
that maybe our
are hidden underneath the battery cover
underneath the sticker because they're
not intended for the end user their
intended for the manufacture during the
manufacturing process
maybe clip onto applied onto once the
device is built and assembled to do
final programming our final testing
and then maybe they just covered up in
hopes that the user never sees it
so we can find that maybe that's
something we could take advantage of
and usually it you know might be like a
set of said it s points in a row or
maybe it's some
proprietary connector it all depends on
the product
doesn't examples here here's like 14
pins on the back up a Garmin GPS unit
covered by a little rubber a cover
here five test points in the back when R
is a security token
so it's like 00 interesting there's a
sticker over that little black sticker
see take that off its okay
is that an interface that I can users at
a read-only interface or write only
interface who knows
this one hears from a job on up
wristband like the wearable wristband
device
that there's a little button at the end
that you can select modes
and that device is pretty cool it so
it's not like I've a molded rubber
wristband on for you if you take this
cap of years the button
there's actually four other connections
on their
see okay that's probably the programming
interface to program the microcontroller
during the production process
because you think about the complexity
of this wristband
it's this its there's like a rubber kind
of
sheath around it see can't program it
once it's all put together its on
nice-looking
there's an there's no way to program it
so the only way to do it and usually
don't wanna program
the devices in in a system that
manufacturing in till as late
in the manufacturing process as you can
in case there's changes in case you have
to do for more updates are at the end
so this is sort of I'm you know the way
they can manufacture the product and the
final programming
but for us if we can if we detect that a
week and then figure out what kind of
interface it is
you know that we have built a convention
that
the moving to internal interface is the
third usually
I guess maybe there's same level as you
say their day usually easier to find but
it sorta depends
I'm internal interfaces are gonna be
things that are on the actual circuit
board itself that requires you to open
up
the housing to get it and that's not
normally a big deal
I have a bunch of access points up here
that are pretty easy to to get access to
you either you know
unscrew the case retracted the unit
apart or whatever
but the finer faces we'd normally look
for a few different kinda key features
one of them would be test points
unpopulated pads and test points
are copper pads all over the circuit
boards
that are put on and signals that I'm
interesting signal that the engineer
might need or that manufacture might
need
so you're not going to see test points
on signals that are unimportant
usually would see test point some things
that are like programming
interfaces maybe debug interface is
maybe on
you know different voltages from from
regulators or something they need to
check
during manufacturing so we can look at a
board and you know identify test points
pretty easily
to see okay those are probably good
targets a look at
but even better safer this example
there's been a lot small test points but
then there's like the sport obvious ones
right in the middle
big day fat test points are in the
middle of the board
so I would say okay those are probably
more interesting than the smaller ones
I'm gonna look at the big ones first
same thing on this site here is the
BlackBerry device as much a small test
points
all over the place but then there's this
big clumping up six plus that one
on right in that group so naturally I
say okay those are bigger so bigger must
be better I'm gonna go for those first
and that's just kinda the process you
can also take advantage of 63 markings
6 silkscreen being printed information
on the board
so if we look on this one this is from a
cordless phone
the background i2c clock i2c data
now I know right away the engineer put
those markings there to help them in to
help to manufacture
now I know that that's an i2c interface
is an internship communication interface
now I can go and and put down with my so
let's go for my logic analyzer actually
start sniffing information that's being
transmitted across that bus
sometimes it's really easy and actually
give you you know that good information
other times too if the test by turning
easy access easy to access location
that also sorta gives it away a lot of
times will see the connectors on the
Anza boards
so I i just dont I'm not gonna switch
the camera for this but
you can come up and look I but so for
example like the J Tiger face on this
access point is right in the upper right
corner so it's kinda away from
I all the other stuff to make it easy to
access
same with like this BlackBerry device
there along the bottom behind where that
where the SIM card was so it sorta bad
either way but easy to access
the normally we would look you look
around the edges first and sort of move
in from there
other times the the pinout is based on
like a common format or maybe an
industry standard format
so it's not just a bunch of random test
flights are like it unknown
um grouping but it's something that's
actually can go online and verify
pinouts
to sometimes it be like a single row
been out sometimes double row
the most the most commonly used to be
like a Jay tag interface which again
will talk about more later
but where you can go to this website J
Tate si.com
and and look at different common pinouts
for different architectures
it doesn't mean that the engineers are
going to use those pinouts
but it makes their job easier right
because if they just use a standard
pinout
than their standard development tools
are gonna work on it right away don't
have to create some interface module to
make it harder
a lot of times we'll see just a standard
interface we can just plug into with Jay
tag
hardware not not even meeting Jade
Jagger later at all
because we already know the pinout
plugin and and go to town
so this example overhears from Barnaby
Jack ATM hack from black cat
2010 and %uh part of part of his
researchers figure out how that
you know how to get access to the ATM is
a Windows CE based platform
and you open up the the unit inside
there's actually a connector right there
Jaytech connector standard industry
standard pinout
so all he had to do is buy an
off-the-shelf J tagged
adapter that supported that Architektur
plugin
and and continue on with his attacks
though he didn't know how have to do any
searching to find the interface is right
there and very obvious
same thing on this side is from the
Xboxes a low pin count debug
a conectar el PC in this one we sleep in
one
which has the arrow it's also up in ones
usually denoted by a square pad as
opposed to assert
circular pad so we can look on the
boards okay you know that's unpopulated
we would still have to suck the solder
out of these holes and put a connector
and
but we have to do a lot of work to
figure out you know what it is in the
LBC debug is another one that sort of a
standard pinout
sometimes you get lucky sometimes it's
easy
you can also use on kinda PCB layout US
tix
to get an idea of maybe which connector
is might be
interesting ones are might contain some
sorta bus so
be taken Evangel a fact that similar
traces are grouped together
so if we look at a board like this you
know there's other little traces and
stuff and some other pads around there
but we see this big grouping up traces
coming up
to this connector at the corner the
right away you can say okay the fact
that all these trace their going up
together probably means
it's some sort of similar interface name
it's a bus have some sort or maybe it's
something else all those traces going
together
I miss something that's a clue but
that's no probably where we want to
attack some
some points at the J tell you later
on the other side I'm here's a picture
of another access point I was looking at
this connector was in here I put that on
later absurd is a match in that there's
no just unpopulated footprint there
but there's these resistors connected to
some other pens
so sometimes you can actually look at
aboard and say okay there's a buncha
resistors Nexus unpopular the connector
a buncha resistors neck to this group a
test points
that might be an interface because
resistors either pull-up or pull-down
resistors are used to set the static
state
above a up a system or other bus
so the unused know kinda idle state so
when I saw that I saw you know there's a
few other connectors on the board but I
saw this one with three this is right
there just seem very obvious to me
and that ended up being the J tag
interface I didn't know which pins
but that's legit I get a human rights
like Italy's identify it and then go to
the next step
other boards try to be a little more
sneaky covering the interface with
solder mask
and solder mask is a coating that goes
on top the board to protect
any copper areas that don't need to be
exposed
but to the to the outside world like for
you know that don't need to have
component soldered onto them
so here's a connector two different two
different connectors actually
with the the solder mask on top so the
only way you can get access to the
to the actual copper and make contact
it's a scrape off
the solder mask so it seems like maybe
during
manufacturing now are maybe during I
development
that area was exposed so developers
could have you know some connector
plugged in or something like that and
then they just changes on a mask
a plot when they were manufactured their
boards just covering
cover that over as a very kinda low
low-cost easy thing to do changing the
mask is not a big problem during many
manufacturing and then PCB fabrication
so maybe they did that to cover it up
knowing that you know and users
aren't supposed to touch those things
same day on this side is from a peak
a two-way a email device
that was on the market for few years
this is what you take apart
housing there's these tiny tiny little
test points
all covered in solder mask so you have
to very carefully scrape those of
solder wires down to it or maybe you
could create little test fixture and
have some pogo pin spring-loaded
in a decade touchdown I love those test
points
which is probably what the developers
had I and then figure out what they are
so that gets that damn that is a little
bit harder right because if they put
solder mask over it
what if what if instead of instead of
having this very obvious connector
looking thing if they were just smaller
points that maybe look like beers which
are connections they go through the
board
it might be really hard at to figure out
what's
a legitimate test point for an interface
purses what's just a normal
you know connection on the board that we
don't care about so gets a little bit
harder and you might have to then do
additional reverse engineer try to try
to narrow down your search
another thing that some vendors try to
do is instead of using connectors at all
or test points at all are using existing
rearm
part packages so this case there's four
resistor
footprints but these are the actual J
tag connections
so its security through obscurity right
on the board when you look at it you
don't know which
which components are there are which
components are missing intentionally or
which ones are there to obfuscate
interface you just don't know
but once you find out that these are the
interfaces
those the interface pins that's not
gonna change for any revision of the
board
so it's totally just security through
obscurity that way only takes one person
to find that
the fine and then release it on the
website for everybody but it does make
it way harder
and that's where the jet I get it comes
in
so once you do find the interface the
kinda traditional way to do things
manually
determining pinouts is you first look at
the board you find your connectors like
we talked about
then you try to trace out where they go
I usually there be like I mean
microcontroller on the board somewhere
that's very obviously marked arts
towards the center the board
and usually the connector you want to
see if it goes back to that party could
visually tracings
use a continuity tester a multimeter Inc
on new demoted
check connections and see if you can get
it
no trace them back to the part
and then use the data sheet to correlate
those pin-ups sometimes they can't get
access to the park if it's a ball grid
array device
which have solder balls underneath the
part as opposed to pins that come out
so it's a lot harder to to probe what's
going on as lot harder to see what's
going on
then maybe you need to use x-ray which
is common with
with contract manufacturers you can go
and stupid device an x-ray machine and
see where traces come out see where they
get broken out
and see if you can follow those to the
connectors I
maybe have to remove the part from the
board remove the BJ parts you can
actually see where things are going
there's lots of ways to do it but that's
where things get difficult if you don't
have the experience you don't have the
tools
and then you can also you know probe the
connections use an oscilloscope monitor
what's going on
trial and error of pulling pins high and
low and seeing if that kicks of some
sort of process with the other pens
is a very a very long process in that's
you know that that would that's the
whole goal the day Tiger leaders to
simplify the process a little bit
so the design requirements um for this
tool
as I talked about open source has to be
open source has to be hackable in this
community that's just you know
that's how we make better products as
have things open have people be able to
look at the design and comment on and
look at the firmware comment on it
I am I'm proud to say I learned how to
use get hub
but upload my firmware so it took me a
while
being a hardware guy is a a learning
curve to figure out get her but I did
and now you know that way everything can
be shared sorta it's a it's a really
cool thing
I a lot of the products that design
especially the hobbyist
types the modules I like to have very
simple command based interfaces
to cook up Anderson commands you know to
see a list of commands it just kinda
inner interact with the device in a very
easy way so I have a simple interface
which we do
proper input protection now talk about
somebody's features in detail but in for
protection to protect
are board from getting damaged from
from voltage levels and from from things
that we do that we're not sure about on
the target workers were connecting up to
punch a different test points on the
board
and they can be a you know negative
voltages they could be higher voltages
to drive an LCD year to drive a motor or
something like it forges arbitrarily
hooking up the test points
which sometimes we do we need to make
sure that we're protected that the J
Taylor is protected
that your machine is protected so if you
look up to something
potentially bad or potentially damaging
is not gonna actually damage to
adjustable target voltage lots of
different systems
have different system voltage levels I
so things like the say the desk on bad
that I have here they'll show demo of
that runs on a CR 2032 with revolt
lithium coin cell
so that's a three vote system mobile
phones maybe our
2.6 volts or 1.8 volts made to get even
lower now
I'm so we wanna have some sort of way to
properly communicate probably properly
have the levels that were sending from
the J tell you later
meet the specifications of the target
port because the jet angular system is a
3.3 volt system
that's what the propeller processor runs
on and that's that's what we're using so
we need a way to come to convert that
make sure that we don't damage any
signals going out any
signals coming back at off-the-shelf
components party being hackable
right being able to just get components
from did you hear from what
market or whatever I'm so just where
using very common parts
and then you could hand soldering it's a
two-sided board the current lots are
available online you could
you know fabricator on board somewhere
you can talk to the park someone ummmm
I'll
most in them our service now up
and some of them are pretty fine pitch
but you can do it it's great practice
actually if you wanted
you know if you don't have a a good
project a really learned service not
soldering this to be the one
I built for them by hand I'm never gonna
do it again but
so the practice
I saw going to some details on the
hardware
is just kinda general block diagram and
I'll go through I'm
summer the some the details but we have
a as the core
a propeller parallax propeller processor
which is a really neat and 8-core
processor is a lot for obvious
applications in industrial applications
and
sort of low-volume I very interesting
complex systems
that was a fun one to kinda hackworth in
Para lacks is a a manufacturer of
electronics designer Electronics mostly
hobbyist educational they do a buncha
stuff and and they
they sell a bunch of other products as I
know this is a cool kinda hackable part
let's use it we have USB coming in a
mini USB
up coming in that's going to provide
power to the J tag you later
also serve as the programming interface
to program
the propeller processor so when we do
for more updates and also to serve is
that the actual user interface to us
three terminal program so showbiz a
a virtual serial port EE prom for for
more storage
our level translators which are for the
adjustable target voltage in for
protection circuitry
and on the on the other side we have a
digital analog converter
that we're generating are just about
target voltage from one point to 3.3
boats are going to detail that
but it's been pretty much like that kind
of a basic system
if you look at it is really the that you
know that the CPU
with a bunch of protection on 24
channels
so it's a very kind a generic for that
you can use for all sorts of other stuff
as well
is why I love it two years the board
very pink I figured you know with the
name ID tag you later
gotta have like you know very pink
border kinda offsets the heavy metal
missive the
J tag you later name and I think you're
a pink circuit board
is gonna be a lot harder to lose on your
desk right at the Evergreen Borgata
blends in with everything else
but people stand out the low is built up
on your tool I'm here looks like
we started the side USB coming in at
status indicator up at the top will be
red or green depending on
you know what's going on in the system
are %ah pants are bitches down here
level translators and protection and
hear the probes
are the the interface connections
there's two different ways that you can
connect to it one is gonna be
through the screw terminal blocks at the
top so if you have flying leads are
wires coming in you can just screw down
to the terms on the top the bottom
RT by five row headers that are
compatible with the bus pirate probes
and when I switch the camera show you
I'm closer what they look like was
basically just an off the shelf
a set up roads that have a little
connector on it
with a bunch of test leads on the other
side in the bus pirate is
a I and a hobbyist hacker tool to let
you interface with serial devices and
manipulate serial devices
but and that's another open source tool
but
because that's been around for so long
there's
these cables that are available
everywhere for like five or six bucks
so I figured okay let's use these
because then you can just click down
help like this on to your jacket and you
have a bunch a test clips you can clip
onto a target port
which is kinda cool having two
interfaces as well is useful
I if you want to hook up like a logic
analyzer organised sniff what's going on
at the same time
because then you can connect your
interfere your target on one of them and
then
connect up to the other ones to sniff
seizes Kennedy
something and did some details of the
the actual hardware subsystems
on the propellers I mentioned as an
8-core architecture
very very neat not completely designed
from the ground up so I'm
chip gracie is a guy that started
parallax and he's he's a a hacker in the
true sense of the word
and he was a retired UHV having to deal
with these proprietary chips in
deal with semiconductor manufacturers
that don't give out all the information
sees a cover design my own ship from the
ground up so he you know built his own
registers and CPU and
everything and it ultimately after six
or seven years turned into the
propellers that is a really neat chip
there's lots of information about it
lots a very smart people on the
discussion forum sharing information
there's a a site I'm on the parallax a
cycle the object exchange where people
can write modules and write different
different but programs for the propeller
and upload them
so it's sort of like a if you look it
was like I wanna have LCD controller I
don't have an FM transmitter I want
output composite video
you can go online and look the object
exchanges or to grab objects
objects are basically like header files
are functions grab those are two
integrated into your design so super
cool
so you know in reality gore the object
exchange in look stuff up its okay I
want to add
VGA output to the J tag you later hook
it up to it you know stand-alone
terminal
out stand alone monitor something there
is also the stuff you can do
so I just love the community support
aspect of it
you can code I'm in Spain which is the
proprietor another Friday but a custom
language
on bill specifically for the Jade
the propeller sorta a high-level kind of
like
Pascal CE sort of combination
mashup live stuff little bit of a
learning curve to to figure it out
that's what but the J Taylor is
currently all all written and spin
so it's very it's at least easy to kinda
look through and read comments and
seized up as opposed to assembly
language
which tends to be a little bit harder we
could write in assembly language also
you can write and see their their
paradox is creating a to right now
a cross-platform tool to be alert to
great see
right now everything is done in spin
the the system normally runs eighty
megahertz would seem slow when you
compare to like
you know a linux-based being a red a
mobile phone or something that really a
megahertz for like I did
a stand-alone hobbyist typeof
Meyer jewelers is pretty good is pretty
fast you can actually overclocking 220
makers have pretty good reliability
on the way the system setup is you have
but some global memory which is called
her memory
that shared with all of the at all the
eight Coggs
there's 3008 32k RAM the ROM is actually
a master on which has the bootloader and
character set and some other stuff
specific to the
to that to get the propeller up and
running I'm so code basically
gets loaded from an external EE prom on
power-up and executes
avram in the remaining portion avram
after that is used for the stack
inferred variables and things
shared memory and then each card has its
own 2k avram as well see could have a
cog
but kinda executing its own stuff in
using its own memory than maybe once in
a while dumping things to the main
memory if you want to know if you need
some other
on taxes it I for for the day together
we don't really have a lot of
complex stuff going on with college but
there is lotsa capability there
up 32 I opens at forty million amps I'm
sink or source current
for Penn in 10 things I want to do and I
was designed as tools like find a
processor that I could use
that had lotsa pins but also had an easy
way to program it and didn't need like
this
you know that weird a large development
environment all the stuff that China
find that balance
but 32 pins reason 24 those pens for i/o
and other
other stuff for using for that you know
and like visual ordeal analog converter
and stuff
so it sort of goes its it's a pretty
good number
you know is you know design a similar
for Jagya later with an FPGA with you
know 128 pins or something
so you could potentially get larger I
over I think 24 sort of a good
a good number for now anyway
so senator ehlmann is done as a tool
called the propeller tool which actually
is
it is in the in a black cat materials on
a DVD
so if you are low that up in kinda play
with it let the source code in you you
can
I'm right now that is Windows only us I
mention that they are doing
cross-platform
version for for CR for C but they're
also
creating cross-platform to let let you
right spin on up things other than
Windows
but for now it's a windows-based
every program the device through that
same interface that were using as the as
a user interface and that's me I just
one connector and we don't need to do a
lot of stuff if we wanna
one program is again never the intent is
to get non hardware people involved in
the stuff that has to be easy
is a block diagram of that up the core
from a circuit point-of-view there's
really not much there we just have the
main part
50 lost external oscillator and their
the
loading capacitors actually internal to
the propeller so just one less thing to
have to deal with
or two less things they have to deal
with the normally need to capacitor so
to Thursday's things you can just throw
on to a five megahertz personal and be
good to go
and there's not much else just some just
that the Sree prop
has a very simple to get up and running
for the USB interface assertive serves
multi-purpose but I love
it powers a device and then let this
program and serves as your interface
I'm using FTIR FTDI ft 232
device which is a standard USB to serial
interface so when we we can send TTL
level cereal from the Jade Jagger later
0 to 3 vote signals
this FTDI parts and convert that into
proper signals and also show up as a
but US USB virtual comp or on your
machine
to work with you know with Mac PC Linux
whatever Windows whatever what everyone
anything that supports
I USB virtual servers virtual com ports
and it under different drivers on the
FTDI website %uh anything that supports
for cio.com poor you'll be other users
this thing with possibly even
maybe Raspberry Pi at some point out um
part of the third party USB interface I
wanted to make sure that we did properly
was have a power distributions which
oftentimes you'll see products that just
have a USB connector going straight
from the board directly but to the
target computer if you look on the
actual
a inside the the board that power is
shared between two red is USB provides
power
but you're supposed to actually have
kinda proper enumeration process to make
sure that you don't
but potentially try to this try to sort
to sink too much current from the target
and make sure that the that the computer
properly knows that you're probably knew
rated it knows what kinda current You're
Expecting
before provided to you so as part of the
USB spec you actually need to come to
power up
properly in a numerate properly when you
plug your device into a computer
most things out there very cheap devices
don't do that
so technically they're not USB compliant
I but I wanted to at least have a way
that if there is some problem with the J
tag later we had hooked up to some board
that was just
causing it to like suck so much turnout
have a device
that would fail properly and it would
kinda disconnect itself from the system
they're using nm I see a micro I see
2025 a power distribution switch
which basically what we're doing is
disconnecting
most have this utmost to the circuit
from the system
and when you plug in the tag you later
only the FTI part
it's powered up so it the new numeration
happens properly
with the target and then once the new
rated and the
the the FTDI parts as I need five
hundred millions
then the that target the PC will give
you that curator at least allow that
about a current to be
to be a to be drawn and then it will
enable the the rest the system
so here we basically can see like the
USB is only plugin
the USB that's it that's the 50 lineup
USB
were only powering FTDI part and then
once everything's good
12 pins on the FTI part says okay we're
all a new rated lets an able to wrestle
owed
and then we enable Asia a low dropout
linear regulator
to enable the 530 to the Bible line will
then go and feed the rest the detailer
system so it's just a good thing to do
with proper kind of power
sick you know is pretty good certainty
that when you play this thing into a
into your computer stock at
blow up hopefully
okay so the adjustable target voltage
this is just a way I can sorta some way
you know to create this adjustable
voltage that we can connect to different
targets
I'm so I'm using the post with modulated
signal PWM on
on 1 I'll line are one output line up
the propeller
and basically the duty cycle over the
PWM
corresponds to the output voltage and I
have is a lookup table
with different duty cycles that I've
measured out I
measure the kinda resulting voltage and
now we have .1
vol increments from one point to 3.3
volt spending on target for the
in the way it works I have a an op-amp
basically RC
filter going through a buffer
to provide the voltage and we really
don't even really need the buffer
but that's going to provide us a little
bit of isolation and also give us
additional
output current is this this %ah that op
amp in
write home about 150 billions about
would try it
so it sorta accesses amplifier for us
where now we have a voltage
but we can also source someone on a
current case you want to use
this be a DJ line he just what target
voltage line maybe two
control the target on the target our
control another piece a circuit your
something gives it'll just a little bit
more about
pits you know kinda future expandability
by having this buffering here it's just
safer that way to
I'm so this is a single supply standard
of it
for level translation this again allow
the 3.3 volt signals from the propeller
up to be converted to whatever are just
will target voltages
we have the txts 0108 you which is a
very common by directional
level translator still takin 3.3 and
then I'll put it
at whatever voted for putting in on the
on the other side
the show you the schematic that I the
cool thing about this part is has
it has a high impedance outputs so we
can use the output enable line
to essentially keep all of the
I O pins that might be connected to a
target board high impedance which
essentially disconnected from the
from the system are from those
connections until we're ready
just RJ tabulating that way you know as
we're plugging things
in were not hopefully not gonna screw
stuff up because the system doesn't
really the target doesn't really know
that there there yet
until we enable the output enable and
then those pens go higher low
79 pins is really kinda a useful feature
and there's not much to it pins coming
in
in going out
for it but protection we have %uh trent
let me resistors and I unclamps
to prevent over current and overvoltage
love test points on the target port
because we don't know what we're gonna
connect to do we need to protect
ourselves there
to an extent there you know there is a
range above some voltage
up that things will get damage but
it's still gonna protect us a lot I'm so
we have is our
from from each target on each channel
resistor coming in and then to a
resistor gone
are a diode going higher and I don't low
so they're called I would clamps
what those do are basically clamping
in voltage to a fixed level which in EB
I a positive it's going to be the
therefore go to the diode
plus whatever the adjustable target
voltage is that points1 point2 3.3 volt
and then for the negative side it's just
gonna be the negative um
forward forward a bodies are the diodes
the Dow dropped
and that was that we use our Schottky
diodes said you need 24 we need forty
eight of them
2 per line having individual discrete
diodes are just sorta be a pain
especially if you wanna
you know hand assemble these things so I
found these diode arrays which are sorta
cool
they're actually designed for for diode
clapping and free St protection
I where each I O line has
its own diode going in. on owned I don't
look so now we only need
I there's four channels per chip so we
only need six of them
that's slightly better
that's pretty much all the hardware for
the bill materials there's mostly
discrete components and resistors and
stuff
the total cost is around 50 bucks US
if you want to buy one no single single
quantity fifty dollars the more you buy
the cheaper parts are
I'm here this bill materials is from
digikey which is a up
fairly large parts distributor worldwide
I'm in the folio PDF is on my website a
few
if you want to see it better
so from a firm or side currently this is
kinda source tree that we have
G tabulate about spin is the mains bin
file that handles all that the initial
state machine a setup and everything
and I tried to I want to keep things
modular size I add new
I functionality our new protocols I have
that as an
as a separate spin file they have the
pair like serial terminal which is a I'm
1ad fall spin files to enable user
interface to enable a serial
serial interface for users I'm using
that for the user interface
real random is a %uh see a random number
generator based on some PLL
I'm jitter the CPU that we use for
bypass can test
which I'll show you and probs a tag is
on the low level J Tiger face tough
in NJ de Kock serial is a low-level
additional serial port I'm using for the
York detection
so it sort of your eyes you add more
stuff there may be a tree gets gets
wider anything but
I'm and house pretty simple you can
think I've like these other spin files
is kinda extra
header files or something even though
they're the other the x-axis the files I
guess
there's still plenty of space left on
this thing even with all of my horribly
um probably bloated and not very a
not very efficient code we're still only
using
1800 longs 32-bit
value so we have we still have quite a
bit of space available
so all the blue lotsa lotsa space for
excess stuff later
I guess we're actually we're going to
take a break now I think it's gonna be a
good time
we'll take a break now until 10:15 come
back and look at the actual details on
chip debugging faces a Jay tagging you
are
I mean we opened up you know do the
demos and I love that