the talk I mean it today is covering a
building it's really a look at
access control facility management
systems so hopefully come away with this
thanks to black out for happy hour hurts
me experience
I and hopefully a you get alerts near so
a little bit about me that my hand on
Twitter sure to follow me
I'm if you go to Twitter look at my bio
to dramatic asking is all smuggler kinda
an old story we can talk about the bar
but that is really me I'm currently
director horribly research and write a
Logitech Wallace
I had a startup that this crisp on a
cost per point does acquired by another
company got silence
I worked at Google previously as a tech
lead for Google's occasion called what's
a really good experience there web stats
for web or other product security
so preemie I was also really singer for
Google+
I worked at Microsoft as well as a
security program manager for Internet
Explorer
its at piece of turbine her but I'll
said it's really singer for online
services
pretty neat stuff I have a couple
degrees I think it really matters here
post couple books actually this case
here
Cooper I'm but I think most importantly
they look into initial control systems
over the last couple years and we have
about
it says thirty publicly true accredited
you know I sister advisers I think it's
a bit more
and I still think I did this with a
colleague of mine
I still think we are like the top your
group to have the most
I sister advisories if that means
anything to anyone so we work with a lot
different vendors
we report over 1000 officious DHS mostly
involving decir control system so
some of them will probably never be
fixed if you find it
interesting time to buy presents and as
the stars so what
i wanna talk to you about facility
manager controls
in-building essentially and so why you
is one answer some Why What Lies sporty
so we actually know that buildings are
being attacked so
if you look at this I see a certain
thing monitor from last year it was the
January to March might be monitored
there's a link up their critical get
herself
we know that publicly acknowledged
there's two buildings our attacked
the energy management systems are attack
so one was a
a state facility I don't know where it
was but
bass guitar asleep or just ate so state
agency of some kind
the other one was a manufacturing plant
in New Jersey so
in when you think about these these
incidents so
the way that I think about it is most
the damage a tumor probably do via
energy management system or facility
management system
if I go unnoticed in fact if something
changes or something breaks
the prices car technician in the
technician probably just change whatever
broke
so in order for someone to be called in
specific leader for DHS to be called in
to investigate something
espy pretty significant so arm if your
air conditioner goes out even if it's a
very sensitive
facility like a hospital or surgical
center I'm
you might be able to picture pretty
quick right but to have some kind of
affect where
it's so bad that you want to reach out
to some place like ths
I'm that's probably really that right so
the details of what happened here
they're not revealed but I just kind it
you know report some threads here
try to figure out what happened your to
the end organization
I'm it's hard to say and the reason
that's hard to say it's because
each building management system is the
same
but the buildings that they manage are
all different right so
I'm pretty much everything going to run
into you the way that are configured in
a way that the building management
system runs the building
whether it's Energy Manager access
control or just environmental control
usually it's done differently from even
the building that's gonna be next door
so it's something that's very important
to understand
so the more you understand about the
various pieces which kinda stay the same
the better but when you actually take
over a building the facility magistrate
energy management system
pretty much every time you do it's going
to be different right so
what is a facility management system
they're very invisible
if your fortune what if your fortune
1000 if you have a corporate campus
if you have a badge reader on the door
that you going to for work
you actually have personally met system
demanded system building automation
system whatever you wanna call it we
actually have those
and the building this officially that
were right now has tons
officially measured systems it so
include things like art accessed it's
not magic
you know a lot of times what happens is
the low battery on the door
it doesn't make a decision by itself
what it does is just collect data and
this be sent off to a pinch or someplace
and the controller actually forgot
someplace else whether to a database
lookup urs other sort some other type a
lookup
basically does a logic an application
server and sends data back saying
you should democracy not a mark or do
something else so same thing with video
right so
every modern facility has surveillance
I'm a lot of times it's gonna be at
what's
gonna be allowed is to serve the people
doing the surveillance
can probably pan the camera zoom in zoom
out take a look at these switch cameras
I'm you're back in the day this used to
be closer to but always move to IP now
spree interesting water its manager HTTP
I'm intrusion
so Wes intrusion nothing about likes nor
like that
doing about like if someone breaks a
window or kicks in the door
befits a if it's a modern facility alarm
is going to go off it's all gonna get
notified
the way that they do that as your
sensors when the sensors detect that
when there's been broken records been
kicked in
what she said the signal someplace AAA
something bad just happened
she there trigger alarm asylum /url or
real or contact security make a phone
call
I'm is also different things that can
happen so these are physical intrusion
devices
I'm elevators re badge into an elevator
with your with your room key and take a
need to go to the
94 whatever I'm there's actually
computer on the back and it's making
that decision saying a
should this person be allowed to get off
on that for not right sir
on edge back we're gonna cover some
these examples here for a check
specifically
this is probably the most common
facility management system that we see
in general
and the reason this is probably one of
the most common facility management
systems that we see
is not because it's cool it's because
it's very cost-effective
so when businesses do you h-back the a
building management system they're doing
it because it's cost-effective
they're gonna save money I know a given
example how they save money
so we look at a datacenter here a couple
years ago
officially if you have a data center its
gonna have building automation systems
the environmental controls for the data
center can be controlled by computers
there's a facility management systems as
ur building automation systems building
management systems
and what this particular data center was
doing was it was basically monitoring
the prices of energy so if they were
cheaper to run on fuel
it which which all the energy to fuel it
or cheaper to run off the grid its
it switched to the grid it was cheaper
to pull in cold air from the outside as
opposed to just generating cold air
via air conditioners it would do that
and so what it was doing as
understanding what's the cheapest way to
basically call the state senator they
constantly readjusting all the time
and it resulted in a tremendous cost
savings for the organization install the
systems
and that's why they did they didn't do
it cuz it was cool they did it cuz it
into the day they know that their save
money
that's why a lot of buildings happily
managed systems in them especially
things for environmental control
same up lighting becoming more and more
common
to control lighting I yet you know like
building management system
it's the same reason just for
cost-effectiveness energy energy savings
cost savings
so and you can actually really cool
thing so if you live in a building
and you sure the building with a lot of
other folks you get into electricity
bill
it's probably done by I don't imagine
system the bill imagine system
understands what your electricity usage
is
up for a given point in time and then
basically sensual bill for that
particular
use it right so it's pretty cool very
interesting stuff
so or start to see that's pretty recent
consolidation all these different
systems
so if you look at the systems in the
past there they've all been these
different silat systems are basically
never talk to each other
or action star to see now is they're all
certificates all it together
a good example of something that's
already consolidated gather in a very
meaningful way
are fire alarm systems we're taking a
look at number up differ fire learning
system so
if a fire alarm goes off in like a
facility like this its gonna trigger
a budget different events so the fire
learning system is probably gonna go to
fire fire department someplace and say
hey look
based on the sensors that I have in the
facility I think the fires a spigot on
this floor
it's this type of fire fire weather
chemical or wood or whatever
I was going to notify those people there
but also do really interesting things
like
maybe it'll turn up to a track systems
for that pic particular for
so the smoke will get put into the Ducks
things like that maybe altar of certain
electrical systems
maybe it'll disable the elevator source
are to see that these a billing and
assistance for sure start to be
consolidated
all start to talk to each other and the
bass kick you control each other which
is actually interesting
on ever talk about a couple different
culture and the reason I think this once
there's just a budget and more
orders but there is I think these ones
are interesting it's called I call this
device passer
retrieval for Billy resenting says
interesting is
all doing that it is is there a look
that houses were built for some reason
where you can actually just touch the
the billing agent system remotely
and pulled passer toute so I don't know
if it's like one person basically
working all these billion pension
systems
or purchase some weird thing are
designed the way these folks are taught
but I
we we've come across a couple couple
different ones so the issue building
management systems are presented here to
Niagara framework and missus
probably to the most popular going
medicines in the world
so-and-so for the Niagara basically an
authenticated user can retrieve the
device passer
that's just an story device password
action code it's not a crypt it's not
hasher thing like that
I'm if you know how they encourage a
candy cane we know how to record it so
we can deter the passwords
I know what you did to the passage you
have a clear text password and login any
with any account that you want are you
most likely want to add
login with the administrator account and
so whatever
system that building manager system is
running on it can run on three different
a platform to run on Windows it can run
on QNX
a run on Lex right so if you get it on
Windows box of system
to get on at your next box or we expect
to get ripped so because the framework
is running as root
and that's pretty cool is gay rutan
underlying device
rights of that device is connected to
something be another ticket a protocol
or clear text for a call like
back network my bus whatever it's
connected to ever network it's on
you'll be able to talk to those devices
well I'm if it so if it's a Windows
machine censure system
you'll be able to extract any kind a
credit of their so admin login to there
are two main actors
like that to be able to get it passed of
its
a same with the Medicis device
authenticated user Kercher the device
password
in this case the password actually
hashed shot one are
but you can also do not indicate a
battery separator user so
if for some reason one other users like
the admin user has released out password
you can just pass receptor and the
market with a password that you want
right so
essentially its authentication all such
a depth of Education bypass but there
are other bugs that just allow you to do
what occasion bypasses
call various things to interact with the
device maker do things
and then there's also wat you are
compromised underlying system
which is always interesting because the
frameworks are really good
in fact there developed to allow
engineers and operators
to easily manage devices that are
connected to you right because you don't
want
engineers have to write my buser back at
every single time they want you
adjust the temperature point for an HX
system so you wanna make it very easy
for them
you want them to do literally click a
button and type in a your
temperature and have that AST that
temperature point set to you in a check
system
so if you can compromise underlying
you don't have to worry about a the
researchers at the framework put it
so if the framework has some paper
research that says hey I don't like you
I don't like it when he said not now for
my buser back into that particular
device
I don't want to allow that if you
compromise underlying system you can
just do it yourself you can use to
everyone
right so compromiser the underlying
system is always interesting when it
comes to you
devices like this and then of course
upper lateral escalation for you know
lateral escalation reasons
a compromise that alexis is always so
on this is the tree in Niagara framework
it up on this device is what they look
like
unit second industrial boxes text your
box reply find a closet someplace
on this a Johnson patrol missus so
controller I'm if I find this a closet
someplace as well
this is not something that you would see
like mounted onto the wall in your hotel
room
this actually control or so the you know
that thermostat and the
environmental controls in your room
would actually get to this device in
place across
or so the first to get real talk about
is physical security because much like
regular computers get physical access to
one of these devices a controller's
game over that's by design every single
a vendor every single person
acknowledge that that's why they always
recommend that you like these things up
and don't allow anyone to physical
access to it right so
a lot times of consular access work you
can get to it you can either plugin
usually via serial Rs 232 yards for 85
notice have a shell is actually on the
device these are very pretty or
so up the technician services passwords
and was always work on your physical
access
ice so if you know technische your
search credential should be able to log
interest by Spurs
and then most importantly is wherever
network it's connected to pick up the
slack just to it
you have access at never network as well
turn the reason that important
is because you have access to things
like back net the building
you know billing automation control work
it's an authenticator protocol it's
clear text
I'm so basically device are just sitting
listening on this network back net
are and if you get on to that network
somehow you'll be able to talk to all
the devices on the network
that's just the way it's designed so I'm
and the cool thing about that is
a good friend of mine Michael toker
he actually wrote a script to enumerate
BACnet devices
and you put into an app so you can go to
digital ones website
and you can actually download this this
and that's and that script
its intended to be run on internal
network but nothing is stopping anyone
from running it on the internet
rates are in fact if you do run on the
internet you actually find active
devices
listening on the internet so this
particular one is Abiomed
boiler system so R and as you can see
with industrial control systems they
what oftentimes
they like to give up a lot of
information about what they are so
on the way that this the way that this
enumeration actually works is pretty
clever
on what might basically did here was on
there's a way to korea system
where it's in the spec where the device
will actually respond with an air
right so if you see the error message
you know that that's actually BACnet
enabled device
and then what you know that's a back to
enable device you can actually create
for information
this so this is the end map plug or the
and map
script thats that's their so anyone can
download listen to actually start
rates on your internal network to find
out where your back devices are
very interesting stuff so the physical
access peace
it's extremely important right because
once you have access to the back net
the building automation control network
you'll be able to talk to a device on
the network
so on and having physical control over
public building
really hard right very very heart so
take this device here for example too
hard to see sexually terms that
in on the bottom it's got a a rj-45 Jack
so its it's not like a network jack is
actually with Jack to basically jack
into the back net
but I am this device actually by a
better picture
yet to say when or this device was right
at this picture at
was at no I was not here
now share this was taken at a.m.
when airport so hundreds of these
their SATs everywhere right and if you
plug into one of them
get on back you talk to any device it's
on the airport back
so pretty interesting sir about this one
when you work on this one
this was really dirty like this is the
dirtiest air saw that I took picture
has preached so there's hundreds of
these
hundreds of them this is at Cedar to
assess really dirty
so same thing I'm rj-45 jack on the
bottom
you plug into that in your own back net
this action its Alexia
work so if you're a public facility
and you have things like this tell you
right now almost impossible to keep some
of the building our mission
work Shia if you have access ports like
this persons
target so
to more about the water bill is so the
Niagara framework
we report a couple different water
release them and said hey you really
need sixties
and so they did so some the water bill
is that we came across the
passer she will even the way that they
store their passers included way that
they had to be called in crash in
they actually fix that now the hasher
passwords and the result was pretty cool
so
I'm just I'm gonna show a couple side
sure about that in about the
vulnerabilities but the actual download
the latest patch
as or believes or game or so that's
pretty neat
missus on the other hand we contacted
them in November
we always contact people to GHS right so
we have a third party that can track it
say
this is what I notified us forever so
that was April 22nd
and we never heard back I actually until
last week like a what he is a doctor
next week
or maybe your device so if we look
deeper into Medicis
which is what we're gonna County dive
into today the device that we have
actually run twenty so that's actually
really really interesting because
a lot at all that we have this criticism
or anything that we haven't you
previously
right so in fact we little either poor
watched your walls and to you
IDA Pro to say these are x86 excuse such
pretty cool
and then some other files actually done
that in some ways we're looking at a
diner some Richard
so if we look at the file systems if you
get when these devices get access to
a device I'm or you have some kind of
exploit or or you actually own advice
I'm we look at the actual way it works
is America vice so there's a flash on
their
side right kick it like secord that it
just says slash right to go to slash
missus
for all the audit logging configuration
files are right so it's pretty important
there there's also another directory
called missus I secure DB
security to acknowledge that that's a
file who's basically contains all these
searches vice x-mas I'll they are hashed
right shot one
so there's an account on Medicis devices
on their resume an assist device called
missus agent
that is the Medicis system agent that is
user ID 1
that is essentially the at been for
missus devices
that's the user account name and so when
you look at the security deduction of
I'll
this is what you'll see so you'll see
the user ID 1 if she table users
user ID 1 are you'll see a lot of
interesting things like for example
but there is no account lockout for this
this account rikers admin
and this account essentially nevers
never expires so
pretty a campy it's not safe obviously
by default as well
so I guess you could maybe changes
I don't know what I would do if you
disable the sys admin account nurture
cessation account literature so
most obvious things the version of Win
CE that
is running on the message device
actually has a shell work you just tell
that to it
election drop into a shower system
rights go
I'm if you're actually looking for these
on the internal network that's probably
the easiest way to own one of these
devices
right they also usually have another
decade have to pee open as well
so you can FTP into it grab the the the
security be direction of I'll
all passwords crackle passer ever so
pretty interesting but
I don't do that as yet the telnet which
gives you showing its
pretty for I don't know made that
decision right but like
is this what needs to happen like no
more for you right no war
so I'm a little bit more about the
filesystem there slash storage
that can check their content about to
crash dumps I it contains much memory
does as well so
it to my server crashes for any reason
that's where those files can be held
and those that are pretty interesting
such maybe for a transaction like that
see why a particular device crashed
you know what caused it so store just
missus such preferences
that a user system preferences are
stored very interesting
and there's another directory storage
missus secure GB as a copy of the
security direction of I'll
I'm if you don't want to use the action
of I'll you can actually use real
database file
I it's called its SDF file: which is
basically like a compact compact file
format
you can connect to it yeah just regular
data Shriver this week for its
it's basically the same thing as a
security XML got these names and
passwords or configurations
users so I'm but what's important to me
is
the thing that's probably gonna be
facing if someone tries to lock down the
shell
and FTP is the web interface because
that's how
engineers operators actually manages the
vices whether
face so if you look at storage missus
dubbed up a router
such missus xxx the excess axes are
actually versions
that's where the application logic for
the weather faces so very interesting to
me
the Webroot actually contains like 50
jars and if you actually connect to the
web interface
those jars will get download it to your
local system I'm it
Medicis does history and as I don't know
why they do this but and a pretty like
if they get some translations of a like
a hundred jars on your local filesystem
so not not it's on a server but to also
get pushed her client
so which is pretty crazy and then so if
we look at a
slash WS there's actually web service
could there that's pretty cool
I'm it so if we look at how the
application logic is implemented
if we look at slash WS which is for web
server such been
we actually see precompiled dotnet
assemblies there so they don't just have
like aspx files we can just read source
right but I'm anyone that knows dotnet
nose at
its you know I also its is later like
best the river straight safety
get the source code if you have the
buyers get the dll's not sure
engineers Minister but so soon as you
get the deal allows you can basically at
the source code for all the deals
and reversing a buyer's actual to preach
the box
so we look at the dot that assemblies we
see things that will
retrieve directory listing from the
device which is pretty cool
I'm upload art refile sartre locations
which is really need
there's also web services churchy
retrieve user information clearing the
path for cash
right because retrieving a password hash
is a
really highly requested feature a super
popular rights every time I should have
some web service to retrieve the user's
password hash
and so if we take a look at what's ur so
common that DLL
on this is what we see in doubt that
reflector right so there's a budget for
a class in here how in this important to
me right now is
dot security its ok we take a look at
that security
it has a budget different a method that
we can call one which is
administration service and if we look at
you know a lot of things are stored in
there we see
basically it like a a method called get
your property which takes an int
which is used right so this is pretty
valuable since we know that that missus
sis agent is always use right he won
that's pretty cool
if we look at the description it always
returns a property for single-user
stored in the database whether that's
the ex not follow the actual Davis
pretty interesting stuff so if we look
at it differently lol subsys is a common
that lol
we see there also has a dot security as
well and if we did a little bit deeper
in there and subsystems the comment that
the lol
we see a function call prince will store
Ryan this is basically
where user's password and user
permissions getting written in retreat
from the device
so I'm nevermind the into computer user
and the Medicis agent
default password don't worry about that
for now appreciate for
but I'm the prince will start pretty
interesting the text is riding a login
name
and every look at how that thing
actually works said she describes all
the information about a particular user
just puttin object itself what service
ever calls it will just return
this giant blob data which is really
interesting rights efforts will start at
your property
and so the way that we would actually
call this webservice
it just by going to the security slash
Admin service I S
ASMX webservice I just doing a simple
push requests like
like it like any good web service and
just say I'm I want to use get your
property
and give the User ID 1 and it'll give
you a response like this rate the most
important thing is likely the user name
but of course the password hash for the
device for that particular user
record so
so running a web service to achieve a
user
Pasir Ris 3 dad but its
worse if you just forget to do one thing
they were know if that one thing is
you forget to put the Websters behind
authentication right so
the web searches built authenticated
users the anyone can retrieve the
password hash for any user on the device
right and so like Wow and so on last
week when you're like a we just were
interested
when missus actually contact me and
they're like a we're going to talk next
week
sorry we haven't talked in the last
three months but I we're just kinda
interested in how you would fix its
portability
like we know how we would fixes words
can imagine what your thoughts are
I was like well first occupied on
leadership people's passwords
second of each plaque put this behind
authentication right so
you know a song I was like wow you know
whoever wrote that web searches
had one job right click 8
yet one job yet one operate your this
web service
you forgot to put it behind
authentication you had one job like and
spree that so that's pretty cool though
so when you get a username and password
you log into device this is what you'll
see
and so this is interesting cuz I was
your show people this because a lot of
times people are very intimidated by
things like building
measured systems officially imagine
systems I think it's just weird thing
you know where you drop it and it's like
totally you know you can't cover and
what's going on
that it's the furthest thing from the
truth in fact when you walk into a bill
modern building and a system you're
gonna see something like this
right its very user friendly it's really
just a web interface for you to say look
I want to push this button reset this
set point for this particular device or
do whatever it is so
if you drop down to the underlying
device you want to communicate to a
device in a way that's not
intended to be communicated to you is
still a bit more complicated reaction
after senator because of her stuff but
for the most part you want to attach a
building you log into the billing engine
system
you set the point click so its first
report
so were talking about how prevalent is
building manager systems are on the
Internet right kisses
action you in part by most part par or
talk I'm we basically create this
numeration effort to find as many
Billing Manager two sons
on the Internet as we could so initially
base of showed an
we need to have some custom scares me
said you right so
which I like fifty thousand buildings
most of them are explosive experts
internet or that their choice later at
well throughout dated right so which run
experts again Sam is critical to
billings
any with everyone so stay and hospitals
police stations prisons will
translations
like everything you can imagine in fact
I am I brought with me
a Excel spreadsheet aceptar I found on
the internet we can just if you watch
others
let you guys say hey or search for
police station and I just like their
control if we can find
stations so all total plight of either a
box
to buy the devices from a yday
and 10 for the easy to time right so not
too expensive
okay so aren't they were actually really
prevalent on the Internet
right so well show you here some stuff
that we've done
okay so this is my worst upstart
right so or over to the top
and so we a researcher
I I'm actually look at 704 so
up there's like some health agencies I
found I'm
this spreadsheet I have actually it
doesn't have the location
I'm I could easily do it but I am and
usually when I start when should I do
publications last by the best place
espy the best way to find stuff but this
just has names right so
which other peacekeeping names we can
find things
with certain names so about like bank
right let's pick up
so there's one right there they're all
right there
it's a there's a right there okay so but
the banks right so
those are not names I pics those are
those are station name so the devices
add these names inside right now sorry I
we got we got the station in turn second
so
anything else
school the pedestrian
I don't know school there's up oil our
schools
schools are very popular your
firms fence
I don't see any defense there
okay thank God
that kid hospital skits
some hospitals impossible's when I say
Fox
it's basically a protocol that I'm using
Johnson is basically I'm
the integrator sigh I just kinda tag is
I think they're interesting
so let me show you how I got this data
it's free it's pretty straightforward
so have some tools I'm basically
I really simple script I just get IP
addresses for things I think or build
imagine systems
or you can just scan the entire internet
like all you never
ipv4 space you can just say run this
python script right and so
it'll just take that list I P is it just
looks up basically
like you know the back that thing that
we saw there's another protocol called
boxer certain
a particular bill imagine systems a
discrete that services is a consolidated
you have about you
and so what you basically get is
something that's returned like this
so at the top is basically what we call
the station name so
it says Fox that's just attacked for me
but DSC
underscore WS I'm not really sure what
that is
but others are like a whole bunch of
information right so for example
the things running on Windows XP rights
that's pretty interesting it also tells
me the exact version
that this particular billing and dismiss
right as well so which is extremely
helpful
have a budget for next week's I know
which ex which will work
and tell me what time zone it's an it
also tells me what the license ideas for
particular device right so I have
another tool
where I can take a licence ID its work
so this is a license right here
so I have another to or can't say a
given a particular license
I want to look up what's basically
enabled for that particular license rate
so
the section of I'll are is the actual
license that the customer purchase
and the cool thing about this licenses
it tells you all the features
that their authorized to run and so if I
find a particular component work I'm
looking for something
in particular I can basically look at
the license files and understand what it
is I want to go after so for example
um like a like an RE drivers Ryan re:
drivers may only be used for certain
things like what's a
power meter for example I just one look
at power meters
I can just a cameo licenses that and
re-enable
and then you can just start from there
pretty cool stuff and then at the bottom
is basically
I'm a different up differ way parsing
the data and so we didn't know at DSC
was
but now we do because we know that the
project for this device actually doctor
surgery center
so we just enumerated going then justice
in for surgery center rights
it's not good is not get whenever you
tell you that that is not good
so a pretty interesting stuff right so
the good thing is
I was assured a Python script at once a
look if you want to rate the stuff
here's python script but then everyone
to be running the psych
skin across internet refineries
buildings and stuff
and so instead what we do is we just I
just talked to the guys showed an shyt I
just do this
that way no one else s and so take a
look at this and
this is basically how your career it's
the same information here right and
there's
15,000 367 buildings that can be
identified with just this method
rights are not everybody medicine has
this particular method enabled
so as you can see there are a lot of
buildings online so
the top on the risk up on it but what I
want whatever one actually show you
here's I'm
this is actually more interesting to me
here so let's take a look at this I know
it's kinda hard to see
but if we take a look at this particular
one the station ID
is Norstar financial right so
guessing that's kinda bank right on
what's it look at the one below as well
so
this is a good one to you I'm which all
diamond right so that's pretty
interesting
and then we take a look at this one here
pure eighty
admin right so but could be right if
things
this one here is vine 500 so
but the reason I i want to point out is
because if we look at where these
eyepiece for I'm with not forget the G
locations for second but
we look at where these IP's are there
are not an organizational IP space
it's actually an ISP IP address space so
this one is Cox medication
this is Norstar financial so it's not
endorsed or financial IP blocks
right and if we look at a hotel diamond
its in AT&T Internet services IP address
space
so it's not in hotel diamond IP address
space right
this is really important so if we look
at on pure
eighty admin it's not in pure eighty
admins IP space
it's in AT&T answers space and the
reason that
this is the case is because when you buy
a building management system
you don't have your employees install
the bill imagine system for you
you always hire third-party contractor
that guys in hard hats coming and it's
not for you
right and those folks are known as
integrators and so what the interpreters
will do is they'll take down your
requirements are
for a place like this to say hey look I
want to be cool in every single room at
what temperature variance be this is
this
and I want to build a turn-on and
turn-off all the aces for all the
solution one centralized location
and integrators I can do that and they
pick out the particular device is that
they want to install
probably want to do that we showed you
here maybe some very know that
and they'll install into the building
right and then what they'll do is
sending someone out to building to this
could you maintenance
is actually really expensive so they
like to do is take cable modem
or DSL line walk into the closet relying
to it and hope their bill demanded
system up
to the DSL line that's why we see so
many building management systems
in commercial I P ISP's IP spaces
so in fact I'm if you're looking for
your own building management systems
online
is probably not in your IP block only
place I really see them
in in in a organizational IP blocker
schools
like the stuff on here this is
California State University network
so university is for some reason the
other billy madison's their IP blocks
for everything else it's usually in a
commercial ISP space
place so if you're looking for the
system's scan your IP block is probably
not the way to go
instead what you need to do is basically
scan the internet and look for other
meditative that associate that could be
your system
right sir let's see if there's a
sheer prequel stuff
so what's up on your I can go showed an
down
it's a running Python script you can
actually look up stuff as well so in
um it can be on ipv6
yep it supports ipv6 ID report which
were common
so I'm just kinda blah run-through of
the export so
there's a budget for Barnardo's work and
pull down various configuration files
this was actually patched
this is what the configuration file for
tritium system looks like
so we can pull this thing down. they're
just section here that has
used as a passwords passwords and coated
with its getting kinda password
I'm if we know how the pastor Tim Curry
begins to code it so this password just
happens to be decoded to anyone's guess
so pretty interesting I'm I out again
early sis wanna know how productive it
is but you can find these things
I it's virtually all too right yourself
it's patched and so
something more interesting choices that
we've seen a like at doing that its
systems
really cool right like this right here
is a jacket
writer the user interface actually
really into it and on how you use it
so something like that also Precor
weather system
cool as pilot their Gables residential
tower
like me and you stick with boeing's
recall of galaxy
so really have the screenshot here is
once again
we're talking about how all these
billing agent systems are kinda
consolidating
so we take a look at this particular
facility manager to some
we see a bunch of different things that
right so she said emergency his loss
after temperatures
all sandwiches security systems so this
is an instance where the security
systems actually tied into the facility
magic system
right it's pretty neat so now we know
that if we're able to actually
compromise underlying device
we can actually talk to security systems
if you want you what the security
systems are not sure but
pretty interesting stuff so this one's
really cause well there's a 100 CPP is
open charging protocol
right so this is like a electric
charging stance in place
so that's pretty and then a I guess
those white less right there that's like
badges
people who care got charging station
actions Jersey
so pretty cool stuff I'm we found this
one
a little while ago as very surprised is
a bill to the internet with no
authentication we actually have a list
a building's other about 2,000 that we
know up
where if you can just get the IP address
you're actually
on the billing engine system so this
jack
this is one that we found are sprinter
say
writer like wow 3 cool so yeah right
that's pretty cool
on were like why they set this up that
I'm back here this is the moment
controls
like all the different sections they
have for the arena basically the same
I'm in a bit of it and I think you're
probably most important pieces would be
like equipment room where the
temperature série
like highly regulated maybe I don't know
but this is
Primeau report is a breaker status so
when you look at PR five direction of
the Breakers
other owner of any given moment right so
this is Tasha breakers
she so there's a process right there so
there's some
there some ups is other apps 1up's to on
there some other things pr5
there's there's like 10 it is pure want
to keep your tent so
what's different things and then using
the tool that we had we can identify
exactly who install this thing
LA installations we contacted them on
the phone we said hey dude you should
probably take this thing off line
at the station in which is important to
guess context because this with in a
commercialize P space right so we don't
know
like station names are things like that
P it's kinda hard to tell who they think
belongs to you or
what facilities being used to run and
then of course we have the times in
which helps confirm like cats is
probably actually for real
I later we found out that he was real
and their the reason this device
actually put in place is cuz im pic
broadcasting
folks need to imagine system to be
comfortable water during
broadcasting so they took it offline
pretty quickly so
pretty interesting stuff running Windows
7 so
I'm was take a look at some other billy
madison's iron it so
idols about 2,000 not assure all 2000
everyone
but if you look hard enough you'll find
urself so but what's your weekend
you can find her a VM here setup I
wouldn't take a look at
you know what it's like to basically
interact with the bill imagine system so
if you were to run an exploit make
password retrieval
basically pour passer down decoder
whatever crockett and then login this is
basically what you would see
right and so this was pretty cool no
authentication accuses
bra site the address for this one
because I can't run exploits inefficient
system right I can do that
but I have a list of 2006 and refused
Seip
it drops you into this right so
basically if you run an XY get the
password
or if you just find one of these 2000 IP
addresses and go to the IP address
it actually drops you into doing that
system right so
I'm what I like to do is there's a file
folder for this particular billing and a
twosome
there's a spear px this is like the
actual user base files right so
we want to you is basically say hey look
I want to take a look at
in the first floor and the mezzanine
here's
in a way that would do that Cisco views
and then WPX
you and this was gonna happen is here
load the interface for me
so than an interface is much more about
what you can see a base on the left hand
side
not limited to the user interface for to
do other things a lot of other things
that you can do you
without being limited by the user is
right in fact
if I wanted to I could just people just
play at owned underlying device itself
and they do whatever I want any attached
devices right so the cool thing
is what you kinda look at somebody's
building and it is is more more you
start to understand where all the stuff
means right so
like every look at second right which is
by a second for like what he sees
are separate by floors in zones right
that's just the way it kinda separating
a particular devices ounce and things
like that so
take a little bit tighter but I it in
this office on job sites
and that's why many civilians there's no
way I would runs record books
so yeah but elections will see
accessing richard is a second are things
like this which are for plans
will show you this its can render here
just one second I'm show you four
planets pictures you
like all environmental controls for this
particular building right and what is
running where
and obviously you can change in the
stuff but what's also cool
after its so I'm as i think is loading
go get another one right so this was
pretty cool I'm because
what the innovators actually like to do
you is actually tell you what building
its managing rates of a picture of it
saying hey this is the building
that's being manager and thats address
so if you want to stand across really
liked this is
awesome you could do that if you want to
you right
I want to get its for user-friendly
slow where
things here
i guess its Java so X while tried to
live his
Missy exist
a your just take time
yet all these have like I am low
animations and set the kinda tell you
what's going on
see
soda pops skin
so once again the user base is pretty
intuitive
and electoral to allow is they'll just
allow you basically the change came into
the bottom
right sir if I hover over the saying not
a click it
over rehearsing you like to see that
their buttons
right and so this is how an operator
real engineer
would actually manage a building right
so so if you put your building on line
to the internet without notification
anyone can manager building it's pretty
simple
from I'll take a larger in a second
on the supreme court to decide punctual
listing so alarms in most cases when you
see the word alarm in a building
management system
it's not like a physical on its gonna go
off what folks usually do is all set
up a criteria to be notified for
something
that's considered a warm so if the
temperature gets too high
or for temperature goes too low or
something is turned off by the time it
was he turned on
they can create in a war and so will
happen is if the criteria is met
I'm either some gets an SMS message or
phone call or something like that
I know an alarm goes off so we see the
word alarm
it's not usually like a real physical
alarm going off it's just like a Sep
yeah so this is pretty cool I once again
you can make
hover over command so if you one click
that thing
you turn the pump on rights priest
report the way that is this actually
works as they could this interface
if you click this button it passes a
command to the underlying framework the
framework basically translates
translates that too whatever protocols
attached actual device
well thats back matter mod bus or some
other custom protocol
and it sends out to the device that's
listening in this in this case would be
some kinda pop
and then the pump understand that
protocol he returns on or just a set
point
response back saying hey I'm on now and
then this user to fish displays in a
nice way
so that's all this user interface is
doing so if you understand underlying
protocols
you actually jump to the underlying
system until the device do whatever you
want
right so in this case there's only one
command really write like turn off and
turn
right but if you wanted to you could
jump to the underlying device it's a
turn on its been really fast
or or don't ever turn on ever getting
were or right next play against the vice
compelling you
device are not very robust are not meant
to be messed with
anyways
see is also a cool other chilled water
system it just kinda shows you what's
going on of
enable status is and then I want to load
up one other one here
this were here so here's one lights
writers and playwrights
here customer lights outdoor lights
this one also actually as energy manager
as well right in turn power on
first so a billy medicines look like
right tell you right now your fortune
1000 their corporate building
their corporate campus at the system
somewhere tell you right now you have
this is a summer
of we're not want these guys are we
pulled out that has no authentication to
theirs
but you could be traffic so I hope
you're not
so from okay
so
little about access control systems her
democrats access control system
I'm not to show it is vendor ask nicely
in was
pretty proactive and 9.6 I will talk
about 10 apiece to but i wanna talk
about the systems in general so
for the most part with you access
control
real about these devices right like you
bad into a door someplace that doesn't
signaling
it try to identify who you are incensed
actors device and then a door magically
a box
it's pretty cool so I get had access to
quality systems here
I thought this was really cool right
because you put your hand on it and the
new badge in
it checks that that's if it's the right
badge for Haitian workers stole your
bachelorette sir
and then it basically Rieger and
Princess I S three Billy we should let
them in
so the crazy thing about it is
everything or these devices
can be open with tacky said for
yeah that key right there so other key
cost like $6 dollars
so yet so super expensive I know it's
probably our most people's price range
I but you really want to get access to
some unease doors
my view my penis right so and so
if you actually pull this thing off the
wall you'll see that there is not a
magical unicorn they're making a
decision
as to what should happen said they're
just wires right and so and
this is kinda hard at it right the
billing agent systems what you are very
intimidated by them
attended a religious computers PK or
networks maybe
using reporter calls or weird you look
alike your networks but
its religious computer works so and this
one has like a
this is the reason I have a strange I
here's actually kinda described what
is going on here right so for the most
part
I'm all that's happening is what the
decision is made usually not by the
using up a system selves they can make
the decision by themselves
can ever user database on actual device
itself
button for the most part they don't do
that for the most part the decisions
action it somewhere else right
officially single get set back saying
yeah you should let them in
I'm in some weird cases were maybe ever
remote station it's way for of
and the user list as a change very often
you catch it but usually on the device
itself
but that usually not the case right and
if we look at some other wires here like
the outputs
wire 5&6 basic control door lock
that says simple as that so usually it's
just about applying right
portage to the right wire if you up as
access rick Scott this License
permitting
so I'm in a simplified way if you go to
a
like a bad thing says or something like
that and your badge in
what could happen as either over cereal
or IP
a signals gonna get sent to compare say
I hate this person dispatched
and this is their number and use the
application servers can look up on a day
to day saying hey does this person
exists in my database
and what are the authorized to access to
send it back to the applications are
saying
is these are the permissions for that
particular user right and then
back or sure your IP is to send the
signal back to the device a
this is what we know about this person
are and then the device actually to
supplies
your voltage to a particular lock and
says locker locker
so usually five orchard art wobbles
pressured
so physical access trumps everything
right so if you go to a batting system
and pull off a wall
there should be a wire behind it right
not your comments just a wire
so and typically some others wire tracks
gonna go to the lock
and usually just fire 12 volt apply to
that wire that's going to open that walk
or sometimes too sir a reply cuz the
door may have a controller itself
right so control connector or so I'm
obviously require Cisco access
and then this user cars 2 similar device
for use at the ticket price of the wall
on so you have to really care for
whatever large is these manufactures no
that if you take the device of the long
get can access the wires it's basically
every defeat
so I don't have temporal arms for if you
pull the device off the wall
or like like I did when I marked the
device itself
it actually has a temper mechanism else
in the signal to the application server
saying hey
someone just marked lanes open your
future
I'm typically install a Windows machines
this application server itself
right so probably the most popular
access control software
are these three here right with the top
one probably the most popular access
control
sus never see secure right Dept a wide
divergence
every data center that ever been to you
you secure ever so their servant
I'm so if you're doing it you're a pen
test and you basically want to gain
access to some the system for you wanna
gain access to some
or someplace urging XO data center
whatever it is a fiscal sanity in
in and play I must say you have
something like two main admin
this is how you would find so we find 60
we know it and install kies
are for these devices itself we have
privilege creds
we can to say I hate tell me where this
thing is installed and
it'll tell us okay there's a secure
database installed on this particular
machine here and they want to get access
to machine once again it's a human
machine interface
it looks just like this rights this is a
secure
or actions are this is Dora sorry
carrier
so are when you want when i unlock
something Israel we actually did this
during like a fantastical contest you
relate to select the door
you want click unlock could Seattle
topic you it's pretty cool
so you have to understand underlying for
recording like that although if you're
really
you could understand Wipro want to send
yourself or you can get access
you impress your mic button and the door
unlocked so
I'm experts vertical I'm adding road
users
that a particular group she's a pretty
difficult to detect
what people are looking for mister so
I'm just some basic general operation
about secure like I said that's probably
most
if you know if your fortune 1000 playoff
secure probably
I'm says progress that state a better
measure out so if you find a single
server
SS progress account somewhere tables or
chairs second
our like secure sequel that's that
default database name
I'm that party secure database server
that means that is controlling access
control sir
facility to get if you own that database
you basically an all access control
facility
so for Carrie there could be at there
could be a file
for carried or not net I'm or to be in a
database the database the names usually
DHS
underscore main and usually is when its
authentication writes it doesn't have
its own account
uses is usually is when I saw but you
can change
force so data structures kinda
complicated so this is the restructure
from a secure database the back and
so it's toward a lot of different things
right but probably most interesting to
us
I'm or the tea cart which is the card
information
the journal which is basically
everything that's going on and the
person right
I'm and also person has all the card
numbers and a particular pin for that
card
so Australia Davis free
creates so I'm were getting real close
here
so if you ask yourself hey I want to
audit my organization
where do I start right so would give you
the shirt and stuff you can go do that
right now
and look for your organization on mine
yessir protocols
the back that scanners gonna be actually
sorry out so you can go down with that
sir and mapping stuff
try to find some so image systems on the
Internet already
internal network I'm or what I like to
do you
is go shower facilities Department so
cancel our times this is not run by it.
such a reminder Solis Department and say
we're
or are truly in boxes right where are my
just extra boxes were my army logic
which might help controls and have them
tell you where the stuff is
or give you the software's to take a
look at it things like that
cool stuff does our facility management
systems
probably using workers I'm if you want
access control stuff
culture physical security folks and said
a saying hey can access control
to say wears a secure Davis wears a
secure software
I wanna see I wanna take a look at it or
was a license cuz I wanna auditor to
wherever
or cherry or shot right and hands
work you have to meet at a privilege to
a tragic end to scan for the
across a surgery given site sir so for
the surveillance systems has got three
pictures systems that you ask for
but the best people to ask are your
datacenter folks they have everything
their everything you can imagine that
actually measure systems
the access control systems that energy
medicines everything
so if you get your datacenter okay I
wanna take a look at all this offer
they probably haven't they prolly avid
but just asked nicely
so I do I take some questions
questions
but that's hard so
I'm that there is one thing to kinda
keep in mind right so
the attacks Ackley control the so I'm
that's a really good question one thing
to keep in mind is
I was classified Billy manage systems
officially measured systems
as a ICS duster control systems right
sir
scan falls under ICS are and ICS
almost always controls a process so you
have computer systems and other systems
embedded systems
but they're there to control a process
right and so
undoing states offer mistakes is pretty
easy control C
doing a process mistake is is heart it's
not possible
so if you are on it in the system's and
you turn something on
I'll you can take that back is a
physical event has occurred someplace
right so you cannot undo that you can
turn it off but you may not
undo what that process at cost right so
if you are doing it. against the
system's you have to be really careful
about that
and you always have to understand that
at the interfaces
while looks very cartoonish and it looks
like it's looks very innocent
its actually controlling a process in
place so I'm if you turn on a boiler
like the the fires gonna get lit right
and you won't be able to make it through
like
I don't want you ever have done that
it's too late it's a process that
occurred
can't take it back it's on a PM we can
revert back to snapshot
rates a very good question always
controlled the process
shares was up heat on the back if the
office
that that's a good point on
usually when folks did you guys are the
question so the question was
it's likely that most but chief security
officers
don't understand that this are falls
under the purview essentially
so they don't understand that this is a
rest dealership to billings online
that are sure to find it there's no
software to manage the structure stuff
that's actually good question a really
good point because
using we talk to folks in like how can
we get a better handle
or officially management systems and how
we secure these things
do we need to change passwords and Mike
will the first step
mister organize your self in a way that
you can manage these things
so the last couple sites that we had to
pay to talk to facilities guys go talk
to your physical security guys
good doctor data center folks I'm
usually what you have to understand is
who owns this from an administrative
standpoint is at the facility spokes
is an IT is it the physical security
folks is it your datacenter folks
because that matters Ryan yet to get
that done first so if you or
a security person in an IT department
and you walk into you
the data center or you walk into the
physical security department where you
walk into you
the Facilities Department say or do
these on it it's likely the report
someone else they will report to the
that's the CIO or maybe there you're
like the sea ESO may not be in their
direction
in a report to CEO right the facilities
guys
maybe sometimes airport to financial
ever write his corporate real estate
ever so that's a really good point so if
you want to get your arms around this
from a strategic perspective yet
organizer software
you have control these and in a way that
makes sense so
it may be under the sea ESO may be under
the CIO I don't know what that looks
like a reorganization
but you have to do something right
especially when a lot of the exposure is
created by third parties
like integrators aqui saw your billing
address is going to be an AT&T
IP address space someplace that's heart
to heart problem right so
good question so organizing yourself in
a way
to wear the person that does have
basically responsibility for these
billionaires is with this clear to them
that this falls under their
responsibility that is the first step
for you and technical stuff after a
strategic standpoint
that's the first step and then once you
have that in place interested they can
cut up on the play
you want to manage its thats so we have
seen some really interesting things
where
but the responsibility as shifted hands
so for example we go to some
organization I would say which one
and her like a um you know you have your
building as it is is online
and they're like are we no like I answer
atti IP address space
like okay that's crazy and then they go
talk to the police auction like I i mean
about this all time right and then
IT folks CIO's like you guys don't have
a clue as to what you're doing
is our computer systems were taking them
over and so they
they took them over and they put them
into you they put them to the core party
space
but they put them under the corp it.
security policies
and then what they ended up finding is
like these devices
act really weird for example yet a
checkered shorts turning onto places are
like a nerd blacklists
you had like also to Internet activity
were like
on certain protocols are getting sent
over the Internet Ryan
and then they basically assets like to
these devices are used like now
visionary doing Ryan they didn't know
this is happening
because the responsibility was very
unclear so facilities is running these
things with
clearly servers someone's desk right
plug into some
comcast modem someplace to all the other
scrutiny that happens for
egress filtering and other stuff is
being missed rights
really good point don't push the buttons
on the internet facing
stuff so go to that these
anything else so
that's a good question out I don't know
like every buildings different
and so depending on the components that
are attached to you I don't know it
happened so I'm as
it's likely that your fans are under a
tractor boiler whatever
a bizarre probably different for every
single building so it's hard for me to
generalize just say well
get access to a boiler by do this I'm
what I'm thinking is
you probably have to have like access to
you yet the question should probably
more like
if you have access to disperse a pic
type equipment can figure in this way
what type of damage could you grade so
or laid out a certain configuration
whatever I'll
I don't know sir but we do have a
project that's we're gonna do this year
where we're working with an interpreter
on the east coast and the integrators
basically
it's pretty cool because they go into
new facilities
and they set up building at systems
right and if they rebel
all this all equipment and what they're
gonna actually do is set up that all
equipment into basically a fatal imagine
that work
and we're gonna try to see exactly what
it is that we can do like whether we can
set a boiler on fire
do christa breakers get you a tremendous
the Sep but on new if we have a comment
that thereafter away anywhere scrap
I don't have any problem a problems with
us doing damaged
systems rates question
I can tell you this the systems are not
designed to be
messed with so like your boilers that
robust
are and hopefully there's physical
strain mechanisms to prevent like
catastrophic damage
but I'm pretty confident like just being
able to just break it
are that's probably wealth and skip
three probably pretty easy
whether or not we can make said a
building on fire selector I don't know
that order to look at
this year Buy stores just breaking
equipment
pritchard can just break it you want you
what that means your business
I don't know at the Canton how your
business is used
systems
what like a can you read it repeat the
question
yep so that's a that's a good point
I think I am a lot of folks don't
realize that they're building measured
systems can be controlled remotely
so that the the biggest problems by
understanding that if you have a
building management system
it's probably likely that your
integrator is managing it remotely
so I mean that's why we see all these
going medicines on the Internet
like the corporations don't put on them
put them there themselves
the integrator puts put it there for
them so watched likely as if you want to
restrict Remote Manager to somebody
systems
you probably have to work with your
interpreter in fact we've seen every
single time is
that only organization the bank or
whatever
their ship the teller a greater like a
look you're not going to login to the
web interface or the Internet
you're gonna ask us for access to this
person specific segment
we're gonna allow for getting point in
time and then you're gonna tear a
management and when you're done
returned of so the interesting also they
can still do remote management but the
organization can now control the remote
management in a way that makes sense
them right so that's a good question
yeah
I mean attended the day you know what I
tell
integrators is like a VPN appliances
like a couple hundred dollars
you know I'm getting for your devices
because
in my opinion they're not robust enough
to be internet facing
even if you have all the security
mechanisms configurations done correctly
I V as obvious by the experts that we
have right so arm
I don't think having this thing on the
Internet is a good idea at all
well because we're
there's yeah
really that at this base is a question
of patch management
um lecture for example the trade in
Niagara boxes others back to throw the
water bill is that we have reported to
them
um if you look on the internet and you
do the enumeration
the boxes will tell you what version are
running you'll see that almost never
fully patched
so trip or and why that's the case
I don't know I don't know if it's
because does device are about facilities
whether they actually belong to an
integrator they're just being leased by
the end organization
or whether people just don't care I'm
not sure but the reality is that
if you find it if i sat on the rats by
not touched
if you find in your internal network
there's probably really not patched
ever fitzco to to do you like
disintegration in the first to yep so
the and map script
I'm downloaded from digital ones website
and then I'm
the Python trip to have that's actually
built into showed and now
so yet it's just the poor
you screw for the port port 1911 yeah
and you get a elicit a botched up
and then on john hasn't helped the guy
rancher Dan
he has a hooked up query capabilities
yet but he just court for that poor
I just don't everything that has as its
done unless it's Ken likable
yet ten twenty thousand devices and then
grip for your company a
I if there's a more questions thanks for
attending a really appreciate it so