so the study at home starting with a
quick introduction ass to use
I'm what our online payment systems him
I
wanna talk about this but what can you
do the
with the times and thanks them for
something I'm how do you go about doing
them
um not necessarily in that order and
legitimately that
this is not a PC I talked shit you
somehow thought that I was talking about
PCI compliance
I'm strong one I'm
I will try to avoid naming the
individual pending a wise use these
issues affect sprints column disarm
degree and it so it is a showcase
I'm gateway acts and using them amid
another one on the site
you probably not to sound on marijuana
some want anything is
bizarre bed and
and one or the other things is that done
most that plugins for
open source tools like you always
commerce sent out whatever
they're often written by a third-party
developer and
not necessarily that'd to you and the
time in
get web understand it isn't I'm stars
like implementation back to go home
lazem anything their lives in credit
good what's in the bag 'em
run been mine credentials married to two
kids
Rex countries in Chester I'm bid Tech Ed
each up i'd right a blog kinda
pretend write a blog on the up but
didn't play your house
and run to projects mostly and
identifying security flaws
on or you explore Jim vulnerabilities
so from a.m. that I guess countries
investors by hunters
I also contribute to some eyeball nom
I'm open source projects hmm
I'm now in what little spare time I have
I'm sup
dumping injured I'm get less are
effectively the point of sale system
up for webshop sign in almost up to walk
in you walk up to cash reg the
hand over cash payment gateway is the
equivalent
and Websense that your own website %um
%um this themselves the timing got white
use
effectively that the cash register I'm
but its to be outsourced to somebody
else
apps
so bomb cricket is actually quite a bit
about on
no what are the actors in the normal
online transaction
about some definitions we look at time
ago at the office
until noon on into the actual the Simon
abilities
ultimate about be usable talk for free
and
finally we going to discuss an
implementation bugs
I'm I a couple demos for
mostly since so I was dotted with the
customer
just in a happy guy wants to shop online
get a startling to store
not describe details Tom on
the Mets and a few months to supply the
goods
or services was Mexico cash I M
and mostly the Sunforce in this
presentation actually
affect mentioned not the customer or
I'm the bank's or panda at the end so
the Panda I'm
I'm typically the large financial
institutions
or and some case a small start-ups they
tech a fractional each transaction
typically and I'm
and basically that's how they would
generate them on
and then there's the attacker
who's up suppose stance internet thinks
the destroyer
and if you believed a popular press and
in this case
it would typically be other you know her
bored kids
Oribe organized crime I'm
while the attacks that we don't discuss
don't release jail to saddam
millions of dollars in damage unless you
do then
across the internet and there's still
enough traction I think that
organize com would be willing to repeat
the stop attacks over and over
I'm however we don't really see them in
the wild but
justice its easy to steal im I did
million
credit card numbers from no RAND
Corporation
I'm but I'm
a sings get more more difficult we might
eventually end up seeing some these
attacks
I'm underwent winds the pope's ever
gonna go ice
from us two years there are medications
in place for a lot of these attacks but
they're
isn't really any some incentives for the
customers to move on
and so think while this summer lull
between
these things are being exploited in the
wall and a solution Texas
at some 100 try to push people to to
move onto
aside for attended absurd
that sup I'm if your cunt ester or
Garza implementing a timing i really
wanna
play around with him and should use Test
cat number so you don't have to
charge it out all the time I'm South
these are
did gonna stop 10+2 put into and is on
time for mum
and implementation testing I'm there are
often additional numbers that
might be specific to that timing I want
that returns
certain behavior you want to test for
insufficient funds on the card or
Todd canceled in Satara I usually find
that summer
information that developers got from the
pentagon where
so on is always look with him in a
low-key
after developers gather that the
documentation I'm
when testing the top be something
serious the muddy banks in the
implementation
in the integration at cetera supper
and I'm the primary means some utilizing
a timing that way when you
run a website that in southeastern I P
I'm
and the general operations from an idea
i i things like charging you cannot
carrying the status of the job pre-order
on some classic your
like a hotel more and camping
plus resort you wanna take a deposit but
not necessarily John
manager during payments if if you offer
subscription service this
on band refunds for I'm happy just us
and the typically accessed through
cheered environments thus the sandbox
which is what you meant to be using
when you're developing apply gains or
integrating mean
with the time however I'm that's an
environment where
its fine to violent in one actually
charging pads it's on a
as its playground. and this production
now the details the mitchen
account your estimates typically shared
between these two environments
if you are an attacker I'm its better to
test your ex parte against the sandbox
kruzel if there's something wrong with
it you know what you have a type or sign
the sandwich with by so we give you nice
their message saying that %um
you men style but one dropping Klaxons
on a fraud detection systems typically
miss
that don't monitor did the moment
and sample that is somber
trying to for by power playing with a
an actual redirect top payment
the sandbox gushing gonna invalidate
aggression
please contact mention and Sagan you can
tweak your exploit
I in sandbox into lab where some time me
want to production from there
sup on looking at on how r
the various transactions where for the
different ways to implement the time ago
I spoke
and direct APR a sign
that we see if a bit and typically this
means that the mission
carries the burden up being PCI
compliant
piece that I receive the credit card
auto corrected himself and pass it on to
Pam Geller
which I suck at so stop with that being
a checkup page
you know I'm to the post directed to
mention website
Sam his work done on this the amount
that I wanna
hyper the goods to mine
then minutes and better as he said bag I
had the mixup progressed
to the timing I'm and this guy sent to
cash in
as an adult I'm and so you wouldn't have
wanted
in person at southern edge in yes you
would have to knead the dough you that
you would have to know the username and
password
I'm them and again which I just a tad
suspects
status whether or not payment was
received as our seats
I'm more information and I'm and then
buy some at the National some action had
small Siam Thai most successful
or minute by minute I'll please try
again
a contact support whatever so that's
something very straight narrow
I'm simple implementation a but
it has the PCI requirements sup
a lot of people moving on to things like
hosted
payment solution where the pattern I'm a
guy where
takes the credit card details director
the nation
doesn't actually have any involvement in
the payment transaction
I'm and that white you what happened to
the PCI compliant
but it means that there's a disconnect
between the mansion and the timing got
white
and South on this room there for abuse
in some will stop
on an example this name is done you get
the check out page
sent back hedged in our on
and is a striker post from
in the brosser to the timing that where
which effectively means that
your magazine but the customers back in
the API call on behalf of the mentioned
and pessimism the API for the pentagon
before this match in
is stop public and so if you were able
to
work out certain details but I used a
ballad
but this is a the gym admission account
you could mess around this yes on
suffer pasqua started coming I'm
with a crack at the Telus IMEI
sense peccary directing at up charge do
Niamh please go back
to mention Gatland provide the following
details so
as you can see there's a whole bunch up
to here in that
us I'm so that I hear em
in the redirect sign in and he's the I'm
out
Center that process yep
redirects to mention website mention
website receives the details
and then based on what the brass
provides determines whether or not
payment has been received your receipt
I'm in a might misek pick in class
if you want us I'm the site you running
alaska missile
punished popular on solutions they often
have integration
they comply Saurer warehouse shipping
sour the moment even Bella that the
other times clearing ice into an account
just don't get chips try to our
and different alternative is without
using a director post
you take it back into a white level I'm
page on the timing that way before doing
that post with a credit card details
the same kinda stuff and yet to check a
patch to help aids
miscast redirect chance to be in your
head small home
up sir and as you can see in the yep
in here this although I mean that offer
and the redirect I'm %um
use and that it happened at Lime any
other suspect had similar homes I'm
up this time you tried to details send
the credit that the toss
and i'm having a ride just a tad sends
you back did mention
web sites I act lol now his
the details provided mention transaction
IdeaCentre
which your breasts and the match and an
image then decides whether or not
you notice your receipt chips at our
success and their
and there's also an alternative which
some people
I'm believe is offers more security
which
am essentially the same thing for a
so you got to take a pass redirect back
to mention Gatland mention every sense
here
home you post credit at the task
correctly
to the timing that way buttons that a
payment gateway
redirecting you back to the mansion with
the details
it makes a POST request a record to a
hidden URL
that suppose the only the merchant and
the time ago I know
on so the left post
progress there medicine and now it's
like Alabama has been received
and then I'm the timing I just basically
redirects a bacteria
like a thank you page so this is you not
giving
transactional beat house or see details
for the brosser this why
I'm and this potentially a substantially
hotter for an attacker to nowhere
the endpoint is to for attacked that
yes um up I do he has the details Europe
on South there is a light but the policy
without
mattis if you're using open source
solution and using a plugin
Maceo as commerce and using them
plugin for this time this topic coming
that way the return URL
stowaways the Siam in the pocket
so in a and might be hidden but
for at same time it's known if you look
at the source code of honor
and if it's a custom implementation
yurman still tend to
name things in a sensible manner gene
you to just come looking for things like
return or time I'm received
top I just on the website I'm to be fine
sup to finish this up just a straight
edge to my badge
and assess and I'm interested %uh
this also said integration which is
where the Managing Director speaks to
I'm the time ago I saw this no customer
momentum at the deluxe sample that is
when you refund money and Customs
columns and their use
you sent me an iPad 2 screen was broke
and I'll send it back to him
give me my money back add so the
customer has no involvement in this
even though there's been a prior
transactions just I stayed a straight-up
self request typically up
and done money gets
300 to the customer sup
if an attacker where to on Gallacher
these and it is stopping transactions
and this typically to rice you do this
you either doing in this component where
it's transmitting the transactional
dollar
to the time ago but to your own lot
young dude 302 redirect neural have
things like the amount dem thousand
dollars
you change that one dollar or and then
you pick the time and
and hopefully that the website on the
other end doesn't validate
yet that the payment amount matchless
just just yet status is paid is a
receipt number
and it should show on your iPad or yeah
laptop whatever
I'm and the other thing that's typically
done this to
and just by pass the test steps to go
straight from the checkout page
and you got to the thank you time has
been received hi Jim just spit for
transactional
detail I'm and since since the maginnis
disconnected from the time you get where
they might not have a wide development
whether or not these details are correct
and South done there are several
CD is applied to the stop attacks on the
onus on a comp
us back to 2002
I'm but that does army the wonderfulness
that have been given a CV
I mean the sinks dead back to life yeah
early 80s
probably and and it's there lies the
problem
sup im traditional tax changed how much
just
and Europe tent change it to send
yeah and that's all this with sign a pic
or request television
I or is 50 times were saved
I'm special this with response to a Best
but you might ask what our questions on
selection its
%uh as the band's name for a message
authentication code
and typically it's sad up its all summer
fairy dress fingerprint see
signature et cetera but the best for the
team
bash the details and NS and hash along
with it
never had it so if you change the amount
in the transaction detail the hash in
along a matchless
and the transaction gets border
sup samples on request election
typically it on a protest the bottle
components of the transactions our the
actual URL
in a redirect this quite page in law can
contain things like the customer
information
transactional da description on items
bought and shatter are
I'm so that our house the whole thing
they just act these are things that we
think are kind of important to develop
that whether or not
other transaction this Balaton mature
the bed unchanged E
amount or the currency on
some examples of this and them straight
up shop on
the this things did the blue details are
the account
ID submits an account reference the red
is shared secret
what's as meant to ensure that people
can just
generate different hasher's biggest I
want have
all the messages at work yep b7
have initialization vector and and the
fog
different order of things so neither one
has an md5 on and if %ah
plus on the secret key an agency
each implementation a slightly different
but they're also
very similar and some when he didn't
come get my skin's kinda get what has
gone way up doing
things so from this item has been
inspected a slightly different
but from past the Sun perspective it's
the same things like yep
generating hash and the house consists
of
values plus yeah the secret should
secret and response to that since the
same thing on a protest the muddy
Charles
I'm to be that just makes my day the
transaction ID and the amount
I'm sup examples of that can see it's
they're almost
the sign as the initial amount know if
the initial example which was request
elevation
sorpresa lessons applied when by the
mission
when it's sending the user the customer
to the timing I'm
and the response on a national issues by
the time to get wired when you're
sending the user back to the mansion
I'm and South the shared secret
this known to both mentioned and the
timing at one so
all the rustic couldn't possibly Vella
that um
so when you're dealing with request a
response on the National you have a
couple
options you can bypass the lesson
you can abuse on the cryptographic
properties or you can defeat validation
what's eliminates the use some singers
altogether
really on to typical by Stu
by possible is I G deeper under Bush
semester you define the same parameter
more than once
hopefully the I'm if it's wonderful
the ash checked Sinjin check when used
in 1st parameter and then the actual
charging cord will use the second
parameter and to click something that is
I'm in a a php page receives it in that
sense it yourself back and
where having two elements defined in XML
core sex multi-use
letter on now you can abuse unprotected
parameters so
since they only protect the bottle brown
purse up transaction
safe yours buy a subscription service
you just modified expiry dates I'll
you still painful process but instead of
having a service expire after Mon
they'll expire after in a a century or
more
I'm which basically means that your
getting a list of free
and this also are abuse application
logic
example this is up and a big payoff
application I
or pre or post for I membership
and some having at WES have base where
on instead of having a transaction
details change in order to Mac
the transaction change from a charge to
just pre or
often amount and the have an additional
parameter
which isn'ta up the singer so
you can this parameter and stunts are
you cannot
it generates exactly the same details
back to that
mentioned but with the addition primer
free of one and so if the
validation code doesn't check for the
presence a priori
all the other parameters are identical
and something up
all been paid 50 bucks buttons that it's
just pre-authorized
50 bucks sup I'm
at if you can't can you send it to us
you might be able to a tactic rip same
the examples that we saw
they're using and the file shot while
now they're typically bundles length
extension tax it's a lot easier on md5
the medicine shop on
missed but I'm sure she researched to
and so the peach I wanna stop
I M if you don mackey let extension
attack this the short
description is that hashing algorithm
works on a
a us Chanda said I'm on a botched
amended if it does I'm not but still pad
benefited has more bites it'll sup
compress the middle section a bit
I'm and what you can do is without
knowing them
the big key which is kinda discuss
you can at patting and then append
a different message switches and two in
this case and because of the way
that the block chaining where X you will
actually
this job the unknown donna
and summer over I did your daughter
seeking have chewed
different messages or you can append
padding and a different message to date
do that non the Tulsa signature
transaction data and actually have the
hash
Clark on end up waking possible
aggression checks
I'm sadly like extension tax are pretty
costly
I'm I wouldn't you have to do it on a
pair transactional basis
finding md5 collisions even is
with all the advancements in crypto it
still a CPU intensive
exercise so
I'm there are a much better solution on
was just defeat to request on the
measure the way you go about that
is you look at how the fingerprint this
matter
be some details that the service/site
script mitchen
website used to generate request
election
sup nearby to the Telus this merchant
account ID
this is seeking shaky transaction time
preference
ID a mountain at times to on
and then the brosser submits the
following information:
to the panic gala a smidge muddy
transaction top reference ID amount
times that and a fingerprint
as well as a result europe I'm there are
often additional parameters but these
are the ones that
so the matter so if we compare them side
by side and
and see that basically the site now
so you might already see the problem
here but
let me holla for you we have a non
password
and then on hash within the whole buncha
other
I'm text upset effectively we can't read
the rest the plaintext
assault and just apply standard possum
cracking techniques
now the shared secret it's usually
bender supply
another chain just in fact there is no
option electron you have to open support
request white for like a week
and as soon as they change the key your
website is broken because
you have the wrong key in now signatures
done match anymore
as a demeanor changes I'm and
furthermore it's often converted to
uppercase a lower castes just to make it
easier for
developers not to screw up I but I just
stacks the odds
further in debt attack this fire is now
you keys by said you have to brute-force
is significantly reduced
and South an attacker could just sign up
to the timing out whether their
look into abuse receive one of these
codes
and because the yeah supply by the
vendor that
would typically but you know how long it
is what kinda complex the dealing with
it
and then just you optimizer
possum-catching called for
that and so what we eat what I'm usually
seen
involve us apart from other dump and has
been used typically it's at characters
of bad to its
really bad isobars complexity and there
are some that includes medicare after a
spotter
I'm they tend to be psyched and so you
know on
to prevent things like an apostrophe
breaking it because some SQL injection
by 10 status on a up a case like ice
I'm and even if the use of it as like as
complex as a sometimes the casket to up
the cash or to lower caste and actually
defeat their own
pasta complexity I'm in general
I know one another time ago whether uses
10 character passwords
the market morton this particular one
but I'm
even kindness is not strong enough that
big cab endorse
used 32 character tax value did ride
from I i jus and
and the ones I have spoken to are
already in the process of moving to 64
character
a shit secret and
if you're dealing with does she have to
pull back on their keylex
extension because you can crack them and
yurman lost time
sup when you want to crack this sticking
it to the club
biggest everything's in the club next s
I'm
why is the club I'll brother donato ball
dedicated cracking hardware setting it
up and you can just hop on Amazon
launch supplements insists ass on office
GP you
I'm I think don't think you told us yet
but I'm sure it's in the pokémon
on find a readily available image
said I'm had to do the install and
typically there's like a shell script
that you can just run
federal install all the development
lovers for you
and you know within five minutes a
pittance da on your instance an Amazon
you're up and running I'm and Udall some
make that elastic
if you're not using GPUs you cannot
elastic and graphics cats
South a you can for example use John the
Ripper
dollar a present right support for
dynamic formats
I'm I recommend getting the jumper
distribution it comes with all the good
user-supplied patches I'm it supports
distributed cracking over in PRC can
you can far as many instances as you
want or you can just
use at elastic BS a
John the Ripper doesn't require jib you
and you can also use both screwed up an
open CL
with John if you're using the Jumbo
distribution how r abour
the cuter lottery so the two dakotas is
sadly lacking and the open sea al
it's not really up to moscow performance
cell well it is available and if you're
gap to write your own home open Cliq to
kennels
%uh I don't see why you should not use
John the Ripper for this
I'm so even if you didn't go in and just
fauna dynamic format I'm Sun discuss
up im bitch
on so just credited
a singer there and then down here
with site map take train bus or stop by
adding some salt stand up and the
password
adds more salt and anchored at md5
and effectively we include a test which
contains
this bit here is step and resolve hashed
is the first salts is the second salts
all the way down there and that's what
the password be
and then develop that could use in
jonathan's test format
other format you defined if you are
using John I would recommend you also up
but
Jonathan Cahn to use a specific John but
comes to make sure that
you max the password complexity in
characterised smallest like
in a which character sets using as a lot
john looked waste a lot on
cracking yes shorter hospital longer
passwords
made a character saddam necessarily
belong in there
on so and what you would need not to do
that
you have been Coco here which on
this does not so wheres this a talk on
it but I am
the concert this is Sammy lot in the
form you find a little moments that
you're after
and then just print model us on
Assad dynamic cache there
and then you put that in a in a far
honey just
that John have a go at it nope
and if you are using John when jumbo you
can
up that the Mac fall tonight Olympia on
seeking to distributed cracking across
multiple hosts
I'm just pretty easy to set up try to
host file
and I'll SSI justification for you sir
i ed key best and cash in saree
Cumberland passwords and then basically
use and pixx
don't John with whatever problems you
would normally do and then
and got takes care of the rest so add
its release ec2 distributed I'm stock
within the hour
%uh however you better off using debut
ed correctly up from sit here perhaps
calculations
I'm scouts but that number Jeff you
course a device s
but you had in in your box and you can
use by the Qatar Open CL depending on
what the boss is she had
and non Plaza some Subrata 7 Amazon
Office India so you can use are the cute
our on sale
s2 why we choose one or the other it
really comes down to personal preference
on most the modern tools tend to use
open CL simply because
chewed on Lee Westwood Nvidia OpenGL
let's whip
a plethora of things on there are some
technical dif
Francis & Sons that I could I have to
manage on threading
more than that on CL some managed
distribution I'm
tasks across the number of course you
have available
I'm however since of 100 a lot easier to
deal with them
populous I could see coding and and pop
guess could actually lost to do some
things that
on missus selig right with block a
buffer offset some point traversed cell
I'm are uninsured up but
the star is my good news on sale and
this planning to open source up so that
you can use to build on you don't
necessarily have to build a cracker from
stock
John the Ripper like to mention crypto
has halted for serbs another
very comprehensive GPS tracker are you
sis
up a CL and supports distributed crackin
I've been does news MPI assets on
services like mobile
I wise cracker had a plywood
uses up in Sea Isle and dust distributed
cracking over
and PRI but it's basically just a a
proof-of-concept
what pics 0 and dad
defused if you cracker sand %uh
judah best one that supports multiple
salsa a base model not
a shelter a good have a look and see
what can also see what some context I'll
be happy with and just
run it from there on there are other
alternatives but
the San Juans tonight so I went sup for
the demo we gonna demo
mom a number of different things
on nothing Coast up of
with a/c
use
them
I check
are
and mister back that's right so
on the first time I was going to be
based around the fact that
if you have a hidden return to
television page
and you can just brute force it Serena
very message
bird for scripted spits out a whole
bundle on C
decide that and a better user
but because the fall season choose to
love that into bed
or and Papa W get I've got this
sir split up to the top and if you can
read that but it was later
runs it for the second brevity I your
I only grabbed for the ones that are
relevant and then
in the loop ado had requests and if that
had request for 10 to 200 OK
I'll echo the Euro so Iran that against
my webshop instance air
should come back fairly quickly with I'm
the bell in Europe
day sup if that was like yeah
a hidden URL you get some stuff on it
just is
humans tend to name the sings in a in a
sensible manner
a.m. and then once you find that you can
proceed with the other attacks I'm sorry
are nerves this
and some sup
I'm I'm
and I'm so we've got our webshop
and I'm and stuff I'm gonna buy a
Macbook Air
good price I'm stay with her
I'm forgot to check up page said
well just register as a new user and
the them
pins
may be a sign that marched working on
small
on then summer
did some first northern get it done
script on a bid
apps sorry acted just like this time
that
them on
any should've tried to the demigods
so it
or
an error
you and
our your
thank you for that on agreed to terms of
services such
and then on instead of actually making
the payment
will learn get the dumb source
select that on
said that Ange good order
go back and read them a
and so
which gives us
this dynamic cash which news and John
the Ripper
so I'm
I go to my books in the cloud
I can
its around this before
on the sad thing about licensee this
since been running for over two hours
I John the Ripper it's not particularly
fast
when you see GP assert sepia
so and brother buildings on the river
will love them cracked this and I'm
creature mmm
sana
in
slightly different miscast
Texas arguments some lacy
sandals and I'm
this but here's the hash that we're
going to crack and then
given assault from the her the password
an assault that the behind the password
and another is a six characters now
I'm chosen six just because I want that
demagogued foster
I'm the best view justice based on what
time and get right
you would be targeting the stale they're
all slightly different
so this cash this case certainly isn't
the not there just
SanDisk s that's the pass for their
once and on the password I can go back
into montana
and I can sign their crest from border
with the password um
Jared I'm message speed the transaction
ID
sign this on and then basically they
given this europe to this I just
what we do this am in a new orders
in in my webshop go back to this on
well done
this is a test huge tits
your own slather
worker
I'm sup water content number
6 and then if we go in
to my shop here
can see here I have a new order
charlotte's
am I'm an accepted as you say that
in the impact on
we can also take advantage %uh
unprotected
parameters in this case subs sorry on
Coast dumb selection but this one am
on so what we'll do this poll on
will make another order for the same
amount
am
on this time registered as a different
user
miss them
scroll down a bit Andrews
on
that's not gonna cat lenses the river
the she agreed to terms service on this
this Tom I'm gonna bother getting the
dome obvious
on the shopping can I the subsequent on
since no one else is using it
I would normally extractor shopping can
I DM and is
in this case the shopping cart ID is
being random
in a hour I'm like this
so does and he's been included here
as a custom rayburn and it's not
protected
by the signature or just tacked on that
we used for
chopping come a seventy or do we just
passed will rerun it miss come well
I'm a Mac shopping cart number right and
on
that will run for let Wall air
I'm
contempt this time warner ides sir 7
get back in here so all orders
and seven here you can see that it says
de materia
I'm interested even though we didn't
pass our
I'm it's also vulnerable to reply
attacks in
on up
unprotected premier tampering
sup on not for my next trick
cash estrich
I'm gonna be looking at a I'm ASCO
injections so
I'm if I get should get this on
hand
I
said on
NHA
had this nom
this issue
am gone have a look I'm
the M here see that
runs Lasko truck seem and I have and
is a nice girl injection this here
see anything
as a priori I am
growth let's go injection
part of the problem with having s gonna
Jackson's
and this message that the shared secret
has to be stored in plain text
ended on a nice an order for our the
I'm imagine to be able to develop night
the requests come and
that the sauna this case we could hamper
go visit
this year I'll us
sided
communist either
and so if we do typical example
you a cosby I'm
a ser I or be in that doesn't really
help
on sits a sub select
and better example I guess is
the Brecker record like that and said
let's try to write
ringo here see that Moscow proxies
picked up
SQL injection put
and also the page a lot for this as very
fast
so once we take it back and this girl
stands where Kim
on the benchmarks makes it straightens
up
to blind SQL injection do that extract
the password
Cup a character stats and take you that
long once you have that
you cannot straight up up spew
hijacked the idea access on behalf
mentioned
on now with this one and they also
happened to be quite helpful
ahead for have a debug like
of club coke rests my brother
the module and so what we can do with
that this summer
just extract EM
and start from this if we get our to
this
a nice
this is ever get
had to be basic and there and then on
you basically pop that into base64
decode
get you some apostles try to Lhasa I'm
just
and on
apps
now and again
should
Ian %uh
first am sale say there it's
that's the reason I'm sup a certain
someone 23
and then bassist for complaints because
it's got up
das and line endings for that's not a
problem
so hom as you can see from some in the
last two bikes
I'm a season last two text
is has a proper resolution
on
second and
on so um once you have access to the
idea I had eaten sonic rests on the
other things you can do is
issue you're on refunds so rather than
speech impairments
you can actually make a genuine payment
the comment will appear in
mentions account you'll get the goods
and then you just
refund Ron transaction on
and if you're feeling particularly evil
even to sleep through
every possible transaction and refund
all 'em I
we just which is a good way to get rid
of the competition I suppose
I dhahran incantation
don't rely on the brosser drug traffic
between them its website and time ago I
i'm
crypto is pretty hot %um
you can either use more than one on on
variable n
request from national years-long secret
or even better
used token best redirection so that the
brosser never touched
and have the transaction details on
salsa recommended that %um you protect
all the parameters
Houston request use hedge maxim that you
cannot be attacked with killing
extension attacks I'm gonna
however even if the have weak request on
a national doesn't necessarily
mean that have an exploitable
vulnerabilities there are some
mitigating factors around
I'm you know a
likely they're always be implementation
bikes which makes me happy and keeps
mean
job I I'm if you do want to look about
bikes and I go and compassion
I'm the falling prices are few good
places to look honorable bender cock
no I'm tree publishing so it's and
about SSL practices this one is
absolutely everywhere it was like a bike
in PHP
I'm that it wouldn't work with certain
certain conditions a certain price
levels a Windows
so basically every PHP developer ever
to avoid breakage turns out SSL
verification
by the foot I and even if you do and I
let
and all divisions of PHP
add having in noble it didn't actually
do correct validation set
in so man in Middleham I benefits
more reason but not the very latest
arrest every language haz had bites
aside and
made last year that saw months from I'm
cbj doesn't that he in
I have something prepared he won for
Ruby one from pokémon pajama
basically if the certificate common name
had another by then it would terminate
and just collapsed
hostage to get maps up overcome and I'm
she can always man in Middle East since
I'm if you happen to have
access on the dot A Center site and
them on my skis pit stop talkin so it's
good when comparing hasher some PHP if
you don't use the triple
comparison operator I'm page you were
quite happily can wait
one one hash to float and treat the
other has a strained
I'm trying to do not lend out while
knowledge Khan a similar to this plot so
we'll just
I'll claim that they match I'm biggest
typecast
I so I'm again missing is unlike
every phpBB like another at the same
time ago I still use the double
comparison
sup up lhasa bucks to be had any
questions
my questions
good alright on the slides are actually
a bit more
up that'd than the ones that were on the
CD I spot a couple mistakes
sauce lighten them a card can be found
here
I will be pushing to get wrapped all I'm
sometime after a
get off stage. sour I'm Graham well
the fresh on get not sick