glad to see so many here it's great to
be here in Krakow Poland
it's amazing venue it's been a great con
hopefully I'll send you home on a good
note
so me I'm a pen tester security
researcher occasionally do some training
social media you'll find me as wire girl
and I have a blog which I've been
neglecting pretty pretty badly for the
last couple years but I'm gonna push
some additional content onto the blog
after this talk because some of the
concepts need a lot more in-depth
discussion so maybe with looking at that
after all right so it's that's with sort
of a story many years ago when I was
doing a pen test of a particular CMS
they had about seven different ways to
upload files but I couldn't upload an
actual web shell and get code execution
on the box which was kind of frustrating
and I felt like it wasn't filtering
sufficiently that I should be able to
exploit it but as Penn tests go you ran
out of time and then a few months later
I was sitting reading a book and I had
this idea because the problem that I had
with the CMS was it would allow you to
upload files but every file would be
placed in its own directory even if you
uploaded a sip fall and extracted
multiple files they all got the wrong
directory and I've been trying to use
htaccess file to say well every a
default that's in this directory that
say a JPEG should not be treated as a
PHP file and get a web shell that way
but that didn't work because I only had
one file in that directory which was the
htaccess file and so I'm sitting there
reading a book in the idea hits me that
but what if the htaccess file could
reconfigure itself to be a PHP file and
so I did some basic testing and HT
access or HT shells as I call it the
project was born it's basically just a
collection of Apache directives and some
fun things some people have called it
super janky well web shells it's really
like not quality code at all but you
know it works and yeah I did someone say
it was sort of brilliantly and furious I
get a bit of mixed reaction some people
think that I'm being really evil and
something people think I'm being really
clever so this is kind of an old project
record has been on github for a number
of years but I'm adding a whole bunch
more to it so I'm gonna be releasing it
after the the talk so the basis for this
is something called runtime
configuration and runtime configuration
corner dates back to to the days where
you sort of had shared hosting and you
couldn't like lock down a web server for
just a particular website because
individual websites would need different
things you know you billet the board
would need something different
configured to say WordPress and for the
trivial solution to this was to allow
the users to configure their own
directives sort of still very much in
use today most CMS have htaccess file
would rewrite rules the kana exists all
over our mostly be talking about Apache
today but it's not just limited to
Apache so this is kind of an order of
morphs useful down to at least useful so
the bottom two the only directives you
can really play around with in an HT
access files for those web services
authentication which may be useful for
some attacks but it's not a quick win on
a pen test by any means so what we're
really looking to do is we're looking to
alter the configuration that the web
server has and because we're able to use
htaccess file we can alter the behavior
for that particular location where the
file is placed as well as potentially
subsequent directories so you know a
really trivial example would be to
combine it with say insecure CSRF file
upload somebody brushes to your website
you push the file now authentication is
disabled for their admin panel yeah
sandy so we'll run it through a quick
sort of idea of how Apache
functions and how these attacks sort of
exists so at the very basic concept
level a web server receives a request
and response with some content that's
really all they all this to it of course
for more enterprise ready web service
you want to have a bit more flexibility
than sort of static content so Apache
has a number of steps to sort of
processing the cycle I'm not gonna go
too in depth the the Apache project has
a lot of documentation on how this
actually occurs and certain web
application firewalls like mod rewrite
has even more information on sort of the
sequence and order of operations
backwards but essentially what happens
is it receives the requests it does like
negotiation parsing you know what
language what compression should have
sent back to the server are they asking
for a subset of just you know byte
sequence
22200 of the file because it's a
download resumption or something said
that's all this pre-processing and it
gets to handler and goes well they said
EC JavaScript a PHP script the static
file
you know don't need to do language
translation but about you can do and
then it passes it to input and output
filters and then once it's eventually
served the content it logs the data so
and it exposes hooks during each of
these stages and that's really what
Apache modules rely on so depending on
on what the module does it little hook
in different sections not super
important for for what we're discussing
today but that's how it works anyway
most of Apache is functionally comes
from modules and you can just go on the
website they have a list of like all the
modules they have a list of the
individual configuration options for the
various modules and and they also cover
this bit here which talks about where
can you use it what are the requirements
etc so the first thing that covers this
is something called context and that
means that
for certain sort of security sensitive
directives you can only use it in say
the server config so you can't you can't
reconfigured to say the SSL keys that
this web server is using you know in a
pure directory basis because it's sort
of structurally wrong and then some of
it goes down to like district this you
know server config you have to be root
to write to the files you know these
things can't be overridden and then you
just sort of dwindle down to HT access
where the I guess least important or
more directives that have a higher needs
to be reconfigured for various behavior
or purposes the other thing that's
important is is which override level you
require so again there's a bunch of
different sort of permission levels most
of the the fun attacks all depend on the
options directives that things like mod
rewrite also depends on options is
usually enabled and so just go back to
this one I'm gonna say this again
probably a number of times during the
discuss the presentation the one thing
you want to do to stop any of these
attacks
you said allow override none and then
nothing of this actually works because
you've locked it down in permissions so
now HT access force is generally
recommended not to be enabled on
production service and the reason why
it's not security sadly its performance
so say you're looking for an image of
this URL
the Apache web server will start at the
root directory and it'll look for HD
access form and each of those
directories if it finds the htaccess
file it'll parse it and then when it
reaches the end it does order of
precedence operation and kinda like
merges its into 1 configure than applies
that for that one directory so it is
pretty performance intensive but you
should also disable it for security
reasons so just twice as important so
now that we know what HT access false
are what can we actually do with them so
some of the existing attacks that I did
and obviously the one that I think she's
the most
use is just straight-up put htaccess
fall in there get a web shell run
commands you hack the server steal
passwords etc but we can do a bunch of
other things too we can coerce the web
server to leak information we can make
the web server disclose things so a good
example might be if you're able to use
for example mod rewrite to set certain
query parameters you can leak say the
the source code of PHP falls on the
server which could be handy to find
other vulnerabilities in the case that
you can't get code execution but there's
a whole bunch of different attacks and
it's kind of important that you you
understand that the the HX is for lists
it's not like it's something static it's
almost like a programming language you
you kind of configure it to do what you
want and then it does it so you can see
here we're executing commands and we're
doing this I'll go through this later on
sort of the important thing here is that
this one is done through the rewrite so
it's not there's a bunch of different
methods to make htaccess do certain
things and that's usually more than one
way to do it
so at the core the htaccess files that
are produced are polyglots so they're a
foremost they were valid htaccess fault
because if you have an invalid htx s
file apache will refuse to serve content
so they have to be valid from Apaches
person perspective typically we also
make them perform an action such as
being a PHP shell or a ruby shell or a
cgi she'll forget code execution and
because we like to see nicer output than
these stuff here I quite often put HTML
comments in there so if you open it in a
browser as opposed to the command line
you get a nice-looking interface with
the input box to run the commands etc so
yeah so there are there polyglots which
a popular choice all right so how do we
actually achieve command execution in
say HT access so access to HT access
false by default in Apache is denied so
the first thing we do is we override it
and we say for any file that starts with
H
you know typically that would be a
denial but in our case we're
reconfiguring access for this directory
so we're overriding that and saying no
you can access HT access files
incidentally this will also let you
access a HT passwords file remotely if
it did exist in the directory so you can
steal an offline crack passwords
possibly the next thing we do is we want
to we want to reconfigure Apache to
recognize that this particular htaccess
file it's not just htaccess file it's
actually a ruby file so yeah we defined
that if the module Ruby exists because
we don't want to use the directive if
the module doesn't exist because that
will break the part of the particles I
don't understand what these directives
are and you get a 500 error so by
putting in a sudden if module it's fun
and we basically go down here and we see
set handler we're just saying when
someone's accessing htaccess file just
run the Ruby code and then of course
down here we we have the Ruby code the
other thing that's kind of important is
up here we disable the built-in safety
in Ruby that lets us do evil or sorry
say command execution so if you don't
reconfigure Ruby as well you you
wouldn't get caught execution you can
still run Ruby but you know we want
shell so that's that's basically this is
it you upload it to a directory and then
you just hit the file and if mod ruby is
enabled you you will get shook alright
so like I said before there are many
ways to do this you know don't just like
grab the HT access file from the the
repo you know feel free to change it a
bit the order of operation doesn't
really matters you can shift the text
around add some spaces to break the md5
sums for you know dodgy indicators of
compromise or whatever or remove the
comments just just make it a bit
different so it sort of looks different
so now that we know how to sort of
attack a web server with the HT access
fault the biggest problem is how do you
actually get the HT access fallen on the
filesystem
biggest said it only works if it's
Apache is serving it from the local file
system so I mean the most generic
methods it just spread up form upload
yeah they'll have something like upload
an image and they'll check for are you
not allowed to upload PHP files because
you know those things are bad but they
use a blacklist and I don't put htaccess
on there and so you just pop it up and
you get show so that most of the I'd say
90% of the time that's what I do
generic method yeah some other ones
there are more I guess sort of specific
you can select into art file from SQL
injection xxe etc etc but it's not so
necessarily so important how you get it
there it's just you got to try to get it
there so yeah I said file upload most
people don't block etch the access files
and that's that's all it is
xxe very unlikely to be exploitable
because of the specific conditions a
you'd need typically an XML parser that
supports this specific behavior in
handling of jar URLs but you can
basically give in the case of a say Java
you can you give it a jar a URL to a sip
file do an exclamation mark and an
individual file man from that zip file
and it will download the zip file
extract that one file and keep it on the
file system and so if you use say
chunked encoding or whatever that'll let
you temporarily place it there
unfortunately usually ends up in places
like temp which are web accessible to
begin with so it would generally have to
be something like a router or something
that has kind of limited temporal
read/write storage and so it places a
lot of stuff in locations where they
wouldn't normally be but it is a way to
potentially do it the biggest problems
with placing a htaccess file on the
server is that you want to get one shot
most of the time they will not let you
overwrite an existing file so you know
if you didn't do
recon and you upload a PHP shell on a
server that doesn't support PHP then
you're usually out of luck there's a
couple of ways around this oneness that
you can usually combine multiple
languages in a false I actually in the
repo have a file called hash access
multi handler slang and it does I think
five different languages so as long as
any of those modules are present on the
server you uploaded you get a shell and
you don't really care where it's from it
just executing commands one of the other
ways to do it is you can remotely
fingerprint a lot of the the modules and
like ten years ago wrote this tool here
I'll be map and it has a an Apache
remote fingerprint that tool that'll
detect sort of which file extensions are
in use of which which modules are in use
so that's pretty handy to have and test
it locally before you upload the road
like Carly has Apache native so just
test it on your Kali instance or
whatever before you put it on the server
so you don't burn your access so you'd
think that with this thing been around
for a number of years and sort of being
I guess infamous for for attacking web
service there'd be some detection right
antivirus that'll keep you safe for sure
it's s on the PC our standard yeah the
first time I uploaded this was almost
three yeah two and a bit years ago still
server detects chance and of course
since you can kind of modify the files
however you see fit I'm not sure if
you're gonna get really effective
detection out of it with antivirus so
yeah web application firewalls maybe
that can stop the actual post with the
upload but if you can't stop the post
with the upload once the follow us on
the file system the Web Application
Firewall can't stop it so yeah it's it's
the wrong sort of protection methodology
this thing is written up in the in the
past couple years like web shell
detectors
I guess because people get hacked all
the time you stead unpatched a wordpress
most of us do a really terrible job and
there's a bunch of them that actually
detect my files
you called them you know web shell dot
txt it'll find it but it doesn't scan
dot false if it's called dot htaccess
and they won't detect it so and again
most of them will generally only look
for PHP faults if you put up like a ruby
one it just doesn't work so Neo P I did
this statement bunch of years ago saying
that out yeah we really should look at
this because you know we we've realized
we we would actually miss it when we're
scanning I haven't actually tested in a
bunch of years they may have added it
but again their focus is on PHP shells
so if you just sidestep that problem
then the other thing is that generally
run from like cron jobs you know like
daily weekly whatever so if you just RM
the shell when you're done man they
didn't find it this thing pops up all
over the place it's someone has
basically tried to implement the Web
Application Firewall through mod rewrite
it's a terrible idea from performance
reason and it's also basically just a
terrible idea
we'll talk talk more about this later
and then of course there's there's this
one rape on github that just has my my
handle has that's the yarra rule for
detecting malware which i think is
pretty funny but yeah so yeah remove my
name from the from the web shop before
you upload it and he will never find you
allow override none that is what you
would do as a system admin it doesn't
stop absolutely everything but damn near
everything there's some corner cases
that'll that'll fall through but you
should always do this on your on your
production service you write the config
in the in the actual server config in
the virtual host section you don't put
stuff floating around in directories
because from a QA perspective from a
security perspective from a performance
perspective they're all bad news so just
do that some myth-busting so I I feel
like a lot of people don't understand
sort of
the mindset behind this and like I said
again it's the sense of a static attacks
you know you you take HX s file you can
modify it and you can maybe you know
bypassed the intended controls etc so a
common one is uploads outside of with
Webroot is safe right if I can put a
htaccess file outside of the web root
and then then everything is fine and
that's generally true please do you put
your web or your uploads outside of the
web root but if you say run the images
through a thumbnail converter and then
have a uploads forward slash thumbnails
and that thumbnails directory is web
accessible because as we spoke about
earlier
it looks through every directory all the
way down even if it sits outside the web
root in a parent folder the config will
still apply and so you can execute code
even though the htaccess file itself
isn't web accessible all right one of
the other ones which I said before this
guy who like wrote HT access based Web
Application Firewall to stop HT access
files it just doesn't work because
whatever privileges or permissions that
htaccess file has as a parent directory
when I'm in the more specific current
directory I should be able to override
whatever it is that you're doing by
reconfiguring the local permissions and
so the only place it would work is like
if you have an uploads folder and you
put a htaccess file in there so I can't
upload one then yeah that'll probably
block it but it doesn't matter what the
content of the HD access Follis at that
point so we'll look at this from sort of
a story I can't remember those have the
year on there yeah so 2015 February I
spotted a reference to my project from
this full disclosure post and it's
basically it's a social media thing
project and they had a insecure follow
up load same thing that didn't they're
blocked by PHP or whatever but they
didn't block hates the excess and they
said the the god of the researchers who
they said you know it's fun because by
default there's a htaccess distribution
fault that comes with the project but
unless you like rename that to dot HT
access it doesn't take effect and if you
do rename it it actually breaks the use
of HT access but you said it does a
redirect match rewrite and they they
actually tried to do a rewrite engine
off and that normally it takes care of
any sort of you know mod rewrite as a
web application firewall protection so
you put that in your head sexist fault
when you upload it and then that wife
disappears because you you've disabled
it in this case there was a little bit
more specific they were using redirect
match and sort of in the Apache
internals this doesn't map directly to a
file
just us reg X on on the handler or the
parser earlier in the and in the request
parsing sequence so it never actually
arrives at like a file handler which
actually stops the use of mod rewrite so
I thought well you know we should have a
look at this revisit this bug and so I
grabbed hum hub
I put dot htaccess file in there and
yeah it didn't work I can't access dot H
access directly because the reg ex sees
it and serves the 403 error but what I
was able to do was I couldn't use a set
handler off operative I'm going to show
you the source code from this PHP or
hates access shell later and so what I
did was instead of hitting the htaccess
file directly you see here I'm hitting
an index.html which they already had in
there and and with the same query string
of course is the HT access to say no
matter which file is being served I'm
overriding the file handler to always
treat this as a PHP file oh by the way
also append this additional PHP code to
that PHP file and then yeah we get code
execution you can actually kind of see
some of the htaccess file leaking out
there
so while well they had
sort of a semi efficient protection
against it if you actually apply a bit
of logic and understand how Apache works
you htaccess false cannot protect
against hxs fault so just you just walk
around it similarly it could enable the
service status as to handler instead of
PHP and yeah I can go on for forever so
so like I said I've released this I
think six to seven years ago and there's
been a bunch of changes to Apache since
then the most notable one which I did
introduce changes for in the repo it's
like semi up-to-date on github was they
changed the authorization code so the
specific directives that you use on
Apache 2.3 and older has like allow
allow from all deny from all sort of us
like the the Corps directives and the
new one has like a require all granted
and of course if you include that
statement and you upload it to a an
older version of Apache you get
directive passing error so you you
really have to like fingerprint apache
and uncomment the one line that you need
they also added like an a low override
list which really lets you lock down the
granularity so if you have to allow
override something say you know mod
rewrite you can actually say well we
Bala will allow override options but
you're only allowed to configure like
these however using like a comma
separated list and then that way I can't
just randomly do whatever I want so that
actually locks it down as well it's it's
a great addition I don't know if it
hasn't been attribute it to me but I'd
like to take the credit for it but the
big one was we've got if statements so
now we can ever add logic to to our
htaccess files so I mean it's not quite
sure incomplete but we can do dynamic
directives so if we put in like a lot of
if statements to do if this condition
apply these directives in if this other
condition and and if you add that to
like granny
add and remove individual directives one
at a time you can build a completely
different runtime execution of the
htaccess file just paying depending on
the query string which we can't so
earlier so I wrote this here pretty
simple this this one doesn't allow you
to like stack multiple ones because if
it checks that the whole length of query
string equals you can see my really
fancy obfuscation there beats all the
web application firewalls but what you
could do is you could you could change
that to be say a regular expression or
something which would allow you to stack
multiple different configurations
directives in one query string but it's
really simple and as we saw before
rather than doing add handler something
for htaccess file we just say for any
any fault in this directory as long as
we trigger this query string that's the
handler it's going to use so so you
don't have to hit the htaccess file
directly which is kind of handy of
course again this is only valid on
apache 2 point 4 onwards you upload this
to an older version you get a 500 error
and you know you're out of luck so yeah
and as we saw just by changing there you
can probably not see that at the back
changing the query string we're getting
service status changing the query string
again we get PHP execution just really
sync them so now that we've we've done
all this you know what what am I
actually doing to make a checks
ourselves better for you know 2018 so
for Apache we're adding a bunch more of
sort of the Apache 2.4 directive dice
shells
I'm adding a new stealth shell and also
doing some syntax and a couple of
different module dependent attacks which
can do some really neat things with a
lot of privileges so I've got one that
will steal passwords or credit card
details using only mod rewrite so if you
have nothing else available on the
server you can you can still do it but
you probably you'd probably have a hard
time getting
htaccess shall on the server if it can't
run any scripts is so suroosh initially
ported the notion of HD access shells to
is any wrote like an ASP classic is web
config version that's really neat but
modern is does not support is classic so
we had added that PHP server slide
include ones but getting code execution
on iOS this is a lot trickier because in
the case of say a dotnet the directory
you're uploading into has to be defined
as an application route in the case of
PHP you need to know where the fast cgi
executable for PHP is see hopefully you
can leak bleep the path through some
sort of you know feed PHP an array and
it'll spit up an error that shows you
what the path is and then of course in
the case of server side includes they
have a set of directives to let you
execute like CGI scripts or whatever
that you can configure in web config but
for command execution you actually have
to set the registry value which again
it's hard to do remotely so here's an
example of asp.net running it's it's
almost identical to the one that did ASP
classic but yeah we're also going to
actually update it so that we don't just
do you know hello world showing it code
execution you had actual command
execution on there so you can actually
do fun stuff PHP and I don't know when
they actually did this they added
support for a pure direct directory
config in PHP and this works unlike
universally anywhere where PHP is run us
like cgi so far cgi pfm etc and it'll
work on on service that don't normally
support the per directory config so like
ng Inc slide hates 3d Heroku if you're I
asked you for that matter if you're
running PHP s like a CDI module you can
just drop a user I and I so he's another
yet another we'd fall
that you need to filter for your file
uploads so this one has some it has a
slot difficulty in in executing it
actually requires there to be a PHP
shell or sorry a PHP file any PHP file
in the directory where you're uploading
to it doesn't have to be yours and just
have to be an existing PHP file because
this is based on the notion that you
just you're just going to append this
file and then you have a comment down
there that yeah again I'm just spits up
PHP info so so yeah one other one other
thing but as I was kind of working
through some of these I had this idea
for a stealth shell so I wrote some
stealth shells with the initial htaccess
project they're kind of like hides from
logs but it still requires that you
access the web shell sort of directly
indirectly since that's not so great and
I kind of had this idea many years ago
we we were sitting on a plane on a way
to to do a CTF in Australia and we knew
that one of the one of the scoring
points was put in your team flag as like
the index page of the web server and I'm
like well what if we could like backdoor
that so even if somebody writes
overwrites the index file it'll still
display our flag
so it's messing around with it and I
found a way to make Mac htaccess file
serve my content no matter what and and
hopefully we could kind of sneak that
file in a location where they wouldn't
usually look like the root directory or
somewhere outside of web root and keep
them confused and sort of keep our team
scoring more so I can add I had this
idea you know yep we do we prepend a PHP
script and then just print our our flag
and we exit and and we don't care about
any other sort of execution that's fun
but it's it's not really a web shell so
you know a bit later well what if we
change the the post the pre execution to
the to a post execution that all worked
fine but I noticed when I was sort of
accessing the website in the browser the
browser would sit there and spin
you know like waiting for data from you
know demo site dot-com which which was
kind of not great but so what we ended
up doing is kind of thought about how
this how does the the browser process
the data that it gets and it's really
simple if you send a specific content
length and then the content that you
send matches exactly that length the
browser goes okay well I'll have all the
data that I want any closest connection
and goes away it doesn't care whether or
not the web server didn't close it so
that was pretty simple we we added some
some way oh sorry so the other thing is
when you're doing this you can't read
and write like sort of interact directly
with the web shell so you have to go out
of band for the command and control so
what we're doing here is first we're
we're saying that we want to append
hates the access whenever this thing is
running we enable output buffering and
that's very important because we want to
see what what Apache is already ready to
send and we want to stop it at the point
where sort of our our content start and
we do that Danny or the first thing we
do is we call go which is function go
down here and then it basically just it
gets the the content that's sitting in
the buffer and then clear the actual
output and then it finds because the
problem is that one character there gets
appended so we got to find that and
clean that out because we don't wanna
show up and in somebody's output then we
set the header for a content length we
set that we flush the buffer and the
browser goes away but we're still
sitting here in execution
so once the function go has finished it
gets done here and then we just we just
read remote code we do a function call
back rather than say an eval because
this is less likely to get blocked in in
PHP hardening or whatever and then we
just call that function and and that's
it so
this allows you to put this on the
server any normal request that comes in
to PHP fall on that server will execute
this in the background after it's served
the content in the users the user can't
see it and it just reads the content
from there it doesn't get logged and and
again before we actually clean all the
other content so there's there's no
additional output that's being added to
there so the log should look perfectly
normal the traffic is coming from just
normal users you know there's nothing so
unless you're doing unless you're doing
on the service side you're doing
connection tracking alright you won't
see that one there and and everything's
fun so we're gonna run a demo of this
this is sort of audience participation
I can do it myself if you don't trust me
so get a demo so here at Nesta Rabia
just another hacker.com and if you guys
want to get ready or your phones
whatever we'll we'll do a bit of an
experiment and I've got I got with me
some koala bears so sorry they're not
they're not actually bear so you're not
allowed to say koala bears have the
correct qualifications so if somebody
wants to have a chat know a koala then
let's do this so and the way this works
is I've just got a command file here you
guys hit that site and then as soon as
I'm done I'll just type in the command
to run if somebody would like to refresh
that we should yeah and it's it's
asynchronous so I'll put this in and
then yeah somebody ran it nobody's
putting anything in the query string
what's wrong with you
so yeah it's just either that or I'm not
I'm not logging so yeah just run one
more and if nobody somebody no that's
not gonna work because you're not
you're not hitting my head to excess
well good try
now this is a very specific it's pure
CNC so all right I'll just and I'll
throw this around or something you can
guys can come up and get them at the at
the end all right so we've seen that
this work it runs out of like you can't
see the website loading any different
and it just it just pulse pulse the
commands txt and the command sixties
it's actually wrapped in a PHP script
but I'm not gonna release sort of the
the CNC part of this because I'd rather
not be responsible for creating like
script kiddie web server botnets so you
gonna have to do your own code if you
plan to do that all right so conclusion
disable this thing if possible like I
said allow override none it just it
stops it of course the dot user i9 in
PHP and the the web there config is
slightly different you have to do other
things with those but I'm kind of hoping
that this will like die off pretty
quickly because luckily the advent of
DevOps and cloud it means that people
are using load balancers and elastic in
containers and when you're only serving
one web site or one web function one API
whatever it is that you have you can
afford to hard code that config
completely and you can lock it down you
can harden the PHP you can harden the
Apache config and then this will never
happen to you
so that's it any questions yeah
yeah okay so yeah in in the South the
question was in the South shot ahead
I'll just pull it up I had some junk
junk Apache directives and where is this
yeah if module of one so the reason why
we're doing that is it tells Apache
don't worry about the content inside
here unless this module exists and of
course we pick the module that doesn't
exist and then we add this this one here
to say because it still does some weed
parsing so by adding that one we we nest
out of the the Apache parsing and it
allows us to write PHP and Lakia like a
nicely formatted PHP otherwise you'd
have to have it all on one line I mean
that still works but this is a bit more
maintainable so the only reason it's
there is just for my own sanity all
right any other questions all right
thank you for your time
and yeah can't see me if you want to
koala