I so first of all thank you all for
being here this morning
I know it's a hard morning after the
party last night so I'm gonna talk to
you about detecting phishing from
passive DNS and I'm really happy that
you're all here
just for a quick recap who here knows
what passive DNS is okay we have like 10
people that's a good that's a good start
so first of all who am i my name is Erin
Adamski I'm Israeli cybersecurity
researcher I'm I I have my own company
it's called domsky tech we were welcome
to visit our website I have a few years
of experience in the industry I ran a
security research for a start-up based
out of the US I used to work for a
checkpoint and I served approximately 10
years in the Israel in military in the
intelligence forces and also I'm on
Twitter I'm on LinkedIn tweet LinkedIn
whatever I don't know what word you use
for LinkedIn so link link in whatever so
and this is my pet unicorn I have a few
of them so just be nice to them first of
all phishing
sorry it's quite bright so who here does
not know what phishing is okay that's a
very good start everyone pretends to
know what phishing is but in case you're
just pretending let's look at the
dictionary I'm sorry about the colors
let's look at the definition from
dictionary comm based on this definition
it's the fraudulent practice of sending
emails perpetuating to be from reputable
companies in order to induce individuals
to reveal personal information such as
passwords and credit card numbers have
you ever gotten the phishing Gmail okay
have you ever clicked the link okay at
least someone here admits that he did
because
most probably we all did they usually do
it in a pretty decent way and I'm not
asking if you click the link inside your
malware lab that's not interesting but
honestly a lot of time it does look like
something that might get us to click the
link because it usually looks like
something that is supposed to look like
something you want to click on right so
it might look like a page that looks
exactly like the secure login but if you
look at the URL on top on the domain on
top yell trend com is not actually
Dropbox or in this case another
assigning screen for yell trend this is
actually an email for both those
screenshots work from a phishing scam
that was running around last Saturday so
a lot of times it looks like it but it
shouldn't look like it so remember that
sometimes the content is very very
different from the domain that is
actually used for the attack itself so
yes who here doesn't know what DNS is ok
good start
so DNS is that a main name system it's
not a domain name server it's the domain
name system so when I say DNS server
it's actually legitimate I'm not
repeating the same word twice it was
first introduced in an RFC from 1983 by
Paul Moka Peters and since it was
updated a few times it's mainly UDP
traffic on port 53 it's mainly because
there are some traffic that goes over
TCP there are alternative ports so if
you're trying to sniff your network and
find all the DNS traffic you should
basically look for everything on port 53
and not limited to just UDP and it's
basically used to translate the main
names into IP addresses and making your
life easier what can you do with it
you can assign friendly names to IP
addresses chances are you're not gonna
remember the IP address of my webs
but if al repeats domsky tech enough
times you might remember that and you
might even wind up going to my website
at the end of this presentation you
should you can create commercial or
non-commercial entities on the internet
that are then used to attract people you
can become a registry or a registrant
and you can buy sell and auction domain
names and make money out of it and on
the other sides of it you can share the
information that you get from your DNS
traffic with friendly or less friendly
entities so you can share it with
governments you can share it with
customers you can share it with other
partners that will possibly or probably
track you and do things with it so maybe
gdpr will help you a little bit but
that's maybe not gdpr for the wine and
you can use this data to build your
products so if you have your own DNS
data you can use that in order to
protect your organization using your own
data and this is actually what we're
gonna be talking about later on in this
presentation just a few definitions in
fqdn is a fully qualified domain name
every fqdn is unique in the IP space
hey sorry in the domain space so it's
only one fully qualified domain name
that looks exactly like this and it has
several parts that are a part of every
domain name so going from the end at the
end you have the dot it's usually
omitted because it represents the root
servers and it's in every domain name so
we don't bother then the next part is
the TLD it's the top-level domain and it
represents the big chunk of information
and what root server you should be
accessing to get the information about
then you have the secondary domain and
that would be the actual website you're
trying to access and then third fourth
fifth tenth level domains and it's the
lowest and
most left hand label of the domain those
are the host or the subdomains so
basically a domain is a collection of
labels separated by dots and if you look
at www.thatsgreatnews.com
in this case on the bottom case it's
actually the third level domain but it
behaves like an acyl D it's the
important part of that I mean and then
you have the subdomains or hosts so what
is a domain basically a domain is a
sequence of 8-bit value and every 8-bit
value is valid for it so you can use any
character you actually want to use as
long as you remember that on the SLD
underscores are prohibited on the lower
levels on the sub level sub domains you
are actually allowed to use underscores
although it's not highly recommended
also there are some T of these that
prohibit use of ID and characters
international characters so sometimes
you can not use those in the primary
domain name on the wire in the wild
domains are allowed to have up to 256
characters and each label is up to 64 so
you cannot have stuff that it's
extremely long and as I've mentioned
before there are some public suffixes
that behave like TL is there is a full
list of those you can find those you can
use those in your systems it's off
and ID and international domain strings
those are translated in our logs into
regular ASCII and those will always
start with X and - - so if you're seeing
something like that in your blog it
means that it actually had a character
that's not a English or a Roman
character sorry let's talk about T
oldies gTLD is the generic TLD is the
ones that we all know and love or
dot-com dotnet dot e-d-u have been with
us forever and a few years ago new geo
deal no new gTLDs were introduced stuff
like dot tech dot paypal moscow you can
actually register a TLD for your
business so for example PayPal might one
day register people and when I say one
day it takes about two years currently
to approve a new TLD with I can I can is
the organization to transfer their
domain system and they're working on it
and hopefully once people will finally
register that TLD they'll start sending
emails from customer support dot paper
instead of PayPal - customer support
comm which looks like fishing then those
are the new ones you can apply for them
and you can get those the CCT of these
have also been around for quite a while
those are country code is you have dot
PL dot and L dot C C dot C C is for
Cocos Islands it's actually a legit
country not just a spam trap right and
you have the ID ins so stuff like Hong
Kong and Egypt Asian scripts Arabic
scripts are the most common ones that
use IDN domain names but it's also
available in Kerala scripts in Hebrew
scripts and in any other language that
you want so finally we're getting some
more passive DNS so
passive DNS was invented in 2004 by
Florine Famer and it's basically a
historical database of your DNS
resolutions so the way you collect it is
basically not asking a DNS server for a
resolution for a given domain but you
are looking at stuff that people asked
in the past it's usually collected using
multiple sensors on the internet and it
is as I said passively collected so it
means that if there are domains that are
not accessed it will not be in your
dataset if their domains are not
accessed from a point that is covered by
a sensor it will not be in your data set
so and that's also the reason that the
data changes based on the database that
you're looking at so if two different
vendors are two different collections
look at this the Internet traffic it
will be built using their sensors and
those sensors based on geographical
locations or and a user behavior will be
different as an example I'm sorry about
the resolution it looks better on my
computer so this is an example for my
website I took it from passive total the
day after I registered my website and
all those circle Lu passive DNS is
marked here as one of the sources that
passive table should be looking for the
resolution it has no hits so no one from
Luxembourg accessed my website in the
first 24 hours it was a very very
hurtful truth to find out I told the few
people I know in Luxembourg that that's
not a que so they went to the website
the next date was fixed so if you google
Google if you look up my website it's
okay now but on the bright side I got a
slide out of it so everything's alright
so ways of collecting passive DNS and
this is something that we
should remember because you can do it at
home you can do it on your own network
so one way of collecting passive DNS is
using sensors that you set up in the
network and in this way you usually
place those sensors above your course
averse over that way you will not get
the source IP of whoever made the query
so if you're looking within your
organization you don't want you don't
really care for passive DNS who is the
user that was looking at a specific
website what you want to know is at a
given time what the resolution what IP
he got and what server he queried so
usually it's above the recursive
resolver it is only cache misses because
the recursive resolver saves a lot of
data in its cache to save on traffic
you only get live traffic so again as
I've mentioned earlier if no one went to
that website it will not be recorded if
no one opened the fish email were you
fished so and the first time that you'll
see something in your data set will be
the first time that someone actually
went to that website the other way of
collecting passive DNS it's less common
and it is also used by some of the
vendors but it's not something that I
would recommend doing at home is a
collecting passive DNS using scraping of
zone files so every time a domain is
assigned a new IP address the zone file
for the DNS servers is updated and the
information is recorded on the servers
so if you're going to scrape those
servers you will be able to get that
information in this case you are not
connected to user traffic so basically
in this case every domain that was
assigned an IP address will be recorded
in your passive DNS collection on the
other hand you will only be getting
information from the teal DS that are
publishing their zone transfers so the
generic deal is both old and new are
regulated by ICANN and they are
obligated to publish their zone
transfers and every time they update a
zone that is released
cctlds are actually some sort of wild
wild west they are not obligated to do
that they have a little bit different
restrictions than the regularity of
these so approximately half of them do
not comply with this rule of publishing
all zone transfers so you will not be
able to use this technique on all of
them also another problem with using the
sensors sensors crate zone file scraping
as a passive DNS collection method is
the fact that you can only collect
information from the first and secondly
very servers so if I'm using a local
name server I am not obligated to
publish the zone files so you will not
be getting information about subdomains
and sub sub sub domains you will only
get those on the primary domains and
that's about it so in this case though
you will be getting information about
the domains based on updates that are
actually happening so once the webmaster
or the main master reassigned the
address to a new IP address that will be
logged in your database int has nothing
to do with user traffic so there is a
benefit on that side as well but again
you will also be getting information
about the domains that no one actually
accessed so it's like blog posts
basically if I wrote a blog post it's
out there on the internet no one read it
is it interesting so it's the same thing
here first time is the time of mapping
not the time of access so two different
methods and it's important to remember
both of them if you don't want to
collect your own passive DNS you can buy
it from a variety of vendors a Farsight
wrist aqune at lab these over all of
these vendors
a little bit of a different data set
some of them do not sell it as a data
set they give it access to researchers
but for example MATLAB 360 gives a dirt
dataset based on the fact that they
collect mainly Chinese traffic is very
different from the data sets that you
will get from other vendors if you don't
want to pay for it you can actually
build it at home do it yourself sort of
way just get a lot like a shitload of
storage if you are trying to do that you
have to scrape all of your port 53
traffic and all of your DNS server logs
in once you do that you save into your
database tuples of domains and IPS per
times span so first time I saw this
domain resolved to this IP was at X
hundred hours in whatever timestamp and
the last time I saw it on this timestamp
was at that time and every time it
changes you add in new tupple additional
information that you want to probably
save is what domains our DNS server gave
me this information because if I got
this information from Google or I got it
from quad 9 or from CloudFlare and they
gave me different results
that's interesting another information
you'd wants to know is where did you
make this query from you don't care who
the user is but it's interesting to know
that if you're making this query from
China or from London or from the UK from
the US you're getting different results
so that's also a major data piece that
you might want to keep so now that we've
covered both phishing because we all
knew what it was some DNS magic and some
passive DNS let's talk about symptoms of
phishing so I'm gonna give you a list of
symptoms that we're gonna talk about
each and every one of them so I'm not
gonna stay long in this slide so let's
move on and basically before I go back
to the symptoms I just want to say this
whole research was
possible thanks to access to the farside
data and what I did is basically I
queried that data with a label for
Microsoft so I was looking for all the
domains that are Microsoft dot something
everything that starts with the word
Microsoft I wasn't looking for stuff
that has Microsoft somewhere in the
center only the beginning and I limited
my search for the past 24 hours I got
almost 7500 domains guess what Microsoft
doesn't own 7500 domains with the word
Microsoft that are accessed on a daily
basis so let's just look at it basically
the first symptom of phishing is when
you have multiple labels multiple sub
labels so once you have more than two
subdomains or subdomain or most
legitimate services usually use only one
so you'd use WWE or website or blog your
website or something your website maybe
sometimes you use two sub labels but
that even that's not common so two is
already a little bit suspicious if you
have more than five of those that's
likely a phishing website or not
necessarily fishing but something
malicious if you have more than 10
labels I call it I put it in the
category I've never ever seen it being
non malicious I covered that sometimes
I've seen those things being non
malicious but their error ously created
by scripts that people write so
sometimes that happens once you do that
you have to remember that you also have
2y plus the results because there are
websites that actually give you results
on your queries a by appending your
query as a sub-label so in this case who
is bucket is a service that gives you
information of who is informations for
domain names and it does that by
appending the
main you asked for with the to the
beginning of your website so Microsoft
CEO al is actually a legitimate
Microsoft website that is used in Israel
and who is bucket is returning the
information so once you look at that you
need you see okay who is bucket is
legitimate I'm gonna whitelist it I'm
not gonna look at it the next example
will be repetitive labels so if you see
the same label over and over and over
again there must be some reason for it
I'm not exactly sure where it is but
it's usually malicious as as examples
there is this wonderful thing of
microsoft.com to terror that blue screen
to critical error don't touch your
computer it mate gets crashed and that
not only appears like as a good example
for the previous symptom of multiple sub
labels but it also appears twice so I
have nothing to say about that but shrug
another example is the Microsoft asp.net
something Microsoft asp.net team so we
have the same sub label or sequence of
sub labels and it is a phishing domain
again
com appears multiple times in the bottom
example that shouldn't be happening
that's a really big symptom of something
going wrong with that domain suspicious
deal this so well there are till these
there are prone to have more
maliciousness in them we know that
and it happens both on utilities that
sell you the main names that you can buy
and register for one cent per year and
it happens also on some of the legacy
and old ccTLDs so in examples for the
CCT of these there are prone to that
would be i am for india or russian till
these and then there is also as I said
the example of new TLDs so when I was
looking at the domains that I
grabbed from the passive they ride got
7500 domains a hundred seventy two of
them war with X Y Zed 163 with download
138 with review and here's the example
of review domains on the left
none of those 138 domains was legitimate
so it's a good sign if you're giving
scores to domains that if it's using a
new TLD that's prone for maliciousness
and sells domains for cheap it might be
malicious so as an example dot tak sells
domains for 40 bucks in a year it's not
very cheap and it's not very worth your
while to pay that much money for domain
for fishing or for CNC that will be
taken down very quickly so you can
actually give scores on the to the T of
these based on their prices the next
thing I've mentioned would be - and tail
DS so actually till these are usually
either a word and do not contain any
characters other than actual letters but
sometimes you actually see in a domain
name com - something or a de - something
and that is in my opinion only there to
make people get confused and believe
that that domain is actually
illegitimate well it's not so if you see
stuff like microsoft.com dot de if it
would have ended there that might be a
legitimate website but Microsoft comm
Dody - flew 9 whatever goes on that's
not so just imagine that a lot of
websites are actually using for example
Microsoft calm romantic so a lot of
websites using stuff like Microsoft calm
slash and
the path for the URI that you're
accessing just replace the slashes with
dots and then use something like a
Microsoft com dot something dot
something dot something dot something
dot something dot some domain.com a lot
of people won't even notice that their
URL was transferred into a domain name
and when I'm saying a lot of people I
mean my grandma I'm not saying it that
savvy technical savvy people won't you
might you might not it's it's designed
to confuse you but a lot of normal users
will definitely fall for that type of
decoy and I actually did leave the
microsoft.com - Melissa malicious attack
that info because it's just a lovely
domain name and I think that they say
exactly what they are so it's a great
example so the next one is DNS list and
actually a it's an algorithm or a tool
that was developed by a Polish guy who
is not here right now unfortunately but
it includes also type of squads so
basically it's a github repo it's on
github it might be on microsoft.com in a
few weeks so I don't know but you can go
and download that and it's a really
really cool tool that checks a lot of
permutations for your domain name so it
will try to add letters to it so for
example it will check Microsoft a
Microsoft be Microsoft see Microsoft
seven and check if that is registered it
tries to omit letters and maybe some
people will try to access em soft like
Microsoft without the I because they
forgot to type it in and if that's a
website then they might actually get
there it tries to switch letters and use
FD T F instead of F T and stuff like
that
it uses type of squats so who isn't the
fact that the screen is not very sharp
at the moment it's actually really good
for my example because it makes the RN
look like an M so suddenly if you have
tried ever tried to go to website RN
icesoft
you actually get to a fake Microsoft
website or you used to at least in the
past CL looks like dcj looks like a G
and so on we all know the zero and one
Oh substitution but V V actually turns
into a W who thought about that right so
those things are actually very popular
and are actually used in quite a lot of
domain names and there was a there is
actually a feed that's available from
for Vistaprint domains that used to have
like on a daily so Vistaprint was a
registry that allowed you to register
the main name for free for the first 30
days they did not ask for your credit
card info they did not verify your name
they did not verify it nothing they just
told you okay get this domain name and
after 30 days pay for it guess who used
it so they had like thousands of
malicious domains of thousands of type
of squats registered on a daily basis so
there is a feed that's actually looking
for those and sharing those it's
available online so DNS twist type of
squats here's an example this is also an
example from last Saturday so May 26
it's very new but Twitter and in this
example the eye has two dots on top and
the e has an accent a some people won't
even notice the difference when they're
looking at the domain name in a URL but
once you click on Twitter and you get a
screenshot like you get the login screen
to LinkedIn you should be suspicious
like you already thought about getting a
really really good decoy as a URL
do your work seriously and that's been
the example that I was heading to and
that's make sure it scripts so basically
most cases you use only one language for
when you type in a domain name so it
will be like Latin letters or you can
use a IDN domain so you can use Japanese
Chinese Arabic whatever a lot of times
you see eBay with an accent on an e that
shouldn't happen that is already a sign
that this domain might be malicious
so in far Asian countries in India in
Japan stuff like that they do actually
use both English and Japanese characters
and both Indian characters it is
something that happens it's not very
common so for me when i'm auram ating
this whole thing if i see two different
scripts within one domain name i'm
giving it a suspicious score and here
are more examples that you can't
actually see because of the resolution
I'm sorry the slides will be available
later you can check it out at home so
another example for some type of squads
that I got really mad at is basically on
Disneyland because there are things you
shouldn't be yeah you should be fishing
you shouldn't be scamming you should not
be hacking the database for or leaking
the database for the Hello Kitty fan
club it's like it's just mean so same
year if you are hacking the Disneyland
or fishing the Disneyland Ferriss
website I kind of hate you
but I also want to show that I can't
show this for some this so there are
multiple different twists that you can
have for Disneyland calm and most of
them are not yet registered so if you
actually wants to fish these mail
go ahead yeah dozens of those and if I'm
this one is actually is Disneyland so if
you want to go to Disneyland it it's
available on this website this is the
name server and this is the output of
the DNS twist algorithm so just want to
show that once you get all those scoring
features you should give those some sort
of a score you can give the suspicious
like ten points they very likely you get
20 points the category of there's no way
in hell that's not phishing will get 50
and then you sum those and you get a
score and suddenly you just look at the
results and like yeah this is phishing
like it has to be there there's no other
option but sometimes as I said you also
have to look at those things and
remember that things like who is bucket
should be white listed so before you
actually go ahead and block those
results in your network look at them at
least for a while this at the beginning
and check out what you're getting don't
forget that this whole thing I've
started it based on a keyword so I
already started it with using the word
Microsoft if I were to start by looking
at things only based on the features of
the domain so I was pouring the labels I
would be scouring the teal days and I
did not have a label that resembles the
word Microsoft that would have an
initial lower score so if you have a
dictionary of brands that might be
fished or scammed that already gives you
a good starting point so if you're
looking for scams about your
organization that's where I'm heading
some future work that's relevant for
this is for example implementing machine
learning on
and once you implement machine learning
on these features you will be able to
catch stuff that is not based on a
specific label but I also want to stress
out that you don't have to use machine
learning machine learning is a cool and
awesome technology I'd say but this is a
very simple thing that you can do on
data that you have it within your
network and you don't have to over
complicate everything
we love over complicating things in
security where researchers and we feel
that if we do something difficult then
we won we don't have to sometimes the
simplest thing will get you to the best
results just think about that when
you're designing a system it's
interesting to also follow up on the
clusters behind that information so I
got a lot of different domains if I'll
check to which I piece they resolve and
I see that I have a bunch of IP domains
that result is some same IP or the same
network or the same s that's a sign that
that IP or a s are prone to
maliciousness and maybe I should block
that and maybe new domains that will be
registered and pointed towards that IP
should already be marked as suspicious
it's also true about name servers so
it's much easier and much cheaper to buy
domains dedicated domains if you're
buying a dedicated name server that's
expensive that is not something you
throw away the next day so a lot of
times specifically the example of DGA
domains for malware the name servers are
used dedicated so once you figure out on
a DGA
what name servers are used you can block
those and then all of the future domains
from that DGA will be blocked that's a
pretty neat feature because in that case
instead of blocking a hundreds and maybe
thousands of domains and change on a
daily basis it's just luck one name
server maybe - well - because you always
have a primary and secondary
the sizes and the amount of rules that
you have to control much more you also
can follow up on who is or you could
until last week I'm not sure what we
will be able to do with Whois
information now with gdpr but it's gonna
be interesting so actually so far they I
can I can said that registries are still
obligated to collect GDP a Whois
information but actually a registry from
Germany announced last week that
that we're not gonna do that
it violates GDP are so there's a lot of
discussion about it and I can actually
submit it a lawsuit about that because
you have to have information about who
registered this domain and this
information might not be available to
the public and you might be obligated to
handle it with a specific care and with
specific love and the emotions but you
have to collect that information so
since this registry decided that they're
not gonna collect this information they
are already being sued so we'll see I'm
like following up on that with some
poker and just let's see what's happened
so this research was done solely on on
DNS data but what happens if we actually
look at those domains that we caught and
actually go and scrape the webpage
that's behind them can we see
interesting elements that are collected
from there so just as a example but if
I'm using google analytics trackers or
cookies and I'm you I've used it on one
web bed website every other website
where I'll use it is probably gonna be
bad as well so it's also a very
interesting part of the content of the
web page on the phishing course in
site that I would like to follow up on
I'd also like to see if based on the DNS
data that I've collected can I actually
do some attribution and can I actually
find who's behind this
so just in this example so I've seen
specifically in this example I've seen a
few dozen domains that had the same
beginning so I'm not saying like
Microsoft comm and saying microsoft.com
dot label dot label 2 dot label 3
something random and I had like a dozen
of those and what I know is that all of
those domains are belong to the same
fishing kit so basically it was hard
coded within the actors code and within
their system to use that substrate
substring as a subdomain and all they
have to do is just change the domain
that they're actually registering once
their domain is been compromised so
we've been doing this research for years
on the URI part so we know that a lot of
CNC servers use the same exact URL but
only change the domain name are they
doing the same on the domain but on the
other side on the left side instead of
the right spoiler alert they do and we
should follow up on that right and again
it's the same thing can the fishing kit
be recognized based on that data and not
only the actor it's off so that's
basically it it's a pretty simple
technique to find malicious
maliciousness using a pretty simple data
set that we all can collect or buy if we
want and I hope you enjoyed it thank you
questions yep
so passive dns is actually a collection
of resolutions so not exactly sure what
you mean but it's basically who tries to
access this domain so the resolution of
a domain to an IP you need to be
somewhere in the middle between the user
who asks for this resolution and the DNS
server yeah indeed but is there already
I don't know cloud service that will
give such possibility so if my let's see
like my domains in the then so basically
you have platforms like passive total
that give you access to different
passive DNS databases and you can query
them and I think this is what you mean
I'm not sure let's talk about it later
and I'm just not sure the question thank
you thank you anyone else thank you have
a great lunch
[Applause]