hello hello everyone really get to be
here today
welcome to the SONA I think you're lucky
because it's not that hot yet and the
UBS coffee stand has already opened so
we caffeinated yeah we'll be talking
about defense and tech techniques for
modern web applications
this is Michaela I'm Lucas we're both
working in a special focus area at
Google in Zurich the last you know two
or three years we basically focused on
stuff like content security policy we
did a year of research it was a really
bad shape and we tried to get it working
at Google which was a very interesting
task and we wanted to share some of our
things and lessons we learned but we
also want to talk about a shiny new
stuff some of that is not even fully
Specht yet but it's kind of very
promising in our eyes to you know
mitigate some of the current and
upcoming threats in web applications
these days so we will start with content
security policy I just want to get a
super quick feeling for who few kind of
have heard about it before maybe just
raise your hands so I know that awesome
there are some people here that have
heard about it exactly and so for the
others I'll do like a super quick
run-through like not more than two or
three minutes so you basically get an
idea what the first part is about so
content security policy is in theory as
simple as a response header for HTTP
responses it's interpreted by the
browser and it can be used by developers
to lock down the application in certain
ways most importantly to highlight here
this is a defense-in-depth mechanism
right so it's not a replacement for
secure coding practices nor for doing a
careful input validation or output
encoding of user or attacker provided
content right so it's
safety net if you have a critical
application like a banking app or Gmail
right there's a lot of secure coding
practices but every now and then because
the copay this is so big there will be a
bark right there will be across the
scripting issue and it's very good to
have something that protects the user in
the case that you have missed something
in your product what is USB not it's all
it's not a mechanism to prevent a data
exfiltration I have a slide later on
that but we're just seeing it used as
that quite often in practice so I just
just wanted to bust some myths here CSP
is terribly complex it's around four I
don't a lot many years now
and over time they have you know they
were adding new stuff to the spec and
it's basically doing a lot of things
unfortunately not very well for most of
the cases but if you know the pitfalls
you can use it in a very powerful way
and this is something we will talk about
today I'll just highlight the most
important use cases - might be a dress
as well first of all cross scripting
this is web threat that we are still
facing nowadays there's good frameworks
that help you to prevent it - have from
the first place but there's a lot of
legacy apps and there's other cases
where you will still have XSS and at
Google it's still the number one big
issue that is reported by external
security researchers so far especially
for us it's a big concern and we're
actually want to use CSP to address that
then you piece if you can also use CSP
to restrict UI stuff that's a bit
advanced but in theory you can for
example also build you know a tool that
X filtrates password just with CSS
selectors I have a slide on that later
so we can also restrict UI elements and
then just completely different use cases
to the you know loading resources main
use case
he was designed for they kept adding new
keywords to CSB because it was like a
very convenient delivery mechanism so
for example it can also use it to
upgrade in seeker requests or to you
know just block everything that is not
HTTP that's also kind of convenient to
guarantee like a lower bound of security
but it's not in the focus of our talk
today and you can also restrict framing
like in the sense of like which frames
you can load or which frame ancestors
you can like you can be loaded in just
like mostly for click checking you can
do it for you know content served like
if you serve user content you could set
like a default source none to prevent
any active content to be rendered and SS
mentioned before some people also use it
to try to prevent data exfiltration by
just you know disallowing some fetch
actions but just workarounds for that
and we'll show a couple of examples
later the main use case is as I
mentioned mitigation against cross-site
scripting we did a CCS study two two and
a half years ago four years ago and we
basically used the Google web crawler to
find all the CSPs in the internet that
were publicly accessible and they were
all of them were like kind of whitelist
based I will talk about that in a second
and these policies can be with some
rules very easily be black bypassed like
even in an automatic way so we came up
with a couple of rules and built a tool
that was able to bypass like more than
94% of the policies automatically and
for us this was the time every said okay
white this base policies are probably
not going to scale we have to do
something different and this is when we
basically switch to nonce policies and
we also edit a strict dynamic to the
spec to actually make it work in
practice I'll have a word on that in a
second as well so we're talking about a
couple of flavors of CSPs that can
protect against XSS or can't just like
the right list based ones you basically
have a script source that controls which
scripts can be loaded and the whitelist
one is for example
just a check so google.com so the
browser will only be allowed to load
scripts from that address right
these can be trivially bypassed then
there's like an on space this piece is
similar but you have a random nonce I'll
show you in a second how that works and
only script tags that have this non
substitute matching the one in the CSP
will be executed and then then you can
also use hashes so you can hash an eland
script put the hash in the policy and
only if the hashes match the
corresponding script will be executed so
super quick intro how does a trivial why
at least CSP work on the right side you
have a content security policy response
header sent to the browser and on the
left side you have what the HTML markup
is trying to do so in this example you
have for example a script here yep comm
and since yep top comm is on the script
was write list it will be allowed to
load by the browser if you have a markup
injection box somewhere like a XSS write
and attacker injects a new script tag
from attacker calm the browser will say
attacker.com is not on my whitelist I'll
block it so I will not execute same for
inline scripts they will be blocked as
well
because in order to they're like
generally blocked in a whitelist
scenario unless you have unsafe inline
which is completely which competitive
finds like basically makes your policy
completely useless in the first place
but yeah so don't do this because this
is like civilly broken there's a paper
there's a lot of bypasses we have
covered that in the past two years just
a summary but I mean just hosting anger
and loading angular and your domain can
be enough to bypass the CSP if you use
white lists it's very bad non-space CSP
is much better in that regard
you basically just define random notes
and all script tags on the page must
have this nonce
as an attribute and only if they match
the tag will be executed by the browser
there's a big advantage you don't have
to come up with a whitelist
so your application will
not randomly break if you change paths
which happens quite often in practice
unfortunately and there's no JSONP like
bypasses and it's usually much easier
and better to do it this way so these
will execute because they have the
random nonce same as in the policy these
nonce has to be random for every single
response right otherwise the attacker
can guess it or knows it right an
attacker can inject script tags but it
does he does not or don't know the nonce
attribute so again the browser will not
execute it what's the problem with that
the problem is if you load a Twitter
widget or a I don't know +1 button or
whatever other JavaScript library that
dynamically creates script tags right it
will fail because the Twitter library if
it does create element script does not
know the nonce on the page or it could
find out what they don't set it on the
child script so it will break a lot of
things if he news nonce only policy in
fact not only policies have been around
for years but no one is using them
mostly because of this reason so what we
did we work together with chrome folks
and the w3c people and we added a
keyword that is called strict dynamic I
know the name is bit weird but yeah it
is but the idea is if a script tag on
the page has announced it's already
trusted by the developer right so if
that script tag creates new script tags
that will be transitively blessed by the
browser so you can basically propagate
trust to child scripts this is very
convenient because suddenly you can use
nonce only a nonce policy with dynamic
with almost no refactoring on the page
and in fact this is what we did at
Google very successfully and the thing
is there's a lot of backward
compatibility quirks as well you can do
so it works actually quite well and in
addition to that it also discards the
whitelist so developers can not we can
up the policy in the sense that you are
basically by possible again which is a
nice property
the thing is it only allows scripts that
are created through the the Dom API like
be a great element script it does not
allow scripts dynamically created
scripts to be blessed if they are rated
for like a parser inserted sync like
document writer in HTML will not be if
you create a script with that it will
not be blessed by strict dynamic so this
is like to make the adoption easier
right but it comes at a cost if the
attacker or the there's like user
provided input here instead of a
constant he right
you could bypass the policy but this is
like a special nobility compared to all
the other cases that are basically
blocked by by default right like it's
all the reflected XSS all the stored XSS
is basically blocked so there's a couple
of trade-offs and guarantees you can get
depending what you do with non-space CSP
there is like deployment difficulty
going up and security guarantees going
up the further you move up the pyramid
on the bottom you have a non space CSP
with strict dynamic and unsafe Evo this
gives you already quite a lot of
guarantees for very easy rollout
properties as well so there's no CSP
whitelist bypasses there's no reflect
classical reflected stored XSS because
the nonce is not known to the attacker
JavaScript your eyes will always be
blocked and it's kind of easy to deploy
if you maybe have a templating system
which also automatically nonce this
script tags you should use a
context-sensitive templating system
though otherwise you should you know you
might known the script tag that has user
input in it so that's also not cool the
other thing is but it's not so good
there's some some Dom exercises are
covered like inner HTML sinks right but
others like Dom XSS will control the
source of a script are not covered by
this policy
and also if you have unsafe evil and you
have some user using evil and does user
input users also not covered so you can
move up you can also prevent an evil
from being used some people can do it
some libraries need it unfortunately
very kind of working on killing it at
Google but it's still around importantly
and even better is if you use nonsense
only but you can only do that if you
control the full JavaScript stack right
if you load libraries from somewhere
else and they don't do nonce passing
like if they do create element script
and they don't to set nonce get nonce
from parents like if they don't manually
pass the script on this will break so
this requires a lot of refactoring of
your code base we're currently working
on that at Google and the nice thing is
it gives you even more security
guarantees for Dom XSS as well right
but I have to say this one is already
quite strong for most use cases there
are some exceptions if you use some
JavaScript frameworks which do like
symbolic execution on top of JavaScript
yes and our right corner is widely
spaced CSP like just don't use it
there's only very very very few
instances where you can use that in the
same way here's examples how a policy
would look like in these scenarios these
policies don't have fall backs you can
add browser fall backs to basically make
the policy gracefully if you know allow
everything if you come with like a
outdated browser like IE
or something right you don't want users
to break or maybe you won't I don't know
yeah so that's that and CSP free is
actively developed just a couple of
interesting new keywords being added
which we wanted to briefly mention
there's unhatched attributes
unsafe unhealthy attributes which
basically allows you to have inline
event handlers in the markup if you hash
them because with normal CSP inline
event handlers are kind of blocked so
you need to refactor a lot of code
so if you have I don't know again like
some third-party widget or some code
base which you cannot really touch and
there's like you know two event handlers
which you can't refactor you could hash
them and put use unsafe hash attributes
to allow it it is a of course a
trade-off right you will lower security
slightly because attackers can inject
this event handler in other items right
so they maybe could change some actions
but on the other hand you will still get
a lot of protection for like Dom XSS and
the other things right so it still
raises the bar and it's probably better
than not having a CSP at all but yeah I
mean I would only use it if fighters
like no other way around it right and
then there's another feature which is
unsafe inline attributes this is a
proposal and not implemented yet there's
a big difference between style blocks
and inline Styles so you can also use
CSP to restrict style source this was
like the UI attack vector I showed you
at the beginning
usually developers love inline styles so
if you don't allow unsafe inline for
style source your application will
probably break or you spend like the
rest of your time to refactor developer
code to move out styles or into style
blocks right so the idea is you can use
unsafe inline attributes which means you
will not have to refactor inline Styles
so this will work but all the inline
script blocks will need to be nonce
or hashed sorry will need to be hashed
so or no yeah also announced so the
thing is why does it make sense style
blocks have more power than inline
Styles for example there's a
proof-of-concept on github that is like
basically a CSS key logger and this key
logger needs CSS free query selectors
and these query selectors only work in
style blocks so by forcing developers to
hash on
style blocks an attacker cannot inject
any other style blocks if you have a
markup injection vulnerability right and
yeah
it's a trade-off because you could still
inject arbitrary UI elements with
arbitrary inline styles but you cannot
exfiltrate user passwords right it's a
very interesting proof of concept is
linked at the bottom I should totally
check it out and I promise the slide on
why not use CSP for data exfiltration
the TLDR is as soon as you can execute
scripts it's game over anyway right so
the the main goal is prevent script
execution in the first place otherwise
you have lost as a you know defender in
this case so if you have script
execution it doesn't really help you if
the CSP blocks you know images and fonts
and everything to prevent you from
basically exfiltrating the cookie that
you have stole because just like so many
other ways that are not governed by CSP
to actually exfiltrate data so for
example you could just write a link tag
evil.com
append to cookie and then click it right
so that would exfiltrate the cookie back
to evil.com and since navigation is not
part of CSP it cannot block it so
there's a lot of other possibilities
like postmessage DNS prefetch window dot
open you can use all of these to
exfiltrate data so the main goal really
should be prevent the attacker from
gaining script access in the first place
don't try to prevent data exfiltration
because it ideally it slows the attacker
down a bit but it's not a real it's not
a strong education gives you a false
sense of security right very briefly CSP
at Google with this non-space DSPs we
were basically able to roll out CSP so
far to over 50% of all the outgoing
traffic all the important applications
like accounts of google.com Gmail Drive
they have it it was a lot of work
but this would not have been possible
with the vitalist only approach right
also the whitelist only approach was not
very secure
like he doesn't was not yielding many
security guarantees and yeah we keep
working on it the goal would be hundred
percent but that's a bit unrealistic we
basically focus on the on the high-value
targets right very very important data
lives in and yeah we are also currently
trying to remove unsafe evil just still
a couple of libraries which we have to
refactor to not use evil in the first
place so we can block it for the entire
domain and we also working on teaching
libraries to do manual nouns passing
since we are in the lucky position to
control the entire travel script
ecosystem so we can use not only
policies but again the strict economic
ones are for the use case we have here
quite strong we don't have any crazy
libraries that inject like any gadgets
that could bypass strict dynamic usually
so for our use case it's quite good and
of course during this journey we also
developed a lot of tools which I
recommend using there's a CSP - a balla
eater if google calm it basically you
paste our CSP and usual tell you in how
many ways it is broken so if there's
anything red you have problem so if you
developing a web app and you want to
roll out CSP maybe run it through here
you'll get some ideas how to improve it
maybe and internally we also have a lot
of tools that power CSP violation
reports coming back from the browsers
because this is like a giant a really
huge task because there's so much noise
by browser extensions and antivirus is
injecting you know weird scripts on
every page causing violations everywhere
so this is basically a two views
internally to crunch down the violations
to deduplication noise reduction it's a
bit fuzzy but yeah and with that I will
hand over to my colleague Michaela
we'll talk about all the other new hi hi
everyone thanks for coming so numerous I
know you guys but it's really hot so
thanks again okay so CSP at Google is
I'll say like that the king of web
mitigations the most important one the
most valuable we have mostly because we
are focused in mitigating cross-site
scripting XSS but there are other very
promising web mitigation techniques that
are a little known and with this second
part of the talk we hope to to solve
that to actually create awareness of the
existence of these tools that you as a
webmaster as a web developer can use to
further secure your your website or in
some cases there will be browser
settings so some some browser settings
especially chromium that you can enable
to have some extra layer of security if
you have any questions about CSP or any
of the web mitigations please save them
for later we'll be very happy to answer
any doubts some of those are already in
production some are being developed so I
will for everyone I will say what is the
browser support like which browsers
support which so the first one is sub
resource integrity or SR I this is kind
of old web mitigation technique or a
hardening if you will authorize more of
a hardening so it ensures that resource
is hosted on a third party server have
not been tampered with so for example if
you include a script tag with a third
party JavaScript and the third party
server gets compromised this means that
it is basically exercised on your domain
like the D hackers can host whatever
JavaScript
and on your website so for example some
very high-value target would be city
ants that for example hosts jQuery or
very common JavaScript libraries you
just include them but if they get
compromised they can execute malicious
JavaScript on your website so a possible
solution is to add the integrity
attribute to the script tag which is
basically a hash of the content of the
script that you're sourcing so if you go
for example to a jQuery official web
page and you search for the code snippet
to include you will see a script tag
that already includes the integrity
attribute but if you want to calculate
it yourself you can go to some websites
like SSRI hash org to calculate this
hash this means basically at the browser
it loads this javascript or in this case
CDN SJS not CloudFlare comm downloads it
compares the hash of the content with
the one that you specified there and
only executes it in the context of your
webpage if the hash matches so this
provides integrity guarantee SSRI is
supported by all modern browsers
particular Firefox Chrome Safari and new
edge it's not supported in I yeah that's
the only one new I just support so
that's pretty well supported the second
one is same site cookies so since that
cookies is an extra flag in the cookie
to basically mitigate cross-site request
forgery attacks so here we're no longer
talking about XSS we are talking about
cross-site request forgery
the idea with cross-site request forgery
is that you turn the browser against the
user so for example you have a page on
evil comm and you I don't know embed a
forum or something that does banking
website comm slash withdraw and then an
action that has some kind of side effect
so the problem is that this action is
out indicated so it sent the victim
sense it's his own cookies to the
vulnerable server
in a lot of cases you don't want that
like you want your cookies to be sent
only if the request originated from your
origin and not if it is cross origin in
a way if it originated from a form or an
image or anything from another origin we
can be attacker controlled so the idea
is you can assert that a particular
cookie should only be sent with requests
initiated from the same side so
basically this is a flag like you know
path or domain or expires you know it's
called same site and you can have two
values tricked and lux strict means
always basically cookies are not sent
when there is cross site navigation this
can be problematic in case of for
example get requests because this
applies also to get requests and it
means that for example if you want to
send an URL via email and you know from
gmail.com the your friend will click on
that and it will not be logged in
because there will be cookies will not
be sent so this might be a little bit
too much sometimes so the idea is to
also add a lacks value that means
cookies are not sent when there is
cross-site navigation and unsafe HTTP
method with more than and safe I would
say HTTP method that implies some kind
of side effects like post boot or delete
which are usually the well by RFC the
HTTP method that you should use if you
have a state a state changing action or
an action that has side effects so for
example in this case get request would
have a cross cross site navigation
cookie sent while these are sufficient
metals but not so for example a post
with a form which is probably what is
used for a withdraw action on a
vulnerable website would not send
cookies so this is pretty cool since
that cookie supporting browsers is
unfortunately a little bit more limited
but it is supported by the major
browsers which are chrome and firefox
chrome supports it since few major
versions Firefox just supported for from
59 which is pretty recent hello
what do you mean exactly like fetch
light same origin
but is not about exercise right this is
about cross-site request forgery so you
have a form that posts will it send the
cookies yes so that's a problem with
this you don't it's as simple as that
so you don't need Java Script right even
if you disable Java Script you have a
forum post well you might have just
before out for sending automatically but
let's say that you have a hidden button
or something right okay so this works
even in this case okay so basically it's
supported by Firefox and Chrome edge
does not support it next ones are a site
isolation C or B Corp and from origin so
these are very new and cutting edge
mitigation techniques and they're
actually well actually some of them are
a header delivered so you as a webmaster
can use them and some are browser
settings so I'll go through them
separately site isolation is basically a
chromium browser setting other browsers
are vendors are pushing in different
directions to achieve the same the same
goal but we can talk about that more in
detail if we have time basically if you
go to Chrome flags you can enable strict
site isolation which is will be on by
default in the next versions but so far
it's opt-in this means that the browser
puts pages from different websites in
different processes and also put some
safeguards preventing some kind of inter
process communication between them so
why doing that this is an extra security
boundary and here we're talking about
not web vulnerability we are talking
about binary vulnerability memory
corruption vulnerability in particular
in this case we are so strict eyesight
isolation has been around for more than
one year if I remember correctly and now
it's very important to actually enable
it's because of Spectre and meltdown so
this speculative execution bugs you
might have heard of basically it's very
important to also avoid loading let's
say document contents so HTML content in
static resources such as images because
basically what you could do is read
memory from the process so the idea is
let's try to avoid that sensitive data
might end up in the process in the first
place and this is exactly what Corp or
cross-eyed resource blocking is or now
it's called read blocking in the change
name but R is still there it used to be
called resource blocking is called read
blocking this is an important part of
side isolation restricting which
crossorigin data is sent to a renderer
process for example we want to avoid
that loading cross-origin HTML in image
tags just to basically taint the process
with having potentially information
sensitive
potentially sensitive data so you might
think I don't care if I do image source
sensitivity III dot HTML because I can't
read it here we're not talking about web
right we're talking about dumping the
memory of the process so you can read it
in that way so no same origin policy
we're not talking about web we're
talking about processes here and it's
pretty cool that web platform is trying
to also cover these cases and it is
actually pretty new it might also be
surprising from origin is a header based
mechanism and you as a webmaster can say
I want to prevent my resources from
being loaded by non-white listed origins
this applies to images this applies to
HTML and whatever so this was originally
thought as inline linking protection or
hot link in protection I don't want my
images I don't know I am IMG you are
calm I didn't want my images to be
loaded from random forums that leech my
bandwidth or you know I don't want to be
slash dotted I don't want to be you know
I don't want to pay for bandwidth by
having you know random people saw a
source and embed heavy resources but it
is becoming more and more important
because of spectra and meltdown so from
origin Korb and site isolation are bit
together basically form a strong
mitigation against this kind of
speculative execution attacks and there
are a little bit orthogonal from one
each other most of them are so if I
remember correctly this still been
discussed but from origin has not
implemented yet but Corp will be
probably be present in chromium only and
Firefox will have a similar thing but
stay tuned this is being discussed now
up to upcoming mitigations that we that
are not there yet but we'd like to see
getting traction sub origins are a very
promising mitigation that basically so
what is a web origin a web origin is is
a tuple this is basically the security
boundary of the web this tuple has
scheme which is HTTP HTTP file host and
port right this is the fusion of origin
some origin proposal says we should add
another part of the tuple which is a
arbitrary namespace that is provided by
a header by the server so you can have a
sub origin header suicide that does I
know it says test or you know account
area or admin area this physically
separates this origin and makes it
separate this means that an XSS on in
that those pages will not be able to
access data from the main origin of the
of the you know host all of the domain
or others so this allows very
coarse-grained you know separation in
cases it's hard to have separate domains
or separate subdomains so the safest is
of course having a lot of subdomain like
for example Google User Content calm
there is a reason why we did you google
is or content because it allows to
upload user data we want to separate
from google.com subdomains are somehow
okay they're not as okay for cookies for
some reasons because cookies are a bit
weird but the idea is think of WordPress
WordPress Maps on slash wp-admin an
admin area which might be XSS prone
because you install plugins and so on it
would be cool to isolate it as if it was
from your site admin area calm right so
let make it work but in case there is
like some kind of exercise its isolated
from the rest of your site and the same
for sensitive functionalities such as a
password reset so without going too much
in technical deep
the thing is an Origin will have a sub
origin and the idea is you will need
some refactoring to make sub origin to
parent origin and sub origin to external
origin communication work in particular
sub origin to sub origin is works by
default as long as the server provides
the same sub origin header so there's a
page and as sub origin admin area and
then wants to communicate via I don't
know xhr or fetch or post message to
another page that is on the same sub
regime so with also sub origin admin
area that works no problem like if it is
same origin because it is same sub
origin some origin to parent origin this
is blocked by default because that's
what we want right we want to separate
but to communicate sub origin to origin
you need to add a new header which is
like the course header ax access control
allow origin so that but in this case
it's called access control allow sub
origin with the name of the sub origin
as simple as that and symbology to X
turn is like cross origin with course so
access control allow origin so I wanted
to give you a quick demo if it works so
an intern of our team Alena UNESCO
created a Chrome extension that
unfortunetely is not public because we
it uses some let's say very experimental
parts of chrome API so we need to find
unit a little bit but if sub origins get
traction will definitely open source it
put publish it on the Chrome Web Store
this helps prototype sub origins so for
example let's say that we have for
example for historical reasons or for
marketing reasons we have some static
web page were paid on a very sensitive
domain which is dub dub dub dub oogle
com so wlcome has PA eyes has very
sensitive data we don't want to so an
exercise on dub dub dub is very bad but
unfortunately these pages these are
static pages or slash about they might
have some vulnerabilities they might
also
you know come with a be you know written
by external people so we might not be as
safe I'm confident about the code
quality so what we want to do is we open
sub originator hope you can see yeah
and we put a target site which is dub
dub dub about and then we started so you
see it's debugging the window okay so in
this case we just you know navigate this
a little bit we open a few are this is
external a few links then we stop it
here I didn't have to do stops sorry we
do this play report
yes
yes just a second okay I probably need
to yeah okay so let's open a few stories
the chute load you know mp3 do xhr you
know there is a there is a video here oh
notice audio okay should do this Perry
yes this is display report and we see
that it's basically only submerging two
sub ology communication so this is fine
this means that works out to the box so
as long as we put the same origin header
this will work so this is fine no
refactoring is needed but if we go for
example to a more complex application
which is a Google Finance that is like
on google.com slash finance or so for a
historical reason and we you know we
just go around a little bit we have to
be careful not to exit the origin okay
then we display report yeah you see that
there is some communication between the
sub origin to the parent origin and from
the sub origin to external this means
that submerging two external probably
works already because otherwise it will
be blocked from already from let's say
dub-dub-dub
to an external so this means that the
course is already in but what we need to
focus on is submerging to origin this
means we have to add this access control
allow sub origin header so for example
in this case we are talking with slash
search slash a sink and these requests
will have to have an extra header added
so in conclusion this extension really
helps in prototyping and seeing how much
refactoring is needed to to use this and
have all the benefits of sub origins so
it's really hot
halogen policy origin policy is a
proposal hasn't been implemented yet
and the idea is to make some of these
mitigations by default like HSTs for
Telus or HTTPS so the idea is you can
add as many policies as you want like
consecutive policy or referral policies
or other policies to an entire origin by
default like pinning so it's sent one we
are manifest and then every source get
those policies applied this is very cool
because it complements header based
delivery and increases coverage for
example let's say you have a reverse
proxy and you have different different
service I don't know you miss deployment
on one or you have some parts of the
stack that do not trigger your code path
where you added these headers I don't
know another page a debug Handler things
like that like these things happen then
you will find out that maybe you don't
have this protection these in this way
you're guaranteed to have this
protection applied to the whole origin
or it may be even part parts of it in
the manifest you can be a little bit
more fine-grain but as I said this is a
proposal so if you search for origin
policy on w3 you will see that are
actively discussed it's been actively
discussed another one is feature policy
it allows the web developer to
selectively enable and disable different
browser features and API such as going
fullscreen or using geolocation
or using web USB in combination with
origin policy it's very good for
restricting for example geolocation - I
don't know search on map action you need
your location only on one action and so
you say explicitly I will need it only
on this action so an XSS on any other
page will have a harder time for example
getting the user location because it
will be disabled hard to disabled on
other pages I mean this is not a
security band I mean you could do things
you could try to do lateral I mean you
could try to jump from one to to the
other but this hardens and makes it hard
harder raises the bar I think we are on
time or slightly slightly
slightly earlier so I have any questions
about CSP or the new stuff please ask
thank you
[Applause]