I don't want it to be too loud so I have
a booming voice so I appreciate it thank
you very much to our organizers amazing
conference I think the single most
distracting thing this this week has
been the smoker and the grill outside
amazing food I don't think I used to run
conferences for Microsoft and I don't
think we've ever had such such amazing
food so thank you once again for an
amazing event so my name is TJ campaña I
came from 12 years at Microsoft where we
developed a number of teams to come
systemic so you may have heard of some
of the teams that we developed out of
legal and corporate affairs so the
Digital Crimes Unit so probably about
eight years ago ten years ago we started
building out a capability and a
framework to go on the offense against
systemic threats to the Microsoft
ecosystem it was called the Mars program
what I've done over the past four and a
half years with Microsoft now is start
to go back to the defensive side so how
in a large-scale organization can you
defend against an evolving threat and I
know that many of the folks in this room
experienced that so your hackers
application security testers red teamers
developers sock analysts so we're going
to talk about today is a little bit
about what HSBC is because I was told
that most of you didn't know what HSBC
was until probably this week we're going
to talk a little bit about the
opportunities and the challenges we're
also going to talk about the approach
that we're taking kind of
multi-dimensional threat so network
defense is evolving it's absolutely not
the same as it was ten years ago so the
opening joke is and I'm guilty of this
as well we had when I went to interview
for HSBC in London I really did have a
good understanding of what HSBC was but
I travel a lot all over the world and I
kept seeing this logo at every airport
so I thought maybe we were a marketing
company
turns out where will the largest
financial services organizations in the
world we connect because of customers
with opportunity and we make sure that
global trade happens thirty nine hundred
offices 67 countries thirty-eight
million customers and the only way that
we can do this is through a massive
network of technology our main offices
are in New York London and Hong Kong
where we always have iconic buildings so
we have two hundred and forty two
hundred thirty two hundred forty
thousand employees to make this machine
work
servicing thirty eight million customers
worldwide 24 hours a day seven days a
week in all the markets that we serve
can you imagine what it takes to do that
always on always available so we start
to talk about many of us in this room
talk about IDs and web application
exploits sequel injection things like
that around Network defense that's kind
of bread and butter for what we do at
HSBC every day we have to defend the
environment from people that want to get
into our into our state for a various
various range of types of attacks but
what folks don't really start that are
starting to understand and we're
starting to adapt to a more of a
military-type style footprint is that we
also had to defend our customers from
our so our customers that get infected
with malware banking Trojans etc we have
clients that again fected with malware
or some type of you know apt attack
trying to go after the payment systems
so you've heard this all in the news how
do we start to get smarter than the
adversary when we go after these types
of attacks it's not just one team it's
not just a bunch of geeks in a room
looking at some screens it's not
it's not the traditional approach that
we're probably all used to on a daily
basis I find myself connecting with my
colleagues in our fraud department that
have a vastly different view of the
threat landscape to our customers I get
along really great with my geeks many of
which we've brought out here today for
the event that's my wheelhouse but think
about it how many times have you had
conversations with your physical
security team it's easy for us to be
geeks because that's where we cats are
that's our happy place when we start to
talk about holistic defense of our
organization and our customer base we
have to start to stretch outside of that
type of a perspective we really have to
start to look at what is it that is that
holistic defensive mechanism how is the
adversary acting and where can we deny
that adversary access to our environment
so as you can imagine in security
operations we have all these great
metrics we collect this many billion of
events per day and we have this type of
technology and we have this type of
firewall but the reality is the
adversary is always trying to go after
the place where you the weakest even if
you are strong across the board you're
gonna have that one place where you're
weak and that might be at a customer
site or a third party it may be in an
application that you just deployed
you'll see a lot of the vendors that are
out here today talking about that
Network visibility and the ability to
understand what your environment looks
like on any given day I sat through the
the presentation from the gentleman from
Mozilla now imagine if you're able to
take that view of the environment that
view of your application stack and merge
it up with cybercrime type statistics
external statistics from crime crime
waves that may impact your physical
security posture this is what we're
talking about when we talk about
security operations of the future it's
emerged fused capability most
governments around the world have
already realized this
they've been doing this for years and
years and years when we start to talk
about private sector we can see that
they're starting to adopt that over the
last five years so you see a number of
organizations that have built out fuse
and Center capability but what is that
fusion Center give you the fusion center
gives you the ability to have
situational awareness across multiple
areas of threat multiple domains of
threat it allows you to be more
proactive when you start to go after
some of the adversaries coming after you
so if you understand your adversaries
motive might be a network attack coupled
with a malware attack against your
customers again the multi-dimensional
element of the threat that we're facing
you can be ahead of the game so that's
the challenge that we face now how do we
get from where we are today to where the
future is
well it's smart people quite frankly
it's you
it's the geeks the geeks will lead us to
the to the promised land because we
understand data we understand the
challenges that we face so part of what
we're looking for is and one of the
reasons that we're out here in crack off
this week is we're recruiting for our
security operations but we're looking
for people that have that mindset so
I've been in discussion so I took over
this role about eight months ago and
we've been to discussions constantly
about org design and where do we put
people and what shape and size but the
whole conversation isn't about people
it's about the individuals that bring
that certain perspective that certain
piece of the puzzle to the organization
so we've been in Cracow for a long time
we've been in Cracow for years and years
and years but what the what does it mean
to build out that full stack secured
Operations Center and bring in that
fused capability
so a lot of times you hear people
talking about outsource outsource
doesn't work outsource is software think
about that full stack capability means
building out a fully capable set of
individuals in each of the locations
where you operate so the ability for us
to have threat hunters escalation
engineers watch commanders all of these
different people in all of the locations
where we operate and connecting them in
new and interesting ways using
technology that's the future it's not
sending easy-to-do jobs offshore it's
more about making sure that the people
that you have in a different location
have that capability to do the job that
they need to do so we're currently
building out a capability here in Krakow
so we currently have software developers
we have IT administrators we have
business business analysts but what
we're really building out from the cyber
security perspective is a technology
stack and an operation stack so our
ability to have the global visibility
that we have within the within the
organization ready at fingertips so
currently what we're looking at is I
don't even know how many billions of
events per day probably around 10 to 15
billion events per day come into our
sock we're probably going to quadruple
that this year so think about that 60
billion events coming in per day there's
no way that we can look at that many
that many events so how do we get smart
about that so we have all kinds of
technology you see them see them all
across the room yeah Splunk or cue radar
or
purple rainbow or whatever it is that we
want to do but when you start to look at
the ability for us to process that
amount of data and actually make it
meaningful for network defense that's a
whole new ballgame
I don't think that there's many
organizations that are actually doing
that today I think by and large we're
looking at the tech companies that
probably have the best position in this
so when we talk about what it is that we
want to do for next-generation security
operations its instrumenting our
environment appropriately making sure we
get the data that we need having the
technology behind that data but it all
starts with people it all starts with
smart people coming in understanding
what that vision is and knowing that
they have a piece of piece of the puzzle
to play so one of the big pieces that I
have here in crack off is working with
our we're working with the Polish cert
working with the universities in Krakov
and in Warsaw understanding what it is
that they need to do in order to prepare
us or prepare students for the future so
how do we get people in the door ready
to contribute immediately upon entering
the organization the skill sets that we
have in this room and that this
conference are not easily attained you
can't just take a class and become a
cybersecurity expert it's people that
have that experience and past that
experience on so for me it's important
to be here because I want to learn
constantly learning I want to talk to
individuals that are interested in
taking us to the next generation but I
also want to know more about what it is
that you find it interesting so there's
a lot more to do one of the big things I
would say is many of you have come over
to our booth it's the big booth in the
back back room today we have
I scream so that's been a big hit we've
got some retro video games the wall
actually turns into a video game more
importantly we have a lot of staff on
hand ready to have those conversations
we'd like to talk to you a little bit
more about what you see as your part in
the in the growth of our organization so
this is one of the month this is one of
the models that we have for our
organizations together we thrive it's
one of the key pieces that keeps us
together as an organization it's one of
the things that we try to in vibe in our
culture so I'm looking forward to having
more conversations with individuals we'd
like to have we'd like to leave here
with some more information about you get
you more information about us but I
would love to open up the rest of the
comp the rest of the session the
conversation you have any questions
concerns or any things that you want to
talk about while you have me here I know
we have a microphone correct no is there
a microphone that you pass word to the
audience or is any questions I mean I
could talk for 30 more minutes if you'd
like if not go to lunch thank you