hi so I'm Jacob and for the next 40 or
so minutes I'll talk about hacking
systems that are non-deterministic voice
biometry so first few words about me two
years ago I moved to Australia here is
me and my mate the gangster Roo
I'm doing application security pen
testing in application security usually
usually I focus on web applications
mobile applications embedded devices and
proprietary network protocols but
sometimes I do have interesting projects
and voice biometrics was one of them a
project totally different from what I've
been doing for most of my professional
career so that's why I want to share it
with you the research idea came in 2015
where I tested fusil few voice
biometrics solution in 2015 back in
Poland these were two applications to
integrations one with the mobile
application the second one with the IVR
channels and for the telephone as I said
it was extremely challenging and
interesting throughout the next few
years I gathered some more ideas I
tested a few more solutions and here
I've got something that I can share with
you I will talk about hacking force
biometrics but not only I will show you
a few general challenges which occur
when when you're testing
non-deterministic systems look in the
past everything was easy right you're
testing an application you're sending an
SQL injection payload or an or an RC you
find an RC e the next day the payload
works the same way you still you still
get the share or if still or still are
in the database while with these
solutions the payload you you sent once
may not work in the future or it may it
may matter which payload use in first
and which which the next one all right
so this presentation is also about
systemic approach to tell
voice biometrics in quite the limited
time as this was a pen testing project
and it was it was time boxed and just
for just for the reference I'm not
saying that voice biometrics is a bad
idea I'm not saying it's a good idea
either
all right so we have an authentication
problem the pins can be shoulder says
the passwords can be cracked ever say
tokens can be stolen or compromised SMS
is can be intercepted so the vendors the
the authentication vendors came with an
idea to authenticate you with something
you are the problem is that something
that you know it can be leaked if if
it's something you have it can be stolen
what about something you are well it
can't be changed
so first few words about biometric
patents is voice biometrics a new thing
not really
so there are already thousand patients
about about voice biometrics technology
and even in in the risky business
podcast episode 10 in 2007 it was it was
already mentioned that something being
implemented already in the corporation's
how does it work to be honest I don't
know it was a black box pen test so what
I know of this system is that there is
an enrollment phase you have to say the
phrase say my voice is my password three
times it's somehow saved in a database
and later you can authenticate so either
either called the IVR Channel or open
your mobile app and you have to say the
phrase and the system will tell tell you
if it's you or not so it should work
even if you have a sore throat it should
work even if yesterday it was a good
party it should work when you get older
and it should not work if you replay a
recording so the current state of
integration of voice biometrics
technology is that
it's a channel but it's it's not the
second channel so once you try to
authenticate with your voice the system
says sorry that's not you you fall back
to the standard password so we can still
say the standard password if that
doesn't work you connect to the IVR
Channel and you can answer the security
questions if that doesn't work you can
go to the branch right so somebody
called that below one factor
authentication and the system is as
secure as the weakest link so as for now
I think that that nobody will attack
voice biometrics yet because there are
much easier easier ways to to attack the
system within the standard password and
we've within the IVR
channel right there is there is one
parameter one function that defines mmm
the quality of the voice biometrics it's
it's not the best parameter but that's
something that you can compare voice
biometrics solutions against each other
it's the equalizer right so we've got
the FA air that's a false acceptance
rate so if I try to spoof somebody's
voice and the system allows me to do
that that's a false acceptance case then
we've got the false rejection rate and
the the vendors can can parameterize
their solutions so that if they want to
provide a better security they can they
can get the false acceptance rate lower
but then the false rejection rate will
be higher so it's not good for the
business the equal error rate or or the
crossover rate it's it's when the FA R
and F are the same so how good is it now
in 2015 the solutions more or less the
average market solution was around 2 to
4 percent nowadays we have maybe one to
two percent in case of scientific
approach of how secure is that how
strong is that it's actually really
basic so if we want to talk about high
security we need to take like
five orders of magnitude better what is
the false acceptance rate for a standard
password if you on the website if you
put your password what is the what is
the false acceptance rate anybody zero
right
what's the false rejection rate also
zero right so it's something wrong about
these solutions right alright so here is
some public data on on the values for
one of the vendors that's new ins they
they stayed on their website that the
values are around 1.5 percent what does
it mean it means that I can take
hundreds voiced trials from let's say
from all of unit here and tried it
against my voice and and I'll have a
quite a big chance that that one of your
voices will work and the other way as
well the horizontal brute force I can I
can take my voice try to authenticate as
each and every one of you and that most
probably it will work for one of you so
the vendors they started introducing
some additional levels of security there
is providing a PIN number so practically
a standard password on this IVR Channel
that's that's when the the false
acceptance rate can can go a little bit
lower but it's that's cheating how the
vendors calculate the error rates so the
ideal world is from one of the vendors
leaflets in ideal world
they'll take 300 participants half of
them will make a proper call and half of
them will try to spoof the other half
but in practice that's what the vendor
says in practice they'll just take 300
participants and each of them will make
five or seven through through user calls
and ten or twelve impostor calls and
generally test with less than hundred
participants are considered anecdotal at
least so come on these vendors there
producing machine learning the AI
solutions the rocket science into banks
into corporations into telecoms and they
they already have 300 record in their
database and it can't just take the API
or the engine and cross-check them all
against each other well let me do that
for ya
so here comes the science there is a
thing called the central limit theorem
and if we took a voice biometric
solution that just analyzed one
parameter a really dumb voice biometric
so let's say the parameter is the peak
peak pitch of the voice throughout the
call the central limit theorem says that
in the population in all of the all of
these cases now there will be a lot of
people with a very average voice and a
small amount of people with a small
number of people with low peak pitch
voice and high pitch pitch voice right
if you take a random user and random
spoofer and try to impose spoof a random
user you will end up at some point
having Morgan Freeman trying to attack
the froda right while in the real attack
scenario if I wanted to do this if I
knew that I have a voice of Morgan
Freeman I would test only well Morgan
Freeman's family right so here is the
case if you calculate that with the
false acceptance rate of 1% and you've
got three attempts per one throughout
the one phone call there is a three
chance or three percent chance of
success to to authenticate properly if
you can somehow trick the system and get
the false acceptance rate of 20% in
three calls you will have more than 50%
chance of success so here is the the key
of hacking voice biometrics you need to
choose your voice trials the day the
audio files that you'll play in a way
that the the system and the acceptance
race will work in your favor so let's do
it one more one more note so the vendors
they they can set their their voice
biometrics solution to either
keep the constant threshold so that an
average voice will will proof more
people with average voice while the
high-pitched voice will we be able to
spoof only few people or the other way
the constant false acceptance right but
we'll focus on that later on the side
note we've been used to
well we testers we've been used to
hacking
well designing test cases to break
software which was written by human or
break the rules that were designed by
human right currently with the voice
biometrics it's not developed well yet
so we are able to develop the test cases
just being a human but as you can see
well this is some random chart from the
internet on the of the intelligence of
AI systems compared to the human ones I
think that in future to actually break
well-developed AI systems including
voice biometrics or next-generation
firewalls behavioral network level
analyzes and network traffic analyzes
and well many other security solutions
that base there are based on AI we will
need AI to design test cases and this is
actually happening now so for the voice
biometrics there vendors who well
develop voice authentication systems but
there are companies that do well they do
the opposite so for example Google
they've got their own team which wants
to prove that a recording of someone
saying something is it's not really
proof because you can spoof it and
they're working on it and they've got a
team of AI data scientists working on
that so I'd really love to see a well -
AI systems fighting with each other as
for this presentation I'll show some
really simple simple tricks that allowed
to design the test cases in a way that
you don't need in AI so let's do a quick
fret modeling we can now track the voice
biometrics solutions during their
enrollment we can try to bypass the
authentication
we can try to break into the system and
grab some voice databases and of course
we can deny service for other customers
I will focus on the authentication
bypass and you can do it in few
scenarios so one of them is the vendor
approved let's say hi rings puffers and
actually trying to make the phone calls
and the horizontal brute force
you can also attack the integration so
there is some piece of technology
parsing the voice and maybe you can
exploit the audio codecs well of course
if the application if the solution is
integrated within the mobile application
you can try to pentas the Mobile API and
of course abusing the process in some
way for example falling back to standard
password or or something like that you
can do speech synthesis but for that you
need a team of data scientists and you
can do a replay so you can record
somebody's voice and you can do it in a
few ways so we can do it directly on his
device if you if you infected his mobile
phone with malware or you intercept GSM
that's not sexy if you if you're right
if you have malware on his phone you'll
probably can do a lot of other things
you can do a distance recording with a
good microphone and I'll tell you what's
a good microphone in a moment or we can
do the sneakers attack who watched the
sneakers movie from the 1984 now there
is there is a film during which a guy he
has a recording of somebody saying some
random sentences he just cut few words
from these sentences and formed the
sentence that actually is the phrase for
the voice biometric system there was it
was in a movie from like 30 years ago
you can also collect some voices from
the IOT toys so not long time ago the
cloud pet teddy bears they have an
exposed
I think MongoDB database on the on
public Internet and a lot of recordings
from the cloud that teddy bears leaked
maybe maybe the kids father was
authenticating to his bank during during
the kid was playing with the teddy bear
right and we also have
Orwell's 1984 telescreens
implementation by Samsung and CIA which
was called the whipping angel
so they modified the Samsung TVs to
record people quite transparently so
that they don't know that what's going
on so let's get to it
we we need to have a plan so the target
is voice biometrics solution in a mobile
app and the IVR channel on the phone
they both claimed that they're there
they have defense against replay attacks
and we'll try to focus on that scenario
so we need to do three things we need to
gather the voice we need to record it
and reductant always or basically
isolate the vocal we need to fuss the
voice so we need to modify the audio
files in some way and identify the
thresholds for bio material for replay
detection then we need to do the actual
impersonation so we need to do we need
to automate the request and in some way
gather the responses to to make some
reasoning out of it how good is good
microphone well here we've got some
prices of the tools some of them I use I
use them for this for this research so
the the initial research was done with a
nexus 5 and Sony ECM this standard
journalist microphone actually provided
one of the best results you can grab
some chip out of all the microphone this
rode videomic also gave some good
results but there most of them they were
not able to capture voice from more than
five or ten meters if you need more you
can buy more expensive stuff or actually
you've rented so here the price is
that's Australian dollars per day this
particle this one is particularly
interesting so this is a telescope mic
used by teams at the football matches so
they want to record the voice what what
the players are shouting right this is
supposed to capture the voice from 50
meters all right so we need a direction
on my
phone right if I am in a cafe I want to
just spot the voice from one person so
this is this Aldi microphone for $15 its
omnidirectional it will work in all
directions but you take off the cap it
works quite well within one direction
okay so we need to record the voice and
isolate the vocal we recorded this in a
medium loud environment so it was a cafe
from five meters with a cheap microphone
and with it few tricks so in other city
standard filters like vocalization that
won't work but few other worked quite
well so the noise reduction high and
low-pass filter to isolate the best
frequencies for the voice some
amplification adding the legit noise and
once you sort out the actual parameters
this will be two recordings one will be
without vocal isolation and the second
wave one
[Applause]
and our week later this is why this is
actually enough for the voice biometric
technology
Oh
[Music]
yep so we were here so some some of the
vendors will call this a black
co-operative because in a cafe some
normal person will spot you well I don't
believe that
so some solutions rely on noise I'll
tell about it in a moment and so that's
why we add some legit noise to do the
isolated vocal and some IVRS can
actually detect noise change during the
voice out indication versus the whole
call so if you call the voice biometric
endpoint you're silent during the whole
call but suddenly you turn your your
player and you play the recording and
there will be some ambient noise there
it will detect it as a spoofing attack
so right so we isolated the vocal now we
need to fuzz it like how to fast voice
well first few things about the
thresholds so the reason original
recording which is a sound wave there is
some threshold if you modify that sound
wave a little bit it will be detected as
a replay attack well a little bit more
that would be perfect it means that was
you this is the biometric shot then the
wrist there is the edge case where the
small modification will actually make
the system not know whether it was it's
real cold or not so usually the system
will ask you to repeat and of course all
of the other modifications will end up
in the incorrect and set so for passing
the voice I use the Sox package in the
standard Linux environment I observed
that linear functions should play the
replay detection but not spectrum and
not biometric so I'll be able to still
get into the system but I will bypass
the replay attack detection so I came up
with just few parameters usually the
voice biometrics solutions they're
they're calculating the voice based on
20 parameters well always just 5 so
different level of noise reduction pitch
levels
levels some random pauses between each
word and some background noise and I'll
play you what all 10th occasion my voice
is my password authentication my voice
is my password authentication
authentication my voice is my password
authentication my voice is my passport
authentication my voice is my possible
no joke after a few days of testing your
your colleagues will ask you to work
from home
authentication my voice is my passport
authentication my voice is impossible by
the way if you want to try that outside
there are some helium balloons just like
they won so can try actually modify your
voice all right the the problem is that
if you combine well 5 parameters around
10 values each you will get around
40,000 recordings that's two days of
constant audio we've got a problem we
can't process that much in in a week's
time or even less so we need to optimize
our our well choosing of the voice
trials to fit into well 100 to 300
recordings which we can do either
manually or semi semi automatically well
here are a few things I learned in my
school which were particularly important
for this research so the darboux
property and the intermediate value
property it means basically that if you
are on the south and hemisphere and you
need to get to the northern hemisphere
it will end up going through the equator
right and the monotonic functions it
turns out that well voice voice
biometrics it's quite small solution
it's it's really smooth so you can't
find terror shots which are non
continuous or there are non convex so if
this represents one parameter voice
biometrics solution and
is the threshold for for the specific
voice trial it will it will it will not
be a disjoint set so we can expect that
that for two dimensions will be the same
and you will find circles or Altoids not
not things which which look like that
which allows us to do some really
interesting stuff we can analyze each of
the parameters separately so first we
take let's say these are two parameters
we just want to find one we try to look
where there where there is the end of
the threshold the edge case we do it
further for all of the for all of the
voice trials and then we can construct
some sets of voice biometric parameters
that we'll use for the later for later
impersonation this actually allows us to
to define the shapes of the thresholds
whatever it is as long as it's a circle
or an ellipsoid alright it is actually
another interesting thing if you take
the pone triangle pwn if you try if you
try just with randomly putting voiced
files in that triangle the ratio of the
successful files and the non successful
trials will will give you a lot of
information about the threshold alright
there's some math stuff the life is not
easy so the voice biometrics solution
they don't work on constant terror
assaults the terror saltcan well it's
not just one parameter is one parameter
across the whole audio which lasts for
five or ten seconds so the threshold can
move during the time right and it can
also well change the shape so in the
beginning of the call for example within
the word my voice it can be a little bit
smaller my password it can be bigger all
right so all of these things it allowed
me to develop this simple receipt for
designing the test cases for voice
biometrics so with the replay attack
detection off we test the parameters
independently so separately each of the
five parameters that gives us no more
than 50 trials we determine the maximum
value of the threshold
and then we choose three levels of for
each parameter which is zero marks and
mark / - then we test we combine these
parameters together so for five
parameters at just three levels we do
all of the combinations and that gives
just 250 trials then we choose most
successful of them I'll be probably
usually less than 10 sorry less than 100
it's quite important to do all of these
tests without replay detection so if we
actually test on on a live system and we
can't turn off the replay detection we
need to create a new account for each
trial which takes a little bit more time
all right after that we have to replay
attack detection on we can trash the
selected thresholds some of the best
values for stability tests and while we
enrolled each time if necessary because
the replay that the detection is already
on sounds easy
so let's do some reconnaissance how does
the voice biometric works
you ought indicate with the standard
mechanism during the enrollment phase
and you repeat your the phrase three
times right my voice is my password my
voice is my password my voice is my
password the phrase the most common
phrase is actually the one I just said
but there are also some other so sign me
in to the XYZ bank or my name is ABC and
my voice is my password the thing is
that none of them is perfect so the
first one it's not unique Pirtle I
intend provider
so if database of these recordings leak
well all other vendors all are the banks
are actually they have a problem so the
second one is also not perfect it allows
a horizontal brute force and the third
one again if it leaks there will be a
problem so what would what would be the
best phrase probably something like my
name is ABC and XYZ bank my voice is my
password but try to convince the
business guys to actually invent it all
right
the authentication face looks like the
following you need to call the info line
or from any number and dial the DTMF
tones and you have to say the trace the
system will respond either with a
success incorrect or replay replay attic
detected well then there is the end of
coal and there is this small edge case
not sure please repeat up to three times
in the mobile app it's already paired
with the account right so we don't need
to enter your custom e this has some
serious security consequences I mean
positive security consequences because
you can't do the horizontal brute-force
well if the integration is is is well
designed all right it would be easy but
there are some challenges and the first
one occurred when I created an account
and rolled the voice i authenticated
properly and abused the system in some
way so try to run and replay attack
detection I found the vulnerability and
the system sorry the vendor said oh no
you you were able to do it because it
was a weak enrollment Ruhlman so
actually some of the vendors they detect
weak enrollments so we so we need to
need to think about like you have to
have a proper proper silent environment
record the voice in a good environment
then the machine learning mechanisms so
the more proper authentications here in
step 2 the system will know your voice
better and it will have the better
thresholds so if you're doing a quick
pen test in a week time the vendor can
just say our customers usually they
usually use the the solution each day
four five times a day so this won't be
the case for major retailer our
customers come on one one is enough we
can just attack somebody who just who
just enrolled alright so we are trying
to repeat the whole attack vector many
times and for multiple with multiple
authentications in between next
challenge you create an account
and enroll your voice with with some
voice now you create a second account
but you try to use the same voice the
question is is it even possible and does
it off doesn't affect the replay
detection so maybe the system will
actually think oh no you can't have
rolled your voice because somebody else
used your voice already so you need more
voices more challenges so you create an
account you enroll the voice and you
transform it with some function then you
pass it to the system and the system
says is incorrect but you you repeat
that process in the same way but you
just use another voice and it turns out
that it works and the system accepts you
so some attacks will work only for a
specific set of people with some
specific characteristics of voice let's
say low voices or high voices but it's
deliverability but you need more voices
yeah so here is some short video of how
to collect the voices just play it some
here just for science you can just go on
a street and ask people it will work it
works the best if you say I'm doing this
university research and please help me
all right that video is not perfect but
anyways in two hours you can collect 100
voices which is more than enough to like
this solution alright even more
challenges it created an account you
enroll the voice and record it then you
transform it with some light function by
light and strong function I mean you
know you change the pitch by 10% and 30%
you pass the small modification to the
system and the system things to replay
and it is a replay attack then you send
this strong quantification then it's
also a replay because the system stores
the the first recording now if you run
the test in in the other in the other
order so if you first send the strong
function it will actually work and you
will be able to spoof the voice so
previous authentication effect the
future ones and that's why I was talking
about turning off the replay attack
detection during the first set of tests
the the learning mode now the challenge
or all a process weakness
so you create an account you can enroll
the voice you transform it with some
function then you pass it to the system
the system says we are unsure please
repeat the way the second time the same
recording without any modification well
with this one modification the system
says unsure please repeat but if you do
it the third time the system says all
right we can allow you to do it so in
the third step in the third world try
attempt the system lowered the jolts
just to help the help the business false
rejection right so that not to piss off
the clients I need so it can happen that
the first shots will be changed within
one call so in some solutions is worth
to send some crap in the first two
attempts and then send a real payload in
the third attempt right
the last challenge you create an account
you enroll the voice then you transform
it with a small and big functions right
you pass the big modification to the
system as a success then you pass a
small modification many times always a
failure but then you try to send this
moment is already big modification and
the system says it's an incorrect
attempt but it's not a replay what can
happen is that different thresholds the
system made simply detect that something
wrong is going on if it's receiving a
lot of spoofed calls the thresholds may
be just lowered or actually high while
getting getting them a little bit higher
if if a brute-force attack is attempted
on a system all right so the hint is to
identify the thresholds on mule accounts
on different accounts and not like only
after you identify the thresholds all
right I lied this is the last challenge
you create an account you can enroll the
voice you pass the recording it's all
good you modify the vocal but the noise
stays the same and you pass it to the
system and the system says the replay is
detected so what happened is that some
solutions they include the noise in the
biometric analysis of whether it's your
voice or not so even if it is you and
you're not playing it from the recording
if the noise is actually the same as it
used to be in the previous recording it
will be a replay so we need to generate
a new noise for the each trial the
aftermath after a week of modifying my
voice is my password my voice is my
passport more or less stable replay
after a replay attack detection bypass
in a more or less standard environment
so this was recorded in a cafe from from
5 meters her shots were set to normal so
it was both acceptable by the business
and it was well quite secure the process
was hacked
so the modifications sent in the last
step was well it played a huge role but
it was not the only attack vector the
tests were
gray box so it required turning off the
and during the identifying threshold
face but that's not a big it's not a big
deal if if you can um if you can create
like hundreds of accounts you'll
probably you'll probably get through
even without turning off the replay
attack detection and there was no IDs so
we had a lot of new accounts for testing
and ourselves was not increasing right
well there are some limitations the
interesting part
well interesting part is how we did the
impersonation phase so we need to
automate the request and gather the
responses so I use basic setup we've
scribe for pie it's just a Python client
for for connecting to Skype API it's not
perfect but it's but it's working max
one connection per time this was quite a
big restriction it was easy to integrate
and and it actually generated its own
noise so so this helped a lot as well
but any other voice over IP solution
will work you can also do a trick with
playing the recordings from the mobile
application using a jack jack cable and
reprogramming the audio input and output
then you need to relay the audio input
and output that was quite easy
so the spoofer was in in bash and python
and and with parvo control I turned off
the physical microphone the audio output
from from the recordings I played was
transferred to the Skype audio input the
Skype audio output was transferred into
the microphone so that it gets back to
the to the to the phone line and then
well a play will talk to scribe and a
record will collect from scribe we need
to dial in to the IV air mode and the IV
R user so we need to use the DTMF tones
that's quite easy you just play some
wave proper wavelengths through socks
and then the response gathering so it's
perfect if you have an API access if you
are testing a mobile app but within the
form test you don't have it so we can do
some free speech recognition like pocket
Sphinx but it will
currently in English we can do well
Google client speech or amazing Alexa
but you can do well gathered the
response and just analyze the length of
the response so if the system says it's
authentic Asian rejected it will last
for around two seconds right the other
one will last for three seconds so we
can do a few tricks in socks just cut
the noise at some level here is forty
fourteen percent pass it to some scripts
and you've got the which you've got the
response so the the aftermath and the
end up process was that we take the next
voice print that we generated we call
the number Donal DTMF tones to get to
the menu play the voice print then we
collect the response based on that we
decide whether to play it again or just
end the call and analyze it and add it
to the results it's good to ask the
provider the vendor to for recordings on
the providers side simply because
something may not work in your scripts
and you you can be passing some some
crap any and you won't know why it's not
working so that's good to do alright
last few ideas about hacking the
integration within the mobile apps so in
one of these solutions the post requests
that well the voice was sent in a post
request
so here was some WAV file contents and
there was a parameter in the same
request F being 44100 so well it's easy
to guess what was that it was a
frequency what happened if you change
this frequency to one the system will
try to I don't know extract the audio
with the same limit of the file but it
will try to generate a file which is
44,000 longer and will dass the system
so often biometrics is actually
implemented as a separate box it's just
a box that is solved by the vendor and
put in somewhere in between the IVR
Channel and the banking system the web
and ID or mobile code is often a third
party so the
the telecoms the bank's the
corporation's they don't control of they
don't have a control of software and of
the libraries inside the inside the
mobile applications
all right the HTTP requests may have
another endpoint so another well as
separate man-in-the-middle tests can be
useful for just for the voice recording
function not just for the whole
application which is connected to the
bank but to the vendor and the voice
authenticated sessions should be
distinguished from the starter ones why
for the fraud detection so if some
attack happens on the voice well voice
authenticated session it may be useful
to just I don't know maybe not turn off
the whole voice biometric
allow users to make transfers only to
the trusted beneficiaries and not to
everybody for example all right so the
summary I always say pentas without the
Fred model is bug bounty hunting well
business assumptions business rules will
help you design the test scenarios
especially when the more you know about
the system the more test cases will you
be able to do design turn off the
landing mode the replay attack detection
to identify the thresholds or well
prepare many accounts but that could be
even 500 there were thousand accounts
solutions integrated in mobile apps tend
to be more secure simply because there
are already pay paired so you can't do
the horizontal brute-force alright so
after all generally voice biometrics is
a good idea
but it should be tested thoroughly and
currently the thresholds the false
acceptance rates
we're not there yet it's it's not it
should not be implemented in all of the
places now and let's do the voice
biometry because there is already other
there are already other teams working on
doing the opposite
all right so soon to break AI and
machine learnings based solutions we
will need AI to design test cases and
it's not only about voice biometrics
it's also about hacking web applications
when the web application fire
all is based on AI and attacking the
networks because of behavioral network
traffic analysis we will need that I am
working on an OS tip sheet for for the
voice biometrics solution and generally
for biometrics non-functional security
requirements for voice biometrics I'm
trying to cooperate with some biometric
vendors they're not really happy while
voice biometrics vendors hate me and
corporations will come with some privacy
movements because they actually care
about the security of the voice and the
recordings there is no draft a little
bit here but if you want to help I'm
open to any form of help all right thank
you very much you can follow me on
Twitter and if you have any questions
please ask them now