everybody like thanks for coming like
right after a lunchtime I know it's not
that easy
you guys probably want to rest and so on
but yeah thank you very much for your
time and coming here so yeah I'm gonna
speak briefly about detection of honey
pots of of the types of low in media
interaction who here like has heard of
honey pots before good quite a lot of
people who is currently operating honey
pot come on beautiful
I know you're here okay and who is
actually operating a capo or curry SSH
honey pot I probably detect your honey
pots here all the way so yeah so
basically Who am I like about myself
like I'm director of professional
services Blaine's from each security be
around security community for a while
like probably more years than I can
remember and now you actually live in
Krakow and I really like it here pretty
much so here is like a briefly roadmap
about the presentation so what's going
to be disgusted and what to expect from
it we're gonna start with the brief
overview honey pots discuss a bit of the
prior art so I mean what people has done
before in terms of detection of honey
pots I speak about also why are honey
pots front to detection and we have a
case study on detecting a pop where SSH
honey pot that's namely keepo and carry
and also about the experiment that I had
of this internet wide scanning of SSH
honeypot so like blowing the cover of a
bunch of honey pots of people out there
and also the closing remarks about the
presentation so a brief review of honey
pots so honey pot like assimilates a
real vulnerable system I have like this
asterisk here because sometimes is
actually a real system is not only just
the the simulation per se and this
concept is pretty old this pans back
from the from the eighties actually from
this book of Clifford Stoll the Cuckoo's
egg is which is actually a must must
read who for whoever's interested in
information security and this is like
consider like a pretty like important
acet for those doing two at research and
threat intelligence and so on because
well a lot of people use honey pots to
catch malware to catch like to do
statistics on attacks and so on and also
it obviously helps to learn about to
statics and procedures of an adversary
and actually lately it's been gaining a
lot of momentum because a lot of
companies are actually offering some
like commercial honeypot solutions in
this so-called cyber deception
technologies actually just like another
remark so most of this presentation like
the content itself it was actually done
three years ago but it was never really
published it was just publish it in in a
small private conference so these like
back then these there was no such thing
as this cyber deception knowledge I mean
obviously there was but it was not as
big as it's being lately so I'm talking
about the different types of honeypot
so about the interaction levels we have
like low medium and high interaction and
obviously each of them have different
advantages and disadvantages and the
focus of the presentation will be on the
detection of medium interaction honey
pots low internal honey pots they're
just way too easy to detect really it's
not even worth like the time so I
decided to actually focus to have like
the special focus on the detection of
media interaction ones so the low
interaction level it provides this very
basic functionality to enumerate the
service so for example there is this
spam pot that's like there in the bottom
so it just it emulates a vulnerable SMTP
service but it has only very very basic
very raw functionalities which means
that anything that goes a bit above like
bit beyond sorry what the the normal
cycle of connecting to an SMTP
authenticating and sending email you
it just doesn't implement so it means
that just like SuperDuper easy to detect
because pretty much every other
functionality is just missing so it
usually it's done
just to detect something very very
specific and yeah like I think it's not
very popular these days at least again
like when it's only for something
specific but if you want to actually get
there more information you better use
something else there is the media
interaction honey pots it has this
enhancer interaction so and it's also
pretty popular with the track research
community there is a pretty low barrier
of entry and also low maintenance and
examples like people curry compost
compost like a SCADA one that it kind of
emulates nuclear plant kind of thing and
so on and people use this to lure
attackers in to try to attempt like
different attacks and try to observe it
and high interaction honey pots they are
usually fully functioning systems with
extra logging or instrumentation
capabilities to actually gather
information and advantage like you can
use it to the discover an opener
abilities because wow it's a real system
so people might use an actual zero-day
to try to pop your your box there but
there is also one this is one of those
advantages like first of all like the
this is a very high maintenance cost
because it's an actual machine and also
the compromised the house can be used it
to attack orders so it's obviously a
good idea to actually isolate these from
a firewall perspective and so on out of
your network and this is actually this
example like people I think these days
use more discussed on PM's and send
different sensors to collect logs but a
long time ago there was a Beck it was
like an L km for for Linux that also got
a lot of discrimination let me perform
this sort of instrumentation in the
kernel to collect all this data later
that was all obviously some previous
work and iPod detection because
especially because I think it started
gaining momentum with the honey project
and so on around early 2000
like late 90s early 2000s and obviously
this attracted the interest of the the
computer security community but like the
offensive security community and and
some black hats as well to know if whoa
if they're actually being trapped or not
so obviously yes those prior art on this
subject and I when I was doing this
research I found a lot of academic work
using like support vector machines and
like and a bunch of other things that I
don't know maybe I'm too dumb or but
just this thing just just didn't look
practical and back then like in the
early 2000s I say like most of it was
actually revolving around the attacks of
virtual machines but well we are not
interested at you anymore like just the
technique that you're inside a virtual
machine is not a reliable indicator that
it's a honeypot these days and this
one's a back if it sounds polish right
semuc it was detected innovating the
fake version of frack 63 is 62 and also
like other people like for example Joe
uber Hyde and this guy's mannish career
they wrote a paper like the technique
honey tea and I think it was around 2006
so since then so we're talking about
like a gap of some 10 years or so that
people haven't done any sort of work in
the tech thing the technique honey pots
or if they doing they are not really
publishing or it didn't really get much
publicity also this guy from rapid7 and
a dreamer is they did some work in
detecting keepo from a pre authenticated
perspective like keepo is one of the
objectives of our detection here in this
presentation and also these techniques
they were made public and they were
patched so I'm expecting actually the
same techniques that are going to be
described it here to be patch it in the
near future but yeah but there is plenty
of other is like it's easy to define
seriously
and most of the textual techniques for
for like the SSH honey pots they
actually rely on the post authentication
which means that you actually have to be
lured inside the trap already and then
when you're interacting with the system
you're gonna tell them oh this is not
real were your system because lots of
functionalities are missing and so on so
the idea here is actually to
attacked it from a completely pure
dedicated perspective which means that
we're gonna not even fall inside the
trap and tell from like before
connecting unauthenticated to their
service that they think is a honeypot
also this guy Darren marching that was
like one of the guys from below sacked
by the way he found like a few ways to
detect kompot honeypot and this was
introducing to show them there is this
service of showdowns called honey score
that you type the IP address and you
will say oh this is like like a cicada
honey poet or something so why are they
detection prone so the low in media
interaction they are nowhere close to
amulet of like real target system and
they have like lots of incomplete
features as I said so this is why is
pretty easy like as soon as you're there
you just can tell immediately that thing
is also um it's not a real system and
also there is for example the some of
the implementation are not compliant
with the RFC's for example and so on so
there are different ways to tell that
again like some functionalities they
will behave in a certain way in a real
system and when you try against these
both these simulated ones they just
don't they behave differently or they
don't even have these features indeed
high interaction like a significantly
harder to detect again like in 2002 or
something people were detecting or
inside the virtual machine this is a
honeypot well not really the case these
days especially where everything's
virtualized everything is on the cloud
and so on but still the affront to
detection like Seebeck don't like a cup
of different ways that people use it to
detect its presence in the system
but then again all the maintenance
pre-high so I think this one the reasons
that people like a lot to use this low
sorry the media interaction ones and
let's go to the case study so like
Carrie keepo like I'd like the most
popular SSH honey pots these days and
all they emulated shell first started it
doesn't really provide a very complete
bash terminal
and then many comments are also missing
so once your site does it say like it's
pretty easy to detect but then also like
it's not super difficult to detect
before you fall into the trap so this is
actually the inside the shell of a real
inner system this is just this fall in
back it will say like this like a echo
is this real like three three times
doing this loop but when you try these
inside SSH honeypot these things just
like common not found so it means that
like it didn't really implement some
functionality from bash but then it's
not really our objective for the
presentation like we want to detect it
from even before getting there so the
basic idea was actually to understand
the behavior of OpenSSH and and the
behavior of keep on carry from a prio
tentacle perspective so in pre
authentication what we have we have
cipher suite advertisement banner divert
alignment compression algorithms and so
on so basically the whole key exchange
and the initial handshake and the idea
is to see how it will react to different
handshakes in the opposite sage and in
honey pots and take note of these
differences so we can do this like
without wasting time like brute forcing
passwords and so on
for a system that's fake so this is like
some of the protest occasion pre
authenticated detection techniques I
elicit four of them here but there are
plenty of more if you spend some time
look at it there is a bad version so
essentially when you ssh client
advertise itself to the server it says
like sshh - 2 dot o - Oh pssh blah blah
version of the banner of the client so
in in Korean keepo whenever it sees of
ssh version that's not either 1.99 or
chu which are the only ssh versions that
actually standardize it keep up with all
this bad
version error whereas Oh pssh we'll
throw something else's I think is like
protocol mismatch or is like protocol
measure difference is like something
like that so it definitely throws a very
different error that you can tell that
thing is not an obvious Sh as it claims
to be there is also this double banner
so when you send the burner twice like
we sent the banner and then a carriage
return line feed the burner again Oh
pssh we'll just ignore the last banner
and Oh finally we'll proceed with the
whole key exchange thing whereas it
would just throw when it comes to Korean
keepo it would just throw like a packet
corrupt error so again another way to
detect it this one's really funny when
you send like eight couriers returns
like with nothing else again Oh pssh
respond like actually fine and then the
other one would throw over this packet
corrupt or protocol mismatch error and
also fuzzy key exchange so some of the
with this initial key exchange and say
like with the whole thing with
advertisement of the cipher Suites and
the compression algorithms if you get
even that further that comes with the
Metasploit of key exchange if you throw
it against OpenSSH it will not break
whereas if you throw it against korean
keepo which by the way it under the hood
uses twisted twisted matrix you know
like python twisted for its SSH servers
it throws like a thousands of different
exceptions so you can tell that some of
this Fawcett key exchange when you try
them against SSH SSH just sometimes
gives an error but it's a very robust
error and gives back like a message like
kind of hey like protocol mismatch or
something whereas the other one just
crashes big-time and nothing comes back
so you can tell there is not an
operation as it was advertising so here
is just like some code like I think it's
very bad to read I'm sorry but you guys
will be able to see this in these lights
but if you see here like in this blue
thing that I made a circle eta is like
RFC section blah blah ask for streaked
carriage return line feed we are more
relaxed it so it says like it's not even
super combined with our FC so also these
differences you can tell you can tell
apart from Oh pssh and these honey pot
ones this is what I was just saying
about the bed version so sorry yeah and
also here it will say like Oh bed
version and so on when the when this
line here like this for loop and these
conditions are not satisfied it would
throw this bad version error whereas
here it would throw something else a
protocol which is different and this is
also like pretty bad read sorry for that
but this is the the key exchange
procedure of twisted and if you see
there is no such thing as a try accept
or any sort of try catch like nothing so
it that's why it crashes big time with
these are handled exceptions there is
this like an again like an example of
this by the way this host like honey pot
that whatever that IO is my server and
it's gonna be there for like the next
week so you guys can actually try by
yourself like all these techniques here
being described so in the first one you
can see here like the port 22 is
actually uh OpenSSH the real one and
whenever you say this SSH this bad
version you just say like protocol
mismatch whereas the other one we give
this bad version errors as we just
mentioned and now for like a quick live
demo actually it's not quite live
because of the have internet here but I
have a video oh no actually I do have
internet yeah I don't have so is it good
to read quite bad now maybe the video
yeah so here we are using this script
that that I published today are actually
to detect curry keepo against the actual
OpenSSH server and if you see here like
it test like some of these techniques to
just mention and it will say oh this is
not a honeypot but when you try against
the port 20 22 it says yes like it's a
trap it's a honeypot
I think 20 22 is curry and the other one
is keepo 20 like the choo-choo choo-choo
like same story they definitely keep a
honey pot because use some of these
techniques that I just mentioned but
then again it's super easy to find
different ones and create your own
probes for that oh let's go back
all right so I also like some some false
positives actually when with some of
these techniques because some
misconfigured Oh pssh servers especially
there is a version of 5.3 or something
that he keeps throwing this packet
corrupt errors and I actually don't know
don't know why and this script that I
just released that let me just show to
you guys and what please do they on
github
it uses these different techniques and
gives a score rick depending on which
response comes back and then if the
score is higher than two we consider
this as a honeypot we have this
certainty of like a degree of confidence
that these things honeypot so then
obviously i decided to do like internet
white scanning to find them all and the
objectives would like to map the entire
internet for to find them to find also a
suitable to through allow us to do
internet wide scanning and plot them in
a map for visualization purposes because
like it's just much cooler to actually
have to like have this visualization of
this whole thing and finally well detect
all the things that was the final goal
and here's like a brief explanation
using masks and for our goals like i'm
sure that you guys are familiar with
masks can mask hands like this port
scanner that like you can do internet
wide scans in just a couple of hours and
it also has a great feature that it
detects banners that also it has a bear
this little-known feature that it's
possible to actually send some sort of
payload it's called hello string here in
base64 so whenever you connect into
something you can send like some sort of
payload and get the whatever response
back however the burner grabbing
functionality of masks can well it does
what it's supposed to do like to do a
banner grabbing so it does a parsing of
the banner so whenever it sees a
response that comes ssh one point
something o as I say CH two point
something it will get only that banner
and whatever comes after the carriage
early return in line feed it would just
ignore
so you would doing the proper parsing of
the burner but then again if you
remember correctly in our in our
detection probes we need not only this
response but also whatever comes later
saying like an error or something like
this so it means that we have to do some
sort of modification in in math scanner
so I just this was actually probably the
least elegant way possible to do this
but they just kind of corrupted like my
scanner in the sense that whenever it
sees SSH 1.2 or 1.3 1.0 or 2.0 it will
trigger this parser right that we only
get the banner and ignore everything
else so I just corrupted it instead of
like I just changed it to H and P so you
would never see this which means that it
will get not only what comes there and
whatever also information because that's
what we needed so I'm sure there was a
much better way to do this but this was
like just like the the crappy way that I
that I found to do and turns out that it
works so that's actually what I wanted
so notes about the experiment like I got
the VPS with digital ocean like a
Goa'uld it's pretty cheap VPS it took
like on average some 20 hours to scan
the entire internet for honey pots and
the logs had like around from nine
hundred Meg's so it means they're like
oh these five dollar chip creepy asses
they will do the job quite well but then
really be prepared to handle those of
abuse complaints per day but like too
many of them I used to get it turns out
that spam house and all these people
days I practically don't know how to
differentiate just a simple TCP connect
to port 22 from an actual active brute
force so I was always responding and
putting like in the end say oh I'm just
doing some research and so on and after
actually a month of getting complaints
every single day they just decided to
freeze my VPS but yeah but at least I
got the results I wanted but so I
recommend doing this if you want to do
some River experiment but be prepared
you might gonna get kicked out from this
notion
so the methodology was like to mask
imports 2202 choo-choo-choo-choo with
the detection strings that we that we
just talked before triage these results
and as I said like some of them have
this pattern of like Bob sorry this
Packard corrupt think that it was not a
very reliable indicator so which means
that all of these then had these
problems I was passing them through in
my detection script so and then plotting
everything in a map just look cool and
well I'm sorry like apparently is not
that great to read to see the the map
but this is like the the mapping of some
of the honey pots there were detected so
these are the results but it was very
funny like there had a very unexpected
result when I was doing these these
whole scanning and so on and it's still
like I'm not sure if this was like an
elaborate joke or somebody really
screwed up their job so when I was
scanning the whole internet like there
was this very funny banner that appeared
if you guys can see it's called GCHQ
honeypot 34 and GCHQ honeypot 12 and
GCHQ like photos who don't know is like
the equivalent of the NSA in britain and
obviously the IP addresses are redacted
here but if you got them put them in max
mind you're gonna see that if they are
from Leiter Kingdom this is the
coordinates the accuracy radios and if
you put this in Google Maps
it's actually very close to mi5 the
security service of Britain and then if
you go to the website of mi5 this is
like we work very closely with the GCHQ
so I don't know really if this was just
like a very very elaborate joke or if
somebody just in GCHQ just doesn't know
how to configure their honey pots and
the closing remarks is just like they're
very valuable tools definitely I'm not
against them but if you're doing try to
research bear in mind that they are very
very easy to be detected
and then this whole thing of detection
it's gonna be like really a
cat-and-mouse game it's like an arms
race because as I said before like some
of these techniques for the tackling
keep oh they were released and then some
people just came patched most likely
they've got a patch some of these
techniques that are made being made
public today but then if you're
interested you can just find your own as
well and do the scanning again there
will always be a way to detect at least
this mini interaction honey pots for
sure and also if you are trying to
research her if you're solely relying on
this for your intelligence you're pretty
much screwed because this doesn't really
provide a very reliable indicator like
against like an actual the determinate
adversary and then a high interaction on
honey pot who most likely I held like
much better results but it comes with a
cost specially of maintenance and yeah
the scripts and supporting material can
all be found in our github repository
and that's all that I have for today so
thank you very much for coming
[Applause]
so I think like question time now
I don't have much experience with
honeypot so my question may be silly but
I just wanted to ask - what's the main
advantage of this high-level honeypot
framers you mentioned in comparison to
the custom virtual machines set up to
the extensive logging for example do
some external network device or like
custom setup is it all about the
simplicity of the setup or well I think
you like mostly about the same place of
setup for sure I think there will be but
also like don't get me wrong I also
don't have much experience of honey pots
I just want to attack them and like it's
like just like to around with
somebody's day that's it but I don't
I actually don't operate them I mean I
do like until next week so you guys can
actually play with what's there but it's
not really my field I'm like penetration
testing and so on but yeah I think like
mostly the simplicity of the whole thing
don't know the questions so thank you
[Applause]