thank you very much so let me start
maybe before we will go to the main part
of the presentation a small disclaimer
that presented work disseminates results
of my own activities which were done
using solely on private resources
therefore the opinions views presented
in this talk may not necessarily express
the opinion and views and policy of my
employer and also examples which you'll
see in this talk are for demonstration
purposes and do not necessarily reflect
the real-world product okay so the main
question of today's talk is can we trust
integrated circuits and silicon chips
and to answer this question we must
answer another question namely do we
have a choice because due to the
technological barriers high production
costs we must count on manufacturers
honesty and popularity and there are
whole countries which now don't have own
silicon production so and also there are
there there are many organizations and
companies which must buy integrated
circuits because they cannot afford
production so what they are doing is
they commonly buy use high-volume
products from leading manufacturers
counting on the honesty on the fact that
due to the popularity of those circuits
it will be easier to detect threads and
the consequences will be severe this is
possible in the mainframe computing in
telecommunication is more difficult and
it's very difficult in the embedded
world especially Internet of Things
where you have a lot of small
manufacturers so already this approach
buying from a big producer is not
available to everyone and then but comes
the question is there a reason for a
concern is is equipment from a large
supplier safe and what is the threat
what it can do actually if we'll have
such a hardware Trojan so is it worth to
get a closer look so this presentation
has fought as an introduction to the
domain assuming that you have mainly a
software background so it will show you
actually
the topics the introduction what can be
done rather than how it precisely is
done to give you a broad overview okay
so before we start just to check that we
are on the same page what is the
hardware Trojan Hardware Trojan is a
definitely it's a function of a hardware
component hidden from the user which can
add remove or modify the functionality
of hardware component and therefore read
reduce its reliability or create a
potential threat so here we have a
simple signal which is an inverter and
in order to introduce in this circuit
Hardware Trojan in integrated circuit
would have to firstly do the payload
modification which means that we are
modifying the circuit here we are adding
and gate and next we are adding a
trigger so it's a signal activating the
payload triggers can be combinational
sequential as as you want but all in all
it's modifying the signal which is going
to inverter and we can get different
result than we thought will get so what
are the similarities to software Trojans
first of all its intention its
infiltration exfiltration so either to
get the data out of the company either
to allow easier attack and also their
designers would like to hide this
functionality from from from other users
so it's seldom activation however there
are very strong differences
first of all Hardware Trojans in
integrated circuits cannot be removed
post deployment so then possibilities of
updates of circuits are very limited
you have micro coded machines but but
this is definitely very expensive having
very limited approach later on those
Trojans do not spread
they must be manufacture which means
either you have an equipment which has a
hardware Trojan ID either you don't and
once you have it one it's on and on on
the market it will be always there you
cannot remove it with an update
so manufacturer has a problem and then
we have high production costs
in terms of equipment and then a skilled
labor but understood as an amount of
money which you need to do to train this
these people so don't forget also about
the most popular option where we have
which is it's still the hardware
software core design so some parts of
such a Trojan are done in the hardware
some are done in software so just a
brief review of the history the history
of hardware Trojan started in 2005 with
this famous report from Department of
Defense which claimed that there is a
possibility of modification of
integrated circuit in the fab in the
silicon fabrication unit so it's at the
very end of the chain and here is the
number of publications with towards
Hardware Trojans in Google Scholar as
you may see it's skyrocketing in between
we've got Snowden offer in 2014 which
showed that actually there are big
organization and institutions like NSA
which are very interested in this kind
of threats so we have last year more
than two 2006 600 publications
concerning hardware Trojan so it's a
definitely hot topic so maybe this is
the first reason to get a look on it
those 2,500 publication has proven
actually that there is a wide variety of
possible Trojan deployments so you may
have different size you can modify
transistors wires if they can be big you
can modify whole eyepiece gates they can
be tightly distributed on a chip so in
the same place they can be spread along
the chip in different places to make it
harder to find them they may modify the
layout but they do not necessarily have
to same width trigger so activation they
can be externally activated for some
radio connection or they can be
internally activated so by set of
conditions it can be sensor data if a
chip has sensors or logic internal state
clock counter some input instruction so
where
go from here in order to give you a
hands-on experience to see how
complicated such a modification of
integrated circuit can be we'll start
with a cpu example with a live demo and
later on I will talk about where and
when can such a modification be
introduced in the process of the chip
manufacturing and finally we'll talk
briefly about methods and of Defense of
detection and their costs so just a
brief review I'm sure that you all know
but all our software security is based
on one basic assumption namely that the
operation of an underlying processor and
its hardware is predefined and and it's
working according to a strict
specification and a set of predefined
rules so commonly applied is prot
protection or protection domains which
were introduced in 70s already so it's
50 years in in multix which is
predecessor of Unix so we have at least
two modes of processor work its
hypervisor and user or kernel kernel and
user mode in hypervisor mode kernel has
access to all comments and addresses in
user mode it has only access to a subset
of commands and addresses and the
transition between those modes as can
happen only according to a predefined
and strictly defined set of rules
Siskel's interrupts and the holy grail
of the majority of exploits is to get
into the kernel mode to have an access
to two whole space so I will show you an
example of SPARC architecture how it is
defined in the manuals so you've got
privileged commands which are which can
be assembly comments which can be only
executed in the in the hypervisor mode
when the processor in hypervisor mode
you have here in SPARC case supervisor
mode and user mode defined already in
the manual and here you have an excerpt
from instruction set architecture where
some commands have a small cross next to
it which means they are privileged and I
selected two of you this is a problem
maybe you can see them but this is read
processor state register and the right
processor state register this
register contains the information which
mode the processor actually is and both
comments are available only in
supervisor mode which means that the
user cannot change the value of this
register when he's in the user mode it
must go through this hardware software
co.design procedure of switching the
mode
so then how in order to explain how this
security mechanism which we would like
to elaborate is implemented we have to
review very briefly the how processor is
processing the comments usually we have
this risk pipeline a pipeline with five
stages of comment processing its
instruction fetch instruction decode
execute memory and write back they have
a counterparts in data path it's they
are using instruction memory register
although you need data memory and
registers once again and moreover we
have a pipeline which means that all the
stages are executed at the same time but
for different instructions so then when
we are implementing this Hardware
security mechanism on each stage what
happens
so each stage has a different
instruction but what we are doing is
actually this is a big while loop done
in Hardware where we are firstly trying
to decode the address of instruction
from instruction memory and if we see
that processor is in the wrong state we
have an exception we have a trap
interrupt the same if we are decoding
the opcode of the instruction we are
checking in hardware this is a big if
realized with transistors if this
instruction is legal if this instruction
is available in this mode of the
processor and so on and so forth so here
you see an example from LAN free spark
processor open source VHDL
implementation and and here you see that
we have some instructions which are
available in user mode and then you have
here they are decoding the opcode so
when the instruction is in the user mode
they are not doing anything but when we
have instruction which is privileged
they are checking if the processor is in
the core
mode and if it's not in the correct mode
you have Trump so when we would like to
implement the Trojan what would be our
payload in this case we would like to
change the value of processor state
register and switch to the hypervisor
mode however the trigger should be
available in the user mode so this
should be selected assembly command
which is available in the user mode and
we'll select the topper and so it can be
ad which is giving us the result 8 7 8 7
8 7 this is for the sake of simplicity
of this talk so here we have example of
hardware software code design so there
is a software code which is triggering a
payload done in hardware so this is a
payload which was published in my
article from the polling conference it's
a fragment of the other unit as you see
a unit has an access to the special
register types so also the control
register it's very simple it's only free
liner we are just checking
what was the result of the addition done
by the hollow unit and we are changing
the state of the register so as you see
those are three lines of the VHDL code
which will translate to a very small
circuit it will be it won't change the
size of the chip and only now it's
leveraging its switching that the mode
of the processor work so now if you
would like to test for yourself how such
a hardware Trojan is working what it can
do to your to your equipment comes the
question do you need a silicon
fabrication unit no probably not
actually if you can emulate a processor
which is working correctly you can also
emulate a processor or integrated
circuit which which has a backdoor
inside so for the purpose of this
presentation I will use camera am elated
emulator for the SPARC architecture the
code is compatible with the with the
VHDL code from from the Geisler I will
use a regular Linux kernel in version
411 so it's fairly new and the
implementation and details of the
implementation sources you can find on
my github page
so in camel the you have this translate
file which is basically going through
all instructions from ISA which
instructions that architecture which you
are trying to emulate and it's
translated them to the in this case x86
instructions so here we have a read
processor state register instruction and
we know that it's privileged so here the
first thing which which camo is doing is
checking what's the mode of work of the
processor and if not it's we have it's
rising a trap so then when we will try
to add a Trojan payload we'll do this in
the signed divide assembly instruction
and we'll simply put those couple of
lines it's also free liner where we are
whenever we are doing sign divided with
this operands we are changing the style
of the processor register so it's very
simple that's that's that's the point so
let me show you how does it work so here
it's firstly we will just run this
routes let me okay
okay now it's better so this is a
regular application what we are doing
here is we are doing a regular we are
doing a regular division 1024 is 63 so
we are not activating our Trojan we have
an inline assembly which is right now
commented but I will uncomment it later
so we are printing the result and we are
doing something stupid we are not very
good programmers so we are doing the
null pointer the reference so I have
here a running Linux kernel and then
here's the output so what we have here
we have a segmentation fault as it was
supposed to be so later on what we'll do
is firstly I will uncomment this line so
we while being in the user mode I will
try to execute a privileged instruction
I will recombine the code
I will copy it to the unit to our
virtual machine and let this run it once
again so right now we have this trap
it's illegal instruction we are trying
to do something which is which is
illegal so right now we'll run the same
code but a bit different what we are
doing here is we are changing the second
operand to 64 yes yes
oops
okay so the sources are available on my
website let's maybe let's let's do this
afterwards but what you what you have
here basically is what we'll do is we'll
just do this division 1024 by 64 then
we'll just try to read with this Inland
assembly right try to read the PSR then
we'll try to write again something to
PSR because if we're in kernel mode we
should be able to do this then I will
check if the result of this operation
stays the same and if it stays the same
then I will print the PSR and finally
we'll switch once again to the
supervisor mode and do this dummy null
pointer there if there are reference
okay so first of all what we see here is
that the result of the division has not
changed so the whole operation was
conducted in the background secondly we
could read the value of the PSR so it's
switched really to the hypervisor mode
and went back so the eighth bit of the
PSR register PSI register has other
values they did change to the supervisor
mode and finally because we are in the
kernel mode no pointer the reference
cannot be handled properly so it's it's
it has crashed simply but it shows that
we are we have denial of service and now
comes the question how would you look
and how would you detect that the crash
disk crash at this moment of execution
from the logs was caused by some
functionality which was realized in the
background and hardware okay
good so we've seen that it's not that
difficult it's very simple modification
of a circuit so now comes the question
where when where and when it can be
introduced so I will discuss it based on
the stages of a hardware of a chip
design so first we have a logic design
so this is a very high level when we are
deciding what the functionality do and
we are only giving clues how it should
be done or how should it be translated
to real circuits with capacitors and
transistors so it's usually done in a
hardware description language it can be
very long it can be system very large it
can be VHDL as in the CPU example which
we've seen so the introduction of Trojan
will be very similar to introduction
Trojan in a software you're adding as
you've seen couple of lines this is
relatively cheap
however because Hardware cannot be
changed in post deployment the hardware
the it's you have a severe testing 80%
of that hardware design is of cost of
hardware design is a cost by testing
which means that if you are creating
this Hardware Trojan in this stage this
code will be tested over and over that's
the biggest amount of the workers the
the highest number of workers which are
devoted to this face and it's very hard
to keep it hidden from from your own
corporation even or organization so what
you could do is you could do obfuscation
so we could create a code which is
semantically correct but difficult to
understand or you can it's obviously
easier in bigger projects which have a
severe backward compatibility like x86
architecture which has a features which
are necessary just to run code which is
50 years old at the second part second
stage we have synthesis so from this
high level description we are getting
the real circuits with capacitors and
transistors right now it can be the
metaphor the software metaphor would be
a code compilation process so right now
in majority of projects the synthesis is
done automatically
using the tools so here the Trojan would
be already introduced as a modification
of electronic circuits so you need new
wires new transistors new capacitors
this is a low-level approach there are
reasons why people are compiling
electrical circuits because it's very
costly and very complicated and here you
have two possibilities either you are
working with compiled code so with a
compiled circuits generated circuits but
then these are normally optimized and
and they are not prepared or not
designed to be read by humans or your or
modification can happen during the
compilation process so the so during the
synthesis process so then comes the
question who is checking the code which
compiler produces at the output so here
it's easier to hide because we have less
developers involved and because we tend
to trust our tools which we are using
but it requires qualified and
experienced personnel and this is costly
so it's not not that easy and still we
can use the white box cryptography so
produce complicated layouts to hide the
the final functionality and finally we
have mask design so from the lions who
are you we are creating masks so we
should be used during the production of
wafers so we could obviously we could
modify those masks but we are not doing
it by scratching with a scalpel that the
real masks we are using it by creating a
new sets of masks this happens on the
far end of the design process so this is
a very hard to detect it's a low
abstraction level it's it's extremely
hard to detect but you need very very
skilled personnel expensive tool
know-how and preferably market position
you have to have your own fabrication
unit and here is an important point and
each of those stages is done usually by
a different entity within the
organization by a different or by
different subcontractor different
company which means whenever the layout
is coming to the fab usually they are
not testing the functionality if you
want to print something out people are
known are usually not asking what you
want to print they are just telling you
ok for printing that that will be the
price the same with integrated circuits
so and the lower you are in this phases
of the chip design the harder it is
actually to to detect this this
malicious functionality that's what
Department of Defense wrote in their
report so what are methods of Defense
very briefly we are we are working with
the majority of us it's it's using post
manufacturing Trojan detection we are
buying a chip and we have to do
something with it we have to check it so
first of all it's very difficult and
expensive it's not an easy task the most
straightforward approach is based on the
golden ship principle so we have to have
an idea how a circuit should look like
without the treasure if we have this
idea and I strongly as in I want to say
if we have this possibility then we have
to firstly get the chip here is a very
old epoxy case from 80s from Intel there
are several methods to achieve it you
can do it mechanically or you can do it
chemically or both
however it's it's difficult because
preferably you want to take out this
case and do not touch the chip even if
you're doing it will face it you don't
want this this is it it's not every
substance because you don't want to
modify the functioning of a chip why let
me show you it here here we have a photo
of a z80 processor it's a very old one
but this this processors from 70s 80s
maybe early 90s or the one which you can
do in as a hobbyist they are in a very
high or very old ancient and silicon
production technology 1500 nanometers or
so so if you are trying to read such a
silicon it's firstly you have to realize
that it's highly optimized due to
technical and economical reasons so not
reason not all the reasons are obvious
for instance in the Z T we have this
register Bank over there and the
register according to the documentation
Tsar 8-bit however the implementation
is a four-bit which is working in two
cycles why in modern computers it makes
no sense but at that time when this chip
was designed they made some other
decisions and they said we don't want
this ratio registers to be single cycle
access because other components of this
chip are very slow it's an economical
decision then and the chips works in
parallel so we all know that to the to
debauch the parallel code is very
difficult and here we would have to
really stimulate those inputs which you
have on the edges of the chip to see
what's happening in the chip to see what
parts of the chip are active during
which operation and finally we have
legacy functions so we have some parts
of the chip which may not necessarily be
directly connected with the basic
functionality so what we would do is we
would cut each layer because it's a 3d
design and we would make a photo scan it
with electron microscope and compare it
to this layout from the golden chip
design so the pro it's a very high
reliability of detection if you have a
golden chip the question is how you get
a golden ship from leading manufacturers
they are not showing you your that their
layout you don't know how to how the i7
should look like or or that its main
functionality is same for for
telecommunication devices also it's very
expensive time consuming and destroys
the chip under analysis so if you are
ordering one hundred thousand for
instance integrated circuits or chips
and you're getting them how percentage
of them you know what's the percentage
of them which you would like to
sacrifice to check if you if they have a
Trojan if it's I don't know one two
percent firstly those are losses for
your corporation it will be very time
consuming because you have still a lot
of chips to test and finally what about
98% which are left you haven't tested
them and the last question is is it
enough is such an inspection which I
showed you enough to answer this
question look at this simple inverter
this is the example from our from the
beginning of this talk we have here it's
it's a very simple circuit we have two
transistors depending on the input
signal either one is open
Muhtar close or opposite way around so
this is giving you the simple internal
inverter functionality and here is the
trojan every one of you can answer the
question in which of them is trojan the
answer is actually you have to check
what are the dopants inside of this of
this of this gate because this is how
the gate will look like on the
integrated circuit when you will make a
photo and then will appear then in the a
circuit you have two different you have
two different transistors but in the P
circuit you have a Trojan because you
have twice the same transistor the
circuit is always half open and the
signal is wrong so optical inspection in
this case is not enough you have to go
deeper you have to check what's actually
inside so where it can be used this is
actually proposed to be used against
cryptography or crypto engines security
units here's example of AES based on an
excellent power presentation from the
last year 2017 from Germany in AES and
Jean you need a random input you have to
register first is random register 32
bits which should be random but due to
the aging due to the temperature they
may not be that random as you would like
them to be so you have also counter
register which is just incrementing
based on the number of operations and
you're using it to get the AES input for
for crypto key so with while doing the
dopant rogent you could fix the number
of the of random really numbed random
registers or a bit or you could fix the
variation between the bits in such a
cipher obviously the pro of this
approach is you are not adding any
additional wires or transistors so
optical inspection is not enough the
chip will look like a golden ship if you
just look it and and cut it into slice
it into pieces however obviously the the
functionality of the chip is limited so
you have damn
cheap parts and you have and functional
testing if you do the functional testing
it will find it right away so this is a
problem what the producer could do is
they could create an T test function as
false wagon did with their car
controllers if if someone is trying to
test the krypter unit for all inputs to
check if really it's using the full
random space it could just trick it and
cheat it and then finally here comes the
interesting question if hardware
components are so extensively tested
because you cannot get rid of them once
they are on the market then what could
happen is you could as a malicious
attacker look for a very bizarre test
cases which are which are very rare and
very complicated and say and leave them
on purpose so just to say later on we
all know that in software projects
people are saying it's not a bug it's a
feature here we would do this another
way around we would say it's not a
feature it's a back which is a very
convenient excuse for a manufacturers
I'm not saying that it happened for
instance in case of Intel bugs maybe
there are those are bugs but but such
such complex bugs could be used and and
the manufacturer can also later on say
ok this is a back we haven't seen it we
haven't tested it or it can say this
chip is damaged so we couldn't do
anything in case of the dopant Trojans
so we haven't see our our tests haven't
seen or reported the diamond shape okay
so let me wrap it up for you so who
should fear of her Hardware Trojans I
think everyone why because they are very
difficult to detect and they can
leverage literally all software
mechanism because you cannot build a
trusted software on and not trusted
hardware so what what can we do I think
we should build a skill first in
hardware domain so this is a person on
training so not having an rusty branch
of hardware it's not a solution we can
see this it's called balkanization of
the of the electronic markets right now
certain companies are
blocked in in countries so they are
saying we are using only rooters from
our national production this happened in
the United States this happened in
Australia this happened in in in Germany
in France so if we have some some kind
of the low-level know-how then we may
start testing the first thing would be
to test the products it won't prevent
the attacks but it will make them much
more difficult so once again if you are
interested in in in redoing or you want
to see the sources because you couldn't
do to the small phones you can download
it them from from my github or you can
check up my website or if you're
interested in hardware then you can
check out my Twitter I will poster if
something new will come on the website
its nonprofit so thank you very much for
your attention I will be happy to answer
your questions
[Applause]
yes they are Huawei it's a very good
example here's a huawei phone I'm naming
them because it's not illegal to name
them you can just look for press
articles about it so you have Huawei is
blocked in Germany Huawei is blocked
they cannot participate in the contracts
for critical infrastructure there is a
list of cons critical infrastructure
components telecommunication so-so
Reuters and and selected switches and
they cannot participate due to the
security reasons same happens with
huawei in the United States also Germany
has this initiative email made in
Germany where they want their holding
that the email whenever there is
communication sent within the country
that not even one electron should across
the physical border of the country so
they would like to have the
communication components and within
their their own country I would give us
another example even in Czech Republic
they are right now producing own
switches they are open source so you can
take a look on them but and did you can
buy them also on Amazon and they are
using some silicon chips from from third
party manufacturers so mainly from from
United States and from their fobs but
once they created a switch they can
easier the tech they know what's the
functionality of the switch and they can
detect which which components can be
substituted for instance or filtered
must be filtered so there are there are
examples things like this can happen yes
please
I I really don't know I haven't heard
about it I hope it is because as you've
seen it's it's it's really it's really
hard to detect if it's so small like
three lines of the VHDL code then you
could do for instance if you would like
to find out my if I have this trojan
then you would what let's say most
intuitive approach would be to do
fuzzing to go through call all up codes
which you have in the spark ISA but then
you would have to run it with all
operands so all operands and plus it
must not be that easy because maybe it's
a combination of of comments which is
triggering such a Trojan so so so I'm in
my opinion it it should be available and
I am I I would say not having an
electronic industry has also security
consequences yes please
so we are saying we are reversing the
chip and then you would like to the
problem is when you're reversing you
have those layers so you will cut the
layers the chips are 3d right now so so
then it's already damaged you cannot
make a photo if if you are if they are
actually modifying the doping then the
point is the chip is damaged because
this inverter gate is not working
properly so you would probably detect it
during the test phase however its first
of all convenient for them to say this
is a damaged chip it happened in the fab
we don't know anything about it we
couldn't do anything because it happens
whenever your manufacturer silicon on a
wafer does part of those wafers the
small chips integrated circuits will be
damaged by design because you need an
insane cleanness you need clean rooms
and so on and because of this you have
this problem I don't know if it answer
to your question yeah it will be
extremely hard III will say it's not
sure you would destroy the chip
I would say extremely difficult it none
no I would say it's it I would rather it
would be cheaper simply to produce a
small series of chips as a manufacturer
a couple of wafers which are already
designed to be bad and then just put you
if you ordered 100,000 of some
controllers then just put a small
percentage 5% and then just count that
maybe nobody will test it or if they
will test it then maybe they will over
seen it and so on and then you are
waiting under those products you're
waiting there on the market people are
changing in the companies they are
buying new keyboards they are buying new
memories they are buying new processors
then you are waiting waiting waiting
until they get a certain saturation
point when when they are through natural
communication let's say channels within
that organization within your company
and then you are conducting the attack
yes please
that's that's a very good question so
firstly I have here for you a small
summary if you'd like to do it at home
you can do this but it will be for for
the chips which are from 70s or 80s here
is the cost of the equipment you see
like three hundred four four basic
microscope used from 50 it's it's not
that it's not that expensive but as I
said it's it's working only for a very
small and very old chips with a very
high a production process but people are
doing it there's this excellent talk
from Markos Janka and Pettit Luqman from
CCC house Computer Club Congress about
it how to do this at home FPGAs are
proven to have also their own Trojans so
there are articles how to put it if you
in order to program FPGA you need a
controller which is setting the values
of the gates which means that at this
time you can already program it is like
in compilation and very late its
deployment of the image onto the FPGA
and you can still do this so I would say
that the easier thing to do is actually
to to produce own clean chips than to
even even in very low technology 1500
for some simple purposes then to try to
reverse the existing chips and check so
and to check what what's on them yes
please
yeah you may try to damage them but if
you're produced yes so so so just the
new chips are in very low process so
it's 7 nanometers right now they're
talking about it or I don't know 11:17
they are they're very small so even with
this advanced here on microscope you
won't see much I've seen people which
are trying to read from the SIM cards
which are we her and modify the memory
values so they try to get as MZ code
directly with with a probe they are they
are putting the probe directly to the
cell memories it's already very
difficult and very expensive process and
it's very easy to destroy the chip so I
would say it's an hardly and probable
that people will try to modify the chip
in post-production I would say it's
rather produced with this with this
backdoor or a certain small amount of
the of the chips which you order either
in either not I would
yes now I get your point
yes so for instance there are chips
which have some update possibility a
very famous example was a proven example
MD have for some small updates a visa
when they when they see that their chip
is not working properly they left or
they made a test when there you have
Micro coded functionality so in micro
code also your assembly instruction that
decoding is done based on some memory
values in micro coded processor so it's
proven there are publication that
through those updates so you can design
you can really design the chip so that
you can modify it however it's very
costly so so it's a costly it's it
decreases also the speed of the device I
would say in very sophisticated devices
you could try to do this but and and as
I say they are publication what they
proven that you they can put for the
microcode update they can put that a
Trojan inside of it so this is an
example they don't have to put the
thermal and other in factors on it but
if your chip is small and simple then it
makes no sense I would say it's it's
it's it's a lot of effort it must be
really someone who must really want to
do this and it I would say it's a
economical question rather than
technical but technically it's possible
okay thank you very much for the
attention