hello everyone and welcome
if anyone's ever taken any of my secure
set online
python videos or something i have a
reputation for saying that a lot every
time i start a new video like hello and
welcome
so anyway my name is serious borso and
i'm here to talk about
snitching especially in the real world
well the real cyber security world
anyway
and the premise of this is really going
to be
my own experience of hosting
less than reputable websites
and how and why they get taken down
and as a takeaway it's not just me
telling stories it's you know maybe some
of you are dealing with the same
situations or you're gonna host your own
c2 servers or beef hooks or phishing
domains or whatever
and this may be relevant for you and
hopefully
i can impart some knowledge and walk
away with you know teaching some useful
information
all right so here's me i can actually
google myself now and i got a little
blurb over there on the right hand side
that comes up
so i figured i'd switch over to this
type of descriptor
of myself i've got a
fair amount of history about 15 years or
so in the world of cyber security back
in my day was called information
security
and cyber security was something we kind
of laughed at when we heard come out
but it seems to become much more
prevalent terminology nowadays
regardless once again my name is serge
borso i'm the founder and ceo of
spidersec
and i teach with the sans institute and
i published a book last year i think it
was the penetration tester's guide to
web applications
and i've been doing what i do like i
said for 15 years for
large businesses big enterprises
application security network security
system security penetration testing red
teaming purple teaming
so on and so forth all of it and that's
what my company does nowadays i did it
you know for 10 11 12 years for the
industry and now i do it for myself that
is penetration testing
and offering those same type of services
i just mentioned
for companies through my company so
that's a little bit about me
and what i experienced working for
companies and doing what i do nowadays
is
among other things fishing
and command control and beef hooks and
other things that require a third-party
virtually hosted platform somewhere in
the cloud
quote unquote that can host this
maliciousness and this course is not
malicious if you're doing something like
a
security awareness training campaign or
spearfishing attack and you know you're
doing this for the purpose of
increasing the security posture of the
business you're working for or you're
doing this as some type of
contract work or consulting work for a
company they've hired you
to assess their security you're going to
have a c2 server
you know if you're doing with any type
of callback communications or
you're going to have some spear phishing
websites that you've registered and try
to you know do some credential
harvesting
or delivery of a payload it requires
some external presence out there so as
you're going through this
talk and kind of that's the premise for
this where you're going to be hosting
stuff
and maybe you already are and i
certainly have and that's the background
for this
phishing is prevalent there's a little
maybe a citation needed for that i don't
haven't quantified
but i think we can all agree that
phishing is rather prevalent and i'll be
speaking to kind of that i won't bring
in too much more c2 conversation
or beef because it's almost irrelevant
the point here is that
there is something that you're hosting
on a website
that to the untrained user
or the layperson they're gonna look at
that and say oh that's malicious or
that's suspicious or that's
not normal that's not a regular website
you're doing something bad
or you're doing something whatever and
it's gonna get taken down
so the background is like i said fishing
the company gets hit with a real
spearfishing campaign
they want to get some awareness training
because the people at their company
clicked on that link and now there's a
network outbreak or something bad happen
me i've hosted a lot of
websites i've registered a lot of
phishing domains i'm under 100 but more
than 50
in my lifetime i guess and
when i do this you know i'm doing
awareness training program for a large
client
i register domain i go and you know copy
the theme
from a real website like dropbox.com and
all the different elements and i get an
ssl certificate to make it look real
and i go about you know doing my job and
then i
launched my phishing campaign the day of
the campaign was supposed to be sent out
for the client
and all of a sudden my website gets
taken down or it gets take down before i
even send out the phishing campaign
and this has happened to me more than
once
over the years multiple times and it's
annoying it's
money it's time it's effort and if i'm
too stupid to back up my stuff i've i've
lost a lot of time
and money mostly time but time is money
the point here is that my stuff gets
taken down and i want to know what that
is going on so i started doing some
research into this
2017 2018 2019 not not consistent like
i'm spending
you know 40 hours a week doing research
but every time i was going to host a
phishing website
i started paying closer attention to
what was actually going on
and i want to find out who's the snitch
who's targeting me out
who or whom is the entity or entities
that is or are causing my websites to be
taken offline
that's the premise for this that's what
i'm trying to talk about and that's why
i'm gonna share with you because i have
found
the smoking gun and at the end of the
presentation i'll share that information
with you but we'll get there
piece by piece so you can read that
for yourself i'm not gonna read the
slides for the most part but i will kind
of
use those to kind of guide this
conversation but that was really the
premise
trying to do my job to help companies
increase their security posture by
sending out security awareness training
and phishing and spearfishing campaigns
and then those websites
being taken offline okay and i want to
find out what's going on
so we can look at this and the question
of course is what is it
and those of you looking at the screen
will easily
say well obviously that's dropbox.com
well
yeah it certainly looks like it right
the theme
the colors the font the size of those
input boxes
that's clearly dropbox.com
just like this is clearly amazon.com
there's even a copyright at the bottom
what else could it possibly be that's
definitely the you know the legitimate
real
amazon.com and those of us who have
apple accounts that's definitely apple's
website right
well no those are all fishing websites
so what so they're fishing websites who
cares well let's think about it
at what point
does a legitimate website that you or i
go register turn
from just a website into
something that's more malicious and
that's why i got the little caterpillar
turning into butterfly up there it's a
transformation
what happens what makes it just a
legitimate server that's listening on
port 80 or port 443
to the
ultimate takedown request that says
someone says hey this is malicious or
this is suspicious or i don't trust this
what what really happens from point a to
point b
that causes something of that to occur
that's a fair question that's what we're
going to talk about so google
your registrar your internet service
provider your hosting provider if you
have a vps if you have aws
or something in the cloud what's going
to cause
them to take action to say i'm going to
suspend your service or disable your
account
or what's happened to me i'm going to
suspend your service
and by the way you just forfeited all of
your credit that you had
prepaid for the next six months
i told you i lost time and money i'm not
joking
let's back up for a second though level
set so what am i talking about here
there's a there's a process that goes
into play and i am by no means
trying to point out these companies on
the slide as you know
good or bad or whatever i'm just giving
you some examples of who you may go to
for your own hosting needs for your own
registration needs
so you me anyone on this call
who are listening to this presentation
can easily go
and buy or you know lease a domain name
if you have a credit card all you really
have to do is just say i want this
domain
and if it's available and you can afford
it you click a couple buttons
and that's pretty much it the registrar
gladly accepts your money and that's the
first
point meaning if i
am google or i am some
some authority of the web who's going to
have the potential to
launch an abuse notification or a
takedown request
this is the first kind of point where
what you just
created could be scrutinized because
before this you there's nothing out
there you don't have a website you don't
have a website
but now you've gone from zero to you
have something you have a domain name
if it's called evilwebsite.com
is that enough for someone to complain
about it you know maybe but that's not
gonna
that's not gonna hold water when someone
tries to take it down so that's that's
point one though
so if you go to register evilwebsite.com
yeah okay not a big deal probably in
most cases
if you go to register evildropbox.com
well that's a little bit closer now
you're you're using the name of a
legitimate company in your domain name
and guess what dropbox does pay
attention to that there is typo
squatting
and even though it's not a typo squat
it's still similar enough to where
you're using a legitimate company's name
in your own domain name and that's going
to raise suspicion
one level above nothing so keep that in
mind
the next point point number two a domain
by itself is just sitting there just
because you've registered domain doesn't
mean you have a website running on there
it could be parked but it certainly
isn't your source code or anything it
has to do with anything you've done
other than register a website so this
next point is
you change dns and you point the dns for
the a name
for your domain to an ip address that
can actually host content for you and of
course you could
keep it with the default dns and ip
address and just use the hosting
provider
that you register the main main with but
regardless it's the second point
once you actually have dns pointing
somewhere
and you're hosting content somewhere now
we're talking about
i go to your website it resolves dns it
points me to a website
and my browser renders that page now
that's you know that's the second point
that's potentially another
avenue where a company or
someone who wants to take down your
website can say hey this this looks
suspicious
this evil dropbox.com now there's a
domain name and now it takes me to
website
point number two point number three when
i'm creating any type of spearfishing
website or even
even basic security awareness training
websites or c2 servers
anything that i'm hosting nowadays i'm
going to get an ssl certificate for if
it's if there's any type of
communication that
is web-based or needs to be encrypted in
transit
and because it's free and it takes very
very limited amounts of effort
although it takes a little bit more
effort than it did a couple months ago
um i'm not gonna get into that but let's
just go ahead and say
ssl search are free there's let's
encrypt and others
like let's encrypt to where it almost
doesn't make sense to not do this
you know when you're going to launch a
phishing campaign you want to make it
look as legitimate as possible
and users have for years have been
trained to look for the https so that's
point number three register an sl
certificate
and we'll get more into why these points
matter in just a moment
the next thing you have a website you
have dns you have
you know domain name ssl cert and now
you gotta start copying over stuff
perhaps the real theme the real logo
the real fonts the real colors all from
the websites you're trying to rip off
or not rip off but you know what i'm
saying like you're gonna copy that theme
i can go straight to dropbox.com right
now
using firefox and say file save as
and all that client-side content gets
saved to my machine
and i can upload it and tweak it a
little bit
but essentially upload that to my
phishing website and i've got a
pretty good copy right off the bat of
the real dropbox.com
i'm not picking out dropbox for any
other reason other than
uh they're on my mind right now okay
nothing else special about that
last point here is we've you know just
to reiterate we've registered domain
we've changed dns we're hosting our
site somewhere we have an sl certificate
we have a functional
website and now we send out our
actual phishing email to our recipients
at any one of these five points i've
outlined right here
those are specific areas
where some company or some human or some
technology
could intervene and say this looks
suspicious
of course there's more to it there's a
lot more to it but
don't have time to go into every single
little thing as far as bots and
keys and firewalls and protection and
stuff like that but essentially
it's not too crazy to do all the stuff i
just said that it takes
an hour or so to do that now the
question becomes
at what point during these five points
i've outlined
do you think that a website could get
flagged as suspicious
and feel free to i'm looking at discord
right now
and i'm happy to you know entertain any
guesses you might have
once you buy a domain is someone gonna
complain about that once you change dns
to get the certificate
once you borrow all the themes from the
real websites
and or once you send out the 50 now at
what point
are you most likely to get a takedown
request or abuse notification or your
registrar is going to say
sorry your account has been served and
your account's been suspended
feel free to think about it i guess it's
more of a rhetorical question
but just to reiterate i am keeping an
eye on
the discord channel and i'm happy to
interact there as well
so just to level set kind of what i'm
talking about
that's the the big red thing you see
right there that's within
i believe google chrome will show you
something that looks pretty much like
that
i've obfuscated some of the content here
just because like i said this this is a
kind of combination of research i've
done over the years but this research is
based off of
me registering real websites for real
customers
that's really have ndas in place so i
don't want to necessarily show
everything but
uh that dropbox.com with the first part
being obfuscated is basically like your
company name
dot dropbox.com or whatever the case may
be
and that's what we see when when google
and their safe browsing project learn
about your website and they come to the
conclusion that it's
suspect or suspicious or a quote unquote
web
forgery or as malicious or whatever this
is what someone sees
do you have any idea how big of an
impact this plays
when you're trying to launch a
spearfishing campaign
to harvest credentials or to get a
foothold into an environment during a
red team engagement
it's a big deal you know i downplayed it
by saying this you know it takes like an
hour to set all this up
but you know i also left out a lot of
complexity there's a lot of
troubleshooting and testing and making
sure that theme looks exactly perfect
and
figuring out what you do with the
credentials once you steal them properly
so on and so forth
so it's a big deal if you go to launch
your phishing campaign and
all of a sudden you're like whoa i can't
even get to my website anymore
and my victims aren't gonna be able to
either that's a big deal it's a pretty
big blow to your whole campaign right
there
okay and there's a couple other things
here i got amazonshipping.io
trainingmachine.net facebookupdate.com
updatingserver.com those are more
generic ones that i've used
over the years or at least a year i
guess
for what we're talking about phishing
campaigns
and so on and so forth and of course the
middle we're seeing a customer
notification that's
you know below this email is a phishing
report we've received about your service
we expect you to resolve this within 24
hours or your service will be suspended
gee thanks thanks a lot where's the
faith in humanity you know i'm doing
this for educational purposes not for
legitimate harm to people right
at any rate this is based on research
and i'm here to
basically tell you what i learned so
let's kind of
take this for what it is what entities
are gonna flag websites i said you know
this google safe browsing project and
companies like
dropbox keep keep pretty close tab
sometimes on
similar domains same concept here we'll
start with the first i've highlighted it
in this
pinkish purplish color your registrar
number one
they're not really going to stop you you
know the the registrars
of the world don't necessarily care
about the name of the domain that you
choose to register
you know there's in this country we've
got free speech you can buy whatever the
heck you want
that's perfectly fine even if it's
called this is a phishingwebsite.com
so what they're not gonna be the ones
that's gonna that are gonna argue out
let's encrypt the ssl certificate the
certificate provider of choice for
many of us who are just setting up
websites like this
not paying too close attention to the
certificates of issues
meaning if they see a request for this
is a phishingwebsite.com
so what once again freedom of speech
freedom of
let's encrypt ssl everywhere type of
thing and that would kind of go against
some core beliefs to just not allow a
certificate based on the name of the
domain
being suspicious or weird or something
like that so
once again not a big issue there
based on my experience robots this is
real
there are bots that are scouring the web
on a day hour minutes basis
looking for copyright and trademark
infringements that's real
and when when i'm copying
fedex or ups or amazon shipping stuff
and i register domain with their their
name inside of it
that's raises some suspicion and when
their robot goes to that website and
they see that there there's actually
some logos and themes from the
legitimate website
i've gotten dozens and dozens of emails
from those type of companies saying to
take down the content otherwise they're
gonna do something legal
against me um so keep that in mind
people humans humans that come across
your website
will definitely say this is weird this
is suspect
and they will potentially go there just
using a couple of clicks in the browser
and report it to google report it using
firefox or whatever browser they happen
to use
and say this i think this is a like i
said before a quote unquote
suspected web forgery whatever that
means a suspicious website basically
so people people now we're kind of
getting a little bit farther up the
chain here humans definitely do have an
impact on this
and there actually are other humans that
will look at some of those abuse
requests
and notices and take some action if it's
so
warrants it next one you kind of already
touched on this that company a
the robots scour the web and that
company
is actually gonna go and see if you're
using their logos and stuff and then
they're gonna
maybe report you or at least send some
email to the abused contact
for the whois information
now other stuff that's going to come
into play the endpoint solutions
and the other company here so if you
register a domain
because you're going to do the stuff
we're talking about fishing
or beef hooks or you need to host
something third party and you need to
have a domain name associated with it
you go to your head register that and
then you send out some
phishing email to your victim
that's email goes through usually
several layers of filtering there's
you know some email filtering some spam
filtering maybe even endpoint detection
perhaps but at least some type of
some email gateway that's going to
scrutinize that and nowadays
because it is 2020 you know this isn't
phishing isn't new
by any stretch of the imagination people
in companies and
a lot of us have gotten kind of a little
bit smarter and they say
well here's a link in this email and i'm
going to do a simple whois lookup on
this and see when it's been registered
and if you registered it like i said a
week ago
that email scrubbing solution or the
filter the gateway as a case may be can
easily ascertain that
and then mark that as a suspicious email
send it to spam
or simply quarantine it it doesn't even
come to you or
something quasi like that they'll just
make it so that link isn't even
clickable
so definitely suspect if it's a very
brand new website
and all of a sudden there's a link in
the email points to that brand new
website
next one no reputation meaning you have
a website
he registered it maybe six months ago
but there's a blank page
because you're like i'm getting ready
for this engagement or i'm gonna go
ahead and register
amazon shipping.io because i'm gonna
need it at some point
then it sits there and nothing is there
and it has no reputation reputation
means it's not good it's not bad
it's not classified it's not no violent
it's not
news it's not a blog it's not
whatever you know it's no classification
reputation
that's suspect okay and then of course
if the certificate has the name of
legitimate company in it
that too is suspect and that's different
than the other stuff we've already
talked about
i mentioned let's encrypt and i
mentioned the company in question like
if you're trying to
duplicate dropbox.com or amazon.com or
apple.com
when you actually register that ssl
certificate through let's encrypt or
a similar provider there is
a log of that and
the more mature companies who have to
deal with this you know at scale
they are looking for those in their
certificate transparency logs
if they can easily query and search for
something that has anything
star.apple.com or starapple.com or some
type of
fuzzy query to see if there's any
apple.com websites being registered
like loginapple.com
and that's interesting now what have i
come across
to kind of answer some of the stuff i've
been laying down here so far
what i've seen is
number five once an actual
email gets sent out
that has the highest likelihood of being
flagged
so the email gateway that's
usually where it happens at meaning i
can host a website
get the dns pointed over to a hosting
server
copy over all the themes from the
legitimate dropbox or whatever
amazon type of website i'm trying to to
copy
to trick users into divulging
credentials or or the like
and i'm usually okay i can host it
for a matter of weeks
what i've come across is it's
typically number five once you send that
phishing email out and it goes through
the gateways
and they're checking all those things we
just talked about
that's where i've had my highest
incidence of
people humans actually reporting the
website as suspicious at that point and
that's
what i found out so i'll show you some
examples here in just a second
but in general that was kind of the
first half
here so once again
we have a website we have a need to do
some type of
security awareness training or phishing
is part of a penetration test or red
team engagement so we go ahead and
register that website get it all set up
and ready to go
and then send out that email and it's
taken offline
like quick with the quickness
how do we avoid that because
depending on what you do for a living
and what your role is of the
organization
or entity you work for that may be part
of your job
and you're supposed to be successful you
know you're the pen tester you gotta
start
trying harder thinking outside the box
and figuring out well okay
as soon as i send the email out i my
website is taken down
and it's the consequences are such that
it's not just like oh that sucks it's
more of a
where were you hosting it was it in aws
because now
your whole amazon account could be
called into question
and amazon you want to go talk to aws
about no it's actually a real website
that's just hosting for phishing and
i'm actually one of the good guys and i
you know i have a job doing security
awareness training and
yeah that that's not so great and what
if you have other
critical assets linked to that aws
account they could all get suspended
okay vps virtual private server that
hosting company
will suspend your whole account i've had
a handful of servers just get taken
offline and they
they never came back you know i
mentioned i briefly alluded to
at the beginning of this money i've lost
where i actually paid for
several months six plus months of
service at a virtual private server
hosting company
and they got one well there's more than
one
but they got they got uh wind of
one of my fishing campaigns and they
suspended service and i
it was right at a really inopportune
time quite frankly
right in the middle of a fishing
engagement with a client who's paying
money for this
and now i look like an idiot and i am
scrambling to get my stuff back up and
running and i've spent money that i've
now got a suspended account and i can
refund my money it's like this is
serious
it's serious on multiple levels so
that's why i'm trying to fail who's
who's the narc who's snitching on me for
this
because that's that's not cool all right
so what do we do about it
the first one test offline user firewall
what do i mean by this
i mean once you get the domain name and
you register
your ssl certificates and you're hosting
it somewhere
leave the firewall turned on white lists
or
allow have an allow list for your ip
address
that you're testing from and that way
you can see it
but any robots that goes there
no connection no tcp connection no
website it's
nothing at all it's like it's offline
for anyone else you guys go to the
website while you're
you're in beta testing no one else can
see it so just firewall it off
completely
what else second bullet point don't
point
website resources to the legitimate
website host it locally what do i mean
by that
let me break that down when you go to
utilize the theme and the elements from
a legitimate website what i mean is the
css files
the javascript files the images
the fonts all that stuff those are the
resources
that comprise any website you go to
right now
when you're copying those from a
legitimate website
there's two different ways to go about
doing this you can just say when someone
loads the page
that image is located at www.dropbox.com
forward slash images forward slash
logo.png
that's hosted on dropbox.com
meaning when someone goes to your
phishing website or even you when you're
beta testing it
that image loads from
a request that got sent to dropbox.com
which directly touches dropbox.com
servers hopefully that makes sense
so hosting locally means you copy all
those images once
you go to the website you get the images
you get the css files you get
whatever it may be and then from there
we're talking about you have it locally
on your server
okay i gotta see a couple of people
typing in the
discord channel is it using hash
analysis of the images and trying to
search in the css
no oh i think he said i think he got it
right so don't point
but can they pick up
if you fill the images absolutely they
can
so the question is we we copy those
files locally to our own vps at that
point
and could dropbox.com
then go and say hey based on this image
you've obviously just cloned it you
copied it yeah definitely but that's
there's no indicator at this point in
time if you're hosting everything
locally
and some vps you just spun up some
virtual private server that you just
turned on
now we're talking about they have no
indicator to know to go to your vps and
if you're still in the demo beta phase
of this
you have a firewall off anyway
firewalled off meaning no one can even
go to that website to see it
so that's what i'm talking about there
rackfire45 is typed in something
we'll see what that individual has to
say
in just a moment and i'll address that
question or comment thanks doug
good call on that all right next one
wait until final moment before we go
live to register the certificate what
does that mean and i got a little
asterisks there it can be a negative
reputation
going back to your reputation i
mentioned if you have the reputation if
you're specifically your website
has a reputation it hasn't uh
it hasn't made it to being indexed as
you know trusted or such a blog site or
b9
i guess essentially is what it would
come down to without that
without you registering a certificate
and having it online and ready to go
you're missing on the reputation meaning
if i go register amazon shipping.io
which you guys saw
a few slides back that's been up for six
months or a year you guys knew who is
look up on that right now and tell me
how long it's been up it's been up for a
while
and the reputation on that should be
okay because i haven't really hosted
anything out there in a while
so the point here is waiting to the last
minute
can have some negative consequences as
well because you don't you don't build
up
that that trust within the whole system
so rack fire says he's uh this is good
information
i'm sorry to hear you lost time and
money yeah no problem
that's probably what keeping me from
going further into the security field
yeah i hear you on that pm scientist and
i got
careful how i pronounced some of these
names question what pros cons exist for
using a site
you manage as a reverse proxy to man the
middle a simulated site versus copying
the right bits
of the simulated site so what problem
can't exist
i gotta think about that happens in
anything
if something i worry about constantly
something i worry about constantly yeah
um pm science
scientist i'll come back to that unless
i forget another in which case i will
come back that for sure i gotta think
about that for a second
all right other stuff here understand
um in black bold points right there
you gotta figure out what your points of
exposure are i highlighted the five main
ones
but there's other stuff out there the in
the maturity level of the company you're
trying to
trying to basically trick people into
going to like it's not really amazon.com
it's not really dropbox.com it's
it's fake dropbox.com
if those companies are on their game so
to speak and they're doing things like
typo scouting checks
and they're they have their center
policy framework set up properly so you
can't just spoof an email
and other stuff you see on the screen
certificate transparency logs for
instance
most companies don't do that i got some
i'm not astrix that's like
only some companies are really seriously
doing this stuff this takes
some automation this takes some humans
setting it up just takes some humans
actually
putting the effort into watching what's
going on as far as typo squatting goes
just to be clear
you can't stop someone from registering
amazonshipping.io
or amazon.photography or amazon dots
ninja or amazon you can't stop people
from doing that it's a free country
okay amazon can stop people from doing
that they can try and they can complain
about it
but in most cases it's just something
you don't have control over so it's
always going to be that
subset of people who are going to click
on that link anyway even though it's
it's on amazon.com it's amazon.ninja or
something like that
but there are other areas of exposure
highlighted in this slide right here
that you need to be aware of
that could potentially get you exposed
before
your time is up all right hosting
platform what do you have to think about
here this is real this is copy and
pasted straight from my hosting
provider and as far as going back to the
main
theme and question of this whole talk
who's the narc who's snitching on me
you can see right there in yellow and i
got nothing negative or positive to say
um this is just reality this is research
and this is me giving it to you in black
and white
okay this is something that happened to
me back in october 2019.
dropbox abuse detected on your
infrastructure which is why i was kind
of harping on dropbox as a
dropbox.com as a example because i got
hit with it
i copied all their stuff just like you
saw on the previous slides
i hosted that did all the stuff i talked
about and
go to launch the phishing website email
campaign
then boom hosting provider is like hey
we got nine
complaints passed from upstream
providers
about phishing so
yeah there's companies out there that do
this there's companies out there get
paid to do this
to protect their customers and it's kind
of ironic
i'm getting paid to protect that same
company
and these people are getting paid to
protect them in a different way to to
watch out so
you know there's value in this one way
or the other yeah
i got burned on it but arguably
they were doing their job not arguably
they started they were doing their job
and it just happened to impact me doing
my job there's no no gray area about
that
it's not bad it's not good this is what
it is but
there you go so the snitch people i'll
give you a heads up on this
the second bullet point there
overzealous i.t administrators back to
rack fire45
yeah it's good information you can get
burned and one of the first times i was
doing this
i remember it was similar to all the
stuff i said you know
register domain get the ssl certificate
set up send out the spearfishing
campaign
it looks beautiful looks great and one
of the it
admins at the company that received the
phishing email
actually went to the who is did like a
simple who is search on the command line
it's pretty
very easy to do found the abuse contact
email
sent down an abuse notification to that
point of contact at the registrar or
i think the hosting platform and got my
website taken offline
in the middle once again in the middle
of the phishing campaign
so there's other you know there's some
other pieces that go into this
um communication with the company you're
working for yeah poop squad 420 that is
an ouch
without a doubt um it got taken i
actually asked that the person
my point of contact at that customer to
hey this is what just happened can you
have your it admin
you know kind of correct the situation
because we got some issues
doing this campaign right now it's like
they're paying me to do this and
their own personally kind of took it
offline but that's what it is that's
just reality of it you know
i used to script the abuse contact when
i was responsible incoming email
yeah yeah technic yep uh technology
that goes back to what we saw kind of in
the last slide people plus technology
technology does a pretty good job
nowadays quite frankly of picking up on
this
just based on the the factual
information how long his website been
around for
and the other easy to identify things
that you could automate
like is there any type of you know known
history this website
has a hosted malware in the past uh is
it
yeah so on and so forth all right so
rackfire45 says i'm surprised you
couldn't fight it after the fact
to at least recover your funding costs
time machine would have helped recover
lost time yeah
i can't complain too much about it it's
almost like the uh
the two coal fire guys who got arrested
for
doing their job yeah it sucked but when
it was happening
around that moment time i'm like yeah
okay it's not cool at
this moment in time but i'm sure they're
gonna have a really cool defcon defcon
talk or black hat talk
you know and of course they did so same
thing here i'm talking about it i'm
sharing my knowledge
and while i lost some time a little bit
of money you know the reality is
i i got my knowledge i can share with
each of you and hopefully
hopefully it's useful
for you all right difference between
malware and fishing that's not a there's
not a huge difference here
okay there's from the perspective of
just like the slide says
from this perspective of this behavior
violates our terms of service so on and
so forth it's not really much of a
difference as far as your hosting
provider
is concerned or your platform or your
registrar
if you're violating terms of service
whether it's a c2 server whether it's a
beef hook the browser exploitation
framework
or whether it's a spear phishing website
it's the same concept there
phishing though definitely some
copyright issues to take into account
meaning
if i'm hosting a c2 server i'm not
copying the theme from dropbox.com it's
irrelevant i'm not doing that
so there's some variance nuance there
without a doubt
and of course phishing is
definitely much better understood i say
c2
command and control i'm sorry if i if
anyone here didn't
immediately know what that was you know
but not everyone does
c2 means command and control and that's
not quite as obvious and prevalent
for people not in the know fishing
everyone knows what fishing is
it most everyone in this industry you
know but c2 well
maybe not everyone understands that so
the point here is when
it's more obvious to the layperson
it's more likely to potentially get
taken down so the other thing here
providers might work with you if they
think your website was compromised
that's that's a reality meaning oh it
wasn't me
doing this on purpose my website was
compromised that's why there's phishing
yeah right
i'm not advocating saying that at all i
always tell the truth
my providers i say hey my here's my name
here's my company spidersec
and you can just go to the website right
now and read what we do you know this
isn't
new we've been in business for five
years and this is
who are who we're dealing with so anyway
other things you can do the difference
here maybe a non-standard report
could help you out so other things to
think about
before i go back to pm science's
question and any other questions that
pop up here in discord
are really going to be firewall
firewall stuff off there's no need to
tell the world about your phishing
website or your commanding control
server before the world needs to know
about it quite frankly you could host
this
on your local linux box or your windows
machine as your
as your preference may be and then just
go live last minute
with the actual content the reputation
helps lot bullet point that means
get the domain name get the certificate
host something benign on there like a
legitimate
blog or a legitimate photography
gallery or whatever and it just sits
there
it gets some traffic and it gets
reputation reputation which isn't
negative and then when you're ready to
pull the trigger that's when
you upload the more malicious component
to it and the other thing here
yeah flip a record mx last minute
absolutely per dog brush
just switch over dns point somewhere
else and you're good to go that's
even smarter other smart things you can
do
redirect if your
target organization that you work for or
you're working with if you know
if it's like a single location which is
probably not nowadays everyone's working
from home
but if people were all in the office
coming from one netted ip address
you know that ip address is because you
work there you're doing this in-house as
an internal
security awareness training pen tester
whatever your title may be
then you already know if the ip address
is and you can just white
you can just you can just redirect
when you see that ip address on your
apache web server or some
other upstream device you can say if i
see this ip address then show
this page that in in php or your.net or
java as occasionally as well
same thing for c2 traffic if you if you
know what to look for
then you can just show the visitor what
you want them to see
so regular visitor who goes and stumbles
across
your phishing domain just use the
regular blog
whereas someone who you're targeting
actually sees
the phishing website i always have some
backup plans in place
and then bulletproof kind of last
thought there with bulletproof hosting
providers
i took a serious look at them after this
happened like the second or third time
yes very sneaky indeed the bulletproof
hosting providers though
they didn't seem to didn't seem to be
viable they were
quite expensive like hundreds of dollars
a month
for hosting and it's difficult to
justify that
that price point number one number two
looking at the second bullet point on
the slide deck again reputation helps
that
what do you think the reputation is of a
bulletproof hosting provider's ip range
yeah okay you're
you're lucky and your your kind of
mileage may vary with that but
generally speaking nowadays maybe the
ipv6
if you can get one of those but still
you're paying a lot of money for it
and what i mean by bulletproof hosting
just so we're on the same page is
when a bulletproof hosting provider
receives an abuse notification or take
down requests
they're going to say no i like this
phishing website
it's staying up that's kind of the
concept behind bulletproof hosting
meaning your hosting provider is going
to have your back
and not take your website offline unless
you violate the terms of service which
is usually
very very limited in terms of what they
don't allow so that's
certainly an option depending what
you're trying to host and what your
needs are you can definitely look into
something like that okay
i'm gonna back up here i'm down to about
nine minutes or so
and i've highlighted pms sorry pm
scientist question
question what pros and cons exist for
using a sites you manage
as reverse proxy to man in the middle or
machine in the middle a simulated site
versus copying the right bits of the
simulated site
i was hoping i'd have a better answer
for this by now i don't know if i fully
understand that question
what's what's good about
using a site i managed as a reverse
proxy
to ban the middle assimilate
yeah i still don't really understand
that i don't think and i apologize
for that
other thing doug brush mentioned if you
can only pay for your hosting provider
with
uh bitcoin yeah that was the other thing
um
i wasn't about it's like i was trying to
pay with um
what was it uh that one that ebay came
up with
uh paypal it's like i'll pay with paypal
they're like no we don't wanna accept
paypal
it's uh bitcoin only i was like well i
guess that makes sense
you know how about a credit card no we
don't take credit cards it's bitcoin
only and it totally if you're a
bulletproof hosting provider i get it
and
i was kind of being foolish there but
you know that's what it is
um he's talking about captioning
credentials in fight um
okay is there any benefit to doing it
that way
um in
in the premise of this conversation that
doesn't
come up so much like
uh
if i'm understanding it correctly so pm
scientist
uh thinking that reverse proxies need to
copy images of css and communicate refer
headers as you know i got what you're
saying i think i already said
yeah without a doubt um that could prove
to be useful for you
the the thing i mean you could do an
iframe too
quite frankly something like that could
work as well
but you're still still going to see some
calls to that
uh to legitimate company
one way or another some amount of
benefit i'm sure there's some downsides
uh yeah there potentially could be just
depends what you're trying to accomplish
um and what your kind of risk tolerance
is there with that
all right what else uh questions that's
it i don't tweet very much
i'm pretty active on linkedin i work at
that company over there
and i'm keeping an eye on this discord
channel for the moments
um i know i got seven minutes left and
would i wanna make sure enough time for
the next presenter to come on
and set up so they don't make the
mistake that i made by being an idiot
hopefully you all got a lot out of this
talk thank you so much for joining i
really appreciate it
if you have any questions please do
reach out please feel free to linkedin
or hit me up you have one two three
different
points of contact for me at this moment
in time so
don't be shy don't hesitate and hope to
see you all in the community and
at future conferences thank you so much
and thank you besides for doing this
really appreciate that thank you thank
you for speaking today
one thing that i think that we can all
agree on is that if he
sends a link in an email we are not
clicking it yeah
pretty much that's fair
certainly fair now i have a feeling that
the last four times i clicked on dropbox
it probably wasn't even
dropbox and he's got all the files i
uploaded but
i don't want you guys to stuff unless
you're paying me that's someone's paying
me for it and it's legitimate uh
not so much nowadays good talk
enjoy all the pictures of squirrels
you know yeah there's no shortage of
that
thank you lucky 225 thank you poop squad
420 thank you
mr doug brush thank you rackfire45
thanks for the question
p.m sciences and yes you're all very
welcome
glad i could be here today