so it's all yours take it away
all right let me get my screen shared
out here
this one and there we go
all right and let me move some things
around i got a bunch of screens in front
of me
all right so welcome everyone
thanks for taking the time to uh come
stop by my talk today
um for those of you that don't know me
my name is john helmes
we're going to talk a little bit more
about me here in a second um but for
those of you that do know me i did this
talk
back at defcon in the red team village
back in
august um this is actually a amended
version
of the talk um just from taking uh
questions and answers from the previous
one and applying it to this one
i've also taken out some of the the
material that you know was kind of
redundant in the old presentation so
it's a lot more concise in this one
um so with that being said
let's go ahead and just you know get to
it huh
so here's going to be the agenda for
today
so we're going to go through all these
bullet points and i don't want to
mention everyone because we
are uh we do have a limited amount of
time so i can sit here and talk about
these bullet points all day however
um just to brief give a brief mention
introduction just going to give a brief
introduction to myself
let you see some of the things that i've
done over the course of my career and
how
it's been at different ends of the
spectrum
we're going to talk about how you
develop a student mindset not an
academic mindset a student mindset
talk about some ways of how we can
become a penetration tester look at
degrees and certifications which is a
big big thing in this
uh in this area cost analysis how much
we got to spend
then we're going to look at some actual
road map diagrams that i put together
and we're going to look at how you can
go from being a help desk
specialist to a penetration tester or
even just a student
because those are the two more common
tracks that i see they're going to talk
about staying curious and there's a
common question
um that i wanted to answer at the end so
let's go ahead and get going so who am i
my name is john helmes um i'm currently
a penetration tester
and a adjunct professor however i wasn't
always that i actually used to be a
naval engineer
um and a help desk specialist myself and
i've gone to the ranks
over the past uh about six years um
after my military career my military
career ended in 2014
so now i've been going yeah
from being a help desk guy to what i'm
doing now i'm also monitoring the
discord channel just so you know so if i
peek over and i start answering
questions
um just so you know that's uh that's it
so somebody said is that am i holding a
chicken yes that is uh one of my
chickens
i have a small farm outside of seattle
um where we have alpacas which you'll
actually see in
a slide or two uh we have goats a pig
ducks chickens the whole nine yards so
let's
uh let's keep going with that huh so but
to give brevity to what's on the slide
right now
as you can see i've had a lot of
different experiences that have led me
into pen testing so what i want to
project
on to you is to let you know that you
know there's a
ton of different avenues that you can
use to get into pen testing and it's not
a one size fits all you can do a lot of
everything and we're going to start to
notice that
there's going to be a common theme where
you have to kind of just be
curious about everything it's not just
about hacking or a certain technology
it's just kind of
being curious about any kind of
technology that you want to get your
hands dirty with
so these are some of the current things
i'm doing
i am a penetration tester red teamer at
nordstrom headquarters up here in
seattle washington
i'm also a agile professor at city
university of seattle and national
university i teach
online courses for both of the schools
that range from
basic cyber security network and
wireless
security cyber warfare at national i
actually
teach red teaming and penetration
testing so if you're interested in
getting a master's degree
in pen testing uh look them up and
you'll probably have me as a professor
so and then i'm also a phd candidate at
the dakota state university i'm
currently
in the phd of cyber ops program
um it's a pretty fun program so far i
just started it
but i'm really really enjoying it so far
and
as you can see here at the bottom right
that is another asset of my life
where i actually have a small mini farm
um we have alpacas we have goats we have
pigs we have chicken stocks the whole
nine yards right
um so that's what i like to do in my
free time because
it's something that actually gets me
outside and away from the computer
so it's uh it's one of those nice things
that physically
puts me away from everything so
uh and just so you know if i look over
the side again just monitoring the
discord chat
no moose no uh
mail mooses are pretty aggressive from
what i've heard
so let's really talk about what we're
here to talk about because we're not
here to talk about me
we're here to talk about how we can
learn to become a pen tester so
penetration testing
also known as pen testing or a pen test
ethical hacking keyword is ethical there
right
is an authorized other keyword is
authorized simulated attack on a
computer system to perform
um and evaluate the security of that
system so we're looking at the security
posture of a system through actually
exploiting vulnerabilities
and assessing the impact and severity on
those vulnerabilities
to the organization however while you
think you might think
it's just technical vulnerabilities we
look at more than just technical
vulnerabilities we look at people
we look at processes we even challenge
culture in an organization
right because culture is something that
is hard to make to pivot
so it's really um crucial that you
understand that even changing culture is
part
of being a penetration tester where you
actually have to look and see
if there's something that's toxic within
an organization that you actually have
to change otherwise
the the company may you know start
losing revenue
all right so it's more than just hacking
right it's a lot of research a lot of
writing
a lot of writing a lot of reading um i
always like to say that you know it's
about 70
writing reading reporting and about 30
technical
so you know a lot of writing and reading
and research goes and takes place before
the pen test during the pen test and
after the pen test
and there is a lot of technical portions
where your hands on keyboard however
think about it as if you your hands on
keyboard and you actually find
a vulnerability on a system you then
have to turn around
and actually do research on that
vulnerability because you want to be
concise and precise with your attack
method so that you can illustrate that
later to the client or your organization
whoever you're working for
so it's it's crucial that you you're
able to perform
not just good technical skills but also
uh proper cyber research and
illustrating what you find
and then i always like to put this the
reality check is it's about people and
processes
right we're looking at the technology
that is intertwined with business people
or well i'm sorry the people
of the business and the processes of
that business right so we're looking at
all the technology stacks and the
culture and the people the processes
that all
all the good stuff right it says
technical skills play a major role they
do technical skills are one of the
is the is a very crucial role because it
plays a huge part
in pen testing it's just not the most
utilized one
because um you know it's about people
right and making an organization better
than it was before
so you have to have soft skills that
play a vital role
in doing so so you have to concurrently
be able to walk the walk and not talk
the talk so that means you have to be
able to do the technical stuff while
you're also able to illustrate it
uh properly and what i mean by properly
is more professionally where you're able
to actually take low level
um technology findings talk jargon
whatever you want to call it
and display it at a level that everyone
can understand it because otherwise
you're gonna it can make people stray
away from understanding it
and they might just completely forget
about whatever you're
talking about so the reality of pin
testing is banging your head against the
wall and looking for systems that are
typically locked down
i always like to say that pin testers
are just highly technical quality
assurance engineers and i'm sure there's
some people on the other side of the
screen that are
that don't agree with that but that's
just my opinion
so and penetration testing is 70 report
writing and research and probably only
about 30
hands-on that's just you know from my
own research and and being in the field
is there's it's just so much research
and reporting
and writing and very little and a lot of
hands-on but the
the hands-on portion makes up the
smaller
portion of pen testing
and then a big reason why we have pen
testing besides wanting to know what
your security posture is
and having to you know actually have a
simulated
attack executed on your organization so
that it can illustrate your security
posture before the bad guys actually get
in
is a is it is a big thing
however the other big reason is
compliance right it's being regulated
companies are now regulated to have
their organizations
ethically hacked i'll say that again
organizations are
being regulated to have their companies
ethically hacked at least once to twice
a year
so what does that mean that means
there's job opportunities because it has
to be done
right and we're going to talk a little
bit about that later about their
certifications
um that can get you so that you can be
compliance
um pen test ready right because in order
to be a pen tester to do compliance
based pen testing you have to have those
certs
there's no bloods or butts about it you
gotta do it
so becoming a pen tester
it looks like we're gonna start to make
our journey down the rabbit hole
as we do this let's make sure we stay
open-minded and stay curious
so down the rabbit hole we go
all right so the student mindset it's
not an academic
mindset will an academic mindset help
you
of course but a lot of other things will
help you too
so developing a student mindset is going
to help you engage yourself be humble
with
yourself to continuously learn and know
what you don't know
right so that goes with continuous
learning staying out of your comfort
zone there's a book that i really
um really really enjoyed a couple years
ago called peak performance
don't know who wrote it i'll have to
look it up and i can put in the discord
chat here in a bit
after the talk um there's a talk or i'm
sorry a book called peak performance
where it actually talks about
maintaining just slightly out of your
comfort zone and then taking breaks so
that
you're able to expand um your comfort
zone right because if you're here
and then you expand a little bit out and
then you rest you might go only like
halfway back and then you actually have
a new comfort zone you're able to take
on more
um it also teaches you that you know you
you can continuously learn it gets you
um conditioned for that being humble
being humble is a big um issue in this
career field
uh so i've noticed um and there's a the
next slide kind of mentions a little bit
about that
um but we have to be humble and know
that we don't know everything about we i
mean pen testers and security
researchers and just offensive security
professionals in general
we don't know everything we know a
little bit about the things that we're
we're targeting right and then we might
have
a subject that we have uh mastered
but we don't know everything so be
humble stay grounded
and ensure that you portray that to
anyone that you interact with
continuous goals this is where you set
continuous
realistic goals for yourself don't set
something crazy
within a six-month span because if you
burn out in the time before that you're
probably not going to want to do it
and i speak that from experience many
many times
and just from observing it from other
people
take your time this is a career field
that is not going anywhere
and you can you know the sky is the
limit but it's
in the skies and go anywhere so just set
continuous goals throughout your career
seek mentors find people that know more
than you that are willing to help
a keyword is willing to help you don't
want to find some jerk who's not going
to help you because
they want to hold the keys to the
kingdom of their information and
knowledge
find people that are going to help you
and are helping others because when they
help others
you may will be able to help out the
other people that they mention at some
point you may
surpass the master so to speak or you
may get to a level where you're able to
help other people
another big thing is don't seek
validation in this field seek education
seek to educate yourself and others
don't don't pen test just to say i
validate myself as a hacker
no you're gonna turn into that
non-humble jerk
um always seek to be educated and
educate yourself
um that's a that's a big thing and then
none of this can be possible without
leaving uh fear in the rear view mirror
if you are scared to do any of this
and anything else within this uh this
talk today
you're not going to be it's going to
help it's going to make you fall short
and it's going to have a a snowball
effect where you won't be able to
to probably achieve the things that you
desire so you just have to leave fear in
the rearview mirror
and not care about the risk right
i'm not saying like go into hundreds of
thousands of dollars of student debt
to buy certs and education but do
set realistic goals for yourself that
you can achieve and don't worry about
um you know the trivial risk that comes
with that
so be humble not a megalomaniac i uh
tied in a
uh twitter post that i put out not too
long ago it says i don't know who needs
to hear this but offensive security
doesn't make you better than anyone last
i checked megalomania is not a must-have
on job applications
for those of us that work in the field
we know this very well where we see a
lot
of individuals who think because they're
a hacker and they know how to break a
certain type of technology that all of a
sudden
they have this superior than thou god
like complex
don't do it um you know your technical
skills are not too much powerful
right your job is to help people and
make organizations better
because it's one common goal to make
organizations better
and um eliminate any kind of threat
right so be humble not a megalomaniac
so be curious don't ditch the bucket
list but
do ditch the bucket list don't ditch the
bucket list when i think about it is
like something you want to do before
before you die right don't think about
the end just think about how you're
going to continuously grow
right and be curious so always look at
things from a different perspective
be hungry to learn new things be willing
to dive into anything
and tinker with anything you have to be
kind of like but yes person
you have to be able to just dive into
anything and take it on
right and that also feeds into staying
out of your comfort zone you have to do
that
i don't know any penetration tester that
hasn't had to maintain some type of
level
outside of their their comfort zone for
quite a while because you're constantly
learning new things so you have to
if you want to get into this field why
not start prepping yourself up
right try to understand different
technology
because being a pen test is about being
a jack of all trades and a master of
none you might master
something however if you master it today
it might change tomorrow
so do you really master it debatable
right
it's it's up for argument uh looking
at the discord chat really quick oh
there's a lot you guys are chatting it
up man
so growing your network this is probably
one of the most crucial things in my
opinion
and why because there's a saying that
you know
getting into infosec is sometimes not
about what you know but who you know
right so growing your network how can we
grow our network well for us
that are going to school or work for
school rather
whatever way it is or if you do both use
the school network
typically alumni are working in the
field or may not be working in the field
but if they are working in the field use
the alumni
networks to get into the field
linkedin linkedin is my favorite place
on the internet
um it's a great place to to collaborate
to reach out and illustrate your skills
i see a lot of
individuals on there right now they're
doing like try hack me challenges and
getting certs and they're publicizing it
all over the place
and that helps you get visibility
because somebody will like it and then
that gets
displayed on somebody else's feed and
somebody might share and that gets
displayed on somebody else's feed
so just keep grinding and posting things
on linkedin and it's going to help you
find a
find a spot and you can network with
people fairly easily right you just send
them a friends request
you know just go find the ceos of all
the big tech companies
just kidding twitter is another good
place twitter i like to think about as
like the common ground between linkedin
and facebook it's where you link with
other professionals but you don't have
to be so professional
um so that's a good place to do
look because there's a lot there's an
infosec twitter that is wonderful
there's lots of resources always being
posted out lots of information a great
place to learn and just to network
in a less professional um
more lackadaisic environment so to speak
online
facebook facebook is an interesting
place because you never know that person
that you knew five years ago might
actually work in the field
and so hit them up mentoring
you need to find um people that can
mentor you
and also find people below you that you
can mentor right it's
it's kind of a roundabout way but you're
able to share knowledge from
who you are a mentee of and mentor other
mentees
um and it creates this kind of like
telephone effect but what happens is you
think it you speak it
and then you hear somebody else
comprehend it and it helps solidify that
knowledge
in you even more and it helps um you
know you never know a mentee of yours
might actually get into the field
because of their network and they can
say oh yeah hey
uh come on over you know we gotta spot
the fill over here
conventions such as today with besides
denver again thank you for having me
is uh another great place to network
right uh for those of you in the discord
chat or on the twitch stream
you guys can sit there and hit each
other up and and banter and talk about
anything you want and you never know
you might make an actual really good
relationship out of that
and that might be the key to your
success to getting into information
security or finding that new uh
role in offensive security internships
are another good thing
i know they're they they didn't really
happen this past uh
summer because of kovid so you know
that's the exception not the rule but
internships are really good to do
um and you don't necessarily need to be
in school to do an internship don't ever
think that
um internships are not exclusively to
just students
and then on the job training you know go
find a company that might be looking for
free help
um or any kind of help that will lead
you into information security
or penetration testing um i did that i
actually was a security guard at one
point and then went and worked in a sock
because i wanted to get into i.t that
bad
so i did a lot of free labor working in
the sock
fun fact so just you know that's again
it's about being
just tinkering and saying yes to a lot
of things and staying out of your
comfort zone
growing your technical skills john how
do we grow our technical skills
well there's lots thankfully in this day
and age there's a lot when i even when i
started
in offensive security like five years
ago there there was nothing you go
download a
virtual image of kali linux and then you
try to find other
things to tinker around with now they
have you know things like this like try
hack me
hack the box loan hub these
organizations are creating platforms
where you can learn
in a fun and encouraging environment to
be honest um
i really like hack the box because it's
competitive and i really like tri
hackney for the fact that it's very
um student-centric where it's more about
learning
and then vulner hub is obviously where
you can go grab images install it on
your machine and go hack away
um in a safe sandbox environment within
your own home the other great thing
about loanhub is that they recently made
a partnership
with offensive security so if you're
looking to do the oscp
i would look at bonehub images in the
future for extra study material
um books obvious one right and i can't
recommend a book
because there are so many i do have a
book coming out in the next couple
months
with pac about aws pen testing so if
you're interested in learning cloud pen
testing
pick it up hacker one and bug crowd one
of these these
are above bounding platforms these are
where you can sign up create an account
and then actually go hack real websites
i love these because they actually have
you hack production websites and provide
vulnerability reports on what you find
and then
if you find something it actually goes
into your account you actually can have
a hacker badge that you can display on
linkedin or twitter and
and use that as a way to publicize
yourself
uh programming i can't recommend a
language necessarily but
i am um biased towards like python and
ruby
just because i'm not a programmer um but
i
do know enough python and ruby to do
enough for my job
as a penetration tester um so if you're
looking at that i would
highly recommend diving into one of
those two languages probably python is
the more popular one
um so yeah so look at those and we'll
talk a little bit more about that later
um and then cobalt io and synack these
are two platforms that are actually
pen testing um services
right it's kind of like a pen test as a
service where you can go
and do uh you submit an application and
then they run you through
a um and a couple interviews that are
technical and non-technical and then
they put you on their teams
and they basically send you pen tests
that you can do
and make money so and you actually are
pen testing real companies so it's a
pretty cool way to do like
crowd source pen testing i really really
like it um
i wish i had the time because if i had
the time as i really don't
right now um i would do it but um if
you're looking to get in the field and
get some
your hands dirty that's a great way to
do something
um for those of you that were in the
discord chat i did mention uh some
elearn security stuff
so uh ind and elearn security um
have made a partnership where they're
actually creating a training platform
that allows you to take all the elearn
security
courses on this one central platform at
one central price
the reason why i put this here is
because their training platforms
are amazing their training courses are
amazing they have amazing certifications
that are going to
give you 100 percent hands-on knowledge
in a specific topic
so if you want to learn something in an
academic and in a realistic sense
these are your guys to go to um and if
you have any questions
uh feel free to ask lily in the discord
she can tell you all about that so speed
bumps
speed bumps are another big thing uh
lacking experience security programming
technical stuff
it's it's it's a conundrum right how do
you get experience
in the field without being in the field
well that's where you have to use your
network and you have to use all these
other resources that we talked about
those bug bounty platforms creating a
blog
a technical blog that's going to help
you out right getting certifications
those are going to help illustrate
your security experience and your
technical experience so you just really
have to climb the ladder
in that sense and you also need to
utilize your network right and i know i
don't put it there but utilize your
network
again utilize it the network um
lacking certs start with the easy ones
uh you know i know a lot of
individuals that when they come into
this field they just want to go grab
oscp
and you know while that's great you can
do it um
why not get an easier assert that's
going to help you get a job right
especially if you're on the outside
looking in
you're like okay uh you do a linkedin
search for penetration testing jobs or
security jobs and you're like okay i
need
at least this cert go for that so that
you at least need not the big one
the one that you need at least uh
certifications like ceh which we'll talk
about in a minute
are not extremely difficult but they are
compliance-based
um certifications so if you get ceh you
can actually start going and doing
compliance-based pen testing
um i actually did that and i got a job
as a red teamer
for the dod so and i didn't have ocp at
that time
lack of job openings um you know denver
i mean i know this is virtual but denver
is actually a
hotbed for security so if you're in
denver and watching this
you're good if you're in seattle and
you're watching this you're good uh
seattle's a pretty hotbed
um for pen testing and security as well
however
i'm actually from uh a smaller town in
north carolina
and i don't really think there's any pen
testing jobs there
so if i had stayed there i wouldn't have
made it into the field right so i had to
move
um so follow the jobs if you're in an
area where where you know you can't get
a job you gotta go where the where the
jobs are luckily a lot more remote now
but you know if that's not the case you
might have to move
and you know just gotta do it
lack of motivation that's gonna be a big
speed bump because you're gonna burn out
because you're going to set expectations
for yourself and you're going to not hit
them sometimes and you're going to burn
out
so make sure when you burn out you take
a break because field's not going
anywhere
right enjoy the little things and you
know i feel
i'm sure you know if some of my family
is watching this they're sitting there
laughing because i don't take breaks
really um so maybe i should i should eat
my own words but uh make sure that you
you take breaks
and that you enjoy the little things in
life from the fruits of your labor for
trying to get into the field or getting
into the field
somebody called me a cheater funny
all right so career paths right
these are the various things that we can
do to get into infosec
right we can take these furious jobs
helpdesk sysadmin net admin
various security specialists right you
can see there's a lot there
you can be an independent researcher or
a bug bounty hunter signing up for
programs like
uh bud crowd and uh and hacker one
or just be a programmer a lot of
individuals go and get um
you know a four-year computer science
degree or go to a coding boot camp and
go be
software engineers for a little bit and
then they come into the field there's
really not a strict way to get into this
field
it's just about you know what can you
bring to the table that's different
right so these are various uh
career fields that you can go into um
i'm sorry jobs that you can go into
to get yourself into infosec has a of
course security specialist you're going
to be in
in information security so that's more
directed if you want to become a pen
tester
but these are just different avenues
that you can take um i've taken a couple
of my
i was a helpdesk guy and then i was a
security specialist engineer
i worked in vulnerability management for
a while
and uh and now i'm here
knew someone who got into security by
starting as a pastor
gonna have to talk about that afterwards
that's interesting
pin testing careers you can be a pen
tester red team or
offensive security engineer applications
security engineer
ethical hacker which actually is still a
job title in some places um
exploit developer consultant or purple
teamer
purple teamers is becoming a hot topic
because it's the in-between
of a blue team and a red team right so
you actually kind of like do a little
bit of both
and you oversee red team and blue team
operations
and then so the rest of these exploit
developers you're actually developing
exploits
for the uh the things that you're
hacking uh red teamers are the
the offensive operators offensive
security engineer
you get it we have a lot of slides so i
have to cruise through some of this so
that i
don't take up too much time so education
these are some degrees that you can get
comp sci cyber security
even an mba i know plenty of people in
this field that have an mba
because you understand the business
sense of things and it really helps out
so bachelor's degree typically required
master's degree typically
desired stay in school if you want to
stay competitive
right and i know there might be some
people on the other side looking at me
and being like john you don't need a
degree you don't
but it is nice to have a degree and make
you competitive right there's nothing
wrong with that
so um and coming from someone who has a
bachelor's degree a master's degree and
getting a terminal degree i mean it's
helped that those have helped me out a
lot
um in both um you know growing my career
and you know for monetary gain
essentially i mean you get paid
typically you get paid more if you have
a degree
um it's not always a case but it's a lot
of times it's the case so don't quote me
on that
but you know and you also learn things
from a different sense if you do the
academic
model as well right there's things in in
degrees that certifications can offer
you
so here's the big one
we got certification so here's some
certs that we're going to talk about
so it's kantia sec plus this is a good
cert to get because it's going to give
you a foundational
knowledge and certify you um in that
knowledge
it's 350 bucks for a voucher we'll say
200 for extra material and you're gonna
have to study for about one to three
months one to three months of two hours
a day
about five days a week and anytime i say
consistent study if i don't say how an
extra amount of time just say
think it's about two hours a day for you
know
five days a week at least um the exam is
90 questions
maximum you can get less i think when i
took it i took it a while back but
a long time a long time ago um i think i
got like 55 questions
but you have 90 minutes to do it you
have to get a 750 to pass which i
believe is like 83
passing without industry experience
because i want to make sure that
for those of you trying to get into the
field understand the difficulty
it's not too challenging if you if you
study properly um
again using the methods that i just
mentioned you should be able to pass it
on your first time
so the average cost per month 160 bucks
because we want to make sure that we're
not going
into crazy debt right and if you look at
it on a month scale
it's about 160 bucks a month
the controversy cert of the decade
controversial cert of the decade the
ethical hackers
um it is a twelve hundred dollar voucher
with a
about two hundred dollars an extra
material so you're going to spend about
1400 bucks total
it's a good cert to get because like i
said you can get it and then you're
you're ready to do compliance-based pen
testing
um it's about one to three months of
consistent studying 125 questions four
hours and you have to get between
60 to 85 to pass so
how difficult is this to get without any
industry experience
it can be challenging but ec council has
a two thousand dollar
course that you can use uh to prep you
up that might make it less challenging
when it's two grand
so the average cost per month without
that two thousand dollar class is about
450 bucks a month so three months at
about 160
and then plus this and you know you get
it and we'll we'll have a breakdown
here in a second of everything um
the elearn junior penetration tester
this is without a doubt the best valued
penetration testing cert you're going to
get talk to lily about it because it's
amazing
uh the cost is 200 bucks for a voucher
however you can spend 500 bucks get
four exam vouchers labs materials the
whole
bang that all you need to do it one to
three months of consistent studying
the exam awesome enough is a three-day
real-life penetration test
it's awesome right because it's one it's
it's hands-on
so you're actually going to learn the
techniques tactics and procedures that
you have to do
in order to pin test so
that's uh sorry i'm getting pain and
discord
so that's what you you know you get you
get from it
um passing without industry experience
less challenging without with proper
study but why do i say that because
you know you think well it's a hands-on
assert it's because e-learn security
really preps you
to take the exam they give you
everything that you need
and they and that's it you don't have to
go digging for extra information if you
don't want to they give you everything
to your path
to success to pass the uh the
certification so i highly recommend this
cert no matter where you are in your
career because it's just an amazing cert
the comptia pin test plus this is a very
difficult cert in my opinion
um the voucher is 350 bucks you're gonna
spend about 300
extra dollars on materials three to four
months of consistent studying
because this is actually going to
challenge you it's going to give you um
test questions that are based on
scenarios so you really have to know
things from a different angle
the exam is 165 minutes with a maximum
of 85 questions you can have less
and you have to get a 750 to pass that's
about an 83
very challenging without industry
experience i had industry experience
when i took this and i found it
challenging
um you know as humble as that is to say
it was an actually challenging exam
i honestly didn't think i passed when i
took it um
but i did barely humbly enough
but somebody asked what made it
challenging there's a lot of scenario
questions in it
a lot of scenario-based questions that
if you didn't work in the field
it would be very very difficult to
answer them correctly
very difficult um and i know like the
cyber mentor
um heath adams has talked about i
mentioned like it's a difficult one
because of the scenario based questions
it's and it's not like uh like stand
certs or like
you know these uh e-learning certs where
you have you know
open books or internets or the internet
or anything you you
go in closed book and that's it
650 bucks for four months so i'm not bad
we're not doing too bad on price
the certified penetration testing
professional this is a 600
1600 uh cert that you get materials labs
all that good stuff it's uh two to four
months of consistent studying would
argue that you're probably gonna need to
do about three to four hours a day
um it's a seven day hands-on penetration
test
with an additional seven days of report
writing it's a real world black box pen
test so for those of you looking to get
into the field if you get this cert it
says hey i know actually how to do this
in a real world sense
not like a like a ctf like a real world
sense passing without industry
experience
it's going to be challenging and like i
said 600 bucks so you're looking at
about 400 bucks a month
then we have the creme de la creme the
offensive security certified for
certified professional
um you're going to spend about i would
say
probably about 1500 bucks on materials
labs vouchers all that good stuff for
this
you're gonna spend about six to twelve
months to take this
if you do it unless awesome on you but
um you know it's a difficult exam you
gotta use hack the box try hacking phone
hub for extra study materials just so
you can
understand things at a different level
the exam is 48 hours you got
24 hours of uh of a hands-on experience
that will just
condition you and break you um
it's a ctf-like challenge but it is not
easy by
any means and then you have a 24-hour
span to write a report that you then
submit
um you have five machines that vary in
difficulty and you have to get a 70
to pass and then passing without
industry experience it's really
difficult
um and then i wanted to give this so for
those of you looking at the oscp it's a
different
type of certification as opposed to
elearn i love e-learning security
because they really teach you the
techniques tactics and procedures on how
to do things
offensive security is more like a
grueling experience
it conditions you into a offensive
security engineer
right so the training platform with
elearn is a good way to build up
technical chops
offensive security is just a mind boggle
that grinds you
and pumps you out as a as a different
breed of security engineer
um i also would like to shout out to my
one of my buddies who works with me
glenn moran who actually got his pass
on the certification today so
congratulations to him
so try harder is isn't just a creed it's
a way of life it's transformative and
that's 100 true that was my buddy chris
who said that
um he mentioned that to me on my first
time when i took this exam and failed it
um the oc pre oscp is a process unlike
any other certification out there it's
going to condition you and prepare you
to think like an offensive security
engineer
um and it's really going to push your
limits and push you out of your comfort
zone so the real cost of this
is priceless the entire journey is
priceless of course there's a monetary
value to it
but once you're done it's it's relieving
and it's
it's amazing so
so the road map this is the cost
analysis i want to mention so first year
second year
right we're looking at a total of two
hundred twenty four hundred dollars on
the first year
thirty seven hundred dollars on the
second year um
we are running short on time so i'm
going to kind of like glimpse past this
a little bit i will publish the publish
the site
publish the slides in uh discord
when we're all done so that way you can
uh use these for later
um and then there the talk will also be
published later um
on youtube so but look at this know that
that's about the money that you're going
to be spending
and it's only about what 6 500 bucks
give or take
that's really cheap for a bunch of
certifications that are going to really
push your career
and get you a six-figure income if
that's what you know part of the
part of the game right because we all
want to make sure we get a return on our
investment a lot of times it's monetary
values right
so degrees versus certifications that's
a big thing
degrees help build your network because
of the alumni groups that you become a
part of
they teach you business processes you
understand people influence culture
um mbas are going to really help you do
that phds are really going to help you
do that
they keep you accountable you have to
turn in assignments right otherwise you
fail
and some provide you with high-level
technical skills uh even technical phds
are doing
a thing now right the phd that i'm doing
is highly technical
certifications provide accredited
accredited proof of knowledge
right so that means that you are
accredited and certified by a governing
body that you're
able to understand this right
uh provide technical skill sets right
the ejpt pen test plus
pcpt and the oscp and then some required
for
dod or compliance those are the asserts
that you can get to help get you a job
uh security plus ch and oscp obviously
osp's the big ones
maybe not go after that one first um
and then jobs often require them because
of hr filters
uh i saw somebody post on twitter
yesterday that they have oscp but they
couldn't get a job as a penetration
tester because they didn't have ceh
that's the kind of silliness that we see
with hr filters so you kind of have to
play the game we don't make the game we
just played it right so we have to kind
of
go and go with the punches of the uh of
the industry
the other big question is why not just
do both degrees provide your career to
excel and certifications provide your
technical skills to excel
so why not both do it all
you got plenty of time programming
python bash ruby c and java so
python bash and ruby are good for
scripting um i've really been getting
big into ruby lately because i'm trying
to develop aws metasploit modules
um so i'm having a lot of fun with that
so if you are interested in
developing metabolic modules look at
ruby um
bash and python are just really good
scripting um
languages python you're going to learn
you can use that to write exploits and
things like that
and yes i did mean excel sorry typos
gamephd canada can't even type or spell
correctly
um c and java those are what a lot of uh
uh exploits are written in so um for
those of you that go through like the
oscp and stuff too you're going to see a
lot of
exploits written in c in java
other knowledge you're going to want to
know obviously the domains of windows
linux networking and software
cloud is a big topic right now and if
you learn that you're going to be able
to be competitive
highly recommend going into cloud if you
can um
because it's just a new technology and
um
it's it's gonna it's going to become
more than just like deploying ec2
instances like
there's um cloud business intelligence
platforms
there's a lot of different things that
cloud
i feel like everything is being directed
to the cloud in the next 10 years or so
um and on-prem stuff while it will still
be there will
almost start to become an afterthought
so here's those high level road maps
what's up
so six months to two years at a help
desk position this is the help desk to
pin test track by the way
while you're in that position why not
get security plus right
and in six months to two years i
guarantee you'll get into like some kind
of sysadmin net admin
maybe some kind of security engineering
position once you're at level two
where you see right there under assist
admin look at start getting some other
certs like ch pintest plus ejpt to start
propelling
your career into security and then
go get a security engineer position
remember to while we're doing all this
besides the certifications you can also
get a degree um
and and utilize your network that's you
know rule numero no
utilize your network um and so while
you're a security engineer
get uh ecppt by either security or oscp
or both
um and then once you have those certs
you can get into red teaming and pen
testing
while you know they're not required to
do it it
is always pretty good um and this is a
pretty common path that people
people go on and then obviously after
that you can go
into management become a director um you
know maybe even become an executive
ciso cso um you know it's
the the world is yours you know so says
tony montana
so um you know just
use this as a template and you know
feed in your own data into it and know
that you know you can go from
a help desk to becoming a pen tester
within less of two years and i
it's pretty common for that to happen
so this is the student to pin test track
this is another one that i see where
students become pen testers
um you know you go through your fall
spring internship stuff while you're
doing an internship get a cert
i see a lot of interns just work and
then that's it
and that's great but why not get a
certain while you're doing it you might
even be able to get your company to pay
for it
degree programs you see the list there
comp size cyber security
info tech i'm sorry information
technology and informatics
once you get out of uh school you know
look at an entry-level position
whatever job that is it doesn't matter
whether it's in security
or it's not in security right
take an entry level tech position or a
level one
and then stay in that role for you know
six months to a couple years to get
comfortable
with the industry and then boom find
your mark and get into pen testing
also get some of those certs that we
mentioned you know on this slide
all right staying curious and giving
back it's a big thing
big community we're big on community in
this industry
so make sure that you give back on
various hacking forums
different blogs um
then also subscribe to those hacking
platforms that we talked about those are
gonna help build your technical skills
and you're gonna meet a lot of new
people
and find your niche you know you got i
only listed a few here
but there's so many things that you can
do in this career field
so you know just make sure that you
really you keep your hands dirty
and you stay active
make sure you find a mentor make sure
you're finding other student pen testers
and then also make sure that you're
finding people that you can teach and
then also make sure that you're getting
on those bug mounting platforms because
those are going to help
so here's a question um that somebody
wanted answered so
how to get into pin testing with certs
but no experience right because you hear
a lot about that
i hear a lot um sign up for blog bounty
programs
do crowdsource pin testing platforms
such as kobold io
and synack find those internships use
your network
and what and big thing is be humble you
know don't say don't just think because
you have a
security certification or even if you
have oscp that you're all of a sudden
some big hot shot guru pen tester
um you know you you have to be humble
otherwise nobody's going to want to work
with you
as harsh as that may sound
and then take security related roles
with a company where you want your pen
testing career to go so if you want to
go work for a big tech company maybe and
you can't get a pin testing job
um think about just you know going and
working for him
in a typical security position
it looks like we're about five minutes
to my time so
which is good because we're closing up
so closing thoughts
how'd you go on your journey into
infosec pin testing
whatever it is that you decide to do
with your life
you're gonna start and you're gonna have
a lot of ambition you're gonna have
you're gonna be hungry you're gonna be
so hungry
and then you're gonna fail you're gonna
hit a ditch you're gonna hit a wall
but make sure when you do that then you
get back up or if you fall make sure
that you make a
make a fall forward that way when you
get up you at least have a little bit of
forward progress right
and when you fail be humble and think
about why you failed
what did you do wrong and from there
you're going to learn
you're going to learn what you did wrong
and you're going to be able to use it as
a learning experience a lesson learned
and be able to grow from that because
security is a journey
and it's not a destination and with that
is my talk today here are some weird
places where you can find me you can
find me on twitter at
musee moose i'm on linkedin under john
helmus
i also have a blog on medium uh under
jonathan c
helmus and then upcoming events
i'm actually doing a four-hour aws pen
testing workshop
at shell con unfortunately it's sold out
uh it's sold out within about five days
so um those tickets are gone
um however i'm going to be talking at
vetsetcon
on october 16th at 10 30 a.m that's
um pacific time i'm going to be doing a
talk similar to this but it's geared
towards veterans so if you know any
veterans that are trying to get into
cyber security and more exclusively in
the pen testing
please direct them to that talk directly
to me be glad to help them out
um i'm also talking at gray hat this
year um at the end of october i don't
have a set date but my talk
is um it's about bypassing
aws policies through pen testing and
then also
um last but not least i have a book
release um
i have my book published by pac it's
called aws pen testing
and that's going to be coming out
sometime in the fall so follow me on
linkedin
and twitter and you'll make sure that
you know it gets
published out when uh when it comes out
so
with that we got q a
so q a on the twitch or on the discord
i'm at your
uh your questions for the next three
minutes
can we pre-order the book uh let me talk
to the publisher
yeah i was going to say go ahead and
watch the discord but answer the
questions on the stream
for people who are not on the discord
okay
so on the twitch stream you read the
questions before you answer
oh go ahead is anybody else sorry
uh it doesn't look like there's anything
on the twitch stream somebody said 20 or
24 000 maybe i made a wrong number uh
it's kind of funny so before i publish
the uh
the slide deck out to everyone i'll make
sure to do a good throw cleansing
uh grammar in it
yeah if i so if anybody has any
questions it doesn't look like there's
anything on the twitch channel
um but i'm going to be hanging out in
the discord channel for the next
20 30 minutes so if you guys want to
hang out and talk to me i'll be in there
and uh yeah
great thank you very much john we
appreciate it yeah
thanks guys