[Music]
bounine
hi everyone
I mean at the beginning of summer my
daughter got a rare illness the pressure
in her spine was increased by by a
condition called afm and resulted in her
spine and a brain pressure increasing
within a matter of hours my daughter
turned from being the crazy fun-loving
girl that we always knew to a girl who
couldn't breathe battle to breathe
couldn't stand up couldn't sit barely
could speak and this happened in a
matter of hours by the time I got her in
the hospital her left arm was completely
paralyzed she couldn't stand up she can
do you should could almost do nothing
how she was diagnosed with acute flaccid
monetizes
it's a rare polio like condition that
effects affected about a hundred kids
here in the u.s. so far the prognosis
wasn't good out of the hundred or so
kids many of them have died and only a
number then less than five percent have
had full recovery the that night I spent
time on my phone
researching all I could I got hold of
some of the experts and some of the
specialists that had treated this
condition previously I also managed to
get hold of some of the some of the
parents that have kids with the same
condition and their overall feedback and
advice was to to try and do as much TN
PT preserve physiotherapy as possible
and hopefully that that my daughter
would be one of those those lucky few
kids that that would get through this
there their primary advice was to hope
that that my daughter would be one of
those that would would get through this
but you know I learned a long time ago
that hope is useless unless you take
action and that is when we decided to
take this project head-on the advice has
been that o team PT would be their the
most suitable treatment for this but
there was only a 5% chance that that
that would really help and that would
really work in the long term so we
decided to take this challenge head-on
we wanted to do something for her we
wanted to make sure that that we do ot
and Pt in them in the meantime but we
wanted to increase the chances of her
actually getting a floor full use of her
arm and getting better so instead of
simply doing ot and Pt over the next
couple of years we wanted to to do
something for her now we decided that
that we would build a robotic prosthetic
arm to help her primarily with the
ability to use her the muscles signals
from our existing arm and tried to use
those two to control the the prosthetic
so by encouraging the use of her arm and
encouraging that rehabilitation to take
place so that was our project and we we
decided to do that so while still in the
hospital we set up a Facebook page we
set up a wiki and we asked people for
some guidance the help now it's probably
at this time that I should tell you that
I have no experience in hardware hacking
before this I much of what I'm about to
tell you I must also confess that I'm
not too sure of everything that I'm
about to tell you so if I I'm new at
this I'm this year so disclaimer I'm new
at this the terminology I may use it may
not be accurate but I trust everyone
here is will know what I'm talking about
I am however experienced as an
entrepreneur I do tackle some some
challenging some challenging projects so
I I do know how to add lease to to kick
these things off
so we started off by boiling down the
issue
my daughter's arm was paralyzed from
from the shoulder down to her wrist
she's still able to use her wrist she's
still able to use her fingers and the
likelihood of her regaining the use of
her arm is very low it's about 5% or so
so we needed to figure out one is we
wanted to give her the ability to use
her arm again and two we wanted to
increase the the chances of her actually
having a rehabilitation arm so that was
that was the that was challenge number
one challenge number two was the the the
weakness other shoulder so we spoke to a
number of parents there that have had
this with their kids over about a year
or two the the weight of the other left
of the limb would pull it out of its
socket and so even that even the weight
of the limb was was going to stretch the
the arm and so we had some some
challenges there now my wife's sewed up
a shoulder sleeve and we use kinesio
tape which is tape that athletes used to
to keep their their muscles secure and
with the shoulder brace that we built
and the kinesiotape
my daughter's able to hold about 150
grams worth of additional weight without
there being any risk of our pulling so
that was the target to whatever we
wanted to build had to be about a
hundred and fifty grams or no more than
150 grams which I guess is five ounces
or thereabouts next is her bicep and
tricep the muscle that would
predominantly be used when when we're
doing this type of motion are completely
paralyzed now there was some hope when
she was in a zero gravity environment
like like when you submerge yourself in
the pool she was able to move her arm
about ten degrees each way unassisted so
we knew that some signals were coming to
her arm through through her neurons but
there was significant damage she could
do about ten degrees either way so we
were going to need to try and figure out
how to pick up those signals they were
extremely weak but that was a there was
a big big challenge
the weight of her forearm was about 400
grams so whatever mechanism we will
needed to be able to pick up that 400
grams continually at least 400 grams and
we wanted whatever we do to be able to
be used over the course of about five
hours so she could take it to school she
could go play friends with her friends
so that was there was another girl and
again my daughter's five years old so
she's going to be growing up quickly so
whatever we do needs to be able to be
designed and continually amended and
updated as we go so that was that was
again something a core requirement of
ours is that it's it's quickly updated
and then if we had any hope that it
would be used on daily basis and that
she would want to wear it it's going to
need to be beautiful her request was
that it was multicolored and add and and
it had flowers on it so we're gonna
we're gonna do that so now we had all of
our requirements and we didn't know
where to go but at least we knew what we
needed and so we we recorded a video
together where we explained everything
that we wanted to do and we we published
this on Facebook within this video we
seeded the conversation with the
prototype is simplified idea that we had
so we wanted to create two arm casts two
arm braces two to hold the the mechanism
we needed to to source some type of
mechanical actuator or something to to
pull her arm up and down be an actuator
or a pulley system or something along
those lines and we wanted to embed the
sensors in the in the upper arm brace
and then we decided to to buy some some
initial equipment to test things out
with we bought the Arduino starter kit
and EKG board so we can test out
different signals we also bought some
electrodes and and and some hobby muscle
sensors and we put this in the video
telling people that you know this is the
stuff we have
how can how can you help us and within
moments literally within moments we
started to get some feedback and some
help one of the the people that have
helped us right from the start was Jose
from from Mexico we had never met him
before but he's now been helping us all
along
initially he started helping us wire the
Arduino and helped us to program the
Arduino to to move the actuator and this
was really fun so that those are my two
kids and they helping helping me now to
sort this out so it was really fun so
this is my daughter and she's she's now
learning how to do all of this on her
own as well well with me from South
Africa and Germany we got help from
experts in electrodes and batteries then
on the west coast we got help from a
friend what we needed to do was get a
scan of her arm so that we can we can
accurately print out a 3d cast and we
didn't really know how to do that so
friend of ours helped us with that and
donated an Xbox Kinect for that then
from Canada we got some we got donated
actuators from a company called actual
Onyx some folks from Columbia University
helped us with the mechanism to pull her
arm up and down making sure that the
that the we had sufficient rotation to
pull her arm up and down so that was
cool again we didn't we didn't know
exactly you know how to do that and then
all around the world we had help from
our friends help with figuring things
out as we go so that was really cool we
didn't expect all of this help over a
course of several weeks we designed we
went through multiple iterations of the
prototype we my daughter and I built an
arm rig first a rig an external arm Rick
to test things out on that first and we
went through a couple of iterations on
that eventually we we built some things
that worked on our arm this is this is
one of the more successful prototypes we
had so we use something called Fisher
technique which is kind of like like a
Meccano or technical Lego to
to build out to account some some
prototypes and that worked pretty well
we then figured out how best to do a 3d
scan of her and and again we didn't have
any real equipment proper equipments but
we ended up using the Xbox Kinect and I
needed to make sure that she she stays
within a certain axis I got her to stand
on the plate and then you know lied on
the floor and gradually turned the plate
to get a scan of her and that worked
pretty well the next thing was we we
really wanted to print it out so it
fitted her arm perfectly and we had
challenges with that so we decided to
print it out flat using PLA plastic and
then boy boil put it in boiling water
and then molded around her arm but I
didn't want to burn her so I made some
casts and ramen and forearm casts and we
molded around that instead and that
again worked pretty well actually did
that for the first time on Friday but we
had a significant challenge was trying
to get that signal from her arm the the
way the the muscle sensor works and you
guys must correct me if I'm wrong but I
believe there's they measure the voltage
difference between two electrodes you
put on your on your on your muscle and
so this is the chart of what it looks
like with when it's when it's looking at
my arm you can obviously see the the the
muscle signal when it's relaxed when
it's active and when it's relaxed again
and what the muscle sensor then does is
it applies a filter tries to filter out
all the noise it normalizes the the the
filter and with this we then apply a
threshold and whenever the the muscle
signal who reaches the particular
threshold we would trigger the actuator
so if if I pull my muscle the actuator
would reach a threshold the actuator
would pull up and if I release that that
that signal it would push it back down I
also had an electrode on my tricep so if
I push down it would actuate and push
the arm back down and
this worked really well for me however
for my daughter it was a different story
this is what her muscle signal looked
like we could barely pick up that she
had any activity when she was really
trying to pull pull her muscle up
so this was a serious serious issue from
us for us we had to set the threshold so
low that occasionally it would be
triggered by her heartbeat or by her
finger twitching or by something else so
this was a serious roadblock you know we
could have solved the problem by maybe
putting a muscle sensor on a risk was
arrested and it did work so she could
possibly you know twist her wrist up and
we could use that as a signal or we
could build a potentiometer on the on
the actual sleeve and have a use that
but that would allow her to use her arm
but we really wanted this to be in a
device that also helped to rehabilitate
Iran so we were really desperate to try
and figure out how to get the signal
from her from her muscle so this was a
serious challenge for us I come from a
computing background and I I know a
little bit about machine learning enough
to be a little dangerous and machine
learning takes a vast not amount of data
and it looks at it looks at particular
patterns that it could tie to try to
recognize and then you could program
that that once it recognizes a pattern
it would trigger another event it could
trigger another another action and this
is how machine learning for works for
visual recognition and voice recognition
so my thought was can't we instead of
using a meso sensor that filters out the
noise and filters out and normalized the
the the signal couldn't we use something
along the lines of my machine learning
to to look at the full raw signal from
her arm and try to to work with that so
again we put out a video asking for help
and after a few days we got a response
we also found a company called coapt who
are doing
something really similar putting on 17
electrodes in step two we managed to we
managed to train a system to recognize
that signal and she was able to control
a virtual arm using the the signals so
now we're pulling this all together
we're at the stage where we're putting
it all together we're trying to figure
things out and and that's where we're at
so we we started a few months back not
having any experience in any of this but
we we get in there slowly
currently we have a prototype that is 10
times lighter than anything else in the
market it's also 10 times less expensive
and we're using a novel signal
recognition detection system and that's
where we're at but I wanted to bring my
daughter here with me today as well but
we couldn't and in the last moment so
she wanted to send a video quick sorry
when I show you that
lorelei can you tell us what this is
[Music]
okay let's show everyone how it works
so the actuator can pull your arm up and
down k-11 why don't you control it show
everyone how it works
cool right he loves to get involved I
know I've got one 30 seconds left but I
just wanted to show you so this is her
controlling the virtual arm so we've got
17 electrodes and it's wrapping up all
the raw data and is trying to trying to
figure out what she's trying to do and
so this is a little game we've got so
now she has to practice by using her her
existing muscles and by doing this she's
already gained about I don't know what
it's what it's in terms of but on a
scale from one to five the
physiotherapists gauged the strength of
the muscle or the ability to pick it up
over over gravity and so when she when
she first got ill she had 0 out of 5 and
she's now progressed to 1 out of 5 on
that scale just by doing things like
this so that's that's been awesome
while this is just one of the prototypes
this is how the the one muscle signal
works my my bicep it senses the signal
and pulls the arm up that's right yeah
it's like a muscle right so this is the
arm rig that we built to test things out
on first and there's my son getting
involved and this she just wanted to
make some funny faces so I decided to
put this in there as well that's it
thank you everyone
[Music]