[Music]
hi my name is Julie um I am community
leader for hackaday I oh so I just want
to take a moment to introduce you to
Chris Coleman chris is a device security
expert and software engineer he is an
active developer for the wolf crypt
cryptology and could cryptography engine
so so round of applause for that son
yessir me okay there we go
alright so like I was introduced I I'm a
software engineer with Wolf SSL we
specialize in ssl/tls cryptography and
related products and protocols so today
thanks for coming to this session the
goal of it is kind of to give you a high
level introduction to the fundamentals
of device security I know the the
knowledge ranges really between
attendees on our level of detail and
security aspects and protocols so this
will cover some of the basic ones it'll
give you a good foundation to grow your
own knowledge and then hopefully help
you to make more secure devices in the
future so promote we've seen this
there's really three or four main key
areas that we think are important to
focus on for device security the first
one being the network so this is data in
motion the second one being storage or
data at rest on your device and the
third one being firmware so how are you
updating your firmware are you
protecting that and making it secure
against malicious attackers loading
their own firmware on your device and
then the fourth element is is a little
bit separate from the first three key
areas but it's cryptography and it sits
underneath all of this top sorry so the
first section we'll talk about is the
network or data in motion data in
transit so there's three top security
goals that we have to keep in mind that
we're trying to accomplish here the
first one is you would like to have
privacy this prevents against someone
eavesdropping in your connection the
second thing that we're trying to
accomplish is authentication so this is
going to prevent against someone
impersonating one or both sides of your
connection either your client or your
server device and then the third one is
integrity this is going to
it's data being modified in transit so
your client is sending the data you
think it's sending or it's receiving the
data that hasn't been meant to be sent
to it and there are several different
protocols or methodologies we can use to
accomplish these goals some of the main
ones being SSL and TLS which is secure
socket layer and transport layer
security or IPSec the difference between
those two are really where they sit in
the network stack so SSL sits between
the application and transport layers or
a zips exits lower at the network level
if sec would be your application
everything sitting on top wouldn't
really even know that it's being secured
by IPSec underneath which is convenient
for the application but it's also less
customizable for each application if you
have three applications for example and
they only they all want their own
security settings that makes it more
difficult whereas SSL and TLS lives more
in the application layer so they can
each customize the settings they want
that appears they want to trust etc and
then the other thing sometimes people do
is design their own protocols this is
this is sometimes a lot harder than you
think it might be even when you look an
established protocol like if secor SSL
or TLS there's there's one er abilities
found in problems and issues every year
and those are by groups of people who
are cryptographers and do that for a
living so I just want you twice before
you go and implement your own protocol
so the most common used protocol between
those two is SSL and TLS so I'm going to
dig into that a little bit deeper you
may be curious where it sits so this is
a simplified diagram of the OSI model
you have the transport layer and gray
there typically that's tcp/ip but that
may be UDP Bluetooth something some
other protocol of your choice the the
blue boxes are the SSL and TLS protocols
there's four sub protocols within that
there's the handshake protocol the
change self-respect protocols the alert
protocol on the record layer
the handshake is responsible for
authenticating peers negotiating a cyber
sweet to use the change diaper spectro
recall signals changes in cipher II
strategies the Aleut protocol pretty
much just does that it conveys alerts
fatal or warning and then the record
layer is really the workhorse of SSL so
that's what's taken care of the
encryption men formatting the packets to
be sent across the wire you can see blue
boxes here those are examples of
application layer protocols which could
be either on top of your transport layer
or one step up above the SSL and TLS
this protocol has been around for quite
a while it was invented by Netscape in
1994 the first version of it ever being
released was sl 2 point 0 in 1995 since
then 2 point 0 and through point O of
SSL are now insecure um in 1999 moved
it's switched names to TLS or transport
layer security and that now has gone
through three revisions one point 0 1.1
and 1.2 1.3 is currently in the works
the TLS working group is working on
finalizing the specification or RFC and
the time frame for that's kind of up in
the air we thought it was going to be
done at the end of last year but it's
not it's still not done so someday that
will come there's some experimental
support in browsers like Chrome and
Firefox if you get their development
version or the development branch you
can have a early implementation of TLS
1.3 and then DTLS is Datagram TLS this
is TLS designed to be run over
unreliable protocols like UDP and then
this is just a glimpse of an RFC which
defines these SSL and TLS and DTLS
verticals
so as a protocol it uses cryptography
underneath and it uses different types
of cryptography and puts them together
and so it uses hash functions like eight
like md5 sha1 sha256 blocker stream
ciphers like AES Triple DES ChaCha 20
and then public key functions like our
essay or ECC and it put these into
what's called a cipher suite which is
pretty much a string representation of
what algorithms you're going to be using
in that connection so if you've ever
configured a web server with SSL support
or a client connecting to a server
supporting TLS you probably dealt with
something look somewhat similar to this
when the client first connects to the
server it goes through a process called
the TLS handshake so this is a kind of
what it looks like some of these
messages are optional so the green
blocks are sent from the client to the
server the red blocks are sent from the
server to the client and the yellow
blocks are optional that are sent
depending on what what protocol or what
options have been turned on and so this
will get this will accomplish several
things for us it will authenticate that
the client Android the server is who we
think it is it will establish that
cipher suite so they set of algorithms
being used in that connection and then
down when you get to the bottom of it
you have your you finally have your
secure communication channel you can
send and receive data across
in addition to cryptography the second
big thing it provides a is
authentication this is done using x.509
certificates and public key cryptography
so one or both sides of the connection
has a public and private keeper this
would be generated using an algorithm
like our essay or ECC and in TLS the
public key is wrapped in what's called
an x.509 certificate this is signed by a
trusted third party called a CA her
certificate authority and these
certificates come in different types of
formatting and encoding the two most
popular being Pam or privacy enhanced
electronic mail and der PEM is a base64
encoded representation an example you
can see here der just being a binary
representation or binary encoding and
there's some others that you might see
like pkcs7 excuse me our pkcs12 because
cs7 is used for signing and encrypting
data pkcs12 is a bundle of certificates
and keys
so once you have one of these
certificates you can chain them up
that's called a certificate chain so
that's where every certificate is signed
by the one that has come previously
before it and when you finally reach the
top that's called the root CA which is
the one you would want to load into your
client if you're connecting to a secure
server to correctly authenticate that
server this is an example of one of
those chains so this is for Google you
can see that Google's server certificate
is in blue here there's two intermediate
cas finally signed by the root
certificate authority the equifax secure
CA so there's some challenges when we
look at embedded use with TLS as you
guys know embedded chips can be very
small other flash sizes or ram sizes
there can be a number of operating
systems so there's that I don't know 20
30 real-time operating systems available
today they can be very slow mmm the
processor speeds they're not the same as
desktop computers and cryptography is
very performance intensive they can have
little quirks like locked and lacking a
file system having varying logging
capabilities memory handlers can be
different you can use different
compilers you can have different
standard C libraries and the good thing
is there's solutions for most of these
so you can exclude algorithms you can
use smaller algorithms you can select
different math libraries to use and
there's these will help reduce your
footprints I see your RAM usage some
math rbcs more stacks I'm uses more heat
for the OS and the file system in
logging you'll want to look for
libraries that have abstraction layers
and porting it reporting areas that you
can tie these into your specific needs
for slow processor speeds you know
there's a couple things you can
you can leverage charter base
cryptography you can also choose more
performant algorithms and then for
compilers on the standard libraries
you'll just want to look for cross
compiler compatibility and the ability
to be able to cross compile libraries so
there are challenges but luckily we can
work through them so the second kick the
second key area is storage or data at
rest now this one might seem kind of
obvious at first so you want to encrypt
sensitive information that rest that
might be user passwords that might be a
sensitive user data that might be keys
and only store what you need to store on
the device so the security of your
system really depends on the security of
your private key so there's a couple
ways you can handle provisioning that
private key to your device you can embed
it in your firmware from the factory you
can transfer that from young to do
embedded device from a remote key server
somewhere and or you can another option
to generate that on the fly on your
device itself so like upon first boot
you generate your keys and then they're
always on your device I never left your
device so there's less of a chance
someone would have intercepted them
during transit and some good practices
you should use different keys for
different purposes so use a different
key for SSL and TLS versus code-signing
versus data encryption so if one gets
compromised and vulnerable the other
areas are still secure you should also
often you should also think about
changing your keys on a periodic basis
hmm so this will minimize vulnerability
again the longer your key is in use the
more chance it has to become vulnerable
and then how do you store your keys
securely so ideally you'd have a secure
element you'd have a TPM or an HSM that
provides a secure area in hardware for
those keys to be stored there's some
some cool advancements that's been
happening at mill has a new 85 05 08 and
the ECC 508 processor that has secure
storage and ECT ECT ation ecdsa
cryptography in the chip but what if you
don't have the secure element there's a
couple other options that you can do so
these are just a few if your device is
attended you could require user input to
decrypt those keys to then proceed to
use them if it's a not attended you
don't have that option to have that user
in putting a password so you want to
take some precautions like maybe
automatically zeroing out the keys if
the device is tampered with or using
your crypto subsystem that would
automatically zero out those for you so
that brings me to my third key point is
for more updates so traditionally
firmware server sends a firm lower
bundle down and gets applied to a device
so that works great but how do we
prevent against this attacker sending a
malicious bundle down and getting
applied to our device how many of you
guys have worked on a problem like this
before a couple
so my next couple slides show you
something kind of a rough outline of how
that might be accomplished using public
key cryptography and hash functions and
so on your server side you would need to
generate a keeper using RSA or ECC or
another public key algorithm you would
have your firm learn you take a hash of
out using a hash function in this
example is shot 256 that will give you H
pash you'll then do an RSA private
encrypt operation so this is taking your
but your private key using RSA to
generate a signature and then this is
your signature for that firmware bundle
that you can apply but now that's going
to be sent to your client and so on the
client side this gets snapped over your
clients gonna kind of undo those steps
and do a verify operation so it'll take
its own hash of the firmware it needs a
way to get the public key from the
server or have already been transferred
that key you live an RSA public
decrypter the RSA is hearing as an
example this could be ECC or something
else on that signature using the public
key that will give you the original hash
we generated on the previous slide if
these hashes are the same we can be
relatively confident that that came from
who generated that original hash and we
could we could continue to apply this to
our device so sure that seems to make
sense but another issue is how do you
get the the firmware bundle to your
device securely sometimes people send
that just over a plain text like a TCP
connection or something but it's you
know a little bit more robust if that's
secured somehow have that transport all
that so one thing that we've kind of
thought a little bit about and I have a
little bit is using MQTT as the secure
transport of that bundle MQTT is a
message queuing technology it's a
publish-subscribe free look
so this is a simple diagram kind of how
an MQTT setup would work so we have our
film or server we have an MQTT broker
and these are our end devices which
would also be acting as MQTT clients the
clients subscribe to a thread or topic
so for example like if i have an iphone
there could be iphone 6 update thread or
topic my server is publishing them to
that topic so it would push an update to
the iphone 6 update topic that would get
propagated through the broker and all
the clients would pull it down so that
have you done over a secure link like
ssl/tls and then your clients would
still be doing that signing and
verifying between the client server that
we looked at on the previous two slides
so that's this kind of a rough outline
of how one of those systems might work
there's various implementations of that
so the first section now is going to
kind of apply to all the three that we
just talked about so that's cryptography
how do you use it effectively and make
sure you're using it securely the first
thing to talk about is random number
generation so just like I said the
private keys are kind of important for
the rest of the security of your system
your whole crypto system security or at
least part of it is dependent on true
random numbers so you need to generate
your randomness but that can be very
hard on an embedded device especially
when you don't have a lot going on I've
seen a lot of ways that people have done
it badly her poorly sometimes people
forget to take test code out or they
just code a constant number to return as
a random number which has 20 randomness
that I've seen people use clock source
which might seem random but if you think
about it the time that you power will
reset your device to the time where you
get to that same point in your code
where you doing a crypto operation is
probably somewhat fairly constant
there's not a lot of random listen
some people also try to use harbor
serial numbers Mac numbers which may
seem kind of random but they're probably
predictable if you can figure out the
sequence of device device manufacturing
I just some quick terminology before we
keep talking about random numbers
there's a trng is a true random number
generator that's a generator that's
getting entropy from from your
environment so that could be like ring
oscillators environmental noise noise on
the chip a PRNG is a pseudo-random
number generator this is a cryptography
algorithm that mimics generating
randomness it's a lot faster usually
than a trng and you need to seed it with
entropy from the trng typically another
thing you'll hear is drbg that's
deterministic random bit generator and
that's just the kind of the see a vp and
NIST's term for prng so those are
equivalent to those last year so you
want to verify your energy is seated
with a good entropy source the
oftentimes the best story on embedded
devices is to use aren't a hard round
rubber generator built into the silicon
and it's really becoming more prevalent
but these are found in embedded devices
today these are some examples that I've
worked with in the past it's all these
have some form of hardware orangie in
the silicon alternatively another thing
I recently read about you could get her
from a remote server and I was looking
at this white wooden at random it's a
library that allows you to get
randomness across the network and
there's actually like a quantum based
solution you want to make sure your key
links are adequate the list in this
special publication 800-53 mendations
one of them being recommended key sizes
so this you can see there's a level bits
of security and then it'll allow you to
match up
the right key length across all your
different types of algorithms and the
effective level of your bits and
securities only as good as your lowest
algorithm or your lowest key length so
if you were trying to shoot for 128 bits
security but you're using shot one you
would effectively only have 80 bits of
security another kind of gold references
this key links calm it it gives you
recommended key sizes across all these
different working groups or
organizations sometimes I can change
depending on what area of the world
you're in another thing when you're
tuning crypto keep in mind that
algorithms perform differently in
performance so here you can see HD 128
stream cipher is way faster than dark
for is the next stream cipher on this
graph or AES is faster than triple dose
for example so I'm an embedded device
for your processors are not quite as
fast as you know you might expect in an
enterprise environment choices here make
a pretty big difference you want to
still use secure algorithms some of
these are known as weak weak ciphers or
weak algorithms like arc for our c4 is
not recommended to use any longer and
again now many vendors are offering this
in in silicon so typically you'll find
block ciphers and hash functions in many
of the the part their processors and
chips from some of these companies these
are some examples of those that you
might typically find in silicon so AES
des Triple DES md5 sha1 shot to you and
performance also very like I was
mentioning the hardware's is a lot
faster usually three to ten times faster
than software crypto so this is a
benchmark i did on a microchip pic 32 MZ
platform here the the blue
is suffer cryptography done in this was
an archival library and then the red is
hard the hardware crypto being done and
then here I also did it again this is on
at nxp previously freescale k60 so that
was my quick overview kind of some of
the areas of security scuri is a huge
broad field and so it's good to start
out with an overview and then kind of
drill down into specific areas if you
have interest in them so this is my my
key takeaways for you guys for today use
a secure protocol like SSL and TLS for
for data in transit I don't use plain
text I custom protocol design is hard I
encourage you not to try to design your
own protocols unless you're you have a
very strong backing in cryptography and
security encrypt important data arrest
and be concerned where your keys are
stored and and how they're stored use
Hardware key storage when you can the
options are getting cheaper and more
much more plentiful prefer using
stronger key links and referenced the
sum of those those things that those
bodies have already put together for you
as the guidance for more updates I do
pose a real attack vector we don't want
someone taking control of our devices
just by flashing a different firmware
onto the vice if it's not intended sign
it and cook the updates and think about
how your trance transferring from the
client to the server or from the server
to the client I use true randomness to
seed your crypto algorithms use secure
cryptography and keep an eye on how the
vulnerabilities are coming out over the
years you don't want you know you want
to be able to the flexibility to change
from one I'll go to the other if
something becomes vulnerable yeah don't
be afraid to ask an expert there's a lot
of people who do this for a living and
all these different types of areas it's
a very complex field and there's plenty
of people to help and then most
importantly have fun
I know it's sometimes it's kind of a
looming topic that it's hard to approach
but it really just takes a little time
time to dig in so that's all I have for
you today thanks for listening and again
for coming
[Applause]
[Music]