[Music]
Kate Reed is an artist and inventor from
Dover Massachusetts and she Ponder's the
human experience at every turn solving
real world problems with simplicity and
economic availability to all Kate's
designs and inventions have been
featured at the White House at Boston
and New York Fashion Week Museum of
design in Atlanta the MIT museum
Boston's children museum and at hackaday
super conference kate is a student at
the brown RISD dual degree program
currently and so let's give a round of
applause to Kate hi I'm Kate Reed here
today from Providence Rhode Island it's
great to be back in this amazing
community sharing ideas across all
disciplines i'm here today to talk about
design and why design belongs in every
step of the creation process and how to
develop healthy design work habits and
it has to do with the people when
creating something new it's easy to get
swept up in the thrill of technology and
mechanics to rush ahead with a new idea
and say it works but don't forget the
people from inventing the wheel to
inventing the automobile we create and
design in an effort to make human lives
better good designs are made for people
they evoke an emotional response from
the user they are intuitive to use and
they're cost-effective to bring to
market over time our inventions have
become more and more high-tech
especially these days but regardless of
that fact we are thinking feeling
spiritual beings that are far more
intuitive and emotional than we often
acknowledged as designers and makers we
must invent for the deeply complex
that we are design and folks an
emotional response when it comes to new
products humans care about more than
just function we have an innate
connection to the natural world shapes
colors and even sound evokes an
emotional response from us and our
environment affects our feelings we are
attracted to beauty and associate
designs with memories and dreams be it
conscious or subconscious we look for
emotion and our designs we need to know
this as we create and keep this concept
in the forefront of our minds for each
project as we create and create spaces
we want to think early on how we want
people to feel as they engage with our
creations classical architecture was
designed to convey a sense of power
starting way back with the Roman Empire
walking into a black room makes us feel
dark inside being in a classy vintage
car makes you whimsical and shifts your
sense of time the world of feeling and
emotional attachment is strongly at play
in the products we surround ourselves
with think of how many iphone cases
there are so many but why people want to
express themselves what brings me here
today is invisible a public art campaign
I created that is entered in this year's
hackaday competition I would like to
share this product project with you and
emphasize how I utilize these design
concepts and habits in the creation
process invisible people are invisible
all over the world for a variety of
reasons some by choice some by necessity
we all have parts of us we want or need
to be invisible be it your sexual
preference race income the list is
endless
invisible is a campaign that places
interactive translucent sculptures all
over the world for people to contribute
their inner and visibility's to and be
empowered by the sharing of others this
human silhouette asks a question etched
on its heart what makes you feel
invisible scribble your answer on a
piece of paper and drop it into the
sculpture the more people who donate
their invisibility zeeeee the more
empowered the campaign becomes as the
sculpture fills with thought donations
the sculpture itself becomes more
visible a stranger's thought donation
will be available to you when you donate
yours or will be anonymously posted
online for all who seek we all struggle
out of fear of our differences and
acknowledging these fears can lead to
social change so this project began last
spring in Cambridge Massachusetts out of
my daily interaction with a homeless
community each morning homeless people
lined the streets of central square as I
walked to school they had already been
out on the streets for hours by the time
I was headed to school one woman always
called me bunkie back back while another
homeless man would always smile and wait
telling me have a wonderful morning
these are my people my morning community
yet our lives are so very different it
was heartbreaking for me to see day
after day passerby completely ignore
these people in their situation why do
we ignore homeless people are we
frightened of the homeless are we
frightened by our differences or by our
shocking similarities what if there is a
way to shine light on homeless people in
their plight without the fears
associated with actually speaking to one
which causes people to shut down and
ignore the problem stifling social
change thus the concept of invisible was
born my goal was to create a sculpture
to reach people make a statement of our
inner worlds
inspire compassion for others to concept
stood out for me the first was I felt
invisible should be human centered she
humans shaped to get people emotionally
invested I experimented with different
representations of humans sitting lying
down standing but there was no question
for me that it had to be human because
that is the element that invites and
intrigues people to come in and take a
closer look the second concept was I
felt invisible needed to be transparent
that would come into play later in the
design but I had this concept from the
beginning to help guide me here are some
early sketches I knew I was getting
closer to an emotional design response
because my emotions were responding
trust your instincts in your community
feedback I sketched until I got what I
was looking for I then mocked up a rough
idea of the sculpture just using
cardboard and saran wrap in full support
of hackaday in the open source community
I began looking for human shapes already
in existence why reinvent the wheel as I
searched around four different 3d models
of bodies I came across this mannequin
made by fab lab using the Autodesk
software 1 2 3 d make and I loved its
aesthetic feel I especially love the
slant of the layers of cardboard this
gave me a place to start I pulled the
Autodesk file into Rhino because that
was the best program for me to
manipulate the files and I plan to do a
lot of manipulating I knew I wanted the
sculpture to be transparent so my
challenge was to tweak the shape to be
so it could be Hollow and take out as
many layers as possible to keep the
sculpture open and feeling i took out
ninety percent of the layers i added
arms legs a neck and a head to create a
body position of hopelessness and being
invisible all the while thinking of how
i wanted people to feel as they saw the
sculpture because i took out so many
layers i also added vertical supports to
a common
the changes I then laser-cut this
iteration in cardboard just to make sure
everything fit together and was
structurally sound with phase one of
invisible complete its it was now time
to explore how invisible would interact
with people this brings me to my second
point usability the best designs are
intuitive to use if you have to tell
someone how to use your product then you
are not done designing here's a door
going into a store it has a handle yet
also a sign telling you to push or pull
it we've all been that person tugging
and pushing over and over again on the
door in the wrong direction and a flow
of people laughing it off after we
finally get through the door this door
is not designed well if you have to
cover your product with instruction
stickers you've not fully fleshed-out
your design oops Dyson hand dryers he
has so many models but look at how
intuitive this one is there is no sign
telling you to put your hands into the
put your hands in there yet you know to
put your hands in with a gentle shape of
the opening and it's called the air
blade which signals you to move your
hands out slowly even though there are
no instructions take the toilet wand if
it were just functional you could just
literally use a sponge to clean a toilet
but nobody does that because it's
disgusting the first toilet brush
designs added a stick which was a
welcome improvement but then someone
really thought through the toilet
cleaning process and sorted out all the
gross parts here's a toilet one with a
drip guard that also foot with a drip
guard that also functions as a lid to a
storage container brilliant a usable
product and one people would gladly buy
over a sponge completely intuitive to
use and decorative this is another
project of mine i created a Tai Chi
environment and experience with floating
dodecahedron
there are five floating dodecahedron at
various heights surrounding an empty
circle as you enter the circle and move
close to one of the orbs it begins to
glow if you move too fast towards the
orb the light shuts off you quickly
learn you quickly learn to move towards
each orb to lead your meditation motion
they can be set for various programs to
represent various Tai Chi routines once
again intuitive to use back to invisible
I needed a way to draw people towards
the sculpture while I accomplish this
with the first step in designing the
body shape and transparent materials I
now needed to find a way to get people
to add their notes to the sculpture I
didn't want to put a sign next to the
sculpture with instructions or literally
make it like a panhandler holding a sign
I felt that would limit people's
interpretations of the project so
instead I experimented with etching
words onto the chest plate I designed a
chestplate that asked the question what
makes you feel invisible at first I
tried a very flowy naturally natural
feeling chest plate with a few invisible
suggestions around the edges but it
didn't match the style of the rest of
the piece I then settled on a sleeker
looking design that allows invisible
suggestions to be more plentiful in
various sizes suggesting different size
problems different levels of awareness
and for different people my goal was to
include as little direction as possible
as people read the chest plate they are
able to see notes inside the sculpture
in the opening in the chest plate to
drop then in just one starter note is
enough is enough to give direction with
invisible now aesthetically drawing
people in and intuitively showing them
how to interact it was time for my third
challenge keep your costs in check you
can design something amazing and truly
revolutionary but if it's too expensive
to make
it's not going to make it to mass-market
maybe your product is so amazing that
you can commit yourself to the cycle of
seeking funding and development money to
make it happen but the earlier into the
design process that you consider money
the better off you'll be bringing your
product to market the hub ting
inflatable bicycle helmet from Sweden
such a great invention but coming out of
the gate it costs 325 dollars the
average bike helmet costs ten to twenty
dollars the Segway was hope was hoped to
take off and truly change the way we
travel within cities it costs over a
hundred million dollars to develop and
prices out these days at six thousand
dollars the first complaint out of
people's mouths when it comes to the
Segway is always it's too expensive the
electric car is now coming into its own
and is going to make it to market but
it's been around forever the first
electric cars were invented way back in
the 1800s just 30 years after the
motorcar but only now has the technology
and cost-effectiveness balanced out so
that the electric car can enter the
market the marketplace as a true option
for people there is a full market
available now to making technologies
more cost-effective here is our hand
drive wheelchair attachment that was a
finalist in last year's competition our
3d printed wheelchair attachment allows
any wheelchair to be powered in a rowing
motion while there are other attachments
out there that essentially do the same
thing ours is available at a fraction of
the cost less than 1% while there are
many factors in determining whether or
not products make it to market the
biggest one is whether it can be
mass-produced inexpensively in
proportion to its value with the design
of invisible complete I now have options
of materials to use invisible can be
made out of glass solid acrylic cast
resin or plastic all at various price
points I considered these options at the
very start of my design process my goal
is for my design to be cost-effective to
find that balance between materials
manufacturing and work hours so I can
deliver a quality product that's also
cost effective I want some of my
invisible sculptures to live outdoors on
the streets this means I need them to be
strong and weather resistant i also want
some of my invisible sculptures to live
in schools and libraries where they will
get lots of hands-on interaction with
children so they need to be sturdy i
also want my campaign to go worldwide so
i need materials that can be
mass-produced inexpensively for my
outdoor kid-friendly version i decided
upon 8 inch a clip acrylic laser cut
pieces secured with epoxy that wrapped
in saran wrap it's inexpensive as each
sculpture costs approximately a hundred
dollars material the downside is it's
fragile until it's wrapped with saran
wrap I've created a second version of
invisible where you can take out other
in visibilities as you put yours in for
this version I added three millimeter
holds five to 10 millimeters apart and
strung the entire structure with clear
elastic this version costs twenty
dollars more in about 20 more hours of
work invisible is now ready to go the
files are downloadable so I can have
them laser-cut in towns where I travel
for an installation or I can pack the
pieces in my suitcase throw in some
epoxy and saran wrap and I'm ready to go
invisible is all about the people with
this design I can show up at a library
or school anywhere in the world with my
invisible pieces and put together an
invisible with the community members
they can be a part of the rapping or
stringing process and can participate in
putting up invisible thought donations
on the website from time to time I'm
hoping my invisible campaign goes viral
in closing my reminder to you is
something that you already know
that design matters and should be a part
of each step of the creative process
from concept to prototype through
developing iterations and through to a
final product design fails often happen
by considering design too late in your
creative process or forgetting to check
in with your design goals often enough
establish good design habits for
yourself and for your team ask yourself
these questions often who is this
product meant for is this product
aesthetically pleasing how do they know
how to use this product and why would
they choose as product over something
else knowing these answers to these
questions at any point in your process
and your project along the way will
result in stronger more thoughtful
user-friendly and cost effective
products thank you for having me it's
been a pleasure speaking with you if
you're interested in an invisible
sculpture in your area I love to talk
with you more to make that happen please
keep in touch and if you'd like to
follow my invisible campaign you can
find me via the website wwm visible
world thank you
[Music]