[Music]
and we're live hi everyone I'm Dan I'm
the Resident Engineer here at the supply
frame design lab and I'll be your MC for
the rest of the afternoon I apologize
for the bright streak of sunlight that
we've got going across the presentations
right now this was a design flaw of the
facility that we just noticed about 16
hours ago so we're actually I would
imagine about 24 hours ago when we were
doing the tests so we gamely tried to go
put some covering on that window and
turns out it's not something that we can
get to with the tools that we have at
hand right now so I apologize for that
moving right along I am pleased to
introduce qualm Ana who is going to be
talking about open mV he is the
co-founder and CEO of open NV he's an
electrical engineer who started working
on open M V because of a love for
computer vision and microcontrollers so
I'm going to hand it over to Kona Lilly
alright great okay so I originally did
this talk for the open source hardware
conference so I just kind of have it in
nice 15 minutes and a little you know
notes sheet just to go over everything
anyway hi everybody I'm Quabbin Hodgman
co-founder and president of open mV and
today I'll be talking about how I took
my project from a hackaday fail of the
week to a success all right okay so
first what is open mV well let's say you
can kind of see that we're a company
dedicated to making computer vision on
microcontrollers easy our product is the
open MV cam it is a microcontroller
programmable in Python and you can use
the opening B cam to take pictures and
video along with being able to run
machine vision algorithms on images that
are captured and stored in its RAM all
you were able to do all of this while
being able to control io pins use a spy
bus I squared C bus you know DAC a DC
turn I Oh pins off and all
interrupts pwm etc the whole plethora
features and last but not least it comes
of across platform IDE so you can
program it easily and you can see the
frame buffer along with your code window
serial terminal and a histogram of
what's going on all in one nice view
so we're a hackaday project
that's how open if we got started it was
originally a co-founder a guy named
ibrahim he created the project on a blog
post pretty much looking for a better
camera sensor and eventually there's a
huge following of people behind that
blog post looking to see this product
realized so he then went on and made a
hack and a post about it and kept
updating features and such so as a
hackaday project we're actually one of
the most scold and love projects on
hackaday we have 150,000 views 2,000
likes or whatever skulls and many
followers if you go to hackaday io and
scroll down you'll see our project is
one of the first projects up on there
just in generic product you know project
list anyway so a lot of people were
interested in the project and this is
how it got steam to go forward and
become a real product Ibraham actually
put the open MV cam into the 2014 hack a
day price we have able to get sim
finalists we didn't win but that was a
good enough view response for us to go
forth and do a Kickstarter after this
and so putting your project on hack a
day and letting people know about what
you're doing can really help out to make
your product a reality and you know give
you that push you forward to actually
help them you know for you to develop it
and finish that product so anyway I said
we did a Kickstarter so with all the
enthusiasm from the community I brahim
went on to do a Kickstarter he was able
we were teasing we were able to raise a
hundred thousand dollars and we had nine
hundred backers considering how we
didn't do any advertising beforehand
this was quite good our video was
for equality but you know we had enough
people were interested in the product I
got a I got involved in the product
around this time I was trying to jump
ship onto something that was successful
or join something that was successful I
thought it was going to be joining a
gravy train anyway
open MV is an example of again how you
can take some idea that you're just
messing around with engaging and using
the community to gauge the response for
do I want to actually make something
real out of this and so on and so forth
yeah I should read these notes a little
bit more actually prepared it a little
better boom kind of AB living right now
anyway okay so there are other examples
of people going from hackaday to a
Kickstarter project to before I was
making this presentation I saw a product
called Mehcad we know online and this
was basically a Kickstarter hackaday
product that it had a project that had
gone to a Kickstarter to make a closed
loop stepper motor controller and
interesting enough their product got a
lot of views a lot of people following
it a lot of people liked it and this
push them forward to go on and do a
Kickstarter they didn't raise a terribly
large amount of money but they got
$60,000 and enough to build the system
and pocket a few thousand personally
just for their effort so by embracing
the community again you can make
something a reality so anyway my story
open MV cam so this talk is about
overcoming failure like in every story
arc there needs to be some rising action
some conflict some failure an open MB
cam story we chose the wrong camera chip
to go into mass production with in
particular we designed the open MV cam
with the o v26 4-0 image sensor from
Omni vision it was a nice chip they had
built-in JPEG compression which allowed
us to take high-resolution pictures and
store them on the microcontrollers Ram
in the sense of it having JPEG
compression or literally just send you a
JPEG image byte for byte on 8-bit data
bus and you would distort a memory and
you could write that to disk and you
were done
it was also cheap to cost costing $2
apiece the only flaw though was it it
was an old chip very old in fact from
2006 so these things have been sitting
around for 10 years we didn't think
there's gonna be a problem we built them
we thought it was gonna be ok but there
was a few or a few issues our prototypes
worked fine but so there were pending
problems in mass production right so
actually no we had a eighty percent
failure rate on the cameras we went to
manufacturing eighty percent failure
rate pretty much thank God we tested
them before shipping them to our backers
we were trying to do this
semi-professionally how did it happen
well it turns out that the camera chips
have little tiny solder balls at the
bottom of them which go bad over time so
depending les they're a complete
temperature sealed so completely sealed
from the outside world in the humidity
protected environment the solder balls
corrode they rust and after 10 years
they're completely worthless there's no
way you can actually put the camera down
on the PCB board anymore so we actually
made hackaday fail of the week because
of this someone gave an anonymous tip
and bam our failure was on front page of
hackaday
so as you can see on this slide the
actual problem in particular is that's
the solder ball on the top and on the
bottom you have your solder paste and
there's not really a connection between
the two right there they're they're
physically connected the camera won't
fall off but they're not electrically
connected and so there's about twenty
eight of these little guys in the bottom
of a very tiny chip and if just one or
two fail you got to start over
cameras dead can't do anything about it
for our own personal production we were
just using a lot of heat with a hot air
gun and that would eventually get it to
work but then also risk cracking the
camera chip because it has a little
glass panel on top of it
so there is a difference of course
between building one unit when you're
prototyping and going to mass production
and building a huge amount so a second
little bit Tim bit of information is to
be careful how you source your parts so
these bad cameras where do they come
from
well our chip our manufacturer macro fab
we actually got in contact with them and
they let us know that and they actually
went over to Omni vision and asked them
how did these chips come about how is it
that we were able to buy these chips
even though it was ten years old and I'm
division tracked that down and looked
into it and responded with those chips
were only sold to cell phone
manufacturers they were never sold in
open market so the only way these chips
existed was from either people
desoldering them from old cell phones
and then repackaging them to sell them
to poor saps like us or them for or from
them literally just being unused stock
that had been sitting around an open
package for ten years pretty much guess
what we bought everything from
Aliexpress great quality low prices
anyway so be careful where you're
sourcing your parts it may not get what
you expect so at the beginning of this
year the situation was bad for our
Kickstarter we had about 18 K of cash on
hand from the 100k initially allocated
we have built up 150 open MV cam so for
80 percent failure rate on them and of
course these cams were not really
repairable we had 14 hundred and 50 bad
PCBs and we had another 500 bad camera
modules on top of the 1450 camera
modules we hadn't soldered on so we had
about two thousand camera modules that
were worthless this was a write-off of
about 10k pretty much last but not least
we had 900 dissapointed backers who
could easily turn into angry mob if we
didn't eventually get something out to
them so these were dark days but while
we were demoralized and while things
were looking really
bad there was a way out so what I did
was I used that 18k to pay for another
manufacturing run I realized that the
open MP cam community wanted the camera
they had come in and supported the
project and from all the people who had
supported us previously before the
Kickstarter I knew that there existed
that this product needed to exist people
wanted it so we went ahead and worked
relentlessly day and night every weekend
doing product updates doing firmware
updates to build hype for the product to
make people more interested in wanting
to and want to buy it later on
and we also slowly tested manufacturing
of 10 cameras to make sure that we could
get it working with a new chip in
particular we switched over to something
called the ov7 725 this is the image
sensor that we bought directly from the
factory so he completely avoided all of
the ball pop solder ball problems and we
did ten at first and they all worked
then we did forty two panels to test a
test to make sure they all worked and
again we were successful 40 out of 40
worked so we were able to move forward
hit the button and go into mass
production and build all 1,500 new camps
so
this was a long amount of work we all
right so I haven't been reading this
thing that's I'm totally off sync from
when I was always saying anyway yeah so
we did a Kickstarter update every two
weeks and we were working like crazy on
this to make people aware of all the
things we were doing and getting working
because of all the effort we put in on
updating the product and basically
making it better and better every day
our Kickstarter backers actually jumped
in and helped to raise us help raise
money for us to ship these products
because basically we took our shipping
money that we had allocated and spent
all that on another manufacturing run
but in the in the end the results were
worth it
we were able to build all 1,500 and ship
them all to our backers and so this is a
picture of someone finally receiving
their openmp cam so what did I learn and
let me kind of resync myself to my notes
here first you need to get the community
obviously as I say for involved in a web
project you're doing from day one and
blog about what you're doing it talked
about it whatever you can do that's kind
of why I'm here
doing a little bit of marketing and
talking about the product trying to get
rid of rest of the units that we have on
stock in general don't develop your idea
in isolation
previously I had spent 1.5 years working
on an IDE that made it easier for your
Arduino to do graphing on it like you
built the ability to like automatically
generate graphs and user interfaces when
you connect to George window to the
computer it was really nice and powerful
but no one wanted so I spent 1.5 years
working for nothing
whatever the case getting the feedback
will let you know immediately if you're
going on the wrong path second you're
going to need grip to do the Kickstarter
project so if you're doing it you're not
going to get any pay in my particular
situation I've been working nights and
weekends and more or less getting that
project rolling without any pay and any
so for for any kind of just basically
sacrificing to make the product or fit
because I believe that if I got through
this hard moment in time
we would get something that's good on
the market people be willing to buy it
later on also make sure you're
passionate about what you do again
because you'll need that to have that
kind of grit to go on and forth and make
your product also biggest thing do
yourself a favor and plan what could go
wrong before you make the thing and try
to figure out ways to recover if you can
in a particular case we had spent all of
our security buffer money on on paying
the two founders originally of the
product and this put us in a very tight
situation later on in time so by saving
all your money and not spending it and
using just what you need wisely it'll
make it a lot easier if you let's do get
into a hard situation second well next
slide so verify your manufacturing
product process and don't go out and buy
a ton of parts immediately one of the
particular problems we had was we had
all these extra camera sensors that we
had to throw away pretty much if we had
just bought a small quantity and didn't
go out and spend thousands of dollars
buying thousands of sensors we would
have learned about this particular
problem immediately and I'd have blown
so many pcbs and camera sensors on it
other projects have died from this does
anyone heard of Zano No okay well Santa
was a Kickstarter project that raised
3.4 million dollars I think it was the
biggest one ever
and there was a whole fiasco on them
doing a product video where they didn't
they were showing off a product that
didn't actually work the way it did in
the video they're kind of making that up
and they got a ton of funding they went
ahead to build their system and they
basically bought all their parts
immediately and because of that they
originally figured out though so but
they were building a drone pretty much
little drone that could take a picture
and follow you around and they bought
them so they bought you know thousand
tens of thousands of propellers for the
drone but when they went to go build it
they found out that the propellers were
too small to make the drone fly so
instantly they had a huge write-off from
all those
repellers that they throw away so
spending all your money up front before
you do your manufacturing is a terrible
idea
instead verify your manufacturing in
small steps and try to get up to a large
bulk order that way you can make sure
that nothing goes wrong and in the
process also updating your Kickstarter
constantly and being transparent as
possible makes a huge difference
we were lucky not to get besieged by a
bunch of angry email messages because we
update it every two weeks anyway that's
all nice and short simple talk I should
have followed the script a little bit
more thanks for listening and also
before I go I just wanted to give a
shout out to macro fab there our
contract manufacturer and they stuck
with us the whole way they were actually
in charge of diagnosing this problem
they were basically trying out all kinds
of medieval methods to make sure those
solder balls worked they actually try
and grindin the bottom chips using extra
heat dipping them in acid rebelling them
all kinds of crazy things to make these
cameras work before we finally give up
with the camp with the ob2 6 4 zero
camera chip and switched and during all
this whole time they were basically
losing money but they kept their word
and kept working with us as a product to
make sure we can get out the door anyway
that's it dude
[Music]