[Music]
okay
so up next we have Derick Schulte a um
he is responsible for our all hardware
and firmware at new matter he works on a
wide variety of projects from follicle
implants to spaceflight fiber optics
he's worked on force-feedback robotics
industrial scale solar trackers and
laser initiated pyrotechnics so can we
all give a round of applause to Derick
Schulte which is thank you I'm here to
talk about efficient processing for
motion control I apologize some of the
fonts are appearing to not show up right
so you'll have some subscripts there off
anyway that really boils down to how to
get from A to B and since this is
hackaday I'm assuming that doing that
along a straight line is pretty easy but
it gets quite a bit more complicated
well you want to go from alpha to Omega
and you're going to do that with
multiple segments in 3-space so you need
to figure out how to round the corners
because you don't want to come to a stop
because we like to make stuff that looks
like that all that said I am the
principal engineer for new matter so I
am a little bit of a corporate shill we
make a 3d printer and it has been a
market for a little while it's an FDM
based printer so we're laying down
basically like a robotic Lu Gong drips
of PLA in 50 micron 40 micron layers
with a 400 micron nozzle I'm assuming
you're all probably familiar with that
process we'll talk about a little bit
about our development process where we
went from a sort of crazy really couple
axis but really small printer to a penny
drive mechanism to what we showed its
yes to a web-based system for
controlling the printer of trying to
sell it also we can make ping-pong ball
launchers it is a consumer focused
printer so if you want to hack your
printer you're probably better off with
a lulzbot which is one of the conference
sponsors that said I am a corporate show
okay so if you want to make a 3d printer
you first need to think a little bit
about what the requirements are for that
printer functionally speaking you need
to do special motion control obviously
you've got an extruder that's going to
have motion that's coupled to that
spatial motion control you have to think
about thermal control for the heater you
need a path planner which we'll talk a
bit about and obviously you need some
comms on that printer if you're building
a product there's a whole bunch of
product requirements since this is
hackaday I'm going to try to avoid
talking about product development issues
but sometimes those work their way in
letting out those functional
requirements into a product you come up
with something that looks like the block
diagram when I do this I highlight
things in red that make you lose sleep
at night particularly connectors and
harnesses this will show up in a similar
form and a little bit later when we show
what the firm water boils down to when
it comes time to select motion control
components often one of the first things
we think of is the good old NEMA 17
stepper motor that's not your only
option they are expensive and they can
be noisy but they're very easy to
control you want happy daddy and fine
brushless motors you can make your own
galvo x' or you can machine out operable
v12 model engines if you happen to have
some nice swiss made motors or gearboxes
around this work well - lots of options
here for feedback and control you might
use something like a quad cell P SD slot
car motors capacitive modular encoder
systems that Hummel solenoid all sorts
of great stuff this is where mechanical
engineers some stay up late at night
browsing the weapon
but if you're actually trying to put
something together for a product you
can't necessarily go into your garage
and grab that air bearing system in the
lower corner so you have to use some
product engineering where you put down
the parameters you come up with a bunch
of calculations you compare those
calculations against each other put in a
whole bunch of merit functions and I'm
trying to avoid talking about that and
we wound up selecting a common motor for
all four of our axes so it turned out
that when we looked at the resolution
the speed the force torque etc
requirements and a variety of during
arrangements we were able to use a
common motor which greatly helped our
selection process and in this case it's
a brushed DC motor with a high
resolution encoder on the back and that
gives us a little bit less than 0.3
degrees per County in quadrature which
is very convenient we put that together
with an emic self belt drive system in
the pinion rod arrangement for the x and
y axes
we used a simple gearbox for the z-axis
on a threaded rod and then a gearbox
with an idler gear for the extruder and
we were ready to go so that cut puts
together a system this is all of the
electronics that gun into a mod t that's
it in that we needed a controller board
we decided to roll our own controller
board predominantly for cost reasons but
also because we were using a servo motor
system I'm not aware of any other 3d
printers on the market at least in the
sort of sub $10,000 range that use a
closed loop control system and that had
some additional complications on the
electronics that we needed to roll our
own on so we use an STM 32 f103
microprocessor and Allegro 849 53
motor drivers with that and variety of
other components that are there you
always want to put in some debug
functions like having a serial port even
if you don't expose it and your product
later on we found that we actually
needed four different voltage buses in
the product in part because of certain
can components that we wanted to use for
example we use
the CC 3100 Wi-Fi module from TI which
is frankly a bit of a disaster although
it does work and it was pretty certified
board looks like that
you can see in the lower corner there
all of the dense stuff is the canned TI
circuit area that you have to follow if
you want to maintain certification you
can see the SD chip there we've got a
little SD card and some flying leads and
some connectorized stuff which people
like me lose sleep over in the firmware
we chose to use free are costs as a
real-time operating system in part to
modularize the development of the code
for the system we use the GCC toolchain
arm compiler in the Eclipse IDE you
implement a bunch of functions you put
together a state machine you wind up
having to fake a bunch of states you
find up having a bunch of events and it
all turns into an eye chart and back to
talking about to actual path processing
for motion control now that we have some
hardware so we're going to get from
alpha to Omega it's not as simple as
just following a simple line we need to
actually compute what these curves look
like and actually get into time domain
information so again we can make another
mess so where does the planner fit in
this process if you're going to create
something in a typical 3d printing
workflow you're going to create some
geometry whether you download that
geometry or you create it or model it in
the CAD package or sculpt it you then
generally export that to something like
an STL or obj file which is a really
simplified a triangular tessellation it
is then sliced in the vertical direction
because we generally print layer by
layer and then filled in with paths and
that creates the G code the G code is a
basically a set of destinations and
target velocities that you would like to
hit in getting it to those destinations
so if you want to exactly execute that
line path every time you come to a
corner you have to come to it
complete stop because in each segment of
the line you're moving at a fixed ratio
between the motors we don't want to come
to a stop in part because the the flow
rate you'll have basically drool from
your extruder nozzle and it will take a
long time to print so we work on a
planner again this sits between the
g-code and the servo execution of the
actual path and we're going from sharp
corners to rounded corners in doing this
you need to think about acceleration
limits in the system whether that be on
the motor specific cider or resonant
frequencies velocity limits in the
system you may be thinking about jerk
limits where jerk is the derivative of
velocity how much path error is
permissible how long it's going to take
how smooth you want it to be the axes
are coupled dynamic computation so
g-code file may have say a million two
million lines in it because of that and
if you're working in 96 kilobytes or Ram
you can't pre-process the whole thing
very easily so you're going to be
trading off between processing that path
and then kicking that path out or
kicking those instructions out to the
servos if you're going to be able to
pause and resume in that system it gets
a little bit more complicated how are
you going to handle the pause and then
remember where you are and then start
planning again you also need to think
about how to handle interrupts desperate
ization or residuals if you're going to
go through a sort of a fixed interval
time clock on the path the actual
computed time to go through a segment or
sub segment may not land or generally
won't land on a specific discretization
so you need to make sure that you handle
that residual so that you've computed
path it's actually where you want it to
be when it comes out all of that said
really boils down to how do you manage
the acceleration so that you don't stall
or you don't skip how do you manage the
corners so that you don't have to stop
and how you don't a crash because if you
can only look so far ahead how do you
know that you won't be coming to a stop
at a particular time if you're not going
to round the corners and you
are coming to a stop you don't have to
worry about crashing there are a bunch
of ways to do planning you can do this
with really simple step functions for a
lot of systems you can use trapezoidal
velocity profiles you can do coronal
rounding you can do finite jerk methods
and you can do smooth jerk or smooth
doubts related methods in the case of
the mod T were used trapezoidal velocity
profiles with corner rounding the trick
here is to keep it simple to figure out
what you can actually get away with in
your system and make the early stuff
work first because chances are you may
want it later during debugging so
oftentimes you'll want to work through
this in a step based fashion as your
system starts to come online trapezoidal
velocity profiles look like trapezoids
here we have one in pink the
acceleration is a step function the
distance coming out of that in this case
we have an S curve and we've capped the
top of the velocity at some limit for
the system the nice thing about this is
that that slope is constant you can have
a different entry velocity or exit
velocity but that slope is always
constant so it's really easy to figure
out what the optimum trapezoid needs to
look like governed by acceleration
velocity and distance really
straightforward functions they're very
nice and that that's just a quadratic
and you have the quadratic formula which
has a discriminant that's easily
evaluatable to tell you whether or not
you have the roots that you want in that
equation but you have infinite jerk if
your servo time is infinitely small at
those acceleration transitions so that
is something that you do have to be
aware of and how your mechanism is going
to handle that and and how the system is
going to behave when it comes time to
actually rounding the corners again
there's lots of ways to do this you
could come to a short corner come to a
stop you could implement a circular arc
you could do a spline and a track
transition curve you can do in order to
brake overs there's low-pass filtering
methods all sorts of stuff like that in
the case of the mod T we put in a few
simplifications the first of which is
that we said when we go into a
we're going to enter that corner at the
same speed as we're going to exit the
corner we're not necessarily going to
hold the same speed through the corner
but are a long path a long path velocity
coming in will be the same as it is
going out and that greatly simplifies
how you look ahead in the buffer and
figure out what you're the look ahead
processing needs to look like which
we'll come to in a second we also said
that we're going to have a constant per
r6 acceleration so there'll be step
functions in the acceleration but you
either have that acceleration or some
other computed acceleration for any
given sub segment of the system
we don't have a continuous function of
acceleration that we're trying to
evaluate we're going to ignore what the
actual path shape is as it goes through
the corner we know it's going to be
bounded by a circular arc through the
endpoints and the sharp corner but we're
going to ignore where it actually is and
we're going to calculate the geometry
the endpoints the fee and row in this
chart before we do the reverse pass in
velocity and we're going to corner in
the plane of fee Q and Rho the three
points of the start and end of the
corner and the actual corner so if
you're doing this in three dimensions
you need to know what plane you're
operating in once you know the per xyx
acceleration and velocity the servo
level target positions are trivial
because we're using those really simple
formulas for acceleration velocity and
distance a little more detail on how to
actually do this we set a limit this is
the the limit that's drawn in blue here
of the maximum path error if you were to
use a circular arc we calculate what
those endpoints look like the screw up
characters there are our vectors for the
input and output directions that gives
you the per axis accelerations you can
then inspect that against the
acceleration limits with your
constraints from the velocity your
volley will also have other limits in
the system from linear acceleration and
long path velocity limits you don't want
to go faster than say eighty millimeters
per second or something like that for
your extruder and once you know those
pieces of information you have a fairly
straightforward set of equations to
solve for each axis again they're
they're quadratic in nature and you know
what your path looks like one issue with
this algorithm is that the velocity can
be overly limited if you have a really
short segment we're going to force that
corner to be less than half of the
minimum segment length when that segment
length gets really small often slicers
will generate something like a 10 micron
move that can throttle the velocity down
even if there isn't a big angle change
that you'd like to blow through one of
the results looked like so here we have
a acute and obtuse corner you can see
that with each servo cycle we're slowing
down as we come into the corner the
velocity along the corner stays
relatively constant and then we
accelerate coming back out of that
corner you can see we're bounded here by
the circular arcs that are shown in pink
the future stop problem is actually
fairly straightforward to solve
conceptually you buffer n segments ahead
whether that's five segments three
segments or sixteen segments you do I
treat that buffer as the end of your
path so you're going to pretend that the
velocity has to come to zero you reverse
plan to find out what the maximum speed
you can reach is and then you release
the first segment making sure that
you're not going faster than that limit
you add the next segment and you loop it
seems really simple but that actually
chances are it's going to give you a
significant increase in the complexity
of your firmware particularly when you
think about how are you going to pause
and resume this because now you've got a
buffer that you're iterating through and
rolling around in and you need to be
able to do this simultaneously with the
servo computations which also means that
you need to have a quick calculation for
your maximum segment exit speed
particularly if you use a large buffer
we use a 15-second buffer for example
and it's it
seems to be plenty deep we use our
feedback in our system we have those
encoders on the motors there's a variety
of different methods to do that there
are open-loop control methods which are
much simpler you can do bang bang and
deadband control which is what your
thermostat does at home you can do
proportional control and that can be
based on position or velocity targets or
some other parameter you can do a
proportional integral control when you
do that you need to watch out for what
happens when you have a step change or
when you're going to reset your integral
buffer you can do PID control watch out
for silver of eight and velocity
resolution issues that may be available
to you we perform our server loops at a
substantially lower rate than many
mechanical systems out there so that we
have a better velocity resolution in our
PID control you can add in some
feed-forward terms these could be a very
complicated system model of the system
or simply adding in some terms that are
coefficients on your target velocity or
your target acceleration you can also
implement adaptive methods where you're
informing the changing the gainsay of
your PID parameters based on the
performance of the system in the case of
the mod T we do PID you with a few feed
with forward terms on acceleration and
velocity in the X and y axis and again
you want to keep it simple here start
with something that's really simple work
through progressive stages and when you
get something that works you may just
want to sit there and optimize it rather
than getting into something really
complicated or academic with feedback
you can use that for Turk utilization in
a closed-loop system you generally need
less margin in terms of the force that's
available on the motors and how you're
using it because you can recover you can
use it for stall detection and motor
protection unit test bump and drag
homing in the case of the mod T we sense
stall in the X and y-axis on our build
tray and we sense the transverse drag in
the z-axis to home the z-axis
automatically because we can do that we
don't need to dial in those parameters
fully automatic and it allows us to
reduce our part count we don't have any
limits which is in the system so what
does this actually look like here's a
simple star the path is drawn in black
the execution is shown in blue because
we have sort of a feedback we can plot
those servo traces if we zoom in on a
corner again you can see this nice
smooth arc that's that's performed there
and you can see how well we follow that
the tick marks here are tenth of a
millimeter tick marks so we're actually
following quite well however this is
being taken at the encoder position not
the actual tray position if you look at
a simple circle this is just the start
and fold over on that very similar
situation I like to look at things like
a what I call a bowtie path and when i
zoom in on that it really helps you
identify when you've got a problem in
your path planner you can see all sorts
of strangeness going on in that path
then back out you can see in the servo
plot on this you can see we've got some
resonance as we come into the centre and
then it drops off as we actually execute
the centre this is just a random path in
space if we look at the positions as a
function of time we have fairly smooth
curves there if we look at the velocity
plots in this case you can see we have
it's basically all lined and it should
be because we're using constant
acceleration which gives us these
trapezoidal or linear velocity profiles
they're capped at our maximum velocity
the combined velocities in red there you
see little dips occasionally for
instance in the top centre that's
actually when we're going through a
corner I said that the entry exit
velocity are the same but the along path
velocity through that corner actually
dips a little bit you can then plot the
acceleration in this case we have a 500
millimeter per second squared
acceleration cap and you can see how
that's implemented there are six spots
there where we exceed that and that's
where we're playing a little bit of
dirty math to deal with handling of
small segments and then we can go back
put those sort of a traces on the path
and actually look at the error as a
function of time
the tick marks here are 50 microns apart
it's about half a hair apart the total
size is the size of the nozzle diameter
so tracks fairly well so we've talked
about how to get from alpha to Omega
with the mod T we do this with the high
resolution encoder that's 334 lines
going around we do that was a little bit
of math and Thank You hackaday for
having me to come and enjoy your time at
Supercross
[Music]