I was guided by my name is security
kamijo in current work
and everyone
a new marine technology thank you so
this talk was basically more of a kind
of a thing I wanted to provide back to
the community there's a lot of struggle
on designing and engineering a lot of
these tools so as you said I'm a
security engineering security engineer
at a small payment processing company in
Atlanta I presented various different
cons about wireless technology mesh
technology firmware linic you know linux
embedded firmware I mean I call myself a
Tier one video game addict
I love first-person shooters on xbox
live and I also love weird science
that's me shining myself with a class 4
laser because you know science is cool
so this talk is basically going to go
break down a lot of the software terms
and concepts basically kind of ignore
the vendor stuff that's out there and
the made-up terms that they have and
then go most importantly how to engineer
and design a lot of these tools so goals
basically go over and more of a
historical progression and view of a lot
of these software tools that exist take
out all the vendor bs provide open
source alternatives if there is some
provide tools with the highest reward
most bang for your buck that you get out
of it help with the information struggle
there's a lot of open source tools that
documentation is good but it's hard to
get to that stage where you really
understand that documentation and how to
deal with that and also explain the good
bad and ugly of each of these tools so I
feel like in every type of talk or
presentation or anything concept you
want to provide you can break it down
into three different concepts so
providing a graph here on the far left
is basically time spent drinking which
equates to how much time security
engineers are putting into addressing or
researching or you know a you know
finding these problems and fixing it and
then the far right is the actual fixing
the problem basically the three
different categories are you're going to
be
signature bass which is everyone knows
like AV products things like that are
all used signatures and I mean it's a
great concept
but I mean if a SCADA firmware has a
exploit on it and there's a signature
for it I don't really care at a payment
processing company about that signature
your leased access which is going to be
more defined towards you know user
permissions I also want to touch on the
application side which I think a lot of
information security engineers are not
really going that deep into and then
behavior based which is more geared
towards my definition is what is your
infrastructure how can you define it and
look at something kind of outside that
normal behavior and this is really good
worthwhile so you can see each one of
these are represented by and it's not to
scale probably signature is like ninety
percent but each one of these are
represented by some type of alcoholic
beverage you find at a bar so that's my
bar graph so thank you so there's and
that's kind of the theme for a lot of us
I'm gonna go talk over some type of a
tool that exists and then I'm gonna kind
of ask you know what type of thing is it
so who has a sim or deals with the sim
okay would you would you classify that a
signature based behavior based or at
least access all right cool good
so sim is basically kind of the
definition is the security information
and event management it's basically a
way to take all of your log sources from
different applications or different
products and put in one central source
and create rules off of it so you get
create alerts or custom panels and
information to provide you see your
security context so I'm going to break
that also down in three different
concepts so the first concept is
internal sources which is basically what
type of logs
you're gonna digest so obviously when
you're deploying a sim it's a lot of
effort involved with it you want to
start looking at all the operating
system logs you know such as you know
the temp or server log be temp or W temp
or securities you know the actual
applications are the login sessions with
that event logs for Windows Apple
Asian logs such as like you know patchy
logs you know somebody's getting a four
hundred or a four or four on the website
transaction logs on your DB Network logs
so if you have your you know your brand
name variant of that firewall how do you
know take those sis logs and ship it
into that device you can also do things
like bro which I'll be talking about
later application or appliance logs so
there's a lot of these black box devices
so like yours--and device or some type
of out-of-band management device and
you're able to take those logs in there
and then the other thing is to a lot of
these same products will allow you to
digest like vendor management or
vulnerability management and policy
compliance tools so you'll have a
central pane of glass of what type of
incident
what type of vulnerabilities may exist
in your infrastructure any kind of
report off of that so the second part to
it is your your outside external
information such as your threat feeds
which is your threat intelligence not
really sophisticated just bunch of
security researchers that spend time on
are these IP addresses known for doing
bad stuff do these dns names exist
because there's some type of spam
candidate or now or you know component
to it are these files or tools known for
malicious purposes and can we put
signatures and hashes based off of that
so that's what the external contacts
that provides that goes into your sim
they could get information off of and
then you can also provide like external
like you know things like you know what
if that logs or bad things you know that
you want to expect to alert on and then
you could do custom alerts so that's the
thing that you would work on when you're
designing your sin so you know cool
concept is like VPN distance so if
somebody logs into San Francisco into
the VPN and tendance later you see that
another geoip of New York login well
there's no way that somebody could go
from San Francisco to New York 10
minutes so kick off an alert if there's
an RDP access from an outside IP you
know I I pee that you're in it's an
internal device only you create an alert
off of that and talk to your firewall
people brute-force attempts so
somebody's you know hammer
sh Loggins on something you can you know
look into that
outside hours so if you have a
corporation that has you know you're
nine to five you could create alerts on
things that are outside those hours a
large data transfer file so somebody
looks like they're trying to exfil files
you could create alerts on it and just
you know a standard user behavior so
what do you expect when you're buying or
designing your own sim product you want
to have basically a central log source
that has you know the ability to take
all that in but also have some way of
using secure data transfer for that you
don't want those logs all clear-text
easy to install
agent sometimes some of these big-box
shops that will sell you a sim product
have the most complicated things in the
world to install and they don't work so
well open platforms to support logs so
if you have a sim product that can't
support standard sis logs get rid of it
there's no point fast indexing and
searching so I'll talk a little bit more
about that also an easy you know user
interface and a graphical representation
so you got to make your c-level people
happy giving them those pie charts easy
to create alerts so that you know you're
not spending a whole lot of time
creating it you know ten thousand line
string to basically create alert off if
somebody you know gives access to domain
admin and then third-party tools
integration so if you have like a laugh
or a vulnerability software you can
integrate that into your sim so when it
might come with your sim product is
vulnerability management sometimes risk
management sometimes it has like
forensic tools that are built in there
sometimes it comes with like an IDs and
IPS software built into it a lot of
these people will try to sell you this
one shop stop type of solution that
includes the sim and I don't think
that's an ideal thing to have one vendor
take you know all of your security
context because you you want to have
different eyes looking at it and then
also you know especially with those big
box vendors you get a pretty empty
wallet and crappy support so I'm going
to talk about the old and new way of the
sim products so there's a little and I
swear if like Gardner coins next-gen sim
I'm probably going to like show up to
their office use a bathroom and not
flush a toilet or something like that
but the the
there's three things that I find then a
lot of these newer Sims that provide
really great information that makes
things you know a lot better overall
first its threat feed integration so you
could have like open source platforms is
like probably like four really good ones
out there that you could download that
from you take the time and effort that a
lot of open source researchers provide
and integrate it into your sense of you
see that information you can learn on it
instantly less black box I know it
sounds weird but there's a lot of these
black box solutions for these same
products that they don't even know these
companies they purchased something a
long time ago that they never the
developers are all gone at that point so
there's some sim products they're full
open-source so you could if you have a
question of how it works you look at the
source code and then also using the
using the usage of inverted index search
engines instead of your standard
original relational database management
systems and I'll dive into that in a
second it's a kind of a cool concept
that I haven't heard anybody ever talk
about so your standard database system
your SQL database this is just an
example I took from Apache loosin which
started the whole concept of your
inverted index and how much more
efficient it is and granted this all
about engineering SQL databases are
still ideal for like a transactional
it's all based case scenario but when
you're dealing with a sim product you
want something that has a search engine
so in the statement the or this example
has two statements in there the quick
brown fox jumped over the lazy dog quick
brown fox is leap over lazy dog and or
dogs in summer the sentence makes no
sense but I'll explain in a second why
this this is a part of that concept so
the first line is nine nine words 45
characters second line is eight words 48
characters so just keep that in mind
that those two sentences yes and the
standard type of SQL database is going
to pay sleep it in all that information
is all separately so you're basically
inverted index has a indexer inside of
your infrastructure that takes in your
event logs and then it basically does
some type of you know indexing and in
that indexing it puts it into different
docks those two different docks get
normalized and this is just it's
depending on your context of your
product and how you're dealing this this
context we don't really care about
uppercase or lowercase we don't care
about all this other stuff we just care
about the context of what the statement
is we don't even care that the word
leapt or jump is there we just want some
type of word representing it so that
this is the index and normalized version
of that and basically it's a lot smaller
so the difference is that it goes from
17 words and 93 characters and bites
down to 10 words and 39 characters which
helps a tremendous amount when you're
dealing with some type of product like a
sim or some type of database that is
gonna you could narrow down and make it
a lot more efficient plus in that
reference you could have a doc that
basically takes you know a bunch of
words into a single byte reference and
it makes things a heck of lot quicker
when you're basically doing a search off
of it so if there's one IP you're not
going through a bunch of SQL data files
to search for one IP you basically have
a reference in there that could you know
say okay this IP is here and here's the
context that's around that so why is
this important
I'm not you guys probably can't read
this at all but this is a Windows Event
log and it's actually there's even more
to this Windows Event log so all this
information basically says that somebody
successfully logged into my network why
do I need all this information and
that's why I believe that these newer
sim products that have the inverted
index are just way more efficient and
overall you know takes down a lot of
resources in time when you're trying to
actually you know look into the incident
so the next category so I'm gonna go
through a bunch of different tools
explain them so that people have more of
a concept and this is the most basic one
in the world so who wants to guess what
category is av
come on anybody signatures thank you as
simple so the pretty much started in
1987 rumors have it somebody made a
virus to make an anti-virus software
it's I think that's all bs a really
heuristic started in 1991 modern-day
heuristics started late 90s probably
early 2000s and I'll explain that in a
second and then your next-gen a V a
signature less 2014 so the concept the
easiest concept to understand and this
is the most basic you could do with an
anti-virus off
and I'm gonna talk about hashes not the
stuff on top not the delicious
hashbrowns right there but a
mathematical compute sumption so um you
have basically a file and that file does
like an md5 checksum which is just some
hashing function and then outputs a hash
a small list of characters so you don't
have to have a large file so basically
if this file exists in your you know
downloading it through your computer and
the AVA kicks off and says does it
equate to this hash therefore it's a
virus simple straightforward that's how
antivirus software works in a nutshell
obviously there's newer stuff since the
early 90s called heuristics which
basically puts heuristics is basically
an easily put a search logarithm that
detects patterns so I don't want you
know don't tell your next-gen antivirus
software but they've been doing
artificial intelligence since the 90s
so this basically this looks into the
when the programs execute it looks into
the data segment static variables the
heap and stack you know what type of
compiler is used functions of that
actual program and then it uses things
like reg X to search through that
program itself or them things in the
memory and it does like in memory
pattern matching and then or what type
of processes does this program attach to
so that's the heuristics that's how
antivirus software detects what type of
behavior and this puts in a category
okay this behavior is normally part of
this virus or this you know exploit
campaign so then basically comes the
boredom of okay we got antivirus where
we're able to look at hashes and we have
some cool stuff eristic s-- what can we
sell to these people now let's do it
call this thing called internet security
package where we provide a local
firewall an IDs and IPS which is really
layer 2 and layer 3 of the OSI
you're just caring about if there's ARP
spoofing or somebody's giving you the
ping of death a web filter in the email
filter so it's just basically a few
additional things added on for the
standard consumer it's not really worth
it for like an enterprise console we're
trying to monitor web traffic or email
traffic it does provide a lot of context
and helps out with that so what does AV
suck
I'm sure you guys hear that before in
security talks basically av won't
protect you from targeted attacks so if
somebody is smart enough to craft you
know Metasploit and if there's a
possible you know exploit that has
definitions you just wrap that function
into something base64 and therefore it's
not a virus anymore so the other problem
is antivirus definitions are generally
24 be our 24 hours behind an active
campaign and the reason why is that if a
it's not like this magical thing that
exists there's security researchers who
generally automate everything they have
honey pots out there that detect all
this stuff and then they put
classifications off of that by the
automated tools that exist and then then
from there they validate this
information and then they send it to QA
and the QA make sure that disease
definitions don't break everything in
the world you know it might have a
similar function or hash that windows
you know running and it's a common thing
you know people had AV products doing
updating and B blue screens every single
computer in the world but because of
that it takes almost a day for those
definitions to exist so this won't
protect you from like massive warm
vulnerabilities that are your zero day
vulnerabilities but she's not really
here today a good example would be wanna
crypt would AV protect you against this
no because it's happening the day of and
there's nothing you can do to prevent it
because it's kind of take more than a
day to create definitions off of that so
signatures keep getting larger and
larger a lot of time and spent into it
and it also tab because the signatures
are so large it takes a toll on your CPU
and unbunch in your memory when you run
antivirus products the other thing I
really hate about this and nobody really
talks a lot avy when you install it on a
Windows computer requires kernel hooks
so if which has been a known thing if a
vulnerability exists an anti-virus
product they're not just compromising
the antivirus product they're
compromising your whole operating system
it's running on a privilege mode ring
zero and it affects everything so they
own your system if they own and of your
antivirus product and the other thing is
there's a lot of enterprise console
tools that exist that require you to use
domain admin which is just such a
horrible thing so that when you plug a
computer and automatically deploys
if somebody compromises that you you
know they have their keys to your
kingdom so it's just it's not a good
thing plus any type of new malware tries
to read code functions every time that
executes so there's easy ways to bypass
it so after I just crapped all over it
why is the antivirus why should you use
it so antivirus is still great for a
little hanging fruit and that's been
talked about but basically there is no
way to protect the end user for being an
idiot and downloading like a PDF file
and executing it or you know downloading
a file called definitely not virus exe
and executing it there is no way of
preventing the end user from that but if
then you know definitely not a virus not
Exe has a definition area of our
software that will protect you against
that and it also still catches malware
campaigns have been going on so it's
still a good thing for that servers not
as much but it's still there so this is
a concept that I want to talk about that
I haven't really seen a lot of more
progression on mostly because one of the
free software that existed on this died
out but anti exploit anti-malware was
such a great thing yet nobody cares
about it so anti exploit kits basically
have the ability to limit executable
resources memories or shared libraries
of an application that generally when in
a vulnerability exists in a program it's
usually referencing like a library or
something else or part of the memory
that it shouldn't be and these anti
exploit kits will prevent that so this
like would drop a good chunk of most of
vulnerabilities that exist malware
requires like I said code execution and
basically and a good example that
visualized this let's say you have
somebody that needs Adobe Flash which
nobody should have but in case somebody
needs Adobe Flash to view SWF files
which are just media files because it
you know the company is way too lazy to
take convert that to a modern a standard
but you could block in your anti exploit
kit ActionScript where the
vulnerabilities exist so if this SWF
file tries to execute ActionScript which
is just kind of like a JavaScript on the
Adobe Flash it's going to crash the
application so you could deploy this and
be less worried about it and so
basically the ant
exploit kits give you the capability to
not just harden your operating system
but the applications as well and gives
you the applications the least access so
if there is some library or
vulnerability or something that it's
trying to do and it really prevents that
so it deals with a lot less hassle so
this was a free product that Microsoft
see you know used they ever had out
there they said that the functions are
somewhat parted in Windows 10 and it was
such a great software and they don't
they're not supporting anymore but it's
not because some conspiracy theory that
they wanted you know windows to be less
secure is mostly because this was an
add-on application that isn't part of
the kernel and there is a security
researcher that always just like poked
around that and found ways around it
because it's an application level that
hooks into the curl so anybody that
talks about like new technology or
threats or antivirus software always
brings up this pyramid of pain it's like
a really cool concept everyone talks
about I just wanted people one of the
cool kids I just want to bring this up
on my slide deck but I don't want to
beat a horse to death so now even I've
talked about it so next is endpoint
detection and response not the typical
IDI that you hear on your emails that
you get but a EDR is basically a your
next-gen antivirus software and you
can't really find information about this
what it is and how it works so I put on
a site that can explain it so basically
EDR is kind of like your sim like portal
so you have the ability to you know have
all of your endpoints connect to a
central box and there you can see what's
you know what's going on with the actual
computer such as like you know if
they're what event logs are happening
what type of you know things are running
in the memory what programs exist so it
basically gives you the ability to go
through and incident and go do some
additional threat hunting on per
endpoint base they also provide some
cool stuff like AI and machine learning
which I mean is essentially if you know
you install the program it gives you a
software baseline and then if that
baseline goes outside of a normal scope
like let's say somebody installs
additional program it creates a abnormal
check behind that so that's how they do
they a I machine
basically it also does like behavior
based control so somebody's running like
me me cats in the memory and that hash
is dumped and it's also you can see that
same hash being passed around and
somebody's pivoting to another box it
has some type of behavior on that so
it's a cool tool and also has like new
Yara rules which aren't signatures but
they are signatures so that's your
signature less antivirus software in a
nutshell it's a cool concept it's still
relatively new I think you know it could
be a lot better a lot of people will
criticize it and because you know some
person compiled a you know C code called
print HelloWorld sent it to virustotal
and that one vendor is like oh it's a
virus because that's how machine
learning works
apparently so that that that could be
something that's going to be a lot
better but if you have like an IDs IP or
an IPS already and a full-on sim product
you already kind of at that stage what
this tool could do so open source
alternatives to that edr software which
are download and install and deploy near
infrastructure right now would be
Facebook OS query Google rapid response
or you could just you know if you don't
have a sim product already use an open
source sim like elk or gray log so
alright let's talk about wife web
application firewall so who wants to
guess what category that is
yeah did it yep it's said yes it can be
behavior but so I'm this little security
engineer at my company I don't got time
to write rules all the time this I'm not
lazy I just got too much going on but
I'll explain to them a few that it could
be used for behavior and it's really
something that should be but buddy
Wassily Web Application Firewall
generally has some type of canned list
of rules so if there's like any SQL
injection attack that blocks it lfi RFI
directory traversal some like that it
sees that type of behavior blocks in and
that's all the signatures that you're
mentioning you know there's a get
request with a script tag in there well
somebody's trying to do cross site
scripting block it known campaigns you
know actually tell you a little story so
I have a laugh at cloud-based laugh and
I see laugh alerts on I think it was
like Drupal maybe WordPress but
something that doesn't affect us because
that's how signatures work they tell you
that this person is attacking sudden
platform that you don't have and it had
the hackers team name in it and I'm
thinking to myself is this really like
are they that brave and just like think
that they could do this and get away
with it this is like an old
vulnerability probably three months old
and I'm like this can't exist so I take
that hacker team name and type it in
Google one of ten plus pages and like so
this many websites out there got pwned
by this I'm like huh so there's that
basically if you have like a cloud based
laughs they have you know threat
intelligence so speak and they they
protect against known campaigns brute
force attempts so you know somebody's
trying to hammer your admin page in your
WordPress console I'll let you know so
go into your behavior control base the
proper way is really doing this is to
sit down with your developers have
somebody in napsack deal with this and
go through the actual application itself
like for example is this URL string
gonna be more than 256 characters no
let's let's fix that block anything
that's not 256 characters so your cookie
session is gonna be longer than that is
this gonna be a post or get requests on
this page you could create rules and
make things a little heck of a lot more
secure it's not your like be all and all
solution really
tell them the deficit fix the issues but
it's a good way to prevent a lot of
stuff there's a open source alternative
called modsecurity it works with n JAXA
patching I think is also and it's just
basically a wife role in there
another thing is additionally a lot of
cloud-based laughs pretty much I think
all of them offer DDoS protection
because content delivery networks tend
to be also cloud-based laughs and it's
an easy thing for a content delivery
network to provide DDoS protection so
generally an added feature with it for
free so your next-gen firewalls so you
hear this all the time you're like I
don't have a typical firewall I have the
next-gen firewall so I have my Call of
Duty reference here this guy gives their
mom cooks some cod fish and the cod fish
does 360 noscopes and then calls Harrell
something inappropriate
so next-gen firewall is basically your
typical firewall but it's not just OSI
layer two and three it's does all the
layers of OSI I it basically provides
intrusion detection some asset and
fingerprinting and then also some of
them might include AV so if it scans the
packets and and it gets all the
information on there they'll digest all
the knockin over there
digest I know
so the digests all the information
creates a file often creates an AV alert
this basically is a firewall Plus
application rules so in general most
people will deploy these blinky boxes in
your infrastructure don't understand the
what these alerts are and you get this
next-gen firewall that's just given your
standard firewall
this is more assets on the network side
so let's say if somebody prime properly
configure something for like slv-3 your
bro logs or your next-gen firewall tell
you that SLV traffic happens here you
need to fix this for compliance reasons
so there's a bunch of a whole list of
things on that so I'm going to talk
about and these are actually for my
training I provided at besides Cleveland
on designing and engineering your own
network security monitoring box and
there's a lot of these I next-gen
software that you could provide but you
could actually engineer yourself for
free because all these tools are
open-source and you could do it so there
was between IDs and IPS and I both are
you know intrusion system ones
preventing and ones detecting generally
the IDS software takes in the network
packet analyzes it and then creates a
some type of rule around that that's
essentially a signature and then kicks
it off and these rules are based off a
community or professionally created rule
sets so I'm going to talk about a
concept that I found really cool that I
never see anybody talked about and it's
basically to increase the performance of
your IDs or IPs software without
sacrificing anything really so but in
order to talk about this concept I'm
gonna provide just kind of a five minute
overview of Linux operating system how
it works so this is started off
everything is a file so your home
directory is a file and repeat after me
so when you basically have like your
hard drive your dev SDA that reference
file is a file thank you so your
keyboard input your which is basically a
char device when you're typing on your
keyboard
that is a your memory layout and how all
that exists that is a reference in the
actual folder structure which is a your
shared UNIX resources u which is us are
not user which everyone thinks it's a it
basically where all your libraries or
information that should programs use is
a
okay even your network card which I'll
talk about in a second which is kind of
why I'm trying to explain all this is a
this guy right here is a pedo all right
thank you so ignore this more ignore
this wall of text right here to go over
simply everything is a file on your
operating system your operating system
has a scheduler and threads that
basically bounces between us so you're
type on a keyboard files are being
transferred your hard drive and it's
just your operating system that tells
your CPU how to handle all that stuff in
the memory so that's how a kernel which
is level or ring 0 lowest level works in
order for an application though to
reference things that are in the kernel
like your network card and it basically
has to do a system call to the kernel
and the kernel base so then references
the network file the network file then
pulls information off of it and then
sends it directly back to the
application so it creates a tremendous
amount overhead and this is why I want
to talk about both PF ring and AF packet
so basically these programs give the
capability have the kernel do like an
nmap where carves off information inside
the network device so that the
application can I like mount it or read
it directly and that gives you generally
between a 20 and 40 percent performance
and I haven't really seen anybody talk
about this or do this properly so and
the other thing is there's a lot of
programs like grocery cata molex if you
want full packet capture analysis all
support AF packet so if you have a
operating since like CentOS 7 or
something newer that supports this use
it and use it properly and you're going
to gain a huge performance increase
because you're not going you know
bending over backwards to get
information off your network device so
if you're going to be deploying like an
IDs from IPS and infrastructure start
with an IP IDs if you're going to be
deploying on the web traffic side use a
laugh
I've actually know a company that paid
for a IPS software inside their web
layer without SSL termination so just
grinding through 99% encrypted data
without creating ever alerts on it and
you know it was expensive tool so if you
do have an IPS maintain a rule a small
ruleset because you know on Trollope
traffic or have an additional CPU
overhead that's going to cause network
latency and then also use a which is not
really harder to get and more expensive
but a fail up and neck so basically
these fail up and Nick's have the
ability that if the kernel crashes or if
the a OS reboots something like that
happens it's not going to drop all of
your network traffic because you have an
IPS that's in line it's gonna basically
have a FPGA that's built into that
network device and it sees that it can't
get calls back so it go ahead and
continue on their network traffic so
snort is the second based ids system
everyone thinks it's the first one it's
basically the original rule set that
everyone bases their signatures off of
originally was a source fire then became
cisco then talis rebranded its or cisco
rebranded italo's it has better distro
support there's a lot of packages built
into log dish shows that have this has
better documentation and apparently
there's a rumor that version 3.0 that
came out in beta like 10 years ago and
still in beta supports multi-threading
so Sierra coda is the newer version of
snort it's created by the our Creed
ended by the open Information Security
foundation is multi-threaded so you
don't have to worry about version 3.0
ever existing it does also which nobody
ever talks about is non port Pacific
protocol detection so in your snort
config file if you want to say you know
there's HTTP traffic you say port 80 and
443 are assumed to be HP traffic which
if I do an SSH tunnel out of port 80
it's not going to see that actual
network traffic in that sense so it's
not as robust because that it also has
Lua scripting capability so it's a
full-on programming language to you know
if there's no traffic in Excel we're out
of executables you could I'm gonna
compress a file and pull things off
event and then analyze alerts off of
that it also has built in IP reputation
which the snort doesn't have so that has
the ability to based
rules off of ip's
kudos sport and stuff like that yes it
Syriac out it does have that sale so if
you have the ability to use a CPU for
signature-based or GPU for your page
detection it can offload that there so
bro is basically a more of a well it's
an IDs system but everyone uses it more
of a net flow or fingerprinting
basically has the ability to look at
custom protocols you could have those
information of all the protocols exist
on a file that you can ship up to your
sims so it gives you all the application
level side of it so things like if the
Alabama management has a login you could
create an alert off of that you have
your multimedia extensions that you know
if a file or network traffic happens
it'll actually recreate that network
traffic and create a file saying this
file exists and it's a DOS executable or
it's a shockwave file so it's it's very
robust in the sense that it understands
all the applications and you can do a
lot more off of it nobody uses a form or
signature base but a lot of people use
it for gathering the information and
ship it up to your sim that provides a
lot of context in your environment so
rule manager so you got two different
rule managers out there you have orth
master and pulled-pork really clever
names so you basically a link master is
kind of like the older version both of
these are going to be like rule sets
that have the ability to go to these
certain you know vendors and download
the actual signatures and then creates a
kind of config files which won't which
signatures you want to drop enable and
deal with only capacitor is outdated
don't use it only use only capacitor if
you have to support legacy tools
pulled-pork is the new thing that
supports everything so you got different
rule sets just to go over this real
quick
you basically have snort Talos which is
a community-driven one
there's also snort Alice professional
there's emerging threats professional
which both any pro set is going to be
have some type of security researcher
behind that providing you better context
but you're also paying for that stuff
emerging threats open know
GPL which is basically just their open
rules and they have also emerging
threats open which contains their open
rules plus the original snort GPL rules
which are going to be more of your like
a layer 2 and layer 3 type of rules like
somebody's gonna pay our spoof and then
also community rule sets which is really
cool because they somebody rates writes
a blog article with the emerging threat
rule set they'll include it into their
open rules so if you have Siri cotta
they have a lot of really good
integration for the emerging threats
because they base a lot of the IP
information off around around that so
and this is more of the behavior based
of your your next-gen or your IDs and
IPS that you could do so generally in
your serie Katayama or snort config file
you could go through there and specify
ok these are gonna be the subnet for my
HP servers and you can do the individual
IP so if you want to you know have to do
the whole subnet but if something you
know like somebody does an SSH tunnel
out of your iis web server which is
running in Microsoft Windows you create
alerts off of it so you could specify
these things in here and it provides you
a lot better context so what would
happen in your infrastructure so when
you're actually going through the
deploying method of this IDs or IPs
software you're going to get a crap-ton
of false positives because certain
things are kind of normal behavior if I
have a network monitoring software that
things at programs all the time and sees
it gets a response you're gonna get
rules on there basically saying that Oh
somebody's trying to ddos and ping your
stuff one it's just a normal behavior so
you go through there you want to start
with thresholds that config which
basically tells the source IP or
destination IP has this signature and
you get to kind of narrow down don't be
lazy and just drop the whole signature
and not deal with it so next type of
tool out there security software out
there is a vulnerability assessment
tools if I would say you know if you're
gonna put money into something that you
haven't yet this is your best bang for
your buck let's take a gander at
somebody that I want to guess on the
signature of the signature based
behavior based released access for
vulnerability assessment tools
yeah it's I think it's all the above and
I'll explain in a second so your
vulnerability assessment is kind of your
thing that you here a data breach
happened I'm not going to name the
company we could probably all guess this
from a three month of old vulnerability
that exists and now you got free credit
monitoring for globally because of this
but it's not because you know they were
attacked by this sophisticated you know
researcher or whatever creating that
crafting those vulnerability you just
didn't patch in three months so this is
gonna be your best bang for your buck
when you're patching it or deploying it
also do it like hardening guidelines
you're gonna get a lot more out of it
too if you use harden frameworks like
the Center for information security if
nobody has ever heard the CIS before
they work with the actual vendors like
Microsoft Red Hat Cisco and they say ok
these are their best ways to harden your
application or your program or operating
system whatever it is and provide me
that and we'll create a template off of
that and a lot of these vulnerability
assessment tools that scan your
infrastructure will have audit files in
there that will scan that say okay are
you based you know close enough to this
hardening guideline that exists when
you're deploying this out scan all the
things I know it may be costly because
some of these solutions are Pro IP based
but it's gonna save you a lot more
headache in long run use SSH keys don't
just do password based stuff and also
use agents because if you have a just
standard Sh passwords you install a box
in there you could steal those credits
for an open source alternative there's
the thing called open bass but you
cannot get what you pay for in the
solution to go over if you haven't the
design or deployed vulnerability
assessment even before this you want to
kind of have a few things in place
before that and SC ap is security
automation protocol which is basically
just the overall package for your
vulnerability assessment tools and how
they work so you want to basically get a
list of all your hardware assets you
want to have the all the operating
system on the hardware assets you want
to have all the application based
software which may be a little more
difficult because you know some people
will have like Firefox some people might
have certain code on there that is
that is running you want to also have a
patch management program if you are
working infrastructure that it doesn't
have a patch management program in there
don't work for them this should be
something that's been kind of a you know
thing that from any company exists that
should have that and then also you know
you want to base your information on
what type of security framework that you
you work in so if you work like PCI
HIPAA you know you want to use NIST
standards you want to decide on that
framework before you actually deploy
this so in this one right here is a kind
of in a way different but similar it's a
static and dynamic application security
testing some of the like newer
vulnerability scanners will do like let
app testing which is basically just a
dynamic application security testing
so generally data breaches are on the
rise and most of these exist via the web
nowadays dynamic application security
testing framework or tool basically
validates the web function there's them
one out there that I'm going to mention
is called Iraq now there's some lot of
paid ones out there but arachnid does
just as good as job as I've seen a lot
of the paid ones and basically what it
does is it scans your website for things
that are might be like SQL injection on
a page cross-site scripting cross-site
request forgery just scans of all these
functions to see what it could get out
of it it's language agnostic all most of
the best so it doesn't really matter if
you have your web application written
Python or you know a Java or anything
like that this is also you want to make
sure you have either of these before you
even do a pen test a lot of companies
will pay for pen test either not even
having a full vulnerability assessment
program in their or their application
doesn't have this it's a waste of money
for the pen testers because they will
find all these vulnerabilities and you
rather just spend it initially and get
those addressed before the pen tester
comes about static source code or a
static application security testing may
vary per language there's actually talk
today that I saw those really good on
web app security goes over a lot of that
stuff referenced that if you wants more
information on this and then there's
also a reference
like I put up there which will I'll
share the slides on later today for your
source code analysis tools alright this
is I'm bringing this up mostly because
this is where a lot of money goes into
at least access your identity access
manager in your debt loss prevention and
it's mostly there for compliance reasons
but uh basically like I said London goes
into this both of them their goal is to
limit access to file shares or system
access DLP is more towards like
preventing sensitive information from
ever existing on there so if you have
like credit card numbers or Social
Security numbers or account routing
numbers you want to limit that from
clear-text and all that stuff and that's
what a lot of these DLP's will scan or
detect on the interesting thing about
identity access management software
they're great tools for pen testers so
if the pen tester pops like the domain
at or the active directory he has the
keys of the kingdom at that point so he
owns all your computers so it's it's a
good thing and it could also be a bad
thing obviously it needs to be there for
a lot of reasons especially compliance
and just how a lot of infrastructures
work but it's also kind of like a weird
thing to think about it that it's one
central point of failure that cascades
everywhere and the DLP though is
generally great for like low-hanging
fruit same with like really I guess I
didn't any access manager but it's not
going to protect you from a attacker
that understands you know ways around it
or you know how to deal with certain
things and this is a good prime example
I saw this a couple days ago Troy's a
pretty famous guy in the information
security realm he basically put in here
at lol yeah that all just work fine so
there's two things wrong with this first
thing is there is not a whole lot of
emails in there that you you know you
that like I think there's some free
emails that you could put in there
they'll still work even if not it takes
like ten bucks to register a domain for
example definitely a real business email
com
and I have an MX record that I could
actually now say that that's an I
personal business because that's how DLP
works they want to make sure you're only
here using business emails only the
other thing that's really crappy about
this the second part is that this
actually client-side code if I want to
throw this through an attack proxy
that's all fine and dandy I'll register
a gmail account doesn't matter because I
can intercept that traffic it's run
rendering on my client side so this is
the list of security maturity so if
you're trying to make sure your
company's good and you know ready for
things you want to start with full asset
discovery patch management software a
vulnerability assessment then start
working into your security framework or
a system hardening if you don't have one
highly recommend CIS templates because
the cool thing about the CIS is that
when you use that template it applies
for every other compliance
they'll have reference saying that this
thing does
you know PCI 2.21 or this will do HIPAA
compliance this thing so they all have
references to all that so if you do see
is you do em all essentially for
in-house applications that you have in
your company you want to make sure you
do static application security testing
and then also dynamic - you want to do a
full log integration and then you know
take all that information and send it to
a sim you want to have your IDs and IPs
and laughs fully integrated and then if
you have resources to build a full-on
sock then you want to also start using
like a network security monitoring tool
so you could analyze information here
infrastructure and do Incident Response
off of it you know things like this
would help you know companies when they
testify against Congress where they're
like yeah we got breach at this time
well what evidence you have well I don't
know somebody one of our vendors told us
that that it was can you provide that no
no but that's what happened and that's
actually last three breaches I hear had
that happen where they testified against
Congress so it's silly that they don't
have that context in their environment
so what do you spend money like I said
your best bang for your buck it's going
to be Ravana bility assessment tools
just spend a lot of money on also
working with the right people in house
allow the actual security to
and provide education I mean your
education to your security people are
gonna be your best bang for your buck
because they'll actually know what
they're doing they're not just
installing this blinky box that's gonna
you know say that we're doing something
when they're really not so if you have
any questions you feel free to hit me up
on Twitter that's my handle and also if
you want to go ahead and open the floor
for some questions good so white
listings always better than black
listing and it did it's it's gonna give
you a lot but the problem is you're
gonna come across a lot of people that
are like oddballs in the situation and
it's gonna be like you have to have a
dedicated person dealing with a lot of
that stuff and then you kind of want to
create like a baseline template for all
that and then work around like these are
the oddball people that have those
additional applications but yeah it's a
great solution though application
whitelisting
is it going to prevent and let's say
like you're doing this on a Windows
environment it's not gonna prevent if
there's a kernel execution off of
Windows NT so it's gonna protect you
from the application side but somebody's
has some type of kernel vulnerability
like a font type vulnerability it won't
protect the against at the still
patching is gonna fix all that stuff
[Music]
Oh
the rain all needed
yeah so his question was basically it if
you already have the list of packages
that are installed in your environment
is there a way to reference that to like
a you know mitre CV libraries stuff like
that a lot of like I said the
vulnerability assessment tools a lot of
them are just pretty much it will run
like a program in there it's like a
young update or Windows Update and I'll
say it reference it to the here and
here's the list of ones that aren't
installed and it references it's the CVS
and gives you a report on that there's
also a lot of compliance tool or a patch
management tools out there like wsus
will have you know these are the new
updates are coming in it'll reference
the CV number on those I don't know
about wsus
yeah yeah yeah IB there's a lot of
different ones out there but generally
if you have wsus you'll all reference
that and your answer question on will
this what type of vulnerability what's
affected it depends on like you may have
an is server that's running internally
only so like the CV score is only based
off of what they view as bad because
this is a common ending but you have
like I asked internally facing only then
that you could technically have your own
in-house CVE score and you know less in
it so it goes into like a whole lot of
stuff like how you deal with the
vulnerabilities if those vulnerabilities
are actually publicly exposed what's the
likelihood of that happening but
generally if it's like a critical no
matter what you want to get that fixed
because if somebody's inside of your
infrastructure with the like a
sufficient campaign or like that they
can they can exploit that good
oh he has a question for information
ticketing systems I think there was um
hit me up on Twitter I'll reference one
to you but I think I seen one I think
was called the hive I had never used it
so I can't give a fair honest opinion
there are a lot of like custom solutions
that I see a lot of these MSPs use
they're all based off of I was at a
service now it was just around custom
portal but it really varies but yeah if
you try the hive and then you find a
successful let me know too I have not
but I heard a lot of good things about
it but it seems like I'm a smaller
company so kind of be it seems like a
little waste to me but yeah they attack
framework has some really cool
sophisticated stuff on that but I don't
I don't see really like an actual tool
that bases off of that it's just kind of
an overall concept
that
oh no I haven't so that's news to me
okay I noticed on your Twitter he
promoted oh say
yeah I heard a lot of good things about
that it really depends because a lot of
times was you kind of does things that
some platforms already do on the the
back end for your sim but yeah that's
that's a really noted and very good
platform that a lot of people use yep
yep they certainly do
so there's a lot out there I don't want
to be my goals never talk about like a
vendor this is besides I want to talk
about like which Center is better I talk
about the open source tools but anything
that uses elasticsearch which is going
to be your elk cinnamon monster green
log which all use elasticsearch all have
that capability and the cool thing about
elasticsearch is it's made by it has
Apache loosin which is the foundation
that started all that stuff no problem
alright any other questions all right
looks like you got time to go see the
hawk you know yeah I'll post it on
Twitter okay and